All right.
All right, then.
Good morning, everyone.
I hope you guys all excited.
I hope you guys all ready for the class.
Have your big cup of coffee, tea,
whatever.
Gives you the energy. Right.
I see people are excited.
All right, that's good. That's good.
Red Bull. Oh, wow. Ten in the morning.
If all of the Red Bull works for you,
then you're more than your.
You go have fun with the Red Bull.
Red Bull to Mohana.
If you haven't Red Bull as well,
we're on water.
All right, that's good.
What is the lemon?
Right.
All right.
Tell me.
Tell me about
how is your first week going?
Cardamom. Tea.
I love that.
It's been great. Awesome.
With my wife.
Great. Pretty good.
You guys learn new things.
A lot of things with summer
Very well.
Yes, Summer Zach is doing very amazing
class.
Usually everybody loves it.
But then Gemma class comes
and then people start living it
more, Right?
All right, guys.
So today's a Saturday, right? Is Saturday.
So from now on, guys,
your weekends will be with me
for the next four,
the next couple of weeks.
And here, guys,
we will be learning about our programing.
Right.
All of you make things easy.
Of course you will make easiest
summer is amazing.
Summer is the best
motivator is the best speaker.
You guys will see him
next week.
He is going to do a quick recap with you.
And after that, you guys
not going to see him for some time,
but he will be coming here and there
talking to you guys, right, While
me and other instructor,
you'll be seeing a little bit more often.
Right?
Okay.
For those you guys don't
that don't know or maybe did not attend an
orientation class.
My name is so
I'll be one of you instructors guys.
Right.
We have multiple instructors
as we mentioned throughout this course
besides me teaching, you guys are going to
have our another great instructors guard
and he's been very amazing,
but stand as one to let him go.
So he's still with them yet.
And today we also guys have his support.
We have two instructors in there.
We have Mozambique and we have Shiva.
So any time, guys,
whenever we do in any practice today,
if you guys have any issues, any
questions, when you guys
are going to start in your code, hopefully
not right, You guys are going to send it
in this support channel.
Okay.
And so I welcome you everyone.
Guys, I'm very excited
and I have a lot of passion to teach in
and I've been teaching Java
for some time already, guys, and
probably this is
my most favorite topic
of most favorite module
out of the our entire course,
maybe because I'm an expert in it
and but all the modules,
of course will be fine.
They will be different.
But this is the biggest module guys,
that you will be learning
and it's going to take us about two
and a half months, I believe,
to finish the concepts that require us
to become a great automation.
Engineers
in Java is very interesting guys.
Java is very, very beautiful language
and of course
you will have to put an effort still in.
Of course, Java will be different compared
to your classes that you guys
are going to have on the weekdays.
Java, all the classes today.
Maybe you guys will hear me
talking about rules.
No rules about things that we going to do
from where
to learn what my expectation
what should be your expectation?
But after that
it will be completely hands on.
Right?
So and if you guys already
have your second monitor today,
you guys are going to see a lot
of benefits of having the second monitor.
If you have not,
then you guys probably will
realize, Oh, shoot,
I probably need a second monitor.
Right.
Okay.
So welcome, all of you.
I'm also very, very excited.
Usually for a lot of students,
Java does become one of the
favorite topics as well. And
I know you guys from
our orientation class, right.
There's probably I know 70% of your guys
coming from the referral
and I'm sure a lot of your friends,
if you ask them
if you have not asked them, please
make sure you go ahead and do that.
So if you ask them, Hey,
what will be your best suggestion
for me to succeed in this course?
So they're probably going to tell you,
please
make sure you guys are doing Java, right.
So from today's class
guys, we are going to say
we're going to start
building our fundamentals.
Why exactly Java? Why? Why not JavaScript?
So Java is one of the most popular
language when it comes to the program.
And right then we will talk about today
just very quickly.
But also it's
one of the widely used languages
when it comes to just automation and Java.
Jarrod will be harder a little bit,
of course, compared to the JavaScript.
And once you learn Java guys, then there
any any other programing language
will become very easy for you, right.
And what's most popular.
And then if you guys
will fall in love in Java
and if you guys would like to later,
of course not, not after this bootcamp,
but let's see
a few years down the road, if you would
like to grow more technically,
if you are becoming the Java developer,
you'll be making the great amount of money
right?
Okay.
So let me quickly look into this thing.
So oh, I need a link.
One memorable link to make
things in with.
I need to make
1001 moment.
This is I'm. I'm looking.
This man here
for a moment is
unique.
A little bit of talking
find the things.
Now listen.
All right?
It's right in
point, all right?
Because we're we're quick. Things like
I'm sure you guys
all can in your calendar, right?
Let me. Okay.
Sorry.
Do you guys bachelor
in here?
All right,
October 2nd, right? October 2nd.
So today,
you guys having your Java classes
and I'm sure you guys are all served
through your
through through the canvas already
right here.
You guys will see the topics.
So what is going to happen, guys,
for the first months, all on the weekends
we are going to have a Java classes
right On Tuesdays and Wednesdays
you are going to have non-technical
classes, so you guys will finish.
Just you'll see.
Then we'll be teaching you mental testing
and then what is going to happen
from next Thursday?
We are start
we start having review classes.
So this review classes
there will be about Java, right?
So for example, today and tomorrow,
whatever amount of information
you're going to learn, then you guys
are going to have additional Thursday.
We do say it's an optional.
However, we do ask you to attend
because they are
you guys will be going over
some new examples.
There is a little bit
more in-depth information will be given,
especially for those
if you guys want to understand something,
but I'll make sure you guys do right.
This is will be just additional where a
way where you guys can
get a better
understanding of some of the materials
if you have not came.
So all the review classes guys
they will be technical
and then after one month
that's one more fun start.
That's when you get going.
You go completely,
completely full into the program.
Right. But for now, only weekends
recorded classes.
Of course they will be of course, guys,
everything is that's the best part, right?
So everything will be recorded
and will be uploaded to Google Drive.
So any time you guys it
or is that or just want to go back
and rewatch it any time
all videos will be available in there.
However, my suggestion
guys, please make sure you do
attend as GA is a great instructor.
He's the one who will be started
with the overview classes
and you guys will learn a lot from him.
Okay.
So, all right, so and as you guys know,
today
we are going to spend 5 hours together.
So I first probably sounds,
oh my God, 5 hours.
The class is going to so long,
I got all my coffee and cookies,
whatever I need.
All right.
But actually, time will go very fast.
And because as I mentioned it, classes
very hands only very practical.
You guys will be following me typing, and
then I'll be giving you some exercises.
So that time usually goes quickly.
But of course, the guys
we are going to have breaks
and the way we usually do guys,
no, we try to give to short breaks.
We are going to have a break around 1130
for 15 minutes
and around 115
also for another 15 minutes.
Right.
So whenever there's
a logical end of the thoughts
and whenever we complete the assignments.
So 1130 11, 2035,
whatever the time will be.
Right.
So that's when we go and to have a break.
So two breaks, right?
Very quick way to think about I hope you
guys will be that will be enough for you.
So once again, guys, any issues
you want to have today
while doing the while
doing the coding right today,
first day again, going to do the coding.
You guys going to write. Our first
theme is program that all programmers
do, right.
Hello World.
And in case if there's any issues
you got going to post it in there
support channel. Right.
Okay.
So let me ask you guys let me ask you
so I'll go over some this stuff, right?
So this is the topics
that we got going to cover today. And
I'm sure, guys, you saw it go happy.
That's right.
And I'm sure you guys saw those
this topics already in the cameras.
Right.
So there's a few things
that we're going to go over about.
How do you succeed? Right.
How do you succeed?
Because as I mentioned,
our classes are different than yours.
You'll see class, right?
So let me ask you guys, did any one of
you have any programing knowledge?
I know we ask you,
but I want to ask one more time.
No, no, no.
There my if I said it right, it's okay.
If you classes, I'm
going to see a happy place.
Happy face basics. Okay.
That's good summary.
I think one person.
One person. Guys out of all of us. Right?
Nothing.
And Keith Cookie thoroughly.
Okay. I see. Basic. Basic.
That's good. As good. Right?
So you guys see
we all starting to see some of you Sure.
Maybe have a little bit
some of my but majority of you are not.
But you guys will be very,
very amazed in you.
And one month down the road, guys,
you will be very amazed of how much
you are going to learn a little bit
a year ago.
Okay, then then the things will be easier
for you from YouTube tutorials.
Okay, that's great. That's good.
All right.
So also, you know,
coming from any background right in.
So how do you succeed
in the course? Great.
How do you succeed in the course?
As I mentioned, classes,
very practical guys.
And if your just attending the lecture,
let's say, and you just sitting there,
I don't know, get instructed for
the things probably 5% of the information.
That's what you want to get. Why. Because
we are
not using you guys, not using programing
in your daily life.
Right.
Something that we don't use
is stored in our short memory.
As soon as we going to close the laptop,
that's it.
That things will be gone. Right.
Okay.
So then what do we suggest you to do?
Right.
Always. Always attend the sessions, guys.
Every single session.
You guys going to learn something, right?
We want to learn something.
And for you guys
that don't have any background, please
don't be scared
or will be starting very, very, very slow.
And then, of course,
our piece will be increase
in increase in increase in increase in
the more knowledge your guys going to get
and the slowly
the peaceful start increased. Right.
So what do we do?
Said especially
because it's a technical classes,
I do suggest you to come prepare right.
It does not mean that I'm going
to ask you, hey, go ahead and
I shall go ahead and study for 2 hours
before the class.
No, guys, just been 20, 30 minutes.
Right before the class.
Right after the class. Of course.
You guys go going.
You have to spend more time.
But before the class, 20, 30 minutes,
if you guys have just do a little bit
reading, write a little,
do a little bit reading on the topics
and of course, do
watch some YouTube tutorials.
And I'm going to share with you guys
some of those that we do recommend
that we find a very good day
about maybe 5 to 10 minutes video.
And I'm sure you guys all have this right.
And so the rest of the rest of the part
guys will come
from the discussions and demonstrations.
So I want all of you to be active guys.
Okay.
I will.
Whenever I'll be giving you the tasks,
you guys will be sharing your code in
here.
I will be asking you some questions
usually from this second class.
We are going to do the recap
at the beginning of the class.
I want you to be guys all act good.
And of course this 75% of how you succeed,
especially the programing is good.
But practice in practice
and practice and practice, right?
So remember this 10 to 15 hours in a week.
That's
what we asking from all of you. Right?
If you want to become a great programmer,
if you want to become
like one of your friends, right.
And then ending up
in having a really good job
switching your career
and getting a good pay rate,
that's what you guys have to do
and hear the rest of the things.
Guys, what you will see
there will be discussions, teach others.
So what are you guys going
through? How we will be doing it?
Several projects with you guys
probably for Java.
We are going to have one
or once we finish our basic.
So you guys are going to form a group,
you guys are going to have
your group discussion
where you guys will be talking about Java.
We guys will be doing
a Java assignments together.
So I think it'll be a lot of fun,
I promise.
A lot of fun, yes.
So that's about how how we are succeeding.
Right. And as I mentioned, guys,
everything will class.
You guys will be learning
new things, right?
So today
we're starting from the ground, right?
So we all have and we always treat to
as you don't have any
as you don't have
any programing knowledge.
And then we start building our
our knowledge right.
I always give an example
aboard the building. Right.
So let's say you want to build,
you guys go and you have about
25 probably classes of Java right?
So let's say we tried to build a 35
storey building.
You cannot jump from the ground
and go to the ten floor, right?
You cannot jump
and go all the way to the 35th floor.
Right.
So we are going to start one by one
by one building those blocks.
But you have to make sure
that those blocks of very strong.
Right.
Your fundamentals will be very important
If your floor number two of them
is not strong,
then those not on floor number 35
probably will be a little bit shaky.
Right.
So that's
why please make sure put all your efforts.
And one thing is to remind some of you,
you do have a basic
some of you maybe steady a little bit,
but the majority of you do not.
Right.
And so the course is going
to have its own piece.
Right.
So we know the amount of material
that we have to give you
and we know the speed with which
we have to go through the course.
Right.
So if in the beginning, for some of you,
it's a little bit
slower, guys, I'm sorry,
I'm not going to speed it up for you.
All right.
But if some of you
the course is a little bit fast, right,
then make sure you get
a steady additional. Right.
So this way
we all go all together to our floor
number 35.
And of course, there will be different
different floors.
Right. Okay.
In one thing, guys,
about the coding, right, Because I know
sometimes studios are telling us
or I try to memorize, right.
Remember this, the coding is not about
memorization, right?
All the things that you will
be doing over and over and over,
they will become very repetitive to you.
But all coding is about coding
is about logic, right?
So we have to develop our logic
so later, right?
Because there will be
tons of the material, right?
So as long as we understand
the logic, things will be easier.
Okay,
but how we are going to develop our logic
by practicing in practice
and in practice in more.
Right.
And one thing what I tell everyone
and give me one moment
this some of you is still typing, right?
Some of you guys still typing.
Angelica Leaf Ibrahim
Eugenie, Can you guys please use Slack
because I'm not looking into the
Zoom chat?
Please guys use our life channels here
in case if you have any questions
or whatever we do in discretion,
I want you to Do you participate in here?
Okay.
Well, maybe
we will still get a little memory, guys.
All right,
So get yourself some nuts and whatever
the things that help you with the memory.
But once need to buy lunch thing.
And last thing about about.
I do with sexiness.
Okay. Actually,
with that nonetheless. Right.
So, as I mentioned, guys
do the prior research.
I do the prior research about the topics.
That's the reason we do specify. Right.
And I will give you
some of the things. Right.
But it's it's
very easy, guys. It's very easy.
For example,
if you want to find some material, right,
make sure you just go
and Google the topics that you guys
are going to learn.
For example, today,
what what of what are we learning today?
Guess which topics are
we learning today? Admitting
now about what topics of Java?
What is our atmosphere?
Do have a program in it?
We'll talk about was it programing?
Java is coming from our oracle.
We'll talk about Eclipse
what is programing types of data right
so let's see so data types
that are types in Java right
so right here once you type right So here.
Yeah what your point is very great
is very great resource geeks for geeks.
Another
very good one Right Oracle sometimes
maybe after a couple of classes,
maybe then you guys can go
because Oracle might be a little bit,
you know, technical, not like technical,
but sometimes the explanation
could be a little bit too hard.
Right? Beginners book. Very good
ones. Right.
So all you guys do,
you just have to go to Google And actually
guys, Google, it's another skill
that you guys will have to develop.
We can find anything in Google, anything
right?
Okay. And
last but not least, is
some of you guys will be grasping
the material very quick and stuff.
For some of you,
it might take some time. Right.
So don't expect please And I don't in
and I don't expect from
you want to spend 100% of the lecture.
Right.
So as long as you guys understand in
70 to 80% right.
70 to 80% was good.
So the rest 20% will come from
you doing homework or interest
because we'll give you a lot of homework.
And also by rewatching our videos
and looking into
some of the YouTube things.
But the most thing what I'm trying
to tell you guys, for example, right?
Maybe tomorrow night is going to
know all of this, right?
Maybe she study already.
She knows all the topics
for the next few classes.
And for example, Yevgeny,
you are a little bit behind,
but this is just an example, right?
So then I don't want you guys
compare yourself to to others, right?
Oh, my God, I'm slow
and the other person already got it.
Or maybe I'm not smart enough.
Or maybe this course is not for me.
No, that's right.
So what I want you to do, I want you
to compare yourself to yourself.
Right?
So tomorrow we're going to have a class.
And if tomorrow are you going
to think of you?
Okay. What do you do?
I know. Yesterday, all my back. Today
no more. Right?
And then after two weeks,
you look into it.
Oh, my God. I learn a lot, right?
That's what I want you to do.
As long as you yourself are making
a progress, that's what's more important.
Right?
And then the other thing, of course, guys,
I will ask you to help each other.
And I saw you guys already been doing
that, Right?
That's the best part.
That's how you guys can learn, right?
Teach others. What do we mean in here?
You guys will be stuck
in some of your programs.
sometimes in your homework, right?
Just message.
Message in the channels. Right.
Which our channel you decide to message.
And if you guys know the answer,
help each other right?
That's how
you guys are going to build your groups
and that's how you guys going to build
your relationship.
Because remember, guys,
we are here together
for the next six months and I want to see
all of you who join today.
I want to see you guys finish in the cause
and I want you to see you when I'll be
doing your interview preparation.
Okay? All right.
E Ward Greenwald. Right.
So now I hope you guys excited, right?
I hope you guys said
had nothing to be scared today.
Guys, things will be easy.
And I just hope you guys all install Java.
And so this way we can do it
our practice, Right?
Okay, so why don't we start?
Why don't we start? Right. So
we'll talk about into our program, right?
So can you just tell me
what is a program, Right.
It is your first programing class
maybe to some in the universities,
but let's think it is
your first programing class.
You should you should have done it before.
You should have done it before.
Today. It's fine.
But in case if you have any issues,
please boss it in the support channel.
But in the future, guys, we are going
to install different different softwares.
Please
make sure it has done before a class.
So this way
you don't lose attention during a class
program.
It is a process of making software
in different applications.
All right.
Coding programing is a coding, right?
That's that's what we all know.
Programmers, coders
and we always think of them.
Well, my God, I used to think that
all those programmers, a genius.
It's it's an instructions that to be good.
The programing is an instruction that we
going to be given to the computers right.
And then the
computers will be performing some task
attempt to computer to complete
a specific task without making a mistake.
They go, That's a good one, right?
So we will have to make sure
there are no mistakes.
Right?
That's why there's a testers, right.
To make sure that all those softwares
are perform.
Correct.
And the process of designing
and building an executable program, one
that's very amazing.
Okay.
In case
if you guys have any issues of first
the first few minutes,
we will be just talking guys.
So if you have any issues, please make
sure you take care of Java in Eclipse.
Making the rules of behavior
for a computer is right in rules.
Okay, that's good. Okay.
Let me ask you guys,
what are this thing about computers?
Are computers smart?
Computers are not smart.
But who makes them smart Guys
who make whom?
Oh, they making the computers themselves.
They're not smart, but who are making them
smart programmers, Humans, right.
People
who are developing all this things right
now, all the software that we build
and we put it inside.
That's what it makes it.
That's what makes it smart, right?
So as are humans are behind it, right?
So now when we
talking about the programing.
Good And then
when we talk about the programing, right.
The programing is a process of building
the programs, right.
Computer programs that. So that's
what are we doing?
And then if we think good, so what are we
what is a programing programing
is that instead of the instructions
that are provided to the computer, right
then the computer
it right,
then they process those instructions
step by step, by step by step
and give us some output.
Right?
No, those executable programs,
they give us some type of the outputs.
Right.
Then you guys talk already with summary
by the software about the hardware.
You guys know the differences, right?
So this software that we are building,
right,
they're helping us to control
the hardware, right?
Software is the brain of our computer.
Right.
And then the thing of the software,
there's a million, a million
different softwares. Right?
Just the software that we use in
right now.
Right. Select right
and then develop right.
It's been you use
in the programing languages, right?
Canvas, Google,
Google sheets,
Zoom, all of this programs, Right.
All of this program softwares,
they have been built, right?
Yeah.
There's a millions and millions
and millions of them right now these days.
When we think of the computers, right?
When we think of the computers. Right.
Who are processing
those programs, it's not just my laptop,
your laptop or a computer. Right.
These days we have different different
of the computers, right.
Our phones, our cars, our refrigerators.
Right. All of those are computers, right?
There's some programs that have been built
and then installed right.
And those are programs
are running, running, running,
getting some instructions.
Right.
And then our computers
are executing our instructions right.
So now what do we think of it? Right.
When we when we start thinking, okay,
you know what?
I'm a human, right?
I'm a human.
I doing this in instructions, right?
Somebody's going to tell me,
hey, you, you your for example,
I have to get up, I have to do this,
and then I have to teach the class.
After the class
I have to do this, this right.
I'm instruction, but I'm human, right?
I can write down my instruction
what I have to do
now, when we think of the computers,
okay, Computers are not humans, right?
How I am
dangerous day by day.
I agree.
This made our computers getting dangerous
and no computers.
Right? Computers are not a human's right.
Computer is You not want
to just understand the language.
Right?
Is not going to understand my language
right?
If I tell something to the computer right.
So then let me ask you
is how then I'm as a human,
how do I interact with this machine?
Right.
How do we interact with them?
You have to speak their language.
Right now.
There is a machine language
that we have, right?
They go,
how do we communicate with our computers?
Right?
How do they communicate with this machine?
We communicate with them
through the programing language.
It's right
through the programing languages.
So now our machines have their own
language, right?
They have a machine language, right?
All this bytecode right,
all the zeros and ones.
That's how our computers run.
But then I'm as a programmer,
how am I going to communicate?
Who is my computer through the help
of the programing languages.
Right.
So now I will be sending
those instructions to the computer
with the help of programing languages.
Now that is, how many programing languages
do you getting?
Are there?
There is many.
There's many programing languages,
nothing less.
Time when we check that,
I know there may be
five, six, 700 languages, right?
There's a lot of them.
There's tons of them,
but there will be some other than
what's popular and the most use there
will be the one they're less used, right?
So there's a tons of different
programing languages.
And in this course,
only from India, Malaysia,
and then in this course,
what we will be learning,
we will be learning
one of the most popular language,
which is Java.
Right.
Java in which about 700 they go
they are Now,
you probably already went to Google right?
You go. You suggest that.
So that's the beauty of Google.
Right. Thanks. Thank you for
for this software.
Right.
So why don't we get all these slides
they will be available to you in
can was right sometimes I
you know I do look at them
sometimes I don't look at them.
So but they all will be available
to exact the same information
that I'm giving you all this
all these things will be giving it
to you. Right.
So programing list of the instructions
executed by a computer
to do what
to do to accomplish a particular task.
Right.
So then when we speak about a computer
is saying that the computers
have their own language, right?
They have their own machine language that
understands only zero and ones, right.
So then those combinations
of all zeros and ones
then means give have a
some specific meaning for the machine.
Right.
So now as a human, I cannot speak
zeros and ones right back in the days.
Sure. Right.
You have to be a super,
super, extremely smart
when you want to do the programing right.
But these days there is a programing
language, is there also
the programing language is the also
has changed, right.
The programing language
has developed. Right.
So now what will we talk about?
The programing language mostly
talk about the high programing languages
with one woman,
this is possible to do just
I was an instructor.
Can you on moment okay Evgeny instructions
you have to go to the course
announcement In the course announcement
guys there's a,
there's a video that we uploaded is it.
But sometimes you will be uploading before
the class, sometimes after the class.
What are we trying to do, guys?
We tried to make sure that we have
an all your full attention on us, right?
Because sometimes
when we give slides a lot bit early,
then students, they're like, okay,
I've seen all of this, right?
But we will try to give it.
We'll try to get because mostly, mostly
when it comes to my classes, guys,
I don't go read all the slides because
you guys can read it yourself, right?
You guys can read it yourself. Okay.
So now computers understand
zeros and ones.
Right now,
as a programmer, I don't speak those years
on one of those crazy combinations.
Right.
So now as a programing,
I can learn a programing language
and with the help
of the programing language, what I can do,
I can set instructions
and then I send
in my programing languages,
and then there will be
some process happening,
which of course you guys doing it
a little bit later.
Not on the first class, right?
There's some processes happening happening
and then the conversion
of my programing language
gets converted to the machine language
and that's how machine are executed
in those steps, right.
And when as I mentioned, when we talk
about the programing language, guys,
there's there's a hundreds and hundreds
of those programing languages.
And one of the most popular these days,
of course, there's a Java,
there's a C sharp, very popular.
There's the python is becoming
very popular.
Right. And there is a
there is a JavaScript is very popular.
But what we are focusing in here, guys,
we are focusing in Java.
This is the this is a language that is,
that is mostly used, right?
This is so people say it's difficult.
Some people say it's not difficult. Right.
But it's very beautiful.
Language is very beautiful.
If you are going to understand
Java. Right.
And in order for you to understand,
of course,
you guys are going
to have to practice more.
But you will see, guys,
Java is very beautiful.
And once you learn Java, guess
once you learn Java and you can learn
any other language, especially I'm
not going to go into details, right.
The things about job, it's
object oriented programing language,
which that particular term you guys start
learning only after one month.
Right. But if there is
another object programing language
such as a C-sharp, such as a python,
it will be so easy for you guys to learn.
We have students
for whenever they graduating right
with their strong knowledge of Java,
they are getting hired by the companies
and then then the companies
they get in train for another language
and the message, as am I.
So I'm learning Python.
It's so easy right now. Right?
So any of those programing languages
will be very, very easy
after that.
No, they're they're not.
I mean all the programing language guys,
they will have some similarities,
especially the first things that you guys
will be learning with me.
The basic concept guys,
they all they exist from our base is guys.
We will be learning the conditioning
and then we will be learning cycles.
How do you repeat particular tasks?
So all those things are pretty, pretty
common in other programing languages.
Okay, Is
it is if you learn German
then other languages really German.
German. German is the hardest language.
I actually used to used to know German,
but since I came to United States
I completely forgot.
So now I don't really know
if I can learn that.
What is the difference
between Java and JavaScript organs?
It's a two completely different languages.
You completely. It's like
when we talk about a T,
and then when we talk
about the mouse, right, two different,
two different languages.
Russian is hard, but I love it.
Maria D Let me see.
Miriam do you speak Russian
or only a little.
Okay. Okay.
Mariam You can get a lot
of a lot of practice in here.
We have a lot of Russia's biggest students
all. So whenever you you're
going to form a group,
you guys can have that
conversation a little bit.
JDK 17 one Step five
We are trying to use Java eight.
Okay,
We are going to use Java eight, but DBA.
Bialystok All right.
So right, so on also here, some diagram
when we look into
but so Python these days
of course is getting is gaining popularity
right in the python
we actually teach in in our other course
C sharp is gaining in popularity
JavaScript is getting popularity.
But Java is still one of the most popular
one of the hospital
high speed Java especially
if you going to speak to the developer.
We do have students from previous batches
or students from batch to batch three.
By now.
They, you know, they've been working
for some time in the industry industry
and they're telling us the best we can
to develop our development position.
Are they making crazy amount of money?
Right. Okay.
So possibilities.
There are endless endless, Right.
Okay.
So programing languages, right.
As you guys mentioned, there is a many,
many different one of them. So
why we're learning Java most popular, it's
mostly being used, right?
Because remember, guys,
the goal of this course, we're not trying
to become a programmers, right?
But we learn a good amount of the material
that you guys will be
will be able to.
I later learned some additional stuff
and become if you would really love to.
But the goal in here
we're trying to become
automation engineers
write software automation engines
and in order for us to become software
automation engineers, right,
we have to make sure
that our programing language is strong.
And when it comes to the software
automation, a lot a lot
a lot of companies
are will are using selenium.
And with this selenium,
which you guys will be learning after
two and a half months, Selenium
and most popular
combination
is to use the tool selenium with our Java.
Okay.
So now let me ask you guys,
what did you learn about Java
because I'm sure you've done the research
first class, usually everybody's excited.
They're doing their research.
So what did you find out about Javabayes?
Or is it okay?
I just I went in,
I probably I once we will do the eclipse,
I learned there will be an option
where you can select and
I would suggest use either
eight or either use 11.
It's a language, right?
It's a it's
one of the programing language.
It's an object oriented language.
All right.
Right. Once use it everywhere.
That's what you guys probably heard.
And you guys will learn
why do we call it this?
We're right on the first clause.
We're not going to drop all this
all this material to scare you, right?
It's all right.
It's object oriented programing language.
It's one of the higher languages. Right?
Okay. It's only been since 1995.
And here right.
What else?
What else you guys learned about Java?
So crime and damage of coffee.
They're going to coffee lovers,
you guys, bro, You know,
Java is the most famous, more spread
language, right?
So whenever you guys were installing
Java, right.
You guys saw that
that that message in there.
Then there's a 3 billion devices
that run on Java right?
Yep. It was it was created by James
Gosling.
Right.
By Sun Microsystems And then later.
Oracle acquire it.
That's why. Now,
what do you guys have to do?
If you want to install Java,
you have to go to Oracle,
right?
Yaman
Java is a high programing language, right?
It's a programing language.
There's a lot of description
that we can give for Jabari.
Another very important thing is
for now, right? For now.
Let me ask you guys,
did you have to pay anything when you were
when you were downloading Java?
No, it's free, right?
Like free things, right?
I mean, there
and there's a paid features
that are coming in Java, of course.
Right.
So how do we cool things
when they are free.
Right.
Any software,
what we are able to download,
if it's free,
we call it an open source, right?
We call it an open source.
Okay.
So what do I mean by object oriented guys
for the first ten classes?
We are not going to touch this concept
of the object oriented,
but then you guys go going to have going
to spend about 25 classes
where you guys will be learning
about the beautiful concept
about Java being an object oriented
programing language.
Okay, So now the things about Joe, right?
One of the most popular
meal, right, is right.
Java is a high level
computer programing language, right?
So Java is free, right?
One free.
We call it an open source. Right.
And then there's
a specific mechanism that Java is using.
It saw a budget. Why?
What do you guys heard once
you run your program?
Right, Once your radio program,
this program be executed
on all different platforms,
on all different system systems.
This simple example
that I can give you, right?
So during my my coding guys,
I'll be using Mac right now.
You guys have windows, right?
But whatever program
that I am going to write,
I can execute it on my MAC system
and you guys can execute it
on your Windows system, right?
So the same thing,
those softwares that have been developed,
right,
the software that have been developed,
our slack, our zoom right,
it can run on Mac, it can have
you can run on windows,
it can run on your own,
your Android operating system,
It can run on your iOS operating system.
Right? Yes.
Yes. All those languages. Yep.
They are coming from the C++, Right.
So if some of the guys have any knowledge
a little bit about a C++,
this will be very, very easy for.
Right.
And remember this today we are talking
we were talking only about very,
very basic information because we're not
going to go and dig it into deep things.
Right.
The knowledge you guys will be
given to you proportionately.
Write some to me knowledge
you will not going to throw it you yet.
Right?
Slowly, slowly
we guys will be introducing that.
All right.
Okay.
So then right then here is case sensitive.
What do we mean by case
sensitive goods, low caps and upward caps.
Right. So, for example. Right.
So today we'll be creating something,
right?
For example, if I'm going to write class
with the lowercase.
Right, and then I'm going to have a write
a class with the uppercase.
Right.
For Java,
they are two different things, right?
Completely two different things.
So Java is actually very, very strong
type language, right?
There is a certain syntax is of course
we will have to follow, but it's a case
sensitive language, white lowercase
operative is will make a difference.
Right.
But there still are things
that will be fooling that you guys
going to talk about it. Right.
Okay.
And that's where we talk about. Right.
So Java is a programing
language, is an independent, right?
So it can run on any
system. That's why there is a
there's a
thing you hear about Java that call it run
once, run everywhere.
Right.
So our Java program can be executed
on different, different
type of the operating system.
Spaces.
Spaces will be matter in some conditions.
In some conditions, no. Right.
And we will talk about in which
specific situations spaces will matter.
Okay. All right. That's right.
So now here you guys will see
a little slide of the history,
if any of you guys interested. Right.
So now we have this programing language,
right?
We have this programing language
and of course, this
Any language
you guys trying to learn, right?
Whatever language you decide to learn.
German, Russian, Japanese, Arabic. Right.
So this language has its own syntax,
right?
When we go going to. Right.
It has its own key words.
Right.
For example, I see something in Russian.
It will have a meaning
while in other languages
it is not going to have some meaning.
Right.
And there's is certain rules
that I have to follow.
The same thing for Java
right now is going to have its own syntax.
Java is going to have its own keyword,
Java is going to have its own
terminal logic, right?
So now, okay, guys,
I want to learn the language.
I want to learn this language.
So now I need to have something where
I will be writing this right,
where I will be writing this to now this.
Tell me,
where am I going to write my programs?
I'm I'm.
I'm becoming the Java programmer, right?
I will need to
write my
program somewhere.
Yes, we are going to write it in Eclipse.
But what is eclipse?
What is eclipse?
It's a tool that will help us to write
our program will help us to correct
and fix our program right
and will help us to execute right.
But when we talk about the eclipse
white eclipse, it's one of the tool
and we call this integrated development
environment.
Right. So
so what do we mean by that? Right.
So think of it goes back in the days right
Back in the days there was no eclipse.
There was there was no such a thing.
Work or program
is used to run their program days
where they used to write their code
in their notepad.
Right in in their notepad. Right.
And there's a lot of things
they have to do, right?
So they had to write their code.
Then they had to perform some operation
in order to check
that the code is correct, right?
When they check that the code is correct,
they had to save that file.
And whenever the they say with the correct
was saved, then they had to execute it.
So all this process has been done in one,
two, three, four different steps.
Right.
What is you know, guys, technology, Right.
Technology is not spending right.
Technologies is growing,
continuously growing and developing.
Right.
So now later, what has been developed
there is that tools have been developed,
there's a software have been developed
that will they're that helping programmers
to to write their code.
So now how do we call those?
I do we call those programs,
How do we call those tools?
We call them ides, right?
Integrated development environment.
So those tools, what they do
now, they make a life of the programmer
easier.
How do they make life of the programmer
easier?
The whenever we will be writing our code,
those ideas guys will help us to highlight
sometimes some
some of the syntax issues
that we will be having.
Those ideas will help us to see our code
and those ideas
will help us to execute our code.
I just click in one button.
Just by clicking one button,
all the process will be done
and our program will execute compared
to the things
that you had to do yourself
before in those in those areas.
Okay, it will tell us.
We will talk about which things.
It will tell us
which things it's not going to tell us.
Right.
So remember, this is also software, right?
This is something that has been developed,
smart software,
but still not completely cannot completely
do all the things as a human can do.
So now when we
talk about Visual Studio, right,
so now the Visual Studio.
So there's a tons
and tons of different programing languages
that we have this right?
So now every programing language guys
will have its own software
on which it can be executed, right?
So for example, when we talk about Java,
where can I write my Java code
to write my Java code?
This is the ideas that are available
for me, right?
There's Eclipse and there is intelligence,
which is a tool very popular.
And there's another one, NetBeans Right,
there's others.
But this is the one that are most popular.
And by the way, guys, in this course
you will be learning both of them.
We are starting off with the eclipse
and then probably
after you guys learn it, maybe about
six weeks, then you guys will be five,
six weeks.
Then you guys will be switching
to the intelligent.
So we to give you
different different tools
to practice with.
Well,
there's other programing language, right?
For example, if you want to learn C-sharp.
Right.
So now C-sharp is a different language.
In order
for you to work with different language,
you will have to have a different IDE,
right?
You will have to use a Visual Studio,
like, for example,
if you will have to learn the python
by a completely different language.
So then you will need to find an idea
that works with that language.
And for Python, that thing is quite term.
That's the software that is used, right?
So every programing language
will have its own ides
where you guys
will be able to write your code.
And when it comes to Java guys,
when it comes to Java, this is the
I never worked on JavaScript guys, so I,
I don't know JavaScript,
but I used to use student scripts,
which is your course on the Visual Studio
and the Python I know
works on the term,
but if you guys say in JavaScript,
now what I do stands for it's intelligent,
it's intelligent, it's
another application that you guys will be
using later to write your Java right?
But this is the of course
there are more, of course,
because there's more, but
this is the one that the most popular ones
and they always have a similarities
about to use them
or because they will be slight differences
between them. But
for us, what we have to look at is right,
what are we what do we have to look?
So if I know Java right, if I know Java,
long as I
know this language, you guys,
you can give me any idea.
I can and I can write my code right.
So this these tools,
they will be very easy.
Maybe it will take you one day to
to learning to practice with them.
But what that plays a big, big role
in knowledge of our programing language.
And that's
where we are going to put our focus.
Okay.
So now as I mentioned, first five,
six weeks, you guys will be working
on Eclipse and later
we will be switching on the intelligence.
So that's 11:00.
Okay.
So what are we going to do right now?
I hope you guys all install if some of you
through the process of the installation
with me. Look, just support channel.
We have more zone.
We have a garden there.
Okay.
So you guys are still installing.
Oh, that's fine.
And we are still solid.
That's fine in what
we are going to have guys in about.
Let me walk you through
a little bit through Eclipse
and then we are going to have our break.
So this way
you guys will be able to catch up.
Okay.
So now also in this course, guys,
in this course,
I know some of you,
when you look probably when you went to
Oracle, you guys are different,
different versions of Java, right?
So why we are using Java eight, right?
Java eight is the most stable and the most
popular version that have been used.
Right.
So even though after eight
there's a tons of the difference.
One come out, there's eight
that is the one that is popular
or people are switching to the Java 11.
But this is the two most popular versions
that being used, not others.
If you did install if you did install
different version,
it is okay, guess it is okay.
But we do prefer to work on Java
eight or Java 11.
Okay.
Now what can you please can you please
message in the support channel
if you need
to, if you have any issues
with the installation?
Sometimes what our instructors will do,
they will ask you to jump off
from this meeting.
They will send you the link.
So this way
they will be able to help you out.
Okay.
All right.
Yeah. Usually if you.
If you have any windows now, please
make sure you watch the our
YouTube tutorial or it will be
it's actually on windows it's it's
very easy process of the installation Mac
sometimes can give a different issue
security issues
but for Windows is usually easy it
yep so as long as it stays 1.8
then whatever the numbers after that guys
don't worry about it so 1.8 that's
what means is Java version eight.
Okay. So the rest of the part, it's it's,
it's not that important.
Okay, so what are we going to do, guys?
We are going to open our eclipse.
Okay, We're going to open our eclipse.
And I'll walk you through a little bit
about Eclipse
and probably some of you,
you guys already start
practicing right?
Okay.
Let me see.
So this is probably if you're go ahead,
guys, and open your eclipse.
So if this does will be the very,
very first time.
Right.
If you have not done, then you practice.
If it will be there.
First time
that you opening up with closed.
That's what you guys
probably going to see, right?
You guys going to see a welcome page?
If you guys don't see the welcome page,
you guys probably
see something like this, right?
You guys probably see something like this.
But I'm going to go back to my complete
my welcome
page right.
Okay.
My welcome page. Right.
So this is the page
that just welcomes you, right?
So here
you guys can look into some tutorial here.
You guys can do different things.
You can start your program in from here.
But usually this page is not really needed
to us.
Right.
So here this on the very bottom,
right on the very bottom
there will be a checkbox box
and you guys will see something is always
sure welcome at the start up.
So it means every time
you guys are going to open you equipped
if you want to see this window,
you can click this checkbox.
If you don't want to see, I'm
going to unclip it
and which one? Click it.
And in here on the right, guys on the top,
right right now I don't have it,
but on the top, top right
you guys are going to see workbench.
That's what you're going to see
guys in the workbench.
Just please
make sure you go ahead and click on it.
Actually, go ahead and click on it.
So or if you don't see the workbench,
but if you see the X button,
what do you guys can do?
You guys can click on this X button.
So and once you've come out from this
wooden or you guys can go hide too.
You guys can do hide. Okay?
So once you click on hide
or once you click on the closed button
or once you if you see the workbench,
if you if your click on the workbench,
this is where you guys
are going to end that up.
And if it looks different right now,
it is okay, guys, it is totally okay.
I'll show you different things.
What can happen in here
now? You definitely so you guys, you guys.
So we'll see.
You guys will see the benefits now, right?
Your is you'll see classes
you guys, we're just sitting
and watching so this is very that's
when you guys will need it.
Okay.
So if you guys see like window like me,
that's good.
If you're not seeing window like me, it's
also good.
That's fine. It's okay.
That's fine.
I'll walk you through about things.
I'll let me close all this things.
For example,
what if I don't see any of this?
Right?
If I don't see anything unusual?
Okay, One thing is the left side.
I can look, make it bigger.
I can bring my company
forward.
Okay? Yep. That's good.
And that's what we need to see.
Marieme, just click.
Just click.
Exit that donation.
Just click on that X button.
Okay?
Yeah.
Any windows, let's say any unnecessary
windows that you would see.
Right.
For example, Mariam, what you saw, you saw
I don't think if you see this right,
you guys will have this X button in here.
I just closed any windows
that you see different than mine.
What you guys can do,
just click on this X right?
When you have or with your mouse,
it will tell you to close or go ahead
and close. Right.
Okay.
So if it looks a little bit different,
that's fine guys.
I'll show you.
I'll show you that you guys can control
what you would like to see,
what you would like to see by
you already of you guys
What are you seeing right now
of you?
What do you have seen?
You've probably seen this on your left
side, right?
That's what you guys
probably seen on your left side.
Right.
So in here, some of you guys probably see
something that sees package export
or some of you might see something
that this project explore.
But eventually you guys
are going to see three, maybe some of you
a little bit more options.
Right?
But at least one of them we will option
we'll see create a Java project
or just create a project, right?
So now, for example,
what happens if you don't see this, right?
What happens if you don't see everything?
Everything.
Now, please,
guys is in here is adjustable.
If there's something that you're missing,
you can easily bring them.
If there is some things
that you don't like, how you how
they look, you can shuffle them.
But this window we need
so this window we need
and we are going to open a project
Explorer.
Okay.
So throughout this cause,
what we'll be creating is
will be creating the different projects.
So for example, y learning
the Java will create one project.
Then when you guys are going to have
a review classes, you guys going
to have a different project.
And then when we're going to have
a different modules, you guys are going to
create a different project.
So what is the package?
Explorer or Project Explorer is,
is going to show you is going to show you
the lives of the projects
that you created on your eclipse.
Okay.
So for example, let's see, Package
Explorer, right?
Package Explorer here.
Once we start grading all the projects,
you want to see them on your list.
For example, what happens if you open up
and you don't see what happened?
If you open up, you don't see.
Okay, so don't panic, guys. Don't panic.
Everything is
fixable in here.
So how do we call this window?
Maybe that's one thing
that you will have to remember.
And the window that.
Where are you going
to see the list of project.
You can find it by looking for
Project Explorer or Package Explorer.
Now, to bring that view you
to bring that window up,
I have to go and click on window.
Okay.
And I'll have to click on Show View.
Going to see
I click on a window show view.
Hey would you view I would like to see
I would like to see a project Explorer.
I would like to explore
what kind of products I want my eclipse.
Right.
So just, just going to click a project
Explorer and this window comes up.
This window comes up.
Okay, So once again, how do I find it?
Let's see if I open my eclipse and oh,
my God, everything has gone right.
So what do you do? You go on window.
You go and show view
and you select Project
Explorer object,
you click on it, it comes back.
And when it
comes to Ides, when it comes to you
in programing guys,
there's more than one way
you can accomplish the same task, right?
For example,
if you work again, if you don't have it,
there's another way
how you can bring this window.
You guys will see a little search.
You guys will see a little search button
on the top
right corner of your eclipse.
Why not the package explorer?
It's there is similar
because once we start
adding packages, once we learn
what is a package, right,
then it will show you a package
view of the project.
We will talk about projects
and then we will talk about the packages.
Okay.
But for now my suggestion
is try use the project Explorer.
But even if you want to select
package export,
the view will be very, very similar.
Then you will become a little different.
Once you have a lot of programs,
a lot of projects
that that's
when you guys going to see the difference.
But as of now, you know, going
to see that much of the difference.
So once again, if you if you lost
and if you don't want to go to window
show view and project Explorer,
there's a little search button on your top
right corner of your eclipse gate.
So what you can do, you click
you can click on this search right?
And now what I'm trying to search I'm
trying to search for a specific window,
which window
I'm trying to select for Project
Explorer.
And you just click in here.
Well, it shows up.
Okay, So don't be scared.
There is that. Next time,
if you open, you eclipse open day.
Try the program.
Maybe your eclipse shuts down.
And if you don't see it now,
you guys know two ways how to break.
Another thing
from my and does
it shows on the left side right
but also this window
don't have to be on the left side.
This this window can be on the top.
This window can be again on the left side.
This window can be here.
This window can be on the bottom.
So what I'm trying to say, this window
that you guys have,
Project Explorer, this it's
movable.
You can drag it to any direction you like.
You can make it bigger or smaller, Right?
How do you drag this?
So once you hover over your mouse, right.
Once you have over your mouse on
the project Explorer, then with your left.
With your left mouse
or with the left button,
hold the left button
and you guys can move it.
You can see it's moving.
It's asking me where I want to place,
where I want to place it.
All this is movable,
so for my preferences,
I usually like to have it on the left
side.
I like to have it on the left side.
I don't like to have it
just strictly strictly on the top
a minute.
Please
make sure your fix your connection of now.
You did not miss much of the things. Okay,
so project Explorer, we know this project
now lets you view this for
a project Explorer.
So once again it's a window where you go
in to see leads of all projects.
Okay I three or
I'll Kazim my suggestion please
make sure you change it.
Please make sure you change it.
We need our requirements
at least I five Yep.
At minimum ie five And of course
if you have a seven that will be better.
But you will need at minimum five.
Okay, so now this is where we're going
to see the list of all the projects
in all the Java programs
that we will be developing.
We are going to see them in order.
We're going to organize them
now remember, guys,
when we talk about programing, right?
We go in. When we talk about programing.
So what is it?
Programing insisted on instructions
that we given.
Right.
And those
then those instruction is a process
and then those instructions provided
some output.
Right? Provided the output.
I mean, I'm going to show you all.
So now where I'm going
to see the output of my program today,
we're going to write very simple programs.
Hello world. Hello.
Hello, Tahmina. Hello, Rahul.
All right, so we're going to see
the output of that program.
So now what do we have to bring?
We have to bring another window.
And this window,
we call it console window. Right?
So this same thing,
what will do will go on window show view.
Hey, what kind of window?
And I need my console. Right.
So this is what I need.
I need my console maker here,
my console Kim And the same thing
as you can make it bigger, smaller
you can move it from here to here,
from here to here, from here to here.
Right?
So this window is movable, this small.
So go see. I switch them right now. Right.
So my most preferable way,
I'll like to have a project
Explorer on top,
and I like to have a console in here.
So in this
window, that's for you guys going to have.
So your project Explorer
usually here is your project Explorer.
My console will be here any output.
So any output of my program
will come in here
and once me create our first program
guide here.
We will be doing out
here, we'll be doing so.
This is my preferable way for you.
Maybe you will like to have a console
on the right corner.
Maybe you guys will like it.
You have on the top.
You guys are more than welcome to do it
the way you like it, right?
The your I likes it and feels comfortable.
Right.
So once again,
let's say I'm going to close.
Oh my God, I need my console.
Where's my console?
I need to see the output.
So my problem, once again,
you go to window show you console, right
or shorter way.
I don't know how much shorter
you go on this search.
Right on your top right corner,
you click on search.
Okay.
What I'm searching for, I am searching.
I lost my console.
I'm looking for my console.
You type with eagle, which you need unique
console.
You click on it and it comes the thinking.
You can put it all the way up.
You can put it all the way down. Right.
We'll leave it in here.
So it depend on the output. Our program.
If I put this program, sure,
you guys can keep it this way.
When?
Whenever we will be interacting
with our program console,
maybe you guys will need to make it
bigger.
You will just make it be great once again.
Just try.
Try it. Don't be scared. This
things will not go away.
But I really want you to try to move
your windows different directions.
Please try to do it.
Console shop Mohammed Once again
let's see if it's not showing up.
Click Go.
In this search and type console once
you start typing see or and that's right
and then it's will are complete
and you just click on it
or another way if you don't have it
go on Windows
show new console
what is the outline?
There's many other Windows
guys There's a many other windows
if you're going to look we know
show you there, you guys,
if you for example, whenever
we'll be doing more of the coding,
if you want to see the problems,
the slick problems, there will be
whenever we start doing more testing,
there will be error logs, there will be
a lot, a lot of different stuff.
So for now, guys, let's not select
any other ones.
Let's not look for any other ones.
Outline, outline.
We will bring it
maybe a little bit later once we start.
I think
once we start the debugging for now
to have your project, your console,
that's what you need.
That's okay, that's what you need.
So I can put it one
way or that I like it
so you figure out, okay, but
so are you guys all able
to move this windows left,
right up and down.
Okay now what happened?
Why are you waking all the triggers?
Because I don't want you to be scared,
okay?
I don't want you to be scared.
I you to try the things you wouldn't
if they.
If it doesn't happen from the first time.
Try, try, try again until you
had to bring those down here, Mike.
So what do you do?
All right, You go for a top, right?
And then hold your mouse with the
with the left key.
And then while you're holding it,
you have to hold your mouse.
Then you can drag them anywhere.
Okay,
hold it with the mouse and then drag it
just.
All right, So.
So now, once we figure out which
which windows we need.
So what?
We will start doing this for the
all Java classes, for the entire
Java classes that we will be doing.
Guys, we will be creating one Java project
that will be creating one job project
or review classes
in the center will be a code.
Okay, Once we start one, once we create a
Java, then this will be the window.
This will be the window.
We will be typing our code.
Okay, So we know to see
our the list of our programs
here, the window to do
it, programing using,
using our java and window
to see the output of the program
that we have created.
Okay, so what do we need to do right now?
Is we going to create the Java project?
Okay, so once again, in the IDE,
there is a two different ways
here at minimum, three different ways
how you can create a job project.
I'm sure you guys, all of you have this
option create a Java project right?
If you guys don't have it,
if you guys don't have this option, create
a Java project.
You guys can select, file, and select new
and then select Java Project.
Okay.
So if you guys don't
have this option on the left
created Java project, then go file
new Java project.
So either from here, right,
either from here
or either from here,
you can select this option.
So I'll click on Create a Java project.
So once you create, click on the Create
Java Project's there,
this window will pop up.
This window right, this window.
So there's a few things
that we have to specify.
There's a few things we have to specify.
What I have to do.
If I have to give a name of my project,
right to has to give a name,
and we will go a little bit later
after we do a couple of the programs,
guys, about
what is the most preferable way
to give names to certain things in Java
and other things we'll discuss.
But for now,
I want to give a name for my project.
I Want to give a name for my project
right.
It's like going the new Year.
It's me. It's
okay.
So let me ask you this.
Let me ask you right.
So what I would like to name,
I would like to name my program
I want to name my program Java Basics,
because for the first thing classes,
that's what we guys going to learn.
We are going to learn the basics
of Java program language, right?
So now let's say I want to type Java
and yeah, basics, right?
So we all can read, right?
It's very easy,
really easy, readable, right?
But now what happens, guys?
What happens whenever Will will be created
a project in Java.
Right? One more time. Sure.
So what we'll do goes here, let me make.
I'll make it bigger.
Right from your left option
right from your project Explorer.
Or even if you guys are going to have
a package Explorer.
Right.
So what do you do?
You just click on Create a Java project.
Just click on Create a project.
And once you click on it,
this window will show up.
Okay.
So unfortunately, guys,
I cannot make this one bigger,
but the actual actual coding wants
will start to
as of course I'll make it big right?
So now what do we have to do?
We have to give a name.
Okay. Yeah.
And by the way, guys, this is just Ed
that I'm using
where I'm going to type a notes
sometimes, right?
So I want to give a name for my project.
I want to give a ninja of these.
Why do we have one issue list?
We have one
is whenever will be given the name here,
whenever we'll be given
the name to anything in Java.
Right.
We cannot
write, we cannot have space
since there is no spaces allowed.
So it means now what I will have to go
will have to combine two words together.
So now if I'm going to combine tools
together.
Right.
So can I still read it?
Of course I can still read it.
I still can read it right my now
because two words I have but think good.
What is some word
You have more than two words, right?
I'm going to have Java basics from
right now.
It becomes a little bit harder
read right now think guys what
if all type of like this yellow pages
And then if I want to add
something like this,
which way is easier, easier to read
first way or second way.
Second way right second way.
It's more easier to read.
Okay, so this is how we are going
to name our projects
and this is how we are going to name
our classes in our classes.
So this type of this way of typing this,
what we call it,
we call it a camel case in right now.
You guys know the animal.
Camel, right?
It has those humps, two humps.
I mean, it can have one, but
we going to talk about two humps, right?
So goes
up, down, up and down right towards right.
So what I'm doing here, I have
Java basics for myself.
I have first word, second word,
third world, fourth word, right.
So now whenever I'm creating the project,
I cannot have spaces.
I will have to remove the spaces.
So now when I'm combining two
or more words,
so we are going to follow a camel case
and every new word
will be starting with
the upper thing will be the opposite.
So why are we doing it?
Do I have to do it?
No, I don't have to do it.
I don't have to do it.
But why I'm doing it,
I am doing it to improve readability.
Right? Readability.
We are not going to call it for my style.
What this probably going to mean.
We're going to name it Java Basics, right
there, like my project
or like later.
We will.
I guess later
we will see what other things we can do.
We will go over some rules
and we go over some naming conventions.
Like what? I'm going to type.
I'm going to type Java
one for one.
So you.
Right, create a general project.
So what are what is the name I have given?
What is it?
What is the reason we can use this
basis for now, let's think about Java.
This is not actually
the Java behind this scene.
We are developing a
we are developing a folder. Okay.
But thinking right now
there is no space is a lot of space for of
things.
So would you in the project name Java
So here guys
we don't have to do anything
except one thing, except one thing.
So right now by default,
you guys will see this option
that says use an execution environment
jury.
Later you guys will learn what is jury.
There's JDK,
there's there's different things in there.
And you guys will see this dropdown.
So what I want you to do, please
click on that dropdown displays, click
on that dropdown and what are we going
to select from this dropdown?
I'm going to select Java 1.83.
I'm going to select Java 1.8.
Okay.
So now we can magnify
some good things.
We have done this in the project name
and for the execution
environment, please select Java 1.8
and once you do those two things,
you guys will see the option finish.
You guys will see that
you guys will see the button finish
to week.
I'll click on, finish and finish.
So now what's going to happen
under your project Explorer?
You guys are going to see
your first project
that's going to see a first project.
And if I click on this right,
if I click to extend,
if I click on Extend, this is
what are you guys going to see right?
So what we created, we created one project
and what kind of project get is
it is a Java project.
You guys see it has a little G later guys.
Once you will learn more and more stuff,
our project will have a little different
name, a little different later,
but for now you guys see it since.
G So what we created,
we created a project where I
m able to see this structure,
this structure from my project, right?
So available on the Project Explorer view.
So now you guys going to click on this
triangle, right?
If you want to click on the triangle
to expand,
there is a two options
that you guys will see that will tell you,
the library will tell you the library
and it will tell you something as r.
C Okay, so now what is our suspense for
This are suspense for story source.
Okay, so now this is a program is case.
What we will be writing?
We will be writing a force court, right?
We'll write the source code
using our programing languages.
There is a process is will be
will be happening behind
which we were able to see.
But there's a lot of things
that will be happening guys in behind
and then our source code will be converted
and the conversion
the code will be executed by our
by our
Java machines
and then we going to see the output.
Okay,
it will be guys in a matter of seconds.
We are not going to see this,
but the main thing to take are from here
us is the programmers.
We are writing a source code.
Okay.
And besides the source code guys here,
you guys going to see the library?
It's the Java library, right?
Where are we going?
To see a lot of a lot of useful things
we will be using for our programing later.
Maybe we will go a little bit inside
to show you the things, but not today.
There's a crazy amount of things
that they in there.
Okay, good things
that we're you guys going to see now?
What are we going to do this
Whenever we are
doing the programing,
whenever we do doing the programing, guys,
from the day one,
we try to become very, very organized.
Okay?
We like things
that are being organized, right?
Think of this
when you would go to the library,
When you go to the library,
you want to look for a specific book.
Will you guys know where to go?
Let's see if you look into the directory,
if you if you search for the will,
you guys know where to go to find this?
Let's say I want to
I want to learn Java programing.
Right.
And I can find it in the library. Right.
Or for example,
I want to look into the history. Right.
I will be able to find it.
But how am I able to find this?
How am I able to find it?
Because it's organized, right?
It's organized in different sections
right here.
So ecology, science, history,
whatever the things you want to do,
you want to find, right?
And then it will be also
in alphabetical order, right?
What the main thing is
here, it's organized, right?
So the same thing.
What are we trying to do, guys?
Because we will be writing many, many,
many different codes, right?
Many,
many different programs in our class.
So what we will try to do,
we will try to organize our code.
So our code will be organized
a specific way.
So now to organize our code in Java,
we have something that code packages.
Okay, we we have something
the code packages packages is just a full
there's guys and what we'll be doing,
we will be giving names to those folders.
Right.
So for example, hey, today is a class one.
I want to find out what I have learned
in the class one.
I'll go to this specific.
Hey, I want to find out what I learn
in the class.
Number two,
I'll go to that specific package.
Right.
So now, in order
for us to create the package
now, the package has to be inside
the source code.
Okay, So I will highlight
my source package, right?
That will just click on it.
And you see this once
you click on any highlights. Okay.
Yeah, it is empty.
Good for me.
It's also if you want to click on it,
it is empty because we have not read
written any Korean. Right? It is empty.
So now highlight your source
and now do the right click.
Once you do the right
click with your mind,
this is the options
that will be given to you.
So what we will select, we will select new
and then we will select
what I'm trying to create.
I'm trying to create a package.
Why do I need the package?
Because I want to organize my code.
I want to organize my call.
And we're going to take a break
soon, guys.
I know it's already 1132,
but let's create a package plus
and then probably we will take a break.
Okay.
When the name right name,
same thing is can give anything.
I can give any name that I want.
One standard way, right?
One more time. Sure.
You select one source.
You do right click with your mouse.
Right
click, select new and you select package.
Okay, Right click.
New package.
And then this window for the package
will come up.
What it's for.
The package will come. All right.
So now we have to give a name
while I can give any name.
While I can give any name.
So the standard wiggle is the standard way
that is being used on the industry.
What we will be using,
we will be using that reverse
way of the euro right.
You can click it, I assure
you. All right.
You should be able if you must.
That doesn't work from your system. Okay.
If you cannot,
let's see what you can click on file.
You can click on new and select package.
Okay.
But make sure you select your stores,
highlighted you stores click on file,
click on new and select.
So package.
It's not like you are clicking it,
you just highlight it is highlighted.
So the reverse way of the euro, right?
For example this for example, right.
So let's see, I am going to hire
right I'm going to have
so what is the euro?
This for example for Google, right.
We have w w w we're going to skip that.
But our URL for Google will be Google dot
com, right?
That will be Google dot com.
So now if I want to do the reverse,
what are we going to have?
We are going to have pull that Google
right.
That's what
we want to have contact Google right.
For example syntax
that come right syntax that comes right
our is almost syntax right.
So now what are we going to type.
We going to type.
Cool that syntax. Right. Com that syntax.
So what it is, it's a
your reverse way right now
when you think of it's also going to be
a very unique Right.
Every single company
they have their URLs in those URLs
a very unique right
so we are uniquely naming our
our packages
when university
we don't have to guess We don't have to.
But this is this this is a practices
that has been used in the industry.
Okay.
But we don't have this.
Is there something there is something
that called rule where you have to do it,
but there's something called convention
naming conventions.
Right.
And by the convention, by
what has been used in the industry,
that's how people like to go.
Right.
And why are we using
the reverse way of euro?
Because think of this,
every single URL is unique, right?
When every single company you are
there is not going to find
duplicate euros, right?
You're not going to type
Google dot com and then all of the sudden
you will be taken to the ABC company.
Right?
You are going to directly navigate it.
Google so in the library. Right.
All those
the name of those sections are unique.
That's what we tried to do.
We tried to give a unique names
to our packages.
All right.
So, so what are we going to type
on that syntax?
Right.
And now, because there's a different way
how we can our code, right.
There's a different way
and all the different way.
But for now,
the way I want to organize my core,
I want to organize it for classes right?
I want to organize stored
there all my little Java programs
that I'm going to develop in the class
one package and then class two package.
And then class three, packaging,
then class four.
So what?
I'm going to top class zero one.
Okay.
So any problems
that we will be developing,
they will be living inside this package
tomorrow, will be creating the new package
and all the programs that we will be
creating in the package home.
That syntax, that Class zero
two will be stored in different package.
So this way, ten classes down the road.
Hey, you know what they are?
We did some nice exercise
and in the had a struggle a little bit
you know what that exercise
was done in the class number two
let me go back and look into it.
You can easily find it How You can easily
find it because we organize it.
How do we organize it?
We organize it
in the form of packages, right?
So what I type my type com that's Internet
class zero one
and we click on finished right.
So now package package is
just a folder
that's now inside the folder.
Right inside the folder.
Even if you take a physical folder. Right.
I can have many, many different files
inside.
Right. I have many, many different files.
So now inside this package,
what we'll be creating,
we will be creating
many, many Java programs.
Now, in
order for us to create a Java program,
what we will be creating, we will be
creating something that called class.
So now where I would like that
class to be stored
because this program is belong
to my class.
Number one,
I want to store inside this package.
So the same thing you guys just click on
and highlighted and the right click new.
And now this time, what are we creating?
By creating a class
inside this package, we are creating
a new class.
You can.
So now this window will show up.
This window will show once again
directly new class, right?
If the right click doesn't work,
I let it file new and from here select
the class column that syntax
and I type class zero one
com that injects that
last one.
That's what I did.
That's
what now I want to create a class
new was in once this window shows it again
I have to give a name right
and you guys probably
when you went to different
tutorials
the very first thing was program.
What is the name that for?
What is the first program.
And that's usually everybody does this
Hello World, right?
So Hello World, We will set a name
Hello World.
Now you guys are going to have your order
first.
Hello World program. Right?
So now the same thing for a name, right?
I cannot have a space, right?
I cannot have a space.
So if I'm going to add this space,
this button becomes enabled, right?
You guys see, I'm
not able to click on finish.
So here for Java,
we don't allow to have space.
Okay. It's a rule, right? Like
in whatever language you want to learn.
Right. That does doesn't have to be
a programing language you want to learn.
I know as I mentioned,
Turkish Arabic, Spanish,
whatever language
you want to learn. Right.
It has a strict rules.
So here the same thing Rule
Java says, Hey, don't give me your spaces.
I don't need your spaces. Right?
And then another thing, what are we going
to observe the rule there.
I want you guys to do something.
I want to click this checkbox.
So this is how your class looks like,
right?
You guys see, there's a one checkbox
that I want you to select
next to public Void Main.
Okay, just click on this checkbox in here
and then click on Finish.
What I'm selecting this public static
would me and I'm clicking on finish.
All right so now that's
where my record shows up.
That's where
I'm actually will be doing my Java coding.
Okay, So Now if your window looks
too small, if your window looks
too big now we can control against okay,
we can control it.
So if you're Mac user,
if you're Mac user like me,
click on the command and select
plus so I can increase it.
Now I can make it
whichever size I want it.
If it's too big,
you'll do command and minus right.
Can the project package name be modified?
Yes we can.
We can modify this
and I'll show you how to modify.
Let's say if you misspell something,
you want to change it.
Of course you can. This one image.
Everything is changeable,
everything is movable.
We can do a lot of things, right?
Yes. I'll show you this.
I'll show and if your windows user,
if you a Windows user to increase the font
right
you in Greece
font in eclipse.
Right. So for Mac
what do you guys will use.
You will use guys command
a month and plus write
all windows
what are you guys going to use.
You guys won't use control
and plus what you will control or for
this will command
and you just click on plot
once again.
Right. Let me delete it
if we pretend like nothing happened.
Right.
So once again, now inside the package,
I will be creating my
grade in my Java classes.
Right?
So I'll do right click, I'll select new,
I'll select class
to you, even name
my program
Hello World and I have to select main.
Let me write public static would mean
there will be a checkbox.
Just click on this channel
box and click on Vanish.
And here our
program showed up in the which I have
to put my instruction
control.
That control class doesn't work on
Windows.
Can you guys double check works for you
worked
SharePoint make sure you will hold you
you need to hold control.
Yeah and you have to select
this particular window.
For example, if you in Project Explorer,
it's not going to do anything. Yep.
Just make sure you are actually
inside this code.
Right.
Put your cursor in here
and do our control. Plus
we'll control and duplex
until it gets big.
Michael Chromebook.
Well Chromebook.
Well I hope it works for now.
I just hope your Chromebook will be fine
for our later
or later things when it will be learning
because there's a lot of progress
that will be installing.
Okay.
All right.
So we are I'm going to explain you
all the details here in there,
but I just want to
make sure your first program runs as
and we're going to take a break.
But of course, there's I'm going
to explain you where you have to type.
What happens if you don't see all of that.
Right.
I will explain you all the things.
Okay. So
now, once you are inside this,
once you are inside,
I want you to be inside
this made inside this means.
So what are you going to see?
My class. Right?
Public class for now
probably doesn't make sense.
A lot of t, but e will make perfect,
perfect sense based on the class number
17. You guys will know every single thing
what it means.
Right?
But for now,
just remember two things, guys.
So if class that you created, right,
we name it.
How did we name it?
We name it. Hello World. Right?
When we created the class,
our class has its own rating.
Okay, guys, we are going to have a many,
many different braces,
square brackets, parentheses
There are many things that we will have.
Right?
So here
our class is going to have its own braces.
And this raises curly braces.
That is going to open
and it's going to close when you open.
Going to close. Right.
And then inside.
Right inside.
What do we have for now?
It also looks a lot of crazy words.
We seen public static would mean okay.
And here also is going to have its
curly braces that it's opening.
That is closing.
So think.
Okay, guys, that's
your class is a building.
It's a building. Okay.
So every building has an entrance
and exit, right?
You cannot have an entrance
without the exit.
You cannot have exit without the entrance.
So there's a two pair, all your curly
braces, all the parentheses.
They always will come with the peer.
Okay, There's notice single bracket
in Java against everything has a peer.
Okay? Everything has a peer.
So our building, our class has a peer.
It has an opening
has an opening peer and it has a closing,
opening, closing.
Now, inside our building, this
we did not type when you finished this,
we did not that when you think so
Now inside the building, guys,
how many doors can I have this?
How many doors can I have inside?
One building?
Many.
It can be many, right?
For example, we build in our 35 storey
building in on the 35 still floors.
Oh, my God, that could be crazy.
Crazy amount of offices.
They're going to have a lot of doors.
But let me ask you guys, in order
for you to enter the building,
are there
going to be one main entrance or not?
They are going to be one main entrance.
Okay.
So now I want you to think of these
big combination or words that says Mingus.
Our main is the main entrance
to our Java program.
Without having this entrance, we cannot
we cannot run,
we can write, but we cannot run.
We cannot execute our program.
It's like without you entering
through the main door.
I'm sorry.
You can never reach the floor
number two or three, right?
You have to pass through the main door.
And that's all.
That's
what our main means in our Java program.
So anything is
anything that we will be writing
have to stay inside that main door.
In our main door,
we're going to open the main door
and we're going to close it right?
Without opening, you cannot close.
So the same thing comes in the peer.
So this is where your main door opens.
And if you guys go to I
highlighted with your mouse,
if your main door opening,
you guys have to make sure it's close.
You open your program,
program has to close, you open your door.
A door has to close. Okay.
If you have to do it, it's okay.
We will go over that wall.
Those two double slashes means for now,
you guys can just delete them
or you can type with under under this
to do
so. Once again, there's all the code
that we will be typing today
must stay within your main door
and the main door lease
within your building.
Okay, so you open in doors
to closing Doors to closing doors.
The now inside the door.
Right.
If you guys going to double click your
mouse after the after the curly braces.
So this is this space, guys.
This is the space that is highlighted.
So this is the space we're in.
Inside, all in only inside this space
we are going to type our program
because that's where we allowed
we allow it to type our program
only once we enter the main door.
You cannot type
your code outside of the main door
or before you enter it,
you have to enter only we type in it.
Okay, so now and in here, guys,
for the first time,
probably there will be a lot of typing.
But and one thing is I know you're
learning somewhere, so no shortcuts.
First class we are not using.
There's a lot of shortcuts.
That's the benefit of using Eclipse
or any other ides, right?
They are friend of the programmer.
They will help you identify
a lot of things.
They will give us a lot of shortcuts
for whenever we the program.
But for today, no shortcuts.
Okay, so what I'm going to type
I'm going to type system, right.
And remember this, when we say
Java is a case sensitive, right?
Typing is the operating system.
Typing is the lower key system.
Two completely words for Java.
So you have to make sure
it's up with these kids.
So we'll type system with that.
We type then that, then we type out
and then we type print
and then and then to parentheses
take different of this,
which will sometimes use sometimes yes.
But there is a process. Guys,
we also do help you out.
Okay, So system uppercase that out.
That print line
there is everything is lower cases,
but we have a nuts in here, right?
Then you have parentheses.
And right now let's say hello right
or whatever, whatever sentence
you want to put right.
For example, I'm going to say hello
and I'm going to say hello.
I right.
So now,
now what do you guys see?
What do you guys see?
You guys see a little X, right?
You guys little X?
I said beauty of ideas, out
ideas is telling you
that there's some issues
I have in my put in my code.
Right.
So now when we talk about Java
Java is very strongly type language
so now think good what we are right now,
we wrote the sentence.
Now we have to finish it.
We have to finish it.
So now this sentence right in
in, in the language,
right in our speaking language,
we call it the sentence here in Java,
we call it a statement, Right?
We call it the statement.
So now I wrote my first statement
now to identify
that I finish with my statement.
We have two other semi call.
Now, once we have a semicolon,
there's no errors.
There's no errors.
He is based here. Yes.
You guys can have a space in here or here.
Don't matter.
We will talk about spaces.
We'll talk about this space.
What are you guys going
to have more space in here or before that?
You guys can have a space
that don't really matter.
We will talk about
which spaces will matter.
Maybe not on today's floors, but overall,
of course, this will help the no does it?
What I have
I have written my first statement.
What is my statement is my statement
says, Hey, I want to print.
I want to print. Hello?
I shot right out of print. Correct. Right.
So now what I would to do,
I would like to execute.
We will go over this.
We will go over all those things. Why?
There need to be quotation one
There is no quotations.
One I would just please type to it.
Think we need a quotation,
any type we want to type word.
Right? Hello is a world right?
Aisha is a name. It's also a word right?
So anytime you want to type
of what you have to put a quotation.
Okay,
so now what I would like to do.
I wrote a statement.
Now I want the statement to execute.
Okay, So now if I want to execute it,
I'll do it right click.
I'll do right
click with my mouse and then I click run.
So now, okay, there's one moment.
Let let me click on Run.
So we'll let people who don't have
any issues, we'll let them take a break.
And then whenever guys have any issues,
right, let me finish this.
And if you still have an issue,
please send it in the support channel.
But one thing is when you're sending in,
please take a screenshot so our our
support instruct this can have a look
and they will be able to help
because we need visually to see
what is your issue.
So once again,
in order for you to execute the program,
we will do right click, we will click run.
And what are we running
our Java program, right?
You just click on run
and as an output here, guys,
where's the output of my program comes
it comes in my console.
So here
what I'm seeing I'm seeing Hello Aisha.
You guys can write whatever name you want.
Hello? Ready? Right.
Then I'm going to run my program.
Execute it.
All right.
And I will go over about the details.
But for now, guys, I hope to work.
Right.
That's. That's it. About our programing.
Guys, Thank you.
Is finished.
You guys did it right. Our first program.
I said you guys are programmers.
Okay, guys.
So now we'll go over details,
but it's a little bit over time, right?
So it's 1155.
So let's take a break.
This 15 minutes break.
I want you to be back.
I want you to be back. Break till
1155, 12, ten.
Okay.
Please be back by 12:10 p.m..
So for those of you guys
who is having an issue with the code,
please make sure you take a screenshot
and place it in the support channel.
But I see you guys already
helping. Mariam.
That's that's amazing.
Guys.
Brant.
Mariam
Yeah.
Mariam Here you don't it's not I it's not
I it's l Atlan
print line
Yep print line.
How do we get it?
Zalmai You have to, you have to run it.
You have to run it. I'll show you.
Let me show you again.
So once your program is ready,
you're ready to.
What do you do?
Do right.
Click with your mouse and click on Run.
There's a shorter way.
Also,
there's a second way how you can read.
But first time I want you to run it
this run it job application.
Once you click on it, your program,
if you
guys have this button, just click
on, okay, You guys can just click.
Okay.
And then once
the execution of your program,
the output of the program
will be shown on the console.
All right.
Okay, guys, with me plus the recording.
All right, We are back.
We are back. Real life.
Let's look into the things
that we have done right now
and we have the okay.
So once again. Right.
So what do we need first, Right?
What do we did first? Right.
We created the project.
Now inside our project,
we have a package, right?
Because that's do we have to have it?
Do we have to create it out or.
No, we don't have to.
What if we want to create our core one?
We organize.
So we decided to create a package
to organize a recording.
How did we name
It's in that class zero one
Now, inside the package.
What is it? Package. Package.
It's simply a folder.
Guest Now, inside this package,
what we created, we created a Java class.
Okay, so what is a Java class?
This Java class is an actual Java program.
Okay, so when we say created, I
the Java program,
I created a Java class, right?
So now Java program, guys,
what is a Java program?
It's simpler when you look for my guys.
Well, then you look in here, it's
simpler file, right?
They build a file
that leaves inside our package.
Right now, and as are their files. Right?
When you think of Excel files.
Right. Excel files.
What kind of extension our Excel files
have, Guys, Excel is six these days.
It's Excel is six, right?
Because we use in the New Year
version, Right.
Our text. Right.
They also have an extension,
our PowerPoints.
We also have an extension, our text files.
They also have an extension right.
And now our job program is also file.
This will go a little bit later, maybe in,
of course, on the class one everything.
But later I'll show you guys.
So a Java program
or Java class is what is an actual
well it's a file that have a
that Java extension
and what do we did
we stored that now inside of folder right.
Or from our eclipse
it looks like it's a package right.
And the name it's in text
that class zero one.
So a Java class and Java
class is actual
it is our actual Java program, right.
So now our Java program,
whenever we'll be doing
programing there,
we will be using the lot of parentheses,
a lot of a lot of braces,
curly braces, braces, square brackets.
Right.
So we have to make sure
we don't get confused
by the one thing
always remember gets any type of brackets.
We will be using any type of brackets.
They will come and pair.
There is no single thing that there's
no single bracket that lives in Java.
All of them has a pair, right?
So when you think of the class, class
has its own
opening and closed door, right?
So if you would like to where your class
starting class
is, there's right after your curly braces.
Guess once you put your cursor in here
with your mouse,
you don't have to put the here,
but with your mouse just double click.
So now what it shows you, Hey,
what do I have inside my class?
What do I have inside my building?
Inside my building?
I can have the main entrance
and there will be other many, many,
many doors that we going to have,
but which going to learn later, like.
Right.
But for now we have to have
the main entrance to our class.
So now inside our class
we have a main equal
method look like for now,
just call it meet me right.
Main all main method is the main door
to our program.
Right to our program.
Anything you have to type,
it must leave inside
you open door and your closing door.
So when you think from outside this
for now it's only one line.
Why the one?
We want to have many, many lines.
What do you have to make sure?
You have to make sure, guys, that you're
always have to close in parentheses
at the end.
Okay.
Just always make sure that. Right.
So now what are we writing in here?
We wrote a statement.
What kind of statement?
You wrote a statement to print right here.
It's easy.
Hey, system can print out something.
Can you print out?
Print out this line which line you want.
We print out and here,
whatever sentence you want.
Any time we have the sentences
or words,
we will be placing them inside them.
Inside the
double quotes right inside a double doors.
So one thing, always remember this, right?
So for example, now these days we use in
ideas and ideas will be very helpful.
Right?
They're helpful to us. Right.
So you forgot that in here.
You forgot the semi column, right?
You forgot the semi column here
because of our idea.
It shows that it shows
that you have some syntax error.
Write this.
The Java follows a very strict syntax
and now
because you did a mistake in the syntax.
Now that's
why your idea shows you the issue.
If you guys will be typing this code in
the notepad, Notepad is not going to show
that code that issue.
We will find out only, only in the later
process that you would have to do.
But now that's a benefit
of using the IDs, right?
So now what are we missing?
Missing the segment call, Right.
Or for example, let's say
let me take out this code
and let's say what if you forgot, right?
If you forgot and, then by mistake,
you place
your code outside, you place your code
outside of the entire class.
You see, guys,
you will be getting some errors, right?
You will begin in some injects.
Erroneous injects is not correct. Right.
Or for example
now you place it outside of the class I
or for example, you will place it
still inside the class, right?
You are still inside.
Of course, this is where your Hello world
program starts.
This is where it ends.
But now what you did, you
did you print statement
outside of the main door right now, again,
you have been shown
that you have some error.
Okay.
So you have to make sure this any code
that we're going to write today
and for the next
1011 classes,
it has to be inside our main entrance.
Get inside our main entrance.
Now, let me ask you guys,
how many statements do this thing
I can write inside my program?
How many statements?
Well, now we just don't.
One print statement.
I can write many, Right.
So if I want to have
another print statement right now,
I can say system that out
if I want to print something on this,
my instruction to let out
that print line, right?
Yeah.
What I want to say,
I want to say Hello students.
Right.
Let's say hello Michael.
Right. Hello, Michael.
Or I want to say another one.
I want to say system
that out
that print line
and I'm going to say
hello,
students. Right,
Right.
So if I'm white, you run right
now, I'm going to do my right
and I'm going to click on Run
my Java program.
How many outputs
I am I going to see my pencil?
I want do
you write y three? Because remember this.
What do you do in your program?
You'd say, Hey, I want to see print out
statement, I want to see one.
I want to see two.
I want to see
this is the third one, right?
And whenever we going to run
these statements, we're going to see.
Right?
I'm right.
That's what we instructed to do, right?
Awesome. Because I want you
to pay attention to the.
All right?
I want you to pay attention to the order.
Now, whenever we doing the programing
this whenever we're doing the programing,
I'll program always always executes
that to the bottom.
So always executes
top to the bottom left to the right.
Okay.
That's why first,
this is my first statement.
Right? My first statement.
And that's why you seen it first.
And here this is my second statement.
The second, my second output.
This is my third statement.
This is my third output.
So if you have a
syntax issue,
if you
going to have any mistakes in your syntax.
Yes our idea is going to help
by layering guys
what we might have in my house,
they're having some logical mistakes.
The logical arrows your
your ideas won't be able to capture.
Okay. So logical errors.
It's only us as a humans,
we'll be able to identify.
Okay. But besides, they can check.
Just simple simple.
Any US index errors
in the odd rows you get a can you specify?
What do you mean by rows?
Oh, you mean
you mean in here to add more lines,
you just continue to enter in the
in the enter? Yep.
And then if you don't need it,
you just delete it.
Right.
So let me see. This is
the thing I want that
you didn't do something like missing it.
Let's see,
what do we have in our slides right now?
We created our first program, Hello World.
Right.
This is our main
method is the execution point print line.
We instructed to print something, right
to print something.
And the output is shown in our console.
Here we're talking about brackets, right?
As I mentioned, there will be different
brackets run brackets,
square brackets, curly brackets,
and then English brackets.
Okay.
Well, now when we type in, we are ourself
type in the curly braces,
but there will be more than that.
There will be more than that.
All right.
Let me see this. And
the things.
Okay, so now how do we deliver the code
we enter?
When I was working on Project
for Negative, we're using
if you want to delete the
entire line, yes,
you can do control Z, Control
the command Z for a mac right,
but you can just delete it this way too.
You just have to
you can use in your backspace.
You also can delete it
and no problem in there.
And now one thing is whenever
you were created a program, right?
Whenever you created the program,
what happened at first line?
What do you get?
So there was something specified using
two forward slashes
and it was saying something to do, right?
It was with the uppercase, something to do
and whatever, whatever, whatever,
whatever the things were in there.
Right, whatever. Something was there.
So now what is this?
Two slashes.
Right. Two slashes.
And let me actually try to write the code.
Run. I'm going to run the code.
I'm going to run the code.
And. Okay, I need just.
David, do you going to see this output
do this you to do whatever
in my output in the console.
No no I don't see in the console
I don't see this out with all my program.
Right.
So now what is this
we specify using two forward slashes
using two forward slash
you guys, we're adding comments, right?
We are adding comments.
For example, right now
we will add a little bit later comments.
But why?
Those comments are very, very useful.
Remember when the programmers
and when asked first is
we will be writing code right?
We will be writing
definitely more than one line
and more than three lines of code,
right? Yep.
So what we will be doing sometimes, you
know what I want to add some notes, right?
I want to add some notes.
I want to add some comments. Right.
Or for example, right.
Sometimes you guys will be given a task
that might take you to three days, Right.
For example,
when the task is two, three days.
And right now,
let's say it's 5:00 or 450, right?
Your your working day finishes at five,
you have to go home.
Right.
So what do you can do? Hey, you know what?
I can add the common right?
I cannot be coming in here.
How can I add comment?
I can use it to forward slashes in.
For example,
you are the common I don't know.
To be continued tomorrow.
Right.
So this new forward smashes.
They are common. They are being
not executed by your program.
So whenever a java is trying to run
your code is not looking at your common
or all in look in it.
Look all we onto this thing right.
So now
not not not there,
not the other way, this way, this way, not
how used not forward slashes back slashes
is there to shortcut.
So there is a shorter way.
How how can you run the program? Right.
There's a shorter way.
How can we run?
But let me go back to one thing. Okay?
So sometimes in our code, as we will have
to get a lot of comments, right?
So if your comment is short,
that can fade under one line.
You can just use two forward
slashes. Right.
But let's say if there is a multiple line
you want to add, then what
we can do, we can pull the one forward
slash and on the star,
the star
and then hit enter comments no comes in
look sensitive
java whenever it's executing your program
Java is not reading your comments
Java don't care
much comments or comments can be read
in whichever way you want it guys.
Right Whichever way you want it.
Worry all Mariam,
you're missing the parentheses, right?
So remember when I talk about the braces,
write
your class as one opening curly braces.
It has a closing your main door.
Once you open it, you have to close it.
If you're not going to close,
it will be cold hat in the house, Right?
So that's what you miss.
And right now.
So now when it comes to
my English, which gets me
my connection should be good base
connection should be good.
Okay.
If your if your console
is on the right corner, no problem.
Remember, as I mentioned this windows
there druggable removable.
You can have them on the left.
You can have them on the right,
you can have them on the bottom.
So you put it in whichever
view it's convenient for you.
Okay. All right.
So now when it comes when it comes
the commons, this balance can be anywhere
y they can be anywhere because
the comments are being ignored by Java.
So you want to do the common
before you start your program?
Sure, you can add the common
before you start the program.
Okay.
So they are ignored so there won't any
so syntax or any logical
things are not checked in there.
Okay, let's check through there. Okay.
So now this is a comment.
So to be continue and let me put it,
this is I'm going to name single line
common and
whenever want to add multiple lines
of comments.
Right.
What I'm going to do,
I can pull the forward slash star
and this is
multi
multi line
from multi-line
multi line or whatever it is if y
or you know
one thing as you you will
you will notice that whenever
I'm typing in probably my pronunciation
sometimes
I will be having some grammar mistake,
I will have some pronunciation mistakes.
So apologize in advance.
Okay. And
here we'll go.
And that's how I type.
I don't know.
We do not like it, but that's fine.
Okay, so let's.
All right.
Right.
So single life
comments, multi-line commas.
Does it mean that
we always have to have that?
No. Guys, we know
always going to add the common word
it's given to us, Right?
Hey, if you want to add any comments,
whenever you're needed,
whenever you feel like,
then this is the way how you can add it.
And those comments are being ignored
by the Java program.
Okay.
This I mean, this is if you don't know
what I don't know why it's
why it's giving me was giving me the issue
but it's fine.
Yeah.
They ignore right now
once again to execute my program.
Right to execute my program
will click on right click and select run.
This is the first week
this is the first way how to run
my program right This the first
this difference first week
now this second way how to run my program.
You guys will see
there is an option right there
an option on our top right corner.
So our top right
corner goes gives us this menu.
Right? It uses the menu.
So in here, what do you guys will say?
You guys will see the run button in here.
If you guys are going to hover over,
you will see it and it says
run, right?
So now instead of doing right
click and run what you can
do, you can just click run from here.
I click on right
and right there it's running right?
Yeah.
Think the line is just to add
the common to other.
Is there any shortcuts for Windows users?
You Guys will have a you are having a
very very short short clock
you guys can look in here right
so when I'm clicking on
I can click on run from here.
So when I click on Run here,
it shows me the shortcut,
but it shows the shortcuts on my Mac.
So when you guys want
if you want to find out the shortcut
for your for your windows,
just go to the your menu,
go to option
before we went to the windows.
Now you have to go to the option run.
And when you click on run, you see for us
the shortcut to have to do the upper
keys. And I have to do that. Come on.
And then I can press F11.
That will be my shortcut for Windows.
It will be a little bit
different shortcut.
But to be honest with you guys, for me,
the shorter we probably will be.
Just to click on
the run button in here, get
in. Okay, great.
But whichever things
will be more comfortable for it.
So comments can be
comments.
And B, when you were in your program
comments can be anywhere.
They can be inside the parentheses,
outside the front.
It is inside the class
but outside the mean that that right
way because this simply Java
does not look into commas
when it's trying to execute you.
Put some of this trick
before for programmers.
Okay.
Why do we need comments
whenever our code becomes big, right.
Whenever our code becomes big.
This is a name.
This when you guys are working.
Because sometimes what will happen, guys,
it won't be just
you are the only one who will be working
on accomplishing some task.
What's the automation task right?
So you guys all
will be writing the code now.
Now all
day you will be working,
let's say these live together.
Now, Elise wrote some code, right?
And then you write some code.
So now for you to easier to understand
and write what
the live has done what she will actually
get at a little comments in there.
So this way without you
looking at 100 lines of the code,
you know,
what was the purpose of this piece of code
that Emily has written
and the same thing you when you write,
let's say, 50 lines of code
and then you will only common
this code will perform
such a such an action.
Right.
So this way is understandable
for other people.
And this way
also, let's say you wrote a code and then,
I don't know, in one year
you go back and you look at that code.
So you know what
actually you have done in there, Right.
This is comments are used. Just for
instance.
So this is the comments.
And what we did are we did just that all
Hello world.
We did this system system out
and what we learned
our program executes from to the bottom,
from left to the right.
Left. Okay.
So now what
I'll give you I'll give you a quick test.
I'll give you a quick test.
Give you a quick task, and
let me write it in here.
Actually, I have it in here. Really?
So let me write it.
So what I want you to do
and I'll explain it for you this
this is the task for you.
Windows
Task will be given to you all the time.
So task this.
But please really carefully write
and remember this new rational
so you think task.
So you have to create a Java program,
right?
So remember this
when I see a Java program.
A Java program is an actual class.
When we say create a Java program,
we create in an actual Java class.
What is the name?
I want you
to give the name of your program.
All your class should be the programmer,
right?
The programmer.
Now, inside the class, I want you to write
the comment inside a class.
I want you to write the comments.
I want you to write a comment.
This is my second Java program.
And your program,
your class should give me a print out
when I'm able to execute your class.
When I'm able to execute a program,
I want to see the output
in a console scene.
I am a Java programmer.
Okay,
So can you guys please go ahead and do it
and whenever you guys doing it,
so what you guys can do,
you can take a screenshot
and you can share it in the channel.
Right?
But this is just, you know, we know that
you actually doing the things,
but also for your classmates,
the first things maybe wouldn't
be that difficult, but later ones.
The task for getting more difficult
well is make sure you guys
just don't
copy what your classmates did right.
Do it yourselves.
Yes, guys.
So all the classes remember now what you
you have.
You need to create a second class, right?
Second.
But because it has to be organized,
it's second Java class, not second
Java program.
Right. Let's call a job program.
But because it's still our first class.
So your second Java program also will be
created inside this package, right?
So you'll be right click
new and you'll select the class right.
And for this entire
next one month, guys,
we will be working under one project.
You're in our Java classes,
you'll be working on the project.
But what we're going to have
we're going to have many, many packages.
And inside the packages you guys are going
to have many, many classes
actually is a task this
plus a now you should this is a
Java program isn't class,
so we can't get it
to see you guys doing it.
So if you guys using
if you guys using windows,
remember you guys can
you guys can use the snipping tool
right to take screenshots
or if you use in Mac
you guys can use use control shift
three or control shift
for to take pictures right
function
much fine.
I hope you
I hope you guys are having fun. Thank
if you ready right in your second program
alexius.
We will go over we will go over
every class we will be talking about
packages and then once you guys
start learning the go after the basics,
you guys will be talking about classes
many, many, many times.
Then step by step, step by step,
Java is actually pretty, pretty fun.
Can you copy?
Of course you guys can copy
by first classes.
I always ask that. Please.
No, don't. Don't copy.
I want you to get used to into the typing
and looking into
what kind of errors you guys can, Right.
So we can start learning those errors
because the more and more
we will be going into different topics,
there's a more and more different errors.
We're still coming.
So at least for now, whatever errors
making is, I want to make sure
you understand what they
they enable to fix.
Okay.
Oh, I want you to allow you
how you have the entire you have a super
big screen.
Mustafa
Okay, click, click on.
Okay.
And once you click on okay,
you just have to
send a screenshot in the support channel
probably to
you will have to connect with you.
They will have to check your
properties about your, about your Java.
Okay, So ask them to help you out,
I believe.
And you can
you can do it a little bit later.
You just will have to go
to the preferences
now. You'll have to go to go
to the preferences.
There you can select are dark background
or you can select a light background.
So let's look into the let's
look at the task is right.
The task was
the task was to create a Java program.
Right.
What what do we mean by job program?
Our program is in actual class, right now
because we decided that all the classes
will be organized and stored
in this particular package, right?
So now the classes
will be created in here.
So you'll do right click,
you create new class
and you type the name
the programmer, right?
The programing key.
So guys, now because you have a space
right behind you, because you have a space
now, you guys will see a little thing
and we will all being on top, right?
It tells you
type name is not valid, right?
Because Java has a very strict rule.
Hey, your new space is
when you trying to name my class.
Okay.
So what we have to do
we will have to rename that space, right.
To rename the space.
And even when you have a space guys,
your finish button is disabled, right?
So once we remove it,
we select on our main right
because it's a very long sentence.
Don't want to type it for now, but later
you guys will be typing.
So for now we'll just click this checkbox
and click on that right
and click on finish.
Now the first part of the task was, Hey,
inside the class,
we want to write the comment, right?
And if you come and sits on the one line
right on the one line,
so we can add this single line common
but using to double it,
you hold Sasha's and here
this is my this is my coming right
now. My second one was what I need to do.
My program should display the output is a
Java programmer.
I'm a programmer Now.
How do my system prints out?
I need to specify this statement. Right.
I need to write them.
Let's give them
that out.
That's trend line, right?
Should them a column.
And here this is my sentence right here.
Just my sentence. Now
or main would be
can you make this selection of main
when by default?
No. You will have to select it every time.
I think you have to select every time.
But on the class number three
or four guys, we will learn the shortcut
on the class.
Number two, we will try to type
all this thing our self.
Okay,
so this is my comment, right?
This is my comment.
It still is inside my class.
It was inside my class, right?
And now you can see here
I was able to pass this sentence.
Right.
There was no issue why?
There was no issue because it's a comment.
Java is not looking into the comments
by now in here.
This is actually a Java coding. Right.
This is actual Java code would be writing.
So now here that's where we have an issue.
Right.
And if you guys going to hover
over what we see and it says, hey,
that there is some syntax error, we have.
So now any time any time this
if you want to print out a word
or a sentence,
you have place it inside a double core.
This right in quotation also has a peer.
This whatever you start,
you have to finish whatever.
We open, we have to calls. Right?
For example,
hey, if I want you print number system
that out that print line.
Right.
Okay.
What I want you print
I want you bring number.
I want you print number.
I want you print 2021. Right.
So if I want you print numbers, of course
I don't need any quotations for numbers.
I don't need any quotations.
But for the words and sentences,
I do need quotation.
Okay, no quotation.
But for the worded sentences,
we need a quotation right
now. Let.
Let me try to run it.
Now. What? I'm going to run here. Right?
I have an output.
I'm a Java programmer and here I added
my snip and print statement 2021.
Right.
And as we seen
so even if even if it's combination
of letters and numbers,
you still have to put it in the quotation.
You still have to put.
But later we will be learning
even on tomorrow clouds
because we will be learning how to.
If you don't want to put the numbers
in the quotation,
how are we going to attach them?
We're going to look into that
of right.
And also program is executed
at top to the bottom.
First line number nine was executed,
then line ten executed and then executed.
Left to the right. Right.
Use different statements
in there on it.
You just do the right click,
you click select,
then run right, do right, select, run.
Or the shorter
we write, the shorter way, how we can run,
the shorter way, how we can run.
We can just run from this option, right?
If you hover over this green button,
it says Run it, Run
which program you want to run.
I want to run the program,
the program and write that seven tells me
which program you want to run.
And I'm running.
So one thing that what's going to happen
if this window was showing up,
if this window was showing up.
So before we execute any
Java program, before we actually run it,
the entire source right there,
the entire code that we are writing in,
the code that we as a program is writing,
we call it a source code, right?
The source code has to be saved right?
So it's going to have to be saved.
And if you want to make sure. Right.
If you don't want to every time,
keep clicking. Okay?
And then you runs if you want to make sure
that your code runs
every time before you click on run,
what do you this can do?
You can select this checkbox.
So it's always resources before lunch
and you program right before luncheon.
So select this checkbox.
So this window is never going to
show up and you click on Key
Eagle.
That's my program.
Execute implemented.
Looks great.
Any questions, guys?
Any questions so far?
So No.
Mohammed if you did not select
automatically because
right now
I don't think it's ever going to show up
a lunch.
Okay.
So if you making any changes
in the code. Right.
If you make any changes because
even if you was going to add this space,
it is a change.
If you're going to add this, please
extra line, it is the change right now
before running, before I selected
that option, when I was clicking on Run,
that window was showing up
and we know was showing up
and was warning me, Hey,
you made some changes.
You did not save them.
Do you want to save them?
Before launching the program?
And I said yes.
So now this window
is not going to show up to me
because I check the I select the checkbox.
Okay.
Well, if you
have a problem please,
please send it to the support channel. Get
inputs like actual actual
coding problem in there.
If you just have a questions
for the topics
that we cover, any you guys are more than
welcome to talk with in here
you just because it's menu you write
if e files by looking into all your
all your screenshots
output cam will take one
you probably like.
Okay that's right so for now
we just known how to write the program
and so now we just learn
how to add the comments right?
So now let's look into one more thing.
So what I would like to do
for the 21,
okay, if you guys are a quotation,
it's still work, right?
It's still work.
But for numbers,
you don't need to use a quotation.
You don't need to use a quotation
because here you are using and numbers
you use in the sentences
this would be a different data
sets which we will touch in the
in the in the class today as well.
So for numbers you don't need quotations
numbers,
but even if you add it, it's still work
but you don't need it.
Okay,
so let me create another program
because going to create another program
because there is
multiple ways
how you can not multiple ways.
There's another way how we can
show the print out on our console
this get in.
I want to show you
what is the other statement we can use.
So I'm going to have a clause.
I'm going to name it.
So this option print
or limit, print or print,
and that's how I want you to name
the class.
Right.
So you guys can
they read whatever where you want?
But I need me print or print it.
Okay. So far we've been using print. Len.
But there is another option
that we have print in now
combining three words together.
I'm removing the spaces are in all
uppercase is to follow the camel case.
Right.
And I'll select my main method.
Select my main method.
Then I click on finish right
and let me type.
Let me write a few print statements,
but I'm going to make them a little bit
different.
Okay, So for example,
I'm going to see carpet bullets, right?
Because you are
in the case sensitive system
that out that print line.
Right.
And let's say
I'm going to say it's
print, it's
not out
screen line right on her line.
And I'm going to say
this is
a line
that we are moving
out of frame
or just being like, okay,
me being here, I don't mind.
Sorry, because I wanted to show you.
So first one will be print, print line.
That's fine. Or print that's fine.
This one should be just print this
print line and this is will be another.
Let's make it.
Just make it three lines.
Oh, right
now. Now let's see
how come there is an
because Muhammad, you misspelled that.
It's print, right? It's print.
You were misspell it.
You are missing t
So now both of these
both of these commands,
print and here print line, right,
is just a shorter way of line.
You just type in most of them,
they will print something in our console.
They will do give us an output.
But now let's see, what is the difference?
What is the right?
Now I'm going to click one run, right?
What I'm trying to run.
It tells me the program
that I'm going to run.
Hey, do you want to run the program?
Print or print line?
Yes, this is the program.
I want to run images. Click on
labels.
So what do you see?
What do you see right now, guys?
They didn't issue
didn't start a new line right there.
Right.
So there's something
something about line, Right.
So what happens, guys?
What is the difference
between print and print line?
So what it does, because
this is the output of my print, right?
So what a print does it strictly prints.
It Strictly prints, Right.
So it printed this sentence and it left
the it left the cursor in here.
It left the cursor in here, right there.
Like, okay, I did my job, I just print it.
Right.
So what is the print line?
Does print line reads
any and moves your cursor to the new line?
It creates a new line
for the next out for a next print
that you want to have.
So print just prints, leaves your cursor,
but print line what it does this cursor.
It moves to the next,
it moves to the next.
So this way, when the next print comes,
it's able to start from the new line.
Okay, once again, print.
Just prints. Print.
I like. Okay, you want me to print?
I don't care. I just print.
I printed the statement.
This is the command and I'm done. Right.
My job is done.
The job was the print line.
Besides print in your need,
you create a new line.
That's what it does.
It prints and moves your cursor
to the new line.
Right.
So now let's. Let's change them around
the. Now
let me change that spacing.
Change the order. Right.
Because remember, that program executes
back to the bottom, right?
So now what?
This thing will be the output.
Now how about what is going to look like?
Is it going to be the same?
I switch them a little, look into,
the lines,
guys.
There will be two lines
right there. Right.
So now.
Sure.
You see three print statements,
but this three print state
is going to give me only two lines. Right?
So this statement is going to be printed
right?
It prints, right?
It prints
and then it prints in here first.
And then we will create
a new line for you.
Then this be printed on the second line.
Right?
This will be printed on the second line,
but the cursor will be left in here.
The cursor will be left in here.
So then when you Hello comes your hello
is not able to start from the new line.
Your hello will continue
where you print left
right where you print.
Right, right.
This is the print line
Come on take our print.
Line it, print it.
You move the cursor
to the new line. Right?
Your cursor is waiting in here.
So now next output. This is the print.
Come on it. Print that and.
Okay, I'm done. My job is over. Right?
And it just leaves the cursor here
gradient. Right.
That's where you will see it
highlighted. Hello.
And then when the next line
comes, you're like, Oh my God.
Okay I am printing.
But where I'm printing, I have to continue
where you guys live the course, right?
But if I'm going to add another one system
and that out,
that's
okay. Let me see.
Even if I'm going to do that print,
even if I'm going to print
and I'm going to say bye
bye, where's my buy is going to be print.
And this will
my body will be printed in here or
my body will be printed in the new line.
So here,
this is where your hello ended, right.
This is your hello.
Right.
Because your hello printed
and then created your new line
so by come coming here.
All right bye will come in here
but because it's just simple print
you will leave your cursor in here so next
print out
statement will be continued from here,
not from the new line.
Right.
I'm going to run it right.
Hello.
Has printed created new line
now by comes in here right?
This is the difference print and print
line and let me add the comment in here.
This line means new line. Yep.
It's new line for you
in print and creates new line.
So let me add the comment
line.
What it does print
statement. Right.
This statement
and creates new line
right where we talk about print,
what a print does.
It's just
prints.
Just print a statement, statement
statement
and makes
sure the same one.
And here I'll add
one half of the year.
No new lines.
And you.
Yeah, there's no quotation.
Yep, there's no quotation.
This why this is a different
we're going to
there's a different viruses
that is being used.
There's different data.
But yes,
your quotation is are not going to print.
They won't be printed
the trick of a good.
Okay, remember this this is
I have multiple lines
that I want comment around.
That's why I use the
I use the forward slash with the star.
But if I want to add the single comment,
I'll just use two for special
thanks to the end of the program.
The end of my
card.
You haven't got to be the quotation marks.
Okay.
Is will
there is there's a
you will have to add more stuff.
We will we will in our
we can look into it on the second class
once we start looking into what
we actually place inside a quotation.
Once we understand what we place
in the quotation,
then we can see how we can add
the actual quotations.
Okay. All right.
Any questions
for the print and print line?
Not so far. Okay. All right.
Let me give you another
another quick test. Right.
Another quick test.
That success.
You got this. Of course,
you guys, you've got this right?
Of course you get this, too. You
another task.
Okay.
So your task is you have to create
a Java program, right?
And go to make it to you
before you write your Java program.
Name will be syntax programmer. Right?
You already know
general program Syntax class, right.
The output. Right.
The output of your program
should look like that.
I want to see one statement.
Two statement
three statement, four statements.
So your program should consist
of four print statements,
but because it has to be printed
in this order,
you guys will need to figure out
which one will use print,
which one will use the print line.
Right.
So two statements
I want to see on the same line
and two other statements
that I want to see on separate lines.
Okay. So please go ahead and
do this step
the billionaire class, right.
Class
Java programing class, Java program.
That is.
Let me project.
Okay.
So let me see.
I don't
I don't even know your name is Kazarian.
Could you could you could you please
tell us your so we can call you by name?
Can you copy and paste?
Of course you guys can copy paste,
but please try to type it.
I know it's a lot of retyping,
but I want you to type it.
I want you get in the habit of typing
once you guys become a pro.
All right,
then you guys can copy and paste
at your work.
There will be a lot of copy and paste in.
But for now, for learning
purposes, this please.
No copy paste,
especially the code from
your colleagues, from
a Erick
while you're typing,
I'll also do it right.
My job program actual my Java class.
I needed to name my class
and text program right
syntax programmer to not have spaces.
And that's my main method,
which I think is
so have to have statements.
Right? And I have to have four statements.
One statement, second, third and fourth.
Right. Okay.
Even if you do mistake
at first it is okay.
Right.
Once you were on your program,
then are able to decide, Oh sure.
I had some
and now that's
fine.
Write
my first statement
and I'm going to copy this.
I hope you don't talk to me.
Okay.
Right.
Then I should have a steady increase
and then this should have our last one
and and then I want to
have three exclamation marks.
Okay. So here I needed to have
each sentence
should be in this separate statement.
Right. So how many sentences.
I have one, two, three, four.
Right.
So let's say it first. Right.
Can you rename it.
Yes, you can rename. Actually.
Let me show you after this. Good thing.
What was that word for statements.
Now I want to run it on to run it.
Okay.
So this is how I'm looking on scene.
I'm Java programmer.
I studied syntax.
I love Java and three exclamation marks.
Right.
But when I look at a test,
this is the output we try to achieve,
right?
So it means the second statement
must be on
the same, must be on the same output.
Right. Okay. How do I make that
all I have to do instead of the print
length?
I'll just type
one. I'm going to run.
This is the output I was searching for.
Oops.
So now one thing is actually few things,
right?
I see some of you have written
a little bit like that.
And then maybe we can eliminate
and maybe like that and
maybe like. Right.
Which is fine, cause it's fine.
What are we trying to do?
Guess or like, one?
My code is nice and neat, right?
It's not just by being nice and neat,
but it's also your alignment is important.
This alignment is important because for
now we just have print out statements.
Later guys.
We will be writing different blocks,
whole different of good.
So you want to see where this block of
could start,
where this block of code ends?
Okay, so what do we need to know, guys?
We need to learn how to format our code,
how to format Oracle.
So in order to format our code,
thank you to our ideas, right?
In our case, Eclipse,
there's a shortcut to format.
So now the shortcut to format right
let me I'm my in here
I got to format your post
right so Mac users Mac users
you are going to use command
from one plus shift
plus F
windows.
You guys are going to use control.
Just control select
class. Okay.
So once you do hold them,
write command shift s
So what it does, you guys see
now my code is formatted,
now alignment is straight, right?
So this way it's easier for you to look.
Your code looks a little bit cleaner,
so will be clean in
you will see even formatted as far as well
formatted my comments
right
So this way when you really look sluggish
when you really look
look you're your class, right?
Your class starts from here
and why you guys see the closing
parentheses right in here as well.
The align public class with the closing
are you with the closing parentheses align
your main method when it starts.
It's also our line,
which is all closing parentheses.
Right?
So with the help of break of break
is right.
With the help of this curly braces,
we are going to find that
there's a block of code.
Hey, I have written block of code
inside my main method.
This is where my main method starts.
This is why my main it's right
and where this block of spot goes,
it goes from here to here.
Right.
Larry,
we will be writing many other blocks.
We'll be writing blocks condition.
We will be writing blocks for cycles.
So we want to make sure
just visually that we see
that we put out the of code
inside vertical block.
So that's visual. It's important stuff.
Always try to format your coworkers
in the last one.
B print formulas when we print write Y
because
here it is
already new line will be created off.
There's not going to be print in here.
Yes it can be print in. That's right.
Because the the statements are unknown.
Right.
And I can assume
this is the end of the program.
Right.
This can be the end.
But sure, you can use it print off here.
We're not going to see the difference
right now.
I'm going to see the different.
But a cursor was left in here,
not on the new line.
It was left in here.
Okay. Yes.
If anything later you want to idea.
Of course, it will continue in here.
It will continue in here.
But just to get the output that we're
looking for, it can be the break.
We can be either print, right.
But whenever
the future conditions will be added, then
we can go back and modify, if you like.
Okay.
Or are you guys all able to format
the code,
adjust the spacing between the four?
Now you can just
either spacing here space,
that's where you get
can I just add this space inside
a double quotes?
Don't have the space in here,
but inside a double course,
inside a double classroom.
Okay, so now where?
So first, when we talk about that,
Java is a key sensitive, right?
So here, if I'm going to the lower keys
right so now
capital as system
lowercase system
completely two different things for Java.
Now Java does not understand this system
with the lowercase means.
That's why we say
Java is the case sensitive right here.
Instead of the small P, you want to write
big P right there, right.
So you have in the issue.
So Java is a case sensitive.
So make sure there's sometimes
if you think that everything is right,
just double check your
low caps and upper caps.
Write another thing. Always, always.
Because we just start into typing.
That's why guys I'm asking you
not to copy and paste a lot
because we will be doing some misspelling
right?
Misspelling that this is where we got
some misspelling from the students.
Right.
So that's why I try to type
as as many as many times.
I know it's repetitive system
that our system that our system there are.
But eventually
you guys will need to know this line.
Okay.
So misspelling, of course, right here.
Another issue is this index
statement has to be finished, Right?
So now when it comes to this space,
is this when it comes to the space,
if you want to add a space in here, it's
no problem, right?
It's no problem.
So here, what do we call this?
The spaces
that you are going to have in here,
we call them a whitespace
white spaces in here, right?
I can have as many spaces in.
You don't really matter.
Java ignores those white spaces, right?
If I'm going to execute my program,
it does not mean that between statement
that going to print from line 17 July 26
that there will be this big
no no, as we call it, white spaces.
You guys see they're ignored.
They ignore it
whenever I'm doing the execution.
But with spaces will be matter.
Spaces will be marked
inside our double quotes.
If I'm going to add spaces in here.
See, I went inside my double quotes
and now let me add spaces, spaces, spaces,
faces, spaces, spaces.
In here I added many spaces right now
if I'm going to run
now, these spaces are shown.
This space is a show.
Mark Why this space is a matter?
Because this space, right?
This space
I place inside my double quotation.
That's where the space will be matter.
There is not like such an industry.
But look, guys,
whenever I'm going to do control shift
f this white spaces will be removed.
Okay?
So that's why it's always,
always good practice to move
to a format you could work for.
Certainly
we we not trying to have any white spaces
on the right
right
so white space speech matter
inside the quotation
space don't matter outside space
but when you for much
what your code will be formatted
in will give you the nice.
The nice.
And some of you were asking
if you want to add single space.
Single space, you want to add more space,
double space, triple space.
But where it's located,
it's located the ready.
Right now what you have,
you have one space, you have second space,
you have space
at it again,
the same as you had it in here.
One to the
right,
it's one 2122 or 22.
So we are about to start our native text
case.
Okay, so let's do this
this let's take a break before we start
our actual, actual main topic today.
Right. Data types.
That's the beginning of basic stuff,
programing language as you guys go.
So let's take a
break. Is 15 minutes, right?
So then after the break,
we will start and we will continue
until the end of the class.
That's good.
All right.
So now you can go
ahead and grab your food,
coffee, water with things you need.
Right.
But if you really look, guys, it's 123.
Did that time go quickly?
We just went quickly for you guys.
It is right very quick.
And remember, guys, at first
I did a little talking and all this.
So when our class will be full of coding,
the 5 hours will go like that.
But I mean, okay, guys,
not going to hold you.
Let's take 125. Let's be back by
let's be back by
140. Okay.
So 1.4 right.
Thanks for making your many of you
and why adding We will
all come out.
I guess I'll be back at 140.
All right.
This So I hope
all those things that we talk are clear
and now we are actually moving
into our Java programing, right
when we talk about our program.
So remember this at first.
Thank you, guys and friends.
When we say we
when they said about programing, right.
So we said, hey, what is a programing?
Programing is a
set of instructions
that we give into a computer
in a computer processing program
and right to the programing.
We're building different software
and applications, right?
So all the things that you guys see right,
this is something has been developed.
So no, whenever you think of
any application, right, any application
that you think of in that application
we are using different sets of data.
Right.
For example,
let me just go and let's see, for example.
Right.
And go
the Facebook right and go to the Facebook.
Right.
So right now, let's say
if I want to create in an account, right.
If I want to create an account. Right.
So right now, this
application has two different
sets of data, right?
It has to collect my first name.
It has to like my mobile number.
It has to go like my date of birth, my
gender, right, and all other things right.
So now.
But not just for collecting data, right?
Anything you seen in here, guys,
this is the data
that has been actually stored, right?
So now we have a different
we have a different sets of data. Right.
So in here we have a name, right?
What is a name?
Name will be a collection
of combination of letters
right here, a number right on mobile.
Mobile. It's a numbers. Right.
So here you have a date of birth,
right here you have a guy here, of course
you have a letters,
but it can be a numbers two right here.
Whenever you select, it will be a number.
The years in numbers two now different,
different types of data.
So now through our programing, we have to
make sure that we are equal, right?
That we are able to work
with different of data.
Now, in order for us to work
with different sets of data in Java,
we have different data types
that will be representing
that data, right?
For example, hey, right,
you want to represent a year.
Year is a numeric value
to represent the numeric value.
Java Pro can provide us
different datasets.
Right?
So now here, first name, last name, right
password, right.
It can be combination of letters,
it can be combination of letters
and the characters.
Hey, to represent
a combination of letters, hey,
Java has a different dataset, right?
And then for example
here, for example for gender,
if there will be just a single,
there will be a single character.
F M Right.
So then that's
a completely different data sets.
So now Java has a variety of different
data types
that is given to us, to programmers,
so we can work and process
different type of the information, right?
So now when we talk about Java,
when we talk about Java,
Java has a different data types,
data types, data types in Java.
Okay.
So if some of you guys already
look at some you,
how many data types in Java
we have because there's different
information, different data sets we have.
So how many data times Java provides is
852. Okay, I understand
two, I understand eight.
Many could be many.
And then a little bit different way.
Yes, could be many.
Okay. Right. So data types. Right.
So we'll start probably from cores
and then we will summarize.
So data types.
So as I mentioned, for example,
on the example of Facebook, you guys, so
right here, what we need, we need to have
some characters here can be some order.
No special characters,
including in the password.
Here can be some numeric values, right?
So now that's what we going to look So for
with the memory data,
write numeric values and then we can have
non numeric.
Then the
like the now
when we have a numeric values.
Right.
So now guys, let me ask you,
let me ask you this, numeric values.
So in here I have to enter the year.
Year can be 2021 are
1935, 1965, 20, 20, 22, whatever the year.
Right So when you look at it,
it's a whole number, right?
My data came from first day 31st.
It's a whole number.
Now think of it.
If you're going to work, let's say
I know on the Amazon when we look
at different items and prices,
so now our prices can be 599, 699, 1099.
Right.
So what kind of numbers are we talking
about?
We're talking about decimals, right?
We're talking about
the numbers, these decimals.
So they are also different, right?
So no jealousy. Okay.
You Know what?
When you work with the numeric values,
you're numeric.
That list can be a whole numbers
and they can be decimals, right?
Decimals. Okay.
So now that's where we are going to start.
So now Java says, hey,
whenever you want to work
with the numbers, whenever
you want to work with the numbers,
I'll give you we're righty of different
types, right?
Java does not give us a go.
This is just only one time.
Go and work with it.
Java uses a different variety.
Okay,
so now to represent and numeric value
as a whole number is a whole number
Java users or different data types.
It gives us by years short,
it gives us integer and it gives as well.
And we going to type all of them.
We're going to see
what is the difference between them.
Okay, So no doubt this okay, I understand
that there can be a decimals, right?
They can be decimal numbers.
So now if you have to work with decimals,
I'm giving you good different others
due to different other kinds.
So to work with the decimals
we have Java's Java says, hey
you can use my slot
and you can use my double
and use my double.
All right.
So now I think that's pretty much
about numbers right there.
Got the whole number, decimals, numbers,
the different representation
of those numbers.
Well,
they can be non numeric values, right?
So whenever we work with the application,
there can be no numeric values, right?
So we can have
a values that
can be represented as a single character.
Right.
It can be a single letter
or it can be a special character.
Right.
Special characters
such as a dollar sign, exclamation
mark, question, a percentage sign, Right.
Any of those special characters,
how do you represent them to represent
those characters in Java
have something called chart, right?
So what a chart does it represents
one character
and it can be it either can be
one letter characters write
one letter can be
when the number one letter,
one number
one special character.
As long as it's one.
Yep, just one plus one.
Right. We are not going into
sequence of characters
such as first name, last name, email.
Now we're talking about single character,
right?
For example,
your have to represent your gender, right?
F Right.
Or are you have to represent
a single character dollar sign, right?
So how it will be represented,
you will be putting it inside
a single point, just one one character
What is your character?
S What is your character?
A dollar sign right here
we have a letter. Character years.
We have a dollar sign.
How we will be represented there.
We will be representing them
in the single quotation.
Okay, so now what else can Come on.
There are non numeric values. Okay.
Under non numeric values
there's some data type
the chart
or I heard there's one data type there.
We call it balling.
Okay.
Now you guys heard of the bully.
Because you guys did some homework, right?
If you say no, then next time please
make sure you are okay.
So boolean is a data type that represents
yes or no answer.
Right?
Do I like the class? Yes.
And my hungry? Yes. Is it cold outside?
No. Right.
So to represent yes or no?
Right in Java.
What do we have?
We have something
that called true or false.
So false, right.
If you want, just say, Hey, I am hungry.
If you are hungry, wouldn't you say true.
If you're not hungry,
you going to say false, right?
Bingo. Joe, we say yes or no.
What do we say?
We say true or false, right?
So, for example,
where you true or false will be in here.
Hey, is this checkboxes clicked?
Yes, if it will be.
If your if you
if your radio button is clicked,
then it will be the radio button click.
Yes, it will be story.
Any form of
if the radio button is not clicked,
you will be stored in the form of false.
It's very cold outside in the buffalo.
Oh wow. Okay.
People people
probably in Las Vegas or California,
they're like, okay, thanks,
but we're not there right?
How cold it is.
Not that cold. Not yet. Right? Not yet.
Going to get pretty cold.
It has 58 in San Francisco, actually.
Is not that hard either.
Right, Farhad?
I've been in San Francisco
a couple of ago.
It gets very chilly, but it's great.
California, 84 degrees
in Chicago, 79 right now.
Right now
somewhere.
Well, that's that's a beauty right
now, guys.
Right.
So let's say your I don't know, maybe
you wanted to go to live in some state
for some time.
Right. But.
But you had no reasons to move.
Maybe after finishing our boot camp.
Maybe your job would be somewhere
in California.
Right?
Then it will be good paying job, right?
So why not?
Or the best part of you.
Let's say you guys want to go live
somewhere outside of the country, right?
Because the majority of the jobs
are remote right now.
So we'll see, of course, what's going
to be happening with the COVID situation.
But let's say you can work remote,
you can be in any country and work
remotely and best part, right?
It Washington Seattle
or yeah you get the US have a lot of rain
you'll love it here that's good again
All right
so now what are we looking at?
Business.
Okay so now when
we looking at this, right?
So once again, whenever we work
with different type of the information,
we have to make sure
we are able to process it right?
We are able to process it.
So now Java says, hey, whenever you work
it means the whole numbers
to represent the whole numbers.
I'm giving you four different data
types, right?
If you have to store one, two, three,
1001, 10 million, whatever your number,
you when you have legal, I'm
giving you the variety of this data types.
Hey, if you have to work
with the decimals 199 to 99 1099,
whatever the number with those decimals
you have legal,
you can use them in store inside the lot
or you can use a double.
You can use a double.
Okay.
Besides the having the numbers,
because having the numbers,
there can be a different data
types, right?
Hey, I can have a single character, right?
I can have a single character.
It's not numeric, so that's why it falls
under non numeric category, right? E
To represent a single character,
we have char
and this is a very special one
data type, right?
So whenever we want to say yes,
no, whenever we want to say yes or no,
okay, then we want to say yes
or no like this checkbox.
When we click
this checkbox, we click right, do
this checkbox when we click right.
If I'm going to click
is going to be stored as a true.
If I'm not going to click,
it will be stored as a false right
in my selecting It is am I clicking on it?
If it's unselected it it's no, it's not
okay. Right.
So now when we look at it, what we have,
Char, is one boolean is two,
three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
Okay.
So now what we have we have a
any eight data types, but all is eight.
There are times guys they are B
they are bearing
being a part of something
that we call S primitive types,
primitive data types.
So primitive data
types of the primitive data types.
We have eight we have to think, okay,
and there's one thing that in Java
we going to have that
we going to call non primitive.
Okay, We're going to call non
primitive, non
primitive data types
and there will be unlimited
of primitive data types.
And what of the example.
One of the example in there will be many,
many more that we will be
learning is one of the example of non
primitive data types.
For example, any time I want you to go
the name, any time I want
you store the email,
any time I want to store the password.
So now what I do is right name.
It's a combination
of multiple characters, right?
Yeah.
Those notes will be available to this.
What is a name?
Name is a combination
of multiple characters.
What is an email? Right.
Let's say my email cell edge syntax
text that com.
Right.
So now my email is combination of what is
layers in the special characters, right?
It's not one, but is it?
What is my password?
I sell 1 to 3.
Now I have a combination of letters
and then numbers.
Right.
So any time we have to use
the combination of
letters in special characters, letters
or a numbers
or just a collection of letters.
This falls under non primitive types,
which we guys will be looking tomorrow.
But one of the examples it can be a
we call it
x string, it will be interesting.
So now when we look this, when we look
how many data types in Java we have, we
two data types,
we have only two data types.
In Java, we have primitive data type
and we have non primitive data type.
So now students
that say that there's eight,
there's eight data types
that can a primitive values
and there is unlimited
non primitive
data types that will be represent in
many other things, right?
They'll just call it
many other things for now.
So not to
bore you with that with the
we call it
criminology.
Right. Okay.
So our focus today, guys, will be
our focus today will be strictly strictly.
We will be focusing on eight primitive
beta types, eight primitive theorems.
Okay.
And of course, we will look what, is it
difference why Java gives us for different
for different data types
to represent whole numbers?
Why does it use as two different data
attached to represented decimals?
While here I uses only one chart. Right?
And for the moving images
when you have true or false.
Okay.
So no.
Let me go to my eclipse. Right?
Let me go to my kids.
I'll create a new program.
I'll call it new.
I'll call it.
Maybe I'm going to call it data text.
String will be a combination, right?
The string will be a combination of
combination of multiple characters.
Right. For example, name. Right.
For example, name.
Your name is Catalina. Right.
So now
it's a single character.
It's multiple characters, right?
It's multiple characters.
Email, Right.
For example, your email will be, let's say
Catalina, a Gmail that can write Gmail.
That's right.
So now you have a combination of letters
and the special characters, right?
You password.
Let's say your password will be Catalina.
One, two, three.
Now you have a combination of letters
in the numbers, right?
So this type of data, this type of data
can be represented in the form of string
presented in the form,
and we're going to look at strings.
And there's a lot of things
that we will be looking at
about the strings just on gifts,
different classes throughout the course.
For now,
we are focusing on primitive data types.
The know
what do we have guys Java gives us?
Okay, you want to work with numbers?
Here is you set of data types.
You want to work with non
numeric values here
as you said, of different direct types.
Right. So okay.
Or missing my main let me type my main
let me bring my main level quickly.
It's oblique. I feel good.
So this is what happens when you feel that
you would need to
an indoor or indoor.
Okay. Right. So let's do this.
So what I have right now
have a data, right.
Okay.
You know what I want to represent, right?
So let's go to our Facebook, right?
My year.
My year is or let's say my, my, my,
my day of work.
Let's say I was born on October
2nd, right?
For example,
what is the day there is second, right?
So now what I want to do,
I want to have to write to know my
my job is complaining right
that even if I had the same column,
I cannot just have a tool in my program
right here.
I'm representing to right.
So now what do we have actually write to?
It's a whole number, right?
Two is a whole number.
Now what it tells us, hey,
if you want to represent a whole number,
you can have y you can have
should you have integer,
you can have long
okay, not let me say byte, right.
So the valid you I'm represented
in the form of byte right now.
I still are happy that I still are happy.
Now let's see what happens in here.
Now, whenever
are processing the information this right,
Whenever we processing the information
in here, what I'm going to store right,
right now, I want to store my first name
right then I want to store my last name.
Now, this information is being poured
and it's actually saved.
Right? Is being saved.
How come next time I can enter my email
and I can enter my password,
am able to log in y because My information
has been stored now.
Now this information is being stored.
Guys.
These values have been stored in
some special containers, is being stored
in some special containers.
And how do we call this
containers in Java?
We call them a variables
at first variables.
And then of course,
they go to the database. Right.
Which you guys also will be
learning about it
for this store in the form of variables.
Right. Let's go, Alex.
Let's go
that yes, information is stored in there.
But this for the
the grub is stored, right.
And they grab and store in the variables.
So now any data
we have gets any data that we have,
we will be storing it in our program
right now.
Program.
We need to store it inside
the variables think to it.
What is the variable?
Variable is just a simply container.
This variable is simply continue. Right?
So now I have my for right,
I have my numeric value.
Now what I have to do,
I need to store it inside a container.
I need to store it inside the box
right here.
So now I have a different value.
Valid is decimals.
I'll be storing also inside a container
right here I have a single character
and if there's a mistake,
it should be single.
I'm stored in different box. Right?
So now whatever data I will be storing,
right, whatever the data will be working
with, I have to store it inside
my continuous right.
So think of it when you have water, right?
In order for you to use water
in order for you to drink water,
what you have to do first,
you have to put it inside a G+, right?
Or you want to drink your coffee.
So first what you have to do,
you have to put it inside your cup
and only
then you are able to use it, right?
So now this exact the same thing
we will be doing is our data, right?
So now our data needs to be stored
inside these variables.
Okay?
Inside this boxes,
those boxes is a temporary placeholder.
Right. Coffee.
While I have a coffee,
it will be inside my cup right then.
If I.
If I'm done, I can throw away the cup.
But while I want to have this coffee,
my coffee will be inside this.
Right now they don't need to be stored
inside the boxes.
How do I create this box?
Okay, how do I create this box?
So now what I need to specify
in order for me to create box, right?
And for different
data types,
there will be a different boxes.
Okay, so now what need to do?
I need to create a variable, right?
So to create a variable
Java is very, very strict guys.
Java is very strict.
Java says, okay,
you need a variable to store the data.
I'll give you the variable.
Why do you need to tell me?
What are you planning to store in there?
Okay So now a process of creating
the variable
is has done in two steps.
First, what do we need to do?
We need to specify, Hey,
what type of values you planning to store?
I am planning to store
byte type of values.
Right.
So now what
will the name of your container?
The name of my container, let me call it.
I don't know, I'll just pull it.
Box one right now.
What I would like to do in inside
this box one
I want to store the value to.
To store the value inside the box.
We will just place equal sign.
So now what happens?
This now is exactly
this part.
That's what exactly you see in the picture
So now you took the value for
and now what you did,
you store it in the box.
How did we name this box right here?
Different names.
And how did anemic, anemic box one. Right.
So now I can give any name
to my variable, right?
I can give it any name to think I this.
It's you have in the box right.
Let's say you movie right?
You moving from one city to another city
and now you want to store
certain things, right?
So what you will doing you'll store your
I don't know
you store your dishes in one box
and then you will add the label, right?
Then you store your clothes
in another box.
You will add the label right?
Then add some.
I don't know, food.
You're going to store only food in there
and you want to add the label.
That's exactly what we're doing right now.
So what I have.
Yeah, this name can be anything, right?
So tomorrow you move in, maybe I'm
going to name it the My box is a food.
Maybe you want it,
you name it something different, right?
Name can be anything.
As long as you know where to find it
later.
Right. Remember this.
Now you move a different city.
We will talk about what in space.
We'll talk about ways
when you move to different cities.
Now you have hundreds of boxes right now.
If you give a proper name to your box,
you can fast to find it, right?
You can fast find it.
So we will be also very careful
in naming our boxes to
box in letters because we are going
step by step.
Right? We are going step by step.
So first, first, what are we doing This?
We will be talking about
storing numeric values.
And I want to store I want to try
all these different data types.
All the different data. Right.
Okay.
So first we took.
But now let's look short. Okay? Not.
Hey, Java, give me a box.
Give me a box. Java.
Give me a variable. Okay.
So what is this variable?
This is basically what are we doing?
We are taking a memory, right?
We are taking the memory from Java. Right?
And that's where we storing our values.
So byte. Right.
The next
thing, one moment,
this would be representing
storing
all numbers, right?
I just I just say,
hey what is the whole numbers?
I'm giving you four different data types
in and we are going to do different guys.
Let's first type them and then of course,
we look into difference.
We will see why Java uses so many, right?
So storing whole numbers,
Java says, I have four different ones.
Okay, cool.
So now first one, we have byte, next one
we have short right next one
we have short.
I want to store short
type of values inside the variable.
Okay.
So now what I need
I need to given my variable right
lets me name in box for example.
Right. Box two.
And it's still a whole number. Right.
Let me let me put it,
I don't know big one number right now.
I'll put it, I don't know, 1000.
Right. 1000. Okay. Right.
Storing a small number inside the white,
storing a little bit bigger
number inside a short now
and brother in the family we have integer.
Right? You have an integer.
So then I need to specify the name box
three equals.
And let's take a bigger number.
Right.
Let's take a bigger number of stores.
Something like this. Okay. All right.
And next one in the family,
we have four box four, right?
And the same thing does because
it's a name, no spacing, no spacing.
Everything has to be combined.
I'm combining it now later with my number.
Right. Okay. Box four, right. Equals
11 leave.
Were there then there, there
longer number.
Okay.
So now with the help of my byte, short
integer and long,
what I'm representing, I'm representing
numeric values.
Write different numeric values.
So now why G-A-Y gives us
this many variations in here?
And what is the difference
between white short integer and low?
Okay, so different is a body sizing
by the size of gift.
So remember this Java was developed
in 1995, right, In 1995.
So remember this back the days 1995,
there was an issue is a memory.
You guys you guys did
went with Soumaya, right?
You guys look at that.
We used to have those.
You see eyes and there was a small
there was really big.
And then, you know, there was when we used
to have you as beasts
or now you can have the smallest
you as big that can store big amount of.
Right.
So the same thing in the computers
right before the issue was a problem.
Right. Issue was a problem.
So before programmers you have to be very,
very careful in terms of what type of
data type you are using.
Right.
So now why is being
as small as small as data type
that can represent a whole number?
This data, the data type
was using one bite of the memory.
Guess I think one byte.
Yep. Eight bits, one byte.
That's what it was using. Okay.
So then, sure,
it's a little bit bigger data type, right?
So now you have a bigger box
thinking you have a bigger box.
So now instead of bigger box,
you can store bigger numbers.
And then integer was the
and not next one in the family
and it's bigger box in the long is
the biggest box is a big buzz.
So now what do we mean in here so now why
why being a smallest data type
byte is being the smallest
the right type so it can store,
you know, smaller range of numbers.
Right.
For example, what is their range?
Can they still.
127 number?
Yes, they can store 127.
But as soon as I'm going to store 128
you guys,
my program record shows the issue.
It shows me the issue. Why?
Because right now, 128 it's
too big of a value
that you try you place inside a small box.
So now
Java says, hey, if you have a number
that is bigger than 127,
please sure, go use short.
Okay.
So why has a range inside of wide
you can store range
of from -128
feel 127
from -122 2127.
Right. Yeah. Wow. Okay.
If I cannot fit 128 inside of by,
let me go to the next brother Short.
Right.
But this is we talk in the lab back
the days right because memory was
an issue. Memory was very expensive Right.
So now the next one is a short inside.
A short?
I can store any values from
until I don't remember
which direction you guys want.
Need to remember this range. Trust me.
So let me see.
Is our short stars
show goes all the way from here, right?
So inside a short you can store
values from -32,768
or negative all the way to positive
30,030 2767.
Right.
As soon as your number Right now,
what if you work in these numbers
right now,
as soon as your number becomes larger.
Now this box is becoming too small.
The value that you're trying to store,
32,769 inside this box, it's too much.
There's not space for it.
So now that's why Java gives us.
Okay, you know what?
If the short is too small for you,
go to the integer.
Right. Go to the integer.
So this is goes from to here.
And one thing is,
do you have to remember this ranges?
No, you don't have to remember
the ranges. Right.
So why you don't have
to remember their ranges?
Because right
now, guys, memory is not an issue.
Look, we have an iPhone that is coming out
is what
with one terabyte or 500 megabytes,
something like that.
Right. So memory is not an issue anymore.
So, of course,
and we will talk about who is with them,
what is the most popular data type
that will be used.
But this is for you guys to know, okay,
This is for you to know.
So now integer, right?
Hey, if you have a value that is bigger
than this, go to the next brother
integer.
So integer will be the one
that is most popular.
This one's popular
and data type
to use
or all numbers and
keeping can be useful when you're sick.
But then we're also going to do something
called long, right?
Remember guys,
our numbers can be long for example right
think our guys your
our phone numbers right ten digit
it's a very low number or for example
when think of all
the financial applications this whenever
if some of you have a mortgage
some of you have a loans right or
whenever you get in your mortgage. Right.
It gives you a long transaction
ID, right one, two, three, four, five,
whatever, whatever.
So now to store these
those big of a numbers down,
which is, hey,
whenever you have a very big numbers
they want be able to fit inside integer
where you can store them
you can store them inside the loan
account numbers right there.
Right transaction that is account numbers.
So there's a lot of a lot of numbers,
guys, that you can store
and use inside the loan.
Okay. Social Security right there, Right.
How many?
Not nine in there, right.
Can you use loan every way?
Yes, You can use long everywhere.
But remember, the loan is memory.
It's not that you should,
but along is taking the more space right
is still taking the more space
and sometimes what do you guys
what do you get minute whenever
maybe you are typing right.
If your number becomes too long Right.
A still not too big
if your numbers becomes too long.
Right.
For example,
this is your transaction, I think,
and you will get a little error, right?
You will get an error.
So sometimes if you want to specify
that you're
if program will give you this error,
you want to specify that you use
in the long number.
What we will have to and
we will have to add in the error letter.
L Okay, it can be a small L
or it can be a big L can be a little.
Maybe this going to be
light ways
of looking with you change this, right?
So they
ready.
Right.
So a small L or big L?
Okay.
Make out what your full name integer.
Yes. It's this one digit $0.90 for integer
again
to represent whole numbers in our program.
And right
Java gives us four different data charges
that can represent a long number
by short integer loop.
What is the difference between them?
Difference between them is in size in
how much size they are.
Quite in your memory, in your room.
Right.
And since the memory
is not the issue anymore, this days
what's popular,
we just use an integer okay, I don't know.
Maybe I'm working on
the let's say I'll be able
and then I'm working on the Friday
Mac right.
I don't want to think about
hey maybe my long will be
20,000
or maybe my mortgage will be 5 million.
Write that.
I know how the calculation, right?
I know this in the future.
You know what? Instead of
there
guessing what a should I use BART
or by byte or integer,
we just want to use integer
in out of this entire family.
Guys, short is the less less
popular family member.
Okay. What do you mean by this?
These guys mostly people don't use byte.
In short,
the most one we will be using most
when we will be using integers
and lots case
to one
moment.
Okay. Those are not the errors. Those are
those are warnings.
Then we will talk about warnings.
Okay.
So now let's look at all data types first.
Now what I want to store,
I want you store representing right.
I will see representing where
we're thinking
and storing.
And here
we will be representing and storing type
of. And now I
think, you know what,
you have to work with decimals, right?
If you have to work with decimals,
I'll give you two data types, Right.
I'll give you two data types.
I give you what?
And I'll give you double, right?
Okay, Sure.
So what kind of values?
Decimals, Right. 199 Right.
So now I have the value 199
I would like to store it.
I cannot just leave it like that.
What I'm doing,
I'm storing How do we store the values
using the equals sign?
So now where am I storing it?
I need to store it inside the box. Right?
Whenever I'm using the box,
I have to give a name right.
And again, the end.
You mean good again? Any name?
Why are we using L at the end?
This? We have to. We have to
specify that this number is a long number.
This once we learn a little bit
about the costing guys.
Okay.
Once we learn them a little bit
by on in the few clauses,
then that will explain key
because by default
Java treats it as an integer.
And we we want to specify
that I'm using the low number.
Okay so that's why we specify them now
representing represent in decimal numbers
right here my decimal value.
Now what I'm doing,
I am storing it, I'm storing it right.
So now what? I would like to store it.
I want to store it inside the box right
and I can name it whatever I want.
Right?
I get them in whatever I want.
So how do you want to name your baskets?
It can be anything. It can be ABC, it can
whatever name you want to give
a. Okay, fine.
We'll do it.
We will do it right.
We'll do it right now, just do compliance,
compliance and jealousies.
Hey, you know what?
Whenever you want to use the box,
you will never.
You want to use the box.
Now I say you have to tell me.
What are you planning to store? Okay.
What are you planning to store?
I'm planning to store a decimal. Those.
Now you can represent your decimal values.
We have loads
on. We'll use double.
So now whenever you specify a float.
Right. And you're trying to store
this symbol value
program
also will give you an error, right?
Or also will give you an error.
So now what we have to do,
we have to specify
that I'm using a float to the
that I'm using a float.
I have to add
f and then lowercase f or uppercase.
Oops, uppercase x exact
the same thing as we use in with the log.
Right.
It can be a lower l
or it can be a big out.
You specify that this number is
a log here.
You specify that my number is a float.
So now let's do another one for example.
Now I have don't know,
1999, right?
1999,
1999 value.
I want to represent.
So now there's 19, 19, 1999.
Well, I want to store inside a box.
I don't want to name one box.
I want to name the boxes.
And now I complains jealousies.
Okay I see that you want the box.
You want a variable.
I see that you want to store the value.
But I'm very strict.
You got to tell me ahead.
What are you planning to
story? I'm planning to store.
I'm planning to store this.
Okay.
And this fabric value can be represented
in the form of float
or double in the form of split for double.
I want to please
make sure you use lower D, okay.
There's no upward load.
You okay?
So two family members in here.
Two family members
that can store decimal numbers.
Okay, so now
the difference, okay,
the difference between slow and a double.
It's ability to hold
those floating
points, those decimal points.
So when we talk about slot float is able
or is able to hold up to
up to 5 to 6 decimal places.
Right.
And when we talk about double
double is a bigger
okay, double is a bigger box
that can hold about 14 to 15 of
decimals.
Okay.
So these I will be able to show you guys
tomorrow from now.
From now, you won't be able to
to see but especially whenever we guys
will be doing the division
you guys will see the difference when we
go into store result inside the float
or when we want to start the value
inside the double.
Okay,
Now that will know that will is
the out of here does
double will be the most popular data type.
Okay let's
put in double.
Yeah you don't need to specify
this is by default of it by default.
Any time you use decimals java treats
it as a double
by default when you use in number
java treated as an integer.
Okay.
But some processes
that are happening inside which we will
in the later things now
we will work with the numeric values.
So now what we would like to do
I want you represent and store
single characters
who can who, who, who hasn't?
Who can I represent
the single characters? This
but that will you do
needed by default any time you we
we use a dash
a number of decimals by default
Java treats it as a double value.
And here we have char all lowercase.
Remember they have to be like char
and that same thing.
Hey, this is the data type
I'm planning to store.
Right?
Okay. Where are you planning to store?
Tell me the name of your container.
Tell me the name of your box.
Tell me the name of your variable.
Okay. I can name it whatever I want.
I can just make a variable right?
Or I can give a name, right. The
let's say I'm in one letter, right?
That's going one letter.
So one letter,
let's say, I don't know, hashtag right now
want to store has to echo
to represent as all
let me see all name of character right.
Or I can have let's say char
and let me name it later.
Right.
I can store whatever singular I want.
For example, this is an example.
And to make them get
to represent a single character,
whether it's a
one alpha character,
whether it's one special character,
it's hash tag in here.
Let's you we are all getting warnings
and I'll go over those.
Okay.
So now one thing, this Java is very,
very strict.
Right. Whenever we are trying,
whenever we trying to
use the variables right in here,
our Java is asking hey,
what would you like to store right here?
What would you like to store?
I want to store a single character
in what we do in a store.
In a single character right here.
What I would like to store.
I would like to store decimals. Right.
So Java looks okay
they're planning to store.
Who represent the decimals?
My double, my double.
Okay, so what they need
they took a container right?
This is what happens based
I took a container B
right
this is that you could contain in by box.
What is the name I have given?
I have the name given the name B.
Now what I did,
I took the value 1999, right.
1999 and place it inside
right now in 1999.
It's a value that lets it decimals.
Right?
So now who can represent the decimals?
I said, hey, I want to use double right
because it's a double whammy
temple type of right, double right.
And as I mentioned, Java is very strict
now you said to Java, hey,
inside this box,
be right inside the box B,
I'm going to store double type of values.
Then you to make sure.
Then you have to make sure that you
storing only double type of values.
If I'm going to
actually be
you going to store different type, right?
For example, let's say let's think in here
what are the numbers 1000 right
now if inside I want just the 1099 now,
it will complete.
Okay. Java will complete. Why?
Because 199, it's not a whole number one.
99 is not a whole number 199.
It's a number that has decimals. Right.
So now Java says, hey, you told me
you're planning to store integer values.
Why didn't you spawn
a double type of values?
Don't trick me, right? Don't trick me.
If you told me you want to store integer,
please
make sure you have only integers in here.
Okay.
All right. In our last one.
Last one to represent and store.
Right to represent and store
storing ruling values.
What do you mean by rule?
We talk about yes or no, right?
For example,
when we talk about characters,
What, 1999.
Yeah. Here. One thing.
Then you know who can represent one 1090
Java says, Hey,
if you want to work
with the value in 1999,
make sure you store it inside a double
or you in inside a float.
Okay? Okay.
I want to work with the whole numbers.
Okay.
Whole numbers.
I give you a variety.
Go use either my buy will use it.
The my shorter will use it.
They're my interior or my low
right and majority of the time
we will be using our integer.
Okay.
Of course this does not have to be.
It can be more decimals. Right?
This is just me
typing in an example of the.
It can be anyone.
Yeah, it can be any number of
you want to.
You want to write B no do it will give
you either give the error D No, no, no.
This for for you works,
but you don't really need it.
You don't need it
then are needed because by default
Java knows
anytime you type A you type a decimal.
Java knows that using and double
this process will be more clear.
Guys, once we talk about the casting game,
once we talk about custom
items that represented
a Boolean values once
represent in the bowling values right?
Look, it's
it's either capital F or lower F, okay?
It does not matter.
Same thing is in here.
If you want to enforce, right.
If you want, you specify in your program
and hey, I'm using the big number.
It's not an integer
and I'm I'm using the big number. Right.
You have to add either capital L
or small L at the end.
Then thing in here, if you're not going
to ask, your Java program will comply.
Okay, you have to specify.
Hey, 199 I want to represent as a one
that we spoke about, No one.
You really think like this, right?
How many decimal values we can have?
It can be many, right?
It can be many.
I can have 199, one 9197, 100.
Right there is.
It can be a numbers of values
that can be stored inside a float
or can be stored inside a double
the same thing with the characters here.
Of course, we have the end, right?
It can be all characters from eight
through Z, uppercase, lowercase,
all the special characters, right,
But still a lot.
Now, when we talk about the Boolean
guys, Boolean has only two values.
One has only two values.
It has a value. True.
And it has a values. So that's it.
Nothing else
you can store inside a bully, right?
Let me limit bullying.
Bu equals you can store to
all of the boolean
one equals two false at the else.
There's no other values
that boolean can have, right?
Hey, are you hungry? Yes. Right.
What we will say or let's say
let say not let's say hungry.
Right?
I am hungry. Right.
I'm hungry.
Bull in spirit.
No, I'm not. Right.
So simply here,
when we say we are saying yes
or we stay right,
go, I don't have an option for me
saying the difference between the fluid
and the double.
It's so first of all, float
is a smaller data type to a double gate.
It's a smaller data
type compared to a double.
So now double can store the numbers
that go up to 1516 decimal
where the float can store,
can can store and represent the accuracy
only of values up to six and seven.
Okay. Up to six and seven decimals
as a different good.
This is a smaller data type.
This is the bigger
this can store more decimal point.
This can store two
or three points in the same thing as Java.
Very, very
minimal variables,
key sensitive.
So what will be important
is what will be important. Right?
If your have a box,
if you're going to write
something on the box
when you ask someone, right.
So let's say would you send your son
Hasan, Can you find the box right now
if you are going misspell something
or for example, if you're going to write
uppercase in lowercase, right,
maybe you are not able to find it.
So here's the
what do we mean by Q Sensitive.
Now, when we saw some value,
what do we will be doing us?
We will be accessing that value.
And whenever want to access that value,
we have to make sure
we typed exact the same box name, key
and maximum.
But once one let me summarize again.
Okay, let me summarize is
so whenever we work with different
information,
write in different data, right?
Whenever we develop in our program, right,
whenever we develop any software.
So there's a different data that we have
to work with to, work with different data.
Java exist, different beta types, right?
So whole numbers gives this four
or now four
decimals, it gives this two to represent
the one single character.
It gives us one chart
and you represent yes
or no values use as a bowling right.
So now to work with those values,
they have to be stored
inside the variables, right?
So our variables are contained or
our variables are boxes
that temporarily hold this value.
Right? The temperature right now
put the water in my glass.
No, I have a water. Right.
They have this container holds my water.
Okay, so now that was very strict Java.
Say, hey, if you told me that
you planning to store bowling
inside this box now, when
you going to try to store a numeric value,
you will complain, right?
It's for example, if I have a plastic cup
right where I'm going to add the water
next time I decide to pour a coffee,
I'm not going to work.
Right.
So the same thing in here, Java says, Hey,
don't trick me, don't add anything.
If you told me you want to store bowling,
make sure you have only bowling.
Otherwise,
all your program is going to have that.
Okay.
Very, very strict.
All right.
So now why are we getting
all these warnings in here?
Why are getting this warnings in here?
Right.
I don't think this
the purpose of storing this.
Okay.
So the purpose of taking the value
and store it inside the variable.
So later what we can do,
we can use those values, right?
If I'm going to pour a cup of coffee
in, if I'm going to put
a coffee in the cup right,
what was the purpose?
The purpose because after that
I want to drink it, right?
It's not like I'm just going to put
and then just leave it in there right then
if I'm just going to leave it in there,
it be unused, right?
It will be unused. It will be wasted.
So now why do you want to put it if you're
not going to use it in the future?
So now we are getting the warning
why we get in the water
because it says, hey, you took that,
you took the value,
you store it inside the variable,
but you have not used it.
You see the warning is is not used.
Then what is the purpose?
Why did you take this variable
if you're not planning to use it, why or?
What do we did right now?
We created one, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight, nine, ten, 11 boxes.
We created 11 boxes.
So now
has been occupied in our memory, right?
So the purpose of a variable is
what are we doing?
We are taking the value we story.
So then in this future
we can use it, right?
Think of it guys, when you using the
calculator, When you using the calculator.
Right.
You want to perform some additions, right?
So first you enter one number,
then number that you enter.
For example, ten is getting stored
inside this variable.
Second number that store 20 is guaranteed
store another variable.
And then once you store them
into variables, now
what we can perform, we can perform
addition or multiplication division,
whatever portion you have to perform
on your on your calculator.
Right. So the same thing in here.
Hey, you stored the value
you store the value inside the variable.
Now please make sure you use it.
If you don't have a plan
to use these variables, then
just simply don't use them.
And for now we going to use them.
For now
we just simply going to bring them.
We just simply going to access
those values.
For example, this if I want to print right
and if
I want to print them that out,
that's straight line, right?
I want you print.
I don't know. Let me see.
I want you print 127 days.
How can I print 127?
Tell me if
so, if I want you print right.
If I want to print 127 Now what?
You look.
Hey, I took the value 120
when you restored.
I store the inside this variable. Right?
So now this variable holds
that value, right?
So now what we have to do
need to cool this variable.
Right?
So where did I store 127
I stored in the variable box, right.
Or we it box one right.
Store inside the box one.
So now what happens?
You program knows, right?
Your program knows before
what you did right before what we did
there, what would we need right here?
Remember, the program executes path
to the bottom right steps to the bottom.
Gallegos goes, goes
and now on the line eight.
What we created, we created a box, right?
We created the box.
We gave it the name Box one.
We said, Hey inside this book, Box one,
I'll be storing by top of that list.
And I did store right what I stole.
I store 127 inside, right.
And toward the program
we created many boxes here.
Box was created
here, Box was created right here.
Box was created.
All these boxes.
My remember guys, all those boxes, what
they have, they will have a need, right?
That's how I can differentiate.
I can have hundreds of boxes.
I can have hundreds of variables.
But how can I differentiate?
I can differentiate by name.
Right by name.
Now on the line 20.
Right. All these.
So here, what are we doing?
We the boxes, Right.
Boxes, boxes, boxes in here.
Now, on the line 28, I'm saying, Hey,
Java, please print me,
please print me a box one.
So now when we call in the variable, okay,
when we tried to access the variable
this inside the variable,
what do we have values?
Any time you work with variables,
we work with the values
that we placed inside.
So now when you going to print right now
box, what you're going
to see in the output.
127 126
And now what
you guys will notice the warning.
The warning from this line has gone.
The warning from this line has gone. Why?
Because now your program sees, okay,
they took
they took the variable,
they put the value inside.
But now on the line 28, the access in it
the access.
And so the actually using this variable
while in here we just stored the value
and we are not using it.
That's right in here you get in the warning that your variable has not been used
and now we want to frame box one one.
Okay.
What you have, you have 127,
you know, one value inside one box.
Okay. One value inside one box.
Yeah.
You cannot store you inside the 127
and then nine and then zero.
No, that cannot do one value per one box.
You like here
I can, I can, I can store only water.
Right.
If I'm going to mix something that's No.
One to the code. Right.
Why you cannot see you again.
Can you please
make sure you save, You save.
And then.
And then you probably will get it.
So that's that's the difference, guys.
So now let me see
what will be the difference.
Now, let's see, guys.
What if I'm going
to put it like this? This and
that out
that print line right in line.
So now I want to say box,
but what I'm going to do
is I'm going to put it inside
the double quotes.
What are this thing will be the output.
It will be output.
This this one,
that's what I'm going to get, right?
That's what I'm going to get.
I'm here.
I'm seeing 127
that is output from the line 20.
But in here I'm seeing
the output is a line 29.
But in power in time, what.
Okay so when we trying to access
the variable days
when we try to assess the variables,
there's no double quotation.
Okay. There's no double quotation.
But wherever you going to put inside
double quotes,
that's what you guys going to get.
Okay. That's when you guys.
All right.
Let me ask you this, guys.
What if what
if I'm putting like this in a system
that out
that spring line and I'm going to say
was, okay,
so why am I
program was not a happy why, why, why?
There is some error I'm getting
because I don't have this
I don't have this variable, right.
I don't have this box.
It's for example guys let's see the name
that we don't have in a year.
Let's
say I'm going to go somewhere, right?
I'm going to start.
Hey, Summer, can you can you you help us?
Can you do it this right?
Can you
can you type somewhere is not there.
He's never going to answer. Right.
So the same thing I cannot have some
I cannot call something
if I don't have it in there.
Right. I did not created this box.
How can I use something
if I did not created it right.
So throughout these all these variables
they being created
and this for inside the memory, right.
This store. Inside the memory.
Now what do I have such a box
when I have such a box?
And that's why my program was confused.
Hey, you want to access this?
You want to access this variable.
But I'm sorry.
This variable is not exist, right?
This variable, it doesn't exist.
So make sure you guys to call
this only
variables, variables that
that you
need. Okay.
It's like if you if you did not
build something, how can you access it?
Right?
If there's a house
has not been been built,
you can live in there,
you can put people in there.
Right.
But all in all, if it has been built,
only then people can live there
and then you can specify the address.
Okay.
Then you can specify that.
And I know, guys,
you have a lot of questions.
Probably some things
we will go over all the details.
We will go over all the details.
You will understand why why
this is also being read, Why?
Why there is a certain thing
to be able to store
where certain things
I'm not able to store what I have.
And why do I have to specify if why?
I don't have to specify anything.
The year.
We will learn
all of that in details. Okay. Just
as I say, guys, hold your horses.
Everything.
Everything will be given to you, right?
Just in a proportional proportion. Right?
We don't want to do all the things
that you and the first class otherwise.
Guys,
I'm going to have an empty class tomorrow.
Okay?
Which I don't want to have. Right.
Okay, so now what?
I want you to do this.
Can you please print actual?
I think I have a task.
Any questions for data types?
Just any questions for data types.
How many do we have?
Why do we have this many and why?
Why do I have wide?
Why do I have low in any questions?
Do the data types
okay, okay.
It's 50.
Let's see
what let's see what we have on the slides.
This is
I think Java has two data types, right?
I like that, guys. I like that.
You guys all should be excited.
New knowledge is coming
in, and I hope so. Why?
It has not been that difficult, right?
Non primitive. There will be a lot.
There's actually countless number
of the non primitives
and once we finish learning basics then
we will be strictly strict
with focusing on the non primitive types.
String is just one example.
Okay. Data attached.
Right. Primitive. Non. Primitive.
What kind of primitive data times
we can have primitive data task can be
some the representation
of the numeric values and non numeric
right out of the numeric you can have
full numbers features in here.
Right. Decimals, floating points. Right.
There's a few data types
that can represent integer values.
There's a two data types that can
represent floating and two data types.
They can represent non numeric.
But all of this this all of this is a part
of non primitive types, right here of the
most primitive story.
We're eight of them right here.
So eight of them
that represented my primitive types.
And when it comes to non primitive guys,
there will be unlimited here.
Think of it it's unlimited.
Okay.
What is the difference between those
then use once we look into this string.
Okay.
Once we look into the string,
the f and f here will look the same.
But if if you want to store them
differently,
they will be treated as a different data
types, right?
They will be treated as a different.
David Okay, so for example.
That's right.
For example, I have a numbers, right?
I have a numbers right.
I cannot store boolean in here,
I cannot store boolean in here.
Why cannot story boolean?
Because what is the purpose
of storing those values?
Because in the future
I'm going to them, right?
So whenever we are working these numbers,
there are some isometric operations
we will be performing right?
Why do I want to store inside a boolean?
Because I will be very fine
where this some things are marked as. Yes.
Whether some things are marked
is no right.
Every Different data type has a purpose.
Right? And later
when we'll be doing the strings right.
When when we'll be learning that strings.
When we learn
how to store a sequence characters.
Because right now
how much single character. Right.
Will be storing the form of strings. Why?
Because these this strings,
you can do different things, right?
I can write my name. A cell uppercase.
I can write it as a lowercase.
I can do conversion, uppercase, lowercase,
all uppercase.
Right.
There's a lot of different manipulations.
You can do
based on the different data type.
So in here, guys, when you talk about
a smaller
F and bigger F, it doesn't really matter.
Okay, here is does not really matter.
So this whichever one you want to use,
the same thing is l small.
Well,
it doesn't really matter
if. Right?
So non primitive guys we will be focusing
starting class 11 and 12.
That's when string strictly prove
focus will on our non primitive types.
And here you guys will see
I go to represent numeric values.
Right?
This is for different family members
to represent decimal values.
You have followed double single character
char to represent false.
True or false.
We use bowling, right? Yeah.
You guys will see the range.
That byte can hold.
Sure can hold integer
can hold in a for as long.
So you don't need to remember that range.
But this is just for your own knowledge,
right?
What is being the smallest data type
and then increasing from
might be good to short
integer long business thoughts.
This is byte occupies one bite of memory.
This is a bias towards of memory four
and then eight bytes of memory.
And the same thing
with the float in the double key.
So that is being
the bigger than the float.
And whenever you work with the
whenever we work with those values
now what do you do?
You cannot just have a value by itself.
Those values have to be stored
inside of containers.
And how do we call those containers?
We call variables.
We call them variables in order for us
to use the variable, right?
So we need to give a name.
But besides, given the name,
we will have to specify a data type.
Right here I have a box with the name E.
What I'm planning to storing there?
I'm planning to store load type of values.
Right.
If I'm trying to store different type
of values, that's when my program.
Right?
I'm planning
to store boolean type of values.
If I'm going to store a number
my Java is going to complete.
Right?
So now what?
In here I created a variable.
I give it a name is hungry right now.
This variable is of which type?
This variable of the boolean direct type.
It means this variable can hold only
boolean type of values, full
sentences,
paragraphs that will be strings y
because a sentence is a combination
of layers, right numbers, spaces do.
Those are special characters, right?
In all other things.
When you have a
when do you have a mix of everything?
It will a string get
well, let's see.
Okay.
I will leave you those.
This slides will leave you this light.
And of course we will go over tomorrow.
But please make sure you look into them.
Right.
Make sure you look into them
and they'll give you the task.
Okay,
so this will be your little homework task.
And this is this thing.
This is just for practice and right.
Because
right now
I was just able to create the variables
and here I was able to access only one.
So your homework list,
I want you to create a program.
Now let's write practice variables,
and then I want you
to create the variables
to spawn different primitive types.
Right?
You have eight primitive types, right?
And what do I mean? To store their range?
Right.
For example, I want you to try to store
the way I did it in here.
Right?
Try to store.
Maybe try to create variables of byte
because the lowest one will be -1.8.
Right?
As soon as you try and you go mine, -129.
That is too big for this small box, right?
So that's what
that's what we mean by testing the range.
That's what do you mean
by just in the right store, Max.
Minimum value of that of that variable.
Okay. Of that variable.
And then what
we want you to do, I can remove that.
Do you have any
other colors in your program?
Okay.
Amazon will help you.
In. Okay.
And then what
you guys will have to do you have
I want you to frame the value
of each variable.
Okay.
So for example, the way we did it in here,
I'm not going to print 127, right.
I'm not going to print one.
Can they print 127 years?
But then what was the purpose?
Distorted 127 And here
what was the purpose?
So we store values inside the boxes,
inside the variables.
So then later we can use
what am I going to
at that point 27, going to type one.
So this will be
your homework is the homework.
I will send it
the homework.
I will send it in the course announcement.
Please do it.
So this homework, whenever you guys done
you can just
shear in your syntax students channel.
This is just a little of homework
I'm giving you.
But tomorrow guys, I will give
your official official homework.
I think now will be about 17
or 16 questions
that you guys will be doing on different
platform.
Okay. Any questions raised?
Any questions?
I hope I was clear.
If it was not, it was 90% clear.
That's what's good, right?
So please make sure you guys practice
with make sure you guys practice.
Please make sure you do homework
and I'm going to see you tomorrow.
It's 10:00
and we will go more over by details.
But here, I'll I'll leave you the slides
with make sure you look at them all.
We will go overboard naming convention.
How should we name all variables?
How should we know more classes?
What is allowed, what is not allowed?
What do we can do with those variables?
Okay, so there will be a lot of things
that we will be going.
Michael, I'm sure you can do this homework
very, very quickly.
You have any questions? False, right?
Slides years ago.
Slides will be slides will be on canvas.
Guys,
I'll upload my notes and canvas as well.
And then programs every single program
that we created today.
It's also will be available in canvas
for now.
Everything be there
until you guys will learn one
pretty cool tool in which
you won't need to go to canvas after that.
Okay.
But until then, everything is on canvas
except the video.
Okay.
All right, good.
Thank you.
Please practice.
Look into the topics
that we will be covering tomorrow
and I'll see of you at 10:00, right?
Okay. Thank you, guys.