Hey, Estelle.
So Ashley's not feeling well.
She might be able to do the classes
in the next week,
but not this week.
Or I don't know.
At this point,
if this is COVID or something else,
let me start my career.
Yes, the symptoms are more of like COVID.
Morning.
Morning, Robin.
Good evening from Istanbul.
Hi, Ali.
Already started last night.
Are there any questions
from the previous sessions? No.
And you guys prior to the rebels
are in great.
Not yet.
I see around
281 submissions on the first exercise.
Second one, third one.
So a lot of you have provided
the five rebels plus five rebels.
Right.
Even been excellent.
Some of you have tried the next ones.
2031 97.
All right, That's great.
We will work at the clips they played
so far following your exercises.
You will be working with the rebels
and are following me during the class. And
once you guys are done with Java,
you guys going to be building your
frameworks, writing large amounts of code.
Then you will be using Eclipse.
They will review the pilot
homework and review class. Yes.
In all the review classes, we will be
reviewing the homeworks as well.
So let's see
if some of you are unable
to solve a specific rebel.
Then I will be following that grapple
with you during the class.
So Arwa is saying
I don't have the link for the class.
I did have to go to an email.
So again, someone by to provide
that she can use the previous
link that she had so far these six months.
The links,
they are unique to each student,
but the link stays same
for all the week, days, classes,
weekend classes and review classes.
So zoom will send you the same link again
and again for all the weekdays
and weekends and three classes.
So if for some reason,
if you guys don't get the link,
you can use the previous link.
Yes, it's the same from last week.
Last week I class
is the link for today's class working.
So now we'll make sure
that you are joining.
I don't know.
I don't think so.
He can listen to me,
but someone please ask him that
he should be joining the weekend
class link
not week
did not review classes.
Alright guys,
if there are no questions, let's start
this session.
Just give me a moment.
I think you here from a
from a season.
I don't remember the name that that is a
it's a great idea season.
If you guys I will suggest you
to watch that season after of when you are
in the middle of drama classes
it will it will make more sense
which they didn't they
the meme is from that show.
I don't remember the name.
It's something.
Are we covering the last week and missed
class content?
I Yes I will be go or revising
I will be going through
over that content as well
when we will use intelligence.
So we will be using intelligence after
four weeks
so that you guys know how to use multiple.
Because in the industry right
now, eclipse and intelligence,
they are used to around 80% of the times.
So we want to teach you both.
So it depends on your company,
which I did in my and they will be using
so that you guys are compatible
with both the IDs.
All right, guys,
let's start from the region.
So let's start from programing.
What is programing?
Who wants to give it
a shot? What is programing?
It's too early here.
I didn't I did not save previous
session, Eugene.
What do you mean
you didn't save the previous session?
You mean the code that you were writing
during the sessions?
It's fine,
but make sure you.
You guys are saving those
notes.
The the code that you will be writing
later on.
We will be teaching you a tool.
The tool will save the the code for
you will automatically.
So programing is a writing instructions
for the machine to execute
list of instructions given to computer
to perform particular task
without any mistakes that they attempt
to get a computer
to complete a specific task
without making mistakes.
So it's simple. It's
giving
instructions to the computer
to solve a
problem.
Okay, so this problem, it can be anything,
let's say, for example.
So you guys are
ASP.NET engineers.
So before ASP.NET engineers,
people used to test websites or
mobile applications
and other things manually.
So let's say, for example,
if they have to,
if they have to
if they have to test this Web site.
Right?
So and if you are manually testing it,
so what you will do,
you have a go ahead and you will check
manually if the logo is being displayed
properly or not.
If the position of the logo logo
is proper or not,
you will check,
you will click on this home button.
Okay, You will check
if that click on that home button.
If it takes you to the proper web page
or not, forget you can click on courses.
So you will do all of this manually. Okay.
And what happens is that
because the the IP sector is so fast,
these websites,
they they
they keep on getting new features each day
and what happens
is that when we add new features
more, sometimes
it does not effect the previous features,
but a lot of times
when we are adding something new
to a website,
it can introduce some bugs
in the previous functionality.
So let's say there are like one, two,
three, four, five, six, seven,
eight buttons in here right now.
Okay, eight links in here.
Let's say tomorrow you add a new button
and the previous buttons,
did they stop working?
Now what do you have to do?
All of these steps
that you have taken previously
to test this website,
you have to repeat all of those steps.
Okay, All of those steps.
And it will take a huge amount of time.
So to avoid that
companies this
doctor, this is position
they started this mechanism
to automate this process
because this website is very simple.
Think of
think of the think of websites like Amazon
or Facebook or other websites
that are complex.
So if you have to make sure that
when you are adding any new feature,
it does not affect the previous features.
Each time you add something
new, you have to test
all the previous features
and if you are doing it manually,
it will take a lot of time.
That means
it can take up to months
to introduce a new feature.
So what do you guys will be doing instead?
You guys will be writing instructions
with the help of Java programing language.
To automate this, your computer
will automatically test
all of the buttons.
It will verify automatically
if when you are
when you click on a button,
if you learned on the proper page or not,
okay, it will automatically check
if you are on the home page.
This this
also is where you
also the button is displayed or not
if this logo is being displayed or not.
If the position of this logo is proper
or not,
it will do all of this automatically
with the help of programing.
So we will write the program once
and every time we have
passed this website, we will just click
on that play button and all of the testing
will be done for us automatically.
Okay, so you it's a one time effort,
but it can so
it can save a lot of time in the future.
So we will be instructing
our computer to do this
task with the help of programing.
Now you guys can use programing
to create softwares as well.
Softwares like Google Chrome, Slack,
Zoom, Windows operating System,
iOS operating system,
all of this stuff that you guys see
on laptops, mobile phones,
smartphones, you guys can create
those applications as well.
Okay. Again, they are instructions.
So you are giving instructions
to your computer
that take a computer
whenever someone tries to click on this
this button that says Vicious,
please show him
the options are like enable login control.
So these are again, all instructions.
So you have written this line
by line, piece by piece,
that computer
or computer takes those instructions
and executes those instructions.
All of the possible possible scenarios
like clicking on this free button
and getting all of these options
again, clicking on this button
and then getting all of these options.
And when you click on this option,
something happens
so that that ping is already
someone has already talked about that
process that if someone will click either
chosen that option, if that link is
displayed, then I will perform this task.
Then I will perform this, this, this task.
Look, this or all of this.
It is written in the form of programing
with the help of some kind
of programing language
Programing is a process.
It is giving instructions to the computer
to solve a problem.
Okay.
And all of these programs that you see,
they are the they are example
of all these instructions.
So my next question is what is Java then?
Okay, so programing is solving the
some some kind of problem
instructing a computer
to solve some kind of problem.
Then what is Java?
So are you facing any issues
or are not
computers, programing language,
the language from those instructions?
Right.
So if you have to ask someone
to do something for you, right.
So you in real life, you can
communicate it to the other person.
But before the other person can understand
both of you,
you must understand
that medium of instructions, right?
So let's say if two persons
they both non English language
now one of them can tell,
one of them can give instructions
in English language
and the other person can understand and
then it can execute those instructions.
So if we want our computers,
our laptops to solve something,
for us to do something for us,
we also need that medium.
We also need that language. Okay.
So in real life, as we have languages
like English, French,
Spanish, Arabic, Chinese,
this Java is the language
of computers, okay? So
Java is a
programing
language.
What about the eclipse?
What is the application
idea and where does this idea
E stands for?
Okay,
it's a extensible
integrated development environment.
Yeah. So
can you give me some analogies of this
eclipse in real life?
Except.
All right, so what
what kind of tools we use
when we have to write something
in English?
The word right, We can use the word
to write that that program, those lesser
essays or any other instructions
or letters or applications.
Right.
Or we can use PowerPoint
if we have to deal with a lot of images.
Right.
So C++ basically is a software
that will help you write
because it will help you execute the code.
It will help you manage that code. Okay.
And it can also do many of things.
But we learn those things step by step,
right?
Okay. So I have used this, this,
this, this combination of two words
I'm using that
if help us execute Java programs.
So can you guys tell me about
what are these programs?
When I say programs and Java programs,
we're doing mean
by that
or right?
So it simply is simply the instruction
instructions that I applied in
Java programing language.
Okay.
So it's a
collection of
instructions
in general.
So as we move forward in this course,
I will be using new new keywords, okay?
I will be using new terminologies.
So at any point of time,
if I am writing a keyword
or if I am speaking about something
and that thing is not clear to you
or it does not make sense to you,
stop me right there.
Ask me in the past
that you have written this Java program
or what do you mean by this Java program?
What are these programs?
So once these smaller pieces
are clear to you,
then you will be able
to figure out the bigger picture easily.
Because I will be using a lot of technical
terminology is technical keywords.
Okay, So make sure that you understand
those terminologies as well.
Okay.
And one more thing, guys.
The source of so let's say some of you are
maybe some of you will like
I would like to revise the concepts
that you have learned in a previous class.
So the main source of that
will be these slides.
Okay.
And what I will do,
I will be sharing these slides
and if 5 to 10 minutes video
before the class.
Okay, so tomorrow, before tomorrow's
class, I will share the fliers in advance.
I will share a video in advance
right after today's class.
So I want you to at least
just skim through those slides
so that you kind of have an idea in
your mind that what you will be learning
in the next class. Okay.
And watch that in that small video
so that when I am saying something,
you are not listening it
for the first time and you can ask much
more sensible questions.
And one more thing, guys,
when you are reading these slides,
okay, give me these slides.
They are available on canvas.
I hope you guys have access to the canvas.
Is there anyone who does
not have access to the canvas
so you can use the canvas
on your mobile phones
or on your computers?
So all of the material related to
Java will be inside this Java folder.
And for each class
you guys will be having a separate folder.
Okay, You can, you can find out
all of the code that I will be writing.
You can get all of this slide,
all of the north
and everything that I will be writing
or using during this class.
So you guys don't have to write any notes
just to listen to me pay attention.
And when I am doing something,
try to follow me.
Okay?
And always stop me if you think I am going
too fast.
Okay?
Otherwise
you guys will be busy catching me
and you guys will be missing a lot.
So let me check what else we learned.
Okay.
So we learned about the main
method as well, right?
So let's say
let me create again.
So, guys, I want to create a new package.
Okay?
Are we going to be learning
what Canvas tells us today
or are we doing what we missed last week
since?
So, yes, you guys will be learning
what you missed in the last week.
Okay. I will be starting from there,
so I will fix the canvas as well
so that you guys don't don't get confused.
So guys, Art, for today's class,
I want to create a new package.
Well, what should I do?
How can I create a new package
in my in my project?
Okay, so.
So what should I click today?
Right click.
Or should I left?
I should first click on this source.
This s r c then I should right click.
I should say new
and then I should say package.
I should say package.
And then I can say Bong Dark.
So I want you to follow me right now.
I want you to follow me right
click on your see folders
and let's create a new package.
We are on Eclipse,
we are on Eclipse
merchandise.
I have noticed this
that a lot of you have sent me messages
directly, personally,
regarding your reputation,
all your eclipse issues,
your classes and stuff like that.
So remember, guys, all of us in here,
all of you, you are here to learn.
Okay, Don't be shy.
There are no dumb questions
or anything like that.
If something is not clear to you,
don't think what people will say,
what other students will say.
If I post this thing
in this Internet sport.
Okay, you have to learn.
Definitely.
You will be learning
if you are asking the questions.
Okay.
So if you are not asking the
asking questions, I personally believe
that you will be missing a lot around 50,
but you can miss up to 50%
if you are not asking questions.
So don't finish. I don't wait.
Do not think that what others will say
if something is not clear
to you also in this course
channel, Tag me.
Tag me in there. Okay. I'll ask others.
Okay, You're fine.
Everyone is here.
Everyone in here is here is to learn.
How can you create CRC?
So you need to create
that as you have to create a new project.
Okay.
That that's how state is created
automatically
when you create a new project
that I showed in the previous session,
you knew
you don't have that project as well.
So if you want to create that, that's I
you have to let me show you.
So click on this file.
Okay, Click on this
file, then click on new
and then then click on this project.
So those who don't have SAIC, please
follow me.
Fine.
Then new
and then project.
Okay.
So then you guys click on this file.
Neo, do you guys see this?
The same window
as I am seeing on my screen.
So make sure you have selected this
Java project from here.
Okay?
Then click on next
and give any name to your project.
Okay.
I will suggest you to give some sensible
name like
start batch 11
project.
Okay.
Not Nyah this screen in here
I cannot zoom in.
Okay.
It is not possible in Eclipse,
but I can zoom.
Did this call that this little window
behind this where I will be acting before.
Okay.
So have you guys
given a name to your project
so he know this
form dog syntax, node class, this package.
It's five packages.
Okay.
It's not for project, but right now
we are creating a project.
I found it my C in that folder.
Okay, it's fine. It's fine.
So still, if you some of you are new,
I see some of you and you are
in the last session.
So those who don't have before
projects here
guys, please create projects like this.
Okay, so if I click on Finish,
I can see my project in here.
Okay?
I can see my project in here now.
And if I expand on this now,
I see my S C folder.
So is there anyone who still don't
have this
RC folder? So
Mohana.
Why, why don't you have that SRT folder?
Have you created a new project
or. I don't you have this.
Why don't you still have this?
Okay. Okay then. Then please follow.
Make clear that project
because I will be writing
the code in here.
Please create a new project.
Do you want me to show it again?
How to create a new project?
Okay, let. Let
let me repeat one more time.
So, guys, those who don't have this
project, please follow me.
Okay, So I have deleted that project.
I go to file,
I click on Neo,
then isolate, select Java Project.
Okay.
And then you should see this
window in here.
So you see this window.
Okay.
And in here
now you can give any name to your project.
So let's see aspect
of Java
badge
and I want project or anything like that.
Okay,
so give
any name and simply click on Finish
and then you should see your project.
And here,
do you see the project Now?
Okay, great.
So let me do this one.
Yes. Dollar Basics is also fine.
You you can give any name to your project.
Okay.
Now I want you to right
click on your s C folder.
So I want you to first expand
your your project using this arrow.
Then right click
it, then right click
and then click on this package.
Okay.
So right click on your s RC folder,
then select new and then select package
and then give and this package
and then like on the syntax,
not the last one.
So have you guys created the new package?
I love you.
This class one package.
Okay, let's get,
let's create a class inside this package.
Okay, Let's create a class.
So what is it?
Class? Guys, I'm using this.
This keyword class. Right?
So what is this class?
Yes, we.
We also call it a program.
So if just simple file.
Okay.
It's a simple file with Dart and Java
extension.
Okay.
So any file
that has this dog to Java extension,
we call it a class, even that class
as the main method as well.
We call it a program in Java program.
Okay.
So, so any file with DART
and Java extension is a class.
And if that class if that file
has that main method,
we call it a program.
Okay, So let's create a class
and let's call it variables Demo one.
Okay.
And I am selecting this checkbox in here,
okay?
I'm selecting this checkbox in here
so that I don't have to write Main method.
I don't have to write.
And so I give any name to my my class.
Then I selected this checkbox
that says public start date, avoid me.
Okay.
So that eclipse automatically arrives
the main method for me.
Okay. And then I clicked on finished
two days package
name must be com or class dart syntax to.
Okay so let's say guys by mistake. I.
I forgot how I forgot that
it should be class two.
Okay.
Or let's say
I have given any name to my file
and and the name is wrong, right?
So how can I rename it?
Okay, so as we can rename our normal files
on our computer,
we can rename the packages
the files in here as back.
Okay.
So if let's say I have given wrong names,
I will right click.
Okay.
And then I will select this option
that says refactor.
Okay, so and then I will select a rename.
Okay.
So right
click on the package, then refactor,
then rename.
Do you guys see this option?
You see this option. So
before I can
rename it eclipses is saying that hey,
please make sure that you use
save the file first.
Okay.
Before you make any
if I will say okay, I will say the first
and now I will change it
from class one to class two.
I am confused.
So why are you confused?
But it's confusing. You.
I am just renaming a file name.
I'm giving it a different name.
Take your time. Right.
Why? You are confused.
So if you guys have given me package
as class one, if you have given this name
last one, then yes,
you should be naming two class two
because we are in the class right now.
All that s Derek batch 11.
That was just to show you
how to create a new package.
But because I have already created
a project, I don't want to repeat
all of that process.
So that's why I give any random
name to that package.
Baby class
we were told to name is Java Basics.
It's also fine. It's also fine.
Basics is also fine.
You don't need to change it.
The name can be anything
if you
guys want, only give the name basics.
It's fine. So right now you guys see?
Let me, let me tell you why I gave it.
I gave so far. Batch nine.
I have this back
and this project in here on batch night.
Okay, final batch.
Then I have this dark batch,
and then I have this one.
So for me, I am organizing
my code in a different way.
Okay?
Because you guys only have one project,
so you can.
You can give any name to your project.
Just naming is not that big.
A big problem.
Okay, So if you have our basics,
you can give that.
If you have any other name,
there's also fine.
You can keep track.
It is clear case.
Yes. Most of all, we can move the packages
and classes from one project
to another project.
So nice.
What do you want me to show again? Yes.
You can have this class.
And the dialog basically says that.
Okay, it's
just my way of organizing the code.
It's just my way of organizing the code.
You guys can organize your code
in a different manner.
Okay, It's fine.
So to to change the
name and you guys right click
retain the name, you guys right click,
then you click on Refactor
and then rename.
Okay,
so right click refactor,
then rename and then you can give
any new name to your package.
Let me write it down in the north as well.
Can you repeat it please?
I already see this
coffee is not strong enough
to put it in here.
So this is how uranium.
So right click
the effective
and then rename.
Okay.
What do I do
if it does not if I don't see cancel?
Okay, so let's say I lost my consult.
Okay, so I don't see my consult.
So if you
try to print out something
so I don't see my console, I right click,
I click on Run and then Java program.
So now my console
will automatically appear.
Okay.
Is it allowed to use shortcuts
like you are not allowed name?
Yes, almost definitely.
You guys should be using the
shortcuts.
Okay.
So what do you want me to do?
Again?
We can also select the class
name and click and do some typing.
Yes, we can also be loaded etc.
From there. Yes.
Now while I rename the class
one to class two.
Okay, so do you see a control now
how you put in the system?
I'll put intel.
So I just wrote this line.
I just wrote this line. Amita.
I just wrote this line.
I right click,
I execute and I see my output.
That's it.
So. All right.
Okay.
So tell me about this main method
or what is this main method?
What is this public start table?
What happens if I if I don't have this
main method in my program, what happens
if they mean or right? If I
let's say
if I so tried to follow me guys really
that that is the right path and BSD
all your your system dark outline in here
and try to remove your main
method.
Have you guys removed your main method.
Okay.
Have you guys created this new file and
and this main method in here?
Okay.
So try to remove that main method
and try to write this system down.
But println,
you see,
I'll have started getting this at us.
Right?
So if I don't have main matter
whether they are repos
or whether you are in eclipse,
your code will not work.
No execution, no starting by
your computer does not know from it.
It should start executing the code.
Okay. So even if I try to execute
and if I say
run as I don't see that run option,
okay, I don't see that as option.
And if I do, if I try to execute
from this one green button here,
I, I get this error
and BNSF main method not found in class.
The last two variables demo one
and the addresses.
Please define main method
as public static void main.
Okay.
So your eclipse is trying to help.
Your java is trying to help you.
It is saying there take a half
that you don't have main method.
Okay.
And that's why you are getting this add.
If you want to fix it,
please create a main method.
Yes, you should be creating a new class
like like me and you should give it
a name as variables and more.
And then this should be the name.
So if I press control Z,
I get my main method back.
Okay. So it controls.
It works in here as
and if I execute, I get my output.
Good morning.
How do you change at the package name?
So Catalina, I think I have showed
it at least five times
how to change the package name.
So have you joined the class right now?
Were you late?
Oh, you joined Justin.
Okay, let me repeat it one more time.
Definitely repeat one more time.
So you right click on your package
and then you select a refactor
and then rename.
Okay, What about Mad Cow?
Do we go back?
So it should be command Z on Mac.
If this is how we rename it,
let to know if if you still
can't rename your package.
Okay, let's actually move this line.
No, it is not working.
So is there anyone else who is using Mac?
And again,
can you guys those who are using Mac
and you try to undo using Command Z
and if you can tell me if it is working
or if it is working or not, it should work
all to get back to Main using control
Z or commands.
The Mac users Command Z, Windows
Users controls
so far for those
if it is not working,
I'm saying about the Mac users.
So it is possible
maybe because you have blinded that e
you have used
that command the E to something else.
So you can assign
different shortcuts on your Mac.
If you have assigned a different shortcut
to that command, the shortcut,
the different command,
then it will not work, okay?
It will not work.
So for that, if you want to fix it,
you can also in this port channel
and maybe she can help
you get back to control command C
command back.
I use Mac.
How did you print it?
I just tried this this out,
so I tried this line
and that's how I put it.
I write this line
and that's how print.
No, I mean number five O
which which number five.
I didn't print number five anywhere.
Main method C means
I am not printing it.
I guess she means line five.
But what I am not printing
the line by line
five is a main matter.
So you don't have this this main method.
You mean you don't have this man method?
So those who don't have this main method,
you guys can type it.
So you're looking at Elsa.
If you don't have this main method,
you can just type public
that big void.
Main like this.
Okay, You can just type it so base.
When I am writing something
in this editor, well,
we said that we are writing something.
We don't say
we are printing something in here, okay?
And when we are seeing any output
in the console,
then we say we are printing something.
Okay,
so, so, so try,
try to use proper terminology
so that others can understand
you better look
so I can
type plus two and then it should work.
Okay, so nice.
Make sure everyone can see the output
that you are writing inside the system.
Not out. Okay.
Because now we will be using this class.
The one plywood.
Okay,
so you guys see this output, All of you.
So it let's say
I want you to type this as well.
I want you to type this
and let me know what you guys are
done typing.
Just write a plus sign.
You know, something like that.
So if I execute this code,
I see to output, right?
What, you guys, I don't want to see this
first task on the next line.
On the second line, what if I want to
see it side by side with class two?
Well, what should I change?
I should change.
So what should I change
in this print to print?
Or should I take this parental to print
the first one?
Right.
So if I if I remove this and then after
this print
now I will see my output in here.
And if I want to put some spaces,
I can put some spaces like, yeah, okay.
As many spaces where they want,
like the administration, if they want.
Okay. And I will see those spaces in here.
Is there anyone who is not getting
the same output as of me
now? Space
before class?
So this is how we can use print
and print.
And I guess this is the difference
when you write print and then
so when you write print alone.
So in here I have written this print.
So everything that I would put after
this line,
it will be printed on a new line.
Okay.
Can anyone remind me how to format decode?
So the format record this control shift
and f
how do I find my control shape?
And let me write it down and you.
Supermarket's string should be uppercase
for spring.
It gave me an address
so the s off of this string online type.
It should be kept.
All right, guys.
So how many?
How many different types
are there in Java?
The basic ones.
All right.
The main category,
there are two main categories of data
types, right?
What are they guys?
What are these two primitive
and non primitives, right.
So first is primitive.
The second one is known two.
And how many primitive data types
are there in Java?
Can you guys tell me the names?
What does primitive means?
So the primitive means a specific type
of matter types
that we will be using to store
different type of data
in our dialog programs.
Okay.
So primitive means they are the old ones.
They are the the
the first ones that in Java introduce.
Okay, so let's start from the numbers.
Right? So we have
byte and
then we have short,
then we have and
then we have long.
Right
then we have load
double
or the end
and then job.
So what kind of data
I can store inside the containers
which have by two that data type.
Okay, can I store numbers
with the decimal point inside byte.
Can I store numbers with decimal point?
Right. So this,
this byte we can use it to store
numbers
without
decimal point from
-128.
So 127.
Okay. So
and this is how we stored it.
So if I, if I have
this requirement
that I will only be storing numbers
from minus one, going to be 8 to 127,
I can use the by two data type.
Right.
So how,
how can I declare a variable of type byte?
I am making notes in an intelligent.
So how I will how I can store
byte,
I will write byte organized raw numbers
inside of byte variable.
I will side with a lowercase
b I will say byte. Then
I can say it's a
small container right?
Then I will use equal to sign, right?
And then I can store
a number in here.
Right.
So if you focus
the first letter
of this variable,
of this container of this box,
I am using a lowercase s
and the after each word,
the next word I started with uppercase
letter.
So do you guys know about this?
We have we,
we have this camel case, right?
So we have this specif notation in Java.
If we want to give names
to the containers.
So this,
this, this, this process of giving names,
it is called camel case.
Okay.
So it's like B thoughts
of that camel, right?
And we have become a leg.
Then we have that top of the camel
and then it goes like that.
So first word, it's
actually the lowercase letter.
The first letter is lowercase.
The next word that we
write, we use the uppercase.
Will we
write
the character of that word in uppercase?
Okay.
It's a convention in Java,
but if you are not following
that convention, we will get any errors.
If I don't follow this convention.
So if I don't follow this convention.
So let's say
if I am using a lot right, and
so I will not be getting any it.
Okay.
So it's just to
write better code, okay.
It's just to
make these variable names more obvious.
Okay.
And guys, I have changed.
I have changed this C
from uppercase
to lowercase
and now I am getting any errors.
Well, what does it what does this mean?
Well, why I am getting an error is not is
not is not
is still the same keyword.
So what does this mean?
Is Java is dumb is they are sensitive to
uppercase and look at things
So Java is is sensitive
by case sensitive.
What do we mean if we write
something in uppercase is not the same
as if we write the same thing
in lowercase.
So java is keys sensitive?
Okay, so that's why Java is saying
that Tasker, you
you don't have any container,
You don't have any container
with this lowercase C Okay.
You are asking me to print out
the value of a container
whose name is small container
with the law. K.C.
But I don't see any container.
I don't see any variables.
I don't see any boxes with this name
because thought of Java,
this container name, this variable name.
This box name is different from this one.
Okay.
So if I don't have
a variable in my program
and if I try to spell, if
I try to print it out, I will get an edit.
Okay.
Because I didn't declare that box, right?
I didn't declare that box.
So and even if I try to execute this
code, I will get this added.
So guys, I want you to focus on the atoms.
So Maryam, please post the issues
in the syntax sports.
Okay,
so it
says exception in the mantra.
So I want you
to focus on the errors as well.
All right?
I want you to focus on the errors as well.
These errors,
they try to tell you something.
So the NSA is an exception in main
thread, unresolved compilation error.
And then it says small container
cannot be resolved to a variable.
Okay.
In simple words,
it means there is you you can declare this
small container variable.
Okay,
So that's why you are getting this letter.
So if I change this lowercase
to uppercase, see,
now the error was let me.
So now I see my output. Yeah.
So it's case sensitive
and an integer type where containers
I can store negative numbers,
I can store a positive number.
Right. But I have to make sure
I don't
store numbers beyond the range.
Okay. The numbers they should be medium.
Please post in this sports channel
index if you are facing any issues
or anything like that post.
In this post we have a special
we have special person over there
to solve your issues.
Shiva. Shiva
is there just to solve your issues.
Okay,
So that way we don't interrupt the class.
So if I try to put a number
beyond the range, I will get an error.
Okay, I will get an error.
So I can also run 20
because the max range is positive. 128
And this
and then if I if I execute my program,
that is why I don't see this 127
on my console.
Well,
why I don't see this 127 on my console
because I didn't use
this command
to put into the value on my console.
Okay.
If I want to see something on my console,
I must first use this system
not down, but parental and command
to put it back out.
Okay.
Otherwise,
even if I have million variables,
I will not see them
so I can adjust this out.
I can put
a small box.
Okay.
And now if I execute my code,
so now I see 127.
They will not see them.
But why they will still be executed in
Java.
Right.
Okay.
So, Catalina,
you see, not all the programs that we used
in our day to day life.
It's not necess
re that they always produce an output.
Okay, It's not necessary.
So sometimes you write some piece of code
that does a lot of things, but
you don't see any change on your screens
or on your consoles in your real life.
Okay, so it's perfectly fine. Okay.
Maybe to write a piece of logic,
you are writing ten lines,
and then once those ten lines produce
an output, then you only put
into the value of that output.
It will clear with time
it will get here with now.
All right.
So if I use these double forward slashes
and if I, if I try to point that out,
if I try to print out,
will I see that on my console?
It's a comment. Right.
So comments there.
Oh, what is the need of these comments.
Right.
Well, why why do we need these comments?
They are not for others
or maybe for the same programmer
who wrote the program.
So what happens is that
when you are writing something
complex, right, you might want to put
some notes inside your file
so that others can easily understand
that how you solve a specific program
using some specific guidelines structure.
Okay, So for that reason,
we have these comments and
everything that we write inside
the Command Java ignore stack.
Okay?
It is not
it is not executed and it is not printed.
Okay.
So if I execute before,
I will not see
it's a comment on my output.
Okay.
Because Java is ignoring they're saying,
okay, it's just a note for us
that I don't have
to do anything with this. So
are there other types of comments as well?
Can you please quickly explain on
when to use bracket and when not?
So you'll get that this is something
that you will learn with time?
Okay.
There are no specific rules
that when you have to use parenthesis,
when you have to use brackets,
then you has to use square brackets.
So let's say, for example, you again
ask me their task.
Go to why you are using square
brackets in here, right?
Why not?
Why not the parentheses
and why you are using curly brackets in.
So they are part of Java language. Okay.
So you will times slowly you will
you will learn that we are
we use parentheses are to use a sphere and
so are there any other types of commas?
Is there any other way
I can write comments in my program?
How can I write comments
other than this
double forward slashes multi-line comment.
Right.
So if I put something in here
I will get an error.
So Java will only trade
down, only treat anything
that I put after
these two forward slashes as comments,
but it will not treat anything
that is in the next line.
If I want to write a bigger note, okay.
If I want to write a beginner
so one thing I can do, I can maybe
keep on adding these forward slashes
before each line.
Okay.
So sometimes it can be
it can be cumbersome.
So what I can do instead,
I can write one forward slash,
I can write star,
and then if I press enter,
it will keep on adding these stars
before each line.
Okay, so now I can write
multiple lines in here like this.
Like just multiple lines.
Multiple. Okay.
So I don't have to put all those forward
slashes before each line explicitly.
Okay.
So if I have to write a bigger note
that contains multiple lines,
then I can use this second way
of putting comments on my program
so I can say
this is a multi
margaret line comment.
Yeah. All right, guys.
Now tell me about about the other data
types.
Well, what if I have those four
decimal, which are data types I can use
float and double, right.
So, so
this byte is
same as this short is same as bite.
Okay.
The only difference is of range.
Okay. Far short.
The range is -3 to 7, six, eight.
And guys, you don't have to
memorize these ranges, okay?
You don't have to memorize these ranges.
And why I am saying that you are
you don't have to memorize these ranges
because whenever you guys
will be writing a program loss
99% of the time,
you guys will be using an integer, okay?
And the range of the integer
is up to billions.
Okay, It's up to billions and so that's
why why do I have this buy chart?
And if I, if I am 99% of the time,
if I will be using integer,
well, why I have this byte short and long
storage capacity. So
if I can show you
when computers were invented in 1971,
first computer was invented.
But can you guys imagine
the size of that computer?
Can you guys imagine
The first computer? So
size of us.
Some people.
So this was first first,
a personal computer was invented in 1971,
but the first computer,
which was not personal,
was of a size of something like this.
Okay.
And can you guys
imagine the total of memory
the computer had that Nassar used to land
the first person on the moon?
It was only 64.
Give me 64 can be
only 64 can be
now even even even if you ask me.
Even that Nokia 3310
has more memory than that computer
which which I used to learn
the first person on more.
So the first computer had this thought
of five kilobytes only.
Okay,
so why, why I am telling you this?
So when computers were invented,
when Java was invented,
Jello was invented in 1995.
At that point of time,
memory was very expensive
and there used to be a very small, small
amount of memory in computers.
So at that point of time, programmers
did this.
They used to decide about these data type,
they used to write their programs
very carefully so that they did all
so that they don't waste memory.
But these days, even on our mobile phones,
we have 12 gigabytes of memory,
16 gigabytes of memory on our computers.
We can have up to 64 or 128 or maybe more.
Right?
So these days
memory is not that big problem.
Okay? Memory is not a problem.
So for that reason, we don't use
these smaller data types any anymore.
Okay.
And as you guys must have noticed that
in day to day life,
usually we have numbers
that are greater than 148 or 127, right?
-128 or 127.
Well, we don't deal with those
that many small numbers in our daily life.
So the programs that we will be writing,
they will not be that practical if.
You are using this chart,
our database. Okay.
They used to be important
back in the time,
but not in today's world.
Okay.
So in today's world we deal with numbers
up to billion or trillion.
So we will be using 99% of the time.
We will be using the integers in
and other times we will be using a lot.
So so that's why you guys don't need
to memorize these buy charts.
What is the other end?
All of that.
I will write the data type
that you guys will be using most.
You only need to know the range
and how to use those type. So
this one is the most widely used
when it comes to store numbers
without the decimal points.
And same is the case would be flawed
and we would want to use flawed
that often in real life.
We numbers.
So you guys,
if you have to store decimal park
then only go with doubles.
Always, always go with doubles.
If you have store numbers
without decimal point,
always go with integer
and this is how we use it.
So let's say
I have a number with decimal point.
I will say double
and maybe I want to store 12.5 inches
and then again I can print it out
on my console
like this.
So I see 12.5 on my console.
What about,
what about the other characters guys that
I see on my keyboard like this
plus sign minus sign
this model, Assign dollar sign.
What kind of data type I can use.
So if I want to store those characters
or those symbols on my keyboard, I can use
the card at that time and
I will write job
and sure, should I use double course
or single course
single right.
So far, the characters in Java,
we use single code,
so I can put maybe a percentage sign.
Okay.
Or any other sign
that I see on my keyboard.
Are you guys following me?
Is there anyone who is lagging behind
or is not able to follow me?
Okay, guys, what if I have to store
only maybe true or false values?
Or maybe only yes or no kind of values.
So let's say I want to store
all this information.
Eve, is it raining outside or not?
If I am hungry or not?
So I if I have to store
this kind of info, I can use boolean.
Right?
So boolean.
So this type of box, this type of
container, it only stores true or false.
So should I use the real course?
And then I should put this false
or I should put this false.
Good double for single code or anything
like that.
I should use
this without the course
and then I can take get like this.
And I put a smaller capital in here.
Or should I always be using the lowercase?
So as Java is case sensitive,
I cannot use uppercase
F, Yes, always lowercase.
If so, I see my files.
I can store the info like this. So.
So what should be the value
of this variable
group?
So if you have to store
something like this,
you can, you can use these type
of boxes of containers.
Okay.
They are called boolean containers.
Did you guys learn about
the string data type as well
in the first class?
Okay, let's go through that type as well.
Not yet, no.
Okay.
So let's learn it after the date.
So how much time is enough of the break
for you to stretch out yourself,
get some coffee?
15, 20.
Let's have a 15 minute break.
Yes, guys, make sure you don't just keep
on keeping on your tears.
It's very important
that you move yourself.
Okay, so waiting for 5 hours
or maybe 3 hours or 2 hours,
it's not good for your health.
And I know this because
I am in the industry for five years.
It creates a lot of problems.
So try to get yourself moving.
Okay?
Try to get some coffee,
take some fresh air,
and please remind me about the recording
when we come back from the break
and we'll be back before 1140. Do not go.
Yes, do not go
farther that far. Yes.
And the note. Okay. So this one.
You're sure
we are spending
our third day of learning,
repeating the same thing three times.
So assignment for the first two or three
weeks, we will be following this process.
Okay.
Repeating the same thing again and again.
So there is a saying in Russian Russia
that repetition is the mother of learning
or something like that.
Okay, so we are doing it
intentionally. Okay?
We are doing it intentionally
because programing
job, there is so much new things
for some of you.
You guys may never have heard
about programing or ideas or the
or blah blah like that.
So we are doing it intentionally
and we will keep on doing it for the next
2 to 3 weeks.
Then we will gradually cut it down.
So don't worry about that.
Yes, definitely.
We will be learning new things.
I am writing my notes on in Intelligent.
So after the break
we will start learning new things.
So I have downloaded. No,
you guys don't need it.
You guys can use the bird or not.
Not bad.
Or at or anything of that at all.
Or you guys don't
even need to write the notes
because I will be
writing the notes for you.
I will be sharing these notes with you
so you guys don't have to write
notes.
You guys can use the Google Docs as well.
Otherwise please be back by 1140.
Let me be the in the recording.
Are you guys back?
Only I show.
Okay so they booleans are to store
profiles
for foreign news.
Jobs are
used for spoof
and most on
then we have these non
primitive data types.
So the one difference between a primitive
and non primitive is that non primitive
data types, they will always start
with an uppercase letter.
Okay.
So on primitive
data type,
always start with
uppercase.
So and the first non primitive data
type that we will be learning if the
so we use string
whose code numbers letters
and detectors
are eight
mixture
of all.
So this thing that are type
B boxes of type string are
we would be uppercase and we like string
and we can we can have boxes
like let's say for example name type
and we use double code.
How do I put a single space in middle?
And I print two variables,
so we will
learn how to put into that space as that.
Okay,
this is called sync and coordination.
We will learn about that
string concatenation.
I can write in here
and it name.
Okay.
I can
I can maybe have
address variable
that can store any address.
I can have a string variable
on that and that can have numbers
like this.
So this new type be sustained.
That type,
it can hold numbers, it can hold letters,
it can hold different symbols like
plus sign minus almost all the things
that you can store inside a character.
You can also store inside this string that
are type the differences in characters.
We can only store one character at a time,
but in strings
we can store as many characters
as we like.
Yeah, and then deposit the same.
We can print out the values
and this name.
And so I see my name in here.
Do you guys see the same output?
All right, So now if I, if I do same name
and if I say
I shop,
I get this as well.
Why I'm getting this error.
Viruses duplicate it.
Local variable name
so I can not have to
same type of boxes with the same name.
Okay.
So when we have two same name boxes Java
and we again confused.
Right.
So if same as if in a class there are
40 student and all of them
they have the same name.
Now if I want to call someone, I
no one will know
to whom I am going to whom I am calling.
Right.
So it can create can create a confusion.
So way
when we have two same variable names
in a class York and confuse.
So that's why it is not allowed.
So I can have string type of variable,
but it should not have been declared
before before this variable. Okay.
So I can have maybe name one or I can have
name two or three or four or five.
I can put any anything
that with that variable name for
make it different.
So even if we don't assign,
even if we don't
find anything, it's
not about the assignment.
It's about it's about having same names.
Okay, so not two variables in.
A class can have same name.
Can we just
run this out?
But the output name and last name together
in one line.
I know,
but in terms of internal and optional.
So yes, I shall. We will learn about that.
No, not worry.
So yes, you guys can do this.
You guys can put a plus sign.
Okay. You can put a plus sign
and you can put into the address as well
in here like this.
Okay. With this plus sign,
this is called string concatenation.
Okay, so we remove this error first
so that I don't get any others.
So I see my name and address in here.
And some of you were asking
how to put spaces.
So this is how you put spaces
like this.
Like this.
So you can have spaces,
you can put multiple variables
in the same system outline,
but we will learn about that in detail.
Okay, this is called string concatenation.
Just give me a few minutes
and I will show you how how we can do
a distinct definition.
Let me check if we are missing something.
So you guys already know
about the data types, right?
So from non primitive data types,
now we know about this thing as that.
Okay,
We already know about the primitives.
These one
guys already know about this,
this, this.
You guys know about naming conventions.
All right, so in Java, guys,
there are some keywords
which are result of our specific things
these keywords,
they mean something to Java.
And whenever we are creating a variable,
we cannot use that name
for that fire, for our variable.
So let's say, for example,
if I say
string
class is equal to I.
So if I try to do this,
I will get that error.
Now, this time, why I am getting an error.
I am getting an error
because this variable name
that I am using, it's actually a result.
Right? Okay.
But is result.
Well, what do I mean?
That it's some specific words.
They have specific meanings
that are defined in Java.
Okay.
So no, it's
not because we have already used it.
It's because for variable names
we cannot use the reserved keywords.
Okay.
Even if I am using a result keyword
which I have not used already,
I still cannot use it. Okay.
So this public, this class, this started
this void, this by this packet,
all the keyword that you see in person,
they are all reserved keywords here.
Okay.
So They have already a specific meaning
assigned for them
so we can not use them
as the variable names.
Okay. So
this is the list of reserved errors.
They're going to be right around
50 result keywords
so that make sure whenever
you are giving variable names, you,
you are not using the desert keywords.
Have you guys
gone through this task already
in the first class?
Great.
So let's move to the second
class.
Okay, So second class, a half of the
second class is we did it today as well.
Okay, so half of this class is based on
do that thing that I type.
Okay.
So now we will discuss what is that string
class,
that string non primitive data type.
Okay.
What is the string concatenation?
What are the automatic operators in Java?
Okay.
Right.
There are some other rules
about the variables.
I'll tell you about the
rules to give names to your variables
like we cannot start a variable
with the number.
Okay, that's stage.
So you guys already know
you may have repeated again.
So fairly simple variable
and they should not start with number.
They cannot start
with specific characters.
Right.
So always talk to your variables
with the letters.
Okay.
If you follow this approach
99% of the time, you guys will not get any
errors and always use meaningful names
for your variables.
Question
Do we want to know all the keywords?
No, we don't need to want more.
Don't need to know
all the keywords around 30 plus keywords.
We will learn in this course, but slowly
over the course of in the course
of the course of three months.
Okay, so right now
you guys don't need to worry about
just just make sure
that when you are giving names
to your variables like this,
you are not conflicting.
You are not using pre
reserved keywords, okay?
So that you guys don't get any others.
So let's create a new class.
String almost takes care of everything
like numbers.
Let us get at this.
Then when to use primitive types.
Okay, that's a great question actually.
So tell me guys, are
you have multiple jobs in your kitchen,
right?
One are maybe to store sugar,
another jar,
or maybe to store to another job
or maybe to a store side and a jar
and another container to store milk.
What what if if you but
if you try to put all of those things
in a single jar.
Okay. All of those things in a single job.
So same jar equal to sugar.
Then you would start, then equal floor,
then it would be
so that is what will happen.
The first thing, whoever is the in-charge
of the kitchen, whether it's your mother
or your wife, that they will throw you
out of the kitchen right
by while they will throw you
out of the kitchen.
Because
let's say you have to make tea.
You have to wait.
If you have to make tea
and you put everything into the same jar.
Now, if you want to separate out sugar
floor, be and salt,
it will be almost impossible for you.
Or at least it will be very hard
for you to separate all this information,
separate all this stuff. Right.
So if you use a strings, Yes,
this has the capability
to store everything.
But later on, whenever
you will be needing information
outside of those strings variables,
it will be a mess.
It will be very hard
for you to separate out numbers
and then characters
and then other things from that.
Okay.
So yes,
they have the capacity and they can store.
But if we are dealing with only
we don't
put those numbers inside this thing.
This is the one reason. The second reason
that you guys, we learned today things.
So there so you have to add two numbers.
Okay.
So let's say you have two
do mathematical operations like addition,
multiplication and division.
Right?
For those operations,
you cannot use Sphinx.
Yes, they can store numbers,
but you cannot perform
those mathematical operations on that.
Okay.
You guys will learn slowly about why why
this thing, that type and hold everything.
And what are they downfalls
and what are the upsides.
So first, let's create a new package.
We cannot use string types
of calculations.
Think of them as a letter. Yes.
So let's create a new class and let's
call it
string
them.
Okay.
So do I.
Have you guys created the class?
So I yes, I can I can store the
I guess or any type of letters,
the nesting.
Okay.
By just speculating,
can you show us one more time Union.
What do you want me to show again?
How to create a class
string there?
The more you write.
Okay, let me think. Name it.
So I right click refactor
and then rename.
Okay, so
you do it right click on your package,
then click on new and then class.
Let let me know once you have created
class.
Okay, so this is how we can declare
a string type of variable.
And then we can just because
whatever we have storing inside that.
So if so, in strings
we have something called as concatenation.
So we don't need quotation
when we print. Yes.
So whenever we are writing variable names,
okay, whenever we are trying
to print the contents of a variable,
we don't put all those double quotes.
Okay.
If you directly want to print
something on the console,
then you use the double quotes.
Yes, that is correct.
Okay.
So guys, if I have to
attach
two variables together,
if I have to can get in there
two variables together in Java,
I can use the plus sign for that.
Okay. And how it works.
So if let's say, for example,
if we write this out,
we use the name of the variable,
both content will be locked first,
then we use the plus sign and then
we use the second variable name.
Okay.
And now if I print out
the contents in here, so you guys see
from this name, I see
this first part of this output.
Okay, This first one from this address.
I see
this second box from here.
Okay. So
Dawn, 26 years old.
So I put name. Okay.
Without course, because I am printing
the values of variables,
I use this plus sign in between,
and then I use this variable name.
Okay. And now Java.
I will
actually contents from both the variables
that we will combine them together.
Okay.
And then if we print them out.
So this is how string concatenation works.
Now this a string string. So
so instinct and coordination.
We can use the plus operator.
Okay.
To combine
the values
from two string
variables.
Okay.
And I can
I can not only combine the values
from two spring type variables,
I can combine the values of one string
and the other one as the integer
one thing, the other one.
S characters, boolean and character.
So let me show you.
Let's see if I have another variable.
Okay, so if I have integer, it is equal to
18, right?
I can see this out.
I can say name plus age.
So what are what
I can see this time, guys?
If I see name plus age,
one variable is off type string,
the other one is off type int
but if you want them in separate line,
then you can use two different system out
or you can use a new line character.
All right.
So if I print out this value now,
so now the values from the variable name
and the value for all that this in B here
E variable contains
they have been combined.
So this is what we call
as string concatenation, combining
two values, combining things
with a string type of variable.
Okay.
And I can do maybe
now I can combine a boolean,
so I can combine two variables
because this
I can put through
in here or may be false.
And if I now do this out
so I can use any,
any string variable first.
Okay,
I can use the plus sign.
And the second variable,
it can be an integer.
It can be a spin, it can be a boolean,
it can be a character.
So what do you guys
think? What I will back now
your address and then is raining.
Okay, so I see this true in here.
Okay.
So I can combine
if being with another string,
I can combine a spring
with an integer.
I can combine all the primitive
data types, which is things.
But if, if I have
two integer variables or two long variable
are two double variables,
then things will work differently.
So let's say, for example,
if I have a double.
Okay, if I have a double number one
30.5,
I already have a double
number 2.5.
And this time, if I try to combine
these two variables for this time,
I don't have a string.
Okay,
So if I have one string type variable
and then the other variable, it can be
it can be of any other type.
But if I don't have
a string variable, then Java
will perform
the mathematical addition
with that number.
Okay, so this time we will not see
we will not see 12.5
and another 12.5 return to get that.
Okay.
This time
I will actually perform the calculation.
It will add two numbers
and then it will show you the results.
Okay,
I should have a number.
So now I see 25.20.
Okay, 25.2.
So string concatenation only works
if we have at least one thing with us.
Yes, because in
now we don't have any string variable.
Okay.
So if if I have this guys
if I have this spring, number three
is equal to 1.5
being
number or
equal to 2.5.
So if I say number three plus number four,
what are what, I will go to this.
Will I get 25.0 or 12.5
and then under 12.5
combine to get. All
right.
So this time I will not get 25.0,
I will get 12.5, then another 12.5.
Why? Because the plus operator,
it works differently with strings
and we call it strength and calculation.
Okay.
Spring recognition
and you guys can also do this.
You guys can also do this.
Let's see, maybe you can also do this.
It's not necessity
that you put the string first.
Yes. Just because of quotations.
It's not necessity
that you put the string first.
Okay.
So it can be maybe if you put the integer
variable first
and then the address
will it still double,
will perform the string
it can concatenation.
Okay,
So 18 and then one, two, three and 450.
So if we have at least
one string type variable,
the other data type, it does not matter.
Java will always perform
the string concatenation,
meaning combining two values
from those two variables.
Okay, I'm
putting those two things together
and this is what we call
the single calculation.
And it can also happen.
It can also happen
even if you don't have variables.
Okay? Even If you don't have a variable.
So let's say, for example, you can have
we can have system lockout age,
you can use the plus sign in here
and double course
and then you can write anything in here.
Okay.
Like this, like this.
So inside those parentheses
or any type of variable,
then again, that plus sign
and then double course,
you can write anything, okay?
You can write anything in here. So now
so now if I had run
so again, I see 18 is
my age, 18 is my age, so
I can put string directly,
I can fast to store
as being inside a variable
and then I can use it.
It does not matter if I have one
part as strings.
The second part does not matter.
The plus operator will always concatenated
okay to it will always combine it
with the other value.
Okay.
It will not perform mathematical addition
or something like that.
Okay.
It will perform the contracting issue.
Okay. Are we get for the string first.
The other variable.
After that we can use the other variable
first and for the string after that.
Okay.
And we can use as many plus guys.
I can use as many plus lines. Okay.
I can again
put a plus sign, use double code,
maybe put spaces or, or anything else
again for another plus sign. Are
other double quotes.
Okay, I can put a number.
I can keep on doing this. Okay.
I can keep on doing this.
What is wrong?
So Cheri is so she said he or
she thought if I mispronounce your name,
you are trying to store
a string type of data
in a double word variable
doubles.
They cannot store things. So.
So remove those double quotes
from that 12.5.
Okay, so please remove those double quotes
and you can post these kind of issues
in this fortune.
Okay.
All right.
So this is how concatenation works.
So now you guys can again, right?
Much more better statements. Okay, I'm
printing out the value.
So so now you guys can write
something like this. So
my name is then space
and then plus sign
and then the name variable.
Okay,
then I write
this time out.
But until then, I knew
this address
and then plus sign and then backless.
Okay.
And I think I can write
now much more better.
Screencast differential right.
It is
your page.
Does it make sense. Right.
How how how distinct concatenation works.
So so string congratulation means simply
combining a string with any other data
is dependent on.
So I can use directly
the combination of letters
with double code I can print out.
I can combine two variables.
I can combine any type of variables
with this plus one variable.
It must be of type string.
Let's create a new class
that's creating new class.
So I right click on my package.
Then I see
I have a question
why something is not colored
when we write is,
but other data types are colored when.
We write them so tamannah.
The thing is in non
primitive data type, okay?
And non primitive data types are something
you can also create.
Okay. So Java does not know in advance.
Maybe you can call your data type
as string one, two, three or string 1245.
Does not know what kind of name
you're going to give your name.
So this is not a result.
Keyboard
and Java does not know that in advance,
but those primitive ones, they are defined
by Java guys and no one is allowed.
Could we find any other
a new primitive that
okay, that's
how Eclipse knows that they are primitive.
Perhaps that's
why you try to highlight them easily.
But the non primitive ones.
I can also create my own a non primitive
that you guys can create your own
non primitive prototype.
So only primitives are highlighted.
Not the non primitives.
Okay, let me show you one more example
before we move forward.
So let me create a new class.
Let's call it thing. Contract them.
Let me know what you want.
You guys have created this.
Okay, Let's declare three variables.
Okay, Let's use
Nobel Prize.
We're like a base.
Let's use a string.
Their fields
start assigning.
Let's try to use distinct recognition.
Okay.
So noble cause
then of course,
I write plus sign.
Then I add the variable name,
then another plus sign.
And then again double code
space.
And another plus sign.
Okay, Then we end the variable name
and another plus sign.
And then the simple.
So please staying full like Z.
What do you mean?
So string, pull.
So can you guys tell me the output?
What output?
I will get?
So if I write this line.
Yes. A prize of not
not is but .34 dollars.
So I am directly using a string
by using those double codes
inside that system, not out.
I am also using different variables like.
Like things like double.
So this is how string democratic nation
can help you
guys understand
why we are getting this output.
Is there anyone who don't understand this?
Okay, let's let's try to solve the task
from the slide.
Okay.
So you guys will help me
solve this problem.
So I have to create a Java program.
Okay.
So what is meant by Java Program Guide?
How can I created our program?
This class, right?
The class with the main method.
So I will create a class
and I have to give it a name
to give it a name variable.
Okay, So. So walk me through the steps.
We are.
Should I click to create that Java program
or that class?
So I c should I right
click on source as I see or on package
on package, not on source.
Right.
So I need to right click here then nil
right and nil and then work days
after right clicking on package
and what should I do next
class right from in this class.
Okay.
And the name of the program should be
variables right?
Like this? Yeah.
Then I can select this this option.
What will happen, guys,
if I check if I check this option,
it will create the main
method automatically for me.
Right?
With this class.
Okay.
Oh, in my program,
it says in your program, create
different type of variables
to store student information
and then bring values
of those variables.
So I have to create name last name
grade, city state phone number.
Okay.
So now let me put your
side by side, duplicate side.
So that is not, you know, help me help me
choose the right data type
for storing this info so far name
what should be
the what should be the data type
that I should
be strings right.
Why things?
Because strings can hold
multiple characters inside a variable.
Right? So I will say string, right.
String
name. Okay.
And let's, let's use
Omron as the example.
Okay.
So let's do them.
So I use double code and then I, I put the
semicolon over What about the last name
against string?
So I'm not what, what is your last name
though?
Percent said
like this.
Or what about the grades?
So grades are the values like A, B, c,
d, e, f, g,
so I can use it
can I use this thing as well guys?
Can I use the string as a
yes. Okay, I can use, but I can use both.
So let's use string grade. Why?
I'm getting an error guys.
I am getting an error on this line
number ten
double calls.
Right? With characters
I can only use
single quotes.
I'm going to remove the normal course.
I will replace it with simple course.
If. What about the city?
Right.
In this scenario,
let me and let me add
another variable from my side.
So let's let's use this edge as well.
So which type of box I should use to store
edge.
Now you can use by
I can use integer, but what should I use
if it comes to choosing
from byte or integer
I should always go with integer.
Okay.
And what about this database
again, string.
And the last.
What about the phone number?
Long integer difference. So
here, here is
dice it how you decide whether to type.
Okay, so with four numbers,
do we perform the calculations
like a nation subtraction, multiplication,
losing, perform this kind of operations
with phone numbers?
No. Right.
And phone numbers can also contain that
plus sign, right.
That plus sign up to represent
that country code.
So which data type can hold a plus sign
with a number
integers cannot hold that plus sign.
So those who are saying indeed, yes.
So if I say
if I say
+114, five, six, seven, I cannot do that.
Right.
Oh yes, I can do that.
But I'll be getting an issue.
So let's say, for example,
in this country, code is zero.
Okay.
So if the country code is zero for
some of the cases,
I will be getting the add it.
And one more thing.
Even if I put this
plus sign in here, guys,
if I try to print this out,
what do you guys think
when I get this
plus sign in the output as well?
So let's say B country code is non zero.
Okay, So I am I'm always using something
that is non zero.
But if I print this out.
I don't get that plus sign now. Okay.
I don't get that plus sign.
So two I cannot put two zeros.
Okay.
And I cannot predict that.
Plus on one more issue
guys. One more issue.
So if I put two zeros in here,
I cannot do that.
Okay?
I cannot put two zeros in the integers.
Okay.
So let's say if your number is
is something that contains
a zeros in front, you will again
get at us.
Okay.
Because when we put the zeros
in front of a number in Java, it is meant
Do you guys know about the number system?
There are other number systems
like hexadecimal, octal, binary.
How many of you know
about the number systems
like binary numbers of octal numbers,
hexadecimal numbers.
So the the number system that we use
in our daily life,
they are based on decimal numbers.
Okay. Decimal system. Decimal system.
So the decimal system after ten.
So so from 0 to 9 we have numbers
and after then the repetition starts.
We, we build all of the numbers using the
combination of the numbers from 0 to 9.
Okay.
In our call systems,
we have max eight unique numbers.
We build all of the other numbers
using those eight symbols.
In hexadecimal, we have 16 symbols.
We build all of the numbers.
So it's a completely different numbers
system.
Okay, In computers they are used.
So when we put zeros, now Java is thinking
of this number in an other octal system.
So that's why
it is also not allowed in here.
So for phone numbers
or something like that
in which you need to put zeros in front,
you need to put other signs
plus multiplication or things like that,
and you are not
doing the mathematical operations on that.
Numbers like addition, multiplication
always go with distinct,
okay, Always go with distinct.
Is is it clear, guys? Why?
Why I am using string in here.
So I should I should go with strings.
I'm getting error rate
for right?
I must be able to double pause
with strings.
So now if I execute my program,
I see that plus sign in here.
Okay, so let me remove it for now.
So I have to print out the values
of these variables.
Okay.
So I will say
name,
then a space.
And then remember, guys, one more thing.
If you put if you put spaces
in between the plus signs
in between the plus signs,
those spaces, they are not counted.
Okay.
So let's say, for example,
the spaces that I put inside
the double course, that will matter.
Okay?
And you will see
those spaces in the output.
But between the plus size
or between the variables.
So let's say if I say name
and before this plus sign and this name,
if I put, let's say
maybe ten spaces,
I will not see those spaces in my output.
Only the spaces which are inside
course matter
in Java ignores these spaces.
Okay, so if I print out this line
like this, and if I don't put
any squares inside the double force,
and if I, if I print this,
I will not
see any space between name
and the actual name.
Okay, So spaces,
they only matter inside the double box
like this.
So a name and then maybe let's see
if I want to print out
if I want to put any of the space
and order
and let's see what do you mean?
Or and then
double quotes, let's say edge
and other space
and plus sign.
Then H
So what I will see on my console both
so name with capital N then if space
then the name because I am using
this variable name in here.
Right?
So the actual name I'm wrong.
Okay, so name space I'm wrong
then and then other space
because I have a space in here then edge
and after that and other space
and then the actual edge.
Okay, so this is how it looks like.
Okay.
All right.
So second part of the task phase guys are
I have to change student city
spare phone number and grade,
and then I have to print out
the updated values.
So after this line in here,
first I have to change the student city.
Okay, So.
So how how can I.
Of the value of city guys,
what should I write?
So this time
I don't need to mention the data type.
Okay.
I only mention city.
Okay, only the variable name
then equal to sign.
And then I can say
the updated city.
I can store the updated city. Okay.
Like this.
So if if I try to left,
let me put the city in here.
Okay. Let me put the city in here as well.
So city then.
Space.
Okay.
And then plus sign and then city.
So if I, if I, if I run into this
so I see
b I see the city as New York in here.
Okay.
But when I have updated
the value of city variable
and if I try to print
this same again, we like
will I see Chicago or the New York?
I am printing out the same values, same
variable names.
Okay,
so on line six
because I have updated
the value of a variable,
now I will see the updated output.
This I will see the object about four.
So run this and then
now I see the updated values.
Okay. Is it clear, guys?
Is anyone confused about about why
I am getting this updated outlook
or how to update the variable
values?
Okay.
So you guys can try to change the values
of other variables as well.
And then print them out.
So on this slide it's just another demo.
Okay, we have a name
and then we are using this plus operator
and the name last grade, blah blah.
Can you repeat the updated value?
Yes. You.
So the task says that you have to update
so you re assigned it s
I reassigned it so I a box.
Right. I had a box and inside that box
I had New York first.
Okay.
What I did on line
16, I opened in that box,
I extracted the city,
New York and, I placed a new city,
Chicago, inside that box.
And then just like as you do in your
in your normal life,
if if you have a paper box right here,
you can put multiple things.
You can put a you can
you can put something, you can
get that thing out.
You can put another new thing in that box
as your
needs, right?
So we can do the same with these boxes,
these variables, these containers.
We, we can update their values.
So our I will do whatever value
we have stored in them previously.
Dollar will discard about the value
and it will put updated
value inside them.
String is not required
before the re assignment. Yes.
So Maryam, if you try to put string
you will get then add it
because now you are trying to re
declare a variable.
Okay.
So you don't need
to put the string in here
if you are updating the content
of decorator variable.
Yes, I'm just updating the info.
I'm just so let's say
one student was living in a different city
then he or she moved to a different city.
Now we are updating that in that info,
right?
It's that simple.
And I said please
post issues in the sports channel.
I you are missing that plus sign.
That's why you are getting
you are missing this plus sign this
plus sign.
Is it clear guys the updating update part
so I can be other values
because now
you guys seemed a little confused.
So let me update the phone number.
Yes, the phone number
is +98,
maybe.
And then maybe I can update the age right.
So now it is
23, maybe.
Right.
So we can update those values. Why?
I'm getting an error in here.
So when I am trying to update the phone
number,
what is command thing whole?
Where is this thing command for?
I have not used this command
double code side.
So strings.
They required double codes
and they require double force.
Are you guys following me?
Are you able to follow me?
Your and pager
can be updated by same,
but if every variable right,
every variable
you can update any variable any with you
either existing integer boolean
job or type of you.
Here it's just like updating the info.
So we have stored and
and in force somewhere.
Okay. In the memory.
Now as time passes,
we might need to update that info.
We will replace
whatever stored in those boxes
previously
when we would put the new values.
So now if I execute this.
So instead of 22 now I see 23.
Yes, we do.
Please give us a little bit
time to catch you. Okay.
Just showed you guys can always stop me
and then I see the updated
city.
Yes, perfect
numbers and don't need quotation marks.
Yes, numbers
don't name quotation marks, only string
and characters because the task required
single core source
and this strings the required
double quotes.
Nicola
getting and adding edit
okay, so
Nicola the java is case sensitive.
Okay, so the variable city
that you have declared in here
you have declared is with Capital C,
but in here you are
trying to write lowercase C
okay, that's why you are getting
that kind.
Are there other students who are getting
issues or any other type of errors?
So in our future work,
is it related to update of information?
What would be the use of this in practice?
I am sure many uses, if you could
informally add those comments to
so about
the use information about the use cases.
Is that great variable?
So the name itself is variable.
Okay, it's a lot.
And then so it
something that keeps on changing.
So you are trying to store some info.
Let's assume that updating the info once
that info is stored
in a variable is not allowed in Java.
Okay, so what will happen
if we store something inside a variable?
Once that info will stay the same,
but in real life
things don't stay the same.
Things change.
Like, for example, take the example
of edge to the edge that you have today.
It will not be the same
as of tomorrow, right?
It will change.
So Java guys,
they have given you this flexibility
that you can change
the values of the variables as well.
If something changed over time,
you can obtain that value as well.
So that's why we
we can update the values of variables.
They are not fixed boxes, right?
They Are variable boxes
if later point of time,
if you want to update the contents
of a box, you can do that.
Think of the real life.
If you if have a box and you can never
change the contents of it.
Once you have stored something inside
that box, you can never change it.
It will be pretty much a useless
box right?
Forever. It's fine.
It's fine.
Please be patient with that. Yes.
I am not rushing.
I'm not rushing.
Don't worry. You can.
You guys can always stop me.
Ask questions. Okay.
If something is not clear.
So the other use
case of this, you guys will see.
I think
after two more classes.
Two or three classes.
Okay, then you guys will use loops.
Okay, Then you guys will use Java
to perform mathematical operations.
Okay, So then you will see the use of
and those are how we can update
the values of variables.
So let me know once
you have this code, once you have
understood this board,
if you guys need a break,
you can also tell me we can have a break
if need some time.
Goodbye.
Just the simple.
I think it's all about our homework
where we can do a lot of practice
and think on our own.
Yes, you guys will be.
Doing a lot of practice on that as well.
Okay, so you guys will be having around
250 plus triples.
So you guys will be having
a lot of practice other than repos
you will almost always you guys will be
typing writing code, dialog word.
Okay.
Till the very last class of this bootcamp.
After you get to your job
almost every day,
you guys are going to be writing code.
So every all of this stuff,
this variable declaration,
creating new classes,
it will be on your fingertips. Yes.
And you guys will be getting a lot
of scary dreams about the code as well.
So so when I when I was a developer,
I am busy with something.
That thing is not working.
I go to sleep that night.
All all night.
I see that for in my dreams.
Until that problem is solved
you are getting
you are getting some errors.
You are unable to figure it out.
Why you get tired of
you spend one hour, two or 3 hours.
You go to sleep.
It will be in your dreams.
Even if you are
anything
that you guys will be doing in your life.
Once you become coders,
it will always be inside
your mind.
Yes, I.
I still solve, but.
And the problems these days,
they are now a little different.
Actually, in my field, this is a
it requires
a lot of mathematics background
and and high skills in programing.
So these days
they are actually it's kind of same.
We are going to
the same. I'm also learning
very complex techniques on
coding
and then combining maths and all that.
Do You see the metrics
you see in the red tape
in your database.
Yes, I am continuing my education
dollar is very sensitive.
If we miss anything small,
it will be on our entire project.
Yes, that is correct.
Create and new programing languages
don't think so.
You should create new programing language
because I think there are more than
18,000 I guess programing language,
languages. This
there are already
so many programing languages,
approximately 9000
computer programing languages.
And are just learning one of them.
I see bugs every year.
Can you execute a security state
and phone number separately?
Yes, sure.
So this phone number
and the state lets by bill.
So by execute, I guess you mean
display the values
of those right so system
I see state
and then
I see
right like this
what is the phone number.
Not number six.
Phone number.
What was the first computer language.
The first languages
they start from that binary language.
Those those ones and zeros.
Okay.
So people in the early days, they used to
write combination of ones and zeros.
So this is how the binary language
looks like.
So you guys are very lucky
that you are born in 20th century
and you guys don't have to learn
those combinations of zeros.
Previously This is how
developers used to program.
So they used to have these
folks.
So right now in today
we write this character a nice
but be like people previously
they used to write if they have to write
it and be used right 1100010
and they have to memorize this as.
Well binary code,
this was the first computer
programing basic message
out of this binary.
Every language is born out of this binary.
After this binary, we have something
as the assembly language.
These developers, they were very
highly paid, they were very strong.
And after that.
So because it was very, very hard,
they developed something
called assembly language.
So then they developed
something like this.
c0106
84 B So
a combination of letters and numbers.
So previously only ones and zeros,
then combination of letters
and numbers,
Okay, assembly languages like this.
So move
and then R seven has zero, blah blah blah.
This,
I have learned this assembly language
as well in my Indian name.
And then they do at
high level languages
like Java and Python that we are learning
today. Yes.
The ones who are the first in any field
did they do a lot of
hard work?
They have to through a lot of the
already. Okay.
So do you guys need a break?
Can we take a break about 115?
Yes, sure.
Let's have a big
ceremony.
It's almost one, so please be
Oops, click.
Please be back.
Can we see you?
You mean me?
You guys don't see me. Screen is variable.
Can we take a break around
around 130
then? Buffy, I need break. Yes,
we can see other guys.
Remind me about the recording.
If I forget
moving always need to type space.
You'll get that on which line?
On which line?
You are asking that we need to type
the space
like any you know we can
we can write like I can.
I can do this as well so I can do.
Speaking here
is equal to without any space.
I can do this
eclipse variable screen
so you can do this as well
without any spaces.
I want to see eclipse variables
eclipse variable screen Illini.
You mean be variable screen
that appears when you are
debugging your program
that we did.
You mean the variables class.
Now this is the screen
that we are practicing
right now. So
yes I am not we had a break
so I am not doing anything.
We are on break.
If I was answering that question.
Okay, remind me about it.
Funny, we started recording
so I hope you guys created to class
with me
this beside a traumatic operations class.
Yeah.
Similar
to that.
So to perform different
operations, we the
we need to some time
do the mathematical operations as well
in order for let's say we are building
a website that calculates the interest
on maybe a website
that calculates the price of something.
So for those kind of things,
we need to have
something that can help us
do that math
and those mathematical operations as well.
Okay.
To solve real life problems, it's
very important that programing, language
support as many mathematical operations
as possible.
So today
we will learn about the five basic
mathematical operations
that we can do in Java.
And these are very simple, or
I hope all of you are familiar with this
other than this one.
So it's simply plus addition,
subtraction, multiplication and division.
Okay.
So we will learn about those now. So
it's very simple.
Most of the symbols are same.
You guys might you guys
might have seen them
already on calculators
this is same same
this multiplication symbol in programing.
We use this static site.
Okay it's on your
he number eight on your keyboard.
And then for our division,
we use this forward slash in programing.
If we want to divide two numbers,
we use this forward and this operator,
this modulus operator is actually to get
the remainder of that region.
So let's let's learn about this.
Let's say I have two numbers, okay?
And the numbers are off type in data.
So remember, guys, this
all of the operations
that I will be teaching you now, they can
they can differ.
If you are using a different data type.
So let's say if you are performing
these operations on integer type of data,
the results can be different.
If you are performing
these operations on a
Boolean type of data,
the results can different.
If you perform these on things that type,
the results can be different.
So we will learn
about all those differences as they they
I think I am already recording.
Okay,
so let's start this from the simplest one.
So the first one is
the integer type of get.
So let's see if I have two numbers.
One, I have been in here
and I have integer.
I'd like to
if I say
number one plus
number two.
So in real life, guys,
if we add two numbers
without the decimal places, look,
should we deserve that?
I should get
30. Right?
So we use the same sign, the same symbol
that we use on our calculator
to add two numbers.
Okay, So we write the first variable,
we write the second variable,
we write the plus operator,
and then Java, I will perform the addition
on those two variables.
Okay.
So I can see wrong
here and I get 30.
Okay, so this is how we perform addition
on into type of variables.
Okay.
And if I want to do the
if I want to do the subtraction,
I can use the negative sign.
Okay.
From my keyboard.
So now Java will perform this infection
minus ten, right?
Because I'm trying to subtract
a smaller number
and bigger number from a smaller number.
So if I change this to
number two
and then one, then I will get the results
as positive. Ten.
I hope this minus sign
is not bothering you.
And then if we have to perform
multiplication,
then for multiplication
we this star symbol
and we use this task.
So ten multiplied by 20 is 200.
So I get 200.
Now the results
for multiplication, addition
and subtraction, they are pretty much
same as you guys might have been doing
using a calculator as a simple math.
However, the results for division,
they work.
They are a little different
when it comes to integers.
So let's say for example,
if I say
if I see
number one divided by a number,
what answers should I get?
Goes?
If I divide number ten with number two?
But this is not the answer
that we get in real life.
I should be getting 0.5 right?
This is what I get in my real life.
If I am using a
calculator or something like that.
So what is going on in here? Okay.
If I try to execute this, I get zero.
Okay, I get zero.
So what? Why? I'm getting zero.
So remember, guys, get
an integer type variables.
Can they have decimal numbers?
No. Right.
So what is happening in here?
So from the rules of math,
we are trying to do something like this,
right?
So I cannot do ten with 20.
So I add is zero and decimal point.
I add a zero in here.
Right.
And then I try to divide it
like this.
What is the remainder in here? This
zero.
Right?
So in integers and integers,
as I cannot hold numbers
as I cannot have decimal places.
So this part
after this decimal point,
it has been ignored.
Okay?
It has been ignored because integers
they can only contain numbers
without decimal.
So java is only showing you this zero.
Okay, only showing you this zero.
So integers if I have entered data
type integrator
type cannot hold those in decimal numbers.
So what's java will do?
It will ignore the decimal part
and it will only show you the other part
if we about the decimal place.
So that's why we get to zero in here.
If I change my data, I
if I change my
data type
to double.
Okay. Can can double.
Can they hold the decimal part straight?
Yes. Right.
So in here, if I am
if I am saying
number three plus
before.
Yeah.
I will be getting 30.
If I say number
four minus number three minus number four
I will be getting minus ten
be multiplication.
I will get to 100.
But now I will see the difference.
Okay.
So if I try to divide in number
and if the data type is double,
if the data type is double,
then I will get 0.5.
Okay, then I really get 0.5.
So let me put paren open
here.
I'm looking at that.
So I see 0.5
are this printout
and I get two zero from this part.
So what do you guys understand
from this example that if you have to deal
with decimal places,
should you ever use the data type?
If you know that the your calculations
they can contain numbers
with the decimal point.
Never ever go with internet type.
Okay.
Always use double data type. Okay.
Otherwise you will not be getting
the expected visitors.
So you guys see how how the same operator.
So the operator, same guys.
The operator is same.
But on one data type
I am getting a different result.
But on another data type
If we use one double and one integer,
it will be working.
Need to specify a decoder converter
type based on the requirements.
So Alex is saying if we use one double
and be one integer, will it work? So.
So Alexa, if you mean by by working,
if you mean
if you will be getting the same results.
So let me try to show you
different variation
so that it is clear what happens if you
if we change prototype.
So let's say
one is
an integer.
Okay then.
And I am trying to divide it by 20.5.
Right?
So one number is integer in here,
the other one is double.
So what do you guys think?
What would happen?
I should see
the decimals in my answer.
Okay.
So if one is integer
and the other one is double,
then the result will be double.
Okay.
But here is one more thing
guys get is one more thing.
Let's see.
Let's say you were storing the number,
you were storing the result.
So you are trying to store the result
in an integer now it will not work.
Okay, so Java knows that the result
of this calculation
that I am trying to perform,
it can result in a double.
Okay, so now Java will warn you
and I will give you an error that good.
I think that the results
can be in the form of a double.
Okay.
So please make sure
that you use the proper data type.
Okay.
And if I change this back,
if I change this back
to both of these two integers.
Okay, So now Java is saying, okay,
both of
the different types, they are integers.
Okay, so now I am not sure
you might get integer
as you might get double header.
So what I will do now
if the result is it double
if the result contains decimal places?
You know what?
I will ignore those decimal places.
I will only give you the part
B decimal places.
So that's why in here, when we were trying
to perform the calculations
and the result was 0.5,
Java ignored the B point five barred.
Okay.
Because both of the data types
were integers.
Okay.
But if use one of the data type as double.
So now java knows their task. Good.
Obviously, you know what?
When you are using both the numbers as
integers, okay, so they are the results.
They can be integer or the double. Right.
But in here I know for sure
that one number is double
and you will ever get integer.
So I will give you an error.
So make sure guys,
if you are using a mix of data type first.
First thing it is never recommended,
never ever try to mix data type.
If you are
if you are performing some calculations
and you know the results will be double,
always use double.
Why use one integer and the other double?
And even if you have to use mix of data
types,
there is something called as casting
that we will learn in the future classes.
So once you guys learn about the casting,
then you guys can freely use the mix
of data types.
So right now
there are so
many rules for using a mix of data types
and that those rules,
they can confuse you.
So I will tell you about those rules
after we have learned
about the casting process.
Okay, Then we will be using the mixture
of data types so far.
Right now,
let's let's use the same data types.
How can we do less number after zero,
like two three numbers?
How can we do less number
after the zero, like two three numbers?
Alexa, can you rephrase the question?
Okay.
So you want a number like zero two,
three, four
not zero divided by three, 4 to 5.
So you can store that number in a double,
you can store that number in a double,
then you will be getting all the results.
So let's
say, for example, let's say, for example,
if you have this number five as double,
you can store this number like that.
I mean, after decimal place,
if yes, you can store after decimal place
or you want to round it off
all you want rounded off.
So the rounding off process,
it works a little different.
Okay, there is a concept of ceiling
and floating in programing that ceiling
and you guys will learn probably
in your six tweets I guess, or three.
Then I will teach you
how to deal with those numbers.
So let's go step by step. Okay.
Otherwise, a lot of you will be confused
if we try to jump here and there.
Yes, it is.
It's a different thing.
We will go step by step, step by step.
Why it is okay to assign
pen to table
and it is not giving out a here it is.
So I show
you guys must have learned
that can double is a bigger box.
Do you guys know?
Do you guys know the range?
So if it is an integer,
it is a bigger box.
So if I try to fit a smaller thing
in a bigger issue,
should I be worrying about anything?
No. Right.
Bigger box can hold easily,
but if I am trying to do the reverse,
if I am trying to fit a bigger thing
into something smaller,
then should be worrying. Right?
So when Java sees that you are trying
to fit
a smaller thing into something bigger,
never does not give you an edit.
Okay.
But if we are trying to do the reverse,
then there is a possibility of loss
of information.
Or you might be
you might break that variable.
Right? That container.
So that's why you got the error for that.
He is asking if the actual answer is
one point, blah blah blah.
How can we just forget we print out 1.43.
Yes, it is possible to only print.
Maybe numbers are still two decimal places
or three or four, but I will teach you it
later.
Okay, so let's try to let's try to
but let's try to apply these operations
on other data types.
Okay. So this is how it works with doubles
and integers.
Let's try to do it with a Boolean.
Let's start with check
if this is possible with Boolean.
Okay. So
variable one never say test proof
boolean variable to
say test
false
FISA law one plus bar two.
I get that one.
But why do we have to use double
instead of integers for Shareef?
If you want the complete answer,
if you don't want to lose information,
if you want the decimal part.
So Shareef, check this out here.
When I do not use the decimal, the answer
I got was zero
when I used the decimal double number.
Then I got the proper answer that
I get in my real life.
That's why you should be using double
player
because
integers, they cannot hold numbers
with decimal places.
So guys, I am getting an error
and that means I cannot perform addition
on two boolean type of variables.
It is not allowed in Java.
They not numerical.
We cannot calculated them. Yes.
Okay.
So it is not allowed.
It's not only be necessary
for little subtraction, not allowed.
Multiplication not allowed.
We would not allow. Okay.
So it is not allowed on
and let's try to do
with characters. Okay
Char, one
equal to one two
is equal to
or equal
to two.
Let's try to perform
the same with the card.
One plus two.
So if I do this addition, I
see I don't get any errors.
That means the
plus is allowed on characters.
Okay, so what do you guys think?
What output what I will get
1 to 1 to
try. I got 99.
What is going on, guys?
I got 99.
I want me to
alphabets.
So let me tell you what is going on.
Actually,
these characters, these characters
instead of characters, your computers,
their store numbers
behind, and every character
that we store in each job.
So let's say, for example, if I see e
and if Book B,
and if I, if I execute this,
I get 114 right.
What is going on?
If I say
A and B,
and if I, if I see, I get 131.
Okay, So this chart is parting.
Yes, the equivalent.
So to understand what is going on,
let me show you something.
So behind every character
that we store in a jar
actually, Java stores and number
behind that, remember guys,
your computers,
they don't understand alphabets.
They don't understand pictures.
They don't understand videos.
They don't understand audio.
The only thing they understand
are numbers.
Okay? Computer only understand numbers.
So what happens
is that everything that we do
on our computers,
it is actually converted to numbers.
And then your computer performs
the processing.
Okay, So in here,
if you guys can see this table.
So this, this character E
instead of E, what Java is doing in
Java is actually storing 65
instead of E, Okay.
Instead, do you guys see this table then?
You go see this table.
Okay.
If not, let me let me show you the link.
So instead of here what Java is doing,
Java storing in number 65 behind it
instead of B,
Java is storing 66 behind it.
So what is 65 plus six?
Right?
Is 131.
So what the Java is doing?
Okay, Java don't know how to add A or
B, So Java, what is being
Java is converting it to 65, then B to 66,
then performing the calculation
and then showing you the results.
Okay, So each character. Okay.
And I think you can also
print emojis in here
if you know the proper behind emoji.
So all those emojis
that you guys see on your computers,
there are actually numbers
behind those emojis.
So if you know the numbers,
you can print out the emojis as well
your in your computer program. So
this is the
Oscar table that shows you
the actual numbers
that behind every character, the numbers
that are stored behind the characters.
Okay, so but don't get confused.
You guys don't need to memorize
these numbers.
You guys don't need to learn
about this mathematical operations.
You guys will never perform
a character
at a committee like adding two characters
or subtracting and things like that.
Okay,
so you guys don't need to worry about.
But sometimes
when you guys will be performing
some calculations, what happens
is that you guys might encounter
this issue
that you accidentally add a character
to a number of things.
Then you can get
some unexpected with this.
So I am just showing you
so that you guys don't get confused
or don't know, don't worry about this.
So let's let's try
to do the next try to do this
subtraction
and let's try
oops, strive
to do the oops
multiplication and then
if we separate out this one.
Okay, so I get 131 minus one 4290
and then zero
I get a different number
when I type small instead typically.
Okay. So now
if you focus on this ASCII table,
so far,
Java smaller, smaller is different.
The law,
it is different than the uppercase.
So if you focus in here this lowercase e,
it has a different number.
It has 97.
So lowercase is represented by 97,
uppercase is represented by a number 65.
That's why you get different results.
Is it clear
these are behind a hash symbol?
We have number 34 plus we have 43.
Okay.
So it shows zero after dividend
because it cannot store decimal bar.
Yes, it cannot support the decimal.
But you see behind every character
the numbers, they are integers.
Okay.
They are not decimals.
So we can perform automatic operations.
Okay.
On integers,
double characters and booleans.
Okay, let's
let's try to do the same with the strings
in next target.
All the same with strings.
Again, who is being
SDR one?
I see if we can
do the addition on
that spot.
Okay.
So yes, Javi's not giving me an answer.
Let me try to execute.
What answer?
I will get dice if I try to add
things.
The string concatenation, right?
Those things will be combined.
So I got by.
Right.
Let's let's try to check
if the subtraction is possible or not.
Okay. Yes.
So if I try to subtract two things,
I get an error.
Okay.
That means subtraction is not allowed.
Let's try to build multiplication.
It is also not allowed.
Yeah.
And the division is also not allowed
within slots.
So these are the four basic operations.
Nice that we can do
on these
primitive data types and the string.
Okay.
Are there any questions from this?
Let's try to understand
that fifth operation, that modulus
operation.
So if they are numbers and string,
it still would not do other
arithmetic operations?
Yes, it does not matter
what stored inside the string.
It does not care about that.
If something is not allowed,
then it means that
pink is not allowed.
So let's create one more class.
I could find that modulus operator
When I divide
r one with char two, I get zero.
Should I be getting there?
Yes, we should be getting zeros
because decimal parts are not allowed.
And don't worry about that
too much about that.
About the characters.
You guys will ever be performing this
this thing.
Okay.
Do the operations or characters
I just showed you so that you guys.
Yeah.
If at any point of time,
if you encounter
something like this, you are not confused,
are you going to share this note
with us? Yes.
I will be sharing all the notes,
all the code, everything that I am
showing, all slides, videos,
everything is available
to you.
Okay, let's let's understand the model.
So if I have a number
let's see,
do you guys know
the concept of remainder in mathematics
when we perform the division there is
one part is the answer of the division,
the other part is the remainder.
Right?
So if I say
if I try to do this,
so if I try to divide 20 with three
so I can say three, six are
18. Right.
What will be the remainder of this
calculation goes
to. Right.
So if you ever need to do this thing,
okay, if you ever need to do this thing,
then you can use this.
That is called modulus.
Operator.
If I say six out,
number one, modulus
number two.
Okay, I get this Commander.
So this modulus operator
actually gives you agreement.
It's that simple.
And anyone confused about this part
or maybe he or she don't know
what is the remainder
why we got the answer to all this.
Modulus is doing the same thing.
Oh, perfect.
So why doing percentage will get reminded.
Yes, percentage will be commander.
And I see.
Do you understand?
What are what are remainders
in mathematics?
So let me tell you in a different way.
So this, this, this or frontier sign
what it will try to do.
It will try to divide this number
in equal
parts and each part will be three.
So let's say, for example, if I change
this to five and then three, okay,
what if we reversed the variable?
I'm not I will tell you what happens if.
University variables.
Just give me one moment.
So if I change this 5 to 3,
what will be my remainder case?
The remainder again will be two.
Right?
So how this remainder is calculated.
So those who don't understand
this mathematical so are is doing
let's say these are these five numbers
of the one two, three, four, five.
So Java will try to combine these numbers
in the form of groups
and each group will three number.
So the five number represent is
represented by these five vertical lines.
So now I will pick first three lines.
It will create a group of it, okay.
It will create a group out of it in here.
And the if Java is unable
to create a group, the number of vertical
that are left behind,
it will it will give that as the answer.
Okay.
So this is how the
remember works. So let's say
you want
to divide something into equal parts,
okay?
You want to divide
something into equal parts.
And if something is on, is not
divide table in two equal parts,
okay, You are the remaining
of that calculation as your answer.
Then you can use the modulus.
So let's say, for example,
let me show you one more example.
Let's say if I change this
to nine,
what answer I will get now, guys.
Zero why I am getting zero?
Because
the Y I am getting zero
because now I have nine
vertical lines, one,
two, three, 419.
Right.
And Java is trying to group these
vertical lines into a group of three.
So Will creates one group
out of these three lines and another group
out of these three lines,
another group of alternatives.
Is there are there any lines left to guys
So three nine go three goes in to 911.
Right.
So no lines are left back a lot and that's
why you will be getting zero The answer
so you want to divide
something into equal parts.
If you want to divide
something in equal parts,
then you can use the modulus operator.
Okay?
And it will tell you if there are any left
or leftovers into number one.
Number two, one system number one.
Number two.
Okay.
Now, some of you are asking me,
what if they are the numbers?
If if we had reversed the numbers.
Okay If we reversed the numbers.
So if I am trying to take the models of a
smaller number with the greater number.
So if the number is smaller,
then the other number is greater,
you will always be getting
the smaller number as the answer.
Okay, so this is something
that is specific to programing.
So this is how modulus operator works.
So this is how it is defined.
Okay.
You will never ever be needing this
or you will never ever be doing this
because it does not make sense and
this is not how it works in mathematics.
So now but this is the behavior
that you will be getting.
Okay.
And so if I have someone
some of you were asking about one
and then one, then I will be okay.
You will get three. Okay.
So let me actually
let me put it in here for
so if I am trying to take the models
of a smaller number
with a bigger number,
I will always be getting the
smaller number as the body.
If I am taking
more or a
smaller
number with a
bigger number, I mean,
I will always get
smaller on
the as the.
So if I wanted the answer and
the remainder, how would I put into that?
Would I say percentage of size.
Okay so nice Let's say let's say you are,
you are
you want that mathematical operation.
Okay.
So you want this this behavior that I
if I divide this this 13 with five,
if I want this part
and this part bought so how can I get this
so far that
what you guys can do you can say
this out number one
divided by number to plug that answer part
and five repayment of arc
you can use the models. Okay
so now
this part I am getting in here
and this remainder
three, I am getting in here.
But remember I was percentage assigned
by division and getting the answer.
I use the division side, but again,
if the answer is decimal,
you will not get it unless you use double.
No Olga,
when you are using the
when you are using the in
integer type of calculations,
that decimal part,
it actually that remainder.
So let's say for example,
let's say for example, if I
if I wanted to
if I wanted to divide it completely.
Right.
So from the rules of mathematics,
this is what I will do.
I will do this right to
then then three
I will put a dot,
I will put a zero in here.
256 are 30.
This is how you will do it in mathematics,
right?
So yes, we are still getting that
that remainder part in here.
Right.
But we are now converting
that remainder part
actually in here to this three
with the help of this model.
Okay.
So it still works.
It's surrounded how get to 13 five, 2.6.
So Alexi has a question that
if I want to get 2.6, what should I do?
Right?
I don't want this.
Remember, I don't want this region.
I want that number.
I want the decimal part.
So if I have something like that,
if if these are the
requirements, I will change
my numbers to double.
Yeah. Okay.
And now if I execute my four.
Okay,
so now instead of two, I get 2.6.
Okay.
But I still get the remainder, same
as if I not the elementary integer.
Is this something
we will be using a lot in real world? Yes.
This modulus, it can solve
your very complex problem in minutes.
And there are so many interview questions.
There are so many testing interview
questions based on this modulus operator.
You guys will be using this modulus
operator a lot.
So try
ask me if there are any questions.
Ask me if something is not clear.
This modulus
woman interviewed for an interview.
Questions
are based on this modulus operator,
so make sure you guys understand it fully.
Is there anyone
don't understand this modulus operator
How it is working?
How does is related to mathematics?
Do you guys know about the even numbers
and the or numbers
or what are even numbers and or numbers?
So let's say if I have to find out
if a number is even then, but how can I
how can I find that
if that number
is completely divisible by two,
their number is even number right?
So how how can I find out if something
is completely divisible by two?
If the remainder of that number
with the two is zero, that means
that number is completely divisible.
So let's say, for example,
I have to find out
25 is an even number or number, right?
I will use a modulus, I will use to
and I will say that
I will say if I get the answer as zero,
the number is
even if I don't get the answer as zero,
the number is odd.
Okay,
so if I execute this, I get one right.
That means this is not an even number.
If a number is even,
I should get at the remainder as zero.
So six is an even number. Right?
If I take the one of six with two,
I get zero.
That means this number is even right.
I can I can test nine
again.
I get the answer when the number is 91.
So very complex problems
you can solve quickly
with this decimal back in mathematics.
You can find out
if a number is prime or not.
many other different things.
All right.
The modulus operator is clear, right?
So we can use the modulus operator with
We would double
as we can use the modulus operator
with integers
nine divided by three equals to zero.
So Fahad, if you want to find out
if something is even
or even or you never divided by three,
you always divide it by two, okay?
That's how you find it.
You always do it with two, not three.
Yes, definitely nine divided by three
doesn't it.
Does not have any remainders.
You will be getting zero.
So do we move forward base
and next next year
and new class?
It would be next thing
that we need to learn is.
And so the next thing
is the increment operator.
So let's say, guys, I have a number,
I have this number as the number one,
right?
If I,
I want to increase this value by a one.
So right now this number
variable contains ten
I want to increase it by one.
How can I do that?
I can do that by
adding one to this value, right?
So what I can say, I will say a number.
Okay, I will say a number
is equal to
number plus one.
Make it number.
So number two, a number
plus one.
So what is going on in here?
If I execute this quote, I see 11.
How many of you don't understand
what what what am I doing in here?
Is there anyone who
don't understand this part? I
it's perfectly
fine If you don't understand.
Understand something.
Tell me.
If you don't understand anything, it's
perfectly fine.
Even if you have 5% doubt, tell me
that you don't understand that 5%.
I am just typing.
So, Mustafa, my is.
I have written this line in here.
Line number eight.
Do you guys understand
what this line number eight is doing
and how it is doing?
So let me let me let me tell you.
So I have this box
and I have given this box
and name and number.
Okay.
So this is the box inside the memory.
I have this box.
And right now I have been
inside this box, right on this line.
What am I doing? I am saying
good job out there today. Allah,
give me whatever is stored
inside the box
so I can say okay, no issues.
It is this number ten.
This is what is stored inside this box.
Then I think that gave up
not only give me the number from that box,
but also add one to that value.
So number ten plus one
it is 11.
Okay.
The tired thing that I am saying,
I am saying, hey, Dollar store
this updated number 11 again
inside the same box.
So if you guys have understood
how about history.
how the values
are replaced in variables,
this should be simple.
So I have broken it down into three box.
So whatever I write after
this equal to sign,
let's see if I am writing.
So let's see.
Next.
Just give me one.
So if I said this So
I am saying to you I like up.
Please add number ten
with the number one
and whatever are the reserves
store those reserves inside this number
variable.
Okay.
But what I can also do
is that instead of directly
having that number,
my calculation,
I can use the variable instead.
Okay.
I can see number in here.
Now, whatever is stored that number
Java will now pick up that number.
It will do the calculations
and then it will store the reserves again
inside the same variable.
Okay, inside the same variable.
So that's why when I put in this number
before I have done these calculations,
I get the result. Then
once I have done this calculation,
I get results.
11 Okay.
Reassign
p value on the existing variable. Yes.
So speaking something from the box,
doing some kind of calculations
on the value
and then storing the
results back inside that box,
that is
how yes, the calculator is created.
Can we put a number plus number?
Yes, we can also do that.
So let's see now
I want to say
oops.
I want to say oops.
The number plus number. Right.
So what is stored
inside the numbers, Olga?
What is stored
inside the number online? Ten?
No, no, no.
I have updated the content.
I have updated the content on line number
nine.
After Java, execute line number nine,
I will have 11 instead of ten.
And if I do 11 plus 11,
what will be the answer?
It will be 22. Right?
So now
I will see. 22.
Okay, I will see 22.
Is it clear, guys,
how the calculations are working in here?
So to achieve this same thing,
it's kind of a longer
B, okay, it's kind of a longer double.
Guys have created something smaller.
Okay, You guys have
created something smaller. So
instead of writing number
is equal to a number plus one Java guys,
Java guys have done this.
So I say is if you only say
number plus plus.
So if you write the variable name
and then two plus signs,
then automatically one
the value of number.
Okay, whatever we have stored inside
number, it will be incremented by.
Okay.
It will have been selected by one.
But what was the value of number on line
11 guys?
Yes, it can be of
it can be addition, it can be
multiplication, it can be divided.
So if I increment it
number 22 by one, what?
Until I will get
I get it eight.
So I get quantity, so a variable name
and then two plus signs.
Okay, we will call it
the shorthand operator, the plus operator.
This operator, it increases
the value of a variable by one.
Is it clear guys?
Is there anyone who is confused?
So let's try to understand
other calculations.
Let's try to understand
So let's try how it became 23.
Okay.
How many of don't understand
how it became 23?
So, Mustafa, what do you think?
What should we d value instead?
Instead of going to three,
what do you think?
What should be the value in here?
Mine became two L Maryam,
you must be doing something about
number ten. Yes.
So. Mustafa Originally the number was ten,
then on line number. Line.
What did we do with the number
ten on line number nine?
What did we do with the number ten?
We incremented by one. Right.
So now the number n that we stored
initially has been changed to number 11.
Okay.
But 11 and after that after back
we performed another calculation.
We added number plus number.
What is stored inside the number?
It's now? 11.
So 11 plus another 11.
It's now 23, right?
So after line ten,
when I printed the value of number,
I got this 22.
Okay.
Then I changed it again.
This time I told the job that, Hey, Java,
can you please increment
whatever is stored inside that number box
any place incremented by one.
So previously there was 22 inside the box.
Right
now it has been incremented to 23.
Is it clear now?
So you'll get the
on line number nine.
You are trying to use a box number.
What do you do.
You you never declared that box number.
So so Java Java is confused Java thing.
I don't know.
What do you mean by number box
because you never declared it.
How did you increment to 23.
So you didn't use you.
You go see these two, these two
plus plus times these two plus signs.
That's how I tell you.
Java two incremented by one.
That's how I tell Java to increment it
by one.
So let's say, for example,
if I store them again in here.
Okay.
Yes. Not number.
Just just plus plus twice and
and it will incremented by one.
So let's say.
Yes, the minus minus eight also laughs.
I will teach you all of that.
Let's let's go step by step.
Okay.
Next step by step.
Maybe we need needed math lesson first.
I do not think we are using that much hard
math.
It's a simple addition.
Can we use four plus signs?
No, we cannot use four plus signs,
so I don't think so.
We can use four plus.
You will be getting into the.
There is no such thing as four plus signs.
Okay.
Only two things. Yes.
So number
plus plus it actually means number
is equal to number plus one. Okay.
So when we write number
plus plus, actually, we are doing this.
Actually, we are doing this.
So I am saying number plus plus.
So I stored number ten
inside the number box.
Okay.
And then I am saying number plus plus.
So what what output I will get
if I print this value in here guys.
11. Right.
So ten if we increment the ten by one,
we get 11 right.
It's simple.
So I get 11, I get 11.
Let's let's create one more class
and let's create one more class.
Let me know once you guys have this code
and you are ready to when you are ready
to create a new class, okay
So let's try to understand what kind of
other operations I can perform.
Okay?
So if I have an integer number, then okay,
so now you guys help me understand
how everything is working.
So if I say number
is equal to number
plus number plus some,
and if I say number,
what output
I will guys, what answer I will get
40, right?
So what I am doing,
I am saying, hey, Java, whatever is stored
inside the number box, add it to again
whatever is stored in the box number.
Then again, do the same, then again
do the same right.
So and then finally I am saying store
the results back to number variable.
If I do this right, if I do this in number
number two, well, what answer
I will get now
to think about advice.
Don't don't don't make guesses.
Think about this.
What I am saying on line number
eight to Java.
What am I saying online Number eight I am
I am saying Java.
Give me a box okay.
And let's call that box number and store
ten inside that box
on line number nine, I am saying,
hey, give me the value from that box
again.
I am saying give me the value
from that box.
Add these two.
Then again, add the result
with again with the same box and again
with the same box and store preserves
inside number two box.
Right.
But in here I am asking
Java to put into the value of number.
Have I ever change the content of number?
Did I ever updated
the value of variable number?
I didn't update that value ever. Right.
So if it had ten previously,
it still it has ten,
but still it has been
because I never updated the variable.
So I never updated this variable.
The calculation that I am doing in here
I am storing in a new variable,
and the name of that variable
is number two.
I never change,
I never updated the value in here.
Yes, I
created a new value, write a new variable.
So that's why.
Is there
anyone who still don't understand?
Why I am getting ten in here.
Okay, so if I change
this to number,
I get 40.
All right, so what if, guys if I say
number is equal to number
plus one
plus ten
plus 20,
which truncate
and then I try to devalue
new value
does not print.
If it has updated the value
birds fly, we see
we see 90.
Okay.
So Obama was saying 6000.
Why is it clear why you are getting 90?
No, no, not 60.
Is it clear now
or do you want me to explain it?
Actually,
we have taken the number in here as well.
Again, why after this line,
the value is 40, not ten.
Okay. Looking okay.
All right, guys So you guys understand
how variables, values can be updated.
So let me store of books.
Let me call back.
Be well, you've been invaded
and this time let me say
a number is equal to number
minus number.
Okay.
And then let me print out today.
So what answer I will get nowadays.
Zero. Right?
So ten minus ten is zero, right?
Then -20 zero.
Okay, Stop me. Stop me right there.
If anyone of you is confused
about these things,
you will be using them a lot
throughout your getting it okay.
Heavily in loops.
Loops are very widely used.
Okay, let me store number ten
back in here.
Okay.
And this time let me do
number is equal to number
multiplied by.
So we're doing guys thing.
What will be the answer in here
if I say number again,
it's under track.
And if I say individual
word answer, I will get
excellent,
super simple.
Let me score number
then back in here.
So as we have again, we go a little slow.
I cannot catch you. Yes, I see.
You guys can always stop me.
Let me know when you have time to score.
It's very important.
I know a normal human can not type
and then listen and can understand
all of that in the same time.
So you guys can always talk me.
We can't catch you at all. Even me.
It does not stop you.
It slows you. So guys.
So you guys have to tell me if I am going
fast, right?
Otherwise, I will not.
I will never know
if you guys are unable to catch me.
You guys have to stop.
So Alex is saying don't go slower.
Okay?
Maybe things are boring for Alex
ten times rapidly.
It's too much.
So ten times repeated it's too much.
Okay, so, Alex, maybe do you have
some programing background.
Pretty much we doing math
with the value of variable, which is in
this case is a representative.
But then
okay, then maybe, maybe you are good
with computers and programing and
if you do, that's also good.
So guys, if you have time
and you can spend like
10 to 15 minutes,
maybe you should try to use YouTube
or Google or other sources to to learn
about programing.
It will help you a lot because
let me tell you this, 80
to 90% of the times on
on your jobs while doing programing,
you guys will be using StackOverflow
or Google
to find out solutions to find out
about the issues that you will be facing.
So it's a very important technique.
It's a very important tool
to have in your toolbox.
Okay, who knows how to search
material on Google
or how to find resources online.
It will help you a lot.
We can also discuss it with each other.
Yes, definitely. Guys try to have
groups,
try to create groups with each other.
Try to discuss things with each other.
And let me tell you this.
This network of
videos is it can be
very beneficial for you in future.
So let's say, for example,
some of you get good jobs in in Google,
Amazon or Tesla
or in some other companies.
Right.
And let's say
if they have some kind of openings
and if you guys are if guys
have friends,
so maybe you can recommend each other
for good positions.
Right?
So let's say some of you get a degree
and and some of you will be getting 120.
And if you guys have this relationship
with each other,
if you guys are friends of each other,
you can always read for each other.
Right?
It will really boost your career.
Ask how to do your name seven times.
It's not really normal.
So, Alexa, think about me.
If you are on my position, I know.
What will you do with these students?
If they are asking you to seven times to.
To tell.
To tell them how to rename something.
Please.
If anyone get a job in Tesla,
you out from class,
please refer to me.
Why I cannot in
the last line.
So Mustafa, try to write, click
and then click on Daniel code
and then shared a screenshot.
You should be getting the last line
as the output
or you are printing on the same line
ten years later.
Hello. Who?
I am sorry.
We're doing it from Orlando.
So let's let's, let's move forward.
So as we have that
plus plus operator that increment
the value of a variable via one,
we also have that decrement.
Operator. We also have a decrement.
So let's say if we have a number ten
and if I want to decrement value by a one,
then I will write two minus signs
after that number.
And then if I say yes, I'll
then I will get
nine because ten DICLEMENTE
two by one is nine.
Okay, So same as plus
plus that increments the value by one.
It decrements devalue the minus minus
DiClemente material.
And let's try to check
if we have multiplication.
Multiplication. Operator Okay.
So as soon as have less plus, minus,
minus, let's, let's check
if we have multiply multiply.
So if I say multiply multiply,
I get then add it.
Okay,
That means it is not supported by Java.
Okay, Multiply.
Multiply is not supported by Java
and then left by total number.
Divide. Divide number. Division. Division.
Okay. Yeah. It is also not possible.
It's also not possible.
And if we see modulus modulus, okay.
Or even a single modulus, it is also not
allowed.
Not allowed.
Yes. Only plus and only increment
only decrement.
All right.
Any questions?
Right.
Next, let's learn something new.
Let's create one more class.
So let's declare again they and be able
volunteer
in their store and in here.
So we learned that
when we do, number is equal to number
plus one,
why can't increment
plus one when you do number
plus number plus number plus plus plus.
So do you mean you are to give me one?
Remind me after this example,
I will explain this to you.
So if I am doing something,
if I, if I doing this
and if I am doing this,
am I doing the same things or
am I doing different things?
So this thing that I
am doing in here, I am saying
whatever value is stored,
add one to it
and updated contents of number.
Right?
And the second thing I am again
saying increment the value by one.
Right?
So they are same in here.
Value will be maintained
by one in here as well.
The value will be implemented by one.
Right.
So if I,
if I printout it
and if I bring this out of course
in here
again, same address
then incrementing by 1 to 11,
then incremented by 1 to 12.
Okay, so they are same thing.
So this this number plus plus.
So you can't do both at once.
Give me we can do both at once as well.
Okay.
But there actually are a loss.
I don't want to confuse you.
There is a there is a concept of pre
increment and post increment.
So you are right now trying to use that
in your in that example.
I will actually show you
it on, on the review class.
Think that's why I'm not discussing it
with you the step by step.
Okay.
But if I forget to remind me.
Okay, I will definitely tell you.
So guys they are actually same things.
This plus plus operator.
It's actually a short divergence
of achieving same result when we do this.
Okay.
So that's why they are called
shorthand operators.
But in here, if I say plus two
instead of plus one, if I say plus two,
am I still doing the same thing? No.
Right.
So now I am not doing the same thing.
In this example,
I Am incrementing the value by two
in here
I am incrementing the value by like,
okay, so this
so this is actually a shorthand of
this is actually
a little shorter way of
doing this.
I can look right this.
So this plus plus is actually a shorter
way of doing a number is equal to number
plus one.
Okay.
Now if I am in incrementing the value
of a variable
by number two or three
or four or any other number
other than one, then you run it
with to see what happens, you should. So
ten was incremented to 12.
It was incremented by two.
Then we incremented it by one. Okay.
So in one case
we are incrementing it by two.
In the other case
we are implementing it only by one.
Okay. So then they are different.
It is clear. Yes.
Plus plus only increments by one. Yes.
When we will.
Oh I am coming to that point
which is like number two.
So if I am doing something like this
if I am incrementing the value.
So let's say I stored ten in here
and if I say number is equal to number
plus, let's say I may be 30, Right.
So is it also possible that we have
some kind of shortcut for this?
Okay.
So yes, as we have this shortcut
to achieve the
same result, but in a shorter syntax,
we have a shortcut
to achieve this in a shorter syntax
as well.
Right.
And that shorter syntax is number
plus equal to 30.
It's the same
as doing this.
It's the same as playing this. Okay.
This is called plus equal to operator.
So if you are only implementing the value
by one, you can use this sort of syntax.
If you are ending the value
by some bigger number,
maybe 1 to 10000 million,
you can use the shorter syntax,
but this time instead of
plus plus you will say plus
equal to and the number by which
you want to increment your variable.
Okay.
So in here by how much
I am incrementing my variable dice
initially, how
I had been by
how much I incremented the value in here
part B so then incrementing by 30 will be
40, right? 40.
And if I implement the 40 again
by 30 using this shorter syntax,
what answer
I will get. Now
78. So I get 70.
So they are just shorter
ways of doing the same things,
get shorter ways of doing the same thing.
When I say number plus number 30,
instead of writing the longer syntax,
I can see a number plus equal to 30
short of syntax of doing the same thing.
Is it confusing guys, or is it easy
to understand?
Easy right?
When I say plus plus, increment
the value by one.
When I say plus equal to
and then I specify
a number, increment
the value of that variable by that number
mine is 72.
Can you share the screenshot
also in the sports channel?
Sheeba, I will help you out.
All right.
Now, now let's try to understand
when you don't make the instructions
system, don't out print.
It will not show,
but the instruction is stored in Java.
Right?
Is there any instance where you are
would not need to print a line?
Yes, certainly not.
There will be a lot of instances
when you will not be printing a value,
but you will still be doing
the calculations
you guys will learn about.
Just just wait for the,
I guess, next class.
Also, you will learn about that.
Okay.
So guys, with this plus plus
incrementing the value
by one, incrementing the value by one,
it was possible,
but multiplying the value by one or two
in dividing the value by one,
it was not possible using that plus plus.
Right.
Using that plus plus.
So I cannot say number multiply. Multiply.
I cannot say number.
Divide, divide. Right.
So in here somewhere I show you
in the last example, I guess
we do that example here.
So number multiply, multiply not allowed,
number divide by let's try to out
if we have something for this shorter
margin in here as that so far
this operator plus plus and minus
I cannot do multiply multiply and divide
to at least by to check
if I can do this ten in the multiplication
and division.
So let me store number ten back
and let me try to do number
minus equal to fight.
So tell me the output base
what output I will get
like five right?
I am saying decrement
the value of this number by five.
Right.
So I am left with five.
Let me check
if it is if it is possible to do the same.
But instead of minus
instead of subtraction,
let me check if it is possible
to do the multiplication.
So I store number ten back.
I say in number
multiply equal to five.
I am not getting any errors.
That means it is allowed. Right.
But let's see what output I will get.
I will get three results as 50.
Right.
Then multiply it by 5055.
Let's try to do the same file division.
If it is allowed for the same 50
so and
divide by five.
So what answer I will get right.
So right.
So I get two. Okay.
So it is allowed with the multiplication.
It is also allowed for division and it is
also allowed for subtraction addition,
but incrementing by one and discriminating
by one using plus plus minus minus.
It is only allowed with minus
and plus not with multiply.
And do we
are there any question this
or I would think is clear
you guys just need practice.
All right.
Let's let's let me check
if we are missing something. So
all we have
we have forgot about the remainder.
Next, try to build the remainder as the
quote answer.
I will get two days for the remainder. One
zero.
Right.
Easy peasy.
So I can do this with the maintenance.
So a shorthand operator is a shorter way
to express something
that is already available in.
Java programing.
Okay, so you clear,
but give us five minute to copy the code.
Yes, sure.
So let me name
this.
Yeah.
And let me know what
you guys have copied it.
We know once you guys are done
writing this,
then let's go to slide.
And guys, when I am painting something,
don't focus on typing that with me, okay?
Always focus on what I am saying
because you can get all of this code
from canvas, you can get all the notes
from canvas, you will have recordings,
but if you miss some contact concepts,
then that's important.
If some if you are unable to type
something, if you are unable to follow me,
just leave it there, okay? No issues.
You can practice it later.
You can fold it up.
But focus on how much.
Focus on what I am saying.
How do you create this
second window in the case?
Okay,
so if you want to create multiple windows
in here,
so let's
say you have two classes opened in here
and you want to split the day view,
you can just drag it
and you can place it
in the second window like this.
That's how you split it.
So let's check if we are missing
something from this slide.
So a shorthand operator is a shortcut way
to express
something
that is already available in upload on me.
If you are you,
you can already do something
in the longer, longer way.
Right.
So guys have created some shortcuts
for you that you can use there.
They are called shorthand.
Shorthand operations.
Do not any feed add
any feature to Java programing language.
Look at them.
They are just making your life
a little easier by introducing this
shorter operator.
All right. So
with your
wrappers, you will
also be getting direct homework from me.
Okay, so I will be posting these homeworks
in the course on our Smart Channel
and I want you to complete these
before coming to the next class.
Okay?
And then in the next class.
First, I will revise all of the concepts
that I have taught
and then I will solve
these homeworks for you so that you guys
can compare your solutions with mine
and you can find out if you have done it
in the proper way
or not yet before tomorrow.
So don't worry.
If you are unable to solve
some of the homeworks,
it's fine.
And one more thing guys.
Let's say, for example,
the instructions are not clear.
So you are trying to read something
and it is not making sense.
You are unable to understand what to do.
Are you updated
the due date for the homework?
No, I will be updating them later on.
Okay. So don't worry about that.
Who is going to be
instructor tomorrow as is?
Yes, she has got the code
I just confirmed with her.
And even though I guess he was vaccinated,
but each day she's
she is saying that she is getting
some kind of new symptoms.
So I don't know.
I'll bear discoveries.
I will just say, you guys, please be safe.
Okay?
Don't get that clever thing you should do.
She is getting new symptoms.
I think she will need an extra
one more week to get until to recover.
So please try to stay at cold.
Try to be safe.
All right, guys.
So I was saying,
if something if
if there is a confusion,
if something is not clear,
you can send you can write it
in this syntax for channel.
Maybe you you can say their task
that I don't understand.
What do you mean?
Write a Java program?
I don't understand
what is meant by Java program.
Can you please clarify that? Okay.
So if statement is not clear,
if there is any ambiguity in that,
you can always post in this
and try to complete them before class.
Is it possible to get the media files
from this class when I will be available?
Yes. The video files are already available
on the canvas.
Sandy.
The PDF files The North Beach
Java Code recording
Everything is available.
Where do we post homework?
So Alona, you post your homeworks
in the syntax student channel.
Then I will go to those homeworks.
Then I will solve those homeworks again
during the class
and then you guys
can compare your situation with mine.
So let me post work in the course
and answer questions.
Okay,
So spin class
string concatenation arithmetic operators.
Okay, There is one more thing
that I want to show you that is important
and that can also confuse you.
So. So those tell me
if I do this.
And plus, then
first
and I'll put out what I mean that
yes, you guys have to post in export
earnings that
what about the second line
but what output will again
the same output for both lines.
I mean I mean will
it always add ten into ten
and then it will concatenate it or what
what what will happen.
So let me let me surprise you a little bit
so far.
The first one
the first one
goes, So Java
code executes from top to bottom
and from left to right,
okay, from left to right.
And the Java performs
one operation at a time.
Okay? One operation at a time.
So Java executes
the start execution from here to here.
It sees this line.
Java will pick these two numbers
and it will try to perform this operation.
So ten plus ten is equal to 20.
Then it sees another operator,
the plus operator,
then it picks the next operation.
It can continue as it would be.
Hello.
Okay, so I see this result 20 plus.
Because first two numbers
were both integers when we when the both
numbers are integers is what happens
and the work numbers are integers.
And if I'm using the plus operator,
the addition
happens as in the mathematics, right.
So once I have ten plus, then I get 20,
then I have 21 integer
and other one as the string.
Now I am trying to add
a string with a number.
So will it perform the addition
or the concatenation?
Concatenation. Right.
Whenever I have a string with a number
and I am using the plus operator happens.
That's
why I see 20 concatenated with hello.
But in here I have this.
Hello.
And then this plus. And then the stent.
So what will happen?
Will it do the
addition or be concatenation
again.
Concatenation. Right.
So hello.
Last bend will be
Peloton.
Is is this. Hello.
Is it a string or a number.
If something in a string right,
then continuation operation
always gives you a string.
So again I have this result of alternation
and then I am doing ten.
So again will do the kind of attention
or the addition.
Again, concatenation. Okay.
That's why I get Hello, ten, ten, five,
this and 20.
Hello for this.
So if you guys want to avoid this
you can use in PCs.
That is what happens when
when we use parentheses in mathematics.
If I am doing a lot of calculations
on the same line in mathematics,
multiplication and addition,
and if I put parenthesis
it prioritize it right,
it gives it priority.
So now on this line,
before anything can happen,
this ten will be added with ten.
First it gives it the priority
and then we can get will happen.
So Now I will get
20. Hello and help 20.
Okay. Yes, that rule of mathematics.
BMD Yes, thank.
Okay. So we can use that in here.
All right.
So let's call it a day day.
Okay?
If you guys have any questions,
can post in the syntax support
can always post in the syntax board
so that everyone can benefit from that.
Let's say
maybe you are encountering facing some.
It is quite possible
that other class fellows,
they will also be facing the same issue.
So instead of sending direct messages,
always posting this Porcello
Go ignore it.
We covered two classes today,
one for today and one for missing one.
It was a bit overwhelming.
No, we didn't cover two classes.
We covered only the class.
Number two. Today, it was only one
tomorrow will cover the typecasting.
If statements and if statements
copy.
So no, no.
There are wrappers for today as well. So
you see this string concatenation.
Now you guys should be able
to solve this thing configuration.
All this, that automatic arithmetic,
blah, blah, blah.
So you guys
should be able to file wrappers.
Bill number 70
and you go back to create sequences.
Yeah, sure.
So guys try to now solve the
that both bill number 70.
Okay And also
you have the homeworks
plus I will be sharing the slides
for tomorrow's class introduce you have
that as well
and a 5 to 10 minutes video
so a lot of our quality what to look
at all of this is due to model
nerdy wrappers not the wrappers
this homework
that I have posted the course
and all sports channel that is only due
by tomorrow
and you please
upload notes from today's class.
Yes, I will upload it right away
after this class already take some rest.
Okay.
And let's meet tomorrow.
Bye Bye.
Thank you. Take it.