Your favorite thing in
programing is two nasty things, right?
You you nested if conditions inside the
if you then nested the loops.
And today we are going to nest arrays.
Arrays inside other areas.
And these nested arrays
one area inside another added
They are called to the arrays.
Two dimensional arrays.
Have you heard this word?
Two dimensional.
Three dimensional.
What does it mean?
If something has three dimension
or two dimensions,
or even one dimension?
Columns and rows?
Yeah.
So usually this is how we understand
a line is one dimensional, right?
Every one.
A line is one dimensional.
Usually we're denoted with X, right?
But if we have one more line,
another coordinate,
then we call it to rhyme or flex and y.
And then we have Z dimension as well.
Something that has dropped as well.
So one de add
is that we have been creating.
And they, they, they grow linearly, right?
We keep on adding the elements
and they keep on storing the elements.
Element number one,
two, three, four, five.
And if we increase the size,
it will keep on growing like
this linearly linear fashion.
What if I add more?
Add is water actually adds well like this.
So this is how it would be added.
Looks like my combination of multiple
one degrees.
This is a two dimensional.
This is what we will be creating today.
So this is adding number zero.
This is adding number one.
This is adding number two.
And this is adding number three.
And this one is the zeroth element
element
on index number zero inside at a zero.
This one is element only at index.
Number one inside to add is zero two,
three, four,
five, six.
And then similarly,
this one is 012, three.
Maybe I should open in an Excel five.
I think it will be easier
to visualize that three.
So this is what we have been doing, right?
Creating arrays like this.
And then we say,
okay, this is element number zero
one, two and three, right?
Everyone understands this part.
And then we have been storing
multiple items inside these adds, Right?
Let's say, for example,
we can put the names on
something like this, right?
This this was our one D addy
or normal addy.
And from this area,
if let's say I want to access
this,
my let's say this at a is called era.
The name of the area is era.
So let's see if I want access.
It's my How can we do this in one day?
We can write the name of the area
and then two square brackets
and then the index.
And it will give us this element.
Everyone understands this.
This was how one D at a
or simple areas work.
But imagine now
you have multiple
arrays stacked like this.
It will be very similar to
how a metrics looks like.
And let's say you are storing some
other names here and.
And we are.
So look at this, Addy.
And these number.
Zero. One, two, three.
I'm simply writing these indexes for your.
So that you can understand easily.
Is it okay if I remove these indexes?
Will you be still be able to know
that in this zero index?
Michelle is one.
Okay.
Let me do this.
This is how I do the array looks like.
Are you still able to visualize that?
It is a combination of multiple one D
arrays.
Okay, perfect.
So this is adding number zero.
This is add in number one.
This is that number two.
And this is adding number three.
Okay, let me put the number in here.
And this is the zero index for added zero.
This is one.
This is two.
And this is three.
All looks good.
These numbers here, they represent
you can call the represents.
The individual ADD is all you use.
If you want to understand from a matrix,
this numbers here, these ones,
they represent rows.
And these ones they represent columns.
Now tell me, are this Bob?
This Bob in which area?
Tell me the index of the area
in which added this Bob is present.
Give me the index of the added.
This Bob is present inside the array,
which is at index number two.
Right.
And if we look at the column,
it is the column number one.
So if we want to get to Bob
and next again,
let's say we are again
saying the name of the areas, Ada.
Okay.
So tell me this.
If I have the name of the array as IRR,
I mean, the one D added,
we use one square bracket and to the array
because there are rules and columns,
we will be needing two square brackets.
This is the
this is how the syntax for the area works.
So here,
if I tried to call my one
and this will give me Bob.
Okay. Now tell me, how can I get John?
Tell me the indexes.
Let's say I have I an area.
What should I put inside this
good breakfast for John?
Exactly. One
and three.
Is there anyone who
who does not understand how writing are?
One and three will give us John.
Okay.
If I want to get to the hand.
Zero zero.
Exactly.
Row number zero, Column number zero.
Then give us a
all could help everybody.
So that was it for today's class.
We just wanted to go over the two areas.
You guys were really quick to understand
how good the areas were.
So let's call it a day.
And now you can start
working on your project.
No, you guys don't believe
that.
Okay.
Let's try to next try to write a program.
Let's try to do coding for this.
Okay.
So let me do this.
Let me copy this exact same metrics.
And let's go to our intelligence
and let's try to write it.
So E one to the
is so
and then we have to create one diary.
We what?
What what is the syntax? What do we write?
Then when we have to create one zero,
what do we specify first?
That type.
So if I want to store these names,
what should be my data type?
Exactly.
String.
And after the data type, what to specify
square bracket.
If if it is
if I'm planning to create one the array.
How many square brackets?
I have to specify how many pairs one.
If I want to create to the area,
I will be needing two square brackets.
Actually, two pairs.
And then
the name of the area,
which in our case is named.
And then when we create one, the area,
how many curly brackets we need?
One pair. Right.
What do you think To create to the array
how many pairs we will be needing
at least two.
Right.
And if I have more rows,
I will be needing more.
So for the first row, I need one.
So let me do it like this
so that it's easier to visualize.
So let me copy this here
and let me be straight here
and why I'm getting an error.
Give me one second
double code.
So let me put it over here.
Do we need a comma as well?
Do we need a comma as well? Yes.
Okay, perfect.
Okay, let's now, everyone, let me know.
Once you are done following me,
then I will copy the next row
or I can share it with you.
Don't type.
I initiated with you once one time to
let me copy this.
Let me be a strategic. So
actually,
I think it's better if we go one by one.
So this is our one we added.
Right?
Curly brackets
and then comma separated names.
Now what I can do,
I can copy this one to add it
like this control C
and then we can see control.
We okay.
And we need one comma here as well
and then one more comma
and we can copy paste it one more time.
One more time
line with the copy paste or more.
So look, guys,
if you look only at this part
is it one any
the the part that I have
highlighted. Yes.
This is one more one.
The addy.
This is one more one. The addy.
This is the one more.
And all of those one, the areas,
they are also separated by comma.
No, we don't need
because there are two square brackets.
Because there are two square brackets.
That means there is a two Daddy.
So let me put those rows and columns again
so that you can visualize better.
So this is how it was looking like in
an Excel.
Okay.
Exactly the same thing.
And this is odd adding number zero.
This is our ADDY number one.
This is our ADDY number two
and this one is three.
Similarly, this was the index number zero
one, two and three.
Take 2 minutes, digest this,
and then we will move forward.
And meanwhile,
let me put some different names
here.
Well, it has to start with my formatting.
Almost old.
Oh, okay.
So if we want to go to the elements,
let me now remove this.
We almost all
get let me put it back here.
So look, when we have to create
two D areas, we need one curly bracket.
One pair of curly brackets
drawn is duplicated
with are okay
one pair
to hold multiple one
we added for example,
this one is a complete one B addy
and what is duplicated.
Okay, let me make it
John. And
so and then we have again
one more complete one.
We add it here, then one more.
If you guys can pay this attention
that you pay on the spellings and
the duplications of name, on programing,
on the concepts that I'm teaching,
believe me, you can learn a lot better.
And then this is one more one D Addy
So basically
one pair of curly brackets
to store multiple one B adds.
And here
when we have to create one together,
we write one pair of square brackets
to the two.
By the way,
there are three dimensional areas as well,
four dimensional five dimension.
You you can create as many dimensions
as you want.
There is no element five dimensional
that is ten dimensional.
That is no, we are not going to love that.
If you can digest this just to the areas.
And then
I think it's going to be more than enough.
Okay, Now let's try to get the elements
from the story.
Addy okay.
Are you able to create 2D areas?
Are you getting any syntax errors
or something?
Do you want to share this one with you?
Negotiate this all the is.
I think it's better that you created
everyone.
Let me give you 5 minutes.
Please create everyone.
Please clear this area.
I want you to go through
at least once through the syntax.
I will wait.
Please clear it on your.
Thank you, Eric.
Okay.
Is there anyone who is still typing or
need more time?
Okay, fine.
Okay.
By the way, those who are done typing,
what do you think work out?
What would be the applications
of this to the addy?
Have you seen that scored
somewhere in real life?
Very similar
to how we are storing the data.
Anatoly. Eric,
can you give me some examples?
Have you seen data stored?
Excel Perfect.
Perfect.
In Excel
we have exactly the same thing, right?
Rows and columns.
No, I'm not typing.
I'm just discussing would be one source.
We are done.
What else?
Layout of lottery numbers.
Okay.
Parking lots.
Exactly. Yep.
So you can write programs
for all of those things
which stored the data in this format.
Name of the students.
Have you, have you played tic tac toe?
Yes, exactly.
Do you guys know how pictures are stored?
How pictures are stored on the computer
into the arrays?
Actually, in 3D areas.
But a very similar idea.
Let me show you.
This is how the how the pictures are.
This is how your computer draws pictures
on the screen.
So your screen is actually divided
into grids.
Like, for example,
when you say my screen resolution is 1920
by ten DPI, do you
do you mean what you are talking about?
Well, what are these 1920 cross penalty?
These are actually the number of pixels,
number of rows and columns
in your screen that represents each pixel.
And this is how pictures are drawn on
two D in a computer
by manipulating these pixels.
Like for example, if you want to move
these things, you will be actually moving
the pixels.
Let me see if
there is a visualization
or something.
It's just going to be complex for you
at this point.
But once I have, once I'm done
explaining to the arrays,
you will start getting
the idea how things are,
are how images are stored.
Basically, they do that
also stored in the areas and a lot of time
they are also processed in the form of
that is your videos are also
a combination of multiple.
Now ADD is pretty arrays so
video is actually multiple nested images.
They are just pixels.
When a specific color code are assigned.
Yes, exactly.
Okay, everybody.
So I hope now everyone is done.
So now just try to learn how
this is one of the ways
of creating the duty.
Add it just like we have two ways
of creating one diary.
This is one of the ways where we create
the array and initialize it right away.
And now we will learn
how we can access the
elements from this to the area.
So tell me if I
want to access John Hammond.
Plus, obviously I will be
needing to write the name of the array
and then to the brackets.
What should I specify here and here?
If I want to access this element?
Okay. Some are saying to two,
some are saying one and zero.
Let me let me label them for you.
I think you're confusing you.
This is zero.
This is one.
This is two, This is three.
So immediately this is zero one,
two and three.
Now tell me
if I want to access this element here.
What should I write here and here?
Is everyone now clear that
it should be two comma, two.
Okay, let me write to here and to here.
And there's next Romney again.
Let's see what we get.
Okay, so this is what we get.
Okay, Now
tell me if I am interested in the dummy.
What should I.
So this will give us
and duplicate it
if if we want to get I mean
in which
in which add a
dummy image present is present
inside the add
which is at index number one
and within that area
is actually the last element
which will be zero one,
two and three.
This will give us dummy.
Is there anyone who does not understand
how this ad is being created
and how when we write these two
square brackets and this number,
we are able to get these names?
Okay, let me copy this class
and let's try to access these elements
with the help of a loop.
But before that,
I want to show you something.
So control C control we
need to
Mohammad actually,
because now your basics are done
and now things will start to repeat.
Well, that's what I was saying to you,
that your initial days,
they can be very hard
because there's a lot of information
you have to learn
how this interface of IDE works,
how discard our how syntax versus new
information, new class members, friends.
So then a lot of information is thrown
at you in a short period of time.
It's hard for a human brain
to to digest all of that.
Now you have big debate
now, things will start to sense more.
Can you show it one more time?
Yeah, hear it is
They have to practice again
and I know project will definitely be a
what is the
new act up what is new
Jerusalem.
Can you tell me the line number?
Where do you see new.
Because what I'm stuck right now
are are the nested for loops
and if I slowly it will get worse.
So I mean it will get better.
No interesting.
Okay, so everybody is done.
Are we are we going for the next example?
Okay.
So if I ask you what is a 2D?
What is a 2D
two dimensional space?
Okay.
Offsprings it can be of any data type.
Exactly.
And add it inside another adi
or nested is.
So what do you think?
Is it
possible to extract this complete fast
one d area from the study area?
If a 2D array
is nested ad is or
an ad inside another ADI?
What if I do something like this?
What if I say names
and zero?
What do you think?
What this will give me?
Let me do this
string
buster. All
and scattered records here.
What do you think?
If I say names,
This is the name of the 2D Adi.
And then I'm saying square brackets.
I'm not specifying two pairs.
I'm specifying only one,
and I'm specifying zero.
This basically represents
this complete, complete
one D adi.
And let me also
print it so that you can visualize it.
So add is dot to string
and let's say cluster. So
and let's run it.
I want you to take 2 minutes
and go to this line.
What this line is doing
here, it's very important to understand
all the areas, what has happened here.
How many of you don't understand
what has happened here?
I said names.
The name of the to the Adi,
and then I only specified
one square bracket and then I specified
zero there
and in a result what I got,
I got this complete
one, the ADI
from here.
And let me let me let me show
you more things.
What do you think?
If I let let me change it to simply
or let's call it zero.
If I put this if I put one here,
what do you think?
What I will get
it will give us the address of the ADI.
So if I run this now,
I get complete secondo.
So are you.
Are you able to get the idea
that when we write it to the ADI,
the first two square bracket,
the number that we put inside
the first letter bracket,
what does it represent?
It represents the complete roll at that
index.
Let me repeat the number
that we specify in first Oscar bracket.
It represents the complete
roll at that index.
Okay.
And once I have that complete roll again,
for example,
coming out of this, if I say
if I say
let me let me change this to only roll.
So that is easier to understand.
So if I say roll and then square bracket,
so so first
I get the complete roll at index one
and then from that roll I'm
getting the zero two element
on roll.
Number one, what is the zero element?
What is the value of zero element?
This is complete roll
present at index number one.
Everyone understands this.
When we say names one,
we basically refer to the complete roll
at first index.
And this.
John what is the index of this? John
It's zero.
Exactly.
So when I will be running this,
I will go to John.
Is there anyone who do not understand
why we are getting done
all good?
Okay,
if I do, let's say two here
and three here, Tell me what output
I will get
exactly.
We will be getting Muhammad, for example,
we are saying two here, right?
So this is zero.
This is one, This is two.
So this will give us this complete
one, the ADI here.
And then from this
one, the area I am saying the roll
and then inside the square brackets
and specifying three. So this is zero.
This is one, this is two
and this is three.
Okay, tell me one more thing.
If you have one D adi complete one D area,
can you also write a
loop to get all the elements
to print all the elements?
Sorry.
Yes, we can do that right.
So is it okay if I write the loop here?
Will it confuse you
if I write the loop here?
Okay.
So help me write down the loop
to print all the elements from this rule.
Help me write down a loop. Should I.
Should I prefer the enhanced for loop
or the index index
based for loop
enhanced one is better.
So we write for
and then what should be the data type?
What type of data is present
inside this one D area?
It's a string
nursing name,
colon, and after the colon,
what should I specify
which variable contains the complete
one D addy?
What is the name of that variable
in our program?
I'm saying
one D at one D Which variable contains the
one D addy
this names?
Is it one D this names?
Is it one day or two D
is said to be
this row?
Is it one day or 2d1d
so it should be a row here.
Makes sense.
And then let's see.
Name.
What do we expect?
What do we expect from this loop Work
this loop blueprint
And do you expect that
all of the elements from this
role will be printed?
The one that I have highlighted?
Exactly.
So let's run this
to look.
We get all the names here, okay?
Those who want to follow me
or want to write this code,
I will give you 2 minutes.
Please let me know once you are done
and is there anyone who do not understand
you are missing the input?
Most probably
you do so.
So everyone understands that to add is
are nothing but multiple one d ad is
every one to the ad is
simply multiple
one d areas combined together
in will put together in one variable
and do you also understand
name role output second rule?
I do not indicate name rule
for the second rule.
Where is second rule
easier than one D?
Maybe because you understand
D okay, who can help Ali.
Ali is confused
that Ali is saying this is second rule.
The Muhammad one is easier to second
draw third rule.
Maybe because of the formatting
you are unable to see it clearly.
Look now is are second or third,
so do not get the number with the index
index.
Always start from zero.
So this rule.
Yes, it is rule number three,
but it is at index number two.
Everyone, do you understand this point?
This is rule number three,
but this is present.
Add index number two.
Okay.
Now, Ali,
tell me you meant the index rule.
So because in areas the indexes,
they start from zero.
That's why they are always one
less than the actual number in real life.
Usually things they start from one
for string name rule.
I don't understand.
This part is an enhanced for loop
and whether it's an enhanced for loop
name is just a variable name.
I mean you you can call it would
like this.
It's just a variable.
What will this print again?
It will print the complete first row
previous example.
You are on previous examples.
I mean, it's already 15 minutes on
on this example.
This is the previous example.
This one you are talking about.
It's nothing just to index this same data
and two values here.
Okay.
So every everybody is done.
So should we move to the next example?
Okay, let's create one more class here.
Yes. Okay.
So again,
whenever we have to create an array,
we need to know the type of data
that we are planning to store.
So let's say this time
we are planning to store numbers.
So we say end.
And if I want to create a 2D array
after the data type,
what should I specify
to pair of square brackets?
And then let's call it numbers
and then equal to fine.
So one pair of curly bracket
and this pair of bracket
is going to hold multiple one at ease.
So let me do this.
Let me do it a little differently.
This this time.
So look, look, guys,
if I have one day out of here
and and let's say if I say roll
the zero is equal to
ten, going to 3040 on line number six
is it to want to add it?
Yes, it is.
And if I duplicated
I'm just trying to show you this point
and that to the arrays are nothing
but multiple one days so let me call it
row number one and or number two.
So let's say
hundred, 200, 300,
400 and or to see one, two, three, four.
So if a 2D area is nothing but combination
of multiple one, we add it.
So I should be able to do this row
zero comma
roll one, comma,
row two and let me put them
on the new line so that is easier.
Or your eyes
again, look at this.
This role zero
is a variable
that can attains complete one.
The addy.
I can directly put it here
or I can store it in a variable
and then I can put it here.
Similarly, rule one is complete
one d addy.
I can put it directly here
or I can store in a variable
and then I can store that variable.
Here I do.
Getting the idea to the ad
is are nothing but
multiple one d
ad is stored in curly brackets.
So what I can do I
can, for example,
copy this complete one d addy
and instead of writing the variable
name, I can put it directly here.
Similarly, I can copy this complete
second one d area
and instead of the variable I can put it,
I can have a mixture as well.
So it's nothing but multiple
one days.
Is it possible to have different
number of elements for AD is inside at it?
Yes, it is possible.
Like for example,
if I if I do not want to have
four elements,
I can have three elements
in the second one to add
the size of individual
one D ad is can be different,
does not have to match how many elements
we have in the first one data
or how many we have in the second three.
So it can be different.
Just focus on this point. Two.
The ad is a combination
of multiple one ads.
I know it's easier to understand
if you look at it
like in metrics, rows and columns,
it's easier to understand that way.
But that's not the correct
way of understanding it
because it's not a metrics.
It looks like a metrics, okay?
It's not.
Yes, the data type should be same.
Okay,
Now help me help me do this.
Let me remove this.
I hope you have understood the idea.
So I want to get this complete section
draw.
What should I write here?
But tell me the type of variable
that I should have declared
to store this complete one d addy
and then
square brackets because there's an area
and then let's call it role
is equal to number
and then square brackets zero.
If I do this, will I get an error?
If I say zero and other square
bracket and one, we like it.
We'd like get an error.
Who can tell me why I'm getting an error?
Let's see.
Who can tell me why I am getting an error.
So the Arab states
that required the data
type is an array of integers,
but we are getting only one
single integer.
What does this mean?
What is the data type of this role?
It's an array of integers.
What is this part of returning to us?
This.
This code here numbers 001.
Is it returning us to the array one data
or one single element?
No, this is where you are wrong.
It's one single element from to the array.
Look, it's not a to the adding.
If I say numbers zero
and one is just one single
element of type integer
from this to the area which is 20, it's
not a 2D area.
Those who are saying to the addy
it's not one.
The array not to data
is one single element
from this to reality.
When we say square brackets two
and if I want to store it in a variable,
I have to say in
number is equal to
and then numbers is zero one.
Everyone understands
what is going on here.
Let me uncomment this as well.
This returns a
complete 11d Addy,
how many of you understand this point?
They scored with one square brackets here
because there's a 2D area.
This this is going to return us one
complete array
from this.
The addy.
When we say this and this code here,
this is going to return
as one
single element.
When we try to square brackets,
we are actually getting single
individual numbers from that ordinary.
When we use only one pair of square
brackets,
we are getting actually complete one.
The add is and if we do not specify
any brackets at all,
we will get the complete 2D addy,
no brackets at all, complete to the area.
One bracket, one dearie,
two brackets, one single elements.
So it's nesting.
One single element is nested
inside, one complete one D addy
and those one D areas
are actually nested inside
a 2D addy.
Makes sense.
Okay.
Only unit really understands this.
Oh. Okay.
So tell me
this.
Let me let me create
one new example.
Is there anyone who is following me,
which is writing this code
and what line 17 means is it
declaring before printing line 17?
It's declaring and initializing
that mean get give me on.
Let me show more examples
like when we were saying our is equal
to zero.
Exactly.
So this is the line that is confusing you.
This one.
Let me copy this line.
Let's go to the previous example.
This is exactly the same line as we did
in the previous
example, line number 14 and line
number 13.
Exact same concept, exact same idea, exact
same thing.
Line number 14.
In a previous example,
what was it was returning to us.
Could you run this code?
Yes, it's exactly the same thing.
Complete one.
The array is being returned,
but this is what we will be getting.
20. Yes.
Returns the complete rule.
Yes, it is the same idea.
Yes, it will return ten, 20, 30 and 40.
Yes, that's correct.
This number zero
is going to return this complete
one D addy
and this complete one D addy.
Whenever we want to store an array,
we have to specify the data type,
then square brackets and then a variable.
Why did we get 20?
Because of this last.
How we are going to print or draw one?
You can try to look for it
or you can use arrays dot to string like
my station.
I'm trying to print the entire second row,
but I'm not getting it.
When we check it entire second row,
I could done.
Okay,
so if we want to print the entire second
row, everyone
we can use at ease
dart to string
and we can say numbers square bracket
if we want to get the second complete row,
what should I specify inside the
square bracket? One.
And that's it.
By writing this line,
you will be able to get this complete
second row
like this.
Okay, If I do this, if I specify
one more square bracket
and then I specify,
let's say
number three, what will I get
Instead of line 20,
we can write this out number.
Yes. So,
yes, we can all be
perfect.
Okay, So let's let's do one more example.
Could you please explain why printing
just an array
actually prints
the object instead of actual draw?
Actually, always whenever
we are printing a variable,
if it is not a primitive variable,
Java is always going to print its address
from the memory.
This is by default how Java works,
and that's why we need borrowed.
This ad is dart to string
when whenever we are dealing with non
primitive data types,
there is one more concept in world is
called the two string method overriding.
But there I guess maybe you will learn
in around one or two weeks
how can we print multiple rows?
I will show you that
and we should do that.
How can we print the complete column pool,
for example?
I will show you that.
Please
pull the comment on System.out.println.
Okay, let me copy
and paste this
and want to move out of it
again.
Now let's try to write
a loop
and from that loop
we will slowly
move towards the nested loops
because look guys,
if I want to go through
all of the elements,
how many loops I will be needing,
there are rules,
and inside those rules there are columns.
So we will be needing two loops.
One loop will go through the rules
and the other loop will go to the columns.
So for example,
if I write a loop like this
or end, I is equal to zero.
Let me call it a row,
row zero.
What should be this row less than
how many rules we have inside are two.
The adding
three and
the index. It starts from zero.
So 012 now.
Okay.
And if we say end in
or let me do this for
I mean let me call it
column C oil or short column flow.
So this column, how many columns
we have or the column number
changing every time, is it possible
that column number can be different?
So to make things easier,
let me let me let me make it
same for all of the rows.
Well, what is the
how many columns we have
in all of the rows?
Four.
Right.
Okay.
Now, if I say something
like this, if I say numbers
row and then square brackets column,
what do you think, What output
I will get. Yes.
If I run this
look, we've got the complete
to the array,
all of the numbers,
everything.
Let me know.
Once you are done typing,
then I will debug this code for you
and you paste this code.
And the question, General, I can,
but it's this better if you type. It
is better if you practice with me
next, giving you time
so that you can follow me.
I want you to type. It's better.
You will learn better.
You will face syntax errors.
You will understand the syntax.
Where the call should go will be accurate.
Shouldn't.
When you copy paste,
you don't learn that part.
Okay.
If after every rule
I want to start a new line,
is it possible that
if, let's say after printing ten 4040
I want to print,
I want to print them on the same line,
Is it possible to
change the print
to print stained the print
and then to print
and then a space here
to learn from?
Okay.
No, but now
everything is on the same line.
I want a new line
for every rule, new line for every.
So I can do that
by putting an empty print.
And then after the first row.
So it will look better. Now.
And let me make it a little more
appealing to your eyes.
Commit on your timeline
so you will be able to clearly see
rows and columns
allowed for drawing
a key.
So everyone, are you ready?
Nasty book.
Okay,
so let me put the label point here
and right click
in the next click on date book
and we we can in space here.
I hope the font is still readable.
Okay, so the row
the row variable is starting from zero
and a zero is less than three.
So we enter the loop
and then we have column.
Column is also starting from zero
and column is less than four.
So this is also true.
So we enter and we do this. So
and this row is zero right now.
This column is also zero right now.
So which element is present at row
number zero and column number zero?
The element is ten.
And that's exactly we will be getting one.
So we say print and this number zero ten.
Okay.
Now the value of the column variable
will increase from 0 to 1.
And this condition will be checked.
Is the one less than four? Yes.
So again, the internal loop,
it will go to the second iteration.
So this time
the value of the column has been increased
from 0 to 1.
So row is still zero,
but the column has been increased to one
and now we split on it
zero.
Rule and column number
one will give us quantity.
So 20 will be printed here.
Everybody understands how we got ten
and 20 here.
Okay.
And what will be the next value
of column?
No, no, no.
The value of column.
This column variable, it will be two
and which element is present at row
number zero,
but column number 230 is present.
We will be getting 30
still ROI zero,
but column will now increase to three.
So we will be getting 40.
And now from three,
the value of the column will become four
is four, less than four? No.
So the condition will fail.
And right now this is our cursor.
This is where the cursor is
because of this empty print.
And then the cursor
will move to the next line.
So it goes here
and then the value rule from zero,
it will increase to one
and now everything will repeat. Yes.
So that's what we will do next.
So now this time things have changed.
So we have rule number one.
Now and column will be fast to zero rule.
Still, one column will be one
row, still one column number will be two.
Then still it will be three.
So row number one, column
number zero, we will be getting 15.
Rule number one,
Column number one will give us 30.
Rule number one.
Column number two, 35.
Rule number one, Bottom number three, 45.
So now one by one.
Okay.
Can you tell me,
are we getting the elements rule by row
or column by column?
Yes, rule by rule.
We get the elements rule by rule
35 and 45.
The next rule 16
and 20, then 32 and then 22.
We can get column by column adjustment.
Yes. Okay.
Let me also share this figure.
Okay. Please
ask if something is not clear.
If it is not clear how,
with the help of this
to be all
with the help of this nested for loop,
we are able to get this one more thing
guys instead of heart.
It is hard coding a good idea
like hard coding.
Three here
is not good.
What we can do.
We can say number start length
and nurse on this.
So still exactly the same output.
But what about this column?
Less than four.
How do we know
the individual length
of every area here?
If we want to get the length of an ad, do
we first need to get to that add itself?
If we want to get the length of an area,
we need to have that add a first.
So here
we first need to get that at a by writing
a rule.
And then from individual rule
we need to get and
and this is important.
It's different for the rules.
We don't need any square brackets.
We simply say numbers that length.
But for columns,
we say numbers and then square bracket
and then document.
So this is how we can write a generic rule
that can go to all the elements
from a goods.
Why there is no space between numbers.
Okay.
Who can
who can tell early why there is no space
between the numbers.
You put the space
focus
here.
No question marks.
Okay.
Do you have any questions or something?
Clarification on numbers.
Zero zero.
Okay, so this part,
when we specify only one square bracket
with a to the adding, what do we get?
Do we get a complete one D addy?
Do we get the individual elements?
Do we get complete to be added
three d array?
This part that I have highlighted here
numbers one square bracket
and then I'm saying
row row will be zero, then one
then do that three
complete rule.
And after the complete rule,
if we write down length,
will it give us the length of that array?
Exactly.
So that's the idea.
This part.
Here it is.
We're going to break it down like this.
This part numbers dot rule.
It gives us
this gives us the complete
one, the edit.
And then after that we are saying dart
length, which means the length of that
addy.
Then I have specified the number
I did not need to mention
rule out when I started using the length,
we needed to specify
which rule it will take all of the rules
one by one
first, when the value of the rule
variable will be zero,
it will take the first one,
then second and third.
Oh, okay.
Thank you.
Limit.
Okay, let me give you a very
kind of easy task.
You have to only print
even numbers from this to the area.
Everyone, everyone to this task
bring only
even numbers from.
This area
right now we are getting everything
from this to the area.
We don't want to get everything.
We only want even numbers.
We think you can you can do this task.
Is it easy or hard or or you think
I'm doing this one?
Okay, let me show you one and then maybe
draw at me,
copy paste.
So tell me which line is responsible
for printing the numbers
from this to the area.
Which line is responsible
for printing line number 13?
Is it gang?
Can we enclose this line inside?
And if condition? Yes.
And inside that If condition,
how can I specify that?
I only want to get
I only want to go inside this loop
if the number is even
very simple. Right?
We can say in number,
row and column
and only if we divide
this number by two
and we go to the answer to zero,
then only print this.
So then there's this for the task.
So look, from the second row
we only have one even number.
So only one is printed 15.
Did not bring 3545 second complete,
a third complete.
Roy's even
and there's the output get.
Is there anyone who do not understand
how we are,
why we are only getting even numbers?
Can you modify it to get only
the order numbers?
Everyone modified the score
to get only the order
numbers.
What the more optimal using the length
reporting the number using length.
Because we don't want
to count manually first.
And then I put those numbers here.
Okay.
So only insert of this equal to
if we put not equal to,
then we will be getting the order numbers
1535 44 right.
If you have any questions
that might change it back to you. But
you can.
Okay. If no questions, let's have a break.
And then after the break
we will do more examples.
What if I want to print even numbers
from the first row?
Only in 2D? Other possible
just change this condition here
so that it only goes through one row. Yes.
Let's have a break
here so you can contact me.
Okay.
So let's say this time what I want is
I want to add all of the numbers
from the store. Addy.
So if I have a 2D area again
and I want to go through
all of the elements,
how many loops I will be needing to,
why do we need to looks?
Why do we need two loops?
One loop will go through the rules
and then other loop will go through
individual elements
from those rules.
So let's call it role.
And do I need to individually count
how many rules are there
in this 2D array or
yes, I can simply numbers
then dart and then length. Then
because individual role can contain
multiple elements,
I need one more array
in that I would call columns
and then I will say numbers
square bracket role.
So from every rule
I see length
so that I can get to the of elements
which are present in that specific table.
And now my,
my plan is to add all of the elements.
Do I need a variable to hold the sum
somewhere? Yes.
So we need one variable to hold this one
like this.
And then inside the nested loop
I can say a sum
is equal to sum
plus some plus What should I put here?
Does that mean one rule can have
four elements by draw three whole eight?
Yes, that's correct.
I want to add all of the elements
from this to the adding.
I have written
two loops to go through all the elements.
Sorry,
I have
created one variable to hold the sum
and then I'm saying sum
is equal to sum plus
some plus part.
What should go here
exactly.
Numbers
and then rule and
and this will add all of the numbers.
And then I'm putting my cursor
in the start of this.
And after this here,
let me bring this sum.
The value of some.
So this is the total sum.
Do you understand how we are able to add
all of the elements
from this to the added?
Okay, so
this piece of code,
this piece of code one by one,
it will first give us ten,
then 20 and 30, then 40 and 1530.
And one by one we are adding it to the
previous value of this one.
So at the end, once we will be done
iterating
through all the elements,
we will have the collective sum. Why?
I have a different number
because here in the last row you have 116,
so it adds ten, 15, 16.
No, it adds ten, 20, 30, 40, 15.
You want me to debug it?
Okay, next step.
Okay,
so we placed a table point here, then
right click and then deeper.
So initially some is zero,
then it all starts from zero.
Zero is less then numbers and length
numbers.
Galante is three right now,
zero is less than three.
So we enter this loop.
Then numbers are all
dot land is for column is zero.
So zero is less than four.
So here we have zero zero, so we have zero
and the value of the sum variable
is also zero.
So this and this part numbers rule
column zero zero, it will give us this ten
and then that ten
will be added
to the zero zero plus ten, ten
and then ten will get stored
inside the same somebody.
So once we execute this line, look,
some you can also see it from here,
some is ten right now.
Next,
the value of column is increased
from 0 to 1.
So row is a still zero, column is one now,
so rows zero column one.
This will give us 20
and then
the 20 that in this code is returning.
Do we need to write Sun?
Can't we collect rule?
No, because the rule is already declared
inside the loop.
We need a separate variable
for that to hold the sun.
We can also add a specific row and column.
Yes, that's correct.
Okay, so some right now is ten.
And this part of the code numbers
all column, it is giving us this 20.
Come here
so you can verify this from here as one
number zero and column
13 the value of 20
and sum contains a value of ten.
So now ten will be added to 2010
plus 20 is equal to 30.
And the result, the sum is ten
numbers.
The row and column will give us 20.
So ten plus property 30 will get stored
inside of some variable.
So observe the value here.
After I run this code
in this ten, it will change to 30
so loop it now becomes 30.
Similarly, next item after 20 is 30.
So with the help of this inner loop
now we will get 30 and this 30 plus 30, 60
and that 60 will get stored inside
some variable.
Then the next element which is 40.
So we are going row by row
taking all the elements
and we keep on adding that element
to the previous value of sum.
So 60 now will be added to 40,
so 60 plus 40 will be hundred.
The results will be stored inside
to some variable
exact same thing.
Now we will do with the row number two,
which is our next number one.
We will pick the 15, add 200.
The answer will be one and 15,
then same 30.
And we will keep on repeating
this for all the elements
in the story, adding
Is it clear now?
So ideas seem one by one.
We first get all the elements.
The extra thing,
the different thing here is we are adding
all of the elements this time in the sum
variable instead of printing them.
Okay, so now a lot of you are asking
what can we add?
Only the first row element,
second row title.
Can we go column by column?
Let's try to do these things.
If you have any questions
you can ask otherwise,
in the next example,
I will show you how to add the elements
row by row or column by column.
I am having a different output.
What was my answer? 315.
Okay.
Are your elements exactly the same
or you are doing this mistake here?
Actually,
look here
you are saying numbers decline,
which means you are not adding the last.
You are not not adding the last column.
You are skipping the last column
because number number
will always return you three.
And if you put three here,
you will go on over
only the first three elements in each row.
There should be numbers
square bracket draw, and then Balkenende
very kindly share screenshot.
Let me copy paste this.
Your elements are different than mine
and last row I have 20
you have compared here.
Okay, everybody
tell me if I do something like this
for I, I.
Okay.
Should I call the operation still raw
or you can now understand my right.
Even if I write
I instead of renaming this total.
Okay.
Maybe left me right draw one more time.
Okay. So
let's say
if I say number
start length, what are this value?
Number length is going to return me.
Number of columns and
number of islands or number of rows.
Rows.
How many rows we have
three of a two.
If I do this,
I'm trying to intentionally confuse you
in one second.
I can print it out
numbers
and then
I say zero
a row.
What is this?
A road or land will contain?
Tell me the number that actually contain
three.
Oh, okay.
It's going to contain three.
If it is going to contain three from
from where the value of roll will start
and where it will end
the start from zero,
then it will be one,
then it will be two.
And when I put the zero
numbers get objective zero always,
which at all I will be getting always
this one.
Okay, so first time it will be zero zero.
Next time it will be zero one.
Next time it will be zero two
when this loop will execute.
So which elements I will be getting
exactly?
I will be getting ten, 20, 30.
Everyone understands this.
Why I did not get 40
because here
let me put four here
Where what will happen now?
The complete first row
ten, 20, 30, 40.
Everyone understands
this when I'm writing this code,
why I'm getting the first complete row?
Okay, if I do this, if I put one here,
if I put one here.
So first thing, cluster square
bracket specifying one.
And then I have this row variable,
which is going from
zero one, two, three, four
complete second
row, ten 1530.
Okay.
And if I do it like this, if I only do
row is less than two
rows. Less than two.
What what we like right now
A everyone understands this.
The first two square brackets.
What do the control rows or columns?
The first square brackets,
Where do they control Rows of columns?
Rows, any second square brackets?
Or do the control columns?
If I, if I make the column
constant like this,
and if I change the row
this time column is constant.
Which column is this column?
Add index number one.
I'm not changing this,
but I am changing the rules.
First, I am saying zero, then one.
Can you guess me?
Can you guess the output
20 and
20 and 30.
And if I change it to three
won't be 3020.
So are you getting the idea
how you can get
to that rule by row and column by column,
This first to square bracket?
It can three It controls the rows.
This second square bracket.
It controls the columns.
If you want to go row by row,
you keep this part constant
and then you change this value.
For example, right now we have
we are saying that
column is always going to stay the same.
It is always going to stay one,
which means
if the column is always going to stay,
always one, This part
because we have hardcoded one
here, column is not going to move
and then we are changing the row from
first we are saying zero,
then one, then two.
So first it will give us 20
and 30 then continue.
But I did not understand, not length,
why the last number did not show,
because there are three rows
in this study area.
There are four columns,
but rules are three.
So if you say a row, not land,
you will get three.
And if you get three, you will not be able
to go through all the columns
because columns are four
and the rules are three.
Okay, here, here is a quiz for you to see
if I am changing this rule.
I'm making it little hard for you.
Yes, we can do that as well.
Okay.
If I do
this,
what are what I will get?
Okay.
Exactly.
How do how do you know that
you will be getting the third column?
Because I have a fixed
I have a fixed in my column.
My column is
always column that is at index two.
So this is column
which is at index zero.
This column is that index one.
This one is two and this one is three.
So what I am doing,
I'm not changing the value of column.
It is always staying two.
But this number numbers
I from from where to where the value of
I is changing
from where
to where the value of I is changing.
It is changing from zero.
It becomes one and then it becomes two.
So the value of I is changing
and this is plus two square bracket.
What does it control
the faster square bracket?
What does it control?
Roles are columns rows
the first it will go to this row,
then it will go to this row.
Then it will go to this row.
So now, you know,
if you have to go row by rule,
you should be changing the
values from the first square bracket.
If you want to go column by column,
you should be changing the values
here in the column index.
Let me give you one more nasty.
If I make one here
and if I put I here, what does
this first is good of bracket control.
It controls the row which row?
I am always specifying.
I am always saying give me the elements
only and only from this row.
What does it mean? What does it mean?
Will I ever get any value from this
first row
ever?
Will I ever get values
from the last one? No.
I am limiting myself to row number,
which is a index one,
and then I am changing the value of I.
What does this? I control columns.
So first it will be column number zero.
It will give me 15, then 30, then 35.
So if we run this,
we get 15, 15,
then 30, then and then 35.
If I want to get this last
element as well,
what should I change in this code?
Either make it less than equal to three
or make it
equal to the floor like this.
So 15/3. Okay,
let me do this.
If I say two here,
if I said to here, what are what
I will get this time
in the first square bracket
I have specified two.
What does this first get year
bracket controls
the row
and which row I am specifying here
the last row
and then the value of the second pair
and second square bracket is changing from
zero one, two, three, four.
So this will give
me all the elements from the
complete first row.
Now let me give you a quick task.
So let me say
control C, control V
20, move it.
So let me add a few more elements here
and let me send this area to you.
You have to write a loop, write a loop
to get all the elements
from second row, one by one,
all the elements from the second row,
one by one,
with the help of one loop.
Do you think you can do it
or is it harder or what?
Oh, okay.
See, I want all the elements
I want 15, 30,
35, 45, 40, printed it on the console.
Yes, exactly Like this.
Then.
Yeah.
So what did you do,
Write a loop
and how many elements
we have in the second adding.
One, two, three, four,
five to start from zero.
Then it's less than five.
And if I am only interested
in the second row,
how can I limit myself?
So I have two square brackets.
Which one controls the rows?
The first one or the second one +21.
And in the first one,
if I always put to one, what does it mean?
Will I always stay within second row?
Yes. And then I change the value of I
from 0 to 4
will care.
15, 30, 35, 45, 40.
Is it anyone who do not understand is
okay?
Are you ready for the task?
It's a little tricky,
but I just want to see if we want to try.
Need more practice?
Let me show you the task.
Let's see if this is the task.
So let me create this. Add a four.
You actually would copy this
task from here.
So this is how your array
should
look like.
So there is an array,
there's pilot student,
and you see it is a 2D area.
The first
arrow contains the name of the students,
and there are four students.
Yes, Deepali.
Thank you.
I'm. I'm missing
a missing
diskette of records here.
Okay, so the first
array inside the study area,
it contains the.
And this second contains the grade.
So let's say a,
B, C,
and let's see me again.
And let me format it a little bit,
and I'll put it on the next slide.
So this is how your to the array
looks like.
So now what
you have to do create to edit this part
I have already done for you in which
first to add will consist of four names.
So this is our first pair.
It contains four names.
Second array will contain grade,
so secondary contains the grade.
Your program should print
the name of the students
that has the A and B grade, so
you have to access the grade
from the second row
and then you have to check
if that grade is A or B
if it is a B, then
you have to print the name of the student.
Do you understand the requirements?
Do understand the question before we jump.
But if you need any help
understanding the question,
please let me know.
Like, for example,
can you tell me the output?
What output should I get
that?
Let me put it here.
Let me make it a little easy for you.
What output should I get?
According to the requirements,
I should be getting Aisha
and Deepali on the output
because these are the students
which have the grade and B,
Julia
and John, they have the D and C
printing.
Okay, let me put A-plus.
Okay, so.
But we don't want to print A-plus.
We only want to print.
And B, so this is what you have to do,
how you are going to access
the second row
and the first.
Okay, first, tell me how many loops
you will be needing for this.
Can we do it with only one loop as well?
Can we do it with only one
loop as well? Yes.
Try to do one loop.
It's going to be easy.
Okay, let's.
Let's do this first.
Only write a loop
that prints all the grades.
Let me know
once you are done with this part.
A loop that prints
all of the grades one by one
from the story, add it.
Just let just let me know.
Once you are done, write the code to print
only the grades from ordinary
and execute your code and verify
if it works or not. Yep.
Yep. We have. This is what I want.
Bring all of the
grades from this to the any
IVC you are using
the new give up intelligently.
It's one
now. Perfect.
Let me also do the same.
So we save for I I.
I start from zero x less than four
and then I am only interested
this second row.
So in which square bracket
I should put to one to control
the array, the first one
and the second one goes through eight one
by one
and I get all the grades.
Everyone understands this part.
Okay, If I change this 1 to 0,
what will I get this time?
I will be getting the names right
so everyone understands
how we can get names
as well as the grades,
all of them.
Now we simply need to write
an if condition.
So for here
we need to write.
If if
students.
If I am interested in grades,
should I put a zero or one inside
the first bracket
one and the second one will go one by one.
If this is equal to a
because there is a string.
So we have to use the equals method.
So if this is equal to a
I also want to say either it's A or B
should
I use and operator logical and operator
or the logical or operator
or grade is equal to B
if this is the case, if the grade is E,
or if the greatest B, then
I want to print
the corresponding names
from the first row
because I am putting zero.
It will give me names
because here I'm putting one,
it will give me the grade.
And now I get Aisha and Deepali
so everyone understands this.
How about working?
Yes. Take 2 minutes.
If something is not clear, please ask.
And still not.
We can debug.
As with
a is there anyone who is typing
who is following
and wants me to wait? Oh.
Okay.
Let me know once you are on. Yes.
See, this is also going to work.
Student's grade
and then dart length
and you.
So guys it is a good idea to hardcore this
or I can get it dynamically.
How can I get the length
of individual role
or any role?
I can say students
then shared objective zero,
not length.
So this is also good.
What am I doing here?
Even I am confused.
What you are still on the example
that we were solving
30 minutes ago on Let's
know 2 minutes ago.
Okay, everyone help him understand
what he is doing wrong.
He is always getting 40, 40, 40.
Instead of using the variable role,
he is always saying
give me the value, which is are 203,
which means row number zero
and what column
he is specifying the column number three.
So that's why you are always getting 40.
What what do you expect instead.
Zero through and column number three.
This is where the fault is present
40 is on column,
which is actually next to number three
and the row is zero.
So mean put 14 every printed row. No,
it means that you are 40 years old
now, I guess.
Okay.
He's still not understanding why
he's getting 40 or what does this 40 mean?
Who can help him.
You still don't understand
what what what does this 40 mean?
Okay.
Ask him if he knows the rows and columns.
So, Mohammad,
do you know that 2D, the arrays can also
be perceived as rows and columns?
But why does
it print 40?
And I gave everyone.
This is this is a challenge for you.
Maybe the moms, maybe the moms can page
18 better because moms, they can
understand everything from their children,
even if they are saying while
while watching our definition of
is asking for leave.
Now he is asking why gets 40.
Okay let let's let's break it down more.
Tell me this
your role zero the role
the variable role
from where it is starting
zero and and this numbers
and what this numbers do
our client will give you.
That's what I'm trying to explain to him.
Tired, faster.
All tired value. No, no, no, no.
It's not going to give you faster value.
This number is not planned.
What is going to reduce
the total number of rows in your to daddy?
How many rows you have.
This number,
not length, is going to return four
because there are total
four rows in your two.
Daddy is this part player numbers not land
and their condition
will be something like this.
So if your condition is like this,
if you have four here
you are starting your loop from zero.
If you have 48,
how many times your loop will execute
four times.
So it shouldn't be clear
why you are getting 44 times.
Is this part clear why
the output is being generated four times?
Because your loop is executing four times.
Now let's understand why we are getting 44
times.
Sure.
To be clear,
because your loop is executing four times.
Look here what you are saying.
You are saying numbers
the name of the area.
Then you are saying to zero.
This first, a square bracket.
We put the row number here
in which we are interesting interested.
You have inserted zero,
which means this row from here.
Then on the
second square bracket
you are saying three.
Three means is column number zero.
This is one, this is two, this is three.
This points to this 40.
And you are always saying zero three.
You are not changing this value.
This loop is going to execute four times.
And every time you are saying
give me the element, which is that
index number zero and add column
index number three, which is 40.
So 40 will be printed four times.
So how should I print that column?
You want to print the last column or rule
or what do you want to print?
4414 41 So if you want to print
everyone who can help him,
he wants to print the last column.
This one
which which
square brackets control the column.
Which square brackets control the column.
The first ones are the second ones first.
Where our second pair
second appear.
So he should
he should keep this three here
or should he change it?
We are always interested
in the last column.
He should keep it.
He should keep three here.
What should he do instead of zero?
He should say a row
because row will change from zero to 1 to
3, then four
and you will get the last column.
Okay, Now let's go back and see
where do we have.
Okay, So
let me show you one more example.
We have only learned how to use the index
for loops, the normal ones.
Now let's try to understand
how we can use other types of loops,
so help me write down
a loop again, a simple one
index based there
start from zero goes to some value.
And I want to print all of the numbers
using that loop.
I can see a four. I
a rule
and this rule
what should be it
less than road, less than what?
I want to bring all of the numbers
from this to lady
is there any better way
instead of putting four
can automatically tell us
how many rows are there? Yes.
So we can simply say number start land
instead of manually put in three or four.
And this outer loop, what does it control?
Draws are columns, rows.
So how many rows we have
three.
So those who are saying four.
Why you are saying four.
Okay, correct. Answer is three.
Even if you have two hard coded,
not for outer loop four rules
rugby, then we can have
one more inner loop like this
and let's call it columns.
This column.
What should this column be?
Less than
how many columns
we have in our to the area?
Four.
Is there any better way of getting
the number of columns automatically?
Yes, we can say in numbers
then square bracket row
and then land.
And then if we print, if we say numbers,
then square bracket the row
and column.
And if we run this, we will get
all of the elements
from the story adding.
But the output is not looking good.
It prints everything on column wise.
How can I make it?
Print everything row by row,
change this print and Len to print.
Put a space here
and now if we run it
this time we get everything roll by row.
So after the inner loop,
we can print an empty print out
and we get all the values here
again.
And put print.
Yes. Okay,
So which is which loop we have used here
to get all of the elements from
this to reality
loop loop.
The normal one index based loop.
This is called index based loop.
Let's try to use the enhanced for loop.
Everyone understands
how this index based loop is working
and how we are getting all of the elements
here.
Now, the second thing I want to show
you is how to do the same with
index based.
Let me quickly copy this
and let me remove this part.
Is there anyone who is following
and walks me to it?
Okay, let me know once you have time,
you are missing the MP println
after the inner loop empty out
we go. Why?
I am getting an error.
The s of it.
And that's
why don't you take screenshots or what?
Why do you take pictures?
One thing
that I can see your student capital
s here and lowercase as here.
Another thing
you are missing a comma after the line
number eight.
Also one more thing.
Some of you are stuck
on the previous examples.
Everyone, please stop doing
whatever you are doing.
This next example
that I'm going to show you,
I want all of you to focus on that one.
It will be released
October six.
I think it was the best out of all
what they have released
when it comes to seasons
and the best seasons.
Out of all the seasons Marvel has released
and I'm also a big marvel.
I never miss a marvel movie.
See, remember from back 15
Moon Knight?
Oh, yes. Moonlight was also very good.
First half.
Obviously the second half was all mine,
but I was not expecting that.
No, Faheem Faheem is here, but he cannot
speak because she punched him so hard.
Hard, that is.
I is unable to.
Maybe skip
speak for next four weeks or so.
Right thing.
This is how Faheem looked like.
Okay, so let's write a enhance for loop
to bring all of the numbers.
So in an enhanced for loop,
what do we specify?
What do we specify first, the data type,
the data type of the element
or the data type of the addy.
So the to the area,
what do they contain first?
First, they contain one D areas
or they contain the elements directly.
How, how is the nesting?
How is the nesting work
to the array contains one D area
and one D areas
contain individual elements.
This is how it works are to
the add is directly
contain elements
nice to the areas
they contain.
The one d areas
and one d arrays in turn contain
the elements
or elements are directly present.
There is no nest
being nothing into adding.
They are not directly present
to the arrays
contain one d areas and D areas
actually contains the elements.
Look here these curly brackets.
This is in one d addy.
This is a complete one D added
so this outer for load
that we will be writing here.
It's not going to give us directly element
it's going to give us first complete Addy.
So here
we have to say end
and then square brackets
and let's call it a R
and then semicolon and numbers
or you can also call it
rows or rule.
I think rule will be will make more sense.
So from this numbers,
which is a to the addy,
we are first getting the individual
one D at is and we are calling them
rule make sense.
One loop is extracting
the one d arrays from the to the area.
Then we will be needing one more addy
that will extract individual elements
from these one d arrays.
So we will see and enter for
integer column.
And here we will see the rule.
So from each rule we are going column
by column to get all the entries.
So let me print
the columns.
So look here,
all the elements one by one.
And again, if I want to print them
in one row, I can remove this.
And then from here
and can put a space here.
And then again after this inner for loop,
I can put an empty println
and now we'll find
exactly elements in this form.
So the only thing that is different,
the thing that is, yes,
it is nested one loop inside another one.
The only thing that is important is,
is to understand this part here.
And let me also debug this for you.
So right click and then debug.
So look this numbers
etc. at this number except for area
one, this truly array contains three one.
The areas one is present at
index zero one and then two
when this
code will be executed.
First to complete one be added
that contains 1020 quantitative 40
will be placed inside there already.
So the moment I run this look here,
this row variable contains
the complete eight complete
first one diary ten, 20, 30, 40.
So out of these three rows
this first all as completely
access the complete row
now from this row individually.
Now we going to be getting ten, then
20 and 30 therefore okay so this in a loop
will now give us from this complete row
it will give us ten,
then 20, then 30 and 40.
So if I run this
look first the value of column is ten,
it gives us ten, then it gives us 20.
Look at output,
then it gives us 30, then 40,
and then again
we move the cursor to the next line and.
We go back to the output loop.
The outer loop this time will give us
which complete row will be given.
This time we are on the second iteration.
This complete second row
will be placed in which variable
this complete
second row will be placed
in which variable inside row variable.
So now if we run it, look here, this
row variable, it now contains the complete
second row 15, 30, 35, 40.
So imagine it like this.
You have multiple, let's say, big boxes
which.
And those big boxes,
they again in turn contain smaller boxes.
So you extract one box
from that bigger box
and then if you want to get
the individual items on our side,
there are some items
present inside this box.
Then you go through individual box
one by one to get all of the items.
So from this bigger box this to the array,
we first get the individual
one D arrays one by one, row by row.
And then from those rows we get the items,
the individual numbers,
one by ten, 15, 30, 35.
It makes sense
for us to get
the complete rows
from the bigger to the array
and then from those rows
one by one, get the individual items
1530, 35, 40.
Then again,
go back to the next complete row
and then one by one, from that group
into the numbers, 16, 20,
32, 22.
What is calling this matter to the attic?
These two square brackets, these values?
You mean nested loop or to the attic?
We are getting all the elements
from this to the array
with the help of enhanced form.
This is what we are doing.
Yes, we are using enhanced for loop here
to get the elements from it to the array.
Previously we were using normal
index based loops to get all the elements.
This is different.
This is a difference
why we did not put the square in the inner
loop.
This is where put it here.
And that
inner loop is storing individual elements,
not areas.
One thing that I don't really understand
is how intelligible on the row
stands for rows and columns.
Columns. It does not know,
it does not know.
For example, you can call it
intelligent,
dumb, intelligent does not know.
It's just going to declare a variable,
whatever you call it.
It totally depends on you.
It's still going to work.
It's just a variable name
that we are giving.
I am calling it row and column
so that you can understand better.
Otherwise there is nothing intelligent
programing or Java
that is understanding
or extracting any meaning from the
variable names.
But we are limited with this loop. Yes.
For example, we cannot go backwards.
For example, we
update the values with this loop.
Yes, we are
semicolon.
Was that semicolon here?
After the loop?
You have a semicolon.
So let me call it
column again.
Or it's also good
if you call it num or number
or something like that.
Line 11 and 13.
Okay.
So here inside the enhanced power loop,
we need to specify whatever
we get from this variable.
What does this variable contains numbers.
What does this contain?
We have to specify that or that I
know.
No, no, not directly contained numbers.
This numbers
is a to the addy
which contains multiple one D arrays.
That's why I was focusing.
That's why I was emphasizing on this to
the Addy
is a collection of multiple one D arrays.
That's
why here I am declaring an area variable
to hold the items.
And then these one d arrays, they contain
individual integer based data.
That's why I'm saying in the column here,
let me show you more examples with this.
For example, look here,
the first example that we did, this one,
getting to copy
this one, it's
a part of the syntax looks like you have
for how we have you guys
forgot how the enhanced for loops work.
Let me let me show you how far loops work.
So let's say, for example,
if I have indeed your skater bracket
and let's see, I am saying numbers
ten, 20, 30,
I want to go over this num addy
with the help of enhanced for loop.
So what we laid out I will write for
then I will write
whatever this num array contains.
What does it contain?
It contained in b years.
So I will say in the getter type,
whatever that thing contains,
then any variable name and then a column
and then the name of the addy
that I am about to create.
This is how this index works.
So now
it will go over all the elements
one by one without me
worrying about the index
or the size or the element
or the land or anything.
And it will give me all of the elements
automatically.
It will manage everything internally.
I simply have to specify the data type.
What does this Addy contains
and the name of the ADDY iterations
and everything
it will do automatically.
So this is how the enhanced
for loops work.
Do you understand it now?
The this part,
the one that I have highlighted.
So we are planning to use
the same enhanced for loop
to go over the to the areas as well.
So idea is going to stay exactly the same.
For example,
this is my to the area
this to the area contain one D areas
and those one D area areas,
they contain individual names.
So if I want to write an enhanced
for loop again
Samsung Dex for all in lowercase
and first thing I have
to specify is the data type
here.
The data type is one to be addy
of string.
So I will say a string one day at a sign
and then let me call it
rule then column
and then the name of the story that
if I run this loop only, what will I get?
What this rule will give me one by one.
Let's say, for example, if I print true,
if I said let's see, add is to screen
and that I print draw,
it will give me complete one D
add is one by one one by one
from this ordinary
look and bleed one.
The ad is one by one, one by one
and I have this one
D ad is
and I want to go to the individual items.
Then instead of doing this,
what I can do, I can write another
for loop.
And again, same idea.
We first have to specify the data type.
What is the data
type of individual elements
present in one data, It's the string
after the string,
after the string.
Do I need to specify square brackets?
Are we dealing with individual elements
or areas?
We are dealing with individual elements
this time.
So no need to specify square brackets.
And then after that, what do we need?
After the data type?
What do we write?
We write any variable name,
any variable name, let's call it V
or C or D or X or Y or whatever.
After variable name we right column
is the syntax of the enhanced for loop.
This we always have the right column
and after the column we write the name
the rule
that contains the elements and that's it.
Now if we put into this, we
we will get all of the elements
one by one,
like this.
I will
if I want to print all,
all of them on the same line,
I can remove the alone,
put a space here,
and after the inner for loop
we can put the empty out
and then we will get all the names.
What a nice uniform likely to be.
So this is how we can use the nested
enhanced for loops
to get all the elements.
The everything is going to stay
the same guys.
The only thing that you have to focus
is for the outer loop.
We specify a square brackets
because we will be getting first one
one add areas, complete rows and,
then the inner one.
It goes only with the data type
and is door to string.
Will it replace the both loops?
No, it's not going to work.
There is another one.
Let me see. I think it's called on.
Let me check.
And is dart.
That is dart.
I think it's called
the four look copy all
we this one deep two string
and if you ask names here
this deep string will print
the two D, three D, four D, R,
and D areas like this
adding is dark to string is four.
One brings four
four printing
it will be added. Yes.
Add is dart posting is four, one date
is this deep two spring is for two days.
You can actually use this deep
two string for one day.
That is as well.
Added or two string
will replace not replace it will print.
Which way is more common?
Osman Common way is to write a loop.
This deep to string or to string
is just for your
E is.
Can you please share your code?
I was listening, not typing.
Okay. Are you ready for the task?
How can we print the number of elements?
Number
of how many elements are there simply by
getting the length of the individual rows.
So let's see.
This is your task.
Leap to string is used to print from A
to b3d 45 D ad is without a loop,
so you have to create a 2D array of cars.
American, German, Korean, Italian
first row will contain
all the American cars.
Second row will contain all the German
cars, third Korean
cars, and third, fourth one Italian cars.
And then you have to print all of the cars
faster using normal loop index base.
And then second loop
can be an enhanced one.
Or maybe you can use
while one or whatever you like like
is the task clear?
And also you can easy
you can go
just down to the God's bar country
or maybe four and mix three
American cars,
then three German cars, three call them
three Daddy, Is the task
clear to everyone?
So you have to first create a 2D array
and inside that
I don't know the names of the German cars.
What?
You don't know the names of the German
cars?
Are you sure?
Where are you living?
I don't think there is any country we are.
German cars are not president,
BMW, Audi, Mercedes.
They're all German cars.
American.
I only know Honda and Toyota is Japan.
I think Honda is not American.
Honda is a Korean.
Ford is American. Yes.
Is KIA is also Korean.
Oh, it's very easy, guys.
Just simply go on Google
and type five American car
companies.
Honda is Japanese.
I think a lot of Americans,
they still prefer to go with German cars.
Right.
BMW already did.
They are equally famous.
Is this a class task
or homework class task?
But we can afford Japanese.
I mean, Japanese are not
and cheaper anymore.
The Prius that was just released,
I think it is pretty costly
compared to the current Honda.
But Toyota is way more reliable.
I have not used that many cars, but
I have a Toyota and
it is always I just
I just bought the gear started
and it's always ready.
I can take it anywhere.
It never happened that something stopped
working or something is better.
Just change the Indian
oil on a timely basis and that's it.
Mostly American driven
cars.
Okay, If someone has created this area,
please share it
with the rest of the students
so that you can save some time.
There you go.
Thank you, Julia. Thank you.
So this is your area
and it contains some elements. Simple.
You simply have to print them
using two different loops.
Guys.
Those who you knows
who have an electric car
is it cheaper to have electric cars
as compared to fuel,
for example, the charging cost?
If you are charging it at home,
the electricity bills that you get,
how much is the difference.
How much is the difference
compared to the fuel?
Pretty much same in the UK unless and
until you have solar, I don't think so.
It makes sense to have electric car right?
Unless and until you have solar
panels for them.
I mean, obviously I don't think so.
Anyone is driving
more than 300 or 400 kilometers per day
and not many
charging points.
You lose that fast or obviously
how can I forget the initial cost?
It's also
a lot of money upfront
maintenance
is costly. Yes.
I think
now every country is giving tax rebates
and the they are they are saying
everyone should be electric.
I think in the US as well,
when you buy a test for an electric car,
you get a lot of money, you know,
17, $15,000 or 17 something like that
region, country 30
Tesla drop from 60 to 20.
It can really
this is how much they were making.
Oh my God.
You can imagine how much money
these companies make, right?
If someone is selling the same thing
at 28.
Okay,
They were at least turkey to cable car
Tesla keep made or they have
reduced the features
or other cutting costs or
well purchased.
By the way.
Congratulations, Bernie.
You can also I heard you guys
have started manufacturing locally
the Tesla as well in India
we claim for you every year
during IPR
a hear here as well.
In Pakistan,
I think there are 16 plus brands, 16 or 19
that are bringing the review
that everything M.G.
Boudreaux Toyota, Honda
is also the by they are very expensive.
Okay.
So everyone is able
to get all of the names of the cars
past using the index based loop and then
we have Honda IKEA there they are on here
and then the using
the enhanced for loop as well
okay, can you please send me the
send me the
to the
area again so that I can save some time
time.
Thank your number is
if you guys are not talking in English
I will start teaching you in Japanese
or so
I am putting AK out to the at school.
I'm Luke Garcia a.k.a Elements Access
Kazakhstan or gas and print car.
So that
it back now. Okay
so let's first
try to do it with
the enhanced volume
so we write for
all in lowercase
and then we specify the guy
what we will be getting from
this to the area.
We get one B areas
first from the to the area.
So that's why we always have the right
and the data type
and then the square brackets,
because this is how we represent
and this is how we create a nati,
and then you can call it rows or
single cars or whatever.
It's just variable name.
It does not have to be a roll.
You can call it anything.
For example, you can call it simply R
Then this column, it's part of the syntax.
It's it's
or it will always be there no matter
what kind of data
you are attracting through.
And after the call
and we write the name of the collection
through which through
which we are going to iterate.
So from the cars,
which is a to the anti,
we will be getting individual
one The ad is with the help in this loop.
So if we are interested in
only in one of the areas,
then we don't have to write anything else.
But if we are interested
in individual elements
from those one D areas,
then we need to write one more loop
and that loop will basically a goal
will go over this R,
which is going to a complete
one D at a one by one,
and it will get the individual items,
individual car names,
which are of type string.
So let's say you can call it car
or C for short,
and then you write odd here.
And now if you bring D value C
you will be getting all the cars.
So let me remove the alien
and let me put some space here
and then an empty
print in any.
So we get all of the names here. Okay
then someone send me
the code for the index based loop.
Do you want me to go over the index
best based?
No question how to use the index based
loop to go through all of the elements.
I think it's very easy.
A variable.
So here
we have the index
based
loop so there can be change in this cost
to the names name and index it.
So starting from zero
I less than fast cars are all planned
and then God's eye
dart land for the inner loop
to exact same map.
But this one using the index for this one
using the
in henceforth
please ask if something is not here.
Also system dot or print that is or
not need to string.
Yes, this is going to also work.
It can work with one due to the 3D.
How many of you were not able
to solve this task?
to print the elements
from?
For me, index based is easier,
whichever you prefer.
It's fine.
The enhanced one will make your code loop
a little easier,
but obviously it has limitations.
So most of the time, one way or the other
way, you be going with the index.
This.
Oh, okay.
So let's see
using to really create
a growth released inside,
you should have an array of vegetables,
fruits,
dairy products, sweets,
then retrieve all the values from data.
Using is the exact same thing. Those
look at this.
Look, look at this.
Or you want to wait here.
I talked to this class was short
and mentally prepared for self.
Oh, you believe me? See,
you guys will believe me.
Less than perfect.
You guys want a short class
crying?
I was just trying to get your attention
so that you can focus
all of your attention,
and then I can teach you to the areas
because they are hard to understand.
So it was district three guys.
Okay?
I was just getting.
Yes, today's a short class, so
I can give you the projects
and you can solve ones as your homework.
This task task number two,
exactly the same as the first one.
Let me pause
straight in the class announcement
and you can
solve these ones as your
as your project.
So let me see.
We created the project.
I am not looking at the chart right now.
So if someone is asking something,
please give me a few minutes.
So this is your project number one.
So first part of the project is
you have to do coding.
You can use Google,
you can ask for help from each other,
but if you directly start
looking for the solutions or start
for asking for help, obviously
you will not be learning anything.
So I want all of you to first try give
15, 20, 30 minutes for each task
and then discuss with your friends
and then only look for help.
So first is create
a program that uses an added
to store
the list of competitors for a week
and then use a loop to find the highest
and the lowest temperature for the week.
Similarly, create an array of integers
that is created to calculate the sum.
So if let's say
you are this coding package for everyone
does not matter
if your group members are three, five
and 15, everyone individually
should solve all of these tasks.
The first part coding part
and the second part.
You all know how to create the YouTube
account.
Everyone you all know how to create
a YouTube account or how to push code.
So this project you have to push
the solutions on the GitHub
and then you have to share the link of
that of your to second parties.
You have to record the video. And
for example, there are one, two,
three, four, five, six topics.
So from the six topics you can choose
topic one person, one topic.
Let's say for
example, the yes,
the flip made these statements.
So you have to record 3 to 5 minutes on
what are if statements.
Give an example, explanation and all. Yes
we did one for format.
You can also do it in groups.
Just record one complete video in
which all the members are going one by one
and then explaining their parts.
So what do you think
this one here,
the deadline for this recording tomorrow
because you still have around
one and a half hour.
So I think it's enough for you
to prepare one topic and then record it.
So this one
you have to do until tomorrow for one,
you have one week recording one.
You can join group one.
No, I don't want to join. I'm fine.
I will do my assignments alone
and my project alone.
Okay, So is the project clear to everyone?
Voting is due in one week.
One code link per group. Yeah. Let me
go to the flip grid and let me make the
folder available.
You can we record solo?
I mean, without being part of Zoom
with others?
Yes, you can do that.
But it's better to do it in groups
because if you do it solo.
No feedback, nothing.
You will not be getting anything.
So SDLC, you have already done
All right.
So it's the exact same thing.
Let me see if we are for him.
Okay, maybe we'll see.
So in this one,
Java Basics,
we make it to really.
And these are topics are also written
here.
Maximum lantheus transmitter. Same thing.
So start date today is 19th of August.
We change to the
in the end it is
let me get in the let's
let me give me one extra day there.
Say the deadline is Monday but
because we are ending the class early so
I hope
most of you will do it right now
because it's very hard
to make sure that everyone is present
in the group group.
Okay. Can you guys
make sure you can access this link?
Let me copy and paste it into course
announcement.
Please click on this link
from the course announcement and tell me
if you can see and uploaded
all options are looking.
Can we add people to our group?
Yeah. Yeah.
You can rearrange the groups
if you want, but
we have to sign up to the flip.
You should
already have signed up for this.
How many of you are seeing this flip grade
for the first time? Oh,
okay. Wow.
So all of you, those who are seeing this
for the first time,
you have already missed one project
actually from your SDLC
classes.
You have already missed.
So please sign up for this
and you have to record the videos
this time.
Someone else in your group did it.
Okay, let me see
all the
SDLC.
The way it's been registered.
They have been in. Then
the PAN, we had
this main shed and we're like this.
You will run and
and guys, please don't do this.
Look here.
I can clearly see that
the reason
the screen in your glasses, right?
This is visible.
If you
if you guys are reading
from somewhere, it's very bad.
The purpose of this video is to be able
to understand and be able
to explain something to others.
When you will be sitting
in the interviews,
they will not be allowing you
to look at notes or Google or something.
So if you really want to do it,
do not put your glasses on.
And I'm not saying she is cheating,
I'm just giving you an example, so
don't worry about
her. You are
look at the issue.
You guys look a totally different thing
in real
life.
Must be very,
very hard to believe in doing the project
to solve
doing
this.
So reading from
somebody is not good.
Ah yes.
I will share the document
at least.
So we
so we for our
people, people with
we will
like to see reading
from some very not good
recording early.
So you know
and I'm in terrible
for maximizing the value of the product
we brought in from work obviously from all
other activities
by reducing human errors, saving time
and improve internet coverage and
everything that we can do on anytime
on today in the fashion,
do one more thing.
Please introduce yourself as well.
Tell your name
so that we know because in pictures
you guys look like from your
Hollywood or Bollywood. But
I don't know in the
you guys look like I'm just kidding.
It's always good introduce yourself name
and the group number
and then please start explaining.
Otherwise it's partners.
We have very hard time. So
having reviewed regional,
we know the whole
the people will remember you
and I think percentages are incredible.
Remember? Madina, what are you doing here?
Look,
I just trying to enjoy the same look.
Remember, we are going
get this for the project
right?
And we.
Okay, it's good.
Just make sure that eye contact is good.
You are not reading from somewhere.
Introduce yourself and please do not read
from notes or something.
It's for your practice
when you will be sitting
in front of the interviews.
They will be asking you questions
and you will be explaining things
in exactly the same way.
So it's a practice for those sessions
I was looking for fish.
Okay, let me share that document with you
too. Okay.
I have shared the document.
It contains the coding questions
as well as the topics
for which you have to record the video.
If something is not clear,
please ask these videos about Photoshop
coding for the coding.
The deadline is next week for the videos.
It's Monday
and I will be watching
all of your videos one by one
and then I will give you a collective
feedback.
So please do not read from somewhere.
I want you to.
You can look at the topic
before you record the video,
go through it, collect the examples,
but then once
the recording starts,
I want you to explain it
by heart.
No, not from normal
for reading from somewhere.
Is there anything that
is not clear about the project?
Make sure no glasses.
I can still figure it out from your eyes.
If your eyes are moving like this.
The reading
clear
and you are reading line
by line, it's out of here.
The more we move them around here
and there.
Look, sometimes here and there.
Yes, this is going to work.
Very three groups.
Everyone left from the groups.
If your group members are left,
you can create new ones.
You can join other groups.
If there is a space available.
Okay.
So that's it for today to the areas
was the last topic in the basics from
tomorrow
we will be starting the object
oriented programing.
This one is a good experiment
is to share it
with you.
Once we have talked
about the basics of Java, it's
so great to watch these videos
before tomorrow.
So actually it's a lot of work to.
Do you have to record the videos
on DEADLINE is Monday
and you have to watch these videos
before tomorrow.
Question Are we supposed to do Zoom and
then record and submit it to distributed?
You can record individually as well
and then share your videos
with one group member
or can combine that and then upload.
But it's going to take a lot of time.
So I think Zoom is better.
They are due next week.
Okay.
If there are no questions,
we can call you today and you can start
working on the videos videos.
What if there are more members then topics
you can repeat to members
and go over the same topic.
Also, what about boys?
All took our direct message you to ask
What was the answer?
If you go and check,
if you open that quiz, you should be able
to see the answers I need to
someone about what would be the agenda
once the deadline is passed.
You can all see the answers
of your week, which quizzes?
I saw the answer but not the exact answer
regarding order of operations is
you can also take that order
and execute that code in your intelligent.
The question was first,
you have to figure out the calculations
you remember the presidents multiplication
and division modulus.
They are performed first from left to
right and then addition and subtraction.
How are we going to divide to the groups?
You are not already in a group
B is coming from the line above it,
so you calculate aid.
Then you calculate B,
and then you perform this A left and B,
Okay.
Is there any space available in any group
or can
anyone who to take
you are able in his or her
group, those who do not have group
you and groups,
you can also create new groups
your post in this index student gender
and if you do not have any group,
you can create
a new one
group that is hiring.
Can we have direct link to record video?
I think in this in flip grade you can
directly, you can also directly record,
but it's good if you do it in group,
you will be able to get feedback.
You will get this confidence
that you can speak in front of others.
Solo is not good because remember,
we are preparing you for interviews.
Interviewers,
they are usually 3 to 5 persons
and you have to explain things
in front of them.
So you do it.
If you do it in groups,
it's better not go solo.
I do not recommend it.
How I join the group then.
Melissa
you have to pay the membership fee.
It's under dollars.
I will send you the account and
then you can join the group number ten.
Can anyone take me please
sign Harakat in his or her group?
You guys can post in this
index donor channel
and those who have some space
you can take.
That's a lot of money. Sorry.
How to get the flip grid?
I have shared
the link in course announcement.
What is the deadline for reporting?
Monday?
Monday.
Okay everyone,
please start working on your projects
and I will see you tomorrow.
Regarding Monday. Regarding Monday,
according part next week.
All right, everybody. Bye bye.
Take care.
And I will see you tomorrow.
Thank you.