Okay.
So let me try to.
So last time
we started discussing about the, um,
string class.
Well, why this string class is important
or what is this string class?
Why we are even discussing it.
How do I figure it out
if they are trying
to figure out this?
And we did it. And there is a process.
Um, it's called thinking.
You have to think.
And then you have to write the logic
and been with loop or without the loop,
you will be able to do it.
Okay, So what is this, a string class?
Thinking is hard.
We can go step by step and break it down.
And one more thing
some of you might not understand properly
are all the cases about the prime numbers.
Understanding how prime numbers work
first and then try to.
Logic will also help you a lot
if you understand what you are doing.
You can easily break
that and break down that problem.
And then you can write code for one
or two steps at a time. Tested.
And then write more.
So understanding the problem
first is very important.
As some of us,
we also make this mistake in the exams.
Usually
we don't read the complete question
or we fully don't understand,
and we just try to hide the answer
and we lose a lot of marks
in the exams as well.
So it's perfectly fine if you
are reading it two times, three times,
so that you can understand it easily
and just know that
they cannot be divisible by any number
other than yourself.
No, there are more things to that.
Negative numbers are not prime numbers
is zero prime.
They also start from the number one.
So there are more and more education
that you need
to fill it out.
Okay, everyone,
let's discuss it right.
Yeah.
Just make sure you try in the room
so that one no one sees.
Are we allowed to go back to the exams
to use a quiz for family members
to test on us with? You can.
So what is this?
A string class, everyone?
Well, why do we use this string class?
What does your test
hold?
A lot of data.
What kind of data?
So a string class
is designed to score almost every symbol
that you see on a keyboard,
whether it's a letters, alphabets, ABC,
whether it's numbers
1015, 20, whatever,
or whether they are special
characters like dollar
sign, high sign, personal design.
And in
a string
you can store these symbols as a group.
So string
classes are designed to store symbols
in the form of a group.
And if you focus
carefully,
most of the processing,
most of the calculations
that are manipulations on the computers,
they are in the form of strings.
Right.
For example,
take the banking applications,
everything your username, password, bank
account, balance, details, everything
other than your picture.
They they are stored
in the form of strings
on Facebook, Amazon, everywhere
you see text.
Most of the information around us
is present in the form of text
on your even the balance you can store
in the form of a string, but usually
they are not stored in that form,
but it is capable of storing that as well.
So because most of the information
in in real life around us
these days, it's in in this form.
That's why this string class
is very important to understand.
It's very important to understand
how to store this information.
It's also very important to understand
how to manipulate this information.
And because of this and this,
the same reason most of your interviews
I mean, I have not seen any interview
hardly there were any questions
or something in which this string class
was not involved in the interviews.
Always loops, arrays, if conditions.
And this string class is nothing else.
When I draw down
these are very important
for your coding question
during interviews,
almost every interview question
when I'm talking about
specifically the part where
they will be asking you to write code.
So there is one verbal part, 1
to 1 questions
in which you have to answer verbally.
And then there is this part
in which you have to write
or they will be giving you a very small
example.
They will be asking you to solve
a very small problem or something,
just like the problems that I have shared
with you in the coding questions.
For example,
find the largest, smallest reverso string.
How many characters are there
and things like that.
Slowly,
once you see more examples and I routine,
I will
I will keep on telling you the topics
and for which part
they are very important.
So from the topics
that we have covered already
in the coding part
where you have to write code,
these are very important.
You should be very good
with these topics.
So this string class is designed to store
all of the numbers, letters, characters,
special characters in this format
in the form of a group means
you can store to three four.
There is a limit of 2.14 billion.
This limit is same as the maximum number
that you can store inside an integer.
Okay.
Now not only string class helps us store
this information.
There are so many matters
which are already written
by Java developers
that you can just use
to just write the name of the method
and then it will process that string
and it will give you back the reserves.
For example,
we saw the Lent method, right?
If we have a string stored
in a string variable,
we simply call that length method.
It automatically counts
how many characters
we have stored inside of the string
and gives us the results.
And we saw the other methods
uppercase, lowercase
contains stocks for garnishment,
so these methods are already written.
The logic is already written
by someone else.
We just need to
know how to use these methods
in so
there are
many methods
already written
by Java developers that you can
just use.
But if we want to use a method,
we first need to understand
what are methods,
how they are related to a class,
how we call those matters
and how do we get results back.
So for example,
these were some of the methods
that we went to.
Okay.
So if you remember, can you tell me what
all this contains method?
Do you
so it searches
if searches for the provided
string,
if it is present, it returns boolean true.
If it is not present in that string,
it pretends to be false.
Okay.
There is one more important thing
in this class.
This is the most
widely new class in Java
and at this point there are around
10,000 classes
which are written
by Java developers for us.
And then on top of that there are library
and frameworks and everything.
And out of all those 10,000
classes,
this is the most widely used class.
So I hope you can understand
the importance of this class.
Each and every method, each and every
concepts concept that I'm teaching you.
It's very important.
So please
make sure you understand it properly
about it.
Why we should
learn about
this class
were very
important for
boring questions that we will be getting
most widely
used class an all
new java
and then
most of the information
and real life
meanings is an
all strings.
Also, there is one more thing.
Half of my brain is not working today.
It will start working
maybe on a monday or Tuesday.
So if I'm saying something different
and I am writing something different
and I am meaning
something totally different,
please, you should all order.
The user would understand it by default
for the next two days.
Yeah.
Usually when I get this flu
and severe fever and everything in my mind
brain does not work properly,
thank goodness.
Okay,
so I hope you everyone now have an idea.
What is this strain?
Why we are learning it? Why?
Why it's important
where we will be using you turn everything
I have taken on this and by the way,
it helped me a lot this time.
Usually previously
it used to take around
seven days for me to fully recover,
but this time it was quick
lemons and
it's very helpful.
Okay, so now we will continue
to learn more methods
from this training class.
And starting from today on these matters,
they get a little bit technical
because we will be passing the information
inside these matters.
Then they will be processing it
and then will be returning us to results
here.
It is very good.
I'll I'll get here doing so.
Let's say we have a stream now.
I am calling it SDR for short
and to see
I'm writing something like this.
So this streaming, it contains a lot of
characters, right?
And you remember the range?
Sorry, the ad is
they were in that structure that can store
multiple items in the same variable.
And when we have to access the items,
we can simply use the index
and then we can access those items.
So if you remember,
everything was given a number,
the number we call as ADI.
Do you think here also we can use an ADI
or maybe
Java developers behind the scenes?
Have we used an array to store
all of these letters?
What do you think?
Is it possible?
Exactly.
So Java developers also behind
the scenes, they use
an ADI
to store all of these letters.
And if they are using an array,
let me also show you
artist find.
It will not make much sense.
But let me quickly show you.
I have four.
I'm holding down my control
and then clicking on this string class
look, okay, don't worry
about this private final byte
focus on on this part byte value.
And actually, this is not the one
in which we
solve behind the scenes.
There is an area that holds the hold
all of the characters.
So if there is an area
that is holding this data
format gives come on,
that means this will make it
a little bigger.
If there is an array behind the scenes,
that means this B is present at index
zero.
Is that one, the two
three or
the spacing there at five
is six seven, Right.
And then we can keep on going like this.
Now tell me, everyone.
Oh, by the way, in this string class,
things are neutral, different
than how things work with areas.
For example,
if you say SDR
and then if you're trying to write
this zero here, just like
we used to do with arrays,
you will get an error.
So this is syntax
because there is a class.
This is not going to work here.
It will only work when you create
added yourself here.
If you want to access any element
from this, you have to use a method.
So let me clear one thing in Java
almost everything.
99.99% things.
They are classes
and these classes
they have methods.
And whenever we want to implement.
Sorry.
So whenever we have to do any manipulation
or when
whenever
we have to access something or something,
we use methods for example.
Yes. To get a stored in the form
of an array behind the scenes.
But if we want to access,
we have to use a method and the method is
called char at.
So what we are saying here that
from this string str,
I want the character act
index zero.
So what this method will do,
the method name is job
and I'm passing a zero in parentheses.
So what this will do,
this will give me back the letter B
because this is the letter
that is present at index number zero.
If I execute this,
I will see in the letter B
and index zero.
Then you quickly
execute this on your end as well
and confirm it with your decision
and liquidate my laws.
I will be back in here in just 2 minutes.
So all of you
get the same results.
Okay.
And and and
tell me if I want to get this edge
or hedge.
What should I ask inside the char method?
So this is 0612, three
nation is at index four.
Okay.
And if I want to get this last dot,
do you think it's a good idea to count
all of the characters default or
there is a better way
those who are saying ends with
what does this what does this matter do?
And does it return the index of something?
Does it return a number?
For example, let's say in
last index I declare a variable
and then so those who are saying and will
follow, what should I do and with
and I should pass the dot here
and we will return a boolean.
So how a boolean value
will help me get the character block
last index
ends with simply returns a boolean.
True or false?
If something is ending
with a specific word or a character,
it will return a true.
Otherwise it will return that false.
So we are only left with this choice.
Either.
Either we manually count
the characters like this
and it will come on down.
This one is
what if the characters will grow?
Let's say a screen contains
1000 characters.
Will you count it manually? No.
So what we can do
instead of counting them manually
a week and
use the length
method, this length method
will it return the last index
or the total number of characters
in the screen?
For example, What do you expect if, let's
say, for example, if I print last index,
what do they expect?
What output I will see
this last index
I want all of you to answer.
If I say
SDR, dot land
and whatever value is being returned
from this land time
storing it inside the last index
and then I'm printing it.
So what output I will see
exactly.
Most of you are wrong, which means either
you guys don't revise things
before coming to the next class
or you don't even open your computers
or not even going through the slides
so it
will not
return and that will not return the 17.
It will return the total count,
which is 18,
just like the land
to matter from the add a
length methods, the return total
number of elements not in the last index,
and because the index is the start
from zero, last index is always
one less than the length.
Let me repeat because index is the start
from zero time in place,
post and disappear channel
because the index is the start from zero.
They are always one less than
the total length or total size
or total number of elements
in that area or string or whatever
you are dealing with.
So it will always be one last time.
So if we are interested
at the last element,
what we have to do, we have to
subtract one
from this.
Let me let me change it
to length instead of last index.
Let me
notice.
SDR not land
and then minus one.
And now I will be getting the start.
I have done something different here.
Everyone look at this.
What I am doing.
I have this println method
starting brackets.
Then I have got shot at method.
Then again in brackets
and then the length matter.
Do you see this?
I am calling one method inside
another method
and inside that method
I'm calling another method.
I am nesting
your favorite topic.
I am nesting multiple methods.
I am calling these matters
one inside, another one.
Do you see this?
This print println.
It is a method
and then inside that
I am calling another maturity
which is charged with an entire charter
method.
I am calling another method
which is length
method.
So what would what is happening here?
Plus to Java
we will solve this part.
It is called calling the method
nesting.
The cause of the methods inside
one another.
So not waves.
It's not that hard to understand.
This SDR client or this method will return
the most last start from the most in a
method.
This SDR total and what this will return
the total number of characters,
and that is 80.
And then we are subtracting one
from that 18 -70
will be equal to 18 months.
One will be equal to 17.
Right?
This is 17
that we will be getting from here.
It will be passed
to this SDR DOT charter method.
If we pass 17 to charter method,
it will return us to start
the last character
inside our string.
Right.
So the result of this will be a dock
and then DART
will be passed
to the print and then method
and this println method will print it.
So basically what, what you can do,
print it like this.
For example, in KFC or drive thrus,
you stop at one place right?
You will give them your order.
Then you take your food maybe, let's say,
then you pay, right?
These are all connected, right?
First you have to place the order,
then maybe pay
and pick the ordered end and then leave.
So this thing here,
it is like placing your order first.
And our client will call
this lantern method, which
will give 18 different window functions
all together, happening all together.
So this will calculate the last index.
Then that last index
will be fed to the chart or method.
That method will go
and pick the last character,
and then that last character
will be given to put into the method
which will print it.
So here multiple methods are being called
one inside another one
that it makes sense.
We can break it down, separate
to a separately as well.
For example, this.
So now I will unfold this,
I will unfold this
and we will go step by step.
And this is how it will look like.
So first of all, I will do this
part.
Oh, by the way,
those who are following me, I am changing
this last index to
length that it does not confusing.
So end
last index is equal to
SDR dart
length
minus one
and print it.
Let me also put in some stars
so that you can see the difference.
It's shift six
refactoring.
Okay, so
welcome to last index and then
once we have the last index,
we can get the character and that index
by pulling the charter method.
And charter
tomato requires us to pass a number.
And that number
we already have works disaster index
and then we have the print method
which is printing it.
So this code, this line
here, it is
same as
this one.
And you see the benefit of this approach.
Now, something
that can be done in one line.
If you do it one by one like this,
it will take three or four lines
and the result will be same.
So here for us,
the last index will be calculated and then
the character, that index will be first
and then it will be printed here.
The exact same result.
Part one is doing all of that on this.
The line, look,
this is giving us.
So this line here
it is returning us to start here.
And then we are we're ending
the last index and then our daughter game.
So it all to the same output.
This is our
and then we can go dog for one second
so that you can see two different
and same output dot, dot.
But in one case
we have to write three lines
in another case
we are writing this only one.
So this is possible.
You can call multiple methods
one inside, another one.
Oh, sorry.
Yes. And the only other. Correct.
And that's why we are subtracting minus
one value.
Would you prefer variable strategy
or sticking with our client?
Darling, this is this is.
This is what I will do.
This one here.
This is nothing more.
More lines of code.
And that's going to wait
here.
Is there a method of string
showing index number, for example?
I right,
it will give me index number esthetics.
This is what we will learn next.
After this method at
I do not understand
the minus one since we have learned method
and you re-explain
of minus x.
What?
Okay, so
dark matter the
satellite
internet. I don't know.
Something is wrong with it.
I have changed the connection. Hopefully
we will be good now
in your connection box.
Okay. The
everyone can hear me now right
now Department.
Sorry
so dark matter can give us
and the character
and the index
that we specify inside the parent
teacher is
everyone understands this.
Okay.
Do you think we can also write a loop
to get all the characters one by one
from this string?
Yeah.
So let's do that.
Which type offer loop
normal one enhance one.
Why loop do y loop
and likes why loop
the Let's use the normal loop for now
because at this point you don't understand
how to use the enhanced one.
Was there any event or something?
Why everyone most of
you have new pictures.
Am I the only one who is using the same
picture for last three years?
Party?
Okay.
So this loop, should I start it from zero
or something else? Yes.
And what should be this?
I less than
SDR No Land.
Why? I'm not subtracting here.
Why Am not subtracting minus one here.
Exactly.
Because here we are using
the less than sign.
We are not using
the less than equal to sign.
So let me see parental two point statement
and then
SDR got to fact I
and this on it.
Okay.
So everyone,
can you confirm if you get the same result
each and every character
being printed on a separate line
and what is this?
But why? There is this empty after edge?
There is nothing.
And then, yes,
it is because of this space.
Okay.
Is there anyone who do not understand
this score that I have written here
on good.
Okay, let me give you a challenge.
Let's see how many of you can solve it.
You have to write a piece of score
which will count how times
the number e has appeared
in this screen.
You have to write a piece of board
that will count
how many times
the letter E has appeared in this string.
Let me write it down.
Do you think it's possible
or It's very hard to figure out
the logic for this.
Do you want me to give a hint?
You can use a false conditions
and you might need to declare
a variable to hold the count.
You have to use the false conditions
and you might need a variable
to hold the count.
Do you think it's possible now
or are you still hard to figure out?
And I think you have done very similar,
very similar thing in your adage as well.
Very, very similar.
So I don't know if you maybe you want to
look back at your knowledge of how to
let me know
once you are done.
There you go.
We have a new picture from C as well.
Yes. Alex,
please don't share the code and also
use some proper good names
for your classes.
We are calling your class and dee
dee dee dee dee dee dee dee dee dee.
How many of you are stuck?
Not know how to do this.
By the way, the answer is two.
You should be getting
two as down to
30 more seconds.
And then I, I
and I want all of you to try
now. That's correct.
Okay.
So I hope it was easy for all of you.
So we need one variable
to hold the count and
count
it initially.
You can initialize it with zero
and then instead of printing it,
you can see if
asked to start cha add.
I is equal
to equal to the letter E
and then increase the count
plus plus
and once you are done
then you can put into account deficit.
This was the solution
to it.
Is there anyone who has any questions?
Is it okay to use the political tool
string?
Ehab Is it a string or character?
It's not a string.
With strings.
We use double codes
and lookup the name of the method as well.
It's a character.
It is returning you a character.
Very. You are using double codes
instead of the same.
I kept using double code
and wondering why I was getting better.
Then we changed method to check for case
sensitivity.
Yes. Okay.
Do you have any questions from here?
This is running through each index
and or child
which gives indexes, not indexes.
It is going through each element, not
index each element with the help of index,
with the help of
index, it is going through
all of the characters
one by one,
and then we are checking those characters.
If any of those character
is the character,
if it is, we increase the count.
Yeah, let's debug it.
Let the label point here.
Yes, that's correct.
We don't go
look, we need to
so initially counted zero.
Then we start at look from zero
and this charted method
will give us the character
which is present at index zero.
Which character is present
at index number zero.
It's B
is B is B equal to eight?
Is this condition true or false?
False.
The condition is false.
We will not enter the if condition
other than the if condition.
Is there anything else
prevalent inside this loop? No.
So we go back
and fetch the next character.
So here.
So I, I will be increased from 0 to 1
and then we will fetch the character
at index one.
Which character is present
at index number one
mean is a equal to the Yes.
If condition will become true
and if the condition is true,
we increase the count
so the count will be increased by one.
Initially the count was zero,
now we've increased to one.
So look, count right now is one.
Then we fetch the next character
present at index number two,
which is the character T
again, B is not required where.
So condition will fail
then refer to the next, next, next, next.
It keeps on doing
this for all the characters
and when it sees the letter
E, it includes the value of count,
otherwise empty
and looking to enter to the end.
We will get the count,
which will tell us how many times
we encountered dilatory.
Oh yeah.
What if there was an uppercase here
somewhere?
It will not count it.
If you want to.
Actually 17 is
incorrect.
Okay, so let's say we have a
90 string, right?
And somewhere
we have the uppercase as one.
So now if we run this again,
it will still only count to be
a lowercase means.
If we want to check the applications,
we can use the R,
and then we can say SDR, Dart,
Char and
I is equal to equal to.
But see,
so now
that it sees the location
or whether it sees the uppercase
in any of these cases,
it will increase the count.
So now we see six
yes, we can use the times we had
to use the ignore case.
We have to convert all of the
string to lowercase.
And if we do that,
it will be a lot of unnecessary
processing.
Imagine there are 1 million elements
just the Java code
will convert all of those 1
million elements to lowercase.
Then you will again
go through all of those 1
million elements to check
whether it contains the letter E or not.
So it's actually double
the processing here.
Computer has to do at least double
the amount of work will get doubled
for your computer.
So whenever you are trying to think
about the logic, also think
about how much work your
has to do in that case
out of that word within a string,
not characters,
I will show you that I would.
I will show you how to replace.
As with today,
we will learn all of these today.
So are there any questions from here?
Okay, perfect
to with
that we actually imagine we have
this screen
and from this the screen
we want to see
and the index of
the index of this letter, five.
So counting manually,
all of the characters
never, ever recommended.
And we don't actually have to do this.
But there is there is a method
and whatever you everyone let's do this
exercise
type the name of the variable SDR
and then press a dot
and then you will see the list of all
the available methods in the spring class.
Go through
all of those methods and tell me the name.
Try to guess the name of the matter,
which will tell me the index
of a specific character from a string
and go through and
and then try to.
You can also use Google.
You can also use Google Drive
to go on Google and search for a method
which in which can tell you
the index of a character
from a string.
Yeah.
The name of the method
is index of
election.
For example, for some reason
you don't have
the access to the internet.
What you can do, you can put your cursor
on the method name anywhere here
and then you can press control.
Q Control
and then. Q
Yes, and then then this
window should pop up.
You see this window?
Let me do it again.
So put your cursor anywhere.
And even if you have your mouse,
you see this
a lot of methods.
Just click on any of this, click
any of this.
The same for Mac.
Hover your mouse
and then click on any of the matters.
Do you all see the explanation
about this method
for Mac and seeing How about your mouse?
I need to show you
what all this explanation says.
Read it, Read this explanation and
explain to me what will work this method.
Isabelle
What are they saying in the explanation?
This method returns the index
within this string of the first occurrence
of specified character.
Meaning
if I specify, let's say the number five,
it will return me the index
at which in this letter five present.
So the name of the matter is an index of
If I don't understand
that method I can cover
my mouse would be my third name.
I can read your explanation.
I can also see some examples here
and then I can run it.
And also
go to the answer.
We all get the answer it.
And do you also understand
what this method
is doing?
Perfect.
Okay.
If five is present
two times, let's say everyone,
if five is present two times
three, the explanation again
and tell me for this method is going to do
read the explanation again
and tell me what this method
is going to do.
It is only going to return
the first index.
The index of the first occurrence.
Okay,
so now,
because we are done with the basics
slowly, I will teach you
how to be independent, how to use Google,
how to use charity beauty,
how to use documentation,
how to try to guess things.
So slowly you can be independent
and then start writing things
on your own.
Okay, so this is how this matter works.
It basically gives you the index of
the first occurrence
of the character that you pass here.
For example, if I was asked here,
what do you think?
What are
exactly I will be getting a zero.
I needed this answer.
I've seen it.
If you find index of some characters,
if you find
index of some characters and it's
in one
out, yes, we can find
the index of some characters.
You want to find the index of
multiple characters in one single result.
Maybe it will give me
a small possible.
It's not possible
and not possible
using the building methods,
but you can write your own logic.
So I guess in the class
I will teach you
how to create your own methods.
If let's say something is not present,
something is not done
by a job by developers,
and we have our custom requirements,
our own different requirements
for which there is no method
already present,
you can write your own
starting from tomorrow
and you will be able
to write your own matters. So.
So don't worry about
okay you know
let me cleared and a lot of times
it's the same string
that we used for the previous
of society.
Okay, There is this term
which is called substring.
What do you understand
from this term? Substring?
We're doing all we can.
What it will be
nested.
A string.
String within a string.
A part of this strain.
Can I.
Can I say that a smaller part of,
this bigger string.
Okay, so
let's say, for example,
I am interested in only this part
of the string.
They want to get
this part of the string.
Or let's say
I only want this part or let's say
I only want this part.
So from this bigger string,
I want a small chunk from this string.
So is it possible to do that?
Yes, it is possible.
And the method?
Try to guess the name for the method.
I want to get a substring
from this middle string.
Right. And just the name for doing it
starts with and ends with.
The first thing was that
who whoever is giving you this comes up
he or she is trying to misguide
because these are the wrong methods
to do that
and they return in boolean.
True or false,
they don't give you some strings.
Try to actually Google
or try to see any method is available.
Is there any method present
in the string class
which is called a substring?
Everyone tried to search for this method
of yeah,
the method is called substring. So
and this is how it works.
You'll get back,
you get back a smaller, shorter string
from this bigger string
and how you can use
your SDR dart
substring.
Okay, so let's say for example,
how many characters
are there in this highlighted string?
You don't have to count them.
And it is the wrong
answer.
No, it's correct.
17 around
1819, which is
okay,
you actually don't need to count them
and really
look at the bottom of your intelligent
look at this party.
Everyone look at this part.
If I am highlighting badge,
if I am highlighting badge
by looking at the bottom
of your intelligent
and you tell me how many characters
are present
in the badge word by
if I highlight this part
and you tell me how many characters
without counting
nine.
So the total number of characters
in this part which I am highlighting.
27 You guys were counting it
manually before.
Yeah, we guys are very hardworking,
by the way, so
if let's say I want to get
the rest off the screen, if
I want to get
the rest of the string. Yes.
So if I pass zero
and five
try to guess
if zero is my starting position,
five is my ending position
work output,
I will see
a while.
I don't see anything
I would want.
Exactly.
I'm not printing it
solid.
I get feedback.
Okay.
And if I say let's say zero
and 25 here,
we think I will be getting this first
highlighted part.
Yes, because my starting point is zero
and my ending point is back.
And if I do this,
if I do this,
if I make my starting point, I have six.
Let's see how many of you can guess it.
If my starting point is six
and my ending point is 25 plus,
tell me, will I see this badge?
Will I see this bad? No.
So you see how I am specifying the range?
How I am specifying the range
from that bigger screen.
And then I'm getting
whatever is present within that range.
So this is how the substring method works.
It requires you to pass a range,
basically a starting point
and ending point.
And from there the bigger string,
whatever is present
within that range,
it will give you that output
makes sense.
Is it easy?
Is it easy or hard?
It goes by index.
It counts dissipative as well.
It can't express it as well
because by index.
So let me push.
What do you use minus one here?
Is there any index or such
as minus one?
Do do indexes, do they exist in negative?
If I try to specify a negative
index, I will get a negative
string index out of bound.
Exception
indexes are always positive.
Is there a way we can tell
if we are starting or a negative space
besides the control we can tell.
Let me go over all the methods
and at the end,
by combining all of these methods,
you will be able
to do all kind of processing.
Okay, so let me do it again.
17 is a great bit.
Okay, Let's have a break now.
Time in which output
you are talking about.
Yes, that's correct. Six is included
and 25 is not.
How do you get this starting index fast?
You can select
that part and it will tell you
how many characters this part has.
And then you can skip those parts
by putting that number in.
Where are you automatically found?
It's so fun.
I'm not mad
in this anybody is not for
is it
for format. Okay
okay.
Output. Any questions wrong
from here?
Just asking you to simplify for me why
the dart is not printed.
Why the let's let's make it.
Let's do this.
Let's say we have four 0 to 4.
So this is how it works.
Everyone is here.
Can you give me a thumbs up? Right.
I would want it here
that I don't have to explain it again.
So this is how the substring
and generally every other method
is going to work.
The first value that we specify here,
whatever character is present
at this value
that will be included in the output,
but not this one.
For example, this for
the character that for is
B is are
208123 and four.
So the connector edge
the latter edge is present at index four.
Right Everyone
which character is presented
index world for edge
but that edge will not be printed.
It is not included in the output.
This starting index is inclusive.
This ending index is exclusive.
This is not included in the output here.
It is like less than
makes sense now and then.
Do you understand
now why this dart was not printed?
Because last characters are not included.
Okay.
Are you ready for a task?
Let me see if there are any tasks.
Okay, so this is the task for you.
You have to create a string
and just randomly store
anything inside that string.
And once the string is created,
you have to check
if the number of letters inside
that string, if they are odd, or even
if the number of letters are odd,
and if there are more than three
characters,
then you have to print
in the middle character from that string.
For example, if the string is hello,
the first thing you have to check
if it is even a rod.
So there is one, two,
three, four, five characters
present inside this string is five.
Even a rod.
It's odd.
So first condition is true
and are the number of letters
more than three or less?
More. So both conditions are true.
Number of letters plus the
all condition.
If both of these conditions are true,
you have to print this middle
editor.
This is the task.
Is the task clear to everyone?
Okay,
so please solve it.
You can ask questions
since the task is not clear.
Okay.
Which part you don't understand.
And it. No, no.
And don't wait to solve it.
Read the question,
understand it and solve it.
If you don't try, there is no way you
if you think you will be able to learn
that you are wrong.
We cannot learn like this.
We have to force their brain.
You have to think.
Tell me which line is not making sense.
Which which part?
Do not play. Uh,
is there any matter that can tell you
if a string is empty or not?
Yes, it's a very good code.
But remember,
you are trying to write be compact,
but you are not checking
for all the conditions
as per the requirement.
It's not good.
Yes, we have to write
the first condition. So
to follow all of the requirements
I counted first.
Yes, you have to count first.
If you don't count, you will not be able
to figure out if it's even or
by the way, those who are
done with the first one,
you can start working on the second one.
You have to print
a string in reverse order.
Instead, anyone who is still unable
to figure out what is going on here
Is there anyone also needs a hint
for the second part,
the hint is reverse loop
and no,
for the second part, reversals.
Okay.
Okay everyone, let's all this fuss far
and it with you.
Okay. So again, remember
in programing questions
breaking and breaking down the problem
in smaller steps
and then solving those smaller steps
one by one.
If the best approach, for example,
in the first part it says create a string.
So you can just focus only on this part
without even looking at the rest.
It's good.
It's very good
that you go through
the complete requirement once
so that you understand
the complete picture.
But then you, when you have to write
the code, you can go very
step by step,
one step at a time.
So create a string
so we can create a string
like this.
For example, any strings
here? The example is given for Hello.
So we can put the handle here
one one step at a time.
Now an expert
says if the string is not empty,
so this is the next step.
We want to make sure
that string is not empty.
How can we do this part?
How can we make sure
if a string is not empty?
We can use the example, the method
from this string class and
how this is empty method works.
It's going to return us a true
if the string is empty,
and if the string is not empty,
it's going to return as a false.
So we can say if
string
is empty
and we can put in note before folded,
which means if a string
is not empty.
So second step
next it says
If the string
is not emptied and perform the following
order,
we have to write more if conditions.
If string
has all the number of characters.
So now we need to figure out
if the number
of characters in a string or even a rod.
And before we can figure out
if it's even a rod,
we first need to know
the number characters in a string.
Is that any matter that can
give us the number of characters?
Exactly.
The name of the method is length.
We can say if
SDR and Lent this part, this piece
of code,
please give us the number of characters
and then
we can take the
remainder by two.
And if the remainder
is not equal to zero,
what does it mean
if the remainder is not equal to zero?
It means there's an odd
number.
So number of characters are odd
and we have to get further, further
and the number of characters
should be more than three
or three or more.
So should I put or condition here
or and continue
and condition
and SDR not Lent
is greater than or equal to three.
Now, some of you
might have gone my time gone.
One more step.
Tell me this goes
If a string
is having more than three characters,
is it possible that that string is empty?
Can can be empty
if the string has three character,
is it possible that it will be ever empty?
No. Then
do we need to write this condition?
Here?
I'll draw one
because this condition
is actually automatically being checked.
And here.
So that's how you can optimize your.
Could
this lend to greater than three?
It is also checking
if a string is not empty
the can this condition length
greater than three
it will only be true
if a string is not empty.
So what we can do, we can simplify output.
We can remove this part from here.
Is this point clear?
What I've just done in that clip?
Everyone.
Okay,
so next, next here, it's very simple.
We have to
we have to print the middle character.
So now how do I get the index
of middle character?
Exactly.
If there are all the number of characters,
if there are all the number of characters.
So for example,
if the number of characters are five,
if I divided by two, what time is it?
Will I get two or 2.5?
I mean, they're two
I will get to, you know, by
this this is an integer value.
Five is an integer, value
two is also an integer value
integer Dagger type
cannot hold the decimal part
in actual yes, the answer will be 2.5,
but because integers cannot hold
the decimal part,
this part will be ignored
and we would like to
and is to the middle.
Yes. Yes. Why?
Because index is the start from 0 to 0.
One, two,
three, four.
This is the middle character.
If there are total five,
the index for the middle
character is always one less.
Then remember index is the start from zero
so middle will always be one less than
the two here to here
and this will give us the middle.
So that's
why some of you might not understand.
But if you do this in the middle,
if you do this
SDR or not, and
divided by two,
you will get actually in the index
for the middle character
and then you can simply print it,
which method
I can use to get any specific element
at an index.
Exactly.
The method is SDR, dart, char add,
and then the index.
So that's how this code is working.
And and let's say
if I put only three
characters, lda
rejects for three characters,
not create indexes
is the length of this string
is three or more. Yes.
Are the number of characters or. Yes.
What is the land?
Lent is three
when this three will be divided
by two more to answer.
I believe that bond
and this is the index of listing.
So I'm gives.
Is there anyone who is still confused
about this part?
I'm going to remove the next example.
How many of you are still working
on the second part?
How many of you
are still working on the second part?
Okay, let me give you two more minutes.
Meanwhile, let me grab some water for me
and after 2 minutes
we will know this part again. And
but we have not discussed
the string builder yet.
How many of you are stuck or maybe think
this this is different or maybe hard
this in the second part
is your take.
Take your time.
Yeah, it's fine.
Anybody?
Why your home minister
is not in the picture
completely.
Does she know that you
this is what you did to her?
You cut her out out of the frame.
You don't love your life.
The only reason she took
this picture is so that she can tell
everyone that you are not.
You are already booked,
you are not available,
and you are doing the total opposite
of it.
You know, it's correct.
How many of you are still working on this
now? It's
You guys look great. Now
let's do this one.
Okay, So.
Oh, by the way, this question,
it's a very famous interview
question as well.
They give you a string
and then they ask you to reverse it.
Yes. Sometimes
they give you an array
and ask to reverse it.
So it's just a very famous interview
question.
Okay, Let's say we have a string PR
and then we have a string inside it,
and then you have to reverse it
and then print it.
So it's very simple.
You can simply reverse it
and then you can print it.
No, you guys don't like my solution
If I'm the perfect output.
Yeah, you can do that in the interview
as well. If.
Okay,
maybe some of you don't agree with me.
So there going to be
under a little bit.
I'm just kidding.
This is not to do it
and this is not what they mean.
So you can always start a reverse loop
and then you can start grabbing the
elements from the end one by one.
So let's say you have this loop
that I want to start from
zero, and then I want to go tail
the last character.
So what is the what is the index
of the last element?
SDR Client
So the last index, if I put SDR
DART length, will it work
or I will be getting in at it?
I'm asking about the last index.
NORDLAND Last index.
Last index is always,
always one less than the length.
Last index.
Let me repeat, last index is always one
less than the length.
So we have to subtract one
and now it will give me the last index,
the index of this. Why
And then this condition.
I want to go
till this character,
which is present at index zero
so I can see
I greater than equal to zero.
I want to go as long as I is
greater or equal to zero.
And because we
going in the reverse direction,
we see minus one what happens.
Without minus one, I would do one.
What will happen without minus one
out of bounds.
We will be getting index out of bound
now which method I can use
to grab the characters at these indexes
chart. Right.
So if I see SDR dart chart Act,
I, and if I run it,
I get all the characters.
But every character
is being printed on a separate
How can I fix this?
Remove all the elements
and only use the print
and then means new line.
So that's how we will be able
to get to the output in the reverse order.
How many of you still don't understand
how we are able to reverse the letters
yet? I mean, it's a very small thing,
whether you put it
horizontally or vertically.
So I am assuming you do not need
this reversed.
You can do that as well. That as well.
Like for
instead of printing here,
you can create another string variable,
reverse string,
and you can initialize it
with empty string initially.
And then instead
of printing these characters,
you can append
reverse and string is equal to reverse
suspend plus
you can append all of these characters
one by one in the reverse manner,
and then at the end
you can bring them.
So when some of you have done this,
this is also a good excuse.
This one is better.
This it is first time
you've changed before.
Look format.
No, no, no. We have done this many times.
Every one Did we write the loop already?
Many times
when we were practicing the loops.
Yes. So
maybe you have missed that part.
Okay, let's debug this code.
How many of you want me to debug
this note
here?
Okay.
So we have an empty variable.
If it is not reversing,
can we use extended loop
for calling the elements of a string
first? Why?
It will not reverse.
It will always reverse.
And second,
what do you mean by extended loop?
Do you mean enhanced loop?
If you use enhanced loop,
remember
you can not go into reverse detection
using the enhanced loop.
Enhanced loop cannot be used.
Nice. Can we?
Can we go in the reverse fashion using
the enhanced?
This was one of the limitations
of enhanced loop.
We cannot go reverse.
We cannot access elements.
And this was one of the limitations
of the so
initially
this PR dark land.
Oh, by the way, I don't I don't think so.
If I have shown you during the debugging,
if you want to look individual,
if you want to look at the output
of individual pieces of all,
you can also do that.
For example, if you first want to know
what this estimate
or client is going to return,
you can select this part
and you can click
on this evaluate expression button here,
this, this.
It looks like a calculator.
You can click on this.
Then it will open this window
in front of you
in which you can write any piece of code
from here, from this line,
and it will give you answer.
For example, if I click on Evaluate,
it is telling me
that SDR total Lent
is going to return six,
then you can also write minus one
and then it will tell you
that this will give you five.
You can also write
SDR Dart Char ad and you can put five here
and it will tell you that it will it is
going to just going to return y.
So if you want, even if you want to go
even in these teeny tiny details, it's
it's completely possible
using evaluate expression,
but it only works during debugging.
You read my mind. Yeah.
So SDR Land is going to return six,
then we subtract one from that.
It will give us five.
Then this condition will be checked.
Is a five greater than equal
to zero? Yes.
If the condition
is true, we enter the loop
and then again we have multiple pieces
here.
One piece, this one SDR shot
and it is fetching the character
at this index.
I the value of I right now is five
this park SDR shot ad
If you want to see where this part is
going to do, you can again evaluate
SDR or chart and I
will give you the letter Y.
Then you are saying then you are doing
reversed
plus.
So after returning Y
you can see it will get appended
to the string reversed
and the result will become y.
So even if you want to see each and every
step, well, whatever Janhvi is doing,
you can go into all of those details
using this
evaluate expression
and it's very helpful in debugging
complex course.
You did not get my question.
If we just want to pull the
elements of a string forward
and we use
enhanced loop instead of no enhanced
loop only works with arrays
and hence loop only works with arrays.
There are other data structures
that we will learn later on.
It can work with those as well.
So in this case, you have to
you actually have one or only one option,
and the option is
you first convert this string
to an array of characters
and once you have an array of characters,
then you can use the enhanced for,
Oh, by the way,
I want to show you that part.
What is the difference between printing
SDR DART chart?
It and then printing reverse? Nothing.
Here we are fast restoring
the output in a variable
and then printing it.
So output will not change.
So reversed plus SDR dart chart.
So keep an eye on this value of reversed
or non.
Then I would ask you to debug discord.
I don't think say one.
They will be allowing you
to use intelligent.
Most of the time.
These coding questions
which are given during the interview.
They will be on rapid or something
similar to that but
they will be sharing the link of a website
which will look very similar to Ripple.
And there you will solve the question
and your search to be
whatever you will be typing here.
They will also be able to see
on the other end
famous
platforms are occurring or they could be
called signal.
So these are the platforms that are used.
Yes, you will be able to.
So they see your mistakes
and figuring it out. Yes.
Yeah.
A big So next we get the
next element, which is
the tell your friend
that no, it's not allowed,
It's not possible.
So the next
the value of AI will decrease by one.
So it will be for and then it will grab
the element of the next four
and then it will append it with y.
So y e is The character at index four
will get appended with the letter y,
then the value of AI will further decrease
by one, making it three.
Then the element of index three which is D
will be grabbed
and then it will be appended
with this reverse string.
And slowly
we will keep on grabbing the elements
in the reverse fashion
and keep on appending goodness.
Reverse the string.
I have a friend who works on
I.t Company for two and a half years.
He could not create
for some tasks
we are solving
here.
Coding is not for everyone.
Okay, everyone.
So now we can do ask.
Can we use hand if we create it? Yes.
Then we can.
Yes, then we can.
And it's totally possible
he might be working as a man.
We're desperate
and automation is not the first thing
companies do.
They are always best do things manually
and once they see
something is being repeated again
and again and it is taking a lot of time,
then only the automated.
So he's actually paying for
or staying in that company.
Okay.
Mikail for opening
the evaluate expression window,
you need to be in debug point
and once you are in debug point, select
any part of the code
and then you can click on this button
here.
So then we have one more question.
This one is formatted once,
so you have to create a program
which will ask to be first of mom
and the first name of Dad.
And if they are expecting a boy or girl
and then it will suggest
the name for the baby
and this is how it is going to work.
If the if they are expecting a girl,
it will take the first 50% characters
plus two half
from the name of the mother
and second half
from the name of the father.
For example.
If they are expecting boy.
So program has taken
first of three characters
from the name of Father
and, last two characters
from Name of Mother,
and then it suggested the name Dante.
So in the case of Y
plus, two half
of Father and second half of the mother,
in the case of a girl,
plus two half from the mother's name
and the second half
from the father's name.
And then
to suggest the name,
what, just a girl to not worry about it.
We don't have to name
other things like this.
Okay, so this is your homework.
Let me give you this as your homework
from the part.
It means if there are six character
in the name of Mother
plus the three characters will be taken.
Even more examples.
For example, look here.
Okay, Don't worry, Madina, you are lost.
Let's take the example from Madina.
Where is after
again?
So let's say these guys,
they are expecting a boy
and they are expecting a boy.
Plus two half of the
father is going to be
taken in the case Y ERP.
And then second half
in the case of Mother,
and here is the name
for your boy, our DNA,
although it looks more like a female name,
but this is
our programing is working.
And let's see
if the parents are expecting a girl then.
So first half of the mother's name
and then second half of P
from the father's name. Yes.
So in the program, search
suggest this name
if they're expecting it.
Very well.
See the here and okay,
we have Aisha and I'll be right.
So names can be
all the numbers and even numbers.
So, for example,
if they're expecting a boy
will take the first half.
So what what will be the first
half in this case?
Okay.
So first half
from here and
second half
or her warning is going to be
and in the case of the
first half from the mother's name
and second half from the father's
name,
your family looks very funny.
Like, who else in here
from where you get this idea,
If just more intelligent brain, you know,
extra ordinary idea always.
You see those love calculators
or other things on online.
They're all working like this.
And no, don't worry,
I will solve it with you Next class. Yes.
For in the case of why first half
from the father's name and the second half
from others, again,
I have shared the question in the course
announcement.
You can use Canada if you want.
Yes. Okay.
So next is again, a very simple letter
in don't to use here.
You can ignore it.
Next method is very simple.
Let me create.
Okay. And please don't share this piece
of incredible piece of logic
with your relatives.
And don't tell them that you have created
very good, which can
relate or which can tell you
the names of the babies
based on the names
of their mother, father,
and whom
a next method is very simple, very easy.
And it's actually most useful, most widely
used method in the string class.
Let's imagine
if we have a string
that has a string
and let's say
you want to replace something
from this string.
Let's say
you want to replace this word with great.
So what you can do,
you can use the replacement part
to string new SDR
and the method name.
Can you guess the name of the method?
I want to replace the good with great
from the string class.
Can you guess the name of the matter?
The method is called Replace.
So it takes two
arguments, two values
plus is the screen
that you want to replace.
So in our case, we want replace.
Good.
And the second is
we do what you want to replace it
so you can say, great.
So wherever
in this string, wherever
the good keyword is present,
everywhere, it will be replaced
with the great keyword.
Then print out
this newest deal.
So the output will say Best 17 is great.
Try it on end right screen
and then try to replace something
from that string. Yep.
And this is the function
that you use basically in your word Excel.
I'm sure you have seen it in your editor
as well.
They extend it as they use it a lot.
Usually the shortcut is control F
or something like this. Yes.
So it's very simple.
And if there are multiple
if if the keyword is present
multiple times,
it will be replaced everywhere.
So this code and this word both
will be replaced.
So by 17 is great.
They are doing great.
And one more thing, if I put uppercase G,
do you think it will work?
No, because Java is a sensitive flip.
This is not going to work.
Yeah. Okay.
Any questions?
I think it's very simple, right?
Easy peasy.
Okay.
So how is everything so far?
The other than the basics?
We started from classes and objects.
Then we started learning new methods.
If we have two words for changing,
then we have to call this
method twice.
Oh, okay. There is one more thing
and we might see
and you might see this a lot.
Now this concept is called
the method of chaining.
We show you.
Okay, so let's imagine
we have a string like this.
A spot is equal to
something like this.
What you can do,
you can call multiple methods
on the same.
For example, you can do this
SDR, not too lowercase,
not not
dream, not
let's say we place
two. So what I have done here
I am calling multiple methods.
It will work just like a pipeline
in a factory or something.
So what is going to happen
first?
All of this, a string is going to
get converted to lowercase letters
because we are calling the two lowercase
method.
Then if there are any
spaces before and
after, let me put some spaces intentional.
Let me put some spaces in the beginning,
at the end of the beginning.
So then those spaces will be removed
and then
whatever string we get as result
in that string, the great keyword
if president
will be replaced with good.
So first
everything is converted to lowercase
and then when we will be converting
everything to lowercase,
obviously great is also
also going to get converted to lowercase.
Great.
And then it will be replaced.
So if I run this
we will see that 17 is great.
What about the spaces between the words?
No, we are not performing any operation
to remove or add
or do anything about those spaces yet.
But if you want to do something, yes,
you can incorporate that as this concept.
It's called method Chaining.
One method is being called
on the output of another method.
You are performing multiple operations
again on the same line.
Is this clear to everyone?
You can perform many operations
if you want on the same line, but
some of you might still not understand
it fully.
For example,
if I do this, I will get an editor
who can explain to me
why I'm getting a net and why I am unable
to change new methods in this case
and this dream just released
all the spaces before and after.
I exactly look at method
Chaining is only going work
if the output of one method is string.
For example, what output
in which form we get the output.
When we convert something to lowercase,
do we get a string back?
Yes. When we print something,
Yes. Replace all to return
the string here, this first method
is going to return a string,
but the second one is empty.
Does it return a string?
No. It returns the boolean.
And if a if we have a boolean,
can we call the replacement
to run a boolean?
No. So this is not going to work.
The previous method must return a string
for the next method to work a format.
30 is expecting a string.
It must the previous method
it must return a string.
Otherwise
this method chaining is not going to work.
Makes sense.
Why do we need to trim
or There is no logic, There is no point.
I'm just trying to show you
that you can call multiple metrics.
Well, we don't need to trim
so let me put it
here.
Also, one important thing not every class
sports methods training.
There is a specific thing that we need
to implement behind the scenes
for this method training to work.
So not expect it to work
with all the classes.
It works with the string because
it is designed that way. So
for methods Channing chaining to work
previous method must
return
the expected
type for the next method.
For example, for example,
a replaced method expects
a string, but is empty.
Instead of returning a string,
it returns a boolean.
So here it is going to fail.
Same matter.
It expects a string
and that's what lowercase is returning.
Similarly, replace method
is expecting a string,
and that's what claim is returning.
So only when the return type
of the previous
method matches with the input and whatever
input that next method is expecting,
then only method training
is going to work
slowly.
Then I will be using it more.
Things will get better.
Okay.
So until here we were actually using
very simple methods.
Now let's try to use
a little more on
more powerful methods
from the string class.
And one such method is
let's imagine
you have a number that occurs
special symbols, things like that, Right?
Something like this.
And what you want.
You want to replace is
let me put some uppercase letters as one
you want to replace.
Let's say all the uppercase
letters are lowercase letters
or or numbers or special characters.
So previously
we were looking for a for an exact match.
Here we are looking for pattern.
If this pattern is found anywhere,
if there are, let's say,
uppercase letters,
I want to replace all of them.
So here we are
not talking about a specific uppercase
letter, A, B, C, D, or Z.
We don't care.
We just care that the letter is uppercase.
We want to
replace all of those uppercase letters
with something.
So in this kind of situation,
we have another method.
It's called replace all method,
replace all.
And this method is works
on the regular expression projects.
The regular expression of value
is a pattern finding language.
You will learn some domain specific
languages in the future as well.
For example,
you will learn X spot, which will help you
identify elements from a web page.
You will also learn about
the growing jobs
and again, in domain specific language
domains, the concept of domain
specific language languages,
they languages designed
for a very specific task.
They are not languages
like Java White on C Shop.
They are designed
for a very specific block.
For example,
when you have to search something
from a larger text, when you have to say
something,
you have to specify a period of time
in these kind of scenarios
because these scenarios,
they can get a little complicated
exactly for the locators,
because they can get a little complicated.
So we have designed a specific languages,
and I will now take you
the basics of that language.
You don't need to learn all of it.
I will share the tools with you
if you want to learn all of it.
The name is a regular expression
injects or shock
and it is used to find patterns
from strings.
Let's do some examples.
It will make things clear.
So let's say
my requirement at this point is
I want to replace all of the uppercase
characters letters from the
So what I can do,
I can specify a regular expression
or I can specify a pattern here.
And for example, the pattern will search
for all the uppercase letters is
square brackets.
Instead, of course, then uppercase,
a little uppercase. See,
this is a square bracket
and this uppercase A dash and Z.
It is a regular expression,
which is a saying everywhere.
If, if anywhere,
if anywhere in the above string,
there is any letter present
from uppercase to uppercase Z.
Let's find it.
And after finding it,
let's say
replace it with the equal to sign
or anything you, if you like.
So what we are saying from
this is string a spot
wherever uppercase A to Z
letters are present, replace all of them
with equal to find.
So if we run this code,
look in the output.
There are two uppercase
letters E, e, and s.
At the end
they have
been replaced with equal to sign.
There were uppercase letters.
Is there s x?
They have also been replaced.
We need to find
actually this regular expression.
It's it is a link to your ASCII table.
Do you remember that?
I show you the ASCII table
of the perfect.
Let me show you more examples.
Then I will show you how it is
linked to that.
Ask a table.
What do think? Try to guess.
Try to guess If I say
A to C,
do you think this is z or x or S?
They will be replaced this time.
You know, only uppercase letters
from A to C will be replaced
with equal sign.
So look, S is still there.
That is still there.
As is true, their access to their.
So if you remember the ASCII table,
basically
it is working based on that ASCII.
David Let me show you more examples
and then I will show you.
Let's say, for example, this time
the requirement is
you want to replace
all of the lowercase letters.
Very simple.
And this can you
if I want to replace all of the lowercase
letters, how can I specify that
exactly?
You can specify a lowercase e
galaxy,
and this time no uppercase
letter will be attached.
Only the lowercase letters
will be replaced
by look here
key SD and they were replaced.
But is the X
all of the uppercase?
This method is called replace all here.
This is the name of the method.
Replace
all the technique that we are using here.
It's called regular expression.
Are things making sense?
If they're too minor,
say exactly the same thing.
Oh, yes. Let me show you other examples.
So let's say, for example,
I can specify a number as well.
I can say 029.
Can you combine two? Yes,
we can combine. Two.
Just give me the let me go
step by step What we can we can do that.
What do you think?
What will happen now?
I'm saying 0 to 9,
all the digits from 0 to 9
will be replaced with equal time.
So the uppercase letters
are there, lowercase letters?
Are there special Are there only numbers?
Only digits from 0 to 9 are replaced.
And one more thing. What do you think?
What will happen
if I if I replace it with empty string
in the replacement?
If I don't specify anything,
I simply specify double course.
They will be basically removed.
They will be removed.
They will be removed
so they can show you. You
look, now
we have a shorter string
so you can basically use it
to remove things
as well as replace or remove.
You can find any pattern
just try to get a sense of
of how these ranges are working.
Is it clear
or is there anyone who is confused?
Yes, there is a range for the characters
as well.
Okay.
Now let me pull the ASCII table
for you.
Yes, it can work with spaces as well.
For example,
if there are spaces in between
like this.
So to specify the space,
there are multiple ways
you can put a space like this
empty one.
And so it will try to search
for all the spaces
and then it will remove.
So look, there is no space in the output,
so it will basically remove,
even if there are spaces everywhere,
everywhere like this, like this, anywhere.
If a space is found, it will be removed.
We are put with our spaces.
How to keep one space
between all the words.
Alex Flexible step by step.
Next step I will teach you
everything that is possible.
Looking right.
Basically, this regular expression
is working based on this table.
For example,
the you see the number
for the upper PSA is 65.
And if I specify
uppercase A to lowercase
Z, everything that comes in between
all of the symbols, uppercase,
lowercase, they will all be replaced.
Uppercase E
as the number 65, the representation
then increasing one by one.
B is 66, C 67, and then lowercase
A is 97, lowercase B is 98, lowercase
Z is.
So basically everything that comes
in this range,
65 to
Z is 122
inside of the ask a table
if I am specifying my regular expression
like this, a dash lowercase
z, this is how computer will interpret
this computer will go and find
the representation for the upper PC,
which is 65.
Then It will go to the A table
and find the representation
for lowercase z, which is 122.
Everything that comes in between.
Now it will consider all of those things.
For example,
for example, if I say
uppercase, it will lowercase z.
Not only all the uppercase
letters will be replaced removed
because we are using up the string,
all the lowercase letters will be removed
and these symbols like bracket
buried symbol, they will also be replaced
because they are within the range
to look
all of these things.
They were in the range.
This was also invented
two, three, two was not in the range,
space was not there, nine eight was not
there nor symbol was not there.
But look at this
great symbol, the scattered symbol.
Is it in the range?
Let's see from the ask the table,
the scattered symbol.
Look, there
it is within the range.
So basically everything that you put
will go and match that thing
from the ASCII table
and from that range, the range
that could get from the ask the table,
whatever comes between
all of those combinations,
all of those letters, director symbols,
everything will be considered.
For example,
let's say if you specify the end
symbol as the starting point
and you specify, let's say the semicolon
as the ending point,
do you think everything that we see in
between will be replaced?
So let's try this.
Oh, by the way,
there are some special characters
which have a special meaning.
So let me specify the
and and semicolon.
So there are some special characters
which has a special meaning.
So anything that comes in the range
will be replaced.
Look here,
all the numbers are in this range.
Zero one, two, three, four, five.
Colon forward slash plus sign
minus sign star, curly brackets.
You can put all of them.
For example, look at these.
Look at this.
Look at this table.
I am specifying the range
starting from the symbol and semicolon
and these opening and closing brackets,
they are within the range.
They think they will be replaced.
These one that I have just
inserted, they are all gone.
So basically it's the ASCII table.
These ranges,
these things that we are specifying here.
Basically Java is going back to the table
and from that ASCII table, it is trying
to figure out what it should consider
and which comes what comes in the range
and what is not within the range.
Making sense.
For example,
let me show you more examples.
Let me say control C control. We
is it time for break?
Okay, We can have a break.
And then after the break,
we will continue from here.
So place things and basically
patrons say
this is how we specify
the regular expressions.
Okay, now
this is good.
Based on the ask a table,
you can pick any range,
you can specify that range
and then it's going to work.
But what happens?
Things are not that
straightforward. For example,
sometimes
maybe
you are interested in only replacing
uppercase letters and numbers
so and single and how you can do that,
you can basically specify multiple ranges.
For example,
you can say, I only want to remove
or replace uppercase letters
and only the numbers.
So there is no symbol
and symbol in between.
There is no nothing.
You just specify two ranges
just like this.
And now what
we are saying in this range is
replace or remove
all of the uppercase letters.
Replace or remove
all the numbers from 0 to 9.
So for example, now we run this code
so you can see from this
string all the uppercase letters
from A to Z, all the numbers
from zero nine, they have been removed
because our replacement is empty string
and special symbols are there.
Spaces are different.
Lowercase letters can be.
So basically this is how you can specify
multiple ranges.
And then let's say,
I don't know, maybe you want to say
0 to 5 numbers and then you
don't like to replace the number from,
the number six and seven.
Then you can specify another range
like this,
and then maybe you want to replace
something
this a two letter J
So any range, basically
multiple ranges, whatever you like.
Are things making sense?
What I, what am I doing here.
So now include on it.
Look, all the uppercase letters are gone.
Then numbers from 0 to 5 are gone.
Let me put the number six here.
So it reads one character.
The character by character?
Yes, correct them.
So tell me, why is this number six?
Will it be removed?
Exactly.
So we see the number of six, and I am
specifying lowercase letters from eight to
which means which means
this letter
s lowercase s, Will it be replaced
or removed?
No, because it does not fall in anything.
So someone was asking me, how can we use
the end operator, specify multiple things.
So this is how you can do it.
There is one more variation
that you might want to try.
For example, you can specify
individual as well.
Individual letters.
For example,
you want to only replace lowercase k
lowercase as
the digit to
the uppercase s.
That's also possible.
You can specify individual characters,
so wherever
it will see the lowercase lowercase s two,
unless it will replace that
and everything else,
it will be it will be it will be there.
So look,
only the K from the beginning,
it has been removed.
Then the lowercase s removed,
then the radius tool was removed
and the upper class
was Mr..
Okay, so everything looks good in here.
Now I will show you
some advanced techniques.
Can you please quickly
expand from first line, please?
No, obviously I will not be explaining
from the first line
why you want me to repeat what I have done
in the last 20 minutes.
You will not hear
what's wrong
If relics and replacement comes out,
it means either you did not specify
the regular expression properly
or you are not following the syntax rule.
Share shared a screenshot.
I will tell you what you are doing wrong.
How to replace dashes.
You can specify a dash like this
individual dash.
I think it should
work. We're not sure that
this school
like this.
I understand your point you.
But some some characters
are part of the syntax.
So how replace them
you can specify them separately.
No, this.
If you want to remove dash,
you can specify a dash like this.
But this is what I have done.
Any other question base anything
which is not cleared, any line number.
So in order to remove dash or use it
at the end of it, know it can be anywhere.
You will do it at the end
or before it can be anywhere like this.
But if you put it between two letters,
then it will take it
as a range.
Uppercase
class will not be removed by A to Z
making comment
out of the other course
and only execute that line.
What is the usage of this written code
in real life?
Okay, so have you seen when you try to create a username and password on a website,
they can go through your password
and they tell you
that your password is not strong enough.
If should contain a special character,
it should contain uppercase
letters, lowercase letters, numbers
What do you think?
How they are identified,
how they are looking at these patterns,
how they are figuring it out,
whether you are using a lowercase
uppercase
special, deducing a password or not.
The they use behind the scenes,
these regular expressions.
They also use these regular expressions.
Make sure you are entering a proper email.
For example,
you can easily find regular expressions
on the internet for these common things.
For example, it's a very common thing
that whenever you enter an email
on any website, for example,
if I go to Facebook
and if I say out of the eight
something like this
or let me try to
create a new account
to create a new account,
this is not a proper
email, right?
Well, what do you think?
How it is figuring it out
if it is a email or not,
it is looking for the advertising world
and it is looking for that.
You have a dot com or dot AEI
or something like that that at the end
and all of these things,
all of this is possible
with the help of regular expression.
For example, a regular expression
to verify email
and you don't have to write it all
and you can easily
find already written regular expressions
which will validate, look,
this is basically a regular expression,
a very complex one. Yes.
And I don't think it's going to make
a lot of sense at this point.
But if
the regular expression,
it will check your email,
whether it is from Google, Amazon, dot
com dot org,
any domain, anything, it will make sure
that you are using a proper email.
You can also validate numbers,
for example, in a lot of forms
when you enter your
when you enter your information,
they can quickly tell you
whether you are using your proper
mobile number or not.
What do you think about
how do they do that?
For example, if you are entering seven
five digit phone number,
something like this,
please enter a valid number.
They are using regular expressions.
So basically it is a very powerful thing
to make sure that the user is entering
proper data.
You create a regular expression
which will verify everything from the data
that user is entering
and it's heavily
used in these applications
where you create new user ID,
you enter your password
filling out these forms,
everything that you see on the Internet.
Is it clear
now how they are used in real life?
Now, some of you might want to go
into the details
and might want to learn more
about regular expressions.
I actually don't recommend it,
but some of you
it's good if you have time.
There is a website which is called
Radix, so
it has all the explanations
how these regular expressions work.
For example, sorry about it.
For example,
if you look at the queue sheet
when you write
slash and W, it means
any word.
When you write backward slash D
it means a digit.
For example here,
if I write
this digit here,
the community will be square brackets.
It means any digit.
Let's run it.
So look at this output,
all the digits
which were present in this string.
They are all gone.
This backward.
Backward slash D means any digit
backward slash w means any word.
Backward slash S means space.
For example,
there are a lot of spaces as well
in our string,
so one way you can directly put the space.
However, one other way is
you can put backward slash s
and we need an extra one
so that it does not take it as literal.
So this backward slash backward slash
s means a space so all the spaces will go.
Now look,
so these
are all the
syntax of this domain specific language
which is called red x regular expression.
So and if you want to learn it,
you can basically use this website.
For example,
you can write a regular expression here.
So if you write D
and let's put some numbers here
then,
so you see it is highlighting
all the numbers from.
This complete text here,
if I tried backwards slash w look,
it is identifying all the words
from this next paragraph.
So if I specify a square brackets, a, b, c
it means any of e, B
or C, wherever
it will see those it will highlight.
So if I write square brackets A, B, C,
it will highlight all everywhere,
wherever it will see
the letter E or B or S.
When you put a range here A to Z, it
will highlight
any uppercase letters from A to Z.
So you can basically
learn a test
and all the explanation and code.
Everything is given to those
who want to dig a little deeper,
more to understand better.
You guys can use this website
and we shared the link with you.
So again,
there is one more thing
that I want to show you.
Are you remember the not symbol,
not basically takes
the note of whatever logic you put
that not also works here,
but symbol is little different.
For example,
if you specify A to Z
and, if you put the scarab symbol
before like this,
it means remove everything,
but not uppercase A to Z.
Edit this.
Let me repeat remove everything
but not uppercase A to Z.
So if you do that,
only the uppercase letters are left.
Everything else has been removed.
And for example,
if you do this, for example,
if you say do not remove A to Z, also
do not
do not remove edge will be
and also do not remove the numbers.
What do you think?
What will be replaced this time?
I'm saying do not remove
letters, lowercase letters and numbers.
What will be left?
All the special characters
will be removed.
And other than that
all the uppercase letters, lowercase
letters
and numbers will be retained.
So look, this is how you clean your input.
A lot of the time you will be processing
the data from text based files.
And before you process the data, lot
of the time you want to clean that data
you want to remove
maybe by injection logs, the spaces
and or special characters
and anything you can process.
You are staying in
whichever way you want with
the help of these required expressions.
So I am saying do not remove uppercase
A to Z,
do not remove or to be
segment policy and do not remove 0 to 9.
And other than this, whatever is present
in my string and remove all of that.
So you see this
how this not a symbol is helping you here
not symbol says do not remove these things
but everything
other than this.
So I see lowercase uppercase numbers,
but I do not see special characters.
So anything that is not in
the range of will be replaced.
Yes. Yes.
And you can sit and do the same
major number and you see, not this.
This means the range is.
And you can also specify the
start and the ending of a string
word, not a word, a boundary,
a scaled special characters.
You can remove tabs, for example, this
these are also very helpful.
For example, if you write
a and then a plus sign,
it will highlight only backwards,
which D means digit
any number 0123456789.
So a and plus means if there are zero,
if there are one or more,
if there are one or more
a is are present, then them.
So it will highlight all of them.
And a and curly bracket means a
and curly bracket and let's say for means
if there are four A's together,
if there are four A's
and if they are present together,
then highlight them.
So for example,
if I put 1 to 3 for it to be highlight,
I can specify say if there are aa2
is are present together then highlighted.
So the latter and then curly brackets
and then the number
how many you want to see together.
You can also specify eight brackets
one and three between one and three
separate out.
I think we I have, I never showed this
regular expression
in this much detail to any batch.
You are the first ones.
I hardly show them how to that range thing
and that's it.
But I think it's not that hard.
And if you want to try it, try out more.
It is also not that
hard.
I think it's simple.
And again,
you don't need to memorize this.
You don't need to memorize this
so you can open the cheat sheet here.
You can read the regular expressions here,
all the documentation, you can test it,
and then you're going to use it.
So and I don't think so.
You still understand the power
that you are getting with the help of,
these regular expressions.
Now, you will be able to process
almost any kind of text
with the help of your Java programs.
Okay.
If any of this is not clear
or if there are any questions, please ask.
Otherwise
we will move to the next example.
Okay, Let me show you more matters.
Yes, the regular expressions
like short shorters.
Imagine if you do not have
regular expression,
you might have to write
a lot of false conditions.
You might have the right lobes
if you want to remove something
or filter out something.
So it can be very challenging at times
if you don't use regular expression.
It's just very simple thing and it
is looking good.
Let me let me give you a task and
so that I know if you have understood
better in our property
and then we will continue
from there.
Let's say I am getting
a string from the user
and let's say this string contains
okay, let's say someone entered
or someone has entered this information
from the website
and you get this output like this
and your menu says, Hey,
someone is entering garbage.
I do not want this thing in the text,
but I do java code to remove this part
from this string.
And you have to write a program
for right, write one.
So that
look, remember question mark.
It's a valid injection.
Dot is also good rest. Also looks good.
But this here,
this is what we want to remove.
Yeah.
Let me send you here.
Well, what is the name of this movie?
Movie anywhere?
No, no, no.
The one from which you have shared to me.
I think it's a very Friday or.
Okay, Yeah,
this one is a very funny one, right?
I'm not going
type to want.
Oh, everyone is there to ask the player.
Oh, perfect.
If you need an
did you want us to manually for them
or you ask me
whichever way you like,
whichever way you like.
I can see from the ASCII
and the right rate
hash and percentage
C and three eight
hash and percentage.
I think if you go with the ask, it will
it will become hard
because remember,
you still want to have a period
and question mark.
Oh, it was the name of the movie.
I thought you were talking to someone
1996.
It would screwed.
Okay, is there anyone
who is unable to do this task?
Why mine is removing this special
I don't know what expression
you have written.
Okay,
so you get this is this was very simple.
Replace all what we want to replace.
We want to replace the error
rate, the hash
and then the percentage.
All right?
And then like this,
okay,
turns.
Okay, one more thing.
What if the string is like this?
Or maybe I can give you that as homework
did not use this brackets and it worked.
Oh yeah.
So regular
expression is just like programing.
Same problem can be solved
in many different ways.
Let me see.
I guess our next method is the split
method.
Okay, so let's say
this is the this is a string.
And from this, a string.
Let me make it even simpler.
I think.
Let's say you have just this idea.
Are you good?
Is this paragraph
it contains, let's say, multiple
sentences
and you want to split
you want to split these the sentences.
That is also possible.
For example, there is a method
and the name of the method
is called split.
And remember again
the split method,
it also takes a regular expression.
How can I confirm
if it takes the regular expression?
How do I know the matter
takes the regular expression
under an almost normal string?
Yes You can look it from here.
Or even better way
is to read the documentation.
If I want to know how this method works,
I can however my mouse over the method
like this
and I can read
the explanation of all this by example.
If there splits this string around
the matches.
Also given regular expression,
this method works if you are invoking
the two arguments method
and then it shows you examples as that.
So now
from this spring
I am trying to split this string
based on the dot.
If I do that, how many strings?
As a result of this I will be getting two
and depending upon this string
I might get the three as well.
Right.
For example,
if I have this, how many strings
I will be getting now as a result?
Three.
So what type of variable I should create
to store the results
of this split method?
Exactly.
We need an array
because depending upon the operation
that we are performing, we might get
three strings.
As a result, we might get 10,000 strings.
As a result, we might get five strings.
As a result, it will split and will create
that many individual strings.
So here the return type or
the output of this
method is going to be an array
of strings.
Does it make sense why the return type
is an array of strings
instead of individual string or?
Maybe something else.
Everyone.
Is it clear why split
method is going to return an array?
So if I am splitting based on the dot,
how many?
How many what?
What should be the size of this? Edit
What should be the size of this area?
Three So if I say SDR dart length,
I should be getting three right?
I do get three.
And from this add a
from this SDR array.
If I put the element at index number zero,
what do you expect?
What should I get or what will I get
the first sentence
this block.
All righty.
At how I remember this dart is gone.
Whatever we are using
to spare something,
that thing is not included in the output.
And if I put two here
or the thing what output I will get,
I am bad.
The last sentence
I am right.
Hmm. I'm getting at it.
Getting a space here.
Is it possible in a string to remove
extra spaces that for example,
I'm getting one extra space here?
Yes. So.
And can I use method chaining for example?
Can I simply write not and can say trim?
Yes. So prim will remove the spaces
which we are getting.
How did you see what SDF
splitting does that detail page?
So for every if you want to know
what that method is for,
you can hover your mouse
over the name of that matter
and then it will show
you will be explanation.
It's a very bad thing.
Julia I think you might also have
to reinstall the windows
if it was doing some critical updates
and if you stop it
in the middle of the process,
you might have to reinstall it.
It might corrupt
computer operating system.
Okay, yeah, you can remove the tree.
So line
it will remove the extra space
that we were getting before I am driving.
So for example,
I print this exact same thing
without rain.
You will notice
that there is an extra space coming.
We see there is this extra space
before the start because
this is my sentence.
After the docked.
So when we split based on that,
sometimes we might get extra
things that we don't like
and then you can remove that.
Okay, how can we split the words?
Let's say this time from this sentence,
I want individual words
based on what I should split.
Exactly. If you split
based on this space,
you will be actually you have
you have made me tell the answer
of one of your homeworks.
But that's fine.
It was one of your homeworks.
So instead of specifying the not
what you want me
to tell the homework number as well,
you can specify a space
here.
Okay. Now tell me, what do you think?
What will be the length of the 80
this time?
So one, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight,
nine, ten, 11, 1112.
Something like this.
We are getting ten, one, two, three, four.
This is five.
You and I,
They will be treated one word
because there is no space in between.
Next slide ten, not 11
is this part clear
why we are getting ten, not 11?
Because if you don't, I
it will be treated as one single word
because there is no space.
We are splitting based on this space.
Okay,
So if I
say SD R and zero, what do you think?
What time is it? Hi.
Yes, why not?
Give me one second
and. If I say, then
what will happen?
I'm saying ten and then SVR ten. Why?
Why are you saying And
why are you saying M?
This is 1234.
This is 5:08 a.m.
was six Exactly.
We will be getting an ad of y error
because indexes are always
one less than the land.
Do not forget this.
A lot of the times you make this mistake,
indexes are always one
less than the length lent is done.
That means at max we can go nine.
So very common mistake
that you are making these days.
So now I will be getting driving
o k and if I get this high
there, let's say
you want to skip this dot as well.
Whether it's a space
or a dot, I don't care.
I want to split based on that.
So let's try this.
I think it should work fine.
You can specify the
cloudy s for the space
and you can specify the not as well.
By this,
I think it should work fine, otherwise
we have to figure it out.
Know.
Let's see if we have this
not to split
based on this
in our style. This
this time it work.
Yeah.
So this time we are getting 12.
We are getting 12 hours.
So one is high
then we are getting bigger.
Then how then are then you
then I am then again.
Good.
And then this space here and then I.
And I'm driving.
So previously this you
and I, it was treated as a single word.
Me comment this for a simple.
So previously
when we were splitting based on the
based on only the space
we were getting
ten words
and why we were getting worse and worse
because it was treating this high
as one word there and another one
this tired fourth and fifth.
So if we try to bring
in the word
number five,
you will see that, do you not?
I would walk into 20234.
Sorry, it was four.
So you and not I.
They were treated as single word.
Then what we did, we
wrote an explainer.
We wrote a regular expression
that whether it's a space
or it's a dog, which
whichever of these is present,
I want to split based on that.
So we used that
as the criteria to split.
You was also separated out from this.
I is this part clear?
What what, what,
what is happening when I specify
a dot as well as a space
as the criteria to split?
Now, whether it sees a space
or a dog, it will split.
And you can also do this.
You can basically write a loop
together, get
see all of the
all of the letters that you are getting.
So for
String S
in SDR and remember, I'm
using an enhanced for loop
and why I'm able to use an enhanced model
because it's an addy.
Oh, I do not pretend.
So now I see all of the words here.
I'm getting an extra space as well,
which can be more busy.
So this is how this works.
Basically what speed does?
Let me show you more examples.
Maybe you are still confused.
If there is someone who is following me,
let me know once you are done typing
or if you want to form.
So let's say for example,
you get some kind of
text and let's say every word
is separated by a hash symbol
and try to generalize it
to make it simpler.
So this is the string that you getting.
For example, every word is a separated
by a dash, and now your task is
you want to see you want to get rid
of the individual words.
So tell me which method
you will use to get the individual words
out of this string
Split method.
You don't need to replace it first.
You can directly use the splitting.
It expects you.
You can
you can provide any regular expressions.
So for example,
you can write an array. SDR
and then you can say SDR or SPLIT
based on what I should split
if I want to go
to the individual letters
based on what I should split
exactly.
Oh my God, this hash
is again causing problems.
Okay,
so I will be getting an array back
and what will be the length of that area?
I will be getting an array of strings
and what will be the length of that data.
So we will get one, two, three, four
and five.
Okay.
And from that area,
if I bring print, print, print, print,
if I say SDR, here are
one productivity.
I got a dear
remember indexes, they start from zero.
So is this split method clear?
If there are a lot
of paragraphs, sentences
and if you want to split that big
the string,
maybe you want to go to the individual
sentences out of that
and maybe you want to get individual words
out of that.
You can also go to individual characters
as well.
If the words separated by space or hash
symbol or dog
or star symbol, whatever is the
character
based on which they are separated,
just provide that character inside this
method as the argument.
It will split the words
and it will give you the results
back in the form of an adding.
If you have questions, please ask.
Can you put a single space
between all words?
Yeah, we can.
Like for example, let me copy this
and let me put it here.
Let's say
the words are separated by a space
instead of hash.
So this time, based on what I will split
based on the space.
Right.
And there are multiple ways to specify
a space you can directly put it like this
or you can use two backward slash slashes.
Then s0i for this
no spaces or any extra thing.
Otherwise you will get going at it.
I put an extra space here.
So for double backward slash s
it also means space.
If you if you find it hard to remember,
you can directly put a space like this
the same upward.
So this is how you can split
based on just any character
or any anything that you have
would be
interesting
to try out the enhanced for loop sprint.
All the added added element are yes,
I think this is what we will be learning
next.
I think this is the next method
for non dark.
It is not here, but mostly
going to show you that fact.
There is a method for that as well.
And there are more.
One more thing.
I'm not going over all the methods which
are present inside this string class.
There are a lot I have just tried
to go over the most important ones.
There are more
So before you try to write custom logic
for any of your tasks, try
look for the method.
Maybe there is already a method for that.
The thing that you are trying to do.
So let's say
there is this string
and let's say
you want to write an enhanced
for to go over all the elements
of this string.
For some reason you just like
the first thing that you have to do is
you have to convert this string
into an array of characters.
And it's very simple.
We we have a method for that.
So first you will be converting
this a string.
Nafisa This is how you can do it.
Stick on the question
so you can have an array of characters
and you can call this method
string dog tool jar. Addy
This booth jar area.
It will convert this string
to an array of characters.
And then you write and enhance for loop.
What should I specify
inside the enhanced for loop?
If I want to go over all the elements
from this area.
Cha cha c column here are
so that's how you can get
individual letters
from with the help of an enhanced module.
For example, in the sentence.
Hi there, how are you.
How can I there, how are you?
You can split it
based on the question mark
and a space and a dart,
and then you can get the first element
from this DCT.
Okay, let's solve some tasks everyone.
Right.
Quick word for this first one, okay?
Yeah, sure, sure.
Side question Why does the rest
of the world hate Americans?
I don't think so anyone hurt here.
Some Americans
especially, I don't think to anyone else
the people living in this
in their specific nation,
you might hear top
guys who are making the decisions
for other countries
or other nations or something like that.
All immigrants, I don't know.
I mean, for example,
whoever is controlling that nation,
they are the ones who are taking
the decisions most of the time.
I mean, some nations, they are very good.
They stand
If something goes wrong, for example, in
I get I guess in France, even if you
even if you
I mean, almost every other day,
the people from France, they are in
some kind of protest against.
Their government, even if their government
does like small things
and they don't like it,
they are always standing and
and speaking about it
like this is the task
here.
People are great everywhere.
All dawn.
That's correct.
So the task is you have to create a string
and then put some kind
of sentence in industry
and then you have to get a new string.
But without spaces.
So basically this task
is you have to remove the spaces
from any
string.
By the way,
those who are done with the first one,
you can start working on the second one
brain has stopped working,
brain overloaded.
If you want,
you can solve them as your work.
Okay,
These are some of the videos
that you have to watch before
tomorrow and.
They might look a little different
and they might also not
it's language.
So everyone I did,
the people who go me,
anyone,
anyone, individual,
they things about
these two videos, they are more important
than the ones that I have shared.
They are also important.
But this is this is what we will be
discussing tomorrow.
Most of the time.
What about the object class?
We will keep on using that
object class
throughout the rest of the course
for second tasks or just for any B
and easy or any B and easy.
Yeah.
Okay.
Let me also share this slides with you.