And then we won.
How are you guys doing?
Elina So you were not okay with this?
I'm good.
All of us know that today
we have a class
because only 15 students are there yet.
Or maybe, like they were planning on
attending the sessions after the class
association.
What kind of facility?
al-Asiri.
Okay, so you also have
these kind of associations abroad.
Okay.
Might be like having
another kind of family, you know,
from the same country.
And so today's session
is not going to be long.
We'll be covering some more concepts
regarding this.
And then most probably
we will be done in about,
I believe, 1.5 to 2 hours.
After that, on Tuesday, we are going to be
having different classes.
Usually what we did
in the previous batches, we combined
doctor with eight of us.
But from this batch
you have decided to make doctor individual
and spend some more time on it.
So this is going to be a session for like
maximum 2 hours.
And on Tuesday
we will be again teaching doctors.
So I believe that the concepts
that we discussed in
the last US are clear to all of you.
And today we can easily proceed
with the next things that we have.
So let's open up our
interviews
and let's do one thing less
than we connected to the instance of EC2
that we created
using natively as consoles.
So today let's learn how we can do it
using the terminal
or the putty for
Windows user.
Let's dive in our search bar.
Easy to.
Okay, let's go to launch instances
and over here
let's launch
this first instance Amazon Linux 2 a.m..
And no,
instead of that let's launch an instance
which has already
some softwares installed.
So one of the instance
that I think we can use in that terms
is the one that already
has Docker installed on it.
Okay.
So in
order to search for such an instance,
what we are going to do
is go to the search bar
and we will write down or there
Docker, compose
and hit enter.
Hi Mario.
Okay, so
are you guys following?
Okay, that's great.
So Docker compose, we search for it.
Okay, that that's fine.
So now we see that
we do not have any of the instance
which has Docker installed,
but it's only in the my arm
if we go to the market place
or the community and I
will be able to see a lot of instances.
So you can also use them
from the community.
Okay, so what is an Amazon machine image?
I believe that we discussed this last time
right?
You guys remember it.
And what is the
what is an Amazon machine image
with the Amazon machine image
file that contains
all the necessary information and software
that you need to have install
on the instance
or the machine
that you are trying to deploy.
So as we are trying to deploy
a new computer on Amazon Cloud,
so what we have is different
machine images available to us
in which we have different
kind of software pre-installed.
So right now
I'm looking for a machine image
which has Docker compose,
so I search for it.
Now I can look upon
any image that has Doppler.
So this one,
if I look upon this, it has Docker,
Docker compose configured to deploy.
Okay.
So I can also use this one.
I believe Amazon Linux agent, Docker
compose, it's also there.
So let's go ahead with the
with the first one.
Let's go ahead and choose the first one.
So at this point, we select
the kind of deal that will be using
so to migrate it
because this one is a free one.
Next number of instances is one network.
By default, you select the VPC
and we will select
any of the default subnet.
Any other thing
we do not want to set that.
Should I move to the next page?
Okay.
So next step is to add storage by default.
It's eight. I'm good with that.
So next this version we skip.
Okay, Security group
is there now for this,
we will have a discussion in today's
lecture that what's a security group
but for now let it be by default,
whatever it is.
So GCP to do custom and all plots
review and launch.
Okay now again, the time where we need to
have a key.
So I'll say
this time create a new keeper,
not limit eight of us.
One, two, three.
After creating a new keeper,
I need to download it
so that I have it on my system.
And then I can simply say launch instance.
So my instance is in.
Instead of launching right now it's
loading up.
Have you guys launched it?
Okay, great.
Now what I want you to do,
how many of you are on windows?
Okay, The people who are on Windows,
what you need to do is go to Google.
And this is only for people
who are on Windows.
Okay?
Typing would be and
download this software from this link.
Let me send you the link to
you. Just
need to download this software
and install it quickly.
For the MAC users.
You do not need to for.
Okay Mac already has one installed
in it.
Install the software and let me know
so that I'll be able
proceed together.
Okay.
So how awesome or what
system are you want?
Is it MSA that you have?
Well, because I've been a Windows user so
I just love Windows more than Mac,
especially with you
as I just don't like Matt.
It really gets complicated
when I need to support
someone with having a mac configuration
issue.
Other issues are fine, but
when it comes to configuration, it's hard.
Okay, so MSA Windows installer
go ahead with
I believe 64 bit.
First one, it should work for you. Just
go ahead and install
the first one.
Okay.
So people who are on Mac,
let me guide you now.
What do you guys need to do
is click on your instance that you launch
and do you see this
connect button appearing?
Any version
that doesn't matter.
Okay, so Mac users,
I'm talking to you guys.
You need to connect on this.
Click on this button.
And then what you'll see is some window
like this.
Okay, after that,
you need to click on the search client
Mac users, click on the search line.
Let me know once
you have once you see this particular
set of instructions in front of you,
do you see this?
Okay.
Now, again, it's for only Mac users.
No one else.
Now what you need to
do is follow these commands,
open an SS.
Excellent.
It means that opening up your terminal.
Okay, open.
And such client means open up
the terminal.
Locate your private key, file.
Okay, So now
I believe that you can navigate
to the location
where you downloaded
the file that key file.
And you can, like, look at it, right?
Just like we learned and get CD
and navigate to the directories we do.
You have the keys.
And after that, once you are in
to that location, run this command C.
S mode 400 and your key name.
After that, connect to your instance
using public DNS.
Like you can use this particular command,
whatever is appearing on your screen.
Okay, so
the example is
over here mentioned
run these commands,
see how it works for you.
It should be able to connect you to your
instance on the NWS.
Okay.
Our instructions here for Mac users,
you just need to follow them.
You follow them.
Let me know if you are able to connect
or not.
If not, then
I'll just share a video with you because
unfortunately I do not have a terminal,
so I cannot run this with you guys
and Windows users.
Do you have your buddy installed?
Okay, perfect.
So now first, let's understand that
why are we doing this
and what are we doing, actually?
So sometimes the scenario may be
that instead of using an address
console,
you need to connect to the instance
directly to our computer.
And we do not have a log in.
Or maybe we are not comfortable with using
that console, just one.
So for that purpose, what we can do
when we launch the instance,
it's inside a building right?
Okay.
So let me draw that instance like this
and this building is our data center.
So my instance has some
IP address, right?
It has some IP address assigned to it.
Okay. After that,
when we were launching the instance,
do you guys remember that
there was something like security
that we configured?
In fact, we said that we will learn them
later on, but we had
we saw something
like security group over there.
We saw that the protocol was
what was the protocol mentioned
in that security group?
It was SSX.
Let me show you.
Okay.
So protocol is SSL,
right?
And the port is 22
and the IP
address is 0.0.0.2.
Okay, So what are we actually
configuring over here?
We are considering that
if you want to access
this particular instance
on the network,
you can access it using the protocol set
and this SS protocol is basically based
upon DHCP.
So what other communication protocols
have you learned in the course?
I'm not learned right.
I'll just say that
you have an introduction
to that.
Exactly. Very good.
You did a
you have learned a HTP and itbs so essence
which is also one of these communication
protocol that allows you
to communicate over the Internet.
There are other protocols.
Also there are SMP and
what we call that
script.
My brain was very popular.
Well, I'll just skip it for now.
I forgot the name.
It says it's GC or TB or HTTPS or TB.
The port is 22
and we are saying that it can be accessed
using any computer, any IP address.
Okay. Now the only problem is that
in Windows we do not have an SS line,
so what is and such a line
and such a such is basically putty
which allows you to connect
to this particular instance over
the define SS protocol
to install the putty.
And this putty has the capability
of establishing such connection.
So what are we going to do right now?
We are going to mention the IP address
of the instance,
we are going to mention
the port of the instance,
and then we are going
to define the protocol to be set
and we are going to see connect
to this particular instance.
Is it clear
any questions that you may have?
Okay, great.
So what I want you to do
is open up what the general in your
search bar right down to the region
and press.
Enter.
This is only for Windows users. Mac users.
I gave you the commands. Try them out.
Are you able to connect?
Okay.
Do you have all
do you have this particular item
opened up in front of you?
Okay, now click on load
and find the key
in your downloads
or wherever you downloaded it.
Find that key.
Let me see your I downloaded it.
Okay.
So make sure that you select all files.
They share the video.
Okay,
I'll share that with you with you guys.
Connect to E to instance,
using Mac.
I know how much you guys
need to find your own key.
I named it. It s one, two, three.
So if you have named this one, two, three,
that would work.
If you have named it differently,
you will have to find your criticality.
So my key. Let's see.
Where is my key? It's
8.122. VM.
Where did that go?
Here it is.
So I'll just open up this file
and once it's there
after that I'll click Save
Public Key.
Eight of us want to B
and C, Okay,
So are you guys with me up to this step?
Anyone who is left behind
know your guitar.
Do not overwrite it.
Save it in a different location
or with a different name.
Okay, so what else Now
click on Save Private Key
and again
I'm going to save the private key on deps
desktop of the name eight of us.
456 and save it.
Okay.
This time I'll see this
particular computer with the hat
and this particular key
is going to be there.
Let you know if you guys have successfully
generated this computer key
using footage. Jack
Okay, what are we doing?
Actually?
So when we created this instance,
we got a key.
A key basically allows you to connect
to your instead.
It's like one added layer of security
for your instance.
So we downloaded that key
and what was the extension
for that particular key?
It was dot
pam file, right?
Whenever we want to use putty
to connect to the instance,
we cannot use DOT then file rather
we have to use dot PPK file.
That's just one requirement of the party.
So what we will do,
we will convert our documents file to dot
PPK file using putty.
Jack.
And we just did that.
We simply loaded the file, the key, and
we saved the private E and the public key.
So more freely
you'll be using the private key.
Okay. Are we done to this step
today?
You guys are very, very sleepy.
I believe you are tired.
Maybe
just a small session.
Guys. This like
only 1.5 hours left.
So be interactive, be active.
Okay. Okay.
Now we have that video in front of us
and we have an option of
giving the hostname our IP address.
So again, someone telling me that
what will go in here, the private
IP address are the public one.
Yes, exactly.
So we'll go and copy our public address.
Where is that.
Let me see instance running
and I'll go to my instance.
Is this the correct one?
Let me make sure.
No, this is the first one, so I'll copy
my public key IP address.
I'll pass it in here.
Okay. The port is 22.
Connection type is SSL.
After this, we only need to have
our key added into this body.
So how are we going to add
the double click on the search?
And then what?
So after clicking on assets and ports,
we see that there's a private E file
for authentication.
We'll add the file simply over here.
So I'll go to my desktop.
I have this file, double click on it
and the file will be added.
Now get go again to my session.
So at this point, are you guys with me
or do you want me to repeat any step
with step with step guys?
If you are able to follow,
you can always ask me to repeat.
Okay,
so which step do you want me
to do you want me to repeat
all of it?
Okay.
Even the
convergence of the key that we did,
we want to repeat that to
let me know
so that I can quickly start on that point.
Do you want me to repeat this
generation also?
Okay, so
since we are up our putty
and we are going to place
in the configuration
the hostname or IP address, so
the IP address, we can get it
from the instance that it launched
and we can simply copy
the public IP address that we have.
So I'm copying it
and I'm pasting it over here.
Let me know.
And once you guys have done this
before,
okay, now go to set
and click on authentication.
Now you need to add your key,
which you converted the private one
over here.
So simply click on Browse
and go to the location where you have
this converted key
with this computer assigned,
double click on it
and go back to sessions.
Okay, Till this point,
are you guys with me?
Okay, great.
So now let's just click on open.
Okay, I'll click.
I'm going to accept this.
Now it's saying log in as
I need to see my username.
So where can I get it?
I'll simply click on Connect
and I'll click on
Do instance Connect.
So for me, my username is root.
You may you may have different it,
maybe root it, maybe if you do user.
So whatever your username is,
you need to type that into your property.
Okay.
Not saying please log in as to user
and then okay.
So you see to that user
what happened.
Okay, my equity got closed
and you went off, you was able to connect
it. Let's
try it again.
Okay, so try this again and this time
log in as a user.
So same steps.
So I'll open up the putty
outpaced in the IP address.
The public one.
I'll go to asset and authentication.
Oh, here.
I'll add the key.
Once I have added the key, I'll click on
session again and I'll click on open
and then I'll see you to that user.
Same steps that we did before.
We need to do again.
The only difference is that
it will take on log in as easy to user
instead of this time.
Okay, now hassle mohamud Mariam,
you'll get that.
Are you able to connect to it?
You'll get that.
Is yours connected?
Okay Maryam
Okay.
William You are not falling right?
And mammoth and soon.
What about you guys?
Yeah, I can get that from the way you type
because everything is good
when you are just
looking at the stuff, the actual problem.
The problem is when you are actually
trying to implement it.
So that's fine.
Okay, So now you see that
we see the same page
that we saw when we logged in using
Amazon console.
But this time you have connected to that
remote machine that we
created using our exercise plan,
which is pretty.
And what about the Mac users?
Do you have a
you have this kind of connection
established using the video.
That video that I showed.
Okay.
So if you run the common
Java Dash version, it's going to show you
that this particular system has Joe
version 1.7.0 underscore
six one installed in the machine.
And if you want to look at the Docker
version so you can do Docker dash version,
sorry, Docker
dash dashboards,
it will show you
that you have a version of it or two
or 3.1 installed on this machine.
Okay.
Unfortunately,
I don't think I can zoom in for you guys,
but what I can do is
I can pace the command for,
okay.
And Docker, these are the two commands
that you are supposed to run.
They will just give you the versions
of the softwares
that are installed.
Eleanor,
were you able to connect to the instance?
Oh, okay.
Go to go to that video.
It's going to walk you to. It's
not far.
You can actually do the same instance.
It should be found.
Okay, try it again.
Some maybe
try it again. The same command.
If the error resist, then
most probably do not have our
tried dockers.
If you have
launched the same exact
am I then it should be there.
Yeah. You'll be taught that.
That's correct. Okay
So the next thing that I want to guide
you guys is about
security group.
So we have already discussed about it.
So I'll just briefly go over to it
once again.
Let me see if I have some slides for you.
We can discuss them on slides.
It would be better.
Okay.
Can you see the slide?
Okay. Now
in security,
we have two kinds of firewalls.
Okay, awesome.
So maybe the possibility is that
you have not connected to the connect.
Am I okay?
You did not connect to the correct AM on.
That's the only possibility.
But don't worry about it.
Even if this command is not running,
you know how to connect the
to the instance.
So you just have connected the wrong one.
So it's not a problem.
It was just there
so that you can check the versions.
Okay. Talking about security,
we have two kinds of firewall.
One is security group
and the other is network ACL.
Okay? Now
in the end of whenever we create
an instance, we configure
our security groups in which
we have two kinds rules that we mentioned.
Number one, inbound rules.
Number two, outbound.
So what are inbound use?
It's very simple,
just as the name suggests, inbound routes.
So whatever traffic,
whatever data is going to be
coming to that particular instance,
whatever routes it should follow
are going to be under the inbound rules.
So for example,
in this particular instance that we have,
if I go to the security
and show you the inbound rules
I have that
the protocol should be TCP IP and such,
let me just make it a little bit big
with this, not this instance.
I want to go with this.
Okay.
So in the end I have that the
type is SSL protocol, TCP
for number trade
two and the source can be any source.
So these are the inbound rules.
It means that any traffic
that needs to be coming to this
particular instance
should be following the SSX protocol.
TCB on the poor trade to
and from this IP address,
If I tried to connect using Port 21,
I would not be able to connect.
If I tried to connect
using any of the protocols
rather than said
I will not be able to connect
if I tried to connect from level
any source, I can't.
Okay, let's try to edit them.
Let's say I want to give access
to someone else or another protocol.
So what I can simply do is select the kind
of port of all that I want to allow.
So let's say I want to allow HTP
just for for example.
So HTP protocol is also a TCP transport.
HTP is going to be Eddie
and which
IP address do I want to allow?
Let's say 192.168.1.1 So this means that
only this 192.168.1.1 can connect
to this particular instance or HTP.
Now that this makes sense,
the inbound route is is it
clear to everyone that what are inbound
routes?
Okay.
Similar to inbound routes,
we have outbound
routes.
Outbound rules refer to the traffic
that is going out of the network.
So any traffic
that will be going out of the networks,
we are going to see that
they come under the outbound rules.
So for this particular instance,
all kind of traffic can go
out of the network.
They can be on any protocol,
they can be on any port,
and they can be to any kind of computer
or IP address.
So we have basically no security
for outbound traffic
in this particular instance.
No, we will not be adding them.
Actually, I'm just giving you the concept
that what is a security group.
So security groups have inbound rules
and outbound rules.
Inbound rules are on the traffic
that is coming into the system
and outbound routes are on the traffic
that is going out of the system.
It totally depends on you.
If you want to restrict someone
or if you do not want to restrict anyone,
you want to allow everyone
to connect to your system.
Okay, Is that clear now?
Can you move forward
or do you guys have any question?
You'll get our customer.
Are we good, Marieme?
Are we good? Yes.
Okay.
Now let me open up the diagram again
and let me make this kind of
so let's say this is our security
group. A
so in our security group,
what rules do we have?
Quickly Answer Yes.
What rules do we
have in our security group?
Inbound and outbound.
Right? Perfect.
Now let's see.
We have two instances.
These are the two different instances.
What what do what do you guys understand
when, say,
the term instance?
Okay,
When I say instance, it means,
you know, it's not Java, right?
We are dealing with cloud.
And let me tell you
that why I was using this term,
because if you have read this, etc.,
what does it say?
It say instance, running right?
So what is it referring to?
This instance term.
It's referring to the computer
Oracle machine.
Oh my God.
All this time were you like
thinking about the instance
regarding Java?
Why would I mention that?
Okay, Mariam, you are smart.
Thank you for
thank you for understanding.
Okay, so if I have a security group
A can I do this
that I add the instance one and instance
to board in it? Yes.
Now same security rules apply on board the
instance.
Okay?
Now, if they are in the same group,
they will be abiding the same rules
for inbound and outbound traffic.
Now, let me open up the slides again.
Okay.
I share these documents with you guys
so you don't need to worry about this.
Okay.
Apart from security group,
we have one other thing
in our firewall, which is network escort.
So I'll briefly go to it.
Network ACL is
monitoring the traffic
that is going out of that subnet.
It's basically you can say that
it's on the router side from where
the traffic is entering
that particular building, our subnet.
It also has some rules and it monitors
that whether it's following those rules
or not in depth of them
because we do not actually need
to configure network ACL,
we can simply have them by default.
The only thing that we are interested in
is configuring the security.
GROSS
okay.
So after that, what else do we have?
I think we have discussed about
everything else.
And now the last thing
that I want to discuss with you guys
is going to be
regarding issue two.
Some more details.
So how about we do this?
We go for a break for
10 minutes
and then we come back and continue
with issue two instance.
Okay, So 1130 I'll see you guys on 1123.
Okay.
He is good.
Just taking on a
okay, so
let's quickly
go to the next
discussion in the instance
and then we will be ending our today
session.
Okay.
So just some more time again.
And the purpose
of having this launch, in this instance,
I hope that it's clear to all of
you that if you want to have
some infrastructure
already installed,
some applications are already installed,
we can easily, you know, in no time
use these particular instances to
deploy our application over there.
So, for example, if a certain application
needs some kind of resources,
we just select BMI and we just simply
go over there and deploy our application.
One of the example is that
when you guys will be learning Docker,
you'll see that
when I tell you to install Docker
on the computers, it's
going to be a very hectic desk.
Configuration of dockers on a computer
takes around
one hour to 1.5 hour
because there are a lot of settings
that you need to make.
There are a lot of configuration issues
that you need to resolve.
So let's say a person
who wants to quickly test
something on Docker
deploying application or Docker
instead of using his own computer,
if he simply use us and use
the image that we just launched
which had Docker pre-installed,
he will be able to
he will
be able to launch his application
within no time.
So that's one of the main feature.
The other features that we discussed were
more resources
that we do not have right now.
So we saw that
we have different kinds of options
for the RAM, for the hard disk
or the CPU's
available to us.
One of the most amazing feature of easy
two instance is
auto scaling.
Okay, so what happens in auto skinning?
Let's say that you launched an instance
and by now
I believe that you guys understand
that an instance
is an easy to machine.
Okay? This particular instance
now has some
softwares
or application running.
Let's say you are maybe running
some test scripts on it.
Now tell me, is it possible that you
chose a computer which had
let's see
those CPU's
RAM was
500 GB
So 5500 is way too much.
Let's go with AGP.
So is it possible that
when you are running this application,
your CPU and RAM are totally consumed
because of the traffic that you have?
Or maybe because of the test cases
that you are running?
The computer is under load.
Okay.
And your performance can be slow right?
It might happen
that your performance becomes a little
this can be a critical scenario.
Let's say, for example,
in the case that you have in a web
application
that is launched on this instance
and what happens in web application,
it is assessed to APIs, right?
So the customers are going to be
accessing that website using EC2 instance.
Right? It's deployed over here.
So they will be using some kind of API
to connect to it.
So if a lot of customers
are using the website at the same time,
is the website going to be slow?
Yes, it is going to be slow.
So EWR provides
us with an option of auto scaling.
So what happens in order scaling?
We do
mention some criteria, let's say
alarms
or criteria.
So for example, we set an alarm on CPU
that if the CPU percentage
is greater than 70%, then do what?
Launch another instance.
Okay.
So we cannot increase the CPU
at runtime, actually.
Okay, awesome.
It is not possible
for us to just add a CPU.
It will not happen at runtime
when the application is running.
We can do this that we stop the server
and we know
build the computer again, this time
a larger one.
But that is not an efficient way
because the traffic is not consistent.
There might be time when in a day
the fluid is not that much.
Right?
So we we put an alarm that
if our CPU percentage go above 70%,
just launch another instance.
So what will happen?
It will create
Amazon machine image.
For the instance
that we have already created.
This image is going to contain
all the information, all the softwares
application that are running
along with the web application
that we were running.
As soon as the CPU percentage
hit 70% and the alarm goes on, it's
going to simply launch
the exact same instance in parallel
and all the softwares
and web application
will also be running on this
particular instance.
Okay.
So now we have two same computers
running the same application.
So this is what are the scaling?
Does. So
any questions?
Okay.
Alarms only order scanning.
No alarms are everywhere.
In DFW
you'll see different kind of alarms.
You can see set down depending upon needs.
So they are also in order scanning.
They are also available in other options.
Also.
No, they are not.
I would not call them exceptions.
It's just like,
yeah, it's just like an alarm that okay,
this particular criteria has been met.
Now the question is that
how is the traffic going to be balanced?
Because this was under stress, right?
This computer was under stress.
So how is it going to share its load
with this one?
The second one
for that purpose,
we have a beautiful feature
in issue
two instance called load balancing.
Very good, very good.
You are
we have a load balancing.
Okay.
Now this load balancer is connected
to issue
two to and easy to want.
Yes, you guys must have learned about it
in the API as
now let's say
hundreds of people
are accessing the website
so it will first go to the load balancer
and the load balancer
is then going to decide
where to rooted out.
And in that way air
traffic is going to be routed accordingly
while setting no response time
lag on your web application.
So you also observe this that nowadays
we have
websites like Facebook, like Instagram,
you know, these are the websites on which
there is the most traffic all the time,
although they have their own
separate servers available,
but they are also using load balancing
and are just getting techniques
so that no person is facing any less.
Okay.
One of the most important thing
that I would like to mention here is that
when in a company
you are using auto scaling,
it helps you save a lot of money
because as soon as the traffic goes down
and your CPU percentage is less than 70,
it will shut down the other resource.
The other instance that you launched,
saving you a lot of money
and as soon as it goes above 70 again,
it's going to launch another instance
and you all get you can also control
the number of instances
that should be launched.
You cannot three, four, five,
six, ten or whatever.
It's your choice.
Okay, So the configurations
are not that complicated,
but obviously you will not be doing them
because it may charges for that.
As we are going
to put some stress on the CPUs,
it may start charging us for that.
So we will not be doing this.
I'll just simply show you the options
where they are available.
So if I go to auto scaling group,
I have launch configurations.
Okay.
So in launch configurations, what we said,
we said the configuration when
the instance needs to be launched
so I can name it
test launch.
You guys should not follow this.
Just look upon what I'm doing.
I'll just walk to quickly
the concept source and I gave you
earlier in the discussion.
I'll just show you that how we need to
configure when we are using the console.
Don't it?
Because I will not be doing it completely.
Yes, just like you.
So it says that.
Which image do you want to launch when you
when you are actually
in need?
So I'll click on choosing images.
But the thing is that
I want to launch the exact
same one that is already launched, right?
The one that we launched earlier.
I want to launch the exact
exact same image
is in the scenario.
I want that kind of am I right?
So for that I will have to create first.
And am I?
So how can we create an image?
Go to your instance and simply
right click on it
and you'll see an icon or create image.
So when I click on Create Image,
I'll name it
my test image.
Okay,
Now the image for this particular machine,
whatever is running on
this, has been created.
I can have a look at that image
by clicking on images.
And there you go.
My test images here
is this clear
that first of all,
they created the image for that machine
which we want to launch
when the resources are out of bounds.
So now let's go to launch configurations
here.
We will configure when to launch.
So create launch configurations.
The name is going to be test launch.
Okay. Now from the images,
which image should I be choosing
my test?
What exactly?
Choose the instance type.
Okay, now this says that.
Okay, which instance
do you want to go along with
if you are now launching another one?
So to micro, I hope that's available.
No. One t to my cross.
I think it's not here.
And then to our s
t to nano micro is not to it.
Okay.
Okay. So no other options
we need to configure.
There are some regarding the security ones
and the keep here.
We are using the existing PPA,
so let it be.
Eight of us wanted to see created
launch configuration.
So launch contributions are there. Now.
We will go to our two scaling groups
and in our order scaling grows,
we are going to
create one or two scaling group.
Okay. So group name is testing
the launch.
Now it wants to
choose a launch template
that contains the instance level settings
such in the Amazon Machine
image type and security group.
Let's see if we have one already.
We will have to create a launch template.
So let's not name a test template
and let other options be by default.
No. An image template that will be used.
Okay, Miami's
my test images there.
I can select this one
instance.
Type p one microgaming
network settings.
We do not need consideration this right.
Okay.
Now let's create
now let's go to launch groups.
Sorry are just going to go.
Let's try to make one
that's auto
test template.
Okay this one is good versions
that should be by default.
Next VPC is going to be default
availability zone.
Okay, so now over here,
I want to mention one more thing.
Let's say you want to run your
application in such a way
that you also have
redundancy for that.
For example,
what happened at the last case
that we discussed
was regarding the load one right?
But what if due to some
technical fault or natural disaster,
your data center stops working,
The whole data center is out of operation.
So in such a scenario, do you want
your application to go on or downtime?
It's not available to people
that you know,
but the problem is
that the whole data center is out.
So in your order scaling
group, what you'll do is
you will choose this subnet
different from the previous one.
So your one machine is going to lie
in one building,
whereas the other machine
is going to be like
in another building.
So that in a scenario
where even one data center is not working,
the other one is
still there to support your application.
So over here,
if I selected the first one to be one
B, now I can select one eight.
Okay, So now if you want to attach a load
balancer, you can.
If not, then you cannot.
For now, you will not be launching that.
These are somehow check metrics.
It means that checking your instance
after every 300 seconds,
if it's there, is good enough.
If not, it's going to automatically launch
another instance
in a separate building.
Okay, So now
what is the desired capacity?
One minimum capacity.
One desired capacity, let's say three,
and the maximum capacity, let's say five.
So we are saying that minimum
there should be one instance,
like I desired them to be three
and maximum can mean a five node.
Not no greater than that.
Now we have an optional
scaling the policy scaling policies.
Okay, now target scaling policy.
You can select on average CPU
utilization, average network in average
network out our application
load balancer request convert target.
It means that the number of request
to load counter is load
balancer is encountering so we can go
with the utilization target value.
We can set to 70
next.
No notifications
needed, no tags needed, and simply create
autofill and grow.
Okay, so auto scaling has been launched
and now it will be in action.
Let's see in our easy to instance
dashboard.
Okay, so do you remember
I said the desired capacity
to three?
I set the desired capacity to three.
So that's why it just like three
more instance of the same
exact image.
Because desired capacity means that
this is what you prefer
in normal conditions.
So now the sad part is
I will not be able to terminate it
even if I terminate
all of them.
They will be launched automatically again,
because the art of scaling up is going to
see that, okay, instance is not working.
It's going to check itself and it's
going to be launching it once again.
So I'll just go and delete
the group.
Any questions regarding order
scaling and load balancing?
Yeah, I'm
just going to delete these things
because they are going to charge me if
if they are there.
Okay, So That's why I need to delete them.
I don't know why, but due to some reason,
every month I get charged $1
by eight of us.
I don't know.
I have not been using any services,
but it's just $1.
So I'm like, okay, just do it.
I don't care.
Actions delete No
option to delete
instances.
Yeah, well, you are right about this.
A lot of money from the don't care
customers.
I checked my account.
I was I saw nothing
but nothing was launched.
So I don't know what's the fee for.
Obviously they will have some reasons.
It's a big company.
Amazon They cannot just charge me
for doing nothing.
Maybe I have some.
Maybe I misread some policy
I don't know about.
Maybe there is an update, but that's
the reason they will not be charging.
Without any policy.
You cannot do that actually,
because one legal case
around them can actually destroy them.
Okay.
So regarding the
issue, to instance, I think
this much information is sufficient enough
and trust me with that, that we have only
like only 20% of SC doing stats.
There are a lot of other options
available over here
that we can incorporate
and start working with them.
They are now as
but it's
impossible
to actually cover, to be very honest.
I am also not familiar
with all these options that are out there.
So regarding the cloud, I hope that
now you get an idea of how vast it is
and how much complicated it can be.
So the good thing is that
no one is right
now expert of the whole cloud
and people do not expect from
especially the testers or the developers
to be an expert in cloud.
If you have the basic information,
you are good to go.
If you understand the terminologies,
what's a security group person?
I am role.
What's an easy to understand?
How many services are there?
How can you make use of a service?
You are good enough.
So for example,
if you have to use any of other
services, let's say
there is one service kindness.
Let me show you.
Yeah.
This one kind of says
so if you want to
use let's say
you do not have any idea about kindness,
is that how and what is the application
of this particular service?
Just go to guidances.
There you'll see a detailed information
of how how it works.
Collect and store data streams, collect
gigabytes of data per second,
and make it available
for processing and analyzing in real time.
It means that
it's a prebuilt application
that collects the data from a source
and makes it available for processing.
So if you have your computer
in your computer, you are generating
or you are getting some data
and you want to have some real time
analysis on it,
you can simply connect that computer
with the stream
and send the data directly to that stream
and apply some pre-built analysis
technique or algorithms on that data
that is available.
Currencies, data
firehose The bear and load
real time data streams into data tools
and analytics tools.
Kindness is data
analytics get actionable insights
from streaming data in real time.
So if you want to create this application,
you can create live
stream, create a data stream.
You'll get a lot of material
on the database documentation over here
that will guide you how to do this.
This explain
the stuff in detail, in depth.
So any service that you want to use,
any service
that you want to learn about,
you can simply go to that service, read
the documentation about it,
and give it a free tier.
Go just play around. It will help you out.
Okay.
Regarding the Dockers, yes,
I'll be teaching the Docker classes
and they are
just going to be more of a conceptual,
not much practical
implementation of Dockers is going to be.
The reason being that Dockers
is really something
that DevOps use testers,
even me as a developer, I have
I think only use Dockers twice or twice
and that was when I was working
in the last company in machine learning
because our team was the one
who were expected
to not go to any of their team
and be capable
of doing the work of testers,
doing the work of DevOps,
doing the work of where like everything
we were supposed to and we were expected
to be able to do everything.
So that's the reason
I had to use Dockers over there
rather than that developers and testers,
they don't usually do to Dockers.
It's a configuration do
and that is the responsibility
of the DevOps team
in your company to handle that.
So do one thing,
just make sure that before our next class
you guys have
the docker installed on your computers.
How to do that?
There are plenty of videos on YouTube.
I'll share or two link.
Try those out,
Make sure that you have Docker installed
so that we can give it a go together
and do one thing more.
Before you sign off on this account,
just make sure you go too easy to
and terminate all your instance
so that you do not get charged for them.
So I'm going to check it again.
It's still here.
Select and select actions.
Now maybe I have terminated them
one by one
state
and so
yeah, and instant state.
Terminate instance, terminate.
Okay, so auto stealing group, just check
that not have our testing policy
so the incidents are
not launched automatically
load balance.
I hope
that we do not have any of the perfect
rate so apart from that, these are some
notes and slides of whatever we have
discussed.
I have placed all the information
in these notes and slides.
There you have
also the steps of our data policy,
how to create an instance
and stuff like that is there.
So you guys can have access to that.
And there are some slides also.
Do we have them read the help you out?
Okay,
so officially we are done with the cloud.
I hope that you guys are now much clearer
about the idea that what is a cloud
and you are able to launch an instance,
connect to it, and if you are able to do
and understand this,
the goal of the class is complete it.
You have three security groups.
You can share the screenshot.
Should I add them to the canvas
or can I just share them
in the course announcements?
Thank you, Mariam.
Okay. Canvas.
Sure, I'll add them to canvas under us.
Under the eight of us what we call
it Less folder Other demo.
What do.
Okay, so
that's it for today.
I'll see you guys on Tuesday.
Make sure that you have your dollars
installed.
I'm not sure about the practical stuff.
I believe that we will not be
working on some real
Docker application.
Rather, we will be discussing the concepts
in detail of
what is a Docker,
why do we need them and how to
launch it, how it help us in real life.
We'll be discussing stuff.
So but just in case,
have Dockers installed on your computer
so that you are familiar
with the interface and
how does it look and how you can actually
launch Docker containers on that?
This is what we will be doing.
You will be launching Docker containers,
so have them start out
and lead those groups
keepers, volumes, instances.
No, you'll get I don't think there is
binary.
You have some.
Sure that you'll be to see
if you can turn off like this.
If not
security group is just a configuration.
Do not need to worry about it.
There is a lot we charge you.
Anything for that?
Okay.
Okay guys, take care.
See you again.