All right, guys, let's get started.
I think we have enough people already.
All right.
Good morning, everybody.
Always everybody doing, guys
as everybody feeling what's going on.
Everyone is good.
I hope everyone completed the homework.
I'm good.
Thank you.
Okay.
Any issues with the homework, guys
that we went through?
Any. Any issues
with the topics that we've covered before?
All good.
Hopefully.
Okay, good.
So let's do a recap
of what we've done
in the last class.
Okay.
What did we cover?
Last class, guys?
Okay.
Well covered alerts and frames. Right.
Okay,
So what do we know about alerts, guys?
What is an alert?
It's a pop up notification, right?
Okay.
What does it do?
So it's a notification or a pop up
right on the web?
On the Web page. What does it do, guys?
It takes our
focus away from the main page, right?
It informs it about something
or asks for an input.
It takes the focus from our main page.
Okay, good.
What kind of.
And we can't do anything
until we close it, right?
Or until we handle it.
Okay,
so how many types of alerts do we know?
Guys?
Three types of.
Okay, so we've got
Web based alerts.
Right.
JavaScript alerts and Windows
based alerts.
Right.
Okay.
So how do we handle the Web based
alerts, guys?
We can simply inspected.
Right.
Because it takes the focus
from the main page,
but we don't have to switch to it or
we don't have to use any different tools.
Right.
So we're simply inspected
because it's a part of our main page
and we don't need to switch to it.
Right. Okay, good.
What about the Windows based alerts, guys?
How do we handle those?
We cannot write by using Sylvania.
We won't be able to handle the Windows
based alerts.
Okay. All right, good.
So now let's get into the JavaScript
alerts, guys.
How do we handle those
using the methods?
Okay.
How do we handle
JavaScript alerts in selenium?
Switch to it.
Except dismiss this for that.
What do we use guys
using switch method?
Okay. What else, guys?
I think I put it in the notes
as an interview question last time.
If I'm not mistaken,
we use an alert interface right?
To handle the JavaScript alert.
In selenium, we use alert interface.
Right.
So using alert interface,
then switching to that alert, accepting,
dismissing, right, getting the text or
depending on what kind of alert
it is with handle that alert.
Right.
So how many types of JavaScript
alerts do we know about guys?
Three types.
Okay.
What are those three types?
Simple Alert.
Confirmation alert and prompt.
Alert. Right.
Okay.
What can we do in the simple alert, guys?
We can just click.
Okay. What else?
Anything else
we can do in the Simple alert? Guys
now or. Yes.
So some people say get attacks.
Is it.
Can we do.
Can we get the text from the simple alert
guys or no.
Why not? Guys?
Why can we get the text
from the simple alert?
So if I click in here,
why can't I get this one?
It's a simple alert.
Right.
So that means we can get
the text from the simple alert as well.
Okay.
If we don't
if we didn't do it in the last class,
guys, that doesn't mean we can not do it.
Okay.
So you need to pay attention
on what we've got on the message.
If you have a message,
you can have, you can get the text.
Okay.
All right.
What about the confirmation alert, guys?
What can we do in there?
Cancel or click. Okay.
Can we get the text, guys?
We can get the text from there
as well. Right.
Okay, good.
All right.
What about the prompt alert
and the prompt alert?
We can enter the text,
send keys, accept or dismiss.
Right.
And can we get the text?
Guys?
So if I click on the prompt alert
and if I get the text here,
which text is it
going to return me?
Enter your name.
Right. Okay, good.
All right.
Okay.
So let's jump to the let's jump
to the frame scores.
Okay. What do we know about frames, guys?
What is the frame?
Frame?
It's like separate pages. Okay.
Nested web page.
Okay.
An independent window in our web page.
Good frames. A separate window. Okay.
So frame is is an email inside?
Another email, right?
Okay. That's very good.
Okay, So it's a separate
and an independent window in a web page.
Right.
So it allows developers
to present different, different
or multiple views in the same page.
Right. Okay.
So how how can we interact
or how can we handle the frames?
How many ways can we actually interact
with frames, guys?
Three ways.
Which are
set by index, by name
or ID and by web element.
Right. Okay. That's very good.
Okay, So in order to handle those
or to interact with the frames
by index name
or ID or web element, what else
do we need to do?
We need to switch, right?
We need to switch to the frames
so that we can interact with the elements
inside that.
Okay.
So what if
I switch into the frame
and then I want to interact
with these elements?
Guys on the very top?
What I need to do,
we need to switch
back to the default content.
Right?
So you have to manually switch
inside the frame
and get outside of the frame.
Okay.
All right. Any questions, guys?
Any questions on how to handle alerts or
how to handle frames?
Okay, All clear.
It's good. Okay.
So today, guys, what we going to be doing
today
is we will be going over
the windows.
Okay.
We will be going how to handle
multiple windows
or multiple tabs in the inside the crawl.
Okay.
So what I want you to do today,
guys, is try not to type, okay?
Try to listen.
What I'm going to explain
because it's going to get a little bit
a little bit confused in the middle.
Okay.
So that's why
I want you guys to listen first
and then you can type your code any time.
I'll give you time. Okay.
Is that good, guys? I hope that's good.
And let's get started.
Right.
Okay,
so let me go back to the intelligence.
I'm going to create a new
note file.
Are we?
We're almost there, guys.
It's seventh class.
We've got, like,
four more or something. And then.
Then we're going to be done
total.
I'm not sure.
I think total is 11 or 12.
Yes, I'll try to push the code
as much as possible.
Okay, guys, today, because you guys
are going to be listening to
this and not typing.
All right, guys.
So handling
multiple windows.
Okay.
So did anyone first of all, didn't
want to do a research on how to handle
multiple Windows and selenium guys?
Okay.
What do you know
about how do we handle
multiple windows in selenium?
Okay, a little bit.
Okay. Let's see, guys.
See what?
You guys.
Fine.
Window handles really good.
What else? Get window handles
three commands.
Get handle handles.
Okay, that's fine. Good.
Using the iterator.
Okay. Sounds good, guys.
So in order for us to
to handle multiple windows,
we will be using two different methods.
Okay.
One of them is get window handle,
and the other one is get window handles.
Okay.
And I'll explain to you
when to use which one.
what the window handler is.
Okay.
In order to handle
multiple windows,
we will be using
get a window handle
method and get window
handles.
Okay.
So obviously, get window handler
was going to get you a single handle
and get window handles is going to get you
multiple handles.
Okay.
So what is a window handle?
Window handle is a unique ID
that holds that address of the window.
Okay. Or a tab.
So it is approximately
or consists of 40 alphanumeric characters.
Okay.
So basically,
when I go in here, so let's say
I have a chrome in here
and we navigate it to this web page.
So this tab will have its own unique I.D.,
which is called a window handle. Okay.
We don't see it here.
It's behind the scenes.
But we will be printing those window
handles inside our console
so that you can
so that you can see how it looks like.
Okay. But here.
No, that. Guys, any tab you open
in the Chrome
browser or whatever browser
you're using any tab you open.
It will have its own unique address,
which is called window handle.
Any questions on that, guys?
So window handle
right is a
unique I.D.
that shows the
address of the window or a tab.
Okay.
And it is approximately
is approximately 40
of the numeric
or their I.D..
Okay.
So it holds a pretty long I.D..
Okay. So we'll take a look at that.
All right.
So now this is enough from the theory
that we need to know right now.
So now we need to dive
into the actual implementation.
Okay.
So what I'm going to do
is create another package,
and I'm going to create another
class.
Okay.
Name it as simple window handling.
And what I'm going to do with the main
method in here. So.
So what we going to be doing now, guys,
let me open up
that page that we will be interacting
with all.
Okay.
So what we're going to do now, guys,
we will be navigating to this Web
page in here.
And what I'm going to do
is click on this help in here.
Okay.
So if I click help in here,
you can see that once I click that,
we're going to have a new tab
open up for us.
Okay.
So and then what
we need, what we're going to be doing,
we will be switching
between two different tabs
and we will be performing different,
different actions.
Okay. Any questions, guys?
Before we get started?
Okay.
All right.
Let's do this right.
Let me like this one.
That's it.
Let's get this copied
in here.
And I need the.
This one of
zero.
Okay. So this is our URL.
We set up the properties when we launched.
The browser would navigate to that URL.
Right.
What do I need to do in here, guys?
What is my next step?
So find the web element.
Right?
Find the web element
that I will be interacting with.
All right. Let's go here.
So we navigate it here.
So now let me inspect this page.
And what
I want to do, I want to click on this.
Right.
What what is the locator that I can use
in here?
Guys, the easiest one
text for Xbox.
But if I if I don't want to use Xbox in
here, I get.
Okay, what else
Address.
What is the locator, guys?
What is the locator
that I can use in here?
Which is the easiest one.
This is a trap.
What about link text? Guys?
Did we forget about the link?
Text?
Can we use the link text in here?
Guys?
Easy. Right.
So you can use the link text.
And you just need this text, right?
Yep. You guys did forget about this.
Let's not do that. Okay.
So I know there's a lot of stuff.
I know there's a lot of
there's a lot of locators in there.
But try to see the optimized way
to solve the problem.
Okay.
So we're going to be using a link
text in here.
So obviously, you can do it with X path,
probably since we were doing everything
by Express
so that we have a lot of practice.
You guys forgot
about the rest of the locators.
Okay, so.
But it's okay.
All right. So what I will do
web element
help link is equal to driver
sign element by
where is that link text?
Right.
And of course the link text in here.
Okay, so I have this.
Okay.
But before I perform any action.
So let's perform
an action as well in here.
It doesn't really matter.
So help link
right
click.
Okay.
So we're clicking on that
and then our new tab is open
right before I go ahead,
find that element and click on that right.
What I want to do, Guy,
I want to have the handle
of the main page that I just navigated to.
Okay.
So what I'm going to do
before I find that element and before
I click on that element, what I will do,
I'll simply go ahead and do driver
the get window handle.
Okay.
So when I do this,
it will automatically go ahead
and capture the address
for that exact tab that I just navigate.
Okay.
Is that clear?
Guys?
And since I set that,
it is an alphanumeric value, Right?
So where do we store this, guys? Exactly.
That's the question for you guys.
What am I getting in return?
I'm getting a simple string.
Right? So let's do this.
We can do main page
handle is equal to driver dot get window
handler.
Right.
So what I'm going to do in here, I'm
going to go ahead and print it out for you
so that you guys can see how actually
this window handle looks like.
Okay, so main page in here.
Okay.
So let me run this.
Actually, let's not click on the Help yet.
Let's just see how our window handle
looks like.
Okay, I'm on.
All right.
So we're navigating it to this page.
So let's go ahead
and take a look at our console right now.
So you can see here, guys, it's very long
alphanumeric value in here.
Okay.
So we don't see this on the on
the browser.
Whenever we're doing something manually,
we can only see it
whenever we are doing some scripting.
And whenever you get that window handle
and print it out,
only then you will see it.
But most of the time, guys, you won't be
you won't need to print this out.
You just need to get the window
handle and perform different actions
because you will be moving
through the different different
tabs.
Yes. It's used for tracking.
Yes. Okay.
Yes. It's good for you guys
to see visually how everything looks
because you won't really understand
if you don't see it.
Right.
So if you just write the code and run it
and it runs fine,
that's not the good thing. But
I tried to visually
show you so that you guys can see,
okay, okay, 32 is fine.
I said approximately 40, right, guys,
It doesn't have to be 40.
It's almost 40. So.
All right,
so we have the main page window handle.
We captured it. We started in the
what's called
in the string variable in here.
So let me
uncomment this one.
Okay.
So now what I will do in here.
So let's run this.
Okay, So let me run this
and this is going to open up a different
it should open up a different tab, right?
Well, this is slow today.
Okay. Running
here. There we go.
So it open up the second tab in here.
So what I need to do in here,
I need to have all the tabs
inside my script
so that I can keep switching between them.
Okay, so this window handle
that we just captured,
it's only one window
handle from the main page, Right?
So I'm going to need all the window
handles
so that I can keep count
or I can keep manipulating them,
or I can keep switching,
or I can close them
whatever action I want to do.
Okay, So the main purpose
of having the window handles
is to keep track of the tabs
and to switch through those tabs.
Is that clear?
Guys, any questions?
Okay, so right now in here, guys,
what we have, we have two different tabs.
Right.
So what I want to do in here,
I want to capture all the tabs
that I have right now on my session.
Okay,
So I open up when I open up a new browser.
What?
What is this, guys?
This is my new session.
Okay, so if I closed this the previous
one, it's a completely different session.
Okay, so whatever.
Whatever amount of window handles
I have in the session,
I want to store them inside the container.
Okay, so the window handle, it changes
each time.
It's not going to change, guys. So
this let's say I open this is to
tabs that open. Right.
So the one that just printed out, it's
going to be the same
through out the same session
throughout the same execution.
Okay.
But when you complete your execution
and then you open up another Chrome
browser, it's going to start a new session
and it's going to be completely new tab
and it's going to be completely new window
handle.
Okay.
So this tab has its own window handle
and this tab has its own window handle.
Okay.
Is that clear? Guys
know that
the window handles,
they change with the session as well.
Okay, so you open up a new session
and you tab is going to change your the.
It's going to change the window handle.
Okay, So if you open up another session
for the same exact website,
it will change the window handle as well.
Okay. So it is always dynamic.
You don't really know
what kind of window handle you have.
So right now.
Okay, guys, since I want to grab all the
all the tabs
and store them inside the container,
what I am going to do, I'm going to use
get window handles method.
Okay.
So driver, the get window handles
which returns us What goes in here?
Is it returning to stream? Guys
get window handles.
It's returning a set of strings.
Right.
Okay, so what?
Why is it not returning me a
a list of strings?
Guys,
any guesses on this?
Why am I getting a set of strings?
Isn't it easier to have
less stuff?
It should be unique.
Absolutely. Right.
Because set will not allow duplications.
Good.
Okay, so what I will do in here,
since I'm using get window
handles, what I'm going to do,
going to have a
set of strings and say all
window handles.
Okay.
Is equal to driver that get window
handles.
Okay, So there we go.
So now what I did,
I got all the all the window
handles right.
And I stored them inside the set.
Okay. So
whenever I click
on the help link in here
and it opens up a new tab,
what I am doing here,
I am grabbing those two tabs
and storing them in the set of strings.
Okay, so this is going to do it
automatically because it's
looking for those handle
on the active session.
Okay. Is that clear, guys?
Any questions?
Okay, good.
All right.
So right now, what I want to do,
I want to print out
how many tabs I have inside my console.
Okay. So what? I will do
the print line right?
So all window handles.
How how can I see how many of those tabs
I have guys that side. Right.
Easy to record.
Or if you if you open up a new one
demo, then. Is that your question? Okay.
After this.
Okay, So.
So in this case, it will not record it
because what you did,
you only captured the once available
for you.
Exactly.
You would have to capture
all the window handles again.
Okay.
You don't have to create
a new set of strings.
You can use the same exact variable
that you have in here.
Okay.
Any other questions, guys
will handle
for the first window
and then use it from demo.
Yes, you can do that.
Yeah.
Declared in the beginning.
Oh, so are you.
Are you
guys talking about the main page handle
or you are talking about line 23.
Oh Oscar each tab. Yes.
So you have to do
you have to do this exact same. Yes.
So to capture all the handles. Yes.
You need to do that. Okay.
So now, guys, let me tell you how
this is works in real world.
So whenever you join a company or in it in
and you working on the application, Right.
So you won't be working on too many tabs
because it doesn't really make sense.
So to open one tab
and then to open another one
and then after that another one
and then test another one.
Right.
So that doesn't really make sense for you
in terms of testing.
So what happens what happens in real,
real applications
that you navigate to one page,
you click on something
and it opens up a new page
and then you continue your work
on the second tab.
Okay.
So you don't have to open
multiple, multiple or what's called
multiple tabs
in order to work on some functionality.
Okay.
So this is not how it's going to work.
So most the most tabs or windows
you're going to be working on,
on a real application
is going to be two different tabs.
Okay.
And one of them,
whenever you switch to one of them,
you will be closing the first one.
Okay. So this is how it usually works.
So don't really
get scared if if I have five tabs.
If I have seven tabs, you won't have that.
Okay.
So the maximum amount of windows
or tabs you're going to have in
in your real
application is going to be two.
Okay.
Having our active session, if we open new
tabs, then we need to capture it again.
Exactly. Yes.
Yes. No need to save the second tab
because you're going to be closing it.
Okay, so I got this size right now
of my set of string.
So let me run this and let's see,
what are we going to
get in return?
Okay.
When here, opening up a new tab,
clicking on help.
Right.
And here you can see that it's number two.
So I have two window handles right now
stored inside the set of strings.
Okay.
Any questions, guys,
before I move forward?
Okay, good.
All right, So now, guys, what
How is it opening a new tap?
We're clicking on helpfully line 2021.
So if you click on the Help link, it's
going to open a new tab.
Okay, Right here.
So click on this.
It's going to open a new tab.
Okay, So now we know
we captured all the window handles.
Now we have
we know how many window handles
we have inside our set of strings.
Okay.
So what I need to do right now
in order for me to switch around
and manipulate those tabs,
what I need to do,
I need to iterate those tabs.
Okay.
So in this case, what I'm going to do,
I'm going to create an item later.
Okay, So what?
I'll do all window handles the
iterator
here. Okay.
So I need to the variable
click to greater
strings. Right.
To just to this and let's import this guy.
Okay.
So now what I'm trying to do,
I'm trying to iterate through each
and every tab that I have inside my set.
Okay, so now,
guys, I'm not going to be creating a
for a while loop in here,
but I'll show you how to do it one by one.
Okay.
So if you if you create a Y loop, it's
going to see if there is something next.
And then will be performing
some actions. Right.
So I want to show you the easy way
right now.
And then we will go to Advanced
Window Hand.
Okay.
So first of all, guys,
when I step forward inside my iterator,
so what am I going to have, guys?
So let's say
I have a set of strings, right?
I have a set of window handles.
So if I step forward,
what am I going to have?
Guys?
Any thoughts?
The first handle.
Right. Okay, So that's very good.
So if I step forward, I'm
going to have the first handle right.
So what I'm going to do my next
step is my first handle.
Right?
Where is my first handle right now, guys?
My first handle is the main page handle.
Okay.
So what I will do
my next step, I will say the main page
handle is my next step.
Okay.
And since we know that
there's two different tabs in here,
I need to create another handle.
Because whenever I am moving forward
the second time, I need a new handle.
Is that clear, guys?
I'm pretty sure this is.
This is the time that it's going to be
confusing a little bit, but that's fine.
Okay.
So I'm going to create a new string
and say
child handle, okay?
And I'm going to assign it
to my next step.
Okay.
So and then let me
just to print line the child handle.
Okay. All right, guys.
So let me explain it to you one more time.
Okay.
So line 27, what we're doing,
what we trying to do?
We're trying to iterate
through the tabs, right?
So the first step
that I'm going inside that set, guys,
what am I seeing?
The first thing
which handle
I am seeing guys
the main.
Right.
So that's why I am assigning
my first step to the main page handle.
Okay.
And then
since we know there's two different tabs,
I need to have another handle
so that I can step forward.
Okay.
Is that clear? Guys?
Any questions?
There should be Exactly.
There should be two different handles
for me
to step forward twice.
Any confusion in here, guys?
Okay.
Okay, good.
So now what I will do in here.
So I'm going to print the child handle.
That is fine.
So now what I need to do
since I opened up a new tab.
What I want to do,
I want to go back to my main page handle
so we could store.
Oh, that's the tricky part.
Okay, Blake,
I'm coming to your question right now.
Okay, I'm coming to your question.
We're already in main page
when we're not on the main page, Right?
So if I click on this, where am I going?
If I click on this, guys, I'm going to
the child page, right?
So what I need to do,
I need to switch back in here.
Okay.
So that's why I'm switching to the main.
So if there's a third handle,
we would like to do another child.
Exactly.
But right now, let's just keep it
simple, guys.
We two tabs.
We will be handling
four or five tabs after this.
So it's going to be it's
going to be a little bit different.
But let's keep it in two tabs right now
in here.
Okay.
All right.
So what I did step two times forward.
One of them is main page.
One of them is child hand.
Okay, so what I am doing here,
I am assigning
my next steps manually.
Okay, so my first step,
I'm saying it's main page,
and my second step is going to be my child
handle.
Okay, so now what I need to do
since we switched and we're seeing right.
Well, looking at the child page right now,
what I need to
do, I need to switch to the main. Okay.
So what I'm
going to do in here, I'm going to driver
that switch to that window.
Okay.
So inside the parentheses,
I am going to put I'm going to paste
a window handle of the page
that I want to switch to.
Okay.
So right now, the page that I want
to switch to is the main page handle.
Okay.
And this is how I'm going to switch
back to the main page.
Okay.
So let me actually here,
give it a little bit of a pause
for 2 seconds so that we can see
what is going on on the Web page.
Okay.
So now what I will do
will go ahead and run
this.
No, you don't have to store it.
No, no, no.
You don't have to sort this one.
So what you are doing, you are simply
performing an action for your tab.
Okay.
So we open up a new one.
2 seconds.
Now, what we did,
we switch back to the main page, Right?
So that's pretty cool, right, guys?
Okay, Nice.
Okay, So now, guys,
any confusions in here?
If you want, I can go over this again.
Guys, How and why we're going.
Okay, let's quickly.
Seems like there are some people
who are confused right now.
Let's quickly go over it again. Okay.
So when I when I click on the help
link in here, what I did is
it opened up a new one,
a new tab, Right.
24, line 24.
What I did, I captured all
set of strengths.
Right.
And then on line 27,
what I did, I said, hey, okay,
I have a set of strengths.
So I want to iterate through them. Okay.
So I want to iterate through them,
but I don't want to do it with Luc.
I want to do it manually. Okay.
And then I said, Hey,
whenever I want to step first,
whenever I want to make my first move,
I want my first move to be my main page
handle.
Okay?
And whenever I make my second move,
I want this second move to be my child
handle.
Okay.
And then, since we opened up the new tab
and we're looking into my second tab right
now, what I did,
I switched back to the main page handle.
Okay.
And if you look at the console guys,
we have the child window handle as well.
Okay.
Switch method, which to any window.
Yes. Correct.
Yes. With a switch method,
you can switch to any window.
You can right.
I mean, any window you have,
you won't be able to do it with indexes.
Okay. So.
So let's say you talking.
I think what you mean is let's say
you have five tabs from the first.
You want to jump on the fifth one,
right.
And not go through the one,
two, three, four.
Is that is that your question.
Andre.
Okay.
So in that case. Okay.
So if you have if you have a four loop,
I mean, one loop.
Okay.
If you have a wild loop in this case.
So I'll show you how this works.
So let's not if I explain it to you right
now, won't understand it.
So let's go over the second exercise
and then I'll explain that to you.
Okay.
No, they're not indexed.
So basically, what we're doing here,
we're going through each and every string.
Okay, guys,
we won't be going over the indexes.
We will go.
We're going through each and every window
handle.
Okay.
Yes. If in real,
real work,
you are going over to different tabs.
Yeah, I is fine.
I mean, we will be using iterator anyways.
Okay, so you're going to be using iterator
in the next example as well.
But we're going to be using it
with a loop. Okay.
So that's going to
be more advanced than that.
Okay.
So right now, what I want you to do, guys,
I want you to capture this logic,
because this is the easy logic.
Your assigning everything manually.
But now in the next example,
we will be dealing with different
windows.
And then there we will have
a little bit of confusion in there.
Okay.
Iterator control.
No, no, no, guys. Iterator.
If it can't handle only two tabs, whatever
tabs you have, it can handle it in here.
We have two tabs.
Okay.
Okay, guys.
So there is one more thing
that I want to show you guys.
Remember, guys, we talked about close
and quit
the difference between clothes and quit.
And I told you guys whenever we were
were going over the window handles.
You will see the better difference
in there.
Okay.
So what I'm going to do right now, guys,
I'm going to go ahead
and do driver that close
after I switch to the main page handle.
Okay.
So let me run this
and see what we're going to have
to go
open it up.
Go back.
But what happened, guys?
So it only closed the main page.
Okay. Why?
Because the focus of our selenium
is only on the main page.
And it.
And we used close instead of quit
and close only closes
the current tab that we are active on.
Right.
And quit is going to terminate
that whole session.
Okay.
No, you don't have to specify the window
handling here
because it close
doesn't accept any any arguments and close
will just close the tab that you are
currently working.
All right.
Any questions, guys?
Correct.
So you have to switch
to the window
that you want to close or perform
any actions,
because whenever you switch, you take your
you take your focus of selenium with you.
Okay.
So if you don't switch,
you won't be able to close that window.
Okay, guys.
So first, before you close any tabs,
you need to make sure that your your
your focus of selenium
is on that exact tab.
Okay. Yes.
If you use quit in here.
So driver
that quit
Now quit.
And let's run
this and see what's going to happen.
This is going to happen really fast.
I think.
So it's going to switch to the main page
and it's going to terminate
the whole session.
There we go.
So it terminated the whole session.
Okay.
Any questions, guys, please?
Okay, cool.
So let me
open up a new Java class.
And here and.
All right.
All right, guys.
So the next example,
what I'm going to be doing is we're going
to be navigating to this Web page
and we will be clicking on each
on each button in here.
So if I click on this, see, okay,
so it opens up
this guy
opens up this guy
and it opens up this guy.
So there's three different pages
on the ground Facebook pages for syntax.
All right.
So we will be clicking on all of those
and then we will be switch it around
and we will be playing around
with those different windows.
Okay.
Is that clear?
Guys, any questions before we get started?
Okay, cool.
All right, so let's get this one
that the URL.
Okay.
So everything
okay?
So what I want to do first, guys,
I want to go ahead
and navigate to that page
and what I want to do right now.
I want to get the main page window
handle, guys.
Okay.
How would I do that?
Finding the element.
Now I need to get the main page
window handle dice.
Simple right driver
that get window handle
right.
And we can store it inside the string.
Do this right.
Okay. So now what I want to do?
I want to find all the elements first
and then click on those.
Okay, So now let's
go back in here for let's inspect this.
All right.
So what I want to do,
I want to find this element first.
Okay.
Let's see here.
What do we want to use in here, guys?
Like text, Right? Easy.
So let's go use the link Text.
Okay. So
I think it was the Instagram, Right?
Okay, second
button for the
element link text
pasted in here.
Okay.
And then
the second one is here.
Can use the same way
for elements.
It's Facebook
button
element by link text.
Right.
And then the third button we have here
is follow Instagram and Facebook.
This is a neat tag.
So that
everyone is clear.
What I have done from line 17 to 19.
All right, guys, any questions in here?
Okay, good.
All right.
So we identified all the elements
were located, all those elements, Right.
So what what do we need to do here?
We just need to perform a simple click.
All right.
So let's go ahead and do this
quick.
And then
click.
Okay.
So we have this.
So what I am going to do right now,
let me run this and see what
what we have on our page.
Right.
So running this.
All right, let's see.
This seems like no such element
exception, guys.
Unable
to look at the element with the link text.
Right.
What's wrong, guys?
So my link, that is fine.
Any idea what is going on in here,
guys?
So my link text follow on Instagram.
So that means this is not my selenium
is not finding this.
I didn't open a tab. Right.
This is the first element, guys.
I what I did, I navigated there.
I tried to find that element.
I didn't even click that
Exactly.
I have spaces in here, right?
So I need to remove these spaces
because I'm not looking for a text, guys.
I'm looking for a link text.
Okay, So if you're using
if you're using a next pack guys,
you see there are some spaces before
and after this text.
If you're using a next path
and you're using a text,
you have to include the spaces. Okay.
But if you're using a link text guys,
you don't have to include any spaces
which are before and after that text.
Okay.
Is that clear?
Is it possible to force the links
to open in a new tap or the new window?
You can't do that.
You cannot do that. Why?
Because it is.
It is built by developers.
So if they want if they want it to
what's called, if they want it to open up
in a new page, in a new window,
they would do it.
They would configure it themselves.
Or if they wanted to open it in a new tab,
then they would configure it that way.
Okay.
All right.
So let's run
this and see if this is going to work.
Okay. Running here.
All right.
So we clicked on everything.
And here we have three more windows, guys.
Or it can be the tabs as well.
So I think whenever you have it maximize
and you do it manually,
it it it's opening a new tab.
But whenever you have a selenium running,
it's opening a new window in here.
So that's not a big deal.
Okay, guys.
So the tab and the window are the same.
So you can
we can use the same methods as we've done
in the previous example
to switch to the main page window handle.
Okay.
So, so this windows opens
on the same session
so we don't have to worry about it.
Okay.
Okay, then.
Then it's fine, guys.
If it if it if it's not about
the maximize, then it's fine.
That's okay.
So now I have a question to you guys.
So I clicked on three different
buttons in here right away.
I didn't even switch to that
to the other windows.
So when I click on first one,
it opens up a new window.
How can I click on the second one? Does
three times.
That's the.
Oh, I didn't said okay.
Okay. That's a good question.
So guess, guys,
guess what could be the
the issue in here
that we can click
three times on the same window but it each
each button opens up a new window.
Guys Any any thoughts on this?
Because we're still in men swimming
or tap
classes and
tap is
not really
no good.
So here's the thing.
Okay, guys.
So whenever you try to open
and tap or a new window,
you click on something,
it opens a new tab or a new window.
You don't lose focus, guys,
even though see the new page guys,
your focus is still on the previous page.
Okay, so selenium, how it works
is what we click on something.
Okay,
so we clicked on this follow on Instagram.
We clicked on like us on Facebook.
Why it happened?
Because we are still on the same
main page.
We don't see it, but our focus is there.
We didn't switch anything yet.
Okay guys.
So whenever you have this kind of issue,
don't worry.
Just think that guys,
whenever you perform actions on one page
and it opens up a new tab,
even though you see
visually you had selenium
didn't switch that focus yet.
Okay.
Is that clear?
So that's why we
clicked on three different buttons in here
and it worked.
And we still have three different,
three different windows opening up.
But the thing in here
that behind the scenes
we then switch selenium focus
to different pages.
Okay, yes, you can print it.
You can print out the main page handle.
Yeah.
After you click after after you click.
And here you can do that.
But as long as you don't have to print
the main, main page
handle in here because you're already
clicking on the second and third button.
So that's the proof
that you are still on that main page
that you just navigate
on the which page.
Oh, could they may the window
handles be a verify point?
No, not really guys.
I haven't seen any way anyone
verifying the window handles.
You can verify the title and see if you're
on the same page, but you won't be.
I mean, I haven't
seen anyone verifying the
the window handles
because you don't have anything expected.
You don't have any expected value
because whenever
you open up a new session, guys,
it will it will change.
Right?
So you get the window handle.
What are you going to compare it with?
You don't know, Right?
So it's it's not a good thing to do.
Yeah, it's fine.
It's fine if they don't if
if one window is on top of the other one.
It's okay guys.
We are just getting the first one
to captured the first window handle,
and I'll show you in the.
Well, we continue this example.
You'll see the difference, guys.
Okay.
Nothing happens for right now. If.
If we don't get this window
handle in here,
we're just going to have to get it later.
Okay, guys guys,
any other questions?
Yeah,
if you comment this out, it still works.
Guys,
I didn't do anything with this. Right?
So. And you can see that
main page handle a little bit
disabled in here and it's gray.
So that means
we need to use this throughout our code.
So now get we get window
handles will give us all the for exactly.
Okay guys.
So it's 815.
Okay So let's take a break guys,
and then we'll start going over
the advanced part.
All right.
There you go.
All this and the code and
time slides on selenium.
Okay? Yeah.
I mean, selenium is more interactive
than Java, guys.
That's probably
or it's me.
So you choose guys,
whichever it is.
The aim is like watching the gladiator.
You okay?
All right, guys,
let's have a break for 16 minutes.
So let's come back at 830, okay?
Or if anyone wants to
type ten, bless me.
Okay. Thank you.
Thank you guys.
All right, guys.
I'll see you guys in 15.
All right, guys, let's get back.
Let's get back and continue
with these handles.
Right.
Let's handle some of them.
I hope everyone is back, guys,
so that we can continue in here.
Okay, So we clicked on all the
all on all the buttons,
which we have on our main page, Right.
And as we said,
we were able to click on all of them
because our focus never changed, right?
We didn't switch to anywhere.
We still on that same page and that's why
we're able to click on all the buttons
that we identified, Right?
Okay. All right.
So now, guys,
now, since I have how many windows
I have right now, how many times do I have
after I click
three buttons.
Four. Right.
Okay, So let's
get them stored inside the container.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is create a set,
create a set of strings in here.
And again, all window
handles, right, is equal to
driver.
The get window handles right
and then import
set in here.
So now let's print out how many
how many windows we have in here.
Going to be all window handles, dot size.
All right. Okay.
So now what we want to do,
what I want to do, guys, I want to iterate
through through all the handles.
Okay, Set
how many windows we opened.
Now we're open for windows.
All right, So now what
I want to do, I want to go over
each window.
Okay?
Oh, by clicking. Okay,
So I want to go through each window,
get the title and, print it out.
Okay, guys, is that clear?
Okay, good.
So now what I want to do,
I want to start iterating right that case.
What we want to do,
we want to create a Knights of Raider
iterator of strings.
And here is equal to all window handles
that are doing right.
So we have this.
So now what I want to do,
since I have more windows than we had
in the previous example, right?
So before we had to, now we have for.
So instead of doing everything manually,
what I want to do,
I want to do it through the help of loop.
Okay, so here what I will do
exactly I will do y loop.
Okay.
And I'll say the wild loop. If
I have something, my, my next step.
Right.
What is going to happen is I need to
I need to get the title
and I need to print it out.
Okay.
So what is my next step in here, guys?
So I have my iterator.
I have everything inside
my set container, right?
And I'm to go through each
and every window handle
by using this violence.
So what is my next step in here?
This.
Okay,
so I to write that next.
Right?
What if I do isolated next?
What am I getting in return?
Okay.
Is it the main page?
Guys, I'm inside my loop.
Okay, so in the first iteration, yes, I'm
going to get my main page right,
but on the second iteration,
I'm getting a different one.
Right? So what we can do in here, since
we're iterating
multiple times and we don't know
either it's main page or either
child's page, right?
So what we can do, we can simply store
it inside the string,
which is just the handle.
Okay?
We don't have to we don't have to
say that it's main
page or child page or whatever page it is,
because whenever we iterating,
we go through all of them, right?
So every step I'm getting a handle, right?
So if there is something I step over,
I get another handle.
Okay?
Next iteration, I step over,
I get another handle right.
Okay, so we have the handle.
So what do I have to do right now
in order to print out the titles
of all those four pages?
Is it handle that get title? Does
handle is a string, guys.
Right. Handle is a string.
So what I need to do,
I need to do.
Okay.
So do I have to switch first
or I have to get the title search?
Guess which one
switch or title.
Okay, so I see title.
I see switch first.
Okay,
so we need to get the title first, right?
Because we get the handle.
We already have the focus, right?
So on the main page we get the main page
title and then switch to the next one.
Right? Okay, so let's try this.
So driver that
title in here,
let's do string
title.
Okay?
And then what we need to do,
we need to switch to the next window
with this handle.
Right.
Is this clear, Guys?
Any questions before I run this?
Okay, so let's run
this and see what we're going
to have.
Okay. Getting for
four different
windows in here.
Okay. What happened, guys?
What did we miss in here?
Guys, What did we missing here?
Where do I see my title exactly?
We didn't print right? So
what I need to do,
I need to print it.
Okay, so I got the title, guys.
I. What do I need to do then?
Do I need to switch
and then print or I have to print it
and then switch
print first.
Right.
Okay, so it's printed first
and then switch
the windows.
Okay, so let's run this again.
If morning.
Here we go.
Everything in here.
There we go.
But now what we have in here,
where for which is we printed on line 29,
which we have for different
windows and then for
titles that we have on our pages.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys,
Any questions in here?
Okay,
so now what I want to do, guys, I want to
since I opened up three more windows,
now I have four in total, right?
We got
the title was switched to those windows.
Right.
So now what I want to do,
I want to close all the other
all the windows that I just opened
and I have two
and I want to keep the main page
that I navigated first open.
Okay, Is that clear, guys?
So Let's go ahead and open this.
So I open these child windows.
What I want to do,
I want to close all of these, okay?
I want this to be open. Okay.
All right.
So how are we going to do this in here?
So we going through the next one,
we're getting title
and we're switching to the handle.
So how can we have that?
I, I keep the main page
open and close the other ones,
the other child windows.
Okay. If condition.
Okay, That's very good.
Okay.
What am I having in my condition guys,
if it's not main.
Okay, that's very good.
So what am I comparing it with?
What am I comparing inside the
if condition
guys, Is it the title?
Because I see two same titles in here
guys.
The titles are the same.
Exactly.
We need to compare the main page
handle with a handle that is coming.
Okay, so the main page handle,
we got it in here.
Okay, so right now
I have this stored already, right?
So what I am going to do,
I need to compare this page handle
equals
to the handle I get right.
And then what I need to do, let's say,
okay, let's get the title,
let's print it out and let's switch right.
And what do I want to do
at the very end, guys?
What am I doing in here?
I need to close it. Right.
Simple.
The driver dot close.
Okay, But here, guys,
my condition has to be the reverse, right?
Because I'm. I am inside my wild.
Look what I do. I get the handle.
So if I want to keep the main page open,
I need to skip
whenever they're both equal.
Right.
So here what I am going to do, I'm
saying that only
if my main page is not equal to the handle
that I just landed,
then perform these actions.
Okay, so let's run this and see
if this is going to work.
Okay. Opening these three
things it sale.
Right.
Okay, so let's see what happened.
No such window exception.
Okay.
What does it mean, guys?
So here, guys,
whenever we're switched, right,
whenever we switched, we closed it right.
So where is my focus right now?
If I am inside this,
If I am inside that,
if statement right now.
So the first one, it's okay.
So it's open.
I am taking I'm getting the title,
I'm switching, I'm closing.
Right.
But then my next iteration,
what happens is
what if I don't have that right?
So we need to get the title when guys
after switching,
we need to make sure we switched our focus
and only then we get the title right.
So let's run this
thing.
So this way and
let me
run this.
Let's see if this is going to work
open.
S There we go.
What happened, guys?
So it's closed.
That's three of the child windows
and we still have
our main page open, right?
So pretty simple.
Any questions on this, guys?
A little bit tricky.
Yes, it's a little bit tricky, but
with with practice, it's it's all good.
I mean, it's not that complicated.
And as I said, guys, in a real project,
in a real application,
you won't be handling like three, four
or five different tabs
or windows. Okay.
So the most the most you will be handling
two different tabs.
Okay.
All right, guys.
So. Oh,
here the title.
Okay, Why? Why?
We're missing that.
The main page title in here.
Because we're excluding the main page
from the loop.
Exactly.
So in the if condition, if our main page
handle equals this handle,
we're not inside this and we're
not getting any titles. Okay.
Exactly.
Okay.
So one more time the wild loop, right?
So we're going inside the wild loop.
We have a set of window handles,
which is for different tabs or windows.
Right?
So the first time I go in there,
my next step is just the handle.
It doesn't really matter
which handle I am getting right?
And then in here I have a check, right?
I have a f condition.
And here if the main page handle that
I got on line 90
equals that the handle I am on right now,
then I'm not going to be performing
anything.
Okay I will be switching to that window
handle right to the handle
that I just stepped in.
Only when my main page handle
is not equal to this handle
that I just Septem.
Okay.
Yeah, that's fine.
I mean, you can you can exclude this
get titles outside of the F condition,
but the main point is to manipulate
with the with the windows themselves.
Right to switching.
Okay.
You can exclude this. That's fine. This
f any questions.
See? Okay.
There's a matter of no such window
exception.
So please send us the code.
Okay, so I want to see the code
that you type in.
I think
you need to change something in there.
All right, guys, if there is no questions.
So what I want to do now,
since I closed all the
all the other child
tabs, what I want to do,
I want to click on this button again
and open up a new tab or window.
Okay.
So it's going to put it in here.
If I run this right now,
is this going to work or no?
Okay, cool.
Let's run
this and see if this is going to work.
Okay.
So I see there's a lot of yes's.
Okay, cool.
So let me run this.
A opening.
Three different windows.
Okay, Closing this.
So now let's
go ahead and take a look in here.
What happened, guys?
No such window exception.
Target window or be closed.
What happened in here, guys?
Why you didn't click on this button?
Yeah, it's not closed. Right?
So I kept my main page open
and what I need it to do,
I want it to click on Instagram button.
We handle it.
Sure, if that's a good question.
So why do we need to switch first,
then click?
Because the focus is not on our main page.
Absolutely right, guys.
So if you go in here so,
I closed three different windows, right?
So when I closed the last one where it was
my focus guys before,
when I closed my last tab,
my focus was on the last window.
So I closed it right?
I closed it.
So now my selenium
is looking for where to go, right?
So I need to tell the selenium.
Okay, so with closed doors.
Good. That's very good.
So now what you need to do,
you need to switch back
your focus to the
main page that is still open.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys, As we said before,
guys, how we opened these three
without switching
Because even though we see
those three trial
tabs on Windows,
we are still able to click on this
because our focus
is still on the main page. Okay
You know, there's no to make a default,
but you have to switch back to the main
right.
So switch to the window.
Where do we have our main page
window, guys?
We have our main page window right on line
19, so grab that
pasted in here.
So we switch back to the main page
and only
then we click on Instagram button again.
Okay, Is that clear, guys?
Any questions?
So let's run
this and see visually what is going on.
The opening three, right?
So we need to close all of them now.
Okay, closed.
And now switch back to the main
and clicked on Instagram
button.
Click all three buttons.
Yes. So okay guys.
So the focus stays on the main page
when, when I just opened it, right,
I open my main page,
I click on three different buttons.
So while I'm clicking on these
three buttons, am I switching anywhere?
No. Right.
So that's why
my focus stays on the main page.
But whenever I am inside the
why loop, right I am.
I keep switching the windows
and closing them.
So the last window when I closed
before I closed, I change my
I changed my focus to the last window.
Right. And then close it.
So when I close that window
now we don't have anything to focus on.
And then
we need to switch to the main manually
and to click that button again.
Okay, I hope this is clear, guys.
Let me actually
put you some notes in here.
So that's going to be
easier to start
iterating
through handles.
They get the next
handle
on there and we need to set
a condition, set
condition in here.
Then the next one,
switch,
switch to a window
that's
equal to
main page.
Then, Okay.
And then
two and
then.
All right.
Any questions, guys?
Oh, clear.
A little bit confusing at first, guys,
but by the time and practice,
we should be able to
get comfortable in that.
Okay.
And I'll give you a homework, guys,
so that you guys can play around with
with different windows.
All right.
The windows are closed
nowhere.
There's no there's no focus at that time.
If all the windows are if the windows
are closed and there's one remaining.
So when you had your focus on the last one
and you close that window
so you don't have a focus at all, okay.
So you have to switch to the
to the main page or to the page
that is open right now.
Can I give you some more homework?
I'll see you guys. Okay.
I have two tasks for you for the homework,
but I'll see if I can come up
with anything else.
All right?
Okay, guys.
So clear with the
what's called clear with a window.
So now what's going to happen is
we will be going over the weights.
Okay,
So we'll start going over the weights
in selenium right now,
and then we'll continue tomorrow.
Okay.
Now, with closing the last window,
the focus will not be anywhere.
Okay.
So you don't have focus on any page
because your page is closed
and you need
to get back to the page
that is open right now.
Okay.
All right.
So let me
get back to the notes.
Okay, guys. So now
so before guys,
before, if we had to pause something,
if we had to add some time to
to wait for a little bit.
Guys, what did we have to use you guys
that.
That's right. Okay.
So in Selenium, we have different
different kinds weights in here.
Okay?
So thread that sleep is going to do
what is going to pause
your execution for a couple of seconds.
However, you mentioned the seconds, right?
So 2 seconds, five, ten,
whatever you want to do.
Okay. Now
what are we actually guys
stopping in here?
So what are we trying to do?
So we tried to exit.
I mean, we're trying
to pause our execution, but for what?
What are we trying to do in here, guys?
So if we don't do it,
what's going to happen?
So our code is going to fail.
So what is actually happening in here,
guys?
So windows take some time to load.
Okay, So our is really fast
and the page might not
be loading too fast.
Right?
So what are we trying to do in here, guys?
We're trying to bring
the our page or the code
to the same level of speed.
Right.
So basically what we're doing in here,
we're
synchronizing our code, our execution
and whatever we have on the Web page,
okay?
Because usually if we run our code
without any weights, it's really fast.
It's not going to wait for anything.
It will just run.
And if it
if it doesn't find any elements,
what it's going to do, it's going to fail.
Right.
So in this case, what we need to do,
we need to synchronize, right.
Synchronize our code, our execution
and the load page, page loading or element
loading, whatever it is.
So. All right. Any questions? Got
it right.
Synchronization right.
So it is
here.
The synchronization right is the process
of bringing
this feed of two or more
components right to the same level.
Okay.
In this case, we're bringing
we'll bring in our script
and page load to the same speed.
Right.
So in this case,
we are
we're
bringing
scripts and
page load to the same
speed level.
Okay. All right.
So basically what we're doing,
we're synchronizing, right?
So thread that's sleep, right?
And we talked about this.
What is
what kind of weight is this, guys?
Anybody know?
Does anyone have any idea
what kind of weight is this
So we set manually.
Okay.
Anything else, guys
with a computer speed?
No, I don't think so.
I mean, if it's computer speed, then
we when you
start your execution,
when you executing starts,
it has nothing to do with the computer
speed
or time.
Wait, time, temporary. Okay.
So almost.
It's a static weight, right?
So whenever you
anything, it's a static weight.
You don't change it.
It's it will wait for the amount of
for the amount of seconds
that you specify.
Right.
So it's not going to change
according to the to the web elements
or according to the web page load. Right.
So what it is, is it's a static way
that you give the amount
of the weight in there.
Okay, So static weight
or we also say
it is unconditional weight, right?
Because here we don't have any conditions.
You are just causing your execution
for the
for some amount of time and that's it.
Right.
As the easiest job.
Yeah.
Yeah. I mean, sleeps all the time.
There you go.
Okay.
So now
any other types of selenium weights?
We know guys.
So there's two types of
so in here.
Explicit weight.
Okay, What else?
Implicit weight and what else, guys?
Implicit, explicit and slow and weights.
Okay, So three different types of weights.
We have in selenium.
Okay.
Implicit weight, explicit weight and
slight weight.
Okay.
So today we will only be going over
implicit weights and tomorrow
we'll finish it up.
Well, explicit and slow int weights.
Okay.
All right.
So what is implicit weight? Does
anyone did research on this?
We don't define.
Okay, what else, guys?
Oh, we will be defining
the implicit weight.
We will be defining it.
What is the implicit weight
by default?
Okay.
A way for a certain amount of time.
So implicit weight, guys,
is a global weight insulin.
So what it does it tells the web driver
to wait for a certain amount of time
before throwing an exception.
Okay.
So we're going to be inviting the implicit
weight only once in our script
and it will be applied
for the whole session
of the execution.
Is that clear, guys?
And I'll show you how to implement that.
But let's go through the theoretical part
first,
okay?
Isn't it based on the page size loading?
Not not this one.
No default for defined.
So it is a define.
So there's no
I mean there is no default weight.
So it's not going to there's no weight
that it's going to be applied
to automatically
you have to define all the weights okay.
If you want any weight to be implemented
in your execution,
then you have to define it in your script.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys?
Oh, the time, the time, the default type.
We'll be setting it ourselves.
The default time is zero, guys.
Okay.
Okay, so let's put in here.
It tells me
Web driver
to wait for a
certain amount of time
before
following an exception.
And then
it will only be
written once and
will be applied to the or
session end of the
execution.
Okay.
And we set that within,
say said the implicit weight
is a global weight.
What's the definition of the exception?
It's an error, right?
So no such element exceptions, right?
No such window exceptions
that we just got.
So that's that's the error right.
Okay.
All right guys.
So whenever we implement
the implicit weight, okay,
whenever we implement implicit weight,
what happens is so implicit weight is
usually set to 20 seconds.
Okay?
So implicit weight is it
works with the fine element.
Find element method. Okay.
And find element method.
We already know that it will go ahead
and identify that element.
Okay.
So what happens in there if your element,
if you're trying to find an element
and if your element is found
in 20
and 20 seconds that you have mention,
but the rest of the time will be ignored
and your script will be continued.
Okay, so let's
say you set your implicit
weight for 20 seconds
and you try to locate the element, okay?
And use selenium found the element
in 5 seconds, so the rest 15 seconds
will be ignored and your code will
go ahead to the next line.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys?
But if your element
is not found in the given time,
we we gave it, let's say,
20 seconds, right?
Only then you will get an exception.
Okay. Is that fair?
So basically,
whenever you try to find any a what's
called an element, you set your implicit
weight for 20 seconds.
If you find if you finds that
that element
in 5 seconds, the rest 15 will be ignored.
Or if it if the selenium doesn't find
that element in 20 seconds
then you will get an exception.
Okay, that's a good question.
It will not work with find elements.
It will not work
with the list of elements.
Okay.
It will only work with single element.
Okay, sure.
Okay, cool.
So let's put it here.
So implicit weight is usually set
to seconds.
Okay.
And if four elements
is found in
any time
between the
between the rest of the time.
All right.
Or let's put it between the remaining
time.
All right.
It said time will be
ignored and you're
script
will move on
to the next line for action.
Okay.
And if the element
is not found
in a given
time, only then
you'll get an exception
can you adjust the implicit weight.
You can adjust the waiting time
on the implicit weight.
Yes, you can put more.
If you want to wait for 30 seconds,
you can
if you want to wait for 10 seconds,
that's fine.
But usually, guys, usually
the implicit weight
is always set to 20 seconds.
Okay.
All right.
Any other questions before we go ahead
and start the implementation,
guys,
Question
Okay.
What I do want to adjusted.
Okay, So let's say it's
set for 20 seconds, right?
But you saying that
so let's say your element is not found
for 20 seconds, right?
So what's going to happen
is going to throw you an exception.
So that means that
you waited for 20 seconds.
Right.
But sometimes you say that, okay,
I want this execution to be
to end really fast.
So now what I want to do, if it doesn't
if it's not found,
if the element is not found, I just want
to wait for 10 seconds and sets enough.
Okay Okay.
So if you set this to 10 seconds
and your element is not found,
your execution will fail faster.
Okay.
But if it's not found in ten elements
in 10 seconds,
then you will get an exception.
But if it's found inside that 10 seconds,
then your script will move on.
Okay.
So this, as I said, the implicit weight
that the time is not really adjusted
frequency.
Okay.
So as I set, it sets usually to 20 seconds
and it applies for the whole session.
Okay.
So it's not really
you will be playing around
with the implicit weights timing
and all that stuff.
It's not like that.
You will set the implicit way
once before the execution.
Okay.
And all the and after that your
implicit way will be set to the amount
that you gave it to.
And it will be waiting for those elements
whenever you try to find them
for the given time that you set.
Okay.
All right.
Let me create a class in here
and simply demo
for now.
It is optional.
For now it is optional,
but when you land them
on a job and you work on the projects,
it is mandatory.
Okay?
Because this is going to be applied
only once
and it's going to be only written
once in framework.
Okay, So here since we having different
different execution points
that we have to write it all over again.
Right.
But when you try to work on the framework,
you'll only have to write it once.
Okay.
Just once. Yes, just one in the framework
you can type as well.
Guys, this one is not
that is not that difficult.
Okay.
So let's see.
See where
this goes? This
All right.
I guess so.
What I want to do, I want to make sure
I know.
Okay, So what I want to do, guys,
I just want to navigate
to this Web page and here.
Okay.
And this might load some
some elements
a little bit later than expected.
Okay.
So what we're going to do,
we're going to set an implicit weight
and we will try to click on
this, start the same element.
Okay So so once you navigate to the URA,
okay, guys, once you opened up a page and
you try to perform some actions, okay,
so before you perform any actions,
what you want to do,
you want to set your implicit width.
Okay, So how you want to do it,
it's pretty easy.
So driver dot manage.
Okay, so you need to manage
so if, if you run out of time,
what's going to happen guys?
If you let's say if your element
is not found in 20 seconds,
what's going to happen.
Exception. Right.
In other words,
it will be a timeout, right?
So what we what we're doing here, we're
managing timeouts.
Okay.
So with managing timeouts
by implicitly wait
by implicitly
waiting for some time in here.
Okay.
So for managing the timeout
by the implicitly wait in here
and what we need to do inside
parentheses, we need to,
we need to set the time
which we will be waiting for.
And as I said in here,
we waiting for 20 seconds, right?
This is the usual time.
So if we put in here 20, that means.
And the second argument
that we need to pass is the time unit.
Okay, so
our time units in here
is going to be seconds,
or if you want to wait four days,
you can do this in here.
If you want to wait 4 hours,
you can do this as well.
Okay, So timeout seconds in here.
I'm in time units. Sorry.
So this is the
the script
how you set your implicit weight.
Okay.
So pretty easy using web driver.
You're managing the timeouts, you're
managing the timeouts of the implicit
weights.
Right.
And you just set here 20 seconds.
That's it.
All right.
Any questions, guys?
Yes, it will.
It will wait until it's found.
Yes, if it's found,
if it's found in 5 seconds,
the rest of the time will be ignored.
Guys, remember that
you want
to wait four days and you get paid hourly.
Good.
But then you're
not going to get the job done.
So that means you're not going to get paid
after that.
We're better than 30 sleep. Yes.
So from now on, guys try to use
weights
instead of thread that sleep.
Isn't it better to put more time
if the computer system is not fast enough?
As I said before, your computer system
system has nothing to do with this.
Right?
Because when when your execution starts
right, it will not wait for anything.
It's just going to run and open up a page.
Right.
So you might want to check the Internet
speed guys.
If it's too slow, then you might want
to increase the time in here.
Okay.
Or if the server is down
or the server is too
slow guys, only
then you may need to increase this time.
But if if the element is not sound in 20
seconds guys,
there is a problem with the performance
of your server or writing.
Okay. Yes.
I can explain why that that sleep
is not the best way.
So in thread dot sleep guys.
So let's say
we try to wait for an element, right?
We're trying to wait
for an element for 2 seconds.
What if that element of
pops up in 5 seconds?
Guess what's going to happen?
It won't ignore.
It's going to fail, right?
So you have to talk to 2 seconds of wait
time, okay?
2 seconds of wait time.
So if it appears in 3 seconds,
that means you already failed.
It won't work. Right.
What's here in the implicit wait, guys?
What happens is, even though you mentioned
20 seconds, okay,
if it finds the element in 5 seconds,
it will ignore the rest.
15 seconds.
Okay,
so your code is moving on after 5 seconds
after it found that element.
And you might ask what happens
if the element takes more than 20 seconds
to appear?
That means that your server has some
some issues.
It's a performance issue off the server.
Okay, great.
Every time.
No. So
there's
no downsides of using the implicit weight
because you will only be mentioning it
once.
Okay, so you just mentioned it once.
That's it.
The only the only downside
I would think of is
when it's it only applies to find element.
Okay.
Even though your element is found.
But it's not if it's if it's disabled
and you want to click on it,
it will not throw that error
because your element is found
and you want to click on it
and it's disabled.
It's not going to look for the disabled
elements.
Okay, wait.
Time will apply,
correct? Yes.
All the actions, all the find element
dies, all the find element actions.
Okay.
So if I do, let me go back.
Where was that?
Okay.
If I find these three elements.
Okay, let me copy this.
Let's say these are the elements.
Okay, So
if it's trying to find the first element.
It will start checking to 20 seconds.
Okay.
Once it's found that element in 2 seconds,
the rest will be ignored.
Now, it will try to look into this
element.
Okay, 20 seconds start ticking in there.
And then after that, if if it
if it this is found in 5 seconds,
the rest 16 will be ignored
and the selenium
will try to find this element.
And if it doesn't find that element
in 20 seconds
only, then it will throw an exception.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys?
Any other questions?
Okay, good.
All right, so
let me get this.
So let's go back in here.
So we navigate here.
So what I want to do,
I want to click on this, start practicing.
Okay, So let's
see what
this one.
Okay, It has an ID here. Okay.
So I'm going to use the ID, I'm going to
find this element by its ID
and then I'll try to click it.
Okay.
So web element
practicing
is the driver.
That element ID
and is this ID?
And here.
So practicing button that
click.
Okay. All right.
Yes I'll push I'll click the code state.
Okay.
So give me some time.
Let me explain this one and I'll go,
Oh, yeah, they spelled it wrong.
Okay, good. Catch the catch. There you go.
You have a defect.
Okay.
Can you write this anywhere
or it should be in the top class.
Okay, so if you write it.
So let me cut this.
And if you write it in here,
what's going to happen, guys?
Will this be applied to this web
element?
No. Right.
Because our code is going from
top to the bottom left to the right.
Right.
So you have to mention this
at the very top after you
navigate to the edge
so that this implicit weight
gets applied to whole session.
Okay.
All right.
So now
let's go ahead and run this
and see what's going to happen.
Okay?
I think it already did.
Yeah, it clicked. Right?
So seems like it.
It just popped up.
So see you
guys. It's not waiting anything.
It's just clicking right away
whenever it finds that element.
So now what
I am going to do, I'm going to put a
it wrong ID even here,
so I'm going to do this.
Okay, so this is a wrong ID,
This doesn't even exist
in the HTML, right?
So what I can do here, I'm
going to run this.
So now let's see
when we're going to get that
exception.
Okay.
Landed on the page.
Okay, We're still here.
So you guys,
we don't have an exception yet.
Okay, So we still here.
It's still looking for that element.
Okay?
It's still giving it a chance.
There we go.
Okay, so
now, guys, only after the 20 seconds,
you can see that there's no such element
exception.
Okay, So we set it to 20 seconds.
So it's waiting for that element
to find right to appear
or to be to be present in that web page,
but it's not present.
So then it will wait for 20 seconds
and we will throw our exception.
Okay.
Any questions, guys?
Any questions on Windows?
Any questions on Waits guys?
Yeah, this one is easy.
Implicit word is easy.
Well, the weights in selenium are easy
because they're all straightforward.
Okay?
I mean, selenium is easy anyways,
because there is a lot of stuff
that is just simple English.
Yeah. Yeah.
There's a lot of information
that is correct.
Yes, we know. Handles.
You need to practice.
Okay.
Okay. So
let's let's push the code, guys,
before we that before we do that,
let's go through the homework guys.
This here.
Okay.
All right, Guess so.
Let me explain. You
this one.
So let's go back.
Okay.
So here's what I need you to do.
Guys.
I need you to click on these
on these buttons, okay?
Okay.
So let's see, we on new tab and then print
the text from the tab in the console.
Okay. So let's click on this.
There you go.
So you have this text,
you need to print that out.
You click on this one, you need to
print that out and you click on this one.
You print that out as well.
Okay?
So where verify the
title is displayed.
Okay?
And then print out the titles
of all the pages.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys,
for this task?
Okay. And then the second one
here.
Okay, what I want you to do guys in here,
I want you to click on this link.
Okay?
When you click on this Link,
it's going to wait for a little bit
and then
it's going to display this text.
Okay.
So get this text
and then print it out in the console.
Okay? Yes.
This is the homework. Yes. Okay.
Any questions on this, guys?
Okay, one second.
Let me check your.
Okay, guys.
Seems like I don't have anything else,
so I'm giving you 20 minutes
back of your time.
But I want to say one thing, that tomorrow
is going to be intense, guys.
Okay?
Tomorrow
we will going over the explicit weights.
Tomorrow we will be going over the
flow and weights
and we will be working with tables.
Okay, guys, Tomorrow
is going to be a lot of information.
Okay?
Yep. Go hard.
Go home. That is right.
Okay.
So tomorrow
we will have a little bit of intense class
because going to be a lot of different
information.
Okay.
Rough day tomorrow, guys.
Okay, so get ready.
I'm giving you 20 minutes of time
back today, but I'll take that tomorrow.
Okay?
All right, guys.
So please complete the homework.
Okay, guys.
And please
practice and I will see you tomorrow.
Okay.
Thanks, Everybody.
Stay safe and have a great night. Bye.