All right.
So yesterday
we have gone through a couple of concepts.
Today, we will do a quick recap
of all those concepts.
Right.
And as we can see, a lot of students
had some problems
understanding their data provider concept.
So we will go through this data provider
concept once again.
I gave you one task yesterday.
We will start with that task.
We will complete that
task for data provided.
And then we do it again.
And then we will start our new topic
for today.
Okay.
Yeah. And right.
So that homework
we are going to go through now.
So liquid
take this homework
first from the announcing
and let me create
another package here.
This was their task maintenance.
What was the question basically is
we have to add one employee or
we have to add five employees in our h.r.
And this application. Right.
So now let's explore this functionality
first in the application manually,
and then we'll decide which approach
we need to go with.
Right.
And which approach would be the best to
implement the solution for this question.
Okay.
So it is always the best idea
to explore the application manually.
So what I'm going to do is to add
we have to log in with which
credential states to add a new employee.
Can I add new employee
with any credential logging?
No. Right.
We have to log in via admin.
So let me write admin.
Now, to add an employee,
what we have to do is
we have to go in the PIM option
add employee.
Correct.
Here.
Here are the parameters
which I need to pass is false to me.
Middle name,
last name, place and my native thing.
So firstname, lastname.
So things like.
And after this,
click here
username
password and confirm password.
How many states employ ID is something
which is given by default.
If we need to add manually
or automation, we have to clear it first
and then we have to add.
But for now we will going to pass
the false name last name
username, password and confirm password.
Correct.
How many police guys
I have to fill here to add one employee
five things.
Right?
And then I have to click on save option.
That's one.
There's some. Correct.
So let's do it one by one. First
I have to log in.
I have to click on this name option.
After this name option,
I have to click on an employee
and inside an employee I have to ID
all of these be their data
related to this group.
So let's create this class first.
Now, when I have to add this access,
add five different employees and create
login credentials
by activating first name,
last name, username and password.
So five different employee values.
Yesterday we discussed one concept
How can we send
five different types of data in this task?
Which concept we have to use
data provider.
Correct.
So we are going to use this data provider
concept here
for data driven testing, obviously.
So let's start writing this test.
Guess what I'm going to write. It is
that driver
driver being late
after closed browser,
there is one more step.
All right.
What is that?
Can you please tell me
for sure
specify a group?
All right. So let's see.
This is this is the part of your smoke
testing, for example.
Right.
So we will going to execute it
from on best candidate
exam and fight.
Now, one by one,
we will do all these things
to implement a data provider
concept, Right?
Again, I'm
repeating their data for later concepts.
Right.
So this time, guys,
if you don't understand,
interrupt me, stop me
and ask the question.
Please don't take white.
Please ask the question
if you don't understand.
Now, for five employees dates,
first thing for five employees,
what is the status?
What would be the size
of my data provider, which I need to
provide given?
Okay.
Then either because they are discussing
about data provider concept, right?
So we are not extending anything
as of now.
Yes. Started this
what I did in the data provider class.
Right.
I removed this.
Your part of data provider.
I removed your part of the condition,
enforced condition
and I extended common methods there.
Then someone posted that
we are not using this data provider
like this and complained.
So that's why right now
I am going forward, Right?
I'm going forward with this concept.
Okay.
And then after this,
I will tell you how we can improve
by using audio for your audience package.
Now, let's remember,
question is here,
if you go in the application,
this strict rules are mandatory, right?
So now see in this mandatory fields,
how many fields I have first name,
last name,
user name, password and confirm password.
How many things guys
I write and for
how many employees I have to define my
I have to define my any.
Now, what would be the length of my data
provider
fireplace.
Correct
plan how it would be five
four on what parameters you are staying
five four send me
this would be this should be five five.
Okay.
So let's implementation
now see guys I'm going to write here eight
data provided by because this is mine.
Yeah, exactly.
But these are the two different
fields, right?
So we have to parse this data
from two different things
because meetings are different.
At one time you will pass via one string,
which is string.
The string is password.
At one time
you are passing by than phone password.
All right.
Now let's consider this. Consider this.
If you have two different methods
where you are calling this situation.
Okay? Yes.
So here, how are you verifying
you're in which in which line you're
passing password and individual line
you're passing confirm password.
If you have two different methods,
what do you have to do?
Basically
in one method
where you are just entering the password,
When you have to send the string password
in another
method, you have to pass a string, confirm
password.
Right.
Even though the data is same,
but the fees are different, right?
So you should convey the different feeds
by different strings.
This is this.
These are the standards
of coding, correct?
Currently we have,
I think, everything in a single method,
everything we have.
I think enough single method.
So you are passing
five strings inside one field, Correct.
But but if you're passing.
Yeah, that's
what I'm trying to expand right now.
We are writing just one method,
so we are passing five.
Method five is printing a single method.
Now if you have five different methods,
like for example, first is into
the username, second is enter password
thirties, enter, confirm password.
Now in this particular function
video passing enter
confirm password
and you're passing a string password.
Right?
Is this correct with your passing
the famous enter
password
method is enter confirm password method.
These are against the standards.
Write in instead of username method.
You're passing the string username
into the password method of passing.
Enter password makes sense.
Enter confirm password method Your passing
Enter password or a string password.
Is it correct
that data
you are placing it
one place right beside the string?
The key
you are showing right your showing.
So if you are showing password
for confirm password
and confirm password for password.
So why does it make sense?
No, it doesn't make sense. Right.
That's why even though the data
is same in password and confirm password,
we have to take two keys here in the data
operator part.
It should be self explanatory.
You don't need to put efforts here.
All right, let me make it now.
The data provider part first.
So now tell me, guys, which parent class
we called yesterday.
Yeah. And it should be self
extended to make, right?
If you're passing one parameter,
then some password,
then the reader of your code
will understand that you're passing.
Confirm password. Be right.
But if the reader of your code
is your client or customer,
and if you show this code to your customer
and it says already there are two
methods, enter a password, be Vincent,
enter, confirm password details.
But in both this method
you're passing the data from same thing.
The string password.
The string password in both the methods.
How it works. Right?
How can you pass like this? Right.
There will be a question.
I'm not saying the data is different.
Data is same.
I know that.
Even I know.
But still we have to pass through
different parameters in two
different methods.
Then we will work on the framework, right?
That you will understand.
Therefore, each and every functionality
we write different methods
and there we parse differences
and different parameters
according to the method.
According to the function,
we pass different parameters.
All right, so we parsed the index object.
This is my pattern.
Static.
So I'm going to write this time.
My data provider name is and
employee data.
Is this correct?
Now, the next thing is I'm going
to define my
utility. Right?
We have already discussed
Andre, if you want to use one parameter
you can use,
but then if you work in the framework,
it will be a problem for you.
If you work in the same industry,
they will not accept your same parameter
for multiple figs.
All right.
There is a meeting in the company.
Remember guys,
our technical architecture review meeting
in this meeting
and technical architecture review meeting,
if you pass this kind of parameters,
if you write your code again and again,
if there is a mismanagement in your code
writing, one
architect observes your entire framework
every quarter
after the completion of every quarter,
you have to go through this process.
Technical architecture review meeting.
There you will get this table points
that, Hey, you are passing in
the password string while you're passing.
This is not the machine, right?
Your key should be self-explanatory.
And if you think as a professional
that there are high chances
or there is a room for possible typo,
then why are you writing the code?
Right?
Technical architect will give you reviews
like this.
Getting my point
according to the standards.
According to the process, I'm
explaining the things
already, guys.
So now remember in yesterday's class
I told you back in data provider
we used to the editor correct
the students who they are
not getting to the error
we are using in our data provider.
So now I am going to define
this object as mine.
The data
new object.
Now what is the size of my error?
Because I have five employees
in five fields, so it would be five
five, correct.
Now when I say five five,
what does it mean?
Five rules and five columns.
Five rules and five columns. Right.
So who fill the data to fill the data?
Do we need to maintain the order or not?
Yes, we need to maintain the order.
Right, in order to add the employee.
So let me do it.
I'm going to write four data
in my
very first rule and in first column.
Right.
What is the first data?
I'm going to put based on
my first name,
not username, write
my first name.
So let's see, I'm
going to take the name as
this one.
Correct.
And then
I'm going to write for my
first rule, second column, Right.
My first rule, second column.
I'm going to write the data
as a last name.
So last name.
The exam writing is simple.
Last name one eighth.
I'm trying to just make this data simple.
So instead of this,
I'm going to write first name
one and last name one. Also
now in the same place.
Let me just copy this from here.
What is the third thing is user name. All
right.
So I'm going to write user
and then password, right?
So I'm going to write user, name one
and this would be my
password.
We will write for everyone the same.
And then again, think
why you don't use the B?
Because, Andre, this is the simplest way
to explain to all the students, right?
First, when every study right now
your colleagues are having a problem
understanding this structure.
So I am trying to explain them
the simplest one first
and then we will talk about the advanced
version.
Okay.
Now, this is for just one employee
that we have edited the data.
Correct.
But how many employees we have to edit
for five employees.
So here I'm going to write as
one. Now this would be my
first name taking
not names like end user name,
taking password
and confirm
password is always seem correct
now for my third employee
already is.
First tell me why I started from zero
and it starts from zero.
Right? Index always starts from zero.
So this is my index, right?
This is my index.
Index means
first position zero means first position.
First means second position.
Right.
Someone adds this question.
That's why I reminded that part.
So this is my index.
This is not my position.
Index defines my position. Zero indexing.
It means first position
right on the right and the correct.
We are going on to the advanced part
there.
I will explain all of this.
Things don't worry about it. Right.
Like I said, after the fourth month,
if you'll see right,
these are the things then
obviously you are going to.
But still, my priority is to keep
everyone on the same page.
At least the stations priority is this.
So please try to understand
that this is the way.
First, I have to explain this to everyone.
When everyone is on the same page, then
we will talk about the advanced portion.
All right, fine.
So far for the fourth employee, that is
the strategy.
Angel.
Guys, tell me,
how many of you guys are okay
with this structure
or do you want me to go
with the advanced, the structure,
what Andre is talking about?
Are you guys comfortable
with this position right now?
What we are doing here?
All right, fine.
So now let's do it.
This one and in the framework
will follow their demands.
Okay.
All right.
Now, let's talk about the last one here.
So now
it says here for the fourth employee,
fifth employee
in the end dies In the end.
What I'm expecting from this proper
method from this data provider,
what I'm expecting in the
we have to take
their data into the fight.
So this is my data provider
ready with me for this employee data.
Correct.
Now now this is the time.
This is the time when we are going to use
our data provider in our actual method.
All right.
In that actual method,
we are going to use it.
So let's write the function
first.
We will write both precondition and post
condition inside this particular part.
And after this we will extend the property
from common methods.
All right.
Since couple of you guys
didn't understand the concept, right?
How we have used the data provider,
I'm going to use.
Yes, we can use the same data provider
for even all the methods, as long as all
the parameters are available
in those functions.
We can use that.
All right.
So guys, can we copy this?
Your precondition and post condition
from any other class?
Can we do that here
in this precondition, post condition,
applicable
or not?
Alright,
so let's take any precondition from
from here.
Right? This is not a precondition.
So I'm taking it from soft assertion to
you can take this precondition
from any class you want.
And here I am writing my precondition
right
after this
I am taking my post condition as well.
So I'm going to take my
post condition
in between this
I have to write my actual function.
So what are
what are the task I have to achieve first?
Chrome browser open.
It's added this application log in.
So navigation today you are at this point
we have already in our precondition
right here the main thing
what we have to do is add five different
employees and create log
in credentials by providing this data
correct.
So this is the functionality
we have to implement in our framework now.
So I'm going to write it.
Yes, we write this part
public, right?
It would be see
add employee method
first.
Now when I'm passing the data
from my data provider class,
then I'm passing the data
from my data provider class.
What is the first thing I have to do?
Send me this.
If I want to use my data provider
in my actual test here, right?
So to use my data provider in this
particular test, what I have to do,
do I need to add something here?
We have to write here
data provider,
right in the name of data provider.
So what is the name of my data provider?
It is an employee data, correct.
And then the next thing,
the next thing it says your test right
is specify group
for this particular test gets.
So to add employee right to an employee,
you are testing something
very first time in the application.
You are trying to add some employee
in your application.
Which category would it be?
Okay if you're trying to test
some functionality in your application?
First time, which category would it be?
Which kind of test you're performing?
Is it smoke? Is it regulation?
What kind of test it is it?
All right. Let me ask another question.
Adding the employee in the application,
Adding
the employee in the application,
is it a key functionality,
critical functionality,
important functionality or not?
It is important functionality.
For example,
you're working in the organization, right?
And some employee came, one
employee came and joined the company.
Right?
But if your software is not working
and you're not able to add
that particular employee,
how would you generate the employee ID?
How would you give them all the documents?
IT right.
So it is a showstopper.
It is a blocker
in your application, correct?
If it is a block it in your application,
you always have to make sure
that your key functionality of application
is always working.
And when you perform this type of this,
you call it smoke based,
where you just make sure that the key
functionalities of your application
is working fine even though you're
testing it first, correct.
So it should be a part of your smoke
testing.
Also, it can be a part of regression
testing as well, right?
So you can pass both smoke integration
in the same group.
It's not an issue at all, but right now
I'm passing only for smoke one
or if you want to pass it
in regression one,
you can pass this test for regression
one as well.
Right now let's take it for smoke one.
Now we will try to implement.
So to add the employee, to add the employer, what is the first thing we have to do?
We have to log in by adding credentials.
Correct.
All right.
So let's take the data for admin
credentials.
I'm taking this data again
from my self position.
You can take it from anywhere, right?
We have so many classes that we have
this data already available.
I have passed this data here. Now,
if I want to use my data provider,
if I want to use my data provider in my
this particular method,
what is the best way to use
all the data
which is coming from the data provider?
In my method, what I have to do here and
in terms of what
we have to parse
the parameter static, right?
We have to parse the parameter.
So is either meters does see it
passing the parameter.
All right.
So according to the order,
according to the order,
what would be the first thing
I have to pass in terms of parameter here
it is your first name.
Correct.
And the format of your first name
is a string.
That's why passing it string.
All right,
then that's taken.
Would be your
last name.
And then the third one would be your
user name.
Correct.
And then the fourth one would be your
password,
and fifth one will be your
ten form password.
These are the five strings.
Right?
Handle my data, which is coming from here
from this five six
for every single employee, the data
which is coming from these five fields.
My application,
my method will handle this data
by add these parameters,
and then I will use this parameters
in my method
to use my data for weight of class.
All right,
So now let's implement the functionality
again.
Someone sent the code for this same
employee up in button
and the employee option if you guys have.
Otherwise we will verify this code.
What do you think?
Should we go ahead and verify
this for this?
Open it.
So first thing is
first thing here, after this code,
we don't have to enable
or disable anything, right?
We don't have to select anything
from here.
The status because we are simply opening
the five things
and clicking one save button.
So user password, user name,
checkbox state.
I hope this one is for checkbox.
Correct
me this despite my
so the idea is correct.
Right?
We are using my check log in.
We are clicking on this point.
Now let's check whether we are passing
the correct spring or not.
This is my confirmed password,
which I have to pass
in my data here.
Point.
Now, I'm not writing.
I'm not providing any value in terms
of keys such as web element, user name.
I'm simply clicking, identifying
and then I'm simply clicking on the member
guys button task is available
here, which you have seen.
It says
Verify it employ
has been added successfully
and take the screenshot
right?
It says verify employee has been added
successfully and take the screenshot.
How would you verify?
Take a screenshot is something
we will learn in our framework.
Fine, but tell me how we can verify
that employee has been aged successfully.
How are you verifying this point?
Dates.
Any idea?
Right.
You're taking the created name? Fine.
So let's do it right.
Let's do it.
I'm just trying to pass some normal data.
Right?
Some raw data.
Yet my username would be say test 20101
password would be my each H&M 1 to 3
and then confirm password would be my.
Now when I click here on same option,
right when I click, you know
what happened?
Which questions?
Fine.
So now
if I go on prem and then an employee
after clicking here on an employee,
I will Right.
See test 0101
And my last name
would be state test last,
but it should be its first
the next year
my password
would be the 1 to 3
in confirm password.
Now if I click on this same option
employee, I exist
24 right.
Okay.
So let's take this post.
Write the verify the employee option.
Right. Did a step we see before that.
Let's try to add five data because I'm
not sure whether it will take the data.
Again, it can say the same thing
that employed exist because every time,
even if I refresh, I'm
getting the same employee idea
a year.
Also, it was the same here.
Also it is the same.
Let me try just one more time.
Otherwise we will execute our step first,
not first,
and then accessible 39 one C2
Fine.
So here on this page it is redirecting us
on this particular page.
Couple of things right?
This is the free
and your false name and last name.
You can verify
all because in the question online,
if you'll see here in the question.
Right,
it is a five different
employee's right why passing
false name, last name, username, password,
income, bump password
since this field is already selected.
That's why we are not enable
or making a disabled.
We are not entering any employer
ID right the employee.
It is also free which is already there
and we are not adding them with
the name is but right.
So things
which are given here in the question,
we are just trying to get those things
correct.
Now you will be on this personal details
page.
So multiple points
from which you can verify dates.
Tell me the first thing is you can take
this one, the test post and last test.
What is this?
Your first name
and your last name appears on this page.
First verification checkpoint.
Second thing first, no details.
Heading page, Right.
This is also validation checkpoint.
Now like on this year one,
he took this one
create a name, text
this one the first name and the last name.
Correct.
Fine.
So now we will take this one
because this code you guys already have,
this is one validation checkpoint.
We will take this one.
So you will be heading to validation
checkpoint.
Great for your page.
So let's take this one
anyways, what you can see for this one.
Let me inspect this element first.
If I go here and select
this particular one,
tell me guys, what is the best way
to find this locator?
Because I don't have class,
I don't have name, I don't have I.D.,
I don't have any anchor date for the link
fixed, right?
I don't have any value.
The only thing
which I can see here is what?
Yes, I have fixed.
Now, let me ask let me check your access
knowledge as well.
If I want to execute my script
and I want to use locator, why this?
It means system selector cannot verify
beyond
that because when you are clicking on
same button,
your application is redirecting
your personal details page right?
If your I.D.
already exists,
it will never read your navigator.
The first thing you can split
it is the only successful scenario
when you're coming on the personal,
you can switch. Right?
And another point is because the
first one, everyone has this code, right?
So that's why
I'm trying to give them another validation
check point.
Getting my point.
So now tell me
in my case, can I find this locator?
I see a select
right because the asset selector doesn't
allow us to find a locator via text.
Andrey Again, I'm repeating my point.
This is the code everyone has.
I'm trying to give them new code.
I'm trying to give them more validation
check point.
This is enough,
but it doesn't make sense. Right?
To copy the code and then if you want to
write this code, let me read this quote.
Then we are not going to verify
another locator.
That's fine.
I'm trying to explain something else.
Guys.
Do you want to write the previous code
or do you want to create a new code?
What do you want, guys?
Andrew You can use that code, right?
I will put that one as well.
I will put this one as well.
Both the verification and validation
check points I will keep.
All right.
Now, fine.
So let's see. See is this selector right?
This selector doesn't allow you
to find any locator via text menu.
So you have to go with only one option.
Which option is back, but correct.
You can find this locator X, but then how
we can rate the spot for this base,
double slash.
When I say double slash,
it is my absolute reality.
One customer is spot. Which one is this
big double
slash?
It is relative expatriate.
And then my big name right?
Can I use start
also a streak also instead of beginning.
Right.
And then since we are writing text
so we are not going to rate it right.
We are simply writing fixed parenthesis,
open and close and then my text value.
So my text menu is
correct.
Now it gives you two places,
personal details here,
personal details
here, right to place as it is here.
Also here. Also,
if I want to take this one right.
And if I want to take this one,
let's set this one the heading.
What if I want to take
so what I have to pass in this
case, as of now, the locator
which I'm having here,
will it work?
10 minutes
now. See, for
I'm going to pause the index.
I'm going to pause the index. Right.
So if I pass the index value here
next to the first,
then it will take only this one.
And if I want to take the second one,
then this one.
Right, this one.
Now. Now, let me tell you,
the previous concept was on that
he was talking about, Right.
This is the export
we have found for personal details.
If I go and take this one right,
this one you'll see from this ID profile
pick.
This is very simple to identify.
Can you see?
It is very simple.
If I am copying this part right,
I can take it.
What I see is a selector as well.
What is the short form of taking the ID
from a selector full stop or hash?
What is the short form
in C selected A protected
right, the
tag name hash and the value of this.
It means for this instance forward
your ID correct
in csv selector
now here because there was no scope
selector.
The main point of identifying
this locator was to tell you
that if you come across a situation
in your website
where you do not have a new tag
which can help you in identifying the
locator YRC as the selector all the way
spotless in name class or something.
In that case, you can pick your text.
Well, you
so that there is verification checkpoint.
Right?
Right now
we are verifying where the user ID or not.
We are not taking the data.
We have parsed again
the question required and
here we are not taking whatever the data.
We have paused in the same data,
reflecting give or not,
we are just checking
after adding the employee
we are on this page are not
we are able to add the employee
or not the point you're talking about,
I can totally understand.
Yeah.
That is your point of opinion, right?
I can't see anything in this. Right.
I completely agree with you.
No issues are gone.
So that is right.
I think in our discussion on this point.
And let's go ahead and go one thing.
What don't he had said
let's take that code.
This is the code his talking about.
Okay, fine.
After clicking on this button, I'm
going to put this assert quote right now
here.
This is false name is string. Right?
So I'm going to pass my false name
because my string is this
and last name is my last name.
It. The previous coordinates,
which you already have everyone.
Right. I'm also using the same code.
I'm not using the new one.
All right?
I just showed how we can identify multiple
verification and validation
check points from your screen.
Okay, now,
now the point is yet again, don't miss.
The point is, why are we using this code?
We are using this code to use our data
to right.
Again,
I'm repeating the main intention is to add
five employees
using our data provider concept.
So this is the data provided that we have.
Right?
So let's go ahead and execute this code.
We have three condition.
We have forced condition VI data provider
ready with us and we have our method.
We have passed the five user name, right?
Fine.
Let's execute this code base.
Then eventually I will show.
Don't worry, I will give you enough time
to write the code.
I will give you enough time
to explain as well and understand this.
Don't worry about it.
I'm just showing you right now
how this things work here.
All right.
So right now, remember,
I am executing this from my class itself.
I am not using it from test. And why?
Because after this normal execution,
I will show this from test.
And you take simple as that.
Okay.
From both the parts because still
the grouping part is left right.
We didn't implement
this group in our first part.
Remember this point?
No, it is working fine.
This button is already
there and the application
Now if
you guys this is your first name too.
Last name do.
It means more data for second employee,
right?
That's why I give this data like this
a user name exist.
That is the problem we are getting here.
The user name exist.
So where it is failing,
it is failing on your which part.
After clicking on
save on the right Nicholas.
Now this is for third iteration.
The data for the third employee.
It is going to edit.
Also my question is to Andy.
If my best guess is failing
and if it is same here.
Right? The user idea already exist.
Where is this person?
Physical speech.
Show me in the application.
No uses.
It will be displayed.
In any case, it is not coming here right
this is
a unique feature of the application.
When we explore the application manually,
we come across this functionality
that in general
I am going to implement this.
I'm going to implement
this on a database, right?
The database is the best way.
So what we will do this time,
then we provide the user name,
we will give the current date.
For example 10172021.
Right. Like this
I will give the user name.
This will be the unique one
for the fifth employee.
Right.
But the main point is the main
point is what we are able to add.
Five employees.
We are able to pause the data
for five employees from our data provider,
plus connect
Jan three.
I got your point. I go to your point.
That's what I am saying.
This is the second level of verification
and validation check point
that you are verifying that
whatever the post name and the last name
you have positive from your test, right?
Whether the same false name
and last name is visible on the screen
after adding the employee or not,
this is what you are verifying.
Am I right?
This is what you are doing
now. You
see, every single test is fake bit.
It is failing
because of this data is not available.
The verification check points.
If you see profile pic edge one
if you go here
created name is not available. Why?
Because it says your user ID
you can verify either of them.
Right. The one you need to verify.
You can take this one also.
There is no problem with this one.
Again, I am saying there is no problem
with this one.
The intention was to give you
one more validation check point.
Right.
One more validation check point.
Now let's skip right.
It gives this part in the code
and then they try to change their data.
This time it says user name already exist.
So which user name
we should put in this case?
Names so that it can work
like this, right.
So we can take one
right.
Or maybe bring it up on
or let's say
10172021 current date.
And here for this user name, 22
for the part 123
for fourth one, it should be 24.
And for 51 it should be 25.
Right. Five user names.
This must be unique.
Now, the next part,
which I'm going to do, is
this is a part of my smoke.
All right? This is the part of my smoke.
So I am going to execute this time
for my test due to take symbol part.
So let me go there.
I have defined groups.
Yes, there you go.
This is our groups available. Right.
And here
this test.
Do we really need this test?
As of now, the regression one,
do we need this part?
As of now, students use their
right.
So can we remove this part from our test
and or take someone?
We can remove it. Right.
So let me remove it. Now
I want to include only those to get this
to get
this belong to particular group
that is smoke.
All right, fine.
Then let me do one thing.
Let me first picture this one.
So I'm going to write this in
for the victim
and I'm going to clear
a new one
from my class
point.
So this is my class, right?
I want to execute this particular class
here. Yes.
So that's why I created the new one.
Okay. I created the new test.
And you take some of here
and now which group I want to execute.
So I'm going to take that group from here.
The group name, which is smoke. Right.
So let me take this group from
here and I'm going to write
this group name
so far
in this test
and do not symbol when I mention my
class right along with the package
and my group name Smoke,
which I took from here.
Do you guys have any question
so far?
Any question in this course then we
the one who was asking
about the save button.
So here you can see in line number 87
we are clicking on
save button as one.
Are you passing a You have to make sure
that you're passing like this.
This index should be like this
group is equal to in double course
you have to pass your group name,
for example, smoke
or regression in double quotes. Right.
And if you're passing it correctly
here like this with your request,
remember, I have seen sometimes
the students are passing it here.
In the method name
you don't have to pass it in the method
name, you have to pass it here.
And then when you pass it
to go into your test and you take symbol
and here
you have to write that one tag inside run,
include the name of your group.
So they should be the same
based groups run
and which group you want to run,
so you will provide the name smoke, right?
As include
the one your
you pass the name right in your method
instead of the request, correct?
Yeah, right.
I have seen so many things.
That's why it took so many students.
But that is common
when you try to practice,
when you try to learn something new,
you always make mistake.
It is fine.
But guys, tell me so far,
this data driven data provider concept,
is there anyone in the class right
who didn't understand
and will want me to go ahead once again
and explain this data provider?
Is there anyone
like I'm already in my exemplify like
this?
Yeah.
If I make I just observe.
So there is
shall we go ahead and execute this code
Now we have changed our data.
We have changed our data.
If you'll see in our
class right here, if you see
I have this username
so this time my username must be unique.
And then here also, right, we're passing
the data.
We're providing complete assertion
it's been now let's execute
a trauma test and do not submit.
Maybe you are passing the data
from that point.
Remember utils class.
That's
why you're extending some common methods.
Might be
again username exist.
This is weird.
We was the unique username
but again it exist
if someone has already executed
with this data.
I'm also thinking the same.
If you guys have executed
someone has executed right with the data
which we are using here,
please let us know so that we can use
the another data.
Yeah, someone must've executed it. See,
when we're adding the data here,
someone is already doing this.
But that's fine.
That's fine.
Now see, we are passing the data.
Yeah, I already did it. And that's
why I'm not putting this condition
in post condition from that class.
So therefore, the data provider
complete concept of data
provider will be available in this class.
All right.
That's why intentionally
I took this work in the class
so that everyone can get benefited
from this class.
And yesterday also when I did, I confirmed
with every student that already
you have this quote, everyone said yes.
Then only I did it.
Otherwise I would not have done that part.
But that's fine. I got it.
I learned that lesson yesterday
and I will not do that
once again.
Yes, Yes.
We have to use this code.
Correct.
I forgot about putting the data
provider in test barometers.
Okay.
Like I can understand that.
All right, so now,
because someone stole our data from here,
that's why our code are getting failed
because someone is already
using our user name.
Right.
But the point was the point was,
we are going to verify this.
Do you guys want me to once again change
this data and then execute it once again?
Do you guys want me to do this?
All right.
So now the most important question
in this part in this.
Yeah.
And a like I said, right, we will learn
the screenshot taking a screenshot method.
We've been done in the framework.
All right.
So that's why verification part
was included here
and this part is not included.
We will learn this in our coming lectures.
How we can take the screenshot
with list next.
Yes, I'm
I'm going to show you this code now.
98. You'll see here
I have started from here.
So now now tell me, guys, is there anyone
is there anyone from this school?
Right.
The code which I have written
inside of my class, my precondition,
my data provider,
my actual test in my post condition.
This is the code we have written today.
Is that anyone with me?
Is this something in this code?
If yes, then better
we should use Selenium did
not test integrate selenium grade and
Alia which code you want me to show
which part of this class
I need?
All right.
Now, when everyone is done with code
writing, is there anyone who still has
any confusion this data all the way to
how are we using it?
Why we are using to the editor,
How are we going to provide this data
the way the name in our method,
How are handling this in the parameters?
Any question,
any questions related to this?
When I'm committing this code and
the repository, I'm asking this question.
So you guys know
you're having the fresh Cortana.
Mike,
can you please send this your screenshot
so that I can see where you're getting
the mistake?
Actually, I should I we will.
We will learn that
I will show you right in the framework.
The next topic is that framework.
Now, after the break,
we are going to start a framework portion.
Actually,
I was supposed to start the framework
in the beginning of the class, but then
again, Nicolas, I know that.
But now this is the time to club
everything
together.
Can you show me the code in your name?
Number 81 Plus.
Can you show me the code?
Line number 81?
Yeah, right.
So, guys,
let's take a break
for, say, 14, 20 minutes.
Sorry. Right. Alright.
This is all
what ever the things that we have learned
that was the part of our testing basics.
Now, from here, from this point,
we will be proceeding the world's
understanding and creating our first test
in G framework.
All right.
Before going on to take part,
before going to start the explanation
for testing D framework, this is the time
when we have to recap the topics.
This is the time
when we have to understand
and we have to realize that whatever
their topics, we understood so far,
are we actually got those topics
or not understood those topics or not?
All right.
Yeah, Mike, I can understand after this
session, right.
I will remove your attitude
and we troubleshoot that.
So it's the one topic
which I can see that most of you guys
are having a problem
or had a problem with was data provider.
Now data provider is good.
Andrey And for you guys, is it
good now?
All right now before this topic
before data provided right
there were a couple of topics
generally I can
totally understand
because this is a configuration file
and there are so many configurations
we generally make in this one file rate.
So sometimes it leads to further confusion
whether we are dealing with packages
or we are dealing with list notice
or we are dealing with groups or classes
or methods.
So many things inside one class
or even execution,
multiple text,
every single thing in one class.
That's why I think you are having some
issues with test and do not act similarly,
not when data provided is correct
when data provider is fine.
Right. Let's talk about this next slide.
Yesterday we worked on laziness.
Right.
Which in this nurse interface
we implemented
experience.
Yesterday we worked on this nurse, right.
So which listener interface
we implemented in our in business class.
In this class we implemented yes,
I tested this, not this one.
We implemented this.
I tested this interface. Right.
And we provided the body of this method,
the definition of these functions
according to our own requirement.
Right. In that part. In that part.
Do you guys have any issue,
the part of listener how we implemented
those are steps, how we had implemented
those methods, how we had provided
the body of those matters.
Any question in that part? Listeners
No questions.
Great. No, no.
For this precondition in a post condition
we had to use this config and drivers.
So the Europeans package,
we used this tool,
we will be going through these two
packages again in our framework as well.
Alright.
So even like said yesterday, also,
even if you have any questions
in this portion, right, don't worry,
we will go through this configuration,
We will go through this your way
of creating our framework as well.
So still, if you guys have any question
in these two parts
specifically I'm talking about config
and utils, right?
These issues will be solved and resolved
in your framework portion, right?
Because these two packages
will be the part of your framework
and that's what everyone.
All right. So now
let's to start
right our new journey with framework.
The conclusion of all the point
the conclusion of all the point
the common point.
Right.
The one station that the one concept
that we were looking for
from the very first day is your framework.
This is something unique or interesting.
I'm repeating once again,
guys, you are a bridge, your java.
Okay, you are averaging selenium.
Okay.
You are just average
or above average in testing G.
Okay, but when you talk about framework,
you have to be an expert on this point.
You must know
you, you must know how
how this framework books in your project.
Alright you must know all the in
and out of this framework.
If you are writing any code inside
any class, you must know
why are we rating.
Alright.
So that's why I'm saying this is
a completely fresh beginning, right.
So try to get every single thing.
I will try to explain the things
as low as possible.
I will try to write everything
from scratch and I will tell you
about the most about the intention behind
writing that particular
method, particular class
or particular concept in framework.
Okay, so I need your complete attention
for these two weeks of
we will be learning on this 20 framework
as well is a cucumber playback.
All right, basics.
We are done. Basics are already gone.
Whether it is Java or it is the minimum
or it is just and it's done now.
The framework new beginning.
Alright, so let's start with the framework
in this session today we will discuss
towards the very first thing
what framework is.
I'm saying framework is important.
You have to be an expert of the framework.
Not now, not now.
I will tell you
when the time comes. Right.
So for right now we need to understand
what framework is and then when we start,
right, when we go for the implementation
then I then you open your project.
All right?
So when I am seeing you have to be
an expert of your framework.
You should know all that in and out
so what is framework?
What is framework?
This is the main question.
Yes. Yes.
And provide
the same framework, the same framework
you will be using for that project.
Correct.
And not only your project, right.
When you go in any organization,
when you work for any explicit project,
the very first thing to remember, guys,
there are always two scenarios, right?
When you will get a job,
you will be a nice distinct.
Either you
will join the organization or the team
is already having an existing setup,
right?
Of the framework of the project
and everything there.
They will ask you to understand
any not their own framework, right?
And then you have to write your code
in their own framework.
Correct. This is one scenario.
And then that scenario is
let's say you join one organization
and they have just introduced
the automation in their project,
right? In their project.
So now in this case,
you will be the driver of this show.
What you have to do is you have to create
own framework there, right?
And that framework
everyone will use to write their code.
That's why it is very important to learn
how to create framework from scratch.
All right.
In both cases, you need basic foundation,
extremely strong.
You need your understanding,
conceptual understanding of framework,
extremely hard.
All right.
That's why I'm saying when it comes
to the explanation of framework,
you should be expert of it.
And that's the overview
why we need this framework.
Right.
And what is the importance of framework
like.
So now then we guys, then I said,
what is framework?
What do you understand
by this word framework?
Static in any interview doesn't matter
which interview you're attending, right?
In any interview, every single interview,
there will be questions on framework,
that is for sure.
Every single interview, what we ask.
Can you tell me something about
your framework which you are using right.
How your framework works?
What are the
modifications
you have done in your framework?
What are the changes
you have made in your framework
how you have contributed in improving
the performance of your framework?
These type of questions they ask
in the interviews Selected Framework.
There
you must explain how your framework works,
how you have contributed in the framework,
how you are dealing with the framework,
how you're adding the clauses
in the framework, every single thing.
It's all about the structure.
Okay, They will go and we will see
all these things in detail.
Right now, remember one thing
when I see what is framework it is simply
an organized structure, I'm giving you
a very, very simple definition, right?
Organized folder structure.
It allows you to write your code
in a systematic way, right?
Yet it says this thing framework
is a set of guidelines
or rules used for creating
and designing your best guesses.
These
guidelines could include coding standards.
Now remember, I was just talking
about coding a standard straight.
You should call every single method
for every single functionality.
You should have separate
methods, should have object repository.
So these are coding standards.
I will tell you in detail
what all these things are.
Then there's data handling
methods, repository
processes.
I will upload bits of framework,
slide right in the canvas
word you and then you will be having
this complete by all every single slide
you will be having in your canvas
right up to the station.
And for a simple definition, yes,
I will write inside code.
Don't worry for simple notes.
Obviously we will take notes, start
the file, print, but don't worry about it
or information
on how to access external resources.
Now let's understand one situation.
Let me give you one daytime scenario.
Let's see.
Anna, Polina, Black and Mike,
you four guys
got a job in the same organization, right?
Luckily you
for all you all four are working.
You all four
are working on the same project right
now. If your
manager says, Hey Mike, go ahead
and write the code for log in Zanetti,
write for the log in page
for the log in page.
Mike is accountable to write the code.
At the same time he gave the task
to blank that you have to write the code
on profile settings page.
Understand is this.
Understand
what I'm trying to explain here?
Write for Olena Dashboard page.
She is accountable to write the code
for dashboard page and for Anna.
Right?
You have to write the code for aid
and might be
right for different guys,
for different modules.
But single application
Now if you do not have
a framework, right,
for different pages, right.
We call them page,
we call them modules, write different. Now
if we do not have a framework,
Mike will write the code in his own style.
Black will write his code
in his own phone,
or then I will write his code
in his own style
and I will write a report
in his own state.
In our own state, Correct.
What is the problem here?
What is the problem when your lead,
when your architect, when your manager
reviews your code? Right.
He or she will get confused.
Right.
Because there is no consistency
in the code.
There is no consistency. Right.
You are calling the methods
in your own way.
Someone else is calling the methods
in her own way or in his own right.
But the data would
that the user of the code is just one
and he is reviewing
four different types of code.
I think my point
makes sense
guys. Now.
Now to keep everyone
to keep everyone on the same page.
What is the best way if your manager
or if your says,
Hey Mike,
you have to write this code like this
and then you have to write this code
like this?
Olena You have to write this code
like this in black.
You have to write this particular module
like this,
how much information
you will remember in your mind
if this is everything,
if he explains everything, just 5%
or 10% information,
really hard to remember everything.
Correct.
So we need one reliable source, right?
We need one reliable source
that can restrict everyone
that can define the rules.
A specific set of rules for everyone that,
you must follow the guidelines
to write the code.
Right. So we need one structure.
We need one consistent platform
that everyone can trade the code
while following
the same set of rules and guidelines
so that everyone can be on the same page.
This is a specific set of rules.
This is structure.
This particular part
we call it as a theme. But
the spirit everyone
settings and kind of
okay, so now,
now when you have one framework in place
right
when you have one framework in place,
your framework means, Hey,
I have precondition for this application.
It doesn't matter whether you're working
log in part, you have to navigate
to the URL first
or you're working on dashboard page.
You have to perform navigation
first, right?
Or you're working on an employee page
or you're working on profile
settings to go on any other page.
Right inside application falls,
you'll need to go ahead,
launch your browser and maybe get to
you want to correct.
So now for all this, for people,
for all of you, for
everyone you don't need to write.
Not everyone has to read this.
The condition, forced conditions.
What might we do?
Make the right precondition
and post condition inside config folder.
Right inside.
Say your configuration common metrics
right inside your utils
indexing in your utils folder.
You write this method
you can make it into the repository
when you commit it into the repository.
What Olena and I will do,
they will simply extends
this common method in there,
the respective modules
in their respective classes,
and they will write their code
related to their respective modules
in the same precondition
and post condition
will work for all this for people
called reusability.
One wrote this code.
Now for people and using this code. Right?
Isn't it time saving for everyone?
Right, guys, things are clear.
I hope you're able
to visualize the things.
What I'm trying to extend right now.
Great.
No, Now the next thing.
Now the next thing.
Let's see.
Mike wants to write
the code in some ls folder, right?
Or if he wants to write the code,
he might take some other approach.
And then I want to write the code
in some other folder inside one.
Fight every single thing. Right.
Then it will be again problematic
because one is writing in another way,
another is writing in another be.
Your framework says all four of you guys
will write your code
in this particular folder.
Now, inside your framework,
if your framework says you have to write
this code in this particular folder,
now, you're not allowed to write your code
outside that folder.
Right now.
What is important is what is the main page
of this in a particular folder
makes it Currently
you four are working in your team.
Write the model Eugene,
Elisabeth and Jamal.
These three also join your team.
Okay.
Now your seven members in your team right
for starting four.
Everything is understandable, right?
For all of you guys.
For four of you,
everything is understandable.
Well, because you guys are dealing
with this framework, right?
But for these three new people.
Right.
What is the important point?
The important point is anyone from
you can tell to these three guys, hey,
we are using this particular
framework, right?
If you want to write something, don't
follow your standards.
Follow the standards of this framework.
We are writing the code.
In this particular folder
you have to write the code.
You are supposed to write the code
in the same format now for them all.
So it is very easy to write.
They will just take the framework,
they will understand.
All right.
Mike was talking
about this particular folder,
so we have to write this things in this
particular form.
Now the efforts are going minimum.
The efforts are reduced, right.
But the explanation is going higher.
Getting my point
because framework is self-explanatory.
It is defining the set of rules,
the guidelines you guys are following.
You are telling everyone else
to follow the same things, right?
So now everyone is following.
Everyone is on the same page.
Isn't it easy to maintain the code
in this case now?
Now the next point,
you have 100 classes, you have hundred
functions, you have one request.
Didn't take 500 different modules.
Right.
But if you have broken the structure now,
if you have a property, the structure
and you know, all of my test cases
are available in one folder, quite test.
I'm just giving an example. Right.
You have one for you that point fix test
and all of your test cases
available inside this one folder.
In this
folder also you have six classes, right?
And let's sit and execute code
for the eight employee page.
Now she knows that I have written
this code inside of my test package.
Inside this package I have one class,
I have written my code this write,
you have written this
everything inside this particular class,
inside this particular package.
You are on holiday.
You're on vacation. Right.
And Olena is trying to execute
the entire piece of code.
Right?
Obviously,
she will also execute your code is.
But she is not going to do this,
that she will execute her piece of code
and not yours. Right.
She will execute the entire project
that this time, if she come across
an error in your editor employee page,
she doesn't have to for the entire thing.
But what she will do
is she will open the test package.
She will go and say Bashford class. Right.
And she will be able to fix the code.
She will be to fix this script.
Right?
Isn't it time saving and very easy
to identify the errors
in the framework?
Guys, understanding
what I'm trying to explain.
Right.
So easy to maintain if error comes
it would be very easy to identify
and spot the error.
Right.
You don't need to
go through the entire framework and check
every single folder in every single file.
You don't need to do that.
Just go inside the specific location
and you will find the
code reusability.
Another point
like I get to give one example, very basic
example of launching the browser,
navigating to role
and closing the browser.
Right.
One person is writing,
the remaining six are using the same code
code reusability for the entire project.
Just one precondition is working in
one condition is working
so it doesn't matter
if you have 100 or 1000 classes.
The same precondition
will work throughout.
And also
these are the advantage they just have
talking about the framework.
What is framework?
I already told you Now see
in the framework in the framework,
another feature
we can create methods for reading,
writing from external data
sources, validation, reporting, etc.
and can place it
in such a way that you need.
Other projects can also use it.
It saves efforts time.
Of course, many of the company
remember guys want wanted
for what?
Everything in it is business.
Everything is business.
Client your customer, your management
is polite with you all the time.
You're delivering
in their time, you're delivering
according to their expectations.
Then never.
They never, ever
appreciate the things that is time taking
because time
is directly proportional to money.
They are investing in the project.
If you are taking more time,
they have to pay more money.
They will never appreciate any
any approach, which is I'm thinking right.
So if there is a confusion to remove
that confusion from the framework,
you need time.
And if you need time,
you will get paid for their time.
And who is going to pay?
Your customer will going to pay.
So what they need,
they need time saving solution.
They need something because
which is very straightforward, right?
Which is very easy to understand,
Which is very easy to implement. Why?
Because if these things are easy
to implement, then it is less time
consuming.
And if it is less time consuming,
there will be less money.
Right?
So every single thing in the industry,
whether your senior management,
your customer, your client, your project,
everything is just business.
Make sure, guys
keep this thing very clear in your mind.
I'm telling you this things
from my experience, right?
I have dealt with over 28 clients
in my career so far in.
This last eight years,
I have delivered over 28 projects.
I know all this.
28 were more inclined towards money,
towards business, not towards invoice.
This is the bitter truth of the industry.
So keep this point in your mind.
All right?
When we are going into the advanced
concept,
I'm giving you the reality of the market.
Alright?
So we have to be very specific
on this part because we have to come up
with the solutions
which are more favorable to the customers.
Not sometimes you have to implement
the concepts in the framework
which are not favorable to you
since these concepts are favorable
to your customer,
then your client you have to do it
even though it
doesn't matter whether you like it or not.
Your customer is asking your client
is asking, your management is asking.
So you have to implement them, correct?
Mike Correct.
My company used to say the same thing
earlier.
Now this job, because we realized,
all right,
now let's follow suit for the
why we need a framework.
Yesterday, remember I told you one
when we are passing their data, username,
password, first name, last name, right.
Or even the part of five.
We should not pass anything hard
coded correct.
Everything.
Everything should be parameterized.
Okay.
From different components, from different
components, from different parameters.
You have to parse this data
in terms of keys, in terms of parameters.
Framework allows you to implement
the functionality, build it,
make sure that you're not passing
any data coding.
That's why
we need framework for thing, right?
So like anything,
you need one
place,
you need one place in your framework.
In that place,
what you will say, Hey, my framework,
I'm going to execute my fit
as to give this
in my ten test cases.
If six are passed and four are filled,
I need the report for this fix
and this for even
it is passed only when it is finished.
I need the screenshot for all this point.
I need detailed report of all this thing
and I need all of these things
at one place.
So your framework allows you to implement
this functionality as
clear.
Now that those things,
even when we are learning this system,
when we were learning this, this stingy
right learning this
just basic this stingy basically
we were executing everything
from right click
or even what we were doing
we were having multiple right.
We use to execute multiple tests
and you don't accidents, right.
If you
observe this point is then
do you want similar testing to detect?
Similarly is small, but similarly creation
protects them in so many things.
Right now
your framework allows you to execute
all of these same insight
from just one point.
You need to execute your script
from one point only.
It means your entire
length of your framework
will be driven
from just one execution point.
Right?
You need to change everything
at one place, and everything will change
automatically throughout your project.
That kind of structure
we can make inside of the.
Yes, I'm going to
put all of these reasons we need.
Our framework is clear to everyone. Now.
The next thing is when I see a report,
right when I see the report
in our framework, the can be customized
right according to your own requirement.
If you
remember yesterday,
I told you that we are going to implement
the one interface
that is my best listener.
Correct?
We implement this interface.
I test the listener.
Why are we using interface?
Because they can provide the body
and the definition
of the method or the function
according to our own required of me.
Right.
So now, if my requirement
is to just get some raw information, fine.
I can give that information
raw instructions
and I will get more information my report.
But if I need a screenshot,
if I need a result
of the particular method,
if I need the name of particular test
along with this screenshot, can I do this
customization in my framework?
So the answer is yes.
I can customize my report
according to my own required is. But.
All right.
All right
guys. So far clear to everyone.
I'm not getting proper responses.
That's why I'm asking.
All right.
Now, let's proceed for that.
Now, what all are
the characteristics of one frame?
What we should know?
So these are the characteristics, right?
We should understand
the remember.
One thing.
Remember one thing, guys,
whenever we talk about framework, right.
That agenda that intention
behind creating any framework
is to give this framework.
If we are giving this framework
to any new employee,
any new joiner of the team, right
he or
she must be able to start contributing.
When I say contributing,
it means writing the code
as early as possible with minimal
understanding, with minimal guidance
and with no setup
by because that is already available
in the framework you are giving
a working product, you're giving a working
framework to anyone.
Now you also don't want to spend much time
on the explanation
part, on the clarity part.
So in the framework itself,
if you will see we are keeping this thing
in the repository,
this thing in this repository,
and the documentation is also available
for this particular framework,
which is what we call onboarding document.
Right?
So there he or she can get complete
knowledge of the framework
with minimal guidance
and he or she can start
contributing at the earliest
in the framework in the project.
Right.
So you have to develop your framework
in such a way
that it should provide this one. Pages.
This is the first characteristic
of your framework.
We are going on day point. We are going on
now. The second is first,
let's talk about project
and then we will talk about
make fun independent.
All right.
It must not be project independent.
What does it mean, guys?
It must not be project dependent.
Any idea? Yes.
Let's it Mike Baleno and
what was the fourth one?
Nor I think like black.
Black. Yeah.
So these four guys, these four guys,
they were working in one project, right?
These four guys were working
in Msme Company.
Right in Amazon.
Company Ltd said they guys were working on
what is the name of Project
Alexa, right?
You four were working on Alexa, now
Anna and Black shortlisted
for another Project.
You got shortlisted because you guys are
working right with the innovative approach
and they knew the people like you,
so they shortlisted of you.
Now you both are going to join another
project that is Amazon Prime video, right?
The one project is Alexa.
Mike is is still in the Alexa one
and is still in the Alexa,
but you both are going there
with Amazon Prime video.
Again, you guys have to use
automation that you have to automate
this particular software.
Amazon Prime video,
the entire web application
you have to automate now on Suddenly
and in Black.
If you guys are joining
this particular new project,
are you guys supposed to create framework
from scratch?
There?
Please make sure right.
What I am trying to explain here,
please pay attention on this point.
No right.
You should not create the framework
from this connect. Why?
Because you already put efforts
on creating that framework
in your previous project.
Right?
So what you have to do
this time is you will take the basic
framework skeleton
from the previous project.
Right? From the previous project here.
This time what you need to change
gesture is that you are in
the administration's
right changed the locators
according to your new application
and your same logging script
will work. You
the your framework will work here because
log in pages log in page right locators.
You just need to change
functionality is you are going to change.
Yes you are going to change that you are.
And so application will change, right?
Because the instructions are seen,
the data is different.
So instead of creating the new framework
from the switch on any other project,
what you can simply do is
you can pick the project,
you can take the framework from,
your previous project,
and you can do a little bit
of modification in this to use
for your new project.
That's what we call
Project Independent framework.
This is the second characteristics
that you must create
a framework which is project independent.
All right.
Hilal
basically architect most of the times.
But if studies on senior position.
So yes, testers
also, for example, I have created
sleeping works, right?
And these particular books
I've used in 22 or 23 different projects.
So obviously I spent a lot time
in creating the framework
right in my earlier days,
like two and a half years back
then, I promoted to that position
as a deputy manager
and then after that,
if anyone comes from any other project,
did him as, do we have any framework?
I said, Yes, the framework ready?
Go ahead, use this framework and modify
it according to your requirement.
This framework work.
So in my entire company
now we have a team of 2500 employees
in my company right
across 14 different locations.
We have a team of 2500 employees
and these employees out of them,
I would say 15, 1600 employees
are working on this 2725 project.
Everyone is using those frameworks now.
So I it's a private one.
Yeah, it's a secured one.
All right.
So guys, remember
when your framework is very flexible,
when your framework is highly independent
of any project?
Right in the beginning,
then you can use your framework anywhere.
And this is the best approach
to create any framework from scratch.
It should be highly customizable
right there?
At some point,
this is what we can use everywhere,
correct?
These things are making sense now.
What are the characteristics of framework
and why we should have
this characteristics?
All right, Let's go ahead.
It should be reusable
and easy to manage and maintain.
All right.
I told you about the maintenance.
What is maintenance?
Basically,
when you're executing your script,
let's say five days to get this,
three are frame rate
when you're working to fix these, three
when you are working
to remove the errors from your three test
kits, this right,
this is what we call
maintenance of your script, right?
Right now,
because you're
working on a very small level,
then you will be working on a high level.
Then you have to execute 2000 test
cases, 2500 test cases every day right.
Then you will be getting errors
in, let's say 500 test,
get this fixed and big test,
get this there.
You have to spend your days
just to fix your script.
It is what we call efforts.
We are putting efforts.
We are investing in the maintenance of
here. All
right. It should be usable.
So why reusable?
Because if I want to click
on 1000 elements in my application
or if I want to send the data, it
1000 plays in my application every time.
I cannot write that,
I would not find the element by not
saying the keys and then pass some data,
I need one function
and that function will perform this turn
because operation it
1000 places code reusability.
If I take one place, execute every man.
This will be the part of your team, right?
Which we are going to obviously implement
in your framework.
Okay.
Another important feature,
if I just disclose this point.
All right, then flow should be very clear.
When I say no should be very clear.
It means the basic definition of framework
is it should be easily understandable.
All right.
Your framework
can not be like a rocket science.
It should be like not rocket science
where you have to solve so many questions
just to understand a simple folder,
structure and organized manner.
Why we are organizing the structure,
why we are organizing
the structure based VBA for providing
this particular sequence right.
The proper manner structure.
Because we need easiness to understand
defeat.
We need easily understandable part.
That's why we are doing it right.
So your flow of frameworks
be very easy and understandable
and it should be very clear so that one
can understand it with minimal efforts
clear.
All right.
Now another point is, let's see again,
I'm taking the same example
why I'm taking this
the life examples, guys, because it might
what I personally think is this type of
examples makes your explanation very easy.
Right.
And you guys can also relate to the things
Let's say I'm talking about Black
Mike Olena and Anna.
These four guys are working in one team
now. Their proper understanding
of programing, their knowledge
about programing and their skills,
about the automation testing
are same among for this guy
among these four guys
or it is different.
Different, right.
I'm giving you one very basic
example, right?
It is a different train in your class.
In your class.
When I explain something,
some people get it very easy, right?
Like a motor, very smoothly.
Some people find it hard to understand
that topic, right?
I'm not telling.
I'm not saying
they guys are taking time or something.
I'm just trying to give you an example
that everyone
everyone
is not having the same kind of potential.
Right.
So what is the practical approach
in this scenario?
As a tutor, as an instructor,
as a teacher, this is my responsibility
to make sure that everyone, one
can understand the thing in the same way,
correct?
Correct. Don't always
similarly.
Similarly, Ben Black, Anna
Olena and Mike are working in one team
for, one project and they have one
framework work with them.
It is not necessity.
They all these four people will be able
to understand the framework
right At the same time,
my group like will understand
everything in just 30 minutes.
Might be analytic.
One day it might be
black will take or Mike will take one week
or might be in just one hour.
Right.
It might be different
because it varies according to people.
Correct.
So now what is the of good framework?
The definition of good framework is
the definition of good framework is
it can be understandable from everyone.
It can be understandable from everyone.
So even not only intelligent a step,
but also in everyday
automation
is to start contributing at the earliest.
Alright,
they can also understand the things
and they can also use this
framework in the earliest
days.
Are you able to connecting the dots?
What I explained from the example
of your class and from the example
of framework, correct?
Why I'm extending this point?
Because sometimes what people think is
whenever they hear this word framework,
they always think we need something
like Pascal's law
or some Laplace equation,
something like that, or rocket science.
No, this framework must be very easy.
You framework must be very flexible
so that everyone can understand it.
We are giving this product
to our teammates
to make their life easy,
not to make their life more hectic.
Correct? No.
Next point,
it should not contain hardcoded values.
I already explained this point.
If you guys focus, if you guys remember
in your framework,
you should not pass anything hardcoded.
Correct.
I'm not only talking about your username
and password anywhere,
even if you're passing files,
but it should not be hardcoded.
Let me show you this.
Yesterday.
Yesterday when you were talking
about this portion inside you
utils
in your common metrics.
Right.
We have positive this part
is this but hardcoded
what it is normal can be.
It is hardcoded.
Right
now your framework says
it should not contain hardcoded values.
If the means look,
we are not going to pass
even your this file path hardcoded right.
We will parameterized this crazy
how they knew that nobody's it
now it be easily extendable.
What does it mean?
Let's see.
Today in your application
you have log in page logout
page dashboard page item by page.
So don't create your framework
in such a way that it supports
only for application or only
for the modules of one application.
You never know what the model thinks
right.
Tomorrow,
maybe you have to add transactions page,
maybe you have to add some
of spending page,
but you will be having so many products
or you will be having profile
settings, page or different page,
or you will be having monetization
page, right?
It could be any kind of integration
that can be done in your application.
You to design your framework
in such a way that it will support
and it can be extended according
to the requirement in future as well.
Again,
flexibility of your framework is make it
great and then answer to your question.
And it's not.
It should be platform independent.
What does it mean?
It should be independent.
It means
someone is using Linux,
someone is using Mac,
someone is using your Windows.
Right now.
You can't restrict your client list.
Say you are writing every single thing
in your windows machine.
You gave your code to your client.
Your client to execute this code,
but he is using Mac machine.
Your framework should work in such a way.
This same piece of code
should work in Windows machine as well.
The same piece of work should work in
same piece of code.
Should work in your Mac machine. Is
it should be made from independent.
Got it.
Yes, correct. And it's getting
so far
based in this explanation,
any question, whatever
the things I expect, any question in this.
Andre, you there?
Okay, guys,
I hope I'm explaining slowly. Right.
And you guys are understanding.
All right.
So now
let's talk about another important point,
right?
We are putting a lot of efforts
in strengthening what this framework.
Right?
We are putting a lot of efforts
in understanding
what are the connectors sticks.
One framework should have. Right?
We are trying to make everyone's life
easier.
Everything is fine.
But what
for me, every single one is my favorite.
Every single one.
And for me it is very good, right?
If I'm getting the company right,
it is very good for me.
It's already one I improve.
It is very good for me.
I am also learning, like I say,
that we all are learning right?
And the learning is ongoing process
till the time you take your last breath.
Right?
So you should always learn from everyone.
Yes, I'm ready.
Whatever the things, I'm extending things.
This is a part of giving that
clarity right.
This is a part of your clarity.
That's why I'm trying to explain.
And from the next slide,
if you'll see from here, I will implement
and extend it the same time.
Now, what are the benefits
before even stepping
into the creation of your framework?
What are the benefits
we will get once we have this framework?
These are the things
we need to understand.
If you're utilizing any framework
for your automation testing,
the first thing, what it will do is by
your company is investing
while your client is investing
this much amount for creating the frame.
But they can also
ask you to write one normal synonym
plus the way you're writing right now.
And then you can simply execute
your script, right?
You can do that.
Why they're investing this much of time
and allowing you to execute
and create this framework
because it will increase
your overall speed of writing
once you have the complete clarity
and set of rules that everything
it will improve,
increase the productivity of your team.
Right? So let's say if you are writing
five test cases, for example, in one day
without framework,
and if you can understand this framework,
if you understood this framework
correctly, you can create
maybe six or seven test cases in one day.
Right?
Or maybe let's talk about more practical
for your writing pretest, because this
in a day often ending the framework,
understanding you're able
to write like this because this
now just don't look at this to test
to get this thing. Why?
Because your team is having
how many members black
your name is having how many members
know Jamal who also joined up some time.
Right. Same kind of.
So now if one guy is writing five
this script in three main for two,
four, seven people,
how many scripts are going increase
14 scripts every day, increasing
14 test cases increased every day
because of this framework.
Right.
And let's talk about the bigger scenario
where you have 5000 best guesses, right?
These 14 steps, Right.
This 14 test is in place.
These are a bonus.
This is just a bonus for one day.
So just to multiply five days in a week,
20 days in a month.
Right.
And then to 40 days in your year
in one year
to 40 days multiplied by 1424 and break
and then the mini 40.
So it means how much?
1000 to 400 to get this
you can save in one year
getting my point
not sure like about it
right so that's how your framework
give you lot of benefits in the longer run
right there so whenever you see
a long term project right video
see so many scenarios.
I know one client or CVS.
CVS health care is a client, right?
CVS is a one health care company
in the US,
right.
I'm just giving you one very small
example, guys, from my experience,
because I've worked with CVS right
in my 2017, I think four years back,
just to parse data,
just to parse their data.
This data
in the framework, in the framework,
can you guys even imagine
how many Excel files they're
using in the framework, how many files
we are using to parse the data
and Andre
Black, Mike, how many test,
how many Excel file we're using?
Just one.
Correct.
They are using a 179 Excel files
just to pass this data.
179 Excel files.
I was blown away
when I looked at their framework
and then said this to my I said, okay,
this is going to be very difficult part
for you now,
and you have to cross this bridge to 879
files.
Yeah, my contact.
So now you can imagine why
I'm giving this example, because if you're
passing 170 main Excel file
just to pass data, how many test cases
they have in their framework,
in their application to execute minimum
5000, minimum
seven or 8000 or 10,000 test to this
in this much long project,
in this much big project, when you have a
lot of 80, a lot of scope of automation
testing framework helps you a lot.
In this case
sense
right now.
The second thing is your maintenance.
Maintenance cost goes down,
it reduces your maintenance cost, right?
Because when you have a complete
organized structure,
then you are more likely
to write your code in a single shot.
It means with minimal errors. Right.
And if you are writing your code
with minimal errors, with minimal issues,
then the maintenance will go down.
So obviously that cost company
will be building on
the maintenance will go down
automatically right.
No more escalations connect
than minimal manual intervention.
Right. This is the main point.
If I ask this team Black or Lena
and Mike Jamal, let's take two more guys.
Oxana and Andrey,
you have your nine guys right in the team.
If I asked you to execute
all the test systems manually,
your nine people, how much time we think
to execute 5000 test kits as many of
you have to put it
in one folder.
All right. Okay.
So it is what I am thinking
process, right?
It is a time ticking activity,
but the same thing
if you're doing in the automation,
you have selenium set up with you
and you're executing everything
by automation, right?
What this
what we do instead of this nine days, know
how many people you need
to execute this script just to one.
Right?
And this one guy
also will put how much efforts
he or she just needs to execute
one combined.
Right.
And once you execute one command,
it will execute all of your script,
all of your test cases in a single shot
because your framework
will take care of everything.
It will generate the report,
it will take the screenshot,
it will execute your things,
it will verify and validate
all the verification validation
check points.
You will get the consolidated report.
In the end, it means what?
Minimal manual intervention Clear
and then maximum based coverage.
Obviously, when you're writing the code,
you're providing more verification
and validation checkpoints.
And every single time, every single time,
it might be possible
that if I give this task to black or then
I and Andre, they hey,
on this particular page or dashboard page,
I have 25 verification check points.
Right?
And if Andre is testing this
25 verification check points or validation
check points manually, he is more likely
to with one or two or three.
Right?
Because we all are humans.
We can make mistakes, make sense.
But if you put this 25 verification
in validation
check points in your automation script,
how many verification
and validation checkpoints
your automation is scripts will forget
or will miss
no one?
Nothing, right?
It will benefit and verify
all the all the mentioned
verification validation check points
because a scripts can never go wrong.
Whatever the code you have mentioned,
it will definitely execute.
Right.
So if Andre and Blake comes and say,
Hey, I've executed these things
manually and everything is working
exceptionally fine, right?
Your manager has a lot of faith in you
guys. Now
he give a green signal that, all right,
deploy this grid onto the production.
You vibe.
You guys, you both
guys missed at least three or four
verification validation
check points and there was a problem
in those check points.
Now, if your developers are deployed
the code onto the production,
some or someone else
identified that loophole in the system
or is responsible them.
Right testers are accountable to answer
right by because they have missed now
and same time
the maximum test coverage rate
the test code.
It is both down by
because you are not giving
the complete coverage to the requirement
that if Vladimir was something else
and you be delivered below,
then the requirement below
the expectations, this coverage goes down.
Right.
But when it comes to automation
it gives you maximum test coverage.
This is the another benefit
of using test automation framework.
Make sense
case.
Okay.
Now the another point
is the usability of code, right?
When we talk about visibility,
it means I gave you this example
all the little three nights, right?
So I hope you know,
what is the usability code
once use every bit
this is simply code usability.
That's what we did yesterday
when we were learning
our test, in part by the mistakes
where we have used this precondition
and post condition,
all the places correct.
All right, fine.
So now, now let's proceed further.
And this is the time to understand
how are we going to implement,
how are we going to implement
every single thing from here?
All right,
Let's do the things practically more,
practically more.
All right, fine, Guys, please let me know
once you're able to see my screen
of framework is project based.
What does it mean?
I mean, we have to
we have to create a framework
which is project
defining Project Independent.
All right.
So now
some of the important ingredients,
some of the important ingredient side,
the vital ingredients we have right
to create a theme.
But what are these vital ingredients
we need first, programing language,
correct.
Which programing language
we are using based
on Java
Python, RB
components.
Now we are going to work on our texture
and this application.
All right.
Yes, Yes.
I'm telling you,
it's it's out in this application.
Remember, whenever we work on framework,
we should keep this things in mind.
Great selection of tools and technologies
according to the project.
Right? According to the project.
So now, right now, right now,
when I'm going to create this framework
from scratch, what are the things
I should have first in place?
That's what I'm trying to identify.
So this thing, it's animate application
is what kind of application?
I mean, it is mobile application,
it is benefits, correct?
This is my web based application, right.
So to automate web based application,
which tool I have to use
web automation tool.
Right.
We have
an Indian, correct.
Now, Now one thing.
Second thing.
Third thing.
We observed a couple of loopholes
in the Selenium alone, Selenium
can't do every single thing, right.
So we did one integration here.
What was that for additional features,
Right?
So integration, what we had is
yes, correct.
To be used.
What.
Speak up guys. You're correct.
You're saying correct. Right.
And stingy.
Right
now. Yes.
Now let's see.
And I turned to Mike and say, hey, Mike,
you have written this code
condition enforcement mission for log in.
Mike says, yes, because I'm almost done
with my log in scenario.
And I said, all right,
I'm going to work on an employee.
So I was busy today
in identifying the locate storm
dashboard page from Pimp
B from an employee page.
But then I realized that you already
logged on to log into functionality.
So do you have a pre-condition
enforced condition?
Mike says, Yes, I have.
And I said, All right, same to me.
What Mike would do in that case
will.
Mike, send it in the slack. Yes.
Because if he sends this in the slack
right, then
he will get escalation from the clean
water escalation.
Your code should never be
can never be shared.
It must not be shared to any any channel
anywhere.
Right.
You can't even share your code
in the document to remember.
Guys, the code is very sensitive data.
You have to keep your code
in the client environment.
In the customer environment,
that is very important.
Remember, guys, this are the
parts of your professionalism
you have to understand store.
You have to keep your code in your
login control.
Correct.
So which one we are using?
Got GitHub.
Yeah, we are using GitHub.
Correct. Banks.
And now in this case
when that comes in, ask to Mike,
am I going to give me the code?
Mike will say,
all right, I'm going to commit to it.
I completely understood ready. So
I'm going to commit in the GitHub.
You can take the updated code from there,
just pull this code
and then everything will be.
Is everything shared in GitHub
open for everyone?
No, it should not be open for everyone.
Dave The access that has access
will be given to only the team members,
so only team members can access
to that particular project.
Not everyone.
For example,
I gave just one example right here.
Take Mike 40 black and Anna got promoted
and they got another project,
Amazon Prime Video.
So now till this point of time, right
when they are working in the
in this Alexa project,
they are having the access of this right.
But once they leave
this project officially, once they left
and they joined another project,
then the access will be taken back
from these two guys instead, whoever is
the new team will take the access back.
Now, even
their guys cannot access the repository.
They guys can not access the code.
They have to commit the code.
And there is a document
called photo Document.
Photo escapes for
auto.
It means hand over, take over document
because the point games I'm extending,
you hand over take over documents
they have to make right.
And then they have to say, all right,
we are leaving the team officially.
This is the code
we have completed in the repository.
We have handed over everything to this
reporting or this consenting person.
And now we are leaving the team.
Once they leave the team and the left,
the exits will be taken back
again.
All right, guys.
So what Mike will do with this code?
Indeed, what is in control?
So we need another part
that is GitHub, right, guys?
And then we need this structure.
We were talking about the structure,
right?
So We need one,
basically. Right.
We need one. Brings it back to is
Marvin.
Why we need this tool?
Because we need to make our project
highly flexible, highly customizable,
highly adaptable project
platform,
independent, every single thing, right?
We should not pass anything hardcoded.
So we need to achieve all of this
features in our framework.
We need
basic tools and that big is your maven.
All right? Yes.
Yes. From today onwards,
Maven is the backbone for everything.
We will deal with Maven.
Forget about the project,
about the normal classes and everything.
We will create
every single thing in seven project.
So these are the things Java, Selenium,
extended GitHub maven.
We need most important thing
are you going to implement, right?
You are going to implement
all of this things integrate
all of the things in your idea
that is intelligent.
So these are the things, these are
the things we are going to implement.
All right.
Nor I can totally understand
since the topic is very crucial, right?
I don't want any destruction.
These just 5 minutes
and then you can go on a break.
Alright.
All right.
An idea or That's what I was thinking.
But since they guys are expecting break
so that's why I said this.
All right.
So now this intelligent by trait
insight intelligent we
Java, Selenium, extended
GitHub, everything.
Alright so let's get started from here
you'll see here Java test and selenium
get in there And these are the five things
I was talking about, right.
I gave you the example
also why we need these five things.
All right,
now let's first understand what is this 11
build automation and management
tool, right?
But it allows developers
to create a project
using form and plugins.
Now, when I say BOM,
there are two types of bom.
I think they do, right?
We need to understand
these two things and plugins right now.
First, let's create this project right?
And after creation of the project
I will explain every single point
here.
Well, all right.
Shall we start
already?
Everyone with
now, many of you guys
didn't find my video helpful.
So now let's start from here
this is our previous framework, right?
This is our previous part.
Then automate testing.
Now click on file
mill.
So click on file
new and then click on
Project.
These guys go to watch it.
Right.
Subscribe also so
that you can get upcoming videos as well.
They're fine.
No, no.
The next thing is next thing
when you are on this screen
because we are not going to deal
with Java project anymore anymore
we have to deal with which one?
Yeah.
Did you do it?
Jamal?
Thank you so much, guys. No.
Did you do it?
All right, fine.
I will post some more code videos now.
All right, guys.
Now see here
that I respect that.
Now here we have to select one.
Correct?
We have to select seven.
Great, great. Select the one.
These is the part
when it says loading of type list
lytic load,
but we don't have to do anything from here
by because what is this obj type?
Basically this arch type is right.
It provides you a template.
It provides.
These are the
similar templates.
What kind of templates?
For example, there are some predefined
functionality you need or developers need?
So most of the times when developers
work right and they create a project from,
they need some specific arch type
from here according to their requirement
because they need to build
the application,
they need to develop the application,
they need to write the code.
Right?
So we are not very specific
on selecting the arch type.
What we will do is right,
because if I have selected
this checkbox clear
arch type by default it will give us two
because you my you must have created
any project in the past project entry
and if you had created any project
in Anaya,
then these words are to write
your debut as an object.
These are the by default are shape.
You got.
So next time
when you try to create new project right
by default
it will give you these two options.
And when you select this checkbox,
it will select these two
by default.
All right.
So now I'm not going to select anyone,
right?
Let it give.
Which one will you create from arch type?
Is everyone on the same screen with me
when I select
this checkbox?
Great.
Now the next thing is click on next.
It is asking for the name,
the project name.
So let's say our project name is
correct.
Destiny Framework match thing.
Alright, now this is not enough.
This is not enough seeing here.
See it is asking for group I.D.
and 80
black.
We just. We just selected the checkbox.
We just selected the checkbox.
All right, so now here.
What is this group
and what is this artifact I.D.?
So let me give you a one
very good example.
But remember, remember when you talk
about this group and artifact ID,
you guys are working, right?
Let's see.
Black or Nina and N Mike,
they guys are working in Amazon.
This group ID is the name of your company
organization or even in the organization.
If you have several department and you are
working in that particular department,
you need to give the name inside
here of the company name
all of their department name.
So for example,
even or do talk or conduct.
So for example, you guys are working
for your Amazon, right?
Or here we are working for which one
syntax.
Got it. So I'm keeping it syntax.
You can separate anything,
whatever you want to do.
Now, this artifact ID
this artifact ID
is the name of your project.
For example, in Amazon, if Mike Olin and
and and Blank,
they are working on Alexa, right?
So that IP factory would be Alexa
if blank and and is working on Amazon
Prime video,
then their identity would be APB,
Amazon Prime video like this.
Or it could be anything.
It's correct so com dots
and because this is my organization name
or even if you're working, let's say
I'm working in e-commerce department
enterprise Quality Solutions, the business
my department in my company
so I would write
com dot equals department.
Similarly you guys can write
your department or company name
and here the project name.
So my project is it's out of
order.
You can write in this simple one
which I in this right
there is no criteria
for guest density or something so
simple
so far in
providing the name of the project group.
And I think that maybe.
Do you guys have any confusion
or any question
in this one
so far clear everyone.
All right.
So let's go ahead and click on finish,
click, finish.
It will ask you
where would you like to open the project?
So just select a new window.
We need fresh instance.
So there is a new window.
There you go.
You got this structure?
No, we don't need to open anything.
So my default setting is it always opens
in the new broad browser or new window.
So is it opening the new window like this?
All right, great. Then it's fine now.
Now, if you see the very first thing
here is by default,
it is giving one instruction here.
If you see right by default
it is giving me one structure.
Then if I'm going inside,
it is giving me men and post
to different packages.
It is giving me right inside main.
It is giving me java and resources.
Inside it is giving me Java.
Can everyone see this?
That's fine.
As of now, it is fine.
Let's see.
Okay, so everyone can see it, right?
Main interest
if you It's light green Java salad.
Green Java. Okay. All right.
This is just because it belongs
to a different back text. My.
All right, so now, guys, if you see why,
why we have this main interest
optional unit two, you need to select
once again this MAVEN project
and then you will get many testable
because identity should come main
and this table should come.
So by here if you see by
we have main interest, can somebody guess
why is it so?
Because the developers of the memory tool
right must have part of it.
That's why they gave you two different.
Yes, exactly. The main folders.
We didn't really use this main folder
to develop the application.
The code B right just for the development
of the application.
We write this code in main folder.
In the code
we tried to best the application.
We keep that code and we write the code
inside the best folder.
Correct.
So where are we going to write
every single thing in main
or interest
interest folder?
Let's close this bar.
We will deal only with this one.
Okay.
All your convert symbol is not any sort of
see it is a part of your project.
If it was inside your inside, your idea
it is RC.
It would have come when you open data.
See, it is not coming
under these equations.
It is a part of your framework.
So it doesn't it doesn't matter
whether it appears here or it appears
it is fine, right.
So meant that it is a no no.
So now simply right click on it.
And if you want to delete, go ahead.
We will believe this.
No more confusion in our project
main folder
we didn't really use to keep the code.
We generally write
to develop the application.
All right,
so many developers use min folder
as a tester, as an automation engineer.
We don't use it, but it.
Yeah, that's kind of it.
That's fine.
So now so far, any confusion,
guys?
Great.
Now let's come here
on to the explanation part.
It says it allows the developer
to create project using page object
models and plugins,
and it helps to build project
dependency and documentation.
Maven allows the developer
to automate the process of creation
of initial folder structure,
performing the compilation and testing
and the package and the deployment
of the final product pipeline.
Now you see the main important
point is the main important point is
great.
Mike.
Now here, see, this is my simplified.
Yes, correct.
Correct.
Now this is my vertex admin file
and in this form
and if you observe the group already,
which I did, is available here
as my company name,
this is article, this is my project name
and this is the Virgin
by default from MAVEN
that is 1.0 snapshot
clear, clear
to everyone.
Okay, fine.
Do you want me to go
a bit further with the extension
or you guys need a break?
You Great.
First time
students are asking to continue.
That's great.
All right, now.
All right,
now. Here, here.
The most the most important concept
I'm going to explain now right?
So please pay complete attention here.
I'm saying here is so far,
we did the job files, correct.
Now, when we added the job files,
how did we do it?
We have added all the jobs manually.
Correct.
Now, when
I say I date the data files manually,
then what is the issue with adding
the job files manually?
Remember I was telling one,
I was giving one
example
and I came to Mike and ask, Hey, can I?
Your code and Mike's is all right.
I'm going to commit this code
in the repository.
Go ahead and take this code from there.
Right, Fine.
You have added all the files
manually in your project.
Understandable.
But Mike has added
the jobs in his machine right.
So where are the job files?
Where are that?
You are actually in the machine itself.
All right,
let me open framework.
Right. This one. Right.
And if I go here inside of my
project structure,
these are the jobs behind it correct.
That is Indian. The Selenium gets the
if you'll see it is giving me this fact
and me
this part belongs to my local machine
or not
local machine.
Right.
But what we said in the framework
being said,
our framework should be platform
independent.
Correct.
Now if you commit this code
in the repository and in this updated code
or take the pull of code in a machine,
will she be able to follow this?
Will she be able to find this
particular jobs in her machine this way?
Well,
this is going to work on her machine.
No, it will not work.
Why? Because jobs were available
in someone else's machine, right?
The bot belongs to someone else's,
not her machine.
What she has to do in this case,
she has to.
She has to download all the data files
once again in her machine
to make this project working
correctly.
The same issue, let's say are
you have 20 members in your team, right?
The same issue exists
for all the team members.
So is it the right approach
to add the jobs manually in the project?
Not right in this case.
In this case, Maven says
you don't need to add anything manually.
You just do one thing.
You don't even need to add jobs.
You don't even need to a job to find out.
What you can do is you can simply add
the dependency of your job in my file.
And then what I will do basically is
I will add all the dependencies
and the libraries for that particular job,
and then I will integrate
all this things in your project, all only
getting my point.
So which file
which by this date we are going to add
all these job files,
we are going to add this dependencies.
We need one
backbone of the project, right?
We need the Indian. Exactly.
The Indian have here
The backbone we have of the project
is bomb dot x email configuration file.
You can consider this longer
email configuration
file as the backbone of your project.
Remember we were talking about best and do
detect similar file in earlier classes.
Right?
So we were seeing this distant symbol
is a configuration file now, but this time
we are not going to deal with this
then do not accessible fight anymore.
We are going to deal with 1.75
correct correct
grade.
All right.
So now, now let's go ahead
and add the dependencies informed X
and build file first.
And then I will tell you how this bonded
accessible
file books right there.
So to add the dependency guys,
tell me is the very first dependency
we need to add, right?
The very first one. Right.
So if you go through here,
if you here right
it will tell you this diagram, Radio Java,
we already have it.
I think they do with selenium.
We need this synergy right.
So let's go ahead and do it one by one.
Yes, yes, yes.
I will tell you this also, don't worry.
It is it is in pipeline.
Don't worry about
it. All right. Everything
now, I came here
on the memory deposit right
in this memory repository.
I will write for selenium post.
I'm going to write
spinning.
Right.
Open the memory repository
and type selenium.
Everyone, please do it.
Because the very first thing, what I need
is I need the dependency of Selenium.
Correct.
It gives you this
first option, Selenium Java.
If this all in the 912 reasons
bothered about this
we are looking for this selenium Java.
Is everyone on the same page with me.
Then click on this selenium java.
Now when you come inside this
you will see all the virgins available
right the way we did in testing.
Great.
We have seen all divergence available
and we can select anyone from it.
So let's take the most straightforward
one 395 downloads.
I can see you suggest 395 for this one.
So I'm going to take this one.
Remember, you can take any one from here,
anyone from here.
But I'm going to take this one because
I can see number of downloads yet are more
trustworthy.
One the stable one, the compatible one.
I'm going to take what you can take
any one
click on it.
3.141
are not actually the current ones
are the latest ones,
but sometimes even I've experienced this
there.
Sometimes if you use the latest
there might be some compatibility issue.
Might be I'm not seeing that.
So that's why I'm thinking
which is most number of downloads. Why?
Because obviously it is working in
so many machines.
That's my most number most number of guys,
you know, downloading this one, correct.
So now everyone is on this page
earlier be used to download this jar.
Right.
I need to be used for download this jar.
Now things are changed.
We are not going to add any job.
What are we going to do is you'll see
it says you have my one project.
I say Yes, I have met and project it says,
All right then add this dependance,
so just copy this dependency from here
in this
maverick tab
you will see this dependency here right.
So just copy this dependency from here.
Go into your project
and here you have to add this dependency.
Now, when I add this dependency,
it is giving me the error, right?
Because it should be followed by
dependencies.
Why dependencies?
Because of this the I'm going to add
my people dependency, right?
Not one dependency right now.
I did one dependency.
After some time
I will add one more dependency
then one more dependency,
then one more dependency like this.
Right.
So all these dependencies come one
because dependency.
Now when you guys do it right,
if you guys see the red icon
right there or any error, right
click on the project, reload from here
or just simply restart your intelligence,
it will work.
So far
we have added the selenium dependency,
correct.
Now, another advantage I can tell you
when you are downloading the jar files
right before going through these methods
and repository repository,
what you were doing,
you were searching for test
and did your files in some other location
you were searching for.
Selenium.
Java is in some other location you are
searching for any other data files.
Mix it up what your comments
or IO in any other location.
Right.
Your methods is.
I have a central repository.
You can find selenium best in Apache
all months io
every single thing in one place.
So it is kind of super shop, right?
Super market.
Then you will find every single thing
that right.
So now this time.
Now this time we don't have to go
and added jobs manually
And then we come across a problem
that hey, I waited for jobs
or five jobs or six just no one.
We take care of everything and we take
care of every single thing on its own.
All right.
All right, guys. So
the first dependency we have added now.
Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
Do what you have to do is basically
you have to reload your project from
intelligent later from this
or after this,
even if it exist, to simply close your up
intelligent and restarted.
Now here if you said right
it says group ID
and I think that today in this dependency
and you see today's group ID
and I think that remember we also give
group ID here.
Can you see the similarity
VI because it says
which organization it belongs to.
So organization is all two thirds
and in HQ, Right.
Which organization?
Selenium HQ.
This is the organization
and artifact ideas of the project.
So which is the project?
It's a selenium Java, right?
It might be a selenium
Python made this an indium ruby.
Selenium for selenium shell.
Different projects. Right.
So it is giving gifts in Indian Java.
So that's why this is Project Clear.
All we can see.
So when you read the project right
before the project, you must have missed
something in your code base shape that.
All right. So now this is the version
I'm taking, right?
If you change this login, it will give you
the updated login is not issue.
All right.
So now
now, if you'll see, I didn't add.
Just do one thing right.
Just do one thing right
click maven and reload a project.
Do this right.
Click on your file
maven and reload project.
When you click on Reload project,
what it will do after this,
you will see here
inside your external libraries.
It will add all this filename, just
it will add all the selenium jars.
See everyone
without even
adding any doubt,
without even adding any doubt to find
it gives you all the added
all the job here
them all and agree you guys did.
I'm not getting any replies from you, but
great note that I know you need a break
point.
So this is just the one we have.
Correct?
Just one we have.
Now let's talk about the another one.
Tell me, guys,
what else we have added in our framework.
What else?
EDIT When we were working with this
engine with John,
the first is just integer, correct.
So let's take the standard post.
I will go here again, very easy approach.
Right. This
right the same platform supermarket search
the first option
it is giving me test in place subject.
And once everyone is here
please let me know.
Yeah and we will use that
also we will use git commander also.
So now when you click passenger here,
right
when you click on test and here it is
giving you all of these options
synergistic
anyone I'm going to take the most number
downloads 7.1.0.
But it
is copy
this one from seven again
as our dependency
and when you copy from here
simply paste it here.
All right
you came here, Jamal right inside this ten
you selected this 7.1.0.
Okay.
Invited 7.1.0.
Go into this maven tab and from here
then just copy this.
Right.
And then you copy this
based to 40.
And now the next thing is about you
take the Apache boy with you.
So again, we will go here.
Why Apache boy?
That's why we need a bunch of help, right?
To access the files. Right.
We will going to pass their data. Right.
So to read that data,
we need these Apache boy
so that I can read my data
from my Excel flight.
So I'm going to write up
my chip boy, and I will for it
to search for this Apache boy.
And you will see here a bunch of boy.
Right? Let's take the Apache.
Well, I think this one,
if we go, then check the Virgin.
4.1.2.
Find this one.
So guys, from here,
when you get these two options right,
when you get these two options, select
the second one.
Apache point API based on OPC and or X7
females.
Right.
Select this.
And here, let's
see again most number of downloads
I can see 367
So just take this 141.2
and here you will get this boy
or eczema and you get this dependency.
Every one.
Just copy this dependency guys, copy this
and simply paste it here.
So I pasted 31 also
got it.
Every one.
Now, now let's take another one.
I'm going to take four
comments.
I know why we need this comments.
I always
Apache comments I why we need you guys.
Tell me
guys, we need it again.
Again, I'm saying screenshots.
No, we need it again
to deal with the data fights.
All right.
So let me go ahead and take this
most number of downloads, 2414.
This 12.8.0 correct.
Right.
You have to deal with the data files
to deal with what you have to do.
You have to close it.
You have to open it.
All of these things. Correct.
So just take this dependency.
2.8.0 is the virgin.
Copy this
and simply
paste it in your project.
So far we added four deployments. It's
how many of you guys
are done with this?
Everyone is done great.
Now, when you are done with this,
just to implement.
If your external libraries
are not updated,
right click on your symbol.
Going to
go into
seven and reload your project.
When you reload your project, it says
resolving dependencies for our project.
Right?
And now here, if you'll see
if you see it added all your Apache part
right on your comments iReport,
write your test and you pass.
If you open this test and you will see
all of these things by default
without even adding single jar fight,
you have all the dependencies
for all the jars.
Then you you have now this, then you have
now Apache Boy, you have no comments.
I hope you have no correct.
Is it correct?
Only one.
Great. All right.
So before going on a break,
let's consider next understand
the last concept I like
you guys
and I think you guys might think that.
All right.
Even if we have.
Right.
Even if we have this chance
here, right in our project.
Right.
Whatever the jobs
we have available yet in our project.
But still, these jobs, when we see right.
These jobs are available
in my machine or not,
these jobs are available in my machine
only.
Correct.
Currently this is intelligent.
It is available here.
What about web drivers? Chrome, Firefox?
For that I have a very good answer.
Right. I may give you
that concept.
Right.
We are not going to deal with drivers
anymore.
No more dirty
if I no more compatibility issue.
Don't worry about it. Don't give this.
You did
a double sided waiting for the right.
All right.
No more chrome grown driver, dirty XY,
no more Firefox driver, Dirty XY.
No more driver for Uber,
no more pipe related
chrome driver executable does not exist.
Nothing.
Right.
We will see that part also. Don't worry.
Now. Now this is that time.
Don't understand the concept right?
The last concept of before the break.
Yeah, because why did we learn it?
Very important question.
You should learn this
because it is not necessary.
Every time that your client asks you
to create a framework from scratch.
Right?
Or ask you to work only in the frame,
but there might be the requirement,
then you have to work on a simple class.
This video project is so small,
so there you have to pass
the part of your driver in that way.
That's why we gave you that option right?
All right.
So now
now let me tell you
how this things work.
Let's say
let's see.
This is the part which I'm trying
to explain to you here right now.
Okay.
This is my machine, right?
So I am seeing local computer right?
My local machine.
I have my
intelligent yet correct.
And inside of my intelligent, I have one
project
database.
And here I'm having inside my MAVEN
project on the.
Is it correct?
This is the setup I'm telling you
for my local machine. Now,
when I see the tape on symbol,
I need dependencies for selenium.
What it means is I have
never since
I have my own central repository
right.
What we have Maven
since I have one MAVEN central repository.
Right.
When you provide the dependencies
it means what
if from here form is the name,
the dependency and it is taking the jobs.
So for example, policies for selenium,
it will give you one cloud
like this, not cloud
actually it will give you one block
where all the selenium related jobs will
You are sending the request in terms of
dependency.
It is giving you
all the jobs related to your dependency.
Similarly, similarly,
the another one is available
for test engine.
You are sending the request
for dependency.
It is giving you
that jobs of the dependency, right?
That's how it is working. Now.
The most important point
when Mike runs this one vertex
and it will return all the jobs in Mike's
machine
when, when and now runs
it will returns the job
and as machine everyone runs,
everyone get the jobs.
But the main point is by
all the jobs will be stored
in the same location in everyone's
machine.
How? Let me show you when this come right.
They comes here in dart
and all that.
It is automatically generated
for importing everyone so machine
when you deal with this MAVEN project now
let me show you here in my machine also
if you go in my C part
users inside of my users
if you go under my name
you'll see one bottom two folder here.
Can you see
right if you open
it here, it says this is the repository.
If You open the repository, you will see
all of the job files
available here for your project
right? Yes.
Yes. The job to find selected location,
no issues at all
because you are not concerned about local
anything.
Right. You Are not anything dealing.
You're not dealing with anything
which is not local state.
No more problems about the jobs.
No more problems about the location.
Nothing. Everything.
Everything is customizable.
Everything can be done
only via only my MAVEN project.
Right.
So by default, all of the jobs
will be stored at one place.
And then you push this,
go to the repository.
And if someone else will get this code,
it will automatically download
all the jobs in the same project,
work on any of the machine, right?
Without even interpreting
and giving any errors about the dependency
and the locations of John Place clear.
How this MAVEN project wants everyone.
All right.
Okay, guys.
So let's take a break, right,
At least for 15 minutes,
because I need a break now.
All right.
And disconnect after the 15 minutes.
I even also I also made solar energy now.
All right.
So let's take a break for
I think 15 minutes is more than fine.
So now now if you see
we have basic structure
ready with this, Correct?
Just a basic structure
and we have added this
dependency state here
on our base.
Now, when we have added
all the dependencies,
when we have these
dependencies installed in our system,
that is also fine.
Next thing is
we have to understand one thing
when we are dealing
with the automation process,
when we are going to write the code
for the automation, right?
So here are we going to write only code
or we going to write both
Java in Java.
My point is
when we are writing some code, right?
So for example,
we are passing the data, right?
We will pass the data
from some excise file,
we will pass the property
from some by zip file.
We will do all other stuff like this,
passing the locators, other thing.
So some of this code,
some of this code belong to Java.
Some of these files belong to non Java.
I remember yesterday we used
config dot properties file,
right?
So that configured properties
file was a part of like Java
or non java
non java.
Right.
So here when I say we are going to
do everything only with this.
So inside this I have Java, all right.
So I can keep all of my java stuff inside
java.
What about non Java.
Do I have anything.
A non java.
No. Right.
So for non java.
For non dharma
we have to one folder called resources.
What we have to do
we have to add one folder called resources
from there from test.
So to do this simply right click
new and here select this, then
select this then increase from here.
All right.
And when you selected
just to give the name
resources.
All right
now if you see I have Java
and I have resources, right.
I will keep all of my non
Java stuff in resources
and I will keep all of my Java stuff
in Java
clear.
Clear.
So Firebase
Great. Now
tell me one thing.
What was the very first thing
we identified and we implemented yesterday
when it comes to resources
for should, right
when it comes
to creating the framework portion.
So the very first thing is
we will not pass
anything hardcoded, correct? Yes.
So the basic configuration
we need to pass in our framework,
we need to pass it from one place
from which we can pass it.
We can pass it from dot properties file.
So which properties file it is configured
properties fine, because all the portion
related to configuration
will be available in my property.
Correct.
Right. So just do one thing.
Take this configured properties from there
from your previous project,
because if we keep writing those parts
right, creating if you want, we can create
from separate a from as well.
I don't have any issue,
but since we have already done
with this confident properties,
can we take it from
our previous project?
Does everyone have that?
Everyone has this one, this file
config folder configured properties.
Let me show you which one
I'm talking about.
The other people see in this config
right here in this country
you are seeing these configured
properties, correct?
Everyone is doing this, so just copy this,
copy this file.
Right. Come here
in your project.
Okay.
Just Create another directory here called
config.
Yes. No.
Inside this create
one config and inside config.
Right. This content dot properties. Right.
Because today we have one
the properties file for configuration.
The model.
Maybe we will be having multiple
configuration.
Right?
So for multiple configurations
we will be having multiple dot properties.
Right.
So it would be good
if we have one config folder
and inside this config you can simply say
come on, what happened
simply based on your configured
properties.
Right.
Can you see
I haven't considered properties yet.
This is the data
I'm having in my contract properties.
Right
up on
from your previous project.
If you take the pull from my code
right in the repository,
you will get this configured properties
like in your previous
project, the basics of test in great.
You will get that
and then which
which problem.
All right.
So you can do just one thing, right?
Create one folder here.
When you create the folder right click
going to nil, right.
You have to go.
And when you click on file and then write
your config type properties,
when you write configured properties,
it will create this file here
and then simply paste this data.
If you want,
I can paste this to values in your life.
Questions here.
There you go.
So these are the values, right?
These are the values
you write in your configured properties.
Now, is it easy for every one?
And so I'm just right
click on your config folder.
Right click,
go into new select file, right configured
the way I can be configured properties
and then it will be available here.
That data which I shared, you can simply
paste this data inside, this type
and I is
working now.
So as on you have to do it right,
you have to create this folder.
We all have created this folder
just now, guys,
we have created this or not.
All right, great.
Now, now
to read this confident Properties file
here I missed.
Fine.
So inside the resources,
right inside the resources
from your previous project version,
if you go into your previous project,
just copy this configured properties file.
Right And then simply create
one folder name
configured one directory, configure
and then pasted inside this confidence
properties.
Now what it wanted.
All right, thank you,
guys.
So far, everyone reached in this point
now after these to read this file
now see this is what we call
framework distribution
because is my non
java I kept it inside non java
but to read it
to read this particular part
I need java function
or not
we need java function.
So that is java code. Right.
So where there we will right there.
Java code which can read these properties.
Remember we had one class yesterday,
we created one
class called configured property
configurator.
Right.
So configuration Reader.
Yes. Inside of Java we have two right now.
Tell me which package we abused,
which package
we have used to keep that particular file.
This particular configuration
reader class is a part
of which tool
it is a part of which concept.
It is a utility.
Correct.
Exactly where it belongs to utils.
So to create this now
now observing
close nigga is what I'm going to do.
Right click on java nil
and select package this time.
No directly select package.
It says package not any previously
so select package
and inside this package give the name
same units.
This is my package
now now inside utils.
Inside utils.
I had classes yesterday.
What are those two classes?
The first one is common methods.
Alright.
Common.
And what was the second one?
Configuration.
But correct.
All right.
So do you want me to write
every single line of code of config reader
in common methods
or simply can copy these classes
from our previous project
right up to the programs?
That's what I'm asking.
What do you guys think we should copy
from there or we should write
Nobody.
And now what I will do, basically
we will send the code
what we have inside this, right?
And then you can simply create
let's let's do it.
Let's do what I will do, basically,
and I will create this from here.
I will create it from here.
And then the code inside this
I will twist here
and I will send in the chart
also so that you can also best.
Alright, so let's do right click here,
right click new in Java class.
So my first Java class is
Common methods,
correct?
This is my first Java class.
I see common methods
right click and create your common
methods.
Already this now.
Now let's take the content of this common
methods.
Take the content,
this common method from previous class.
So in my project I had this common
method right?
I will copy this code of my common
method from here.
Right.
This is my code.
I'm copying this court from here
and I will paste this code here
as well in our life.
Questions
use this code and
others also wants to use this code
and paste this code here.
Posting
it is giving me the error
for configurator. Why?
Because I didn't use any configurator
so far.
Correct.
Now this is their time.
This is the time to copy the configurator.
So that is my configurator.
This Is my configurator.
Let me open. Right.
And I will simply copy this code
configurator, copy this file
and, pasted it
by now.
Whatever the code
I have inside this configurator,
I am copying this
instinctively
anyways.
So far.
Which point you guys have reached.
I'll wait for this.
Wait for this.
You are going to get on the same point
as you. Great.
Now now open all of you
your common methods every month.
Open the common methods
already
and then you can simply create this class
configurator
and then paste the code
our check right into my questions.
So all the code is available here?
Yeah. Do it.
Really should take your time.
Or I should. What is the error?
Mebane is a builder.
Two years later. Automation.
That's what this category
said.
What is the error?
These two mistakes
you need to check in your configurator
right?
When you're trying to call this redo
the properties and get property value.
White is not coding here.
Property check that
when you go in your configure check.
These are public first thing
whether you are able to access it or not
and your properties is also a static
check.
This part.
If everything is exactly like mine,
then why it is giving you
the error.
All right. On
the property.
Oh, it says rename reference.
I don't see any reason because I'm
just taking this
because see, this method never used.
It isn't great, right?
Gradients never used up.
Nobody is.
You can put this in the support. Right.
And more awesome
is there right to help in that case
and otherwise I will take care of this
after the session quickly
if it
if you can resolve it via dynamic,
you can also dynamic.
No issues.
All right, guys.
So far, everyone on this page.
Now, tell me,
how many of you guys got the error
when you were trying to execute?
You might you might have been trying
to execute your script in selenium
and you were getting the driver
executable does not exist because the path
you provide of your drivers.
Sometimes it is not able to identify
your driver or the exit.
How many of you guys get this error?
Quite
right
guys.
Focus. Focus on this point.
What I'm trying to explain,
this is something very crucial okay,
so I'm just trying to extend
some situation.
Now see in this code
we are going to make some changes now.
First thing stick anything.
Even though
if you're not getting this error,
your browser,
your web driver is right on base now.
Right now, I'm using my conversion.
Let's see,
my conversion right now I'm having is
nine people, right?
And I'm using my chrome driver,
which is compatible to 94.
So currently it is working fine
in case I got automatically update
micro browser to 95 or to 96.
And what if my call driver
is not compatible
to execute my stream with Google driver
Chrome browser 95.
What would happen?
My script will fail
right?
My script will fail.
Right? So that's what it is
I'm trying to explain.
That's what I'm trying to explain.
So now I think a couple of
you guys are busy in writing the code.
So guys, please pay attention here.
Stop writing everything,
because this is something
we are going to discuss,
which is very important.
Okay,
So now in case also your script will fail
if your browser or your driver not exist,
the script will fail.
If you have grown driver or driver
opener driver i.e.
driver, so many driver
file in your project, right?
It will make your code bulkier, right?
It will the size occupy unnecessary space.
What we will do,
we will tell all of these things
to one tool that hey, go ahead.
If I want to execute my script on call,
I'm not going to provide any chrome
driver part.
I'm not going to provide any driver
or taxi.
I'm not going to provide any browser.
You are you are accountable, right?
You are answerable to me.
How you have executed.
You have to execute my script on Chrome,
Firefox, on opera, on eight.
At the same time, I'm not going to give
any composer Adobe XD.
I'm not going to give any driver,
any browser, anything.
Right.
That concept vehicle web
driver manager.
It means work.
Once we add this web driver,
manage it in a framework.
We don't need this fast.
We don't need this anymore.
Okay?
We don't need driver folder anymore.
We don't need this cool driver
or to see anymore.
All right, guys.
So to add Web
driver to manage it in our project.
Right To add this driver manager
in our project, what we have to do is
again, we have to go in our super shop
and you have to write that driver manager
without space, but you have to write
this driver manager without such funding,
the first option you will get
is the driver manager, Bonnie Garcia.
This one,
like, like this we have driver manager
for Bonnie Garcia, right?
This one.
Everyone got this
plus and Slash.
What does it mean?
Yes. Well, all right,
so now I'm going to click on this
this driver manager.
Okay.
The first link, the first thing
you guys have to click here,
Web driver manager.
When you come inside this web driver
manager part right
in this load, Driver manager, you'll see
you have to
again
let's take the most number of downloads
takes three, six, four, 23, 24, 63.
I got 3.8.1 guys you can take you 15.0.3.
It's completely up to you. Right?
You can use anyone since I'm
going with this one because
ranking matters.
Click on it.
Click on it again.
We have to ag dependency
right of this baby driver manager.
Copy it.
Go back to your project.
Go in politics similar
in your dependency.
Add this dependency to simply this
coordinate be one way
driver manage your partner's
again right click on maven
right click Maven
reload project.
So far everyone is done
that.
Now let's come back here.
Come back here.
I'm saying I don't this line.
Let me come in.
Get out
then if I'm seeing I don't need this line.
So who is going to open my chrome
driver then?
This is the question.
So you have to write here
baby Driver manager
Right.
And when you click here, Dot can you see
Chrome Driver Edge Driver
Firefox Driver I'm a driver opener.
Driver Synonym in driver, standalone,
everything right?
So let's say
I'm going to take Chrome Driver
Chrome driver
dot setup.
That's it.
When you say cool driver setup, what web
driver manager will do
it will set up Chrome driver
Dougherty, XY, which is compatible
to your current browser picture
Z compatibility.
It will open the browser
and it will execute your stack.
Similarly,
someone says, If I don't have Firefox
browser yesterday
someone asked, Can I come in this code?
I said, But now today we can try it here.
Simple web Driver manager dot
Firefox Driver dot stick up
and then driver is equals to a new
Firefox driver.
Correct.
No new drivers.
No need for chrome driver
Co-driver Dougherty XY
guy understood
this code.
The yamaha's.
Connect this into chrome driver
don't be talking about
or driver or.
All right. So now your headache is gone.
You don't have to take care
of the part of your.
I think it is. It is having let me check
it sure that this
No it doesn't get somebody
I have age
enhanced Firefox because
it has grown even it has chromium
it doesn't give somebody.
All right.
Yeah.
Maybe in the newer version
you can find it.
All right.
So now let me tell you
one more thing here in the new login,
you don't need to copy this complete part.
Once again, simply go back check,
which is the new version 5.0.3.
Right. This is the new version. Okay.
Go in your symbol write
instead of this 3.8.1 just right.
5.0.3 find
it is giving you this error
order.
The project
and you say guys, here it is upgrading.
Now my appropriate according
to the new wording of web driver correct
state the error is also gone
now. Now
let's go back to my common metrics
this time if I write here, this time
if I write
web driver manager, dog
it, safari
dog, and it
so now next time lets
it new Werdum came in the market
and you want to upgrade.
You don't have to add this group
by default.
Once again, just change the version
and reload your project.
Your will get the updated libraries
every single thing just by changing
these values. Yes.
Got it.
Is there duty is one of the things
that you are learning right now.
I told you so many things on the way.
Now your one problem is going.
Which one? Chrome driver
right now.
Another problem will be gone in
just half an hour.
What is that problem? We didn't
remember
yesterday when I was executing my code
by mistake, I gave the wrong part
of this particular fight
and I was getting null pointer exception
when I was executing the code.
How many of you guys remember?
Right.
Why it is happening?
Because I'm trying to give this thought
manually correct.
I'm trying to give this spot
manually the file path,
but I should not pass anything
hardcoded, right?
I should not pass anything is hard coding.
Then what is the resolution?
What is the alternative?
So this is not the only thing.
This is not the only thing
that we are going to pass.
Like file. But
the path that I want to store
to my screenshot,
the part where I want to pass
my is data from
or sometimes implicit and explicit wait.
So final values see every word
I'm passing this time right?
And then I'm passing this
ten and 20 everywhere.
So I don't need to pass this things.
I want to simply pass one parameter
here, right?
And I will define this new way to
one place because these values are final.
These values are see
your data.
This final or not in the project.
You are not going to change your data.
But again and again, right?
So your data path is final.
You're confident properties
support is final or not in the project.
Tell me this, but final or not
unique?
That's what we were talking about.
Organized structure.
It means
things are not changing their places.
So the part we are defining it one based
these spots are not changeable,
but they are fixed and final.
So I need another class where
I can all these constants.
Then I can keep all of these constants.
Now let's do this.
I'm going to create another class here.
When I say class.
It is a Java code, and the name of my
class I'm going to create is
Constants.
This is my class, Correct.
Now tell me is the constant
I want to utilize.
I want to use this constant spot
throughout my project.
So which access modifier I have to use
public?
Let's make it's technique.
Now I'm saying
my path is not going to change, right?
My path is not going to change.
So When I say my path is not going
to change, it means I have to make it
find it
and what data type
I would be having when I received my.
But let's define path or any other part.
What did I say?
Screen
I'm writing string.
So the very first part,
the very first one is my disk
configuration file path, right?
The path of my configuration file.
So to keep everything which are constants,
I always write the always write in caps.
So I'm going to write configuration
file path
correct.
All right.
Now from here, I'm
going to copy this thought right?
I'm going to copy this path.
And I've been here since this is my string
I'm going to paste to click this connect
and connect. Yes.
By it is not correct subject.
Fine.
Make me do one thing then let me copy
the path from here.
This is my path right?
I will go ahead and constants and
then I will paste the path of my new idea.
This now, is this correct?
Yeah. All we are going to do this
now. Still we are passing
hardcoded data, right?
This is the part of my local machine.
When it works for other machines.
Tell me no right then.
One way to do it is this.
See, you can provide the path
like this
right
inside to my It's not a C folder
because this is my project hierarchy
and inside my project hierarchy
I'm going to get this spot correct.
This is one part. Now.
Now what I'm going to do is see,
let me take my previous project
just for one thing,
I want to show you something from here.
Let me take any class
just to execute my code.
Let me take this particular class
here.
I'm going to write I'm going to write
one thing
there to remove this part
right?
There is a command called
System Dark
Gate property, right?
What I'm writing here is system
dark gate property.
When I use this command system,
guarded property,
I can get so many properties off my system
and so many other things, for example,
which operating system I'm using, right?
So I can write here or s dart name,
see this
system dart gate property
and owns dart name when I use it,
when I run this code, you will see that
it is giving me Windows ten.
Can you see here is
it gives me Windows ten.
This is my current operating system.
Correct
guys can see
similarly
similarly if I want to check
my user name right,
so this property will retain the user
name, right?
Right.
Now where I'm using this code,
where I'm executing this code
with which user I'm using this.
So see,
it will give me the user name also, right?
Can you see it gives me the user name,
my name, correct.
It is here guys.
Similarly, similarly,
when I write this command user
derby, I are user D r.
It provides me the path
of my current project in this point.
It gives me the plot user directly.
It shows explains that in which directory
you are executing your part, in
which directory you have your RC folders
and other structure.
So when I execute code,
see this
is something new you're learning now.
This dev driver manager
constraints and everything.
It is a part of framework
You'll see here
it says it returns the part.
Right? Which path is this?
There is this thought is this one
You'll see users my name workspace
and then project name user's
my name, workspace and project name.
Correct
Now now just copy this,
copy this right now going our project.
This is our project, right?
We come here in our project.
In our project.
Let's do this
right.
What are we going to do here
in our project?
Is we will write
this code.
Now I am creating a range relating how
does any matter
which project, which system,
which directly you are using,
because these is the part, right?
This structure is fine.
Remember their definition of framework.
This structure is final.
No one is going to change this spot.
Right inside is RC, inside is RC.
Everything is same.
Inside resources everything is same.
The only thing change is this location
of the project in every other machine.
So now we made it common for everyone.
It doesn't matter whether you're studying
it in desktop or in users
or in downloads or in workspace
or in ideal projects or anywhere.
It will return that board
for all the system.
And since this part is constant
for everyone, so every every time
this board will work
in every single machine,
correct?
Correct.
But if someone is not following
the framework
standard rate, he
or she will not be able to
commit the code in the repository
otherwise everyone's code will break
up underneath.
When we decide,
when we define some variables
which are final
values are not going to change.
Right.
Those variables
will define this by encapsulate.
All right, guys, does it make sense?
The post word.
Now let's take the second one. Right.
I'm going to make it for the exit public
static final.
And I'm thinking for my for my
implicit and let's see,
I'm going to make it
finally, 10 seconds for every single one.
Right?
I will tell you similarly, right.
For right now,
let's take it for implicit quickly now.
Now, just two changes
we are going to make right
in our common methods.
If I go in the common methods,
we you think we need to parse
this data this time, you and me
not deleted
what we need to write.
We need to write your constants
dot can you see
it is giving configuration
file path click a configuration point.
But now,
now come here.
It asked for 10 seconds. Right?
I don't want to parse this time here
I will write
constants dot
implicitly
correct.
Right. Can you see this code?
This particular piece of code?
Isn't it very simple and straightforward
than ever before?
The browser name is coming
from configuring
configuration file,
but this coming from constants.
You are reading the properties
from somewhere.
You are getting the keys
from your configuration properties file.
You're passing the keys Web Driver
Manager is the handling or the execution
field browsers for all the browsers,
not only just one browser.
You're this configuration file part
the mix
your project makes your framework platform
independent
right At the same time you are passing
even the time, right?
The integer values you are passing from
bit from your constants.
All right.
I'm glad.
I'm glad that you guys found it helpful.
So far, so good.
Guys, Everyone.
Does it make sense?
Bring.
All right.
Like I told you so many things on the way.
Still, since
so many things on the way.
All right.
Can we say 1014 today?
No, no, I'm just kidding.
And they don't worry.
Don't worry.
I'm not going to take care of this
much of time.
I can totally understand.
Yes. Short of financial,
this is your constants.
All right.
So for now,
guys, still, we are just starting
right?
It's still we are just starting
with the framework creation rate,
because these things
are one, the starting one hour
on this data driven concept.
Right.
We have spent our one hour on day five.
That's why we are not able
to complete every single thing
what we were supposed to complete.
Right.
But yes, in Tuesday's class,
I will try to cover
the remaining topics of today.
And then New for Tuesday.
Okay.
Now, the important point here, right?
I'm not going to add anything
new from here.
We will add all of this
things from that point.
Don't worry about it.
We will do it on my on Tuesday.
Right now, the important thing
which we are going to do,
what is an important thing.
Can somebody tell me
first you need this code.
Go ahead.
Whatever the code I have written here,
you all need it.
So let's commit this code, create
a new repository and then committed there.
Yes. GitHub setup.
So let's go ahead and do it
right.
I'm going to create a new repository
from here
and my new repository is
based in
framework
Bash team.
Correct.
All right, Node, I'm waiting.
But for what?
I mean, no, no, no. You don't have to.
You don't have to waste.
I am going to commit to my record.
I'm just showing you how
you can create your repository as well.
All all right.
That's what I'm showing you,
how you can create your own repository
and how you can commit to your code.
Anyways.
You will be
you will be having this application site
on how to create the repository.
And there
you will see how to handle this part.
Okay,
so creating this repository name, right?
So this is the repository name.
This is my repository here.
I will keep all of my code.
Remember I used to commit the code
and then use use
to take the pull of code
straight from the repository.
That repository also we had,
we have made like this.
All right.
So now I'm showing you how
we can make the repository
and how we can integrate this repository
and you can use the same repository
using intelligently.
You don't have go and use it
even though if you want
you can use command prompt as well, right?
CMT But on our terminal as well
for Mac users.
But if you to use directly
from your intelligent
then also you can use this
so I'm going to make it public
so that everyone can access.
You can see here anyone on the internet
see this repository
you choose or can commit.
All right,
I'm simply clicking on the repository.
When I create repository,
it is giving me that you are right,
which I generally share
with every one of you.
This is the repository you are in.
You can access it
and you can take the code.
It says create a new repository
on the command line.
So these are the commands.
So you have to take care of.
Like I say in your decisions,
you will get the details right of it.
You will learn how you can use this from
the command, from the from the terminal.
Now, I just copied this part from copy.
You already copied this.
Now, if I go in my project,
all right, if I go in my intelligence here
on my intelligence,
you will see I will show you guys how
we can use it from command prompt as well.
Don't worry.
Right
next time, when we will commit this code,
we will commit from the command from.
Don't worry. Right.
So from here. From here.
Can you see this vicious?
How many of you guys can see this
see option?
All right, Mike,
let's see why you're not getting it.
I'm going to click Enable Control
integration.
This part, right?
I'm going to click here
and enable Virgin Control integration
of node step.
Right
now, I'm going to commit the code, right?
So you have to take the code.
Once you commit
your code in the repository, right,
then you will get all of these things.
Now this is virgin control system.
They run tools and after tools
you will see this
because you already have gate,
you already have gate.
So you guys select on, you already have
good there.
Now click okay.
When I select right, I click okay.
It gives me this option.
Now tell me how many of you guys
can see this get option?
How many of you guys can see this
option now?
Everyone. Right.
All right.
Point go in two weeks on the vehicle,
select the first option right.
Enable integration, Virgin control
integration, select the gate
and click okay.
And then you will see this
get option here.
Remember, guys, I'm showing you right now
how we can commit our code
and how we can integrate
out of virgin control out of gate
via using IDG that is intelligent.
You can do the same thing for command
from as well.
It gives you more power
when you use command.
All right. So I will show you that.
But also how we can commit our code via
using command.
Okay.
Everyone is getting this option gig now.
The next gig I need ask for manage
reports.
Okay.
I'm just select on this manage remote.
I'm going to get it
and it gives you this plus sign.
Right?
When you select this, let's sign
it will ask for the
You want it Now remember I copied this.
You are in from here.
This the you want to write?
I copied this you are in.
I will go and simply paste this
You are in here correct?
Right is understandable.
So what I'm doing click on get manage
reports then click click click on this
plus sign.
Enter the you are in and then click.
Okay. And you see this.
You are in here.
We're due.
I'm trying to integrate this
with my project
because I'm going to commit this code.
Right?
I will give you this.
You are in so you can update the code.
You can get the updated version
of the code, right.
If you also commit the code in this
repository, there will be a conflict,
right.
I will give you this.
You can use it to get the pull of the code
the way you guys are taking the code
from my previous repositories.
Right.
You can take it from get as one click.
Okay, fine
guys.
So far is it fine. Yes.
Correct. Correct.
You will use this repository
after your good session
when you will be working on your project.
Right.
You will use your own repository
that you have to manage your remote
and you have to do everything
the way I'm doing right now.
Okay.
All right.
So now if you see I'm
having these three options, wait
to take the updated code from the project,
from the repository to commit the code
and to push the code.
Remember, before pushing the code to the
repository, first we have to commit.
Commit means transfer your code
from local machine to your depository.
Right.
So first you commit and the moment you
push it, it will go into your repository.
So first I'm going to commit this code
exist.
Just select all the checkboxes
so it will get all of the files there.
Right. And commit a message.
So I'm saying
the latest code.
October 18
2021 Right.
This must be the commit the message.
So this is the standard message
because every day you commit your code
and whenever you commit your right every
single day before leaving the office,
you commit your code to the repository.
This is the procedure, guys.
Never, ever keep your code on to the local
machine before leaving office.
Always commit your code
into the repository, getting it.
Everyone
code.
What if your system gets crashed
in the night?
Every data, every single code lost.
Right.
So that's why you should keep everything
in the repository? Yes.
Like yes.
Correct.
I will see my that I will
I will look into this.
Why it is why is it happy now?
Now you'll see all of these files
I've mentioned latest
quarter message
and simply I'm committing this coming
the moment I can make it.
So two files contain problems, right?
No errors and three warnings.
Fine, because no errors.
I can commit to my code.
You will see one message here.
It says ten files completed right?
Yes, it is fine. It is fine. No issues.
It says ten points committed right
now after committing What is the next.
Come on, we have to after commit.
We have to
push, right?
We have to push our code
to the repository.
So from here this is the option.
See, it's this push
and the short key is control shift key
Mac users
command shift key or option shift key.
Right. Command shift.
Basically click here on PUSH
and it says from master to origin Master,
you will push your command.
Right now, all this project structure,
this project you will get when you push it
right, when you push it again,
you will get successful message here.
I'm going to use token
because it will ask for the token.
So I my token available here.
I focus on this.
This is my token.
So I will tell you
how to get this token right
by forces because
the second
point but this is the same one
I have it already.
It says the token is wrong,
but I've deleted this token.
Let me take this token from here
once again
by going inside settings.
So no, it is incorrect.
This is not the correct one.
And comics is someone has changed.
No, no, no. It's not working.
There a problem?
Yes, someone has updated already, guys.
So I will update this code. Right.
I mean I'm updated
the code and communicate as well.
It is just
we need to check the credentials because
someone has changed his credentials.
So we have to check the authorization.
And once I get this token, I will update.
It's okay.
I will push discord
in the repository for sure.
All right.
Because it was working
and I don't know what happened.
Now someone has updated the password
again.
It will ask for this.
Let me copy one more time.
No, Someone has changed
to define nowadays.
So there is so far this code, right?
Whatever the code we have written.
Do you guys have any question
in this code?
All right.
Was it understandable for everyone, guys,
to this session
session?
All right, great.
Guys. I think I'm done from my previous
session. Thank you so much for that.