See. Can you guys hear me?
Hey, guys, What's up?
Are you.
Let's see who's here.
Who is here?
Who made it to what is it?
The third week.
What's up, guys?
What is. Has everyone.
How is your day?
You know.
Did you work today? Was it.
Was it a stressful day?
Work. Work
good this year.
Oh, physical therapy.
Are you injured, Martin?
Well, let's see.
Ruptured third lumbar.
Lumbar. Wow.
So. I wish you a speedy recovery
to work.
Guys, what is this, The third week, right.
Your third week?
Is that what it is?
Are you sure, or is it your fourth week?
The third
Masters.
Last called to drop It is to my last.
Last call to get your money back.
Right.
Starting September 25, 25th.
What?
Today?
I think that's awesome, Guys, that.
That.
Dude, it's about to be the fourth week.
Time flies.
There's only, like,
what, five months left to the course
that Jean says he believes is the third.
I think. I think Eugene is right.
I think you guys are right.
Maybe it is the third week.
Alex?
Yeah, I got your.
I got your assignment. Yep.
Got your assignment.
Thanks.
Thanks. Dex.
Logically,
I know we have five months left,
but it feels like
it is still another six months.
I. Let's just say
it's going to be a rough time.
You know, you're going to have some.
Some tough holidays for sure,
but it's all for the greater good, right?
It's all for the greater good.
Remember, guys, remember,
winning is a decision made before trying
to you remember that
you committed to it.
You chose this, you stick to it,
you follow through.
All right?
You follow through.
No matter how hard it's going to be,
what hurdles
you may have,
you're going to stick to it, right?
You guys are going to stick to it.
You guys are going to prove yourselves
right.
You're going to find it, you
know, inside you to to keep to keep up.
You you owe it to yourself, right?
You owe it to yourself to be great, Right?
Am I right or am I right?
You have nothing to prove to anyone
but yourself.
You want to be great or not?
It's up to you.
No one can force you to be great.
It's. That's up to you.
That is up to you.
Lennie says we try.
Will. Trying is all you to do.
Right? Trying.
That's all you can do.
Okay, cool, cool, cool.
So let's say 705.
Let's give a couple more minutes to some.
Some folks like to to join late
because they got better things to do.
I'm kidding. I'm kidding.
Some people have important things to do.
That's another class too.
So let's see.
All right.
Menu. Class three.
Of course. Of course. Of course.
Guys, I didn't share my notes with the
yesterday right, that I read, did I not?
I don't think I did.
Jeez.
Terrible, Terrible.
Instructor,
I got some of your messages from
you guys were saying you don't teach good.
You know, this and that.
You know, you're the worst teacher.
And I'm just like, okay,
thanks for sharing
your opinion to.
All right, so here are the notes.
Okay.
Here are the notes from yesterday's class.
I'm going to send them.
I'm going to send them in.
I'm going to I'm going to send them
in the course.
That's what I'm going to take everyone.
Of course, notes,
just a little music here.
The good. It's
okay.
And again, one more thing, guys.
This look, these are high level
notes, right?
So they're not complete sentences.
Okay?
And I kind of already talked about this
before we even started all of this.
You know, I told you guys
that I'm going to write these notes down,
but the rest I'll be saying during class,
because I kind of need you
to write your own notes on it if you can,
you know, And do you guys know how to
see? We sit
down and see if I'm saying the right thing
to you
once again while I send this
to the class to and
that is notes dear
senior notes.
And of course announcements
occur in course announcements, guys,
and of course announcements.
And there you go.
Kind of.
All right.
So go ahead. And course announcements.
Those were the notes from yesterday.
Keep them.
I told you guys that
for the rest of the notes.
Right.
You should be taking you guys know
how to take notes down like you guys know.
What's the
that you guys know what's what's the
like the best strategy to take notes down?
No, I mean,
it doesn't matter what you use.
If you use notepad,
you can use pen, paper or whatever.
You guys know what, what, what it is.
Eugene It's
nice, right? So one was nice. Yeah.
The best way to
take notes, Don, is when you hear someone
speak, okay?
Yes, I sure.
I say, you know what?
You ready for the market? Right?
You are ready for the market.
I shot Florida.
I said Florida. Yes.
Keywords, red
keywords, keywords, keywords, keywords.
Keywords means you're not writing
full sentences because it's really hard
to write a full sentence after
someone says a full sentence, write you.
You're not that no one is that fast.
So you write keywords, not you.
You hear something, okay, you'll see.
Okay, keywords.
This many faces, these faces, bam.
That's it, right?
And that's it.
But keywords, keywords, keywords.
All right, so manual testing, Class three.
All right.
So now that you guys
are officially testers,
you guys know how to write test cases.
You guys know about SDLC,
you know about the software testing
lifecycle, you know the software
development lifecycle.
Tell me, what did we learn yesterday?
What did we learn yesterday?
Some things that come, come.
So very good, right?
Good.
Again,
so I'm going to say cucumber scenarios.
Cucumber scenarios, right.
We learned.
Oh, let's not write
then what is very good?
What is good?
Good, What is
good?
It's a syntax.
That's plain English text, right?
Yes, very good.
Right.
That's okay. Very good.
Take a smart, intelligent, wonderful.
All right.
What else did we learn yesterday?
Okay, let's learn about gherkin
keywords, red
gherkin, keywords, right. And so on.
Nobody said it.
We have given, we have given
one then.
Okay.
And what else can we use,
Right.
What do we say
you can use and, and we can use but.
Right.
Can you tell me something about
these keywords like just one thing,
like how do we have to write them,
How do we have to write them?
Very good. Right?
First letter is
capital.
It's capitalized.
So that makes sense. Okay, that's complex.
So what is Gherkin
given one than what is given what is?
When we say given Mike,
we'll get there tomorrow.
Thanks for that.
That's the next point.
But let's take a few steps back.
What is given
given is what when you usually use
given key word you're writing,
what's the precondition? Right.
Very good. Very good. Very good.
What about when
we're about one?
Okay.
One is where you specify in action.
Right.
And then as what
looks
very good, wonderful, put wonderfully.
But these are the rules. Right.
But what do we say about rules?
Once you know the rules, then what?
You can break them. Yes.
And what is the whole point of writing
like?
Well, what is the main goal of writing
a cucumber scenario like your main goal?
What is the main goal?
When you write?
One of writing
is to make it make sense. Yes.
Very good. Right?
They need to make sense.
Okay.
So when you write it down, right when
you write it down, read it to yourself.
Right.
Read it to yourself and ask yourself
if it makes sense.
And then once you read it to yourself,
then as someone else say, can you
can you read this?
Can you understand it? Right?
And they say, Yes.
Then you're good to go, right?
Does that make sense?
And for my fellow,
my fellow folks here
that are in different countries
where English is not your first,
your first language,
that's completely okay.
That is no problem.
As long as you try.
That's okay, right?
As long as you try. It's all good.
All right,
cool.
Okay.
So someone said to me, What is that?
You said,
Oh, is it better to write them in?
First person First person or third person?
Third person. Right, exactly.
Third person.
I'm going to say it's recommended, right?
For best practice.
It doesn't mean
you have to have to have to write.
First person is used, but it always.
What is the goal of BDD?
What does BDD stand for?
By the way, was that for.
Yes, very good.
That's right.
You see, we're
the again.
And what is what are what is the goal
when we're writing to cover scenarios.
Right.
What what is a goal?
You remember
we use BDD to describe
business tool to write
what our business rules.
Yes, very good.
Jamie, what are our business rules?
What are business requirements?
Requirements.
Right. And what did you say?
Yeah.
Describes to be here
the user will take on an application.
So how will the user use the application?
That's how you read the scenario.
Does that make sense?
Right.
How will the user use if you are
if Sharif if Sharif is the user.
So how will Sharif use the application?
Okay.
Given the user is on this page
and the user navigates here
and the user, you know that you go back
to, does that make sense?
Is that clear?
Does anyone have any questions?
And this is, you know, you guys did
very good yesterday, by the way.
We're going to do more of it today.
We're going to you're going to do like
a lot of it throughout the whole class.
Okay,
cool.
You're going to learn a lot.
So one thing you want to look out for
is, is I'm going to I'm going to type
an example.
It's going to be an example.
And I want you to correct me.
I want you to correct.
Okay, cool.
I want you to correct me.
All right.
And hold on. Don't start yet.
I'll tell you what to go.
So don't type anything yet.
That's
okay.
Okay.
Good.
So anything you
and funny thing is
that a few of you send the same scenario.
So I don't know what you guys are like
in a dream team or something,
but some of you guys
sent the same scenario, right?
So here we go again.
This is an example
given a user is on the syntax website.
Okay. All right.
Are you going to give this stuff
a thumbs up or thumbs up?
Someone says, we can simplify that. Okay.
All right. Can I tell you what I think?
Can I tell you what I think?
Right.
Given the users on the syntax website,
what syntax
website.
Right.
What syntax website.
Right. So let's fix this. Right.
Given the users on the syntax,
even the users on the syntax
and the what is name of the application,
it must write
given to users on the syntax HMS website.
We always want to capitalize the first
letter of of of the name of a page.
Right.
So instead of locate lowercase s,
I'm going to change it to capitalize this.
Right.
So given a user is on the syntax
HMS website, right,
you can say website,
you can say applications.
Right now it's much better. Right now.
We know what
we know,
you know, and if you want to
use the website, we can add it.
We can only use that.
We know without that, you know,
I was going to make a sub syntax.
I got into syntax,
I forgot what the URL was.
I'm stuck on that. Cool.
You can add it here. No,
you don't have to.
You don't have to.
You don't have to do that.
You don't have to go
right.
But you
can't. There's nothing wrong with it.
You can see absolutely nothing wrong.
Does this make sense?
I'm going to go ahead and delete it
so it makes sense now, right?
Thumbs up.
Very plain and simple.
We made those two corrections, right?
We specified the website
and we changed this lowercase s
right to have capitalized s y
because it's the name of a page.
Right.
And you always capitalize
the first letter red
when you write your name down,
you say, Hey, my name is Marvin.
Like this.
Or the you say, Hey,
my name is Marvin with the capitalized
right, How do you do it?
Capitalize on it.
So same thing applies to pages.
All right.
Let's go to the next
let's go to the next step.
When users are on the HMS Home page
game, they should be
able to enter the username
when users
are on the web,
when users should be able to enter
the username.
Let's see,
you don't need the first part. Hmm.
Well, can I.
Can I
can I just tell me what I think?
I go.
All right.
Right. So
given the user is on the syntax
HMS website, so
and now I said this is thumbs up.
Right?
But now reading this and and we're
analyzing here, we're analyzing together
because you guys are also going to be test
analysts, right?
So we are going to analyze this scenario
again
when users are in the syntax or I mean,
it doesn't even say syntax,
it just has a charm as home page.
Right.
Well, the thing is,
if I want to use the word home page here,
why don't I just go back to the first step
and say,
given any users and the syntax mess
page right, this makes sense right now.
I specifically narrowed
that down the website
to home page, right when user and not now.
Check this out.
Now check this out
when users are on the home page,
but they're already on the home page,
so this sounds redundant, right?
It sounds like
we're repeating the first step.
Right?
So that makes sense.
So let's get rid of this.
Yeah, let just remove it. It's redundant.
You guys. See what I'm saying, though?
It's redundant. Like, we're like.
We know we're already there.
We're seeing it again, right?
So let's get rid of it again.
They should be able to enter the username.
Okay, let's say
let's, let's change this.
Let's, let's change this to and.
Okay. Jimmy That's very good, Jimmy.
That is very good.
But we're going to build off of this
what we have right?
How about this?
So, okay
I don't
want so I said with cucumber scenarios
you can use should
the word should right with test cases
you're allowed to use that.
But I forgot to mention yesterday
that the word should should only be used
with the then clause with cucumber again.
Okay.
Like then the user should be loved it.
Right?
Does that make sense?
Does that make sense with everyone? Yes.
With the validation.
Then we can use that.
Okay, so
I'm going to delete this part
and says and enters
the username and where
Nick Nikolai, you're you are correct.
You are correct.
Nikolai Very good job,
but we're just making this one better.
Okay? Nicola
We're just working on this one.
You are 100% correct.
Okay, let's just work on this.
Pretend that we have this.
I work
and we need to make some adjustments.
But Nicola, that.
That is very good. You are not wrong, but
so and enters username
into into the username textbox.
Right into the username textbox
username field.
So what if I said okay, I'm
going to give you an example TextBox.
Right.
And user
should be able to enter the password.
So we're going to delete this part.
Okay?
And enters the password
into the password field.
Okay, What's, what's wrong?
So we use the word should in cucumber.
Yes. Anthony But you always want
to use them with the then clause.
Okay.
With the done now with and now with given.
Cool. So what, what is what is.
Just give me like
you're doing a test case review.
What's up with this
connect clarify the HMS website log in.
Is it okay to say username.
I don't understand the question.
The HMS website log in.
Yes Anna That's right.
Christine 100% correct.
They understood this, right.
There's inconsistency in these two steps.
In the first step,
you use your same textbox.
In the second step,
you're seeing fields, right?
Stick to one, you pick one,
you stick to it.
Right?
So we're going to take the textbox
because we already had that right.
So given a user users on a syntax
HMS homepage that enters the username
into the user textbox and enters
a password into the password textbox
and click log in clicks,
write login button.
Is this how login is?
Well, first of all,
they did good at putting this
the name of the button into quotations.
Right?
They did this very good.
Okay. Right.
And actually for Hot brings a good point.
Like what about the quotations for this?
And I'm sure you're talking about the
the name of the passwords, right.
The password that we're talking about,
we can put it in quotations.
That's fine.
But see,
where is that?
What's a let's see. It's right here. It
will see.
Oh, by the way, the URL, please
go see black market,
because you're going to use it
for the rest of the class.
But here it is again.
So Farhad is saying
that we should put those
we should indicate the names
of those fields and hues.
Right.
So enters the username into
the username textbox.
Okay, so that spelled username
with the capitalized you.
So we're going to come back here,
we're going to change this to capitalized.
You know,
we're going to put it in quotations
and the next one is called password.
Okay, you guys, you are one with this.
Very, very good.
Very good.
Farhad Good job and clicks login button.
Right?
So we know that there's one login button,
but what is the name of the but actually
it's log in, it's one word
and it's all capitalized.
Right.
Very, very good.
So I'm going to say login button.
Are we clicking
log in one with valid credentials?
Are we just clicking log in button?
How do you click a button
with valid credentials
so it doesn't make sense, right?
You can only just click a button.
Does that make sense?
Right.
So and clicks logging button right.
Then the user should be logged in.
Okay,
that is fine.
Okay, cool.
That is fine.
Does that make sense?
So we went from the first scenario
that we had and we fixed it.
We made it much better.
Now can you write it?
You cannot click enter.
How can you click enter?
A lot of you guys said in your test cases
that you guys would set,
you guys would press enter right
when clicks log in? No.
What do you mean?
Yeah.
Irina here you can actually use went
right one,
you can use one and it'll make sense
but Oh and here's a good example.
Look.
So Irina is like, Hey,
can we use web for this?
Right.
The question is the answer is yes.
And I want you guys to understand
this, Right.
Everyone pay attention.
First of all, does everyone know
you don't have to use all three?
Remember, Marianne, what we said?
If you know the rules,
then you know the rules, right?
That you could break them, Right?
The whole point is for you to make
it make sense. Right?
But Irina brought up a good point.
She said, Hey, can we use
when in this statement,
okay, look, everyone
pay attention to cute to this, okay?
The very close attention to this.
Again, it's like we're writing.
It's like we're
speaking in English. Right.
And you
can compare this to any other language.
I just don't know how to give you
examples, like in Russian or Ukrainian or
whatever language you may speak,
But I want you to pay attention to this.
Okay?
Look, given a user
is on this syntax, HMS Home page, right?
And when we're using and it's
a continuation
of the previous step, right.
So with this and we don't have to say
and the user enters the username password
in the title right now
we don't, we don't need to specify
and the user any more.
Right.
And enters a password
into opposite textbox and clicks log in.
But if you want to use one right,
you have to do this one
and then you have to specify the user.
Again.
When the user clicks logging button,
then the user should be logged in.
Does that
make sense?
Does that make sense or.
Well, plain and simple.
Okay, just keep it nice and simple
if you want to remember right.
If you want to make a short,
just use end right
when you use and you don't have to say
and the user, right.
You just continue
from the last step. Right.
And we've already declared the user here
with this step right now
when you want to use
when or when you want to use, then right
then you specify the user again.
Does that make sense, guys?
Does that make sense?
Now, the cool thing was I was reading
a lot of your comments, right?
How about present tense and last one?
What do you mean, present tense?
What would it be?
But that is the expected result and
that is actually what we're looking for.
That is
actually so it actually makes sense.
That's why
it actually makes sense.
Can we use when for second step?
Yes, you can.
You can.
But you have to specify the user,
right, for hot.
So you have to say when the user enters
the username and the username textbox
and enters.
Right, you can make it make sense. Read.
Another thing is okay,
but is this making sense to everyone?
And the really cool thing was that
a lot of you guys would give me answers
right now that are not incorrect.
Okay.
If you can, Gerald, you can ask
if you can
and if it makes sense, then you can count.
It definitely can. Cool.
Okay.
Now, a lot of you guys were giving answers
that make sense
that that actually would work.
And I want to talk about one like this.
So this is the scenario that we had.
We simplified it, right?
We made it make sense.
Nods clear, right.
It makes more sense.
Which way is preferred? Way for Madison?
Cucumber of creating a spreadsheet,
you mean which way is preferred
for like either writing
the classic mail test cases or cucumber
scenarios?
I think if you asked me this is easier,
right?
You don't have to go through the whole
hassle of like,
you know, our task,
which is cut more today.
A lot of types are be used. But
but cucumber is is very popular
is cucumber is very popular.
Okay.
All right.
So okay, so let's
now now we fixed this very good
job, guys. Run!
APPLAUSE, Run! APPLAUSE.
You guys are smart.
Okay,
I'm going to tell you what. This is it.
This is the best batch we've ever had.
All right, So the thing is now, right?
Let's make this scenario, guys, as a team.
Let's grab this scenario
and let's simplify it.
Okay?
To make it easier. Okay.
What is cucumber?
Once again, please?
Okay,
so let's grab this scenario.
Let's
let's simplify it.
Cool.
My words. It's okay.
You can read the notes that I sent
you guys.
It'll help you out.
Can we use press enter button swimming
keyboard?
No, you don't want to use that.
You don't want to.
You don't want to use it
unless the acceptance
criteria says that the user should
that that function should work.
If one presses the interval, get
by default,
everything should be done by clicking
cool.
Like, you know, when you're filling
a form, whenever you're filling a form,
you can actually press the tab button
to go to the next to the next field.
Right?
Right.
These are
what we call keyboard operations, right?
You can when you hit tab,
it goes to the next,
it goes to the next to the next field.
Right.
If you had into a on windows
or you had return on a mac
that sometimes will like submit
a form or process something.
Right.
We don't we don't use that.
We don't use that
unless the acceptance criteria
specifically specifies, hey, you have to
you have to be able to do this
and the user should be able to log
in by pressing enter
when entering the password.
Okay.
We don't
necessarily test those keyboard operations
unless those are business requirements.
By default,
a website can allow that to happen.
Does it need to make sense?
It needs to make sense to everyone, the
business analysts, actually to their work.
We had to share all of our cucumber
scenarios with our client
because they're going to do the testing.
Right.
And we had to share the cucumber
scenarios.
12 of them with all of them.
So how bad would it look if they read it?
And it doesn't make sense, right?
They're going to start to think
a few things.
They're going to be like, wait a minute,
they're writing their scenarios like this.
It doesn't make sense.
So how are they testing? Right?
That's that is the
the number one question, the number one
thought that will come to their head.
Right.
Whether you write
the manual classic test cases.
Right.
Or you write a cucumber scenario
that doesn't make sense
to them, the first thing they're going
to think about is, wait a minute,
how are they testing this scenario?
Doesn't make sense.
This is the test case
that they have to follow,
but it doesn't make sense.
So how are they testing?
You know, like you know what I mean?
So is that is
that is everyone understanding that
everyone understand where I'm trying to
right now?
You don't need to stay away
from certain terminology.
What I'm saying is that
if you're writing scenarios
that don't make sense
and then you show them
to the rest of the team. Right.
And when they read them
and it doesn't make sense.
That is going to be a big concern
because you need to show what you are
testing through documentation.
Right.
And these you will be writing
any document, either zero or
something like that.
You will be writing,
but this is going to be documented.
Okay.
Does that make sense to everyone? Right.
So what you're testing is going
needs to be documented.
You can't just say, yeah, I tested this.
It works, right?
It needs to be documented somewhere.
It needs to be documented.
In this case, we're creating
the testing areas of Cucumber Center.
So the test cases,
they need to make sense.
Okay,
but does everyone understand that concept?
Like if this isn't making sense,
is there someone checking
the test cases after that, doesn't it?
Yes, I was going to talk about that now.
So in our project right in my project.
So I didn't tell you this, but
I'm currently a tour manager.
I lead the automation development
for over 30 applications
within the National Institutes of Health.
Right.
And I oversee different teams
of about 30 testers.
Right.
So we can
we have weekly test case reviews.
We conduct weekly test case reviews
to make sure that test cases
that we're writing make sense.
Okay.
Because you remember when I told you
that these were going to manually
write them, right?
We're going to manually write them.
And then once they're ready to automate,
we literally just copy
and paste it into our job of coding
that you will learn later.
But the thing is that
if this is a poorly written scenario
and then we automate this scenario, then
our automation is going to be poor.
Does that make sense?
Our automated
test cases reflect our manual test cases,
and we have a poorly written
manual test case or cucumber scenario.
Then that means your automation
is going to be poor.
Okay, does that make sense, guys?
Does that make sense to everyone?
Okay, cool.
Right.
So, yes, to answer your question is yes,
we have test case reviews
and your project, if it's organized,
they will have test case reviews
because at the end of the day, yes,
sure, you're going to be writing these,
but you're all the team
at the end of the day.
And you guys need to make sure
that you guys are presenting yourselves
well to the client.
Okay, cool.
Okay.
So do we have any more questions
on these cucumbers and errors before
we simplify it?
Okay, so we can write the last two.
Okay, so let's simplify it.
Okay, We have one, two,
three, four, five, five steps.
Okay, Let's stick to this one. Right.
Given a user's on the syntax
h mess homepage
for going to say simplified.
Simplified.
Okay.
It's going to be like this.
Right? Cool.
Okay, what else?
And I saw Jeremy send that somewhere.
I was just responding to something else.
Right? And I saw some of us on the right.
So what was what can be my second step?
What can be my second step?
Ahmed says when the user logs
in with valid credentials.
Yes, right.
That is true.
Jeremy also said the same thing.
I believe so.
I'm going to copy this.
Okay.
When the user logs in with
valid credentials, right,
then the user should be logged in right?
You see this?
Does this make sense?
It perfectly makes sense, right?
When you are entering the username
and the username textbox and you're
entering the password into the password
textbox in your clicking log.
And what does all you're doing here
is logging in right?
That's all you're doing, right?
So we can simplify this even more
and say when the user logs
in with valid credentials,
if it's too long for you,
then then you can even simplify
it even more.
We want.
But it is perfect.
Yeah, this is good.
Does this make sense for everyone?
Right?
Is this is this clear to
everyone?
That's it.
We simplified it.
Now, was that to say that
this one was incorrect?
No, we didn't say
we didn't say this one was incorrect.
We just said,
hey, let's simplify a little bit more.
Right. That's it.
Yeah.
And what was the acceptance criteria?
Let's go back
and read the acceptance criteria.
Look at this.
Look at that.
Because we're like,
I think, guys, I would hire
absolutely every single one of you.
Every single one of you.
Not even joking, Right?
What is the acceptance criteria? Right.
When I say act
because you know what, acceptance criteria
as an admin,
I should be able to log in with syntax.
It's a system
that is almost without credentials.
Is this satisfying
that acceptance criteria?
Right?
Yes. Right.
There you go.
That means test case review past.
Very good job.
The results round applause. Right.
Give yourselves applause.
Give yourselves a round of applause.
Right.
Cool, cool, cool.
Does this make sense, Drew?
One right Again,
The first one was okay, too.
There's nothing wrong with it, right?
We just changed the wording a little bit.
We made it make sense, right?
We have to. We had to write this code.
Cool, cool, cool.
Okay, Keep it simple, basically.
Yeah, Keep it simple.
Unless asked to elaborate.
I like that, Marianne.
Like that.
Okay Cool. Keep it simple.
Keep it simple if you can go.
So basically reword.
We didn't reword. Yeah. If that helps you.
If you want to think about it
like that, sure.
You just got to write it
in separate steps, right?
So that's really good. Very good.
All right, ladies and gentlemen,
gentlemen and ladies.
All right, class number three.
Okay, so before I start this
class, can everyone, everyone in the cell
and she said that
all of you should have had
or should have received your access
to JIRA.
Okay? You should have received an email.
I believe, with your credentials.
And I believe that your username is.
First of all,
did you guys receive any email?
Are you sure?
Because they're saying
that anyone received
any email, any notification
or like anything.
Can you please just
log in real quick and check?
Just log in real
quick and check.
Not one has it.
All right, cool.
All right, That's fine.
That's fine. That's okay.
So listen,
you will receive access to JIRA, right?
And then next week,
we're going to get your heart.
Okay? Does that make sense?
We're going to be very hands
on. You're going to work.
It's going to be a lot of fun.
All right.
So it's going to be JIRA,
not Gyro Zero a thing,
I think Hasim think you're hungry to see?
I think that's a thing.
You're hungry, right?
So good.
So today, let's talk about what is about
what we already talked about,
what is about. Right.
And then we're going to talk about a bug
lifecycle.
All right.
We're going to talk about what
what that means,
what that is, how to approach
a bug and everything like that.
So what is a bug?
We already talked about this, right?
A software bug.
This is the Wikipedia definition,
by the way.
A bug can be described as a mini.
We're talking about a software bug,
by the way.
Right?
Can be a system error,
a failure, a fault, something.
Right.
Does it necessarily
have to mean that something is broken?
Right.
That does it
does it necessarily have to be like.
Like something's broken
or anything like that?
All right.
It could mean that the application's
working just fine.
Right?
And when I
talk about the different types of bugs
that we're going to be talking about,
okay, so bug examples,
software doesn't do something
that specification says it should do.
A user was not able to
log would not code then Charles software
does something that specification says
it should not do
user was able to log in
with invalid credentials right.
Aside from this being a bug,
this could be like a security breach.
It could be really bad.
These software
bugs can lead to a very big,
you know, big problems sometimes.
Okay.
For example, what if I was able to log in
to your bank account
with invalid credentials?
How big of a problem would that be?
Well, first of all, if you had no money,
I don't think it would be a problem.
Right.
But if you had money,
then then it be a problem for sure, right.
So these bugs can
take can play a big, big role.
Right.
So bug examples can
software
does something that specification
does not mention software
allow user to add
two spouses to the policy.
Right.
This can happen
like with different forms. Right.
For example,
if you're signing up for insurance, right.
Or for health care or something,
I think you can only have one spouse,
right.
Legally or something.
But the application is,
you know, taking that information.
What if it's what if it's
allowing you to add more than two spouses?
That would be a bug, right?
At least here in the US.
I know what a lot of
you guys are going to say.
You know, maybe we should have thought
about a different example.
Software doesn't do something.
That specification doesn't mention
when it should log
in, but is in between
the username and password fields.
So how weird would it
look if the log in bind was right here?
Like in the middle?
It look weird right? It
it would look. It would look weird. Right.
But it works, right.
But it's still it's still a bug, right.
It looks obviously it's it's it would be
an issue.
So why do bugs happen?
Why do they occur?
What do you guys think?
So someone says bad mess.
Okay.
Would you like most of the bugs
that are detected
happen during the requirements phase?
Okay.
Then a lot during the design phase
and then some during
the development phase.
And what does that mean?
It all starts from the requirements
and a misunderstanding
and requirements.
And this can happen in different projects.
It happens less in agile environments,
but it can happen like in Waterfall.
It does happen in agile environments too.
But it all happens
because the whole team thinks that
something is supposed to happen
the way it's the way a certain way, right?
But because they assumed one,
because they guessed to
because they thought
that something was going to be some
some way, they went ahead
and they developed it right.
And then when they came time
to present it to the client,
they're like,
Hey, this is not what I want it.
This is not what I
this is not what we wanted.
This is not what what, what we ordered.
This is not what we want it to happen.
You know?
And guys,
I have been in a lot of these projects
and a lot of these situations where
literally we developed the whole module
and the client's like, it's
not where we want it, you know?
And then it's like, dude, you know,
like we spent all this time, right?
You know, and so forth, right?
So it happens.
And everyone is at fault with this, right?
Because your company.
Right. Your team should be
the one always should be
the ones to be always following up.
Hey, is this correct?
Is this good?
But it's also their fault, too.
You know, they're going to be
the ones that need to review the product.
They need to see that they need to have
a good understanding on these things.
Right. And that's what happens.
So the main reason
is because of requirements.
And believe it or not, the last reason
is because of development phase.
Okay, A lot of bugs happened
during the development phase,
meaning that something keeps
breaking or something, you know,
So some stuff, it all depends, right?
So why do bugs occur? So
let's see.
And this is the road
to cost of fixing defects.
This is a really nice chart here.
Actually, where if you find bugs early,
you're you're your client doesn't
really lose much money.
A lot of corrections
can still happen. Right.
This is why you see this little arrow here
very low.
You guys see this right
here? Right. It's very low, right?
If there's a misunderstanding.
If there is, if you can find, like,
a flaw in the system right here,
then the requirements phase right?
It's a easy fix.
It's not in production right now.
You know what production is, right?
Wow. You see, now
you understand this terminology.
You guys are.
I t professionals, right?
So this right here is
it's not in production yet.
So you find that it can be fixed, right?
But what if you keep waiting, right?
If you wait and you find this bug
like right here in this phase.
Right.
Literally, it went through all of this.
It went through the requirements phase.
It went in the design space,
and then you found the bug here, you know,
like it's you waited all this time
and time equals what time is what
time is money, right?
Time is money, right?
And then look and then what happens
is you find a bug here, right?
Look.
And you the basically the longer you wait
to find the bug,
the more expensive it costs.
The overall project in general.
Okay, that makes sense.
Cool.
Go. All right,
so you're testing an application, right?
What company you want?
What example should we get? Google?
How about we give this?
You guys like Disney?
Guys like Disney, Apple?
Well, let's say Disney, right?
Say, let's say Disney.
All right,
we're working for Disney
and you're testing the homepage, right?
Let's go to Disney. Is it Disney Plus?
Because none of the Disney
Plus or Disney World.
Walt Disney World. Let's see.
That was Walt Disney World. He's
right here.
Okay. Walt Disney World. Okay. Bam.
We're on the homepage right now.
I'm visiting this website
as a regular user.
Okay.
As as a regular user.
And I'm scrolling
through the web page, Right.
And these companies, right, they do a
very good job at marketing, right?
Because that's how
they're going to make their money. Right?
So what happens if I come here, right?
If if I if I come here
and then I scroll down and you see
all these advertisements here that you see
here, like, you know, stay here,
the magic Disney resorts, blah, blah,
what if this wasn't displaying
to the user?
Again, this wasn't displaying to the user.
Like I just scroll down
and it's a blank page
or maybe it's a broken image, right?
I won't be able to see
what's being advertised.
That could lead to the company
losing money, right?
So I don't see what it is I see here.
I keep scrolling down and
and stuff like that.
Right.
So everything seems visible. Okay, cool.
So here
what do we do?
We're testing
and we're testing the home page.
Okay?
We're the ones.
We're responsible
for testing the home page.
Let's say we're responsible for testing
to make sure that that we can check in.
Right. Let's check in.
Let's say we're going to get there October
30th and we want to check out,
I don't know, like
default, Right? Okay.
Then let's say we want to take
five adults,
two children, right.
And then fine resorts.
Right.
We'll go is going to find that it says
enter each child's
page at the time of travel.
So let's say
11, say 12.
Okay.
And we're going to go ahead
and find resorts. Right.
All right.
So you're testing this, right?
You're the tester.
You're working here.
You see the results, right?
And and okay, cool.
Right.
So you're testing it and then
you find the bug and you find the bug.
Okay.
What is the first thing you should do,
let's say and I'm going to make this up.
Let's say when I
when I search for something
and I filter by price range
and I say 0 to 175, right.
If I click on this and there's not here
obviously because they would never
I don't even know why
they have that option.
And they want to make it seem
like this is affordable for
syntax.
Students I'm just kidding. Or,
you know, just let's just say over $250.
All right. So, okay, cool.
So let's let's
think about something, right? So
now what have you found the bug, right?
Like, what do we do? Right?
So we get here and we're saying,
okay, we'll filtering by something and
and the results don't come up.
All right?
But you know that
there are packages for over $250 waiting.
Okay.
So once I reported
someone said documented and reported.
Okay, cool.
You know what
you have to do in the testing environment?
You actually have to reproduce the bug.
Okay.
This is where we're going to talk
about the bug lifecycle.
What do you do when you find a bug?
The first thing you do
is you reproduce the bug.
You try to reproduce the bug.
In this case, I made up
what's in there, right?
I said that I'm trying to filter
by price range of packages over $250,
but nothing puppies.
Yes. Reproduce means do it again.
Okay.
So what were the exact steps
I took to reproduce this bug?
I went and I typed in Walt Disney World
right in the search engine box.
Okay.
I clicked on the link on Google. Right?
I came here.
I waited for the page to load.
I insert the dates, right,
that I wanted to travel from.
There you go. It's already selected.
I enter the information
and then I clicked on find results.
I mean, find resorts
to find resorts.
And then once it went on to there,
I went to price
range and I click on deals over $250.
Okay, cool.
Okay. That is reproducing the bug.
Does that makes you
does that make sense that when we talk
when we say reproduce the bug,
that means make it happen again?
Okay.
See if you can make the bug happen again.
And the best way to do
that is to take the exact
same steps you took to reproduce the bug.
Yes. Basically repeat again
the same procedure.
The exact same steps
do not change anything.
Right. Recheck it
and to make sure that it is a bug.
Okay. To make sure that it is a bug.
It's good practice to reproduce it
at least five times.
At least five times.
Cool.
Because what happens
if you're able to reproduce it two times,
but then the third time it works, right?
Then the fourth time it doesn't work,
and then the fifth time it does work,
right?
So do you know what those kind of bugs
are called,
where they don't happen all the time,
but they happen sometimes.
They are.
Those are called
and those are the very famous ones.
They're not called glitches spread,
but they're called intermittent bugs.
Intermittent bugs.
Okay, cool.
This means that it happens sometimes
and that happens all the time.
And guys,
these bugs are the very famous ones
and very difficult to reproduce sometimes,
especially for very big applications.
Okay.
The reason for that is, is because,
you know,
think, think of you like,
have you ever applied for a credit card?
Have you ever applied or filled out a form
a long form of something?
I don't know.
Maybe something very important. Right.
And then like at the end,
something happens,
like it doesn't let you submit it
or it's saying something weird, right?
And the user spends
all that time into the form, right?
And it doesn't work,
but it doesn't happen all the time.
Maybe next time you try it out,
it's going to work, right?
It is a bug, but
it's called an intermittent bug, right?
It doesn't happen all the time.
Okay, cool.
Does that make sense?
Good. Happens all the time.
And I'm sure you guys have experienced
a lot of intermittent bugs.
Okay, A lot.
Why did this happen?
Because there could be
something wrong with the code.
Okay?
It could be. It could be.
No, it's not. It's
not there for a purpose.
No one never,
ever wants to do that on purpose.
It's just there because
it's not acceptable.
Absolutely not.
The truth is that with these intermittent
bugs,
you have to report them and the developers
have to try to fix them.
But I've actually been on projects where
we've had some serious intermittent bugs,
but the developers have never been able
to find a solution for it.
And it's it's really it's
it's really tough for the development team
because out of 20 times
it would happen three times.
But those bugs were so big, okay?
And they really went down.
And then we're trying to find out
why is it happening, why is it occurring.
And and it was very,
very difficult to reproduce.
But what we do know
is that those bugs are exist
like they do exist,
but they're intermittent.
Okay.
So some people are going to ask,
why don't we just try to fix it?
Well,
the truth is that in an agile environment,
you have to keep moving on, right?
And you can't spend so much time
trying to fix
a bug that you can't even fix
when you have so much other work to do.
Okay.
Does that does that make sense, guys?
So and we're going to talk
about prioritizing and stuff like that.
Okay.
But the whole point
is that the first thing you have to do is
you need to try to reproduce the bulk.
How many times you tried to reproduce it
just to be safe, How many times?
At least five times now,
the next thing before you report a bug.
Before you report a bug,
the first thing you need to do is check
the requirements, read the user story
under under the acceptance criteria,
and see if what you are considering
a bug is actually a bug.
Okay.
See, and I told you that a bug doesn't
necessarily mean
that needs to be a showstopper.
Like your application breaks.
It could be anything. Right?
Do you guys remember
this example gave you with this hamburger?
Bring you here?
This one right here. Right.
Google wanted this with three lines,
right?
You see this? There's three lines here.
But if we develop the with four lines
and it works, you can click on it.
It does what it has to do.
Right.
And obviously, the applications working,
it's still a bug, right?
We agree that it's still a bug
and you're going to report it.
But before you report it,
you should try to,
see and read the requirements
and see if this is actually a bug.
We're not see of the acceptance criteria.
Clearly states
you know, developed this bug with three
lines develop this one with three lines.
Does that make sense?
Cool.
The next thing you do is you report it.
And that's exactly
what we're going to talk about next.
We're going to talk about
how reporting works,
what should be included
in reporting and everything.
Okay. So when you report a bug
reporting a bug
reporting, so we're going to say the bug
lifecycle kind
lifecycle, what is the first step we do?
Step number one is what?
What is it? Produce the bug. Right?
We're producing the bug at least
how many times, right?
At least five times.
Right? At least five times.
Okay, let's say
you're able to reproduce it.
Okay.
Good for you.
Right here to reproduce in what is next?
What should you do next, Right.
To make sure that this is a bug?
What do you do?
What about requirements
you read the requirements, right?
You read the requirements.
Okay.
The requirement scope
and step number three.
Right. Okay.
It is a bug.
Okay, then we have to document the bug.
Document the bug?
How do we do it and how do we document it?
Okay, cool. So
when you document the bug you have to
you're going
to have to tell your development team.
You're going to have to tell the team
and you're going to have to give them
instructions
of the exact steps,
exact steps you took to reproduce the bug.
So you're like,
it's going to be like a test case,
but without the expect the results
or the actual results, you're literally
going to write the exact same steps
you took to reproduce the bug.
So it's going to look like this
step number one gain.
You can say
no right in safari.
I'm going to talk about the bug
that I just. Reporter All right.
And safari browser engine in safari
browser engine
search engine.
Walt Disney
World. Right? Walt Disney World.
Okay, Step number two.
Step number two. Guys, What did I do?
What was dev number two?
What was step number two?
Have you paid attention
to what I was doing?
What was step number two?
Reproduce is not testing.
No, you're going to click click on.
And what was it?
If I go back here
to reproduce the bug,
I clicked on the the first link.
Okay, the first link.
I'm going to say the first thing,
not the ad one,
the first link and to specify
that you're going to say this.
Okay, click on the first link
and to say non advertisement.
Okay.
Advertisements. Right.
Step 311. Step three. Nice.
Step three.
After I click this
right. Step three
was what I do.
You clicked on the reservation so
I, I selected reservation dates.
Right.
I select the reservation dates.
Select
reservation dates.
Okay. And you know what?
To be more detailed with this test case,
you have to actually specify the dates
you chose. Right?
So I'm going to say over
what did I say, October.
I was going to be something
that October ten to November six
or six, 2021.
All right, Step number four,
Step number four.
Okay, specify
what do we say? Five.
Those
select
and say select five adults
and two kids. Right.
Two kids.
Okay.
I'm going to say the kids age are
15 and 13.
I'm just making this up
15 and 13
years old.
Years old.
Then step number five, then number five.
What was it
When I do first step number five,
let's say
I was here, click find resorts, right?
That's what it was.
Click
find resorts.
Okay. Watson Right.
So when I clicked on that,
I'm going to click on this
and what else did I do?
I select a price range
right?
Step number six. Step
to select
the price range
to be greater.
See, what was it that I selected
price range
to be over $250, right
to be over
over $250.
Okay, cool.
All right.
And then start number seven.
Step number seven.
I did.
I clicked on find resorts,
right? Actually, I didn't do anything.
Okay, that's it.
I just for this And the result,
the results are populated automatically.
See now they automatically put
All right
so now
and then when you can have here
as the last step is you're going
to have the expected results.
Okay. And I'm just going to make this up.
Expected
result was many options should display.
Okay.
To display actual results.
Actual results only, two options.
Just put it.
I'm just making this up.
Okay, cool.
All right.
Now, this is how
we need to report a bug,
but we're not done yet.
You see how descriptive
and this and specific
we were with
reporting the steps to reproduce, Right.
This is exactly how like this is exactly
how much information
you need to provide the development team
so that they can know how to fix this bug.
Now, you don't need to.
Okay, You don't need to.
So the thing is, with this information,
we're still not done yet.
Okay?
We're still not done.
You need to enter this
information browser, used
browser, used safari.
Okay.
We're going to say the time. What time?
What time do we test this
are going to say around eight.
Around? I'm going to say around
8 to 815,
8 p.m.
to 8:15 p.m., East Eastern Standard Time.
Okay, Does that make sense?
See, I even included the browser.
I even included the time.
Okay.
Now, as a good tester, yes,
I should try to reproduce the bug
in other browsers as well
to see if this only happens in safari.
Okay.
Okay. Cool.
Oh yes. Very good.
Very, very good. Mohammad.
That is a very important one, right?
So operating system.
Operating system was iOS, right?
And what is the operating system? iOS.
But something big or something like that.
And then the date.
Yes, the date.
What is the date today?
The date is October. What?
October 13.
Right. 2021.
So a bug when you report
it should have as much
as information as possible
okay,
does that make sense? Goes
that as much as information as possible.
So when you report a bug,
this is how you report it.
Okay,
cool.
Yes, go with that.
This just makes sense.
You guys get the gist of this.
So you guys understand this, right?
This is how you report a
so you document the bug.
This is only step three of the development
lifecycle.
So first was reproduce
the bug at least five times.
Then step two, read the requirements
to make sure that the bug you are
reporting is a bug.
Step three document the bug. Right.
And then step four.
Step four
The bug needs to be fixed, right?
The bug needs to be fixed.
Okay.
And step five, step five
what is step five?
Once the developer is playing that
they fix the bug, you say, okay, cool.
What do you do?
What do you think?
Step out of this.
Yes, exactly.
I see very.
But do retest to make sure
to ensure bug does not exist anymore.
Okay.
And then step six
once your testing is passed, once
you your testing passes,
passes, we can close the controls
pool.
That is the bug lifecycle.
Okay, cool.
So let's go back here.
Okay? Okay.
Does that make sense to everyone?
Does that make sense?
We got
okay, Do we have any questions on that any
more?
Step six again, what was step six guys?
Lower Step six, What was step six?
How do you close the bug?
I will show you how we work with zero.
Okay, but subsections once.
Once your testing passes, you can close.
Okay, moving on.
Right already.
And severity of bugs.
Okay.
Priority and severity of bugs.
What is the difference between priority
and what is the
difference between severity?
Severity is defined as the level of impact
that the bug has on the functionality
of the application.
Okay.
We're talking about how severe it
is, right?
So users
not being able to check out on amazon.com,
is that a severe bug?
Yes. Right.
It's severe.
It's very, very, very severe.
Right.
You and that you're not being able
to log into your bank account,
is that severe?
Right.
Exactly. And
priority is defined the order
in which the defect should be fixed.
Okay.
The higher priority,
the sooner the effect should be resolved.
Okay.
And now let's talk more about this.
Okay. Let's let's talk more about this.
Let's talk about priority.
Okay.
There's different levels
of different types of priority, right?
We have a showstopper go.
We have a showstopper bug.
A showstopper bug.
It's like an Amazon.com
user not being able to checkout
you, not
being able to log into your bank account.
What else, guys?
Give me some other severe bugs
that you have experienced.
What else is a severe bug
with any application?
Okay, well, what else?
What else can you think about?
Site not loading.
Okay, that can be one, right?
Can deposit your check online sign in
button missing when you need to sign in.
Right.
Data not saving,
unable to pay by something right.
Right. OTP not generated. You'll get it.
That is a very good one.
That's a very good one.
First time I heard that in syntax class
people can log in
with invalid credentials.
Is that a loss?
What is that?
A cross-site scripting. Scripting?
Is that what it is?
Not not able to update your password?
That is that is a very big one.
Can't get medical
records. Very good. Right.
It's basically showstopper.
Right.
And then after that
some projects have major
like major functions are not working,
but you're still able to like test
the application. For example,
let's say
where you log in again,
you see the log in button, right?
And you see the forget password,
but you see the login button.
But it's like the colors of some things
different.
Like it looks weird, but it still works
when you click on it, right?
So you're able to proceed.
So that makes sense.
You're able to to proceed, right?
Sometimes that happens and start.
It's some companies considered major
but you can continue to test that's fine
a minor right
the bug does not result in a termination.
It does not damage anything. For example,
you log into Amazon.com and
they have like a happy Halloween
picture there, right?
It's just a picture.
But but the picture doesn't display.
So is that a showstopper?
Is that, like,
serious bug, Right? Is that.
No, it's not right.
That picture was just there to say
Happy Halloween or
Eden Bar or Merry Christmas or whatever
it is like.
But it's just a picture, right?
They have these are their images change
based on holidays and stuff
they're not really doing doing much.
And then there are the cosmetic issues.
What is an example of cosmetic issues?
Cosmetic issues are when like
something is spelled incorrectly,
right?
That could be images,
something could spell that,
something can be spelled incorrectly, like
it's like, you know,
for some reason
you find that says, like Mary Chris
there Chris nurse and it's spelled like,
like this with two S's by accident
right It's a cosmetic bug, right?
It's just that they obviously
they have to fix it,
but it's not affecting,
you know, it's not affecting anything.
Does that make sense for.
Got it.
Right.
Good. All right. So cool.
And then severity, right?
We have low severity. Meaning?
Meaning severity and high severity.
Okay. Low.
It's okay.
It's has low severity.
The repair can wait. Right.
But perhaps there are other more severe
bugs that can be fixed first, Right?
The medium ones,
the real ones are the ones that
that will eventually be
could become higher.
They don't get fixed. Right.
And then the high severity models
are like the showstoppers, right? Yes.
But Jimmy, you're also going to get these
you're also going to
get these slides as well. Got
to be good.
All right. So
this like lighting can be a bug.
Yeah.
Especially if you have your Wi-Fi is good,
especially if every other website
that you've been using loads fast.
Right.
But for some reason,
when you visit the website, it's lagging.
Then that's application specific, right?
It can definitely be a bug, but
so then examples
high priority and high severity users
unable to log into their bank account.
Okay.
That's in this case is Bank of America
high priority and low severity.
Bank of America logo on the front page
misspelled as Bank of America
with a K right high
priority and low severe.
Okay, it's not that severe, but Bank of
America folks have this as high priority
because they want to fix the name
that America spelled right.
High severity and low priority on syntax
acknowledges website
on their campus section,
not able to scroll view pictures.
I don't know if that bug still exists.
Maybe to fix it.
I don't know.
Low priority and low severity.
Any cosmetic issues.
Image playing on top right.
Instead of center right or spelling issues
we use is trying to make sure there's
always acknowledge message or something.
Right. Just very very small.
Good.
Does that make sense?
Right. One
Q Google.
All right.
So the next is the bug lifecycle.
We've already talked about this.
We went through this a lot
and I wanted to understand
something as well, right?
All this
all this terminology
that we've been using, all these bug
lifecycles, everything,
it's it's like this for all projects
ready for most projects.
But some things always change
and things are always different
from project to project.
Nothing is the same anywhere you go.
Okay,
I want you guys to understand that. So
and maybe
in the bug lifecycle in a project
is slightly different than what
you've learned or something like that,
maybe you're going to realize that
you're going to work on multiple projects.
As you move on with your career, you're
going to realize that it's different
with, you know, in different projects.
Okay, New A new bug is a new bug
that is in person for the first time.
It could be a sign.
It's a sign. The status of new
this is a big one, by the way.
Rejected.
Rejected feels that the bug is not real
or genuine or a big deal.
So the developer rejects the bug.
Okay.
Then the state of the bug
is changed to reject it.
So you reported a bug, but
the developers say no, that's not a bug.
But you are very sure that it is a bug.
Okay.
What do you do that
can and we're going to talk about that.
We are going to talk about that.
Take take the fall entry.
What does that read?
Someone said fighting, fight, fix it
anyway.
You can fix it.
You're not the developer.
You can't fix bugs. You're just testing.
That's it.
You're not going to be a developer.
Okay, So
usually if your bug gets rejected
and you are very sure that that is a bug
and your developer
rejects it, your developer
the developer is not your lead.
He's not your manager, he's
not your project manager.
He's not the program manager. He's
nothing right.
He's not the product owner.
If rejects it and you're very sure
that it's a bug, you can kind of,
you know, say, Hey, this is a bug.
And then he says, No, it's not.
Then you
you reach out to your
to your business analyst, right?
Say, hey, is this a bug?
And then the business analyst can say,
yeah, this is about right.
If the developer still rejects the bug,
then obviously the next person to schedule
the meeting with is the
the program manager.
Okay.
And I don't know how good you guys are
with confronting people,
but at the workplace
you have to look out for your job, right.
So if there's a bug
and you're sure it's a bug reported,
if you're not being listened to, scheduled
that meeting with the program manager.
Right. And then hash it out.
Hash it out. Right.
That's all you got to do.
You got to say, hey, this is this is a bug
fight professional.
I like that.
So you're
just going to say, hey,
this is what the requirement says.
This is how things have to be like.
This is the understanding.
The business analyst
also agrees that this is a bug you know,
it's our guys.
I have experienced this so many times
with different types of developers, game
developers are either going to be
a very good friend of yours
or they're going to like
not like you at all.
And that's
just the truth about about testing.
Yeah, there are going to be times
where you're going to give developers
a hard time.
Okay, But there are
some developers that you're going to
that are going to be very helpful.
They're going to be understanding
and so forth.
Okay, cool.
So a sign and this will all make sense
once we start working with JIRA
and stuff like that.
Okay, I'm gonna talk about a sign
that all that stuff.
Cool.
What if my stapler was adding to the Hub?
I don't understand that.
His way about his behavior
the last ten years.
Business party.
Good luck with that.
Right.
So we talked about the bug lifecycle
and we're going to talk about
we're going to talk about more.
There's a rejected bug ever come
with an explanation of why it's rejected?
Sometimes
not most of the time, no. Joseph.
So you kind of have to
because here's thing right
And one thing
you really have to understand
and also this is a question to you, but
if he's saying it's not
a bug right, he rejects it
and you don't stand your ground.
And then the bug is found in production
and the client finds out,
who do you think is the first person
that they're going to reach to
when they find a bug
within, they go to you.
Then they go to developers,
they're going to go to the testers.
And that's very unfortunate
because that is actually true.
There have been many bugs. Guys.
My project
manager woke me up one night at 3 a.m.
on a Saturday night
because they found the bug and production.
Okay, We did very heavy testing that week.
We all passed it and something happened
and that's how some says
how serious some bugs can be.
That's not so serious.
Some some bugs can be.
Sometimes your job will not just be a
9 to 5 thing,
especially when you work
for a big project.
Go. You're not just going to leave
your laptop open 8 to 4.
You may have to be available on call
whenever they call you.
Okay?
So these bugs can be very serious, but
the point is that they're going to come to
you and the first thing they like to ask
is, Hey, did you guys not test this?
Did you guys miss this? Right?
Like and then it all
depends on the situation, right?
If you're saying, well,
actually we did a test this,
you're going to get in trouble, you're
going to say, why didn't you test this?
You know,
and that actually happened one time.
But the point is,
when something like that happens,
you need to do everything you can
to cover your back because your team
is not going to get your back.
There is not
I don't want you thinking that, you know,
even though your team
is going to be helpful and everything,
you can really trust people and everyone.
So you got to look out for yourself.
Does that make sense to everyone?
You have to kind of make sure
that you're doing your work right, that
you document everything that you report,
everything you cover your back.
This is your job, right?
You're working so hard
to make a great salary to get your first
six figure paying
job, 80,000, 90,000, 100,000, whatever.
Right. Cover your back. Right.
You know, do do whatever you can to
to document everything.
All right.
Remember, we talked about communication.
The difference between word of mouth
and email, right?
You guys
remember when we talked about that,
like the first class
we had together? Right.
If you think something is is, for example,
if really saying that this is not a bug,
you know what you can say to them to
to cover your back, you can say, okay,
I understand, can you please send
an email, CC management
and the bay and indicate in that email
that it's not about please.
Right.
And then get it in writing.
And there you go.
That's your evidence. Right.
So if they find that bugs say,
hey, there's an email about it,
right?
You see everybody CC Somewhere in a cell.
All right.
CC And you can
write
Who does that?
Does that make sense, though?
This point is this point made, right?
You got to cover your back, right?
And even though you had
you have an amazing team, people
can be good, right?
Still like cover your back
and do what you can to to, you know,
stay on top of your stuff.
Mohammed, They reject the bug
because they don't think it's a bug.
They think that it's really not a bug.
Like it's like
they just don't agree with you or like,
you know, and it could be anything.
It could be could be different, Right.
Get test or insurance now.
All right. So it's 830.
Come back at eight 4840.
Cool. It's all right.
I bet you anything that someone in like
a minute is going to ask
me, are we on break?
All right,
so go ahead.
Go on, break it.
I'm going to be here to answer
any questions you guys have right?
Homework from class. What?
Office space
you with with the right attitude
and right mindset.
You can do anything you want.
No, they don't have insurance.
This is not like
they're not going to fire you.
You know, like
I'm just saying that
the whole point is just come back.
It's not that hard.
I wrote notes.
What do you mean I wrote notes?
Hammock
Lifecycle reporting.
Yes, I will share those notes after class.
I wrote all of them here.
Everything cool?
So, guys, we're back. Or we're back.
Or back. We're back.
Or are we back?
So a cell sent
the instructions to how to log into JIRA.
She posted them in the course
announcements channel,
so go and review
the course announcements channels
so that you can
know how talented your listen are.
Please, please.
Okay, just log in.
If it works, it works.
But please do not do anything in JIRA.
Okay. Does that make sense?
Please do not do anything in JIRA.
Okay.
Does that make sense?
Because the thing with JIRA
and we'll talk about it next class
is that it's a project management tool.
And the really interesting thing
about these tools, because you work about
you'll work with it in your project, is
if anyone does
absolutely anything in zero,
there is a history area
where we can see exactly who did what.
Okay,
so now that you have logged in
and we'll know who
your we'll know your username, okay?
I'm telling you right now,
please don't do anything in JIRA,
okay? Or,
or you know, I'll ask you,
why didn't you follow instructions right.
Cool.
Does that
does that make sense? Guys, just.
Just log in.
See if you logged in that You logged in.
Cool. That's all you have to do.
Okay.
That's all you have to do.
Cool.
Got it.
And if some students come late
or we have some friends in this class,
please tell them the same thing to say.
Hey, log in. Okay. And that's it.
Okay. Okay. That's it.
You logged in. That's all you had to do.
Now log back out and we'll touch that.
We'll touch it next week.
Okay, Cool.
Go. Cool, cool, cool.
All right.
So, no, you don't have to get an email.
You have to read the course announcement
channel and you'll know how to do it.
So just go ahead and do it and you'll see.
All right.
So all right, let's let's continue.
Let's continue this. Continue.
Are you ready
or are you ready, guys? We're taking this.
We're going to next dimension enough.
You guys are the smartest batch
we've ever had.
You guys are making this so easy.
So we're going on five levels higher.
Okay, Are you ready? Yes or yes?
You ready or are you ready?
Lewis, are you there?
Anthony, are you there?
Dominic, are you there?
Alexis, are you there?
Jimmy, are you there?
Where's.
Where's Louie?
Louie, Are you there?
Dominic Is there.
Who was that?
We have What was her name
too? Tamanna, Are you there?
Miriam?
You there?
I'll remember your names.
That's fine.
Okay, cool, cool, cool.
Ready?
All right, here we go.
Okay.
What's going
on? We're moving on. We're moving on.
We're moving on. Ready?
All right,
so now we're going to move to talk about
the different types of testing we can now,
this is going to get very interesting,
but it's going to make a lot of sense.
Okay.
We're going to learn about functional
and nonfunctional testing.
We're going to learn about the software
testing hierarchy.
Right.
We've already covered
hierarchy before. Right.
So we're going to talk about that.
We're going to talk about
regression testing.
We're going to talk about ad hoc testing.
We're going to talk about smoke testing
and finally, compliance testing,
white boxes, but black box testing right
now, these are all buzzwords you
but they're all going to make sense
by the end of the class code.
What is the requirements
for stability matrix?
We are going to come back after
once we work with zero.
Okay.
So these this list is like this.
I will come back to it. Okay. All right.
Are you ready, guys?
Are you ready? Yes. Yes. Okay.
All right.
Let's keep it simple, All right?
There are only two types of
only two types of testing Can.
How many types are there?
Only two.
Okay.
Functional and non functional.
Okay. Functional.
A non functional.
Yeah.
Does that make sense?
We're going to talk about what that is.
All right.
How many types of testing are there?
Functional testing.
What is functional testing?
Okay, Functional testing is a type
of testing where we test the functionality
of an application game.
What are we testing?
Buttons, dropdowns, text boxes,
links?
What else, what else functionalities,
anything, functionality
on the web application.
What else do you do?
Are are buttons, dropdowns, text boxes,
radio buttons,
checkboxes,
you know, small menus,
you know everything.
Everything, everything. Everything. Okay.
That is what we call functional testing.
And there's a lot of functional testing
that we are going to be doing
because it is also very important.
Yes, it could be verifying text,
it could be verifying layout, too.
Sometimes. So that's an extent.
And we're going to talk about that
as well.
Okay.
So first thing we do when a code
or new functionality comes from developers
is we make sure
that the functionalities are working okay
to business requirements
and that there are no bugs.
Functional testing is performed
by manual testers and by automation team.
Okay,
who does that make sense so far?
And we're going to talk more about
about how that works.
Term functional tests can be being able
to log in with valid credentials
right in that test case, what you're doing
is you're going to the text boxes,
you're typing in characters,
you're clicking a button, right?
That's you're
testing those functionalities out.
Does that make sense?
Okay,
there are some weird bugs
sometimes with some real projects
where you try to enter something
in a username box or something like that
and nothing is being in the box,
nothing that can be about read
the functionality there is not working.
Okay, Now all of that is done
manually, right?
You're typing manually,
you're clicking manually,
but that test case can also be automated.
Right now I want to show you
the automation test. Last class
number, I showed it yesterday.
I showed you guys
automation execution. Right?
But if I were to do that
manually, it's going to be like me
clicking me typing, entering,
you, doing things manually, right?
So those functional test
cases can be automated.
Does that make sense to.
All right, cool.
Then there is non functional testing.
Okay, There is nonfunctional testing
and what does this mean?
So we know the functional testing is
but now there
a different type of testing
that's called nonfunctional.
Okay.
It focuses on the way
that a system operates
rather than specific
behaviors of the system.
Okay, so what is an example for this?
Okay.
So I'm going to give you example
of a nonfunctional testing scenario.
Okay. Okay.
You know what?
Functional testing is clicking
and logging in and checking out.
You know, you're clicking
buttons, all this stuff.
But there are other types of testing
that take place.
One of those types of testing
is what we call performance testing.
We and you will not perform
that kind of testing.
Okay.
Usually this testing is done by developers
and this performance testing
is basically testing the performance
of an application by trying to see
how many users
the application can hold at once.
Okay.
So for example,
we talked about environments last class.
And one thing that Amazon does right
is that they run,
they do some type of testing
that's called performance testing.
And what they do
is they basically run this test
that will
add like thousands of users
at once to the application
to see if the application will break
or anything like that.
Again, the reason for this is because
they want to make sure
that their application can hold thousands
and probably thousands
and millions of users of that application.
It doesn't test the whole infrastructure,
but it tests the performance
of the application. Okay.
Let me give you an example.
Do you remember?
Yes, exactly.
Developers only do nonfunctional testing
very well.
So the thing is that do you guys remember
like last Black Friday?
Right.
And I don't know if you guys like
to shop there in Black Friday,
but obviously everyone was
closed because of COVID and
Costco had some great deals.
Right? Costco had some great, great deals.
And everyone was looking for
the online sales and everything like that.
Well, the thing is that
when I went on the Costco website,
the website was down, okay?
And the website was down
because too many users
tried to use it at once.
Okay.
Walmart was down, too.
Okay. There you go. Okay.
So what that showed me, right
as a tester or any developer
that wanted to go on Costco, Costco
is that their application obviously
cannot handle many users at once.
Right?
Maybe the performance team,
maybe the developers
didn't run the right performance testing.
Right.
But it just the system was down right?
Okay. It was. It was down.
Yeah.
Now, imagine during Black Friday
where Amazon makes a lot of their
money and Amazon was down,
Right.
Well, what happened then?
How much money would they lose?
They would lose so much money.
A lot of money. Too much money. Right.
So we are very sure
that Amazon is doing some next level.
And same thing
with all these big companies, Disney,
you know, Amazon, now Netflix.
So software test.
So software
testers can log stress testing.
No, we don't do stress testing.
We're going to talk more about that type
of testing journal in just a second.
Okay.
Facebook, Instagram, right.
You you name it. Right.
These applications need to be able
to hold so many users at once.
Okay. Does this make sense so far?
That is a type of nonfunctional testing,
right?
You're not testing functionalities.
You're not testing to
then you're not testing
to see how like a button,
if one is working,
a dropdowns are working,
the developers are using different
programs to perform this kind of testing.
Don't worry,
you don't have to know how to do it.
Okay.
But you should just know
what performance testing is.
Okay. Does that make sense
code?
So that is just one example.
Okay, that is just one example
code.
So software testing hierarchy.
Okay, cool.
So this hierarchy right here is
is is kind of it
is exactly what we actually talked about.
Okay.
But it's one so that you're responsible
for not you guys will be doing
nonfunctional testing but different types
of nonfunctional testing.
Okay. You guys will be testing rest APIs.
You guys will be doing API testing,
you guys will be doing backend testing
with sequel.
When you guys start
writing sequel queries and everything
that is nonfunctional testing.
We're going to talk
more about that in just a second. Okay.
So this right here, this nugget,
this hierarchy, you guys are right.
When we talked about one, two,
three, four, right.
So in this diagram right here, we have
what's called unit testing.
Okay,
So what I didn't tell you last class is
unit testing.
Developers
develop their code and what environments,
what environment and the dev environment.
Right. Very, very good.
But what they also do,
right, what they also do is they do
what's called they perform
what's called unit testing.
Okay.
And Unit testing is done by developers.
And what unit testing is, is
they test in a development environment,
but they're really testing their own code.
Okay.
They have some different testing
techniques to test their own code.
There's a lot of different types
of testing techniques that they use that
they have to make sure that their code
satisfies certain requirements
and something like that.
Right. You don't need to know that.
You just need to know what unit
testing like, what kind of testing
developers do and it is done
in development environments.
Does that make sense?
Okay.
Okay, cool.
Then comes integration testing.
Okay. And in this phase right here,
we have integration
and this is the dev environment.
Now this is the Q8 test environment.
Now you guys will be doing
functional testing, but
we also call it integration testing.
It's not done by developers,
it's actually done by the Q team.
Some developers can do it,
but it's done by the Kuwaiti dev.
And what does that mean?
What is integration testing?
That is a very good question.
So what integration testing is
okay, is this
and this is where you're going to start
to to realize the magic
behind these applications.
Yeah, let's think about Amazon.com.
Okay?
When we go to Amazon.com, right,
we think like, oh, we're on Amazon, right?
Yeah.
When we go here, we click anywhere.
As a user, we still think that we're on
Amazon.com, right?
But the thing is that this is not just one
application.
There are a lot of modules
that were developed separately
that at the end were integrated
with the Amazon home page.
So, for example, if I come here
and I click on Prime or if I come here
and remember that test is now run
and we click prime video
and it takes us to the preview homepage,
this is a separate module
that was developed
separately from the Amazon.com home page.
Okay, This is a separate component.
But what they did
was they integrated this with
so that we can access it
from the Amazon home page.
Does that make sense?
So you guys will be performing
integration testing
without even knowing that you guys are
performing integration testing.
Okay.
For example, here Prime
video is a different component
that has been integrated the Amazon home
page, right?
The toys and games section, the Kindle
books, the version of pharmacy, the books.
Right.
The books is also a different component.
Okay.
And Amazon has so many development teams
that work
on all of these different modules.
They don't have one team
that works on everything.
They have so many different teams.
I mean, so much work
goes into all of this.
So, so much work goes into all of this.
Okay.
Does that make sense to you guys?
Does that make sense?
So let's talk more about other types of
integration testing that we'll be doing.
Oh, Facebook.
Who has Facebook
who has Facebook?
If you want to message
someone on Facebook from your phone,
you know, you have to download
an application called messenger, Right?
And that messenger application
is that messenger
is actually a separate application.
Right.
But the way it works is that it's
integrated with Facebook app, right?
So that when you go on Facebook
and you want to message someone,
then the messenger application opens.
Does that make sense? Right?
Do you guys understand that?
Cool, same thing?
And you can think of many other types
of applications.
Okay, cool.
All right.
So you guys will be doing a lot
to talk more about this in just a bit.
Right.
So then after that call system testing
and we put this with the
with the weight testing team, right,
with the world stage testing the UHC,
what does Unity stand for?
You guys remember I told you guys,
what does your weight stand for?
What unity stand for
with this?
Come on, let's see your notes and we'll
learn about that to user acceptance.
What user acceptance? What
user acceptance? Testing.
Nikolai That's right.
Okay. User acceptance testing. Right.
And what they do is who does unity?
Who does unity testing
the client.
Right.
But do we know exactly how the client
is going to test their application
so we know exactly how they're going
to test it now right.
But we do know that they're going to test
what we said pass, right.
Passes.
They're going to make sure of that. Right.
They're going to do this type of testing.
Those system testing.
They're going to test everything,
the whole system. Right.
There's a lot of testing
that goes onto system testing.
We may have to help with that.
That's fine.
Okay.
And what does that mean?
That actually means a lot.
For example,
the Amazon account page, right?
When you do system testing,
they're going to test Amazon.com.
They're going to run so many tests.
But a of other testing needs to know that
a lot of other testing needs to happen.
One unit testing, right?
Developers have to test the code
performance testing we've to make sure
that millions of users can use the
they can use Amazon.com
without Amazon breaking
three security testing right.
They actually have
to run their security scans.
They have to see that the security
engineers have to see if they can
hack the system, see if see if it's
if it's if it's secure.
We actually have a penetration tester
here.
Lewis In class,
who can talk more about that,
who has a lot of experience doing that.
But they do a lot of this testing.
They've got to make sure
that they're doing all of this testing.
Okay.
And what they also do is they
these applications are hosted
on a cloud server these days.
Right?
You've probably heard buzzwords like NWS,
you know, Microsoft Azure,
different servers,
all of that stuff, right?
Everything that is integrated
or that the application uses.
Okay, is what is going to be tested.
Everything,
not just the application process.
Absolutely everything.
Okay.
Does that make sense to everyone?
And you may be
you may be assisting with that system.
That's obviously the testing
that you will do is, only going
to be part of that system, testing
all the functional testing that you're
going to be doing, all the integration
testing you're going to be doing.
All of that is going to be part
of the system testing
that will be done as a whole.
Does that make sense? Cool.
So everyone takes part of this, everyone
takes part of system testing everybody.
Okay, cool.
And then acceptance.
We left it up here because then the client
just will do what they need to do.
Okay.
So let's talk about unit
testing again, unit testing is
is is there's two type of tests and I'm
going to talk it's going to call white
box testing and black box testing.
Okay.
Unit testing is considered
a white box testing.
White box testing is a type of testing
where you are actually testing
the internal parts of the application,
meaning you need to understand the code,
You need to understand the code
that the application was developed with.
You need to be able to test
and actually know how this code works.
Who else knows that other than developers
write only they know it.
They're the ones that are developing
the application.
Does that make sense? Right.
So they perform white box testing.
They're the ones that perform unit
testing.
Okay, We do not perform unit testing.
Game developers perform DNA testing in
the done environment integration testing.
We're really talked with this.
You will learn you can read more of this
of this testing system testing.
We talked about everything red everyone
has to do part of of
system testing, your manual testing,
your automation,
everything that is part of system testing
and then acceptance testing.
We all know what it is.
We already talked about that. Okay, cool.
So how many types of testing are there?
Only two, right?
There's functional and nonfunctional,
but now the different types
of testing
that we just discussed are types
and they fall under either
functional or nonfunctional testing.
Does that make sense?
Okay, so there's only two,
but system testing, integration, testing,
all of these, they either fall
under functional or nonfunctional.
Okay.
But in the end, only two types of testing
that are functionality nonfunctional.
And we're going to talk
more about this now.
Okay.
There are different types of testing
that you guys be hearing a lot
that you guys will be conducting a lot
and some of them you won't.
One of them is called smoke testing.
One is
one of them is called regression testing.
We have performance testing
and we have ad hoc testing.
Okay, Smoke testing.
What is smoke testing?
Okay. A smoke test is a quick
sometimes it
can be a long, but it's a quick test
and it's a it's a small number of tests
that actually test the most important
basic functionalities of the system.
Okay.
So, for example, logging in with valid
credentials, being able to check out.
Right.
And purchase something, being able to,
you know, something,
you get the idea, right?
So very basic,
but important functionalities can
this okay.
So in a real life scenario is
like when you get in your car, right,
your car has so many features
that are very, very important, right?
It actually has so many features,
but it actually has a number of features
that are more important than others,
right?
You get in your car, you make sure that
that the lights are working right.
You make sure that the windshield
wipers are working.
You make sure that the brakes are working.
You make sure that the view mirrors
can move, that you can put your seatbelt.
Right.
So all these things would be something
that's considered a smoke test
right there. The most
important functionalities
of, in this case, your car.
But what about testing the radio
to see if it works
right?
Is that like, important functionality
that you would consider,
like as as like checking your brakes
or your seatbelt?
Right.
What about like,
give me something else in your car
that's not like a big deal.
You know what?
What else would be considered
a low priority in your car?
AC There you go.
Okay.
Wipers are a big priority, right?
If it rains, you're needed.
Okay. Seats moving or not.
If your Bluetooth is or
not that your seat reclining,
these are not as important as you know,
making sure that the brakes are working,
making sure that the directional lights
are working, that your mirror is working.
So that similarly we do this
with with
applications we call them smog testing.
So for
with my project
I work, we actually have smog
test cases
that are executed every single morning.
And these are test cases
that cover logging and a user being able
to like check out to perform
certain important functionalities.
And it's not many test cases.
It's actually for one application.
We have like ten test cases executing
that.
That's all we have.
But for example,
an image to verify that an image
displays, right?
Is that as important
as someone being able to log in?
It's not right.
It's not sure it has some importance,
but it's not as important
as being able to log in.
Okay, So it makes sense.
So those kind of tests,
the ones that I just talked about,
like checking of the
images, they're checking of
if I don't know what is something
that is not super high priority
on an application, the spelling,
checking, certain spelling, what else?
What else is there?
Colors.
Maybe colors can be a big deal
and I'll talk about that in just a second.
What else?
A picture or design?
Something like that. Right.
So all of those are actually what we call
regression
tests, cases of regression testing.
Okay.
There are certain functionalities
in the application that if they are
broken, okay,
then it's not going to be a showstopper.
It's not okay
if they're just it just depends
on the product that you're working with.
Cool.
Those test cases are still important.
Okay. Important.
And and you know, they should pass,
but they're not really in most places
as important as smoke test cases.
For example, if tomorrow
we checked our automation report
and we saw that our smoke test filled,
that is a very big red flag, right?
Because that's an indication
that one of our most important
functionalities
in the application is broken.
Something is fairly good.
So lots of big, big, big red flag.
Okay.
Now when we run our all regression
test cases.
So as you mentioned, I told you that our
smoke test cases, our smoke
testing, we
think we have 10 to 15 smoke test cases.
Okay.
But you know how many regression
test cases we have?
We have about 300 for one application
that that are being that are automated.
Okay.
So we run the whole regression
automation, right.
And if something fails,
it's not going to be like a super big
red flag again.
Who decides which kids are Smoke?
That's the team.
You guys discuss it and we're going
to talk more about that later, actually.
Okay.
But you will you will talk more about that
when you start automating
and stuff like that. Cool.
So the regression test case could fail
and it's not going to be
like a super red flag, you know,
But we it's still going to be a failure
and it should still be addressed.
Does that make sense, guys?
So that makes sense.
Okay, cool.
Okay, So here's the thing.
So, okay, when we execute our smoke test
cases, right, we're making that.
We're testing
the most important functionalities.
Okay?
Now, the reason that we have a regression
of the rest of the regression testing
is whenever developers do something,
whenever they move their code,
they introduce new changes
to the application.
Okay, We run our regression testing
to make sure that nothing else
existing from the application
was affected by the new changes.
Okay.
Does that make sense?
Okay,
so every time
there is an update to the code, right,
we need to run our regression
test cases to make sure that nothing else
was affected by the application.
I remember one time for one project
developers introduced some new code.
Okay.
And this was for like a new form. Okay.
For a new form that users had to fill out
and stuff like that.
But for some reason, for some reason,
that affected
the forgot password functionality
from our application.
Okay.
These two components completely separate
from each other, right?
You know,
you're talking about a form
that users can fill out, right?
That code was introduced,
but for some reason
when that was introduced, the forgot
password functionality was broken.
Users were not able
to reset their password.
That broke
because of the new code changes.
Do you understand that?
Like, even though things like that
are very different,
they can still have an impact on something
else?
Okay.
Does that make sense?
So it makes sense. Okay.
And it can be anything.
And you'll find
you'll find a lot of these things, right?
Amazon can be updating some things
for their for their Halloween
or for their Thanksgiving,
you know, everything like that.
But and not to smoke.
It doesn't work that way.
It cannot end up to to smoke.
No, it doesn't know
you're smoke.
Test cases should always pass
no matter what.
Okay.
And there are also other functionalities,
right,
that we talked about like a regression
test is can be like verifying
that an image is displaying
or verifying that a certain text display
is the way it is. Right.
Where do you start?
Testing and regression of the website
is huge.
That stuff you will come to learn later.
Mohammed Okay,
just understand the concepts right now.
Okay, cool.
For example, in the car
scenario that I provided, right?
Verify that radio works
or that you can connect to your Bluetooth,
that would be considered a regression
test case.
Okay, cool.
Right.
So that can be considered a regression
test is at the end, even though
it's not as important as your seatbelt
or your directional lights
or your brakes working, it's
still a future that makes the car right.
And it should work.
So it needs to work and it needs to be
addressed and fixed, right?
I don't know.
But what if sometimes, like
it's like someone doing an oil
change to your car
and this is not going to happen,
but it's like you're taking your car
to the mechanic shop
and they're fixing like the tires
or something or changing something.
But for some reason
your radio isn't working anymore.
Okay?
Those two components are like very,
very separate
from each other. But
but that's just what happened.
And does that make sense?
And it can happen to these
kind of things just happen.
And that's why regression
testing is important.
Okay.
Performance testing, we already talked
about performance testing.
Okay.
Will you be performing performance testing
what you know you want?
Okay.
And just FIA performance testing.
Performance
testing is the same thing as load testing.
Okay.
And the same thing, test stress testing.
You may hear these terms,
you may see these terms,
you may come across them
like they're the same thing, right?
Load stress test.
So you want to stress the system
with many users
to see if your website will break temp.
Cool.
Does that makes sense. It's
all the same thing.
Can it's all the same thing.
Security testing is a little different.
Yeah.
Cool. All right.
It can be called spike testing,
load testing,
endurance testing, volume testing,
scalability testing.
These
all these words are the same thing. Okay.
All right.
So questions up.
So right now.
Dozens of thoughts right now.
And we are crushing it today, right?
We are crushing it.
All right.
The next type of testing
is called File a testing.
And by the way,
this is the type of testing
that is actually really, really cool.
Okay.
It's really cool.
You mostly likely will not be doing it.
Okay. Depends on your project.
Okay.
But far away compliance testing is a very
unique and special
type of testing.
There is a law
that's called section 508, right.
Which is a requirement
for government websites
and actually not just websites
for all websites
and in general, like federal departments
and stuff like that.
So what is by the way.
So this type of testing.
Okay. And it's and it's
and it's really enforced
by the government.
Okay.
This is to basically make sure
that everyone
can use your application
and when you are developing
an application, when Amazon is developing
an application, Amazon, Target,
Walmart, Disney, everyone read
they are making an application
that is for the general public.
Okay?
That means that the general public
includes people like you and myself,
right?
And what this means
is that people with disabilities
are also part of the general public,
people who are blind, people who are deaf,
people who have hand injuries
that can use the keyboards
or they can use the mouse.
Okay, people
that have some sort of disabilities,
they should be able to use your website.
Okay.
This is called accessibility testing.
Yes, that's true. Okay.
And there are different tools
that is used for this testing.
For example,
some of you guys were mentioning something
about colors and stuff.
Okay, I'm
in order for your website to be five
way compliant,
there are some rules that you need
to follow that developers need to follow.
Like, for example,
your colors can be so like,
like hard, too difficult to tell.
Usually the problems are
when it comes to like white and yellow,
you know what I mean?
Or some colors that may seem very similar.
Also text and may seem very small
or hard to read or something like that.
If you guys have a Windows, if you guys
have a windows, you can go do this.
I want you guys to do this.
How to turn on.
NARRATOR On windows ten,
if you guys have a Windows
press, the Windows
logo key, the Windows Key,
press control and enter
and put the volume up.
Okay?
What this does is it's
going to turn the narrator on.
So what you're going to see
is that whenever you press a key, it's
going to your computer's going to read you
the key that you're pressing.
Okay?
So if you press like G is going to say,
gee, if you say if you press backspace,
it's going to say backspace
actually going to read it to you.
Okay, The volume needs to be up.
Okay.
That's how you turn.
NARRATOR On with windows. Okay.
And if you want to turn it on with Mac,
you want to turn on with Mac,
you need to
press command f five
you or you can use Siri.
So something like turn voice over on
or something like that. Okay
Go ahead and do it.
Okay.
And see that whenever you press a key,
okay, you're actually going to to,
I don't know, Google it for Chromebook.
I think it uses an Android OS probably.
Okay, so
Google it and and you're going to see that
put the volume up whenever you press
a key is going to read.
The key back to you
is going to say like, you know, it's
going to tell you where you're typing.
Similarly, there are different tools
that that can test these things
for these websites can now,
there was an incident
a few years ago where
a lot of
companies were not taking this seriously.
Right.
And so one day a customer,
a customer
accidentally bought something like
they checked out on the target
website, customer with disabilities.
And this transaction
was for a lot of money.
It was for like thousands
and thousands of dollars.
And this user happened to have that money.
So it was charged.
The user never wanted
to make that purchase and the user
the user sued
because of that
and because of section five or eight,
Target lost millions of dollars
to this user to this customer,
They lost a million
like multimillion dollar lawsuit.
So what happened was right,
as all great companies out there,
they learn from the mistakes of others,
right?
So Amazon, Google,
Disney, Netflix, all these companies,
this what they did,
they started hiring 508 testers.
Right?
They wanted to have a508 compliance team
and they needed to make sure.
And they're still making sure that
that, you know, companies
don't run into this problem.
Okay.
Because again
and if you ever think of developing
an application for the general public,
you need to make sure and remember
that the general public includes
everybody, right
even those with disabilities.
Does that make sense?
It can be disabilities of any type
colorblind, blind hands, injured.
You know,
there are folks with no hands, right?
There are folks with with no arms.
And honestly, if you ever have.
That's a good question, Gerald.
You can become a fireblight tester.
Once you're in the testing field,
it'll be easy to transition
over to five way tester.
There's different classes
you can take, but it's
actually a type of testing
that is very rewarding.
Okay, There aren't a lot of people
that do this and it pays very well.
Okay.
I have a friend
who is a five weight tester
and he makes about 200,000 a year salary.
Okay.
So that is that is big money, right?
It's a big, big money, dude.
I know. I didn't even know about this.
And There
are a lot of roles out there in I.T.
that are just as important.
But this is the type of testing
that is very, very important.
Does that make sense, guys?
Does that make sense?
Okay, cool.
Right.
So just keep that in mind, right?
So if you ever have the opportunity,
you want to do it
now, I heard it's kind of boring, but
last time I heard making 200,000
a year is not boring.
It's actually a lot of fun.
So anyway, ad hoc testing,
what is ad hoc testing?
Okay,
Another type of testing is ad hoc testing.
And this is what we call
what is also known as exploratory testing.
Okay. Ad hoc testing.
Exploratory testing.
And really what this is and
and is testing without documentation.
Right? What does that mean?
That means just go and randomly test
the application,
like just go and randomly test it.
Okay.
And after you run your test cases,
especially when there's going to be
like a big release
to production and stuff like that,
whenever you're testing, you're going to
be performing this kind of testing, right?
You educate all your test cases.
Let's say they all pass, right?
But just to make sure they're going to ask
the whole team to just go and test
the application, like just
and randomly test
the application, go and try to break it.
Everyone does
this kind of testing in the project.
You will do it, developers will do it.
Your base will do your
the clients will do it.
They go
and they perform this kind of testing
to make sure that everything works okay.
Does that make sense, guys?
Does that make sense?
They go in
that this is a different type of testing
call.
Okay, cool, cool, cool. Right.
So plus, exactly.
It's it's like you just go
and see if you can find.
Okay. Retesting.
Do we know what retesting means?
What does retesting mean?
We talked about this.
We were talking about the bug lifecycle
to test again
for hard.
You are so smart, man.
So to test it again tomorrow. Wow.
Unbelievable.
Right. Unbelievable.
Amazing. Right.
It's retesting.
That's what it is,
guys. Just test it again.
And when do we do a lot of retesting?
Whenever there's a bug, we find a bug
when the bug gets fixed and we retest.
Right?
That's it. Plain and simple.
Different testing techniques.
Okay, so why bugs testing?
We talked about it.
We basically said that it requires you
to know the internal structures of the
applications and we're the only ones.
I know that
we're the only ones I know that.
That's right.
And what kind of testing
the developers perform.
So what kind of testing the developers
perform?
Unit testing.
Very, very good. Right?
Then there's black box testing.
Black box testing does not require you
to know
the internal structure of the application.
If anything, it's testing
as testing the functionalities like that.
What do you think will be doing
that kind of testing?
We think we do that kind of testing, yes.
Right. They're waiting.
Right, guys, Give yourselves one applause.
Give yourselves around applause because
you were able to put one and one together.
Okay.
Very Very, very good.
They're very good code positive testing.
Okay.
A positive test case is.
And here and here it goes Right.
Being able to let's say
the acceptance criteria says something
like being able to log in
with valid credentials.
Right. Okay.
You log in with our credentials.
Bam, That's it. Right.
But to negative test that. Right.
If you want it to.
If you want a negative test
that tried to see if you can log in
with invalid credentials.
Okay. And you shouldn't be able to log it.
You shouldn't be able to log it.
Does that make sense to everyone?
You shouldn't be able to log in.
Now, if you do log in
with invalid credentials,
then your negative test case cells can,
if you want your negative test case
to pass in that scenario,
you should not be able to log in
with invalid credentials then. Okay.
And then we have a boundary value analysis
that's also known boundary testing.
All right.
So there's this type of testing
where you're going to work with
applications that have text boxes,
text fields and so forth,
and The requirements would say something
like, okay, in this
and maybe you've already use
these applications where there are
some text boxes, some fields, right
but they have a character maximum, right?
Like you could not like
you can't enter
more than 500 words, right?
Or this text box
will not allow more than ten characters.
Have you guys ever used or experienced
that with any application?
Have you guys you know, so
what if there's like a form, right?
And it says that, okay,
this form cannot have more than 500 words?
I actually to go in there and type
500 words
like, okay, one,
two and I'm going to manually count it.
Now what you're going to do
is you're going to put you know,
you're going to think right,
you're going to put your thinking cap on
and you're going to Google.
You're going to
you got to type in word counter,
word counter.
You click on any link
you want, any link and type of word.
Right. You can type in three words, right?
What do you think I'm going to do?
Allen Then that says that you're ready
for the market, right?
You're ready for the market.
You're ready.
The market. Okay,
You're ready for it.
Right on that. Right on.
Okay. Okay.
So now what I'm going to do
is I'm going to pull out.
I want to get to almost 500 words.
I'm at 388. Okay.
So 492. Right.
So I'm going to type one, two, three,
four, five, six,
seven Okay.
Eight. Right.
So I have exactly 500 words. Right.
So what I'll do is
I'll type a different word,
so I'll type in
whatever I'll say difference right.
And now I have 501 words.
If I'm going to test the field,
that will only allow 500 words.
What I'm going to do
is I'm going to copy all of this
and I'm going to paste it in that box.
Right?
I'm going to paste it in that field.
If I see the word different,
does that mean
that it's a line more than 500 words?
Yes. Right.
That's what some people are saying.
No. And yes, let me repeat that question.
If I'm testing a field
that will only allow
500 words right here,
we have how many words?
We have 501. Right.
501. But
if I copied all of this
and I pasted this into a field
that will only allow 500 words,
but I see the word different here.
I see the word different.
This word
that I typed in different in that field,
does that mean that it allowed
more than 500 words?
Yes. Right.
It allowed 501 words.
Okay.
So is that a bug? Yes.
Is that a showstopper? That
Not really. Right.
Or it's a bug. Right.
So in the application, still working
and still functioning,
everything is still working.
But look, this is a bug, right?
So this make sense,
right? This this is a bug.
Does that make sense?
I want Coca-Cola.
Right?
So that is called boundary value analysis.
It could be with anything.
Like even the password
feels like the password
should not be more than ten characters.
Still read the forces that try
to create a password with 11 characters
see what happens.
By the way,
I like to say that one of the worst
websites I have ever used
is the DMV website.
You know these people in the DMV,
these people, they hate work.
They're
you know, they hate to work there.
For some reason, I went to the DMV
and I was like, why are you working there?
Like, you're like, pissed off I came here.
I said, Hey, how's it going? And like,
he was pissed off.
I was like, Oh, it's
like it's
they're forcing you to work there or,
I don't know, like, it's
it's bad, you know? Let me tell you.
Can you imagine a world where they provide
good customer service, a DMV.
Imagine that, right?
Imagine that.
And imagine a world where they provide
great customer service at the DMV,
Right?
It'd be amazing.
Yeah, but I don't know.
I don't know why they're so unhappy.
I don't get I've never I don't even know
anyone that works at DMV.
But if I ever do know someone,
I'm going to ask them straight up.
Why do you hate working there
and why do you work there hate it so much?
You know, I really want to ask that.
Yeah.
Okay.
Why? Box testing techniques.
Requires programing skills.
Dito. Programing skills. I'm
talking at the developer level.
Okay.
Most done by developers
when they execute their code
before it goes to the environments
they conduct, unit testing,
the internal internal
structure of the application
is only known to the developer.
Okay. Yeah.
I agree with Eugene.
There's a lot of people in the US
that that hate their jobs,
you know, but
I don't know, man.
That's, I guess that's kind of hard. So.
But you're here, right, Eugene
And that's all that matters, right?
And let's hope you like it.
All right. So
all over the world.
Yeah. So requires.
So do Q8 testers perform
white box testing?
Do they?
Yes. Or they don't.
Exactly. They don't.
They don't, Right. They do not.
That is actually write it down
That is an interview question.
And I'm
interviewing
people with 1050 years of experience.
And this is one of the questions
that I ask them.
Can this is one of the questions
Okay, So black box testing requires
no knowledge of internal structures
or anything of the application.
Tester doesn't need to know.
The question is,
what is the difference between white box
testing and black box testing?
Okay, black box
testing that Tester doesn't need to know
how the application was developed.
They're testing
basically the functionalities.
Everything else
is diagram to help you out.
Okay, So what is the difference between
white box testing and black box testing?
It's very simple.
It's very on. It is very simple.
Very, very easy.
Cool. All right.
So when earlier when we said to eight,
it was just for positive and negative.
So when earlier we said,
what is the question?
They say, I don't I don't understand.
What is the question? It's
Q Team does only know.
I don't want you to think about that.
Positive and negative testing
is part of the testing that we'll do
when we perform functional testing right?
Does that make sense? Right, Exactly.
So it's just a different type of person
that we have to do.
In my box testers should partially, no,
not partially.
Nicolae and white box testing
the tester
who would be the developer needs
to really know
the internal structure of the application.
Okay. Does that make sense?
So. So Q8 test developer's done? Yes.
Negative and positive testing
are just techniques. Yes.
This idea from Florida
helping show from Fairfax,
that's like the coolest thing ever.
So what is the difference between smoke
testing and black box testing?
You tell me.
You tell me for hard
When when I tell you
about the smoke test cases
that we have to execute
like logging in, right?
Making sure that we check out so smoke
testing is a type of black box
testing as well.
Does that make sense?
They are the same thing.
Cool, cool.
But then again, how many types of testing
are there really?
How many types of testing are there?
There's only two, right.
And what are they?
What are they? What?
What are they?
Functional and nonfunctional.
Right.
And all the techniques,
all the different types
of testing that we're talking about,
they fall under those categories.
Does that make sense?
They fall under those categories.
Okay, cool.
So white box testing, is it
a nonfunctional testing
or is it part of functional testing?
Why box testing?
Is it nonfunctional or functional?
Guys, guys, white testing.
Very good.
Okay.
Are you sure why box testing is functional
or nonfunctional testing?
What? Why? Why box testing? Right.
Very good.
It's nonfunctional.
Okay. Right.
Black box testing.
Is it functional or nonfunctional
Black box tested? Yes.
Developers perform
nonfunctional testing, right?
They're going to test their code.
When they're testing, they're called.
That's not testing the functionality
of the application.
They're not testing to make sure
that buttons work.
That dropdowns worry
that the textbooks are working.
They are testing their code.
So again, is white box testing
a type of functional nonfunctional?
Nonfunctional Is black box testing
a type of functional or nonfunctional?
Functional? Exactly.
Does that make sense?
Cool, cool, cool, cool.
Exactly. Mikel That's right.
Okay. Positive testing.
We already talked about some positive
test cases. Let's see
if you are doing positive testing
for blind functionality.
You are only used valid credit card
number and expiration day
like enter only numbers, right?
So in this field it says enter
only numbers a type a different way
to negatively test that is insert
characters instead of numbers.
Right.
Have you ever
like gone to an application?
And for fun, try
to see if you can enter like characters
like in a number textbox like say, oh,
it only allows numbers.
Let me see if I can type
some characters in there right.
You listen like a good girl.
Okay, that's
that's interesting.
It's good to know.
But has else done that?
Okay. Yeah. So just.
Just just
you asked it.
We put other characters. Yes.
Like if you enter, like.
Like, for example,
if this is only numbers,
have you ever tried to enter characters
to see if it allows characters
once that type letter?
Oh, instead
it was frustrated that it wouldn't work.
Oh, as I said, no, I do as I'm told.
Oh, okay.
So cool.
That makes sense.
Give me an example of a negative testing
that you can do.
What literally anything like
what else?
Give me an example.
Let's think about like let's
let's think about there's a fields
on the
when you're when you're up
when you're entering
a credit card or when you're applying
for credit card application.
And let's say it's asking you to enter
a phone number right?
And it only allows numbers.
What is a way to negatively test that
entering letters, Right?
Exactly right.
What about a field
that says enter valid email?
How can you negatively test that?
Enter a valid email address,
enter invalid.
But how would you make it invalid?
How would you make it invalid? Yeah.
Okay, good.
So you can make an email invalid, right?
Just like saying like for example,
like a valid email would be like
email test dot com.
Right.
Maybe you can enter like this
email dot com.
See if it works. Right?
You can say email at the test icon.
Right. See if it works right.
Does that make sense?
Just go ahead and see if you can.
Or maybe you can do this.
You can also do email at test
but don't at the dot com.
Right. See what happens.
Cool.
Will be your gmail with gmail part
I tried with gmail that doesn't work.
Will be your gmail.
Gmail that doesn't work. Okay. Yep.
Cool. Cool, cool.
All right.
All right
so we've covered this boundary testing.
All right.
So we've already talked about this.
Another type of boundary testing
is when you're entering like, a number,
like it's saying like it's there's a field
is verification code negative?
What do you mean verification code?
Negative testing would then mean.
What do you mean verification code
one time password explained like
what do you
what do you testing in that scenario
and how would how
would that be a negative test is explain
when you try to log in some application
they sent a verification code.
Okay.
And what what's your point
you get a verification code
and what
how can it be
how what do you
what do you negatively testing
in that scenario.
Right.
If you're
if you get sent a verification code
with most applications,
that means you have already test it.
That means you have already entered
a valid username
and you have already entered
a valid password.
Right then only once that works,
then you will be sent a one time
passcode right.
Cool.
Right.
Exactly.
So what what is
what do you or what was your question?
I didn't understand it just to.
Okay, maybe what you can do is
if you get that one time passcode right,
enter the wrong entry, wrong code
and see if it works right.
So, for example, if the 110 passcode says
one, two, three, four, five,
but I enter 37296
and that works is that like is that bad?
It is, right, because at that
point it accepted any code.
Right?
And that at that point
you can negatively test that scenario.
Does that it does that make sense
that that that answer your question.
Yup so that that would be bad.
That would be
yes that is a negative test case
entering the wrong one time passcode.
Right.
That can be
that can be a big a very big risk
because at that point
that future didn't work.
It literally just took anything.
Okay, cool.
All right.
Very, very good. Okay.
So we learned a lot today.
Let's recap what we learned.
How many types of testing are there
and what are they, too?
Okay.
And can you tell me in your own words,
like what is performance testing
like using your own words?
It's a type of nonfunctional
or functional test performance testing
Is performance
testing type of nonfunctional?
Functional, nonfunctional.
Yes, it is considered low testing.
It is nonfunctional. But what
what what exactly is done
with performance testing
is testing to see if the system can fail.
But how?
Right. They test to see if they can.
If the application
can can handle many users.
Right.
And it doesn't crash.
Right. Exactly.
What is a small testing?
What do you mean important
to quick testing, Quick Testing.
What though?
Quick
testing of some of the most important
functionalities of the application. Right.
What is regression testing?
Second priority test. That's good.
That's a very good answer. Lorna.
Right.
And you would usually run it after
developers introduce new code, right?
Right.
And then you do your regression testing
to make sure that nothing else
broke based on the new changes were to do.
It's right.
And we talked about we talked about
how new changes can break
other parts of the application.
Right goes for example,
maybe a new change was made on some form,
but for some reason that broke the forgot
password feature, right.
That that can happen as well.
Cool.
All right.
White box testing versus black
box testing.
What is white box testing versus black
box testing?
White box testing.
White box is only done by the does.
Okay, but with white box testing,
what do you need to know?
Black box testing don't need to know
internal structure that's good
with white box testing,
white box testing.
What do you know?
You have to know the internal structure,
right?
You have to know the code red
by box testing is like back in testing.
No, is not.
Okay.
We'll talk more about that later.
Okay, Cool.
All right, guys.
Very good class today.
All right. Very good.
We crushed it next week.
We're all going to be hands on zero.
And at this point, there's really nothing
new we're going to learn
which is going to work with JIRA.
We're going to create test cases.
We're going to use a lot of this
terminology already learned
is going to we're going
to we're going to finish
we're going to add more color
to to these topics.
Okay,
cool.
To the point where
to the point
where you understand it and stuff.
And then for those of you that don't
really understand this, that is okay,
because at the end of the course
we're going to review all of this again,
it's not like
we're just going to learn this
and we're just going to put it behind us.
We're going to learn this right now
that you're going to continue
learning everything in class.
And then at the end,
when we review everything, okay,
like it'll probably and most likely it's
going to make a lot more sense at the end.
Okay.
So what program are
we sending the link to download?
What program are we talking about?
Me The
you don't download
JIRA, it's just a website.
Yeah, it's
just a website and a
please read a sales course.
Announcements. Okay. Yeah.
So just log on if you can log in.
That's it. Don't do anything else.
All right, guys,
have a great weekend. All right.
And have a great week.
Keep up your Java skills, All right?
No homework.
Just to
chew homework.
Right.
What should we focus on the most?
Just relax or not. Just relax.
Focus on your job right now.
We're going to.
We're going to hit class hard next week.
All right, cool.
All right. See you guys.
To a good day.