Everyone forgot for the record.
So now Hooks when we talk about
hooks, basically we have two hooks in.
What are these two?
You can, you can.
It's an open gate or
not the same words.
If it
if you were right, then I would take it
if it is already in my mind.
And then later.
Then after that I have spoken before
an honorary consul.
We have in order to deliver the posters
before and seconds after,
we have seen the same kind of annotations
in this dingy part.
But did we had a lot of lot of information
available for victims of litigation
before up to method, before class,
after class before based on her best
before, soon after.
Right.
And sometimes we get confused
which one we use, which will not be.
So let's
wait to make this job simplified for us.
And then instead of using
so many annotations
we can simply use
just to default and appear to simply be
first states for your preconditions
and participants for your condition.
I agree with
high level.
All right.
You don't need to be
imported from
the hooks.
Hooks in the
obviously.
Yes, obviously
we have to use it, particularly
because with the J, you need to remember
whatever the things we are doing with
Jane is related to your class.
It is a little
bit better class.
That was the portion we use
from the unique associates.
These are the versions we use from David.
But apart from these two, all the things
we are importing
from consumer part of the trade.
So please take care of your worst case.
And any the if you have this code
in your machine, then
we have an improved
point.
So before,
after these two hooks, we have more
information
post condition
this precondition,
both hooks would be correct.
Yes. Yes, correct.
So I am coming to this point though,
how we can really put these hooks.
When we keep these hooks in our project,
we give them enough steps.
Package three
steps, library steps, definitions
that are available.
We keep these particular hooks
class inside that each framework is, but
then we could look at group of mistakes
and we are using good management class.
It takes my hooks as a precondition
in most condition
and its package
it should
extent Common interests are common,
but they're spotted.
Like if they're tied for a little bit
about the common.
But there's very much time on specifically
this particular class common metrics
as it is very important, something
this is something we will do in Saturday's
class.
I most probably in separate
this class three and into one of the
class is very painful.
So yes, then you will see that
you will see things.
I'm intentionally, you know,
taking the topics one or two here
and then because if I see that this class
is going to take 3 hours,
not even complete 3 hours, three,
including breaks and everything,
but then do something
if there is a topic that we can not can
begin this two minute 140 minutes.
I intentionally was one.
Those topics to the bigger classes
and their topics would be completed.
The short class in digital.
You take those topics in these classes,
so I cannot I should not break the links
and I can complete
one topic in this class.
So you guys might be thinking
why we are not learning common methods
by going to that.
So there is a particular standard
that is a
I don't want to break the links
to the top of the topic.
I expect to be off
of the topic of extreme tomorrow.
And then sort of do you break the chain?
I don't want to do this until you
So in one flow,
if we could complete one topic
because that it is intended of people,
it is a short topic but it's good it's
a good plan is to complete one topic in
1 to 3. Okay
days.
So now before and after,
these are two hooks we have up the ropes.
The first thing we learned was so far
we paused.
Hard coded data is not possible.
Simply hardcoded it.
And then I showed
all of the possible scenarios for you guys
to parse the data from different sources.
Trade.
So tell me one by one,
what are those sources
that we can predict?
First one was yes.
First
we simply passed are username and password
from config build
properties by right.
First
we passed it from computer properties, but
so that this time I need to pass
hardcoded data and instead of hardcoded
data, what I can do is I can simply code
my get property right value.
And then from there we are reading
the property is based on the key
those guys will provide and based on
those is the best data
by function, especially data
from confident properties mine.
And it could simply
it would simply be in my user password.
Correct.
Is this correct case
nice.
Second we deposited that is stronger
feature rate
feature by now that we showed
how we pass this data
in terms of double quotes rate,
we passed this data.
So you see
that's how we passed the data.
So now this time we are not passing
these keys to add the employee
from my confident properties,
but instead I'm passing it
directly from my cementing right
in my feature point.
So this is the second one, how it reads.
It will convert these particular steps
along with them and then we would see
when I actually implement
this step, it will give me this
stable step definition
where I'm handling previous strings
but force them really last that right.
And then based on the keys
that have voided values are that provided
in my feature while it is taking the data
in my function.
And then I'm calling
this a number of different
so for any question in this part,
instead of calling this data
as a hardcoded or instead of calling
this data from computer properties,
I'm simply passing this data
from my feature.
Right. But again, that is a problem.
I see.
That is a problem.
I see. What is the problem?
The problem is
I can use this in a new build
in one bank for just one import.
If I use this particular step,
then I can implement my decision
and make it execute this scenario just
for one employee, not for all the inputs.
Correct.
Okay.
But when it comes to our principle,
what is our target?
The target is to achieve data driven
testing,
right?
So when I see the target is to achieve
data driven distinct, it simply means
my one scenario should execute
across my deposits of data.
So I need to come up with the idea through
which I can execute my escape across
multiple people's books of data.
So it is pretty much
clear that
if I want to make these kind of scenarios,
I can execute once multiple names
across different sets of data.
I have to either
rely on some external point
to achieve the speed or I need to search
more and more functionality.
Right?
So when I searched
more functionality of the toolbox,
then I found one concept
calls the matter of like
right.
Then I found one concept
called scenario of this.
It would put all of these things
in the process, but
first thing is,
the second thing is
seeing the data from
the box.
People.
So now next thing,
what we didn't really do
is we simply provide scenario outline
instead of scenario.
And then when we provided, then
how do you apply it to the real examples?
Table three This example statement
generally gives us how we can
muster data based on key.
And when
you see you, when you talk about examples
tuple based on key
and we can pass the data
gradients.
So these keys
we will pass in our scenario.
Now tell me one more thing.
This example statement
is limited to just one step,
but we can be use
all the keys can be used in multiple steps
once in any
equal step straight,
it can be using multiple steps.
For example, if I was them with them.
Lastly, and I want to handle this post,
the post system made a limited
second one and last.
The third one is I can do this on,
I can do this.
But so this is the second
we know how it works.
Basically
when you actually execute your scenario.
So executes three names here.
My because the data I mentioned in line
number 2424 disease, it creates three
region in when it creates create region,
I will simply get this data.
I can simply execute this in any one time,
but it will get executed.
Three things.
This is the functionality of the Google
G data
team on disk.
Is this clear? Everyone
wants?
Then what is the other way?
The other bit on behalf of B is
to parse their data by our data table.
Correct
data.
Right. So.
So now what we are going to do
is we are going to parse the data.
But tell me guys, what is the difference
in between detectible in examples?
Examples is also a table
is also going to be a passing data
from both basis.
Then what is the difference?
If you see in data table
there is a key and false
name with the last name is the key, right
is to 1 to 3 M is just 4.6 is the value.
So there is a key and value in the name
Elizabeth
No steps
lost in any argument.
Yes. Yes. Got it.
So one detectible. The major difference.
The major difference
most in any of is body
major differences.
We can use examples
table for multiple steps.
Right.
The keys which we are defining and values
which were DV.
We can use this keys in values
in multiple steps.
But here in this particular
detectable part, we can use this data
only for one particular step,
nor for multiple step.
Yeah, got it.
Where were you guys?
I was expecting your answer.
Since long
a great.
All right, guys.
Now they did.
I do tapes of scenarios.
We have been detected with.
What are those two?
The first one we are seeing here
and what we are doing.
We are simply passing
first name with a them.
And lastly,
and we are providing the values.
That's what we are doing.
So now here what we have to convert
according
to the functionality of the convert.
When I actually create this,
it will give me a different
kind of like this when it gives me
the argument, quantitative grade
this that I would have any to handle.
I need to create a data
the debates automatically insert
this table with
I know key and the loop is a concept I'll
develop it as a concept. All
maps in Java. Right?
So when we talk about mapping,
do what we have to do.
Every single line is returning the map.
If I have multiple rules, multiple maps,
okay, If I take one at one time, fine.
But I have to put it somewhere, right?
So my people maps.
If I have to do that, I need one list.
Then I can store these multiple maps
so listed or add.
This is the last thing
this particular function.
And then I'm adding all the members
together.
However, these things that are working
internally, but I'm just explaining it
the functionality and from there
we can read this database from the key.
So inverse preparation.
By passing all the guides, it will read
the complete data from the of these
I am passing values which is reading
similarly passing in the Keys.
We have already provided values.
It will read similarly Bertoldo excellent.
There are some things working here,
right?
Great.
Great. Someone forgot the homework.
I I'm not to remember the need.
Someone forgot I was.
I woke up last year, right?
I mean 530 or six I woke up
and I saw a couple of messages
from students and someone was discussing,
Hey, I forgot the whole room better.
Well,
so even if everything they do let me know
so that I will remind you again
and again and again.
All right.
I see you are the culprit.
There
is going to
Angelino, Chicago.
Really?
Not a great one for like.
Fine.
Excellent.
So now let me put this part of the books
in the data from examples
and then from 830
oh, we're supposed
exempt books.
That is
a keeper, because that word
simple statement, we keep
it. We do
that.
So for any questions, a student,
any questions, anyone
here?
Excellent.
Is there any other one
who has any question?
Just fine.
Now, now,
let's come back to this particular
topic here.
Again, important point is
now we are going to be a little bit
on not much.
Obviously, that framework
is not deep down, but two years
from now onwards,
we are going a little bit deep
and will try to understand how things
connected internally in the framework.
Right.
So from now onwards
we are starting to give the real sheet
of one compute framework and we will see
how this thing works for rate.
Right now we are using Neven Project,
but I know we do not have this memory
do it right even though I have been
writing in my machine.
But you guys looked at it so I wish it
when reading and we think you would meet.
Great.
I hope for Mac users Bruins join everyone.
Everyone has a room in your machine
and for
Windows users always easy to download
to create memory in your local machine.
So I mentioned the reduce
bottleneck. Great.
No idea.
Nine such
good idea
slide
illuminated
only two days.
Now see one more scenario left
so far for passing their data.
Again, this data table examples
Table feature While parsing the data
from config properties.
Fine.
All these options are available.
Very good options.
Data table.
Excellent options.
Let's say game scenario.
They will show you here we are passing
the data would not based on gain value
there
we parsed as maps here we are passing
this detectable as
in list
rate in passing this data as list point.
No issues.
So now this time
when we are simply passing the options,
we can take all of these options
in the list.
Similarly, we can take these options
from the application on the list
and we compare these two options. This
to list together.
It would list adequate possibilities.
But again, like I said, these
are these scenarios
that are applicable and appropriate.
When the volume of your data is small,
the volume of
your data is not small,
then this to not use
more use that.
In that case, what we have to do,
we have to keep our best
data separate from our best script.
This is very important.
We need to learn this line
so that the model, the world,
we do it.
What we are going to do is
this is my Alexa
script, my class.
I should be having one district
of finance trade
separate district of late this time.
I will write my script everything here
and I will keep my data here.
I will pass this data in my script
from here.
Right?
I have to create a function through
which I can read my data
and use my trade in my classes.
So what is the advantage that advantages
this fight could
be a large amount of data.
This particular district
file can be a large amount of readers.
Even the volume of the data is large.
I can keep it the same thing
if I am changing something in my code,
if I'm changing something
that the class is, it's
not going to affect my business
development
or if I'm changing or playing
with the data, it's not going to affect
with my code
or district the advantage
of using this data to replace
everything.
Whenever you will be working
in the daytime
industry or on the project grade
that you have to follow
this particular functionality,
this concept you have to follow.
You cannot pass here today.
You should not passing to this particular
individual based or not because let's see
if you are working with Facebook
or if you're working with a Netflix
or maybe any company data
the big fight next.
Big James If you're working with them,
you have produced every single application
across millions of years,
right?
Invest in mine.
We did not millions of users,
maybe hundreds of users.
We don't have that much of time to invent.
Every single user was named middle name,
last name, similarity, date of birth,
location, nationality,
passport number and love level.
So many things in your example.
Stupid.
Do you have that window of time?
No. Right.
So we're to pass this data.
Simply
keep this data in your one particular
apps migrated from that find you can read
so now need we use sequence for data
sequel is for data
this it's not a my great support
so when you will be actually studying
the database that you will read
the database connection and everything
but I'm talking about one particular
result no data right?
So what, what would be the data plans?
We can have
sort of options see us to do together.
We can mix them all by.
We get faster in this environment, we can
pass stricter directly picture weight.
Similarly,
we can pass data from our Excel,
find your is correct data, but
all right.
So now the next thing
which we are going to study is excel
in how to read data
from Excel in our scenario.
So we will be writing a function
which will be the global function,
whatever the things that we will going
to provide in this data by,
except why it will read all the data
based on the gives from there
and it will simply pass
through that framework.
Is it clear?
So class, it's very easy.
I should
clean and clear.
We have one option simple
with the name clean and clear,
crystal clean.
You get about it.
You do that
well.
Shampoo in progress.
If everywhere it is
now, people are not afraid of this.
This how convenient.
Really? And made in India.
So how would we Indians
maybe adopt things?
All right.
Like with Indian, with the right industry.
You see faith.
People from India, the U.S.A.,
they become the CEO of the companies
and the managing director, assistant vice
president, president of marketing,
and so many things.
Right.
Is it Asian?
We read by.
I had never come across
with this kind of information in books
I never meet
says, Well, to be honest
right they look like in like
this piece
to the founder of please
to make him I made in person
yeah look in the category
All right
thanks.
Why I always request my experience.
Stop watching television.
There's some memories.
Right?
So now what we have to do is see
if I am going to provide my decided
that it one particular place to tell me
this providing this data in a bite,
it is a part of Java
or non Java
has seen.
My question is if I'm going to provide
Wendy's did that in one particular funny
right to this Baileys Java or non
Java called mystic Mundo Excellent point.
Passing their data in a Katrina
search on is non
java good.
So now.
Nor is it possible that I can be passed.
I can pass my data in from my people.
Excel likes language
possible for particular module.
Speak to them readable by trained.
We can do that to tell me
which position I have in my framework.
The framework.
Now we are starting to break slowly.
We are starting to be
good me which part I have
where I can keep all the non java stuff
and the resources
and the resources.
Fine. So let me do one thing.
If you see I have features, I have config,
I'm going to create one of the default
and I'm going to create another directly
component
is data
release.
I created another pool
directly under resources called this data.
The reason behind
this is because in this disaster now
I can have an Excel point
or I can have multiple exceptions
to bring me on the situation
depending on the request.
Because if I keep only one Excel point
here, then obviously it is of no point,
no use because no multiple examples
would make this resource structure
complex way.
So I need to have separate position,
separate
location for separate kind of things.
All right.
And in save this particular I can provide
my Excel point.
It's not going feature on us.
It started will be to expand
independent resources.
You'll see if it wasn't a feature
it should be.
And this under feature it should again.
But it is in the same line
with the feature
I hope is
you know how to read this header,
how we can observe this error
in everything in the project.
Everyone knows it.
Great, simple book.
So now, now remember we have
we have
two versions rate of Excel in mind.
The first is DAW excellence
and second is DAW excellence.
It's these are two for amount of Excel
we all have.
We only started this to excel points
and not only not excellence
and not excellence,
everyone is available this
nowadays in the latest in of this we use
we use which one
majority of bunch we use both
Excel is ex getting
by and so here also with it
I use both nice silver
jack of almost four month clean.
So now dart excel s extra
we are going to use here.
Let's see.
But if your Microsoft office
is the older one right
and you guys are using the word Excel
this time to probably point
well, we should change that.
I reached any rate in our code.
So let's start.
Let me prepare one excellent post.
So let me open the exam. Find this
fine line.
So let me create a new exemplar control
and now I'm going to provide I'm
going to provide the data
by voting support, check
how to district come up.
You mean this one?
Well, you
simply right
click on resources
and you going to directly
and rate is required
and then it can use this data.
So now whatever the excel
by which we will be using to master data,
we will keep all those exit points here.
Okay. So
any name.
Right?
So now, guys,
let's prepare the district of Post
and now to prepare their district
that we must know the scenario
which we would be using.
So let's talk about this scenario first.
I would go here
even as do I need to pull the enemy
username and password from that particular
base?
Do I need to pass admin username
and password to simply know
it is a one time activity
which I am dealing already with
and paid with my configured properties?
Fine. So I didn't.
I don't need the password
for my particular
by the data
which I would be using every now and then.
Made for news
and where the value would be.
Large bank. But I need to pass from Excel.
But the upfront rate.
So now
what I'm see is basically I need to pay
the employee getting
credits, I need to add the employee.
So when I'm going to add employee,
I need to pass force to me,
I need to pass,
I need must be asked to me.
This time we will provide for do but
photograph visible.
All right.
So we will upload the photograph
also will select this create login details
will provide username password, confirm
password and then will simply separate it.
Okay.
I hope you understand my point.
What I'm excluding whatever the are
there needs to be able to save me.
We are sending
mostly we are sending within them.
We are sending last two names.
We are sending photo that we are taking on
to create login details checkbox.
Then we will enter the username password
convoke password
and then we will click on Save
and that's how we add the employee.
This time
it is going to be one
nice.
So let's go ahead and do it
with is.
My ex implied that this is my exit
from external. Right.
Right right.
But real employee. Correct.
So now the first thing I'm going to write
it is mine
forced me.
The second one is mine,
isn't it?
The third one is my last name.
Then the fourth look is mine
for the Ram.
That is the remote point. What?
I'm doing it.
Then it would be my username
and the last one would be my password.
So I need to pass anything for logging
checkboxes here.
No need to pass anything for checkbox.
Norm.
Do you think that we need to pass
or confirm password field as well
in exit by?
Because whatever the things we are passing
in, our password rate does seem to
be killed by something.
The password is well, same as password.
We can use.
But then why do it unnecessarily?
When instructed, we can use the same.
Right? Exactly.
Now, now let's create
a user security force
name with an impossibility.
So first name will be alone. And Aisha.
So it would be Alicia.
This would be the first name
is always be Ms..
It is no better than this for Milena.
And then the last name will be
the Ms.
nine and both have in it
and a definite trade in the last.
So now, even if I mix
it, it could be seen
for a and with the same
photograph part trade photograph by trade.
Just to keep it, keep it like this.
I will tell you what to do
with the photographs.
Also.
Then the user name would be here.
The user name would be should be open.
Excellent volume
if you want to. Sebastian.
You can also you can do this.
No issues, but in the end you will get it.
See the last four words of someone's
name, right is the complete name and
unusual almost.
Really? Yes.
Or one I know.
All right, so now the username.
I'm going to grow a trade, so make sure
that this username must not exist there.
There's white indentured.
I provide this kind of name so that
my data don't match their contract, but
whenever I meet them, I.
Okay, so now let's take the username
and password.
So here I'm thinking for these below show.
One, two, three.
The username and password would be
one, two, three,
four, five,
and then the password would be replaced.
It's based.
One, two, three, exclamation mark.
Now the only thing remaining here,
the only thing remaining here
is the photograph getting
selected.
So how we generally buzz
the photograph in know exactly.
But we need to post the bad photograph.
Yes, yes, yes. Correct.
So unfortunately, I do not have any
images of its downloaded post
of images
of the images.
Lipstick. Anyone from here?
Maybe
like this? Something.
So this one
and save the image.
So which format we need GBG.
I will take the GBG one
and let's keep it in the download.
The name of the image would be badge
image, the image of the Bachelor.
When this very political
not wanted to exist or gbg
image point record
this image is not really.
We have this particular image. Mm.
Nice one.
Someone use this one
is a take it from here.
Right. And
would be listed here
now can you see this actually
would be image behavior on my text.
Always
going
be one.
See this particular part.
Right.
I have to provide the body of this image
in my excellent Right.
So how to get the path of this.
In which case when should I go
this?
Should I go to get the bad
properties?
Thank you, sir.
You see here
it says this is the bottom, right?
This is the board.
And here I have to provide the name
with the extension.
Right.
So we take this particular path from here.
Okay?
No reason why.
Excuse, I.
I have to go in my exit.
I will be used to this particular block.
Is this the complete board
or do any to do anything else here?
This can
slash
image talk
g b g name of the file with extension.
So now if you see I have this
match element image right.
Would really name would simply image
image file.
So this is that image or gbg
copy is part of it.
Right click by the gentleman.
But everyone is not using this right.
So that's why I have to read this
image.
Don't you be? Is this the correct one?
People might be having Windows
eight, Windows eight.
Right.
So for them also, I need to take, you
know, there's going to be a single person.
Everyone can understand the things.
If I'm one of those vendors
of an operating system,
we people who are using
the little logins, right.
They might be having the problem
or the older the problem
now is create looks created.
Thank you, sir.
Do you want to
take another image
for on that user of the scene
which we can use
whatever the other user, any
similarly we can use?
Or do we need to remove symbol for
one, let's take the neutral name.
It would be Silva plus Marina, Silvana
Right.
And middle name is always the best one. We
but the last name be
along
the same.
But it would be
said one the near one
right it is
1235.
I can come up with new names. All right
then. Once
then after this.
The third employee.
We need
is So the third one
It with the grid is noble.
So Hanna thumb.
So see is going to
observe a nice fade.
Next take this.
So Hanna nice once you look mine only
in as Google using same image for the
oh five.
Audrey let's take this and then simply
we need to change this one.
So I'm changing it too.
So one, two, three, four, five.
For these three employees,
we prepared this data.
Is this correct?
Let's now
the very first thing I need to do is
let's change the name of this particular
sheet from here.
So when I change the name of this sheet,
I will provide this neat
name as I would name as employee data
because I want to add on the employee
copy,
I need to add on the employment database.
So for any question how we prepare this,
this data and let's see,
this file is excellent.
You see it is asking for the text
unless it is asking for the text this.
So I'm going to save
and it's not excellent.
It's fine.
And the name would be it's
taken.
Believe it, Jared.
It was fine.
Would be nice to
remain
documents
or big stock because it would take
yes it is an index to know what I'm doing.
I see. I'm simply copying.
I'm simply this particular part because.
Thank you, sir.
Because this file should be
in my framework, not in my local machine.
But it right now
it is in my local machine.
Does it make any sense
to have this right on my local machine?
No, because tomorrow
my goal will be in the repository.
My good will be in someone else's machine
and then also they will use
the same database.
And we need to make everything
organized, everything unique and uniform
across all the platforms.
Doesn't matter
which operating system we are using,
which location we are in, right?
Every single thing doesn't matter.
But whenever I want to call this data,
I should be able to call this data, right?
So that's why this fight
must be having in my in my favor.
So let's go.
And simply copy this particular mine
and pasted under your district apart
instead of like,
see if this does their day job.
Every store in this.
Yes. Okay.
And Eric,
now you'll see I have this
decided that each mistakes
the list explained here available in my
lists.
Anyone has any question in this part
why we kept to this particular example
in the framework.
Is everyone good
for now?
First,
let me give you the overall scenario.
What we are going to do, the function
see, we have four spec
to be
every last name,
be a username and password.
Can you do it again
please. I this to find.
So what you have to do is
go wherever your excel file is available.
Just right
click on add fight or simply copy
the code simply copy the point.
When you copy this file from here,
go to your intelligent.
What is your project with your project?
Development Goal input is data
heart rate click and paste it.
Or simply, you can use concurrency control
for Windows
one in command C command we put make once.
All right.
City.
The very human I was giving the name,
I would have given you the name as Koroma
with the Katrina
this take
all right case
so now now here
see these are these are the keys
I have provided in here.
Let's see.
I appropriate the values.
I'm just giving the random values going.
Okay.
So did you can see
is this looks like my ex
and we read the data which I'm passing
from makes it like correct.
Is it same or not?
Now just imagine.
Just imagine the concept.
Somehow you have a three for now.
Just there's been a noisy
way is the concept of data table
in detail also
when passing the key and value data.
Also we were getting one map correct
correctly.
We were getting a map
from every single room.
Remember he's coming from here, values
coming from here.
Right?
And when we talk about key
and value, it creates a map.
It creates the map.
But the problem is now the
what is the problem?
The problem is when we were actually using
art or detectible,
right in that detective,
we had all these things be implemented,
we had all these things pre implemented.
But as a pre implemented,
it means the function was already building
function, right?
So we were not actually
writing the function,
but we were simply implementing
the function, calling that function.
But now this, the menu is different.
This time we have to write this function
to parse the data
from our excel by not actual script.
There's what we need to do
on our own coding.
And to do this, we need to put this
how we can create this particular part.
Okay, so first
we have to get onto already this data
in Excel by now we will create
a global function to read that.
It doesn't matter
how many boots I would be having,
how many drawers,
how many columns and everything.
Just one function will identify this
and that function.
We definitely read the data for me
from my cell phone.
I wrote Case,
so we are going to write that particular
function, how things will work there.
That's what I'm going to spend you
now first with this example
and then when we see this example,
then only we will proceed further
and we see how things are going to work.
Okay, Is this okay to everyone? Want
nice.
So now see,
now see,
this rule
is your key.
This rule is your window
bistro again.
Similarly, if one more rule,
it means also one more value.
So remember one thing.
If you observe,
if you can see here, you're one
that is your key is always constraint.
It means your key is on risk
coming from just one rule.
Every name values are changing.
Three would be level d
d 30 defaulting deep.
And so on.
This particular part, this particular part
is always unique, right?
So we can provide the value for this one
and then yes, got it.
And then for every single rule, when will
I treat it will give me the values.
So these will come
always from the same point,
but every time values will come
from the different points.
Great values will come first from B1, B2,
then B3, then reboot, etc.
Based on the number of lines here. Great.
Understood what z 20.
Now here, here.
Let me tell you another important point,
because when this point is clear
how we're going to take the data
right in the form of G in the loop here.
So these will be constant
values would be changing everything.
For the second thing here,
what is more important,
see how to read every single detail
from every single.
Remember, first we have Excel workbook,
what we have Excel file,
we call it Workbook
release.
Now, like I said, in automation,
we have to do
what automation wants,
what we need to do way automation.
Your automation doesn't know
in this workbook you have so many sheets
from which we have to read it.
So the ready force thing,
what we have to do, we have to look in
this workbook in our code.
To my point,
we have to locate this workbook
in our code.
Second thing in this workbook,
if you see a lot of small
sheet names available here,
we're deploying the name code employee.
Did the grade, so we have to build hey,
going to this particular workbook
and in this particular workbook
go into this particular worksheet
because my need to be
I can have the same kind of data
in some other worksheet as well.
But your code will not want to read
anything like this, right?
We have Google what to read,
what part you need, read this.
So first we will locate the workbook.
Inside
the workbook will locate the worksheet.
Inside the worksheet
we will provide this rule
where we are having all the keys,
all the keys played,
and then we will provide the data
for all the rules.
We will be having all the values.
So remember for reading the data,
for reading the data
and getting the physical number
of rules we have a function
for getting the physical number of rules.
How many rules are available?
We have the function,
but we do not have a function,
but physical number of columns.
For physical number of columns,
we do not have a function.
So how we will do it,
I will tell you in the function.
But right now I'm
just giving you the overview.
Things which we are going to implement
is first we will identify
Workbook three,
then we will identify worksheet in their,
we will read the data for all the keys,
all the rules in terms of math.
So now, now see, when I have this
particular key force to read
because it is part.
So now if you see
my first rule is return me first
met one great map, one using the key.
And when you read
from this particular room
next time in the next position
when it will return the values,
it will return the value from this rule.
So my map will also be having
key and value.
It will also be have a key
and then the correct.
Is this correct?
So every row is returning one
particular map.
If it was returning one particular map
or not,
big keys always seem
like value is different for us.
It is coming from one second.
It is coming from we would.
Yes, correct.
And every rule is returning the new web.
Now, what is the problem here?
If I don't stay this map anywhere
next time, if it returns the new map.
So this map will overwrite the old.
I think
if I look see then what would happen
if I take the over rate simply replaced.
So before getting and reading data
from this, they can rule.
First I have to get this map
and then I have to add this member state,
this map somewhere.
So how we will read,
we can take map 1.17 and then map two,
then see, then map three,
then see if and so on and so on.
Read this.
So when I see this same option,
it simply means
I need multiple maps in one place,
one map to remember.
It's one depending on the dataset
I will do, provided
I read all of these maps there.
Right.
So to get all of these maps in one place,
which point of collection
I can use here from Java.
Yes, we can use here list read.
What we can use here is
we can use this list.
So in this list of map, right
where I would be having de comma value,
but it is free trade.
And then I would be using your classic
ABC function.
Something that gives
this is something work
my data table is A to
Z on my list of map connect.
So now what I'm doing, I have a list
and in this list I'm having multiple maps.
Correct. And making multiple maps.
And this particular function,
if you observe closely your data
when you go into your deductible,
it is actually returning us.
This particular mark
in your data
when you see it is returning as this,
but only data table is maps
in your suitcase.
My detective is returning
the same function
what we are going to implement.
So this is specifically for detecting,
but we are going to create this function,
a global function, to read
any kind of data, any value from any cell.
In my example
is everyone,
should we go ahead
and write this function?
Right?
So now this one function
will be applicable to my entire framework,
right to my implement.
The same function will work.
So tell me if I have something
that is applicable to my airplane work.
And this is a part of Java
because I with great Java codes
where we keep all of these things
common, we
is in utils
correctly,
we're getting a better job of this.
We will keep this particular thing. Right?
So when I go utils right lives, click here
another find and the name of this file
would be a new class
the name of the new class would be
excellent.
The the name of this fight,
it would be Excel.
Really great case.
So the code read my excel by
I will write this
code here industry
in the spirit of one
point
should be in this function
is everyone with me
doing or support as you said.
So I will follow
public
stating
like open exit.
The very first thing.
What I have to do is I have to open the
my category.
We have them the right.
So first I have to open the excellent
right to expand.
Unless if I open the fight,
how would I read the data?
I can't read so I will not pass anything
hardcoded again,
I will provide the fighting party
of frames, but I the file
fight board for my exam like this.
Very very well.
We'll call this particular matter.
I will provide this, but wherever
I want to read this particular thing.
So it is here.
How many of you guys still remember
for the data to open the fight?
The go to open the fight
lights.
Come on.
We have done it. Then millions of times.
The new fight
the stream to
We are passing this particular
file input stream right is
it should ask for a fight,
not form exception.
So we put it here. Correct.
And then here
I'm going to raid for my vulnerable.
But it would be my workbook.
I'm taking rate of workbook
which can begin here
from my user model.
This particular one, what textbook?
So from being I'm taking this or argy
bargy 0.0 is
is don't use at a moderate or workbook.
All right.
What is
equal to which I'm speaking here
is equals to new X.
This is the workbook X is the workbook.
Now let's make sure here.
Okay, fine.
Excess baggage clause. Fine.
Let's get the get across here guys.
Whoever is using whoever is using
Excel as X fight, you have to call X.
This is F workbook
and whoever is is in not excellent fight.
You have to call edge.
Is this
workbook
Silva You have all the files, right?
So for different files
you have to call different marks.
The first one is acceptance of workbook
is for the ones
who are using not a 6.1,
but if you're using not explicit plain
Excel point, then be able to use Edge.
Is this one you see?
You'll see here you
will get the edges of visible
rate again.
Book one
edge bit of this if
workbook can you see guys
we are getting this page
is this F workbook also does this
for the ones who are using
you're not Exelis by appointment
since majority or I think everyone
is using a six by appointment.
We are using x.
This is one book.
Is it clear to everyone?
Fine.
So this is my this is my post function
that I have three days.
This is my post function.
After this
I need to write another function nicely.
I open,
I open my excellent multi excel played.
What is the next task?
I have to identify which sheet
and would do work upon
getting
that it would sheet and working in.
If the fight is not X,
then the end of it x and the end of will
no flag.
We can't take the extension. Right.
It should support.
I mean it depends on the Microsoft Office
word and which one you use.
If it is in 1997 it will not support.
Don't extend it six
If you're using this 2003 in the later
one, it would support or take to six
point.
Now the next thing is
we have the particular sheet
here.
I'm going to write the function
public element is why
I'm making one of this functions
the statement.
What is the reason behind this one?
Making this function
is treating invalid functions.
Yes, because I'm going to use
all of this functions in other classes.
I know which class I'm
going to read the data so I can read it.
Anyway, this data way
I'm making, this functions as static.
I don't need to create
the object of the class.
And because this function now, I'm
not returning anything.
That's why I'm making them void
reusable.
Great, ma'am.
So now here also
they will provide sheet because today
I'm busing the data from one sheet.
Tomorrow I might be passing the data from
some one of the shooters would be erased.
So sheet again belongs to your or not
Apache or boy or assistant user model.
So from here
I would provide this sheet equals
to in this book don't
look don't get that
What is the issue here?
That is why I'm not getting this book
object
any any data.
Yes. Correct.
This is not my variable,
which is look and see.
This is middle my one function.
So the accessibility
is limited to one particular method.
So what I have to do,
I have to define it on a class level
because I will be using it
in different methods.
So let me do it.
I'm going to make it this technique,
this workbook as book,
and this time I read deleted from you.
Now see, in the end it is called
similarly sheet.
I will be using everywhere,
so I'm going to use this sheet as sheet.
And here I will remove this part.
Now see,
it is working on what we did this time.
Make sense?
Gates First I opened the template,
then I got the sheet name in this sheet.
Now I am going to read how many Jews
I had right there from visual.
I'm going to get what kind of data.
So now let me write another function here.
The function is public
static.
I'm seeing in is
why I'm singing for the to count
is why I wrote
the return type is in digital
in this particular function
because it will return
the total number of rules
and then it will return
to the number of rules.
It will be in the digital form
like there's when I'm writing.
It is in digital function,
so it will return me.
What it will eliminate is a function
called from this sheet.
It will return get
physical number of course
retains this function due
to physical number of rules will return
How many rules I have in particular sheet
is this being
every one, each
let's now.
Next thing I need is a public static
and now I need gained
columns. Come
this time.
This time I'm having a problem
because there is no function
that I have in Java which returns
the actual column column for example,
the physical number of columns.
That is no method. I don't have anything.
So here I have to rely on my rules
right from which rule
I am getting the data.
So remember
how to get the actual column
going to every rule.
One example here, this is the Ruby
here.
It gives value, a new value value, right?
So when we go into this rule,
the last the last number of column, Right.
Which is a physical column.
Physical column. Right.
So we will see every single scene in
last number of physical scene,
which would be easier to read.
It means the total number of columns
that are relevant.
For example, how many physical
since I have available in digital?
One, two, three, four, five.
So how many columns I have in this room?
Five.
Similarly going to this look again?
Five and so on.
Understood how I'm going to read it.
We're going of columns.
So here I have to rely,
I have to rely on my
first row index right?
I have to rely on my windings.
So from here
I will see what it will return.
It will in my first
sheet.
Don't get
it through here.
I will pass my drawings.
Don't it says get
physical. No at all.
Since it physical since.
This is the function.
These are the two functions
which will return my overall
total rules, scope and total the cops.
So for any question is reduce
opening the exam by opening the sheet
in Excel point with sheet
taking the total rules
and then taking the total columns
so far.
Is this understandable to everyone?
What I'm doing
now, whatever
the things we are seeing here, right,
you're seeing as of now,
it is returning me
draws, counts, sheet name by name.
But in the end I need to work,
I need values, I need to read the data
which is available in every drawer.
And but in this still screen,
I need to read that data.
So how can it read the data to me
right under the function of late standing.
And this time I'm my function name is
Gate Gates to
why I make this gates as a stream face.
I am it is a string because the data
which I'm widely
available in my excel,
it is available in which forward
I'm passing User name Password.
First name William last name.
We are this in which former days
stream forward.
Right?
So when I'm passing this
in the spring forward,
I'm going to take this data
as a return of this particular function
industry.
Fine.
Let's go ahead and do it.
So first, what I would write,
I would write in integer.
First thing is going to the part.
So take index Second thing is
go into the column parts
of 30 column or index.
It means in which rule, which column
you're going to one rule, one column
it reads once it contains in that still
we will assume that it will read the data.
So let me read your return in this sheet
straight
post to get through on this little index.
Don't get
sent from here.
And in this state based on the column
index,
don't do the last thing
because now we got the rule,
we got the steel in this.
And what it the data
I'm having convert it into a string.
So to convert something into string
that is a method in Java we use
which is don't do is bring
that can would simply table
string for
all the here on the Java
the easier case which is
getting whatever we want not.
Is there anyone who has any question
in this part what we are doing.
I hope I'm I'm expanding it
in your satisfaction level.
It is that anything
if I'm missing, do let me know
what you do in 43 point.
So I'll see you See what I need?
Let me open myself.
This is my exit point.
I got this rule.
I. I got this column.
For example, second row, first quarter.
I got this identified.
But still it is of no use.
If I don't read this data correct,
I have to read the
data which is available in every state.
So this one, the highlighted one is in
this one is also said.
This one is also state.
This one is also saying
how we can identify the state,
identify the state based on rule
and quantum mechanics.
So for this one, the rule is two,
column is one,
this one rule is two, column is two,
this one, the rule is three columns one.
This one rule is three.
Column is to install, right?
So here in my function
I'm passing groupings in column index
to identify a bristle
when I'm taking in the single center
data, which I'm heavy,
I'm converting it into string.
So this function is returning the data
from every single cell
and converting the people that spring upon
which so in the to find the important
thing
is the string from every single set. Now
nice so far right
raw ingredients spaces are really good.
Maybe not
opening the excel by cinnamon,
cumin, seeds, oil, everything being played
good shit, row, count, column count.
So data, everything we now know actually
starts from year grade
with Hollywood movie.
Which one?
Now we are going to make
Every single rule is a map.
We will create the function
where we can see
that every single row
is returning me somewhere.
After taking that the in the map,
I will it in the list
and then again I will do it in a digital
and then the little
and then another little thing.
So this is what we want to do now.
So just one function
I have to write just one function.
Should I write the break rather than
I think we should continue.
We should continue right now.
Okay.
Yes, yes, yes.
That's what I'm thinking.
Before, if the rate before rates
that let's hook it.
I'm going to write in
public
static
all use all format
and where every map is returning me
string in terms of key
the string in terms of value.
So I am writing this function excel
in two
Excel and to list my
client launch was important
is very case exiting to list map rate.
So from the Excel,
we are taking the data in the form of MAP
and we are putting
all of these things in the list.
That is the thing we are going to do
that is not good.
Things
don't take this much attention rate days.
I see a lot of people
not commenting though
because everyone is busy in typing
till there is just a five lines of code.
This code can not make you afraid of
anything.
Don't worry,
we are doing it and we will do it.
I will experiment with great stuff.
I know, I know.
I'm When I say that you're not yet
you always ready And I have just seen.
Don't pay any attention. All right.
Good extras. It's very easy.
We are going to do
it now. See, first thing news
is there.
Discord will be reusable,
y'all.
Whatever things I'm writing,
it is reusable.
There is nothing which we can not reuse.
That's why we call it framework.
Those things is for getting the data
from the Excel.
Find.
First, I need to identify the Excel points
so to to get the Excel value
we have any function.
Do we have any function
to get the accent by
students?
Yes, we do have Open Excel.
We do have open Excel. Great.
And it is asking for five months. So fine.
I have to provide this.
I have to provide this here
argument is string file, but comma,
the string next thing will be mine
sheet
shooting rate.
So it would be my file.
But in this Excel fight in this sense,
by any token
do we have any function to get this unit
is do we
have any function to get the sheet name.
Come on
you just we do have that function called
get sheet and here we are operating me
see how easy it is.
This function is reading the sheet name.
This function is going to return the file
name read file pop.
So now my file is opened,
my sheet is open.
In that sheet,
I am going to get the data right.
So first the first thing,
let me define my function call list
inside this list,
because I'm going to prepare for
this is the preparation
screen as a user.
Name the string also as a key
and as a value right here.
I'm going to give it C as my
data is equals,
but I'm going to make it in the edit list
for which
reason we are making it Grace
because we are going to get the maps,
we are going to get the maps
from every single row.
Those maps we have to add this list,
so I am putting it in the list.
Okay.
That's why we made this a list.
As of now, we just declared it.
We are not using it as of now
if someone has any question
why we declared it,
because we are going to receive the map
from Excel by at every the map
we have to add in the list.
All the maps declare it as of now.
Fine.
Let's go ahead
because I'm going
to write the code for Outlook.
So my outlook is going to define the over
all complete rules
that I would be having to read.
The keys.
My outer loop, which I'm going to write
here,
is going to define the keys that I have.
Fine.
So what I'm going to do here
see, I'm going to write a for loop.
I'm going to make a look.
And this loops the integer.
The rule is equal one
line.
There's always a concern.
One this
and then simple.
This rule
book.
When the rule counties less than three,
then I'm seeing here again Great rule
plus last plus, plus, plus.
Now see,
because I'm going to read the data.
I'm going to read the data.
So my zero through my zero
draw is already there.
Is I one this excel
find this excellent line if you see
So my business is already booked
it is already constrained.
I don't need this right now.
I need the data from the hospital
and then swans one so on.
Right to explain digitally.
I buzzed equals to one.
Those are indisputable.
I am passing two is equal to one
and then two and I would be getting right.
So rule count minus one.
It is the last rule in the last rule
one by one because increment of greater
I would it.
So it will read the data for all the rules
from here this particular function
let's cross further
while I am reading this.
I'm reading this I'm going to write here
Creating a map.
Creating a map. Every rule.
Now see this If I am in the force total,
if I'm in this or actually rule one,
it means second rule.
If I in this rules
principle one not as good
index is always a spread from zero here.
But rule one we're taking
because my values start from little one.
Okay, now here, see,
when we are in the rule one,
we are getting here,
that's also an index of keys.
We are getting values from the rule.
So when we are ready and value both.
We have to prepare and we have to create
a map right for every rule.
That's what we are going to do now.
So first
I'm going to write a map, root,
key and value out of the string forward
or not, based on case
what key and value is available
in my string one.
And I'm going to link the hash map here,
which is why we use
Java clusters of link is,
but it maintains the order.
The order of insertion maintains.
It means if I am going to read first row,
it will maintain it the first place only
and then second place, third place
and so on.
It's using the link map. Yes.
Right.
You see everyone understand?
Everyone knows already.
So I do need to teach you, but a mini code
you can write on your own days.
No issues.
Then the next thing is I'm going to write
the looping
through the values.
Looping through the values.
Oh, on
I. No, sir.
But if you do everything,
then what would I do with C?
We are going to create a map.
So not inside this map and I'm
going to add the value for a string.
Read string as a key
and spring as a value.
So first we are taking fine.
I don't have any issue for that,
but for getting the data
from every single from every single set
we have to write it.
Let's write another for loop.
This for loop
is under my previous or loop.
Make sure. Let's
make sure
this for loop is under my
this particular follow
character correct.
So now I'm going to write
for this particular one.
I'm saying
integer column is equal to zero.
Then you to my appointed a column zero
when I provided
rule one
you had nested for the print case.
I have related column zero but draw one
Earlier time I provided
Yes because doesn't matter read
which rule we are in.
We will always read the values
from the first column to columns.
You know what it means?
First column three.
So my first name is all relevant
in first column, middle
name and second columns of next zero
means first column.
That's why I'm waiting here.
And then my column is going to
define is defined by total column counts,
which is coming from my group
in which you am right, guys.
And then simply I'm putting it
here, column,
column plus plus again, increment operator
again increment.
Any issue in understanding
this particular line
index,
my column count is depending on room rate.
It is so how many rows
I have based on these rules
I will use
before my code.
Nice line.
So now see here, read
my column count is depending on my rules.
Railways doesn't matter
how many rows I have.
My This particular part
will read all those rules
and based on these rules
my this particular function works
and will give me the data
from every single column great
progress.
Now in the map.
In the map, I'm going to put the data
so when I use what method, it
simply needs to be the use Mr.
Dot egg to build something in the list.
We use map
to put to add something in the map.
Please correct me if I'm wrong.
My concepts of governance
is very, very sympathetic.
Is this correct?
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Next, I will ask if I have any problem.
You got it right.
So now here in this map,
right in this map, I'm going to put what
simply stated
that there is the use of this case.
I'm reading from one here already.
I need only send to read to select
from every single column.
So let me call this particular my text.
It is asking for two things row
index and column index
and I'm providing
intentionally through index zero.
What does it mean? The row index is zero?
I wish I knew the meaning of this function
and column index coming from my column.
It coming from my column
in case.
So when I provide this data rule
in data
zero and column index, it means what
it means, what it means.
This is my key.
Now I need a value.
So for value, simple go here rule column
will come on.
Now let me explain you
this particular function,
how this function will work
now sees my memory
density and value correct
categories.
Display display is something important and
when I write this line
map don't put right this matter.
Look straight here.
See, this is my key and this is my value.
When I see zero, it means my force.
See, consider.
This is my exactly.
When I see rule zero, it means only this.
We not
only destroyed it and when I say column
counter,
if column is zero, so zero zero, this one
zero comma one, this one zero, comma two,
this one, zero three, this one.
That's how it will read all the keys
from this particular line or not.
And that's good how we are getting
the keys from this function.
Now see this second after comma,
we get values.
So in values are requesting zero.
I'm passing through.
This row is coming from me
and from the rule one.
It means that it is starting from
it is a starting.
Come on, it is starting from here.
Right? So it is giving me all the rule.
Count one by one,
one by one, one by one column control.
So coming from here
because it starts from zero,
so one by one, one by one, One by one.
Right.
So next time I go from here, value
over from here.
The next time I go from in value,
I go from here.
Next time I go from here and value
I got from the right place.
When I got this value in value,
it is making one simple grade again.
It is also creating one map.
It is also creating one map and so on.
That's how my function will work.
Any issues?
One understanding this,
what we are doing
and the issue in this part, students
noise.
Good.
So now, now, now see here so far
what we are doing,
we have created a map for every tool,
but it forced migration.
This particular part will return me
forced to read
this particular will return was to map
not all the maps.
One maybe one thing too.
When I got this one map, remember
I told you
we have to speed this map at one place.
If we don't save this map,
then what would happen?
My map.
My next map, which is upcoming that will
override this particular menu correct.
And then I would be able to utilize it.
So first, I have to keep this map.
I have received this map somewhere.
Let's do it.
How would I do this?
So the moment I complete,
I dreamed of the first map.
I'm going to put in the E mystery data
and to add something in the list,
there is a method called list mode.
What I'm going to add simple.
So now what map?
One map collected from here.
Added here.
Sacred map collected from here.
Added a third member collected from here.
Added here.
Great
place.
Is this correct?
And then?
Then once I'm done with all the maps,
it means up out the outer.
This to this.
For once I'm done with all the keys,
all the rules on the columns.
I've read every single thing.
And in the end I need this function
to return me the list down the list, the
rest so far.
So far. Understood.
Can you please repeat line
number 68.3 display?
That was good
looking by non
see my this particular key
in this particular row with returning map
if. I got a sacred map from here
and I didn't see this map.
Then what would happen?
This map will override
the value of this map
that it.
So I don't want this condition what I want
when I got this map
first I will save it somewhere
and then I will see a second one.
And then I will see the third one
and so on.
Great.
I will tell you how split the split
thinking everyday
director equals of Whenever we do,
we get this great type of opportunity
right to work in the industry.
So as a as an architect trade, what
I generally follow is here in the company,
it's not a leap.
See, my job title is something else.
When my responsibilities
are something in trade.
So they are also me also human being,
and we could not
equal it.
Every single thing that we use it often
see it is a one day in the case.
This is one name.
You don't have to do it every day.
Once you
created a new framework in every industry,
all these methods.
So most of what we generally do
is basically we follow this particular
big thinking speed, think,
what does it mean
if there is a big task
or big role responsibility
you have or so many technical aspects,
just bring them in shorter pieces
and when you spread them in shorter
pieces, just identify
which are very important, which is
you will be using every now and moment.
Memorize all of the things you see.
Okay, I can go from here and there.
Then don't memorize those points,
memorize those.
That happens
Just so next time we just open
those appearances, you will get the data.
Put it here.
Your work is done.
Right. So there.
So you need to perform this.
You can save this building, implement.
We can save this
move.
Just copy copying your front.
There also is a best thing you can do
listening,
right?
So it's not only about writing
this particular function, it's
a long term,
great long term tip I'm giving you.
If you want to really survive
in the industry,
remember the moment you speak up, right?
The moment you speak of the moment
you introduce yourself,
it shows your thought process,
it shows you thought process.
Everyone is doing the same thing.
I need to talk about the waste
because the trade of the industry
is also doing the best.
No static. No.
Sorry.
Yeah.
Many of them
are going to be up in one hour anyway.
We are going to complete the class
or we're going to be okay
if we take a call after the class.
And I will tell you this,
but the way we generally do,
every class way
they share the link with everyone
sort of enjoying their rate
and we can work this fine days.
So far, we created this function
to read the data from the X,
and by now the next task is
we are going to use
this particular function
in our scenario right?
So let's take a break first.
And after the break,
we take the scenario into consideration.
Okay?
Okay. Let me do it
first. Don't want to break anyone.
I go from Marina.
I have to do it first
in line number four or in three lines.
You better.
Yeah.
Review part is okay,
but I hope everyone understood this point.
Everyone understood this
what day spent and there is nothing
which you guys are not understanding.
Is there anything if you guys think that
you should explain Once again,
I will explain.
Once again, I don't have any right.
But I need from you.
I need to hear this from you.
It's all good. It's
all right, guys.
Let's take a break for maybe 15 minutes.
And after 15 minutes.
All right,
so now we have written this function
great.
We have written this function
so that we can read all the data
from our Excel like correct allotment.
Yes. So I know you're here.
You are also in the last two weeks
for the president elections.
I'm going to declare
three names this time.
By now,
let's use this function
in our feature way.
Okay? How we can write this.
So to add in the feature value
in any employee,
I will come here
and I will write a scenario.
So my segment you name would be any
employer from X
rating, employees from x someone.
So now my frequently shown
is already available in the books.
We all know this.
We don't need to write to use the speech
elements, application or anything else.
The time user clicks on, add employee,
but then you build their time
user place on an employee button. Right?
We had this function available
already in our recruitment
days.
We already have this functions
in every growing part time.
So now after that we have to write.
So I'm going to write your rent
user and
keep my employees from.
We have a good way to get it from
simplifying using
Excel by using sheet
and redefine
employee.
So I am C user X multiple employees
from Excel.
My rate how we can provide the data
for the x
and by the but I that using the sheet.
So now see it one time.
How many should I'm going to use in once
in any one day?
How many should I can use
only one sheet.
Right.
So isn't it a good idea to provide
a sheet name here for the employee.
Repeat,
this is my sheet
and if I'm going into how I got the sheet.
BMC If you go here, right,
this is your data that we provided,
not this one.
This is your data and you'll see the name
of my sheet is employee data, correct?
Is this correct?
So here I am providing my sheet.
Now everyone knows already
if I provide something
like this, it converts can do
it converts it into even.
I created this definition.
It converted into what
is print grade.
So let me do it for exudate liquid,
do it for exalting.
I put this exalting way because I want to
create the is to be finished.
Fine going to smoke this time
and change this dashboard data
so to exceed day grade
and then make but is equal to true.
So when I write it is equal to true.
It simply means this time
I'm going to create a step from here right
now, see what happens.
It give me this step.
It is using this particular string.
So my sheet name, my sheet name,
I will be passing through string.
Let me pull into my post.
Let's make it
now. We're going to an employee steps.
And here, here
I am writing this particular function.
Now see how I'm going to use this function
posting
In this particular function I need to.
And the first one is my final name, right?
And the second one is my sheet name
should.
Name is coming from my feature point,
but still file name is a problem.
Finding is a problem.
So first let me handle this.
The spring is sheet and putting the handle
this is issued me now.
See that is what I'm going to do here.
Tell me which function we have,
which function we have,
which we use to read the data
from the Excel.
Reading this is my explaining
which function we have to use
to read the data Open Excel sheet
go through the column.
Government will consider data
or excel in to list which function
the open exit
alone.
I can see opening
signal already used. Yes.
Whatever. The font.
Yes. Correct.
Whatever the functions
we defined the line number 49.
We used all those functions here
to make one global function,
and that global function
is excel in the list map.
So this one, we need this one.
We need didn't
because we made it already static.
So what I can do,
let me go into my employees
and here I'm reading
from my accelerating point Dart
excel into list.
Correct.
And here it is asking for duty.
The most is file book.
And the second one is should me. Right.
So now let me put the sheet name forced.
It's a sheet and it was coming from here.
So you see sheet name is coming from here.
But my file but I can take
from it.
This is the book.
Now let me revise your concept.
Remember we provided the file,
but it is today's financing.
But remember for configured properties.
Then we were reading.
Right?
Let's see in config properties
we provided the file, but from here
you see this is the dynamic file.
But so do we have any particular with root
package?
Yes. Correct.
So do we have any particular place
in our framework
from where we can pass this book,
the part of the file?
Do we have anything in our dream
because of no
strings?
Constants, Constants for hard.
You see, in constraints,
I provided the path of my file
for configured properties.
Remember system
don't let property user build it for you
and it gives us the path
it returns the path of the project.
And in that project,
whatever the things we have read,
whatever the file we want to call,
we can call this finally here like this
there is one.
Remember this button or tell me.
Yes, but we have to create a path for it.
So that's what I'm saying.
Do we have any place in our framework
from where we can provide the path?
So, yes,
we do have this place straight, see
under this resources grade,
and that is resources.
We have this data line.
So let's go ahead and do this.
I'm going to write this
and I'm going to provide is as
is due to the school
my grade.
So when I said instead of file
but here I'm having a world record is
did not slash here
I'm having the venue called
the test data
and each part is not fixed.
It is
correct.
Now school. Where did you find me? Fast
in this part
because we just started
after the pre printing.
Before the break, everything was pointing
nicely, made really fast.
Okay, let me repeat it again.
Yes, yes, yes. So here, here.
Remember this particular part, right?
Remember this constant class
that we have from here?
We are passing all the file,
but the things which are constants.
So what are constants?
All the file parts are constant.
This part of, the files.
I'm not going to change in the framework.
And if there is something,
we have enough beam
which is constant to provide those things
in our constants.
The but super confident properties
by the configuration file.
But we provided using system
the property grade.
If you guys watch this video,
then you must be having the knowledge
of this part, this the stronger
object property, any user dot bigger
it returns the part of your project
when it returns the part of your project.
Inside this project, you get this data.
When you get this,
do not grade, it returns the complete.
But similarly for this data
also I'm doing what systemd
did property user data which is returning
the part of this project.
Inside the project I am writing this RC
based resources and the resources.
I have this data under this I have this
particular byte, this data batch element
X in a sixth grade case.
So now this part will return the file
part of my excel sheet.
Now clear for constants
everyone knows good at any
right now is what I'm waiting on some is
great.
Now let's come here
it is asking for two things.
See now I'm doing is it is asking
for two things and it's accelerating.
Bit C is the most display
but so now I can take this file.
But from here from my
constants don't is data mind
and the sheet name
I am getting from my feature like
this particular partly
this particular.
What I'm doing is
now C
here when I'm calling this particular
part.
Right.
It is returning me what
it is returning me the list of maps.
Right.
So let me back here
to handle this list of maps,
which is having my keys and values
in the stream form.
And I'm going to provide this is new
drawings, mostly what I'm doing.
I'm reading accelerating class.
From there,
I'm calling this particular function,
which is calling
this particular is data file,
but it means my excellent file
and in this sheet.
So this particular part is returning me
the list of maps.
So to handle this list of maps, I call
this particular object new employees.
Now, my new employees will be having
this particular object, new employees
going to be having all their data,
all their data from, the exam point,
and now this data
I can use via migrations In my script,
I find our industrial
grid.
Now see what I'm going to do here.
I'm going to write this function ten days
if I'm having something right.
The object, for example, new employees,
which is having multiple values
and I want to fetch
every single value from there.
What is the best approach in Java?
We have to edit all the things,
delete all the things.
One by one, one moment
I did a
simple thing, so let me use it.
We use I bring that
I had written on this particular map
where I am having this dream
come the string which is returning
every key and value for me.
So let me rate
idea is equal to which I written
for which object
then going to use it for my new employees.
Part matrix.
Any confusion in this code?
I'm going to break the map rate
based on keys and values using Trigger.
And this is the list of maps
I'm having new employees
replace.
Now the limit is what is the force
to matter to be called When we use article
which look
we have to use here for a trigger.
They look very good
inside of a look
which method has next or next
idea behind has next method we use.
What this method does gives
my views as mixed method.
What is the function of
it? Returns
true builder type elements
one by one, one by one.
It is checking right?
It is taking one by one.
Whether we have a new,
whether we have a new way
that we have a new builder time
we have values.
It keeps returning the operation moderate.
That's it.
His next
method is the first part of my iterator.
Fine.
Now, when I came inside this
because I know I'm going to get my keys
and my spirit in the form of map.
So I'm writing a new map to make this
new map for work for every new employee.
I'm getting one key in one way, right?
So I'm reading here idea
not next for every single one.
Now, this map
map new employee is having key and value
for one employee again
for one employment again for one employee.
Read every single thing
I'm getting one by one into
my mind is beginning
right at this point here First
with the B and
it returns
when the key
employee's right
So now now what I'm going to do
is see first,
whatever the data I'm getting in this map
and I know I'm having keys,
I know I'm able to keys.
Tell me what gives me here.
We have force name in middle name.
We last name.
You have so many other use relays.
We have so many other keys
which we can use here
right?
Getting my point done.
So now let's use all these keys.
Let's use all this keys from here.
So first what I'm going to do,
I will take this both memory,
the name and last name. Three locators.
I already have like three locators
I already have.
So let me copy
three locators and let me pasted here
this three locators.
After taking this data from here
like this.
Now, I wrote of this post number,
so how can I get this new
I can get this value from here.
I'm writing here
map new employee.
Don't tell me guys which material to use
to get the key from the map
for this
to add to get something from the key.
Get to my right.
Get What is the key.
My first name
is this correct?
My keys Postman
the my point to one
point similarly similarly
for the name
also I will get the key
course immediately.
I will show you where are these keys
available and last name.
Also I have a key to go Go ask
now see let me open.
Right. Excellent.
Right. As said, this is my first name.
This is my middle name.
This is my last name.
Right? This.
And you see, these
are the keys available on my first title.
So when I have all these keys
in my first room,
I'm calling this keys map new, right?
This map is aiming all that is target.
So what? It returns.
It returns the value against these keys
one by one.
Correct.
So in the first iteration,
in the first iteration,
false name, whatever the Muslim, whatever
the last name, whatever the middle name,
I'm going to get. Fine. Right after this.
The next thing which I'm going to do
is see what I'm going to do.
I'm going to write
here first,
let me open the application that we have.
We need to look of this particular
path or not.
Did me
guys, do we need
look again or not?
Let me take this. Look at that.
Yes. Do we need to without locator,
how can we pass something?
What I can see and I only
can we see a negative value based?
Let me take this idea.
Let me go here
and I'm going to rank there.
And let's see
for both equal to driver
or find any element by dark by D
This is the photo.
Fine.
And then I'm working here.
Photo for CINETIS And here
in this case, I'm going to pass more.
I'm going to pass from my map
door again Gate And what is the key?
The key and the key
which are provided here.
So what is the key?
The key is photograph you see
right.
Whatever this building drop baggage claim
or to
frame.
Now see these three things for things
the enforcement rate
middle name last name,
photograph should be first click.
Yes. Yes.
I'm coming to my notebook.
I'm coming for that one.
Good.
Now you'll see here
if I go in my application, read C
first name with the name
last in photograph I selected.
But let's say I create log in details
checkbox is not
available, is not selected.
Will I get the username?
Yeah, but I will do that.
Will I get the username password face? No.
Right. I won't do this.
So first what I have to do,
I have to select this checkbox
or I have to check whether this select
the box is already selected or not.
If it is not selected
then only I will select the checkbox
right.
Fine.
So now let me take
the expert of this particular
check log in
again. I need to block.
I will pick.
So after after sending the photograph
here, I'm writing one
if I see whenever I think if
my right
influenced
reality.
He made
chunks in sequence to
try to find.
That was my idea.
So if my checkbox store is
if not checkboxes,
then I set this exclamation.
It means the opposite grade.
If I don't use this,
it means checkboxes selected.
It will check, it will be selected.
If I put this exclamation,
it means it means check and performs
the operation when it is not selected.
Just opposite.
Have you guys remember if you guys
understood this point, exclamation means
opposite simple trade so not checkbox is
selected simply checkbox is not selected.
So if it is not selected
then simply do one thing to.
Go start, click
next.
And that's put the logic What I'm doing.
If my checkbox is not selected,
the checkbox simply
reads.
And now after, after clicking
here, after clicking here,
what is the next thing we have to do?
We need all these points.
We need your username, your password.
You can confirm password
and everything. Great.
So let's go ahead and check
if I select this particular one.
It opens username password confirm
plus what point.
Take this locator one by one
exists.
User name
Client
element.
User name as it is to.
I'm typing it fast
because we all have this code right?
You just need to confirm this. This. Okay.
The second thing is
password user password
element
constant, which is impossible trying,
but trying to find elements.
I think this is the password.
And the third one
I'm going to get is confirm password. So
this would be my origin password.
I'm going to get my
password, my
verbatim link.
I shall try the compound
password is equals prior word or
element by got a D
it should be my password.
Well forced constant encoding, correct?
Correct.
So now C first username don't send a keys.
You take the incoming
from my new employee.
Don't get
and then this would be mine username.
Correct. I need to check the keys.
By the way,
this gives username and password to you.
Capital B
This would be my username.
Similarly for password or
same keys.
Again, make it
so it would be my password.
And the third thing here is my
password there.
All I need to do to do this
again, it take from here or
not, I might.
Again, I'm passing the same key
password in control password Also
put the places to redeem.
Plus the way we can consider this,
we can add
one more in the exit fight with the name,
confirm password or password.
And then also we can pass the symbol
there.
Also, we can do it.
It's completely up to you guys.
It's completely understood.
If you want to do it, just do it.
I don't have any problem since it's just
we need to save our time.
I'm doing this here
now. One more point.
So far. So far.
Tell me any question in this first memory,
the name, last name,
photograph part,
which we are providing here.
And then after this username, password
control, password,
everything is clear to everyone.
Now just look at this part first.
Look at
this point it says invaded by the error.
Namely,
it is taking one more thing
verified and an employee can you see this?
Everyone
assumptions be able to use mine.
But how that is the main questions.
There it is the main question.
Think midway. I'm just committing.
I'm just writing a new could
see this after entering username password,
click on Steve.
But not everyone knows.
Everyone knows.
When we're clicking on Steve, we're Done
apparently conceived
but it will take me which please
guys again remember it is also a part of
it is kind of similar to my table
and remember in their data table
what was happening in Detective.
It was just executing one
simple step again and again.
Right?
So there we had to click on option
and they were options.
Remember this part we did this eight
employment and again, we have to click
guys.
Remember this part we were doing
right?
So first let's take this particular part
from here clicking on their button.
Also, we have to do
and then clicking on an employee
would then let me show you how this works.
Then we translated
insert the look around the room.
This part
inside of confines.
So let me do it
first.
Let me simply aim for the save button.
Treat What is my save button?
Let me to move this part.
This person
first.
So far, so far, what I'm going to do is
let me come here for some data.
Make this
device
this is waiting for my
password is to be worksheet
one briefly for
exclusion.
See? Well,
we we edit menu difference
just to show you functionality.
Wait, wait, wait.
We will do it.
I'm going to show you something as
now see guys here.
Let me add some data, see what I'm doing.
Going to see this employee everyone.
It is by default,
it is by default available.
Right?
So now see this employee
and just look at this employee
in when I'm clicking on Steve Button,
when I'm clicking on Steve, when it is
coming to this particular report,
it is coming to this particular part
and you see
here today's
rate is coming to this part here.
Here you see employer is available here.
Also, we want
right now now two ways of verification.
First thing in homework,
what you have to do
when you come to this particular part,
when you come to this particular bar,
next thing
do one thing going to employee list.
Once you go into
employee list, you'll see
all the employee's available here.
Can you see these?
All the employee's available?
How many of you is in this?
Again?
I'm giving you their task, this task C
And then here
you have to provide the employee ID
value, right?
You have to provide the employer
ID which you got, which you will get
while creating the employee.
So enter this employee search from here.
Then you actually search from here.
You will get this data in this particular
part, right?
You will get this data in this law here.
And when you are getting this data
in this line from the table in directions,
you have to verify that you're
getting your first name, middle name
and last name, same as the previous one,
one you have added.
You are having the same plus name
with elements in each industry.
What you really want
Everyone in
this room, this is their task
you have to do.
Now let me go back to my employee page
after clicking on Steve
and what it is doing
after clicking on Save Button again,
it is blending into one page
where I can get this employee option.
Oh, there are multiple steps, but yes, I'm
going to do it.
So now after clicking on See it were done.
It is taking me again.
It is taking me again to the employee
beach database
days.
It is taking me to a template.
So again I will click on it employment
and then it will go on and on and on.
Trade goes there.
So we can correct
so far in this particular portion.
So far in this particular part,
do you have any question this part?
See, again, I'm repeating here we started
we put a greater to the values
from the Excel
which we are getting in the form
of list of maps trade.
When we got this list of maps,
I came here, I did the value.
I provided one map because it returns
the gain value for every employed.
It means the data from every single rule
which we are getting.
I'm putting this data here in their name.
It is checking.
Once I have all the data of my supply
available in this particular object.
I am calling this particular object here
based on the keys.
Whatever the keys I have,
I will provide this kizzire retrace
when I provide this key here
and I provide the data, it will send
all the values against this keys
available in the exit right in here.
I'm doing this and after adding
all of these details I simply click on
say button.
When I click on
Save it returns B on would be to it.
I will point this to an employee.
But again, why?
Because my background is work.
One day it's going to work one time
my hook is going to work one day.
So I will be on this page from here.
I have to see the workaround.
A workaround is to
click
on an employee again, go to that screen
and one more employee, one more employee,
one more like this.
And this tool
is this and just what everyone,
just a handful of ways.
Just a hint for you, for associates,
what you have to do right.
An employee I.D.
like by
creating the employee while adding them.
When you're adding the employee there,
you will get the employee great.
And you get the employee
from there. Right.
What you do after adding the employee
third group in the employee list,
search it in the employee list.
Once You search it in the employee list.
We need to give the employee nonmember
with the code.
With the code, you can do it.
It is in even the code.
Should I tell you how to get this
via code?
Now there is a method written
so the name of the member
did attribute so against the entry
would just do it instead of work
so there won't be a pending
definitely
loophole if the post and giving it
this will work.
Right.
And then after that, great.
What I will do tomorrow
I will load this here in the note with it.
List a link everyone try
and if someone is panicking
or if even if you guys are able to do it
or not do it, I will do it.
Get in the people okay.
I will do it in the class.
The verification part
already
in line
101, we put shooting.
So this is coming from your feature file
you see in this feature file disconnecting
and it's like
shred on this code now goes post
started in the employee list.
You or do do
all the links
with text from the
Oh no
see you got the image.
Can you see this
and go to the image to our jpg.
Right see the employee created images
there.
Know what is happening.
Unable
to look at the element statement. Fine.
Because my execution was so fast,
I didn't put the weight in between there,
so I find no issues.
Let's do it one more time.
Let's do it if we go here
and of the clicking on saved one,
I would do provide the vertical trade
or sleep minimum for this.
And then after adding implement and again
I'm going to provide
its third JP
the same one trader sleep for 56
that is getting it.
I provided the weight
when putting the rating.
Let me open this file somewhere.
Right.
And then I'm going to change this. Name
one one. So
you would probably close
one. Now
let's run it again. Now.
See it got the data for the first one.
Username exist.
Fine, but that's okay.
We are going to click on the second one.
Second data came right.
Great.
Noisy third one click.
When they're internet data
for the third one, upload the images
working plain username exist.
That's why
it's closed
names
data.
It is taking from excel file or not
can be.
It is taking the data
from your existing file only.
We are putting all this data
in the actual filing.
We are using this data there. So now.
Now see my this function right?
Even if I have been fi it didn't lose
ten rules in columns, 15 columns.
I don't care about this
single function will read all this data.
Bear in mind steps.
So if you go in my steps, you'll see here
I'm calling this particular function,
which my this object employs, is holding
all these nice documents importing the AJ.
Do you get all the maps one by one
where one map is having all these vendors
from every arrow
and it is returning the values
based on these keys
which and providing here.
And then I'm putting this data
this to
underscore that
we want this part.
Yeah, I got it, got it.
But isn't it easy
it is a one name activity
and if we have the
we have to close the Excel point in
and of course we are already closing it
in already.
It's already closed.
We are just reading was open closed
and then we are reading in simple.
So we don't need to do
any additional store.
We don't need to open it
and close it again.
If the exception is to be visited
when people should get employed to do
our code exception, to do the exception
instead use it as well.
People employed by converting mine runs
meaning? Yes.
Yes it is for better for the shooting
naming rate.
Just check whether you provided
the shooting name like this or not.
If you provided with this job
greater than the smaller than symbol,
then this would be the error you get
right just provided like this
because then it becomes the driver.
Right.
So this is the issue.
Your code with related to.
By the time
we are not providing this by yesterday
the must have been by the time
this screen is loaded properly
taking you further
fluidly will resolve your queries.
So far based on me,
any question is for you.
If you provide this
a greater than it is, one or two things
in one writing becomes key.
We're not passing the key. We're passing.
This is a better eight here.
See, this is the key
you passing like this.
So it is expecting
some from getting triggered.
Not reading the data from itself,
but we we need to store any
data to excel in the future.
We destroying their data in future.
There's nobody using your grades
or from simply
in the future.
Also in your company is right.
When will you go?
When you will go in your companies
and you will be working on your name
projects, Then you have to deal with Excel
in your current
operating on this is just to
but is a must or reason for just this
and what it is for practice.
Just do it. Otherwise
I will do it tomorrow for you.
That's okay you are in jobs.
So when you have to, you have to.
That's why I'm calling it right.
It is a one time ability.
It's not something you do very often.
And every now
and then it is just a one time activity.
Once you write this function,
once your function is working right,
then you are reading this data point.
Everything is more than a
more.
Next time simply call this things it
Can someone please copy this
particular part in this life.
Questions. This is to please.
Yes, yes.
Yes. I'm a
of this method called detected.
No, not detectable.
Not detected.
That's what I'm saying.
It's a simple,
you know, remember this particular one?
This one, it was not a detectable trait.
Nothing just provided
one key, the parameter.
And then we it
then you have someone remember this one.
Similarly,
this method is we correlate this.
See with one pattern.
So now you see this method properly.
In the end of the method,
what you're getting just one shoot me.
That's it.
The barometer, the start of supply.
If this is the start of dependency,
you'll see it just as shooting him.
There'd be a passing
from.
The feature
of this is when we are handling you exit
already committed
a good straight in the time we did
whatever the good we did.
So far I have committed
already in the repository.
You guys can take this code from there.
Every single thing is available so far.
Guys, tell me any question. Yes.
And please wait.
Please.
Good.
I see you're asking the question.
Is there any other one
who has any other question?
So one.
And what then is?
What?
Boss, did you use?
So which practice is better
to use a web driver route?
In our framework, we will use this.
This one. Right.
We've already passed from here.
You'll see it in this state.
I showed this on your own.
So let me show you.
Existing takes 1 to 3 exclamation mark.
This one
is the ideal one that you guys can use.
Okay, everyone.
Right.
On rainy days.
Nice holidays
then I think time
then from my side for today's class.