All right, guys.
Good to see
all the great
orchestra.
How have you been?
Great. So
in this class, when I'm seeing the way
that you are on the right.
But believe me, the level of operations
you guys are doing great
now is just tremendous industry.
Even after eight or nine years,
people do not have
this much experience,
this much in-depth knowledge.
What are instructors
are giving you? Right.
It's just intangible.
But issue,
you just need to look on this thing.
Right.
Captured every single thing.
What I what we are seeing,
what we are teaching yet in the class
I will try to get a couple of students
from best right
one more time so that they will share
that experience with you.
Great diva in your place.
What we taught them, how they
absorb all of those things.
Great. How they implemented those things.
Those are completion of their classes
in the interviews
and see they are on the job.
They all a majority of the great.
I already got the job so intimately.
We have to create the job, right.
That is the main point we have to get.
The job market is extremely good.
By the time you beat the market rate in
one would maybe the majority.
Maximum one month,
one one half month in the market.
I want you maximum.
I would make the majority of you
to get the job
in. When there's a majority of you.
It means in the first month
majority of you
should get a job.
And for that time is not after one month.
Time is now.
Trade.
You should start working.
You should start revising.
You should start understanding and
everything practicing from now onwards.
I've been repeating the same points
again and again.
Reach out to me and each of us that
they don't want to reach out to anyone.
And even if you think, No, we need clear
this.
Don't come up.
It come to us, ask us. Right.
We have your dogs
and we will clear your for sure.
But for that
you have to come up with for us.
Okay, fine.
Let's start last.
There's work
we're going to get for the class.
One will translate further
for new topics, right?
I hope majority of you
will have already downloaded this.
Postmarked majority of you believe.
I already share that
with you. You got enough time
for that?
Nice.
Amazing.
Okay, students, tell me, what is
great.
Does it still announce that
if someone asked you in the interview,
what is EPA telling?
Vagueness
Finish Excellence starts on Twitter.
It is a vacation
programing
interface
right now.
Why? We use application
programing interface
basically basically to
constantly improve chance
to meet the information
being applied.
Some order
to try and sponsor with the information
right or establish the connection
in between plane
connect.
Now here, connecting everything together,
booking
a B.A.
connects everything together,
no connect systems
together, right
to transmit the information would
not indicate what is claimed
release what is claimed.
You are not the one
x first.
What is server
of one who
forms do the request
that is born but exactly
file so in simple language.
In simple language
EPA is generally used to transmit
the information between client and server.
The client. Right.
When we talk about information,
what plane say we call it request
and the information plane to the seat
or server sent,
call it response simply.
Next question is my
why do we need it?
Is my post
to do
to communicate
systems.
It could not in
different programing language
communicate
the systems developed in different
programing languages.
We need API now.
There are so many reasons.
Three dinners, food.
There are so many reasons rate.
The most reason is security. Why?
Because no one wants to share their data
with us.
No one wants to share that.
Everyone wants to share
their data momentarily.
So how we can do that?
We can simply exist
a particular piece of information
from their database
based on the search we are trying to make.
Right.
Based on the search we are trying to make,
we are going to get
that particular piece
of information from the database.
So how we can get that particular piece
of information via API.
So at the same time, API API enhances
security, security of data.
You you
enhance the security of data, right?
Relays API enhances security, greater
by after this.
Next thing
here,
when we talk about client and server side,
we are going to talk about
server
architecture.
Generally, when we talk about blank server
architecture,
how many types of architectures
we have claims and a
we have one architecture
lead first one be an architecture.
What does it mean?
This would be an architecture
all in one place.
It means my presentation. In
my presentation is
my application layer and data layer.
All three layers are company, but in
one machine quality
because it won't be an architecture.
Yes, I think the best example is
if you complete blank,
then the next one we are going to
talk about is architecture.
That is
to do architecture means presentation,
layer
it One place, authentication
and data.
Now available
under the buildings
and that piece rate
application and data layers available in
another presentation here will available
one piece of this type of architecture,
we call it to be an architecture.
The best example is
guys is the best example is
Domino's Pizza, right?
Exactly.
Domino's for instance, where does this the
high end?
Jimmy?
I think my answer to your question right
wasn't really answered yesterday.
Sorry I was so busy today.
I wouldn't ask you for that.
You got that answer
of one right?
So today's.
But yesterday,
if I answered right lady to anyone
because I couldn't see my leg.
Right.
So that's why
I was actually actually engaged.
That's one point.
So now when my presentation, my indication
near my mind is that if
all are
delivered
in different places,
then we call it 3D architectures, right?
So the best example is
Facebook, Amazon,
Instagram, etc..
Is this going to increase
one then?
Then we discussed one
really important point.
If you remember,
we discussed one very important point.
The point was
operations.
We perform operations we perform
using selenium pre
you are using selenium.
For what reason?
They're used by Mussolini. One
is doing fine.
But what
load testing.
Excellent.
Then is
really
they we use selenium to perform.
To perform
functional functionalities
on a simple UI testing,
printing, testing, rate printing testing.
We use selenium
replace what ever
we see,
whatever we observe on to the screen.
We used to automate.
We use selenium to automate
that particular part which we can see on
the screen.
So what you see on to
the screen is a UI on the screen.
This is the print
and this is the presentation layer.
So we always interact
with the presentation.
Then on a
UI part on the screen using selenium,
we are to make this
particular version correct.
So now when it comes to automate web
based application on screen,
that is the UI,
but we perform basically for operations,
create, retrieve, update,
be, create, daydream update, delete.
Is that correct?
Why now?
Tell me why we used my sequel workbench
Reach database.
I simply make it for
for database testing.
Great database testing.
We need my sequel workbench.
So we work with my sequel
workbench here cutting.
So yet also we perform basically
for main operations, grid operations.
Is there anyone who does, who doesn't know
what is the meaning of this
great operation?
Is that anyone
knows?
Is that anyone who has no idea
what great operation
means?
Nice.
I was thinking if there is anyone.
Yes, I am getting I was about to call
in is the upgrade
so politely agreed.
Otherwise do not raise their hand
and the moment they raise their hand.
This is the last of all
boring learning with complete fun.
You will get the maximum,
the maximum of the class.
Right?
If I just keep explaining the things,
it makes you bored.
It leads to some boredom rate.
That's why it's better to keep in mind.
We like to keep the in my hand
deep under me.
I want them to get in my right.
And this
right,
you either learn it
or you don't have any any of that option.
Getting
this point.
Nowadays, I'm kind of with the the
you have to follow
what I'm saying.
I gave him a license to carry
in the class.
We never know.
We never know when we needed trade
the way we got one instruction right
Couple of minutes back
you script came into the class is it.
He shared the recording as
possible non loop escape by
one else I need
trade I need I should call in
is in that case
getting movement
in without any should upload them.
We have.
There is only one king.
Sometimes we have to claim a territory.
It is also important
scary.
Welcome to scary helps to find.
So now when we perform
the same operation on the printing,
we perform
the same operation in the banking.
So the point is very simple
to understand that in the middle, bear
in the middle man.
This really hour when we talk about API,
we are going to perform
same operation.
We are going to perform the same
operation, correct, of operations.
So now school is very clear.
We will use API to perform
great operations
or either we are going to earn
a new record in the database
and we divide or we are going to retrieve
the information from their database.
In my order,
we are going to delete some information
from their database and verified
or we are going to edit
some information
in the existing record of the database.
And we
these are the four things.
These are the four things we, we
connect.
Not to me is that it is undeniably
excellent.
Excellent.
Coming to you.
This will make you personally
great just to make a list of the students
I'm going to do is
fine.
All right, so now,
now see, now see one very important point.
Actually, I'm actually implement.
So now let me open this
for me.
I think may definitely
99% in May and
right now noticing
welcome the moment that they did
And then if I bring a few issues
all over job credit
with see you next week.
Definitely definitely
excellent.
Yeah right.
What do you mean?
All right.
So now, now, here.
You see.
Yeah.
Zimmerman coming.
Be ready with that
bleed.
I still. I still remember that. Great.
Oh, Andy and Glean
was that played along with there being
some mix of good I would see mix of both
majority of things
90% business 10% obligation
I would see
when he has
the main intention
is to meet with the people because no
not of not of quantitative use.
Lot of I would say majority of my
what exploited me was some dip
and keep asking the same question
haven't you coming there?
So there's what
Definitely.
Yeah definitely.
It would be an honor for me. So
there you go.
There you go.
Yeah. Yammer. Right.
But I would not sleep because
I don't consider this as my business.
Right?
This is my network. Uh,
no, because it is very difficult
for us. Not.
That's very difficult for us. That's what
friendly.
And when it comes to read my network.
Read.
See, let me tell you one thing.
You see.
Exactly. Exactly.
Now, here, you see,
I open the calculator, right?
I'm. I'm trying say, well, I'm trying.
When I put two plus five
in this calculator and put do
plus five, it gives me
similar rate.
Let's it give me seven.
So now tell me, do I need internet
connection. No.
Somewhere in the banking,
somewhere in the bank.
It would depend. It a 2 to 5
and give me the reason then this kind of
API did this, this API
did this onboard
at the same time.
Mostly
one thing very crusty at the same time.
If I go here and outside
guys can
now take me here
here on the Skyscanner.
Here on the Skyscanner.
If I tried to search something
you don't need internet on Mark
Gates to search something on Skyscanner.
Do I need internet or not?
We need it, doesn't it? Right.
We need Internet.
So now.
Now, how is it possible?
How is it possible
then in one place? API
doesn't require
internet
in another place,
API requires, isn't it?
It one place.
API is working without internet,
but another place API
needs internet connection to function
and you see the difference.
These two types of API.
Guess the really interesting topic
I'm about to touch.
There's a mosquito industry
attempting to explain you.
So now.
Now remember
two types of API seeing J.A.
will give you the examples over
Deal architecture radio in this way.
Microsoft think this is the example
of your one near architecture.
Your calculator is the example
and all the big stop application
is standalone application.
These are the example of your is of
the examples of your one bit architecture.
Great.
So now you see this two types of API,
everything,
two types of API,
you see the one which needs internet
and the another one
which to me doesn't need internet current.
Now. Now listen carefully.
API is
which are just
post big
over the domain
are called
Gibson.
So how many of you guys ever
heard this term services?
Yes Amazon web services.
What does it mean?
Amazon provides some of its services.
So Web services
simply means you need Internet connection.
And these web services
connect multiple systems
because services are nothing but the API.
Right.
And what API does
It establishes the connection
between the two systems
developed in the different languages.
Great
trade, Great.
So now APIs,
which are hosted over the Internet,
we call them Web services.
So for example, if I start something here,
if I start something
here, let's say Google, great,
I open Google map.
It connected me to Google
Maps, click here.
It takes me to this particular
place on Google Map
Connect.
You see,
it took me to this place on Google map.
Great.
So how their data is being transported,
how it is connecting
to the Google, to the Google
map, to the Amazon, to all the places
via via his web services.
Right.
So we are able Israel.
So which APIs?
Now we are talking about the EPA,
which is a wireless Internet connection
so that NEPA is required
Internet connection.
We call them web services,
great web services.
First thing understood what is up.
So in this case, people think so.
When one says if a services does it
only with API.
Yeah.
Web services that is a part of API.
API is a pending web services, a changed
that API is a parent web
service is a trade outlet.
How should
let me put this one here if I
take would be into the
on called
services Oracle web services
right now you see this
Google example
I gave you for web service, right.
For Web services.
This is also EPA, the calculator example
I gave you right there.
It is also API or any.
Yeah.
Alex So you can study that example, right?
I will give you one
map 1 to 1 map example.
Also that map. The map, right.
You will see how I'm going to great
how this that maybe it will not work
without it.
I will tell you that is create
non web services but still API.
So remember remember the point
all maps that have says are APIs
but all it is are not
web services.
Right.
Let me read this definition some bridge
that is very important point where this
all services
it a part on
if the ends are non
non services
make sense based
off it
perfect so now now we are going to focus
we are going to focus only on one part,
only on one part.
And that part is
services.
It means only the part of API
which are hosted over the internet
because the API doesn't
require internet connection.
What we can do with those,
we shouldn't do anything.
We cannot do anything
and we don't have to deal with those.
It is only web services.
Only web services because we are going
to test something over the Internet.
All right.
All right. Based now.
So even
even if someone asked this question, hey,
you know, that sort of services
just before this point,
if someone would have asked,
you would have answered no. Now,
if someone asked to do you to Web services
to think what would be your answer?
Yes, I'm services testing.
Tell me which web service
you want me to test.
I will do that.
Great, great.
Nice.
Let's proceed further.
Now, when we talk about Web services.
Right, Region
really have two types of Web services.
How many types of Web services
we have based
two types of services.
What are those two?
See the first one, because it is
RESTful Web services
and the second we call it
superb services.
We have restful
and we so have never had this
donkey's soup interest
in your.
Even if you heard trade, you always
see what is this support is these rest.
So web services
are basically of two types.
Great
services are basically two types
of list food and soup.
And this is what everyone
restful and soup.
What is the full form?
The presentational
stage runs
the presentation straight lines.
But and this one is simple
object
exist for
simple object access protocol.
The presentation is to transform
two things.
Two things
extrude
majority of time,
99% of time in the application rate
we deal with,
we deal with
just services.
So here in this session
also we are going to focus on
we are going to focus on just right.
We are going to focus on the rest.
There are
some obvious reasons of this.
The first reason I'm telling you, right,
the first reason you install
install, basically
whenever we get the data rate,
it takes more bandwidth
to transfer the data.
And if we need more bandwidth, simply
it needs more time to better
travel light because the information
this group gets right.
It is it gets a lot of information.
It gets a lot of information.
Right.
And if it gets not enough information,
it takes a lot of time.
And only one language it accepts it is in
which language it accepts
which language it accepts,
examine.
However,
however, when I will definitely give you
other graphical representation
of the dismal graphical examples.
Now see here in RESTful in restful
at rest.
So it accepts only externally.
It accepts examine
Jason
next HDMI
and you'll see all this accepted.
My opinion is
this to accept only x okay.
Because
because it has a lot of information.
It takes time.
It takes buying
coupons for their data
and takes more bandwidth transfer data.
X-Mode.
Basically this one, this one provides
less information, right?
But relevant information.
So that's why it takes less
bandwidth required
less time to transfer their data, right?
So takes
less time to transfer their data.
Three days.
The only thing the only example,
the only example
which I can see in which so is better is
soup is more secure than rest.
Soup is more secure than rest.
So who uses soup?
Majority of time
banking applications uses soup.
Who uses soup Banking applications
uses soup only because of safety.
So for them, even the application,
if it is taking time, me
give you the real name
example of what you see here.
If I search for Google,
how much time it took
to open the application,
how much time it took fast?
What if I search for ICICI Bank?
See, it is taking time to load the BBC.
It is taking time to learn a bit.
And now we get this
particular page, correct?
Correct.
So even if
there are differences in minutes against
but still it does taking time.
So I just to give you one simple example
there you see a lot of examples, right?
If you perform hundreds of operations
every time you get this example,
you see the difference.
You see the difference in between this
and this.
Probably one.
So we are going to work with rest.
Okay?
Okay.
We are going to work with the rest.
No lipstick. Very good example.
Now one starts
first thing.
What all are the things I need
to communicate over the internet?
That is more important point, right?
This is more important.
Playing with a list full API.
Right?
So when we talk about restful API, right?
When we talk about API spaces,
I need complete address.
What I need, I need complete address.
For example,
you are it is not a complete you're
just that's what I'm telling you now.
See if I ask is he his email.
So what would his demands? U.S.
Why the
demands in U.S.
now in U.S.
is the mother only one who lives there?
It was.
He must have. I live in U.S.
Is it a complete answer me.
I be able to find the mother Mandarin.
You will see. No.
Right then it's.
And then Z was his own.
I live in Arizona, in Phenix, Arizona.
Maybe you visit Phenix, Arizona.
Now tell me
one. Arizona.
Also in Arizona also is the one only one?
No, we
I would ask
will get in Phenix
what is your house number?
Is this 2048204?
Is it fine now in U.S.
in U.S.
made in U.S., in Phenix, Arizona,
the house number is 204.
There I can find Zima or not do. Yes.
If I go if I go to his house read,
someone will definitely ask,
You want to see who you want to meet
because the email is also there.
Silver is also correct.
So I have to say.
All right, I need Zima.
You need nice
given get to get re enforce fine.
Nowadays. Great.
So I found Galen K to get three gift
for Sylvan Zimmer,
the beautiful family of six people
right now
they ask We want to meet as a zima
so now see not understand is exempt
but incorrectly in state in house
in house
I have provided this particular point
in okay in this in this particular one
I want here and work here.
I want to meet this person correct
for me.
Excellent.
So what
29 zero.
You will see undisputed champion.
Right.
So now, now, here you see,
I give this complete entry state.
I give this complete.
It was even if I missed some the
Yes, yes.
I am both Conor McGregor, Dustin Pryor
and Habib Konate and then Dustin
White.
So now here you see
when I give the completed list
then only I will be able to identify
this particular address.
Right.
I will be able to meet this guy, otherwise
I wouldn't be able to make this correct.
And then it sees the same thing
in the news.
Is, all right, you know what part point
that part is not enough
in that part unit
that you have this part. Yes.
So what is this part?
This part of this part?
Is this what we need to understand?
All right.
Now, let's consider this
the example in call minus
worst case, practically understood
what I am trying
to explain how to make the computer this.
Now, see this example
in technical aspects. Now
we talk about Amazon database.
Great. Simple.
We are going to talk about
Amazon database.
So when you try to exist is Rigzone
database for first word, you need
most words you need address of the server
address of this network
or we simply called database.
Right guys
address this are what our database
posting when when we reached in this point
when we reached this point in Amazon.
So what
tell me how much information is available?
A lot of information.
We don't want it. How much?
So we need only the information.
We need
only the information which we want.
Which we want.
So for example, it says, okay, fine,
little habibur
excellent.
BUPA Superb.
All right, so now see here
address of the server, right.
First thing.
But in this address, in this address,
if I see I want to access users,
then what would Amazon ask?
Amazon ask.
Well, I have existing user.
I have guest user, I have new user.
I have prime user.
Which one you want to access
in. My point is
it is existing
user, new user, guest user, prime user.
All kinds of users are available
in database or not installed in me.
So only if you see
only if you see I want to access user.
Is this the complete answer?
No. Right.
Then you say already
I want to access existing user
which when you take an
existing user.
So now again Amazon ask Will I have
five millions existing users,
I have five millions existing user
You want to get the information
of all the users
or you want any specific user,
any specific
rate. It's the same.
I reached the my house,
but there are six people
that are asking you want to meet who
we all are human beings.
Which human being
you want to me then I, I specify.
I want to read Z1 right then only again
read similarly.
What are the things we need?
First, we want address of the server
in terms of API trade.
The next thing in this address
where my EPA is available.
So I need API location.
I need API location in the server
and under the API location.
What it would be operation.
I want to put a form I need take point.
I need that point. Understood.
So how many things
we need to make this complete address?
We need address of the server.
We need API location.
We need the point in
API location, which I want to
getting my .33.
I'm I'm
just I'm just coming to the window to.
So now now when we talk about
technical aspects,
we colleague
base you are I
what we call it based
what we call it based You are.
I am.
Okay.
Now remember this.
You are I distance for uniform
resource
Identifier.
Uniform Resource Identifier.
Already this
one student's uniform Resource identifier
right now.
See Now, see what is this
uniform resource identifying?
What is this?
This You are I is this.
You want to consist of three things.
Consist of how many things
consist of three things.
The first is
address of those that are not.
What is this
address on the server liquidity?
If I open this
part, see if I open this part
Google dot com.
Can you see two in
everyone's is Google Street.
But do you know that this Google dot com
is just a domain name which we see here
which we see here.
This is just a domain
name read on for example Amazon bought it
so this Amazon dot is just a domain
name in banking.
In banking, great.
On the Indian side, what is going on
right this Amazon not in our
is Google dot com is linked to one address
for example 198.192.8.1
or 192.198.4.3.
This is what we call in normal language
IP address
or we colleague
address of the set of
what we call it,
address of the service right now.
Now, if you ask me this one website,
I said yes, I do have said
give me the name of your website.
And I said 62.347.32.1.
How it sounds.
Would you be able to identify
would you be able to see me?
No link, No.
Instead, if I say hey, just going to
WW dot com
easy or not, which one is easy.
12% dot com or 34.237.1.
something you know so remember remember
we provide this thing
for our understanding
otherwise this part is more than enough
to search anything.
Let me show you this.
Do you see here we provide a chain.
So index dot make this part.
You are using this
now see you find idea three dot.
You see
I'm forwarding IP address in the moment.
I provided this IP address.
It is opening the same application.
It will going to open
the simple application
opening plan.
It will open the same application
which I see it opens.
Let me open this page
right
here.
API and an API.
If I open anyone using this page
and this page, read this page in this page
what are seen.
But the difference is it one place
I have been to this particular
domain name,
this particular name and it one say
we went to this particular lawyer
IP address.
You see, I built this.
All this information can be found here.
The same information can be
found here also.
So what is the meaning of
basically
this part is for on understanding,
but in actual it is linked to this part.
It is linked to this part.
Now, let me give you this example here.
See, I'm going to read
can you see the IP address of Google?
It means when you read Google dot com,
it is linked with this.
8.8.8.8.
Right.
It is
linked with this IP address so intimately.
We are trying to excuse this server.
We exist this server.
The information is coming
from this particular location.
Whenever we name google dot com
understood.
And this phenomena,
this phenomena of linking your IP address
to your name, this name we call it the
and is domain
name somewhere
industrial not our
now how domain name server works everyone
everyone understood
the concept of DNS based
nice place.
So now we were talking about BS.
You are right.
So the first DNS is the number of number
or the name domain name.
See domain names.
So it is name of mistake.
Now see based you are anytime, sir.
Here we need three things
because you are right and you want to know
what is the difference.
Remember the first thing that I see
address of the server?
Address of the server is nothing but
base.
You are in. Base you are.
And so if you go here
and if you see right Amazon,
so this is your base,
you want to write this, you want to
it means the address of the server
now, now in this format,
if I want AC, if I want refrigerator,
if I want mobile,
if want laptop, if I want curtains,
if I want one wallpaper, write
anything, whatever the things they need,
they are separate departments
available in this particular interest.
Right.
If I want to purchase,
let's say clearance a store, click here.
The moment I click you see this
you are in changes
this you are an Amazon don't intend use
to Amazon in slash something
something can you create this
Hello you may see something
now similarly if I click on mobile
again, it changes to mobile phones.
Then you see
again it changes to mobile phone.
So when you talk about
when you talk about base you are in,
it means we are talking about
only this part, only this part.
Read the address of the server,
the address of the server.
Then how about this?
The remaining part?
What about this remaining part?
If you see here, if you see here,
if you talk about base you are in
and this is the base you it
then what about this part?
What about this part?
Understanding two points
with the two points.
See? Great.
So now come, now, come here.
This you are listing for your uniform.
Uniform
Resource Locator.
First thing
we got this address of the server.
But for this address of the server
is not enough.
This address of the server is not enough.
Again, just consider the example of email.
Amazon.
Right?
You want to access the users
so all the users available which users
you want.
Similarly, we we already exist
the address of the server.
It means the database, but in database
what information we need.
So we call it
a by location
location of a being.
Yes. Correct.
If you want to access Amazon in the U.S.,
you have to use Amazon dot com.
If you want to use in Canada,
it would be Amazon.
But see if you want to use it in India
Amazon
not and if you want to use in Australia
Amazon not EU
if you want to use it in Pakistan
Amazon don't be like this.
Okay, fine.
So now see guys in this address, I'm
saying wherever a browser available,
a browser are available,
just take me to that
particular place. Why?
Because why I am here.
We are here to perform this on
to perform testing on
API. One has seen
we have been doing it
right from last for 5 hours.
The last time
one in the afternoon is three.
So API three we need API location.
So now,
now you see, now you see if I go here
at this point,
if I go back, see
if note of information is available,
this is the address of the server.
Right. This is the address of the server.
Now in this address of the server,
I need API location.
So you see everywhere,
even in a development for the application
or in any other application,
if there is API exist,
there will always be a place
or the IPAS separately.
So here if I click on API,
this is the API location.
So now you see in API, in API,
this on are the person.
For example, API is the
host of Zebra, Zimmer's Houses API.
Under the house
we have given Q2, Q3, Q4 segment Z, Ms.
six Great.
Similarly for creating the employee,
creating the user, deleting the employee
employment status to generate the token
one employee, all employee.
So many things,
so many things are relevant.
Which one you want to use,
you want to use create user.
Go ahead and call this one
you want to use create employee.
Go ahead and call this one.
You want to generate the token.
Go ahead and call this one like this
kind of stuff.
Management. Right?
So this is what we call point.
Remember the point
I was telling the third place,
the third the supporting record
address of the server
and that it was the server
API location under API location.
Third thing is, third thing is
and one third thing is endpoint.
So now now
when we have these three things together
and what are these three thing base
you are by less
API location,
less endpoint, we call it
because you are I
and we need this base
you are to perform on the API
is to
industrial
base.
Any question in this
question.
No question
dummy.
Nice.
Can we make our first request for you.
Opens index with the numbers that is
not designed the Yeah because I did
I didn't rent to this particular point
to see
I'm I'm coming to that on
this is the swagger one if you see right
so I got Ed so here
I didn't go to this bigger Ed part
if go from here and you click here right
then it comes to this particular point.
You see
now you got
using
actually, yeah.
Please ask the endpoint, the end point.
You will understand what I will
explain to you.
I will explain the endpoint.
Nobody wanted use it.
These are the endpoint,
these are the ones that every day
you don't really
about the endpoint how endpoint looks
and excuse ask, yes, after 2 minutes
I, I may die
all of my horses for 15 minutes
so they won't run anymore.
14 minutes.
How much, how much course covered in views
soon it was a giant dot
com or it similar to it.
It seems that
it is still
basically this index Italian protocol.
But why it looks different
and it doesn't look difference.
You see here it's all about picking
this particular part in consideration.
Let me show you if you talk about this
particular one in this particular point.
Right.
See if I'm taking this particular point,
then what would happen?
See what is what it is opening
this big
server configuration works, right?
And if I take this particular one,
this will also give me the same thing.
See this part to see read
this part is in and this part is it.
So this is just the address of this one.
It takes you to the same place.
It also takes you to the simplest
understood this
and this will this not
great,
great. Let's take a break.
You're going to get into base.
You are right means this you are helpless
API location plus end point it.
Let's take a break for 15 minutes because
everyone understood this
This you are really what is this?
You are
everyone understood this API location also
right
now let's talk about this endpoint.
What is this endpoint?
So you see
all their databases available
and they will look forward
something like this,
something like this, correct.
Replace columns and rows and everything.
So now, for example,
if I want to add existing users, right,
so all their data related to existing
users might be available in this one call
rate.
So here on their data
for existing users of
right
in this particular one,
all the new users available
in this column,
my biggest users are available, but
in this column my prime users available
guys getting my point.
Hello
students.
That's how things work in this table
platform and data available, right?
So fine.
You came into the database, right?
In database.
Multiple people that have
multiple tables are available right?
When you spawn. Maybe.
Let's see for composer,
one is for legacy development,
one is for let's see, eBay
and this whole information,
there's a whole tables are available
in one set of one.
There it is. Mine.
There
it is. My database or simple language.
So so first first I came to base.
You are in Firebase You wanted.
I came to this one right?
This under this server.
Under this server.
I need API location.
So I have compose I have developed.
I have API. I have compose.
I have developed API.
Right.
Great piece.
I have these things.
So now the second part API location means
I'm going to hit this particular mark.
This particular part,
I'm going to leave this part.
Leave remaining part.
Just started on
this target on one bar.
That is this one correct.
Now in this part also my people
roles are available for existing user
new user, guest user, prime user.
So if I want to use their
data only for existing user,
I have call this particular time
if I want to existing permission
or delete the information
or update the information
or to add a new user,
I have to on this particular point,
getting the point of this in IPA location,
we have multiple points right?
You cannot save new user in existing one.
You can also just use a new one for the
for destroying the guest user
to play with their data.
For the guest user, you have to connect
with this guest user point
If you want to play with the data
for the prime user,
you have to connect with
this primary is point understood
and this provides.
This is like Zimmer's home
in Zimmer's house.
We have given it to get tricky for Zima.
You want to meet Zima,
so you have to connect with Zima latest
industrial.
So when we talk about this particular
existing new
guest and brain, what are these?
These are and points.
These are end points.
So this complete server is the address,
the server
in the address on the server,
we have multiple tables under this table.
One is API location.
Under API locations via multiple points.
In these multiple points,
if we connect with anyone,
this is what we call API end Point.
Now what did anyone
know? Understood.
What is the point
right now?
Now see Nazi
so far
based.
You are a concept player
API location concept player
right.
API location once player
then endpoint concept
and one conceptually is great.
These three things
we will get the final product called base.
You are right, which we will be using
for API testing purpose.
Understood. Now let me show you.
Let me show you all these things,
all these things.
Remember, whatever the things
we need to make the request.
Guys, what are we doing?
Basically, we are planning to say
that exist as a client right?
So to send a request, I needed it. Simple.
If I need to send a postcard
to anyone, what
I need,
what I need is to send a postcard address.
Right. So if you tell me. Okay, fine.
The address is USD,
incomplete is a no no, no in U.S.
and New York.
Again, don't.
Now, you said it was it for House number,
some X-Y-Z Street,
Brooklyn, New York,
United States along with the zip code.
Now this is completed completely correct.
So similarly,
if you said this, you wouldn't.
Okay, sorry.
You are it is fine incomplete API location
find incomplete
end point API location
because you are in the desert
of this are now completed
now completed this.
So pretty quickly we found the house.
We found the house in which whatever
we want to do, we can go the right.
So now coming back to the point,
we are going to do
just four things
clear operations right on this address.
What kind of operations
we are going to make.
Right. We will see.
We will see this.
All right.
So now you see
what I'm going to explain here Right
at this particular point
when we made this, you are I.
So how we select this end point, right.
What is the API location?
What is the base you are in?
What is the base you are? I train.
What are the other ingredients?
Need to make a request.
How we understand all these points.
How we understand all this points.
So here to understand all of this points,
we need to follow one document
and then document.
We go
swagger.
You can consider this like there is API
documentation or in non normal language.
I would say it is API.
I would
this swagger document in the studio.
This swagger document is nothing
but the API Bible.
It gives us
the complete information. Right?
So if you go into the industry,
if you start working
on any of the projects,
you will get one document called Swagger.
Once you get this swagger document,
that complete information is available.
We just go through the information,
you just read the information,
you understood everything you understand
every single point you make, request,
what kind of response you will get.
You will get that response
also from the beginner part.
All these things, all these things,
whatever I am explaining,
you can do all these things from there on.
You can do all these things from there.
Only understood.
So now let's see how we read this
particular swagger document,
how we did it.
Okay, Just don't.
All right?
Always think of big who hanoch who
is it
you want to You are to remember
we have already discussed it.
Guys.
You are I and you are in.
You are only you are.
And these are two different things, right?
You are and is a part of you are I
uniform Resource Identifier
and Uniform Resource Locator do things.
Uniform resource
locator is the basic allocation
where we have the complete
the address of the sort of what you are.
I is the complete address,
the complete address read
in that particular of in this particular
point on particular table,
we are going to perform this operation
Desert Bitcoin based.
You are a moderate, so you are
it is a small fortune.
You are is a complete is
not understood.
You know they are they are from
last two years have seen great.
The guy said we bring this at least
three times for the last two years.
They told care of their families
and everything.
They do care of other peoples.
They always go out, they always take care
of people and everything.
So is and it is pretty genuine
because in the country of 1.4
billion, 1.5 billion people.
Right.
But you see people
every minute, every state, hundred billion
there.
So you to make them aware,
basically you have to go out of your home
right.
And they can never be certain
digital access.
Got it.
Fine.
So now now let's see, guys, how rigid
these particular documents
I have already written
in the notes I've already written.
This is a result.
This are going to be as you are, a
plus location of API plus in point.
This is your you are
what else you want me to read
in stone.
I think if you don't read it any.
Yeah, that's fine.
That's really fine.
All right.
So guys, now see how we can read
this particular document.
Great swagger.
So now, now, if I open.
If I open. Right.
If I open this particular document. Okay.
If I open this particular
document, swagger So now can you see
this is basically you are
and it is available here.
The very first thing
it is you guys
this is this.
You are l right.
This is this you are in.
So now now remember
here when we talk about base,
you are and it has two meanings.
First, do you want it?
Second, your location of input.
Remember two parts we discussed
this you are plus locational API
base your plus locational API.
Even if you connect the two things
together, it still it is base you are in.
And then and then after base you are.
When you connect this with end point.
With end point, then it becomes base
you are all right.
So these two things
you are in any location of API,
you can find it here,
you can find it, you can you see
till this point, in this point,
what is this?
This is your base. You are in normal.
You are in.
And what is this index API slash eBay.
This is your this is your API location.
Guys, can you
see this is your you are in
this is your API location.
Do this available here. Great.
So let me copy this post.
Let me put it somewhere
so it won't be difficult us to investor
rate so base you are less
vacation or
recorded this way.
Well now after this.
After this you'll see it says
for creating user end points
slash API is for generating a token file
is games is a steep fine.
I will tell you this
you see create user
available here again you see so
for creating the user, we have to use this
for generating the token, have to use this
for creating all the employee details.
We have to use this.
Forget one employee, we have to use this
for getting the job title.
We to use this for getting employment
status, use this,
create employee,
use this, create user and create employee.
I give you the difference
in these to update employee
the employee
update partial details of the employee.
So now you see to perform
different types of operations.
To perform different types of operations,
we need to create different endpoints.
Can you case
we need to different endpoints
going
right now?
Now imagine the example in our district,
the example which I gave you
in database of Amazon training, right?
BHP So this is the endpoint,
This is the endpoint.
So they develop like BHP with the endpoint
with their SPI, we have to use it.
No issues
on its development,
not arguments.
This autoresponder,
this.
But I will tell you this totally.
I will tell you this also
this law human rated,
how really open this speech will define
I shared this in the chat
in some video as this changes,
I open this speech, open this speech.
So now now here we have to read we have to
read this complete information point.
Now you see we have address of the server.
That is basically what
we have right now, API location,
good things.
And the third thing,
the third thing we have is end point.
So it says it says you have endpoint here.
Can you see slash create user.
So if I want to create user, I have to use
this is beside big role in API location.
This is specific table.
We all the newly created
user will be stored straight
if I want to access, get unemployed
and try to create user data.
It will not allow
every single place, every single place
as it's already defined location in DPA.
Okay.
Okay guys.
So for example, if I want to take this
particular part, what should I do?
I have to copy the endpoint
to create the user.
I have to copy this endpoint
and then I have to edit, you see.
So I added this point to
now you'll see
this first part is my base you are in,
this second part is mine.
The second part is my location of API
and this third part is my third
part is my API endpoint.
Right?
Right.
This one
not understanding
another more.
Another important point
which we are going to touch based on this.
If you want to live in use,
you have to follow all the rules
and regulations of the U.S.
government or not.
You have to read.
If you don't follow, then what I'm
the for.
Basically
it will not allow you to leave the great
read.
Similarly, if I want to live in
India without initiative
or don't I have to follow
the rules made by Indian government
on our Constitution.
But I have to follow my Constitution
similarly.
Similarly, if I want to do a business
in India,
I have to follow all the business rules
defined by the government.
If you want to open your own business
in the US, you have to follow
all the rules
defined by US government for the business.
But it
similarly similarly,
if I want to interact
with some application on to the Internet,
I have to follow the rules
and the guidelines
defined by the internet.
It will never happen that I can.
I can interact with any of the application
on the internet according to my will.
I cannot do this.
I have to follow the protocols.
I have to follow the rules,
the regulations, the policies,
the procedures of the Internet.
So what is this?
Rules, regulation, policies, Procedures.
The protocol on Internet, we call it.
We call it.
You might have seen multiple times
this GDP with every user.
You would have seen this content.
Everyone can see HDTV.
What does it mean, Hypertext
doesn't matter
whether it is secure or not.
Transfer
protocol
just now here,
sometimes you come across HD, PBS also.
What is this is this is a for security.
This is transport secured.
If this is available
with your applications, you are it.
Your application is secured.
If it is not available,
your application is not.
So you find you're not going to bother
about this security.
But as of now,
we are going to focus mainly on
this duty.
People should
be strictly proportion understood.
So hypertext transfer Protocol
three workers protocol
is it says, Hey,
I will allow you to communicate
with my people
applications over the Internet right.
We can communicate,
we can indirect the application
rate with the applications,
with the website,
with the website over, the Internet
using one protocol.
The mean protocol is hypertext
transfer protocol, right?
So how we follow this protocol,
how we follow these protocols,
we have certain metrics.
We have what
methods
or recorded functions.
We have methods for functions in
certain methods
or certain functions in it.
We have understood
everyone so is GDP methods.
What is GDP functions?
We need to concentrate in order
to communicate, in order to connect
with the website over the Internet
Hypertext
Transfer Protocol.
Okay.
It's prudence.
Does it make sense?
What I'm seeing?
Fine.
So now, now here we are going to.
Yes, yes, yes. Everything is on Twitter.
Everything is on speculation,
like concerts, videos
available, everything.
So now see
Gregg
closed operations.
What does it mean?
Create
the big
B? Really great.
I see.
He is GDP.
I want to perform these four operations.
These four fine.
So we have to follow some function,
some methods of GDP.
When I say, hey, I want to create
a new record in the database.
So HDTV protocols is all right,
you can do this.
You have to follow my one method.
The method name is
most regrettably, you are correct.
Correct.
Then then I said, Hey,
I want to retrieve a record,
want to get some information
from their database.
So this is
you have to call my gate method.
If I have to update something,
if I say I have to update
something in their database,
it is all my method.
It is put.
If use it, I have to delete
something from the database.
It says you have to call my method,
which is being
so boost gate put delete,
not pull it.
Still you are in this good
pull get push did origin master
get commit minus then good push minus
your origin double course
message of the minus message is till you
you're in that point
good as good stash
did add once to get clone
you are in
good push You're still playing this
The API command
will not batch also update your batch.
I will tell you it is for partial update.
I will tell you they don't ready.
But right now
we're not going to focus on that.
But that is not that when need reading.
These four are essentially so I will feed
you only the things you can digest.
As of now, overfitting
doesn't make any sense
otherwise in desert is one thing
and nothing else made fun.
So now these are based GDP metrics,
which we are to call
for particular reasons,
for particular brand of operations.
Right.
Let's good on swagger
now first come we can put it
people protocol
allows us
to do
good science
over that
we communicate over the internet.
Great So here to be forced
would
be great.
Is now
you'll see here
this document is very simple.
It is just endpoints.
So to create a user first,
first, tell me one thing on this index.
A job application.
If you want to add a new user,
if you want to delete a user,
if you want to approve the leave,
whatever the things you want to do,
you need to have first.
One is special type of user.
What does that user can
everyone can everyone at the employee?
No, only a green get empty.
The employee only admin can delete
the employees.
Only admin can approve the leave
and everything.
Right.
Only admin can do it.
Not everyone can do it. Right? Correct.
So this is the difference in between
creating an employee
and creating an admin user.
Creating an enemy needs that.
So when we talk about this, create user,
it means first we are creating
an inconvenience.
What we are
doing, creating an enemy new user.
Right now, if we talk about the common
nouns are common terms.
So we had been talking
about this particular part.
If I want to add a new record
in their database,
we call it Create operation.
Great. Yes, from great operation.
The first one is one create
to create means simple.
I want to add,
as I want to add a recording database,
I want to add something in the database.
Is this correct?
So now, now see another thing,
another important thing here.
When I said business, you are right
with little malaise.
What is with you are
my you are
less my evaluation, less my endpoint.
Right.
This is the place I got.
This is the place
I got where I can create.
Where I can create. It means
right.
This is the table I got that I can create
the admin user, correct or not.
Tell me
this is the place where I can create.
It means read click No.
Now to add a something in that database,
to add something in the database
to create a record in their database,
I need to have something in my hand
first or not.
This is just the address.
This base, you are right,
is nothing but the address.
So I need something to edit or something.
It's simple.
Like if I want to give you $100 first,
I should have hundred dollars
in my pocket.
Then only I can give it to.
If I don't know, hundred dollars,
how will they give it to you?
Right.
So first I should have something.
Then I can add it to the database. Right.
So that something in
API language is nothing but
the bank
pain, or we call it
body, what we call
that is what we call it, body cutting.
So remember, remember one thing
whenever, whenever
you want to add something in the database,
you always need body,
you always need a payload.
Because if you don't
have something in your body,
what would you add in the database?
This base you want to is just the address.
Address doesn't mean body on that address.
If you want to add something,
you have to add something additional.
Not anybody who gets something
from their database,
but anybody.
No plate.
So forget operations
to retrieve operations.
We are going to fetch the records.
Why would we need a body?
We don't need a body.
Maybe we use brain for them. Exactly.
Exactly.
This is something
we have been missing from last for months
and be interpreting this point.
All the geniuses, Einstein, by the name of
beautiful, instant, brainless
cutting.
So now this billion auto body,
we need to create a record
in their database.
But to get something from their database.
You don't need this.
You don't need body getting So right now,
because we are going
to create a record in the database,
we need all these things.
So let me put all these things here.
One by one, which we are collecting,
we are putting.
So I'm going to write here to do
this is the very first request
to let me write
a proposed request
for API, which we are making.
So what honorable components
we need the right components
we need to make components.
We need to make
forced linguist, right.
So here what we are going to do,
we are going to create
and it means user
based,
we're going to create an admin user.
So we need, we need base.
You are I.
So to do that base you are
I need three things.
It is address of this API location
in the endpoint this is we already got.
Then we need another thing that is my
it is my payload.
It is my payload
or simple language recorded body.
Remember remember we discussed this point.
Remember this we discussed this point.
What is that point?
We are going to use?
Which web service
API is already web service
in the Yes, we are going to use rest.
We have to list will install
and we will going to work mainly
with just right.
So now in the rest
trade in the rest services.
I told you it exists JSON,
XM and text HD and remember
remember Jason HD and will examine
text etc.
so many languages it used reused.
We use decent language,
we use just the language
JSON language to break the body
right. Body.
It is a unique map so nobody read the word
plane is
so now see how we arrange some languages.
Really easy.
We are not going to write this first.
Come here.
Going to swagger.
So now what example Google disturb
the user who registered the user.
Maybe you'll see on Facebook
if you want to register yourself
what are the fruits you need to see
who restored
the user
to create a new user in Facebook working.
What are the rules you need?
Maybe first name, last name, email,
password of birth,
something like this.
Similarly, if you go on to the Amazon
to register a user, you need just a phone
number, mobile phone number.
Right?
If you provide your mobile phone number,
that is enough to register yourself
or even
read.
If you talk about some
website, for example, Skyscanner,
that if you want to register your search
so you can simply provide your name
and your email or name
or your phone number, it
it means pre-registering
the users on different forms, right?
And according to the platform, we are
changing, we are changing the concept.
The form is not same everywhere.
Someone is asking your first name
with a name.
Last name
someone is asking just your phone number
or someone is asking just your phone
number or email with your ID and password.
It is changing. Fine.
So how would we know?
Third way Creating the body.
What all are the things I need to think?
What all are, the things I need to change
to create the use and what I need.
The body I do. So who we deal with this?
These are the information we need in
the body.
Who is going to tell me this
claim
which claimed
development?
We have nothing for developers.
We have just one document called Swagger.
Now, if you come here on to the swagger,
you see
which request
we are going to create for creating user.
This one, correct?
Correct.
Click on this.
Now you see it says This end Point
will create a user.
This End Point will create the user.
So this is the end point you use.
It will create the user
lost values in spring.
For me, it says everything in detail,
boss values in the string for
it says here, see it says body.
And then when it is required,
what does it mean?
If you want to send something, create a
new record in the database, you need body.
So we have to send
body because can you create?
We have to create
body now in body
what all are the things we need.
So we need name, we need email,
we need password.
Can you see this?
We need a name, we need email,
we need password
and in which form key and when the key
and when the key and when did right.
So this is my decent one week
This is my decent forward.
How would we know
this is my Jason Baldwin.
You see it
this content in application is application
slash Jason
application slash Jason can you see
this is the information
all the information is available here
not to
every single information is available
here. Read
it was it for the non
open your postman's press
open it was for
everyone
that can you see this
plus icon here first select collection
can you see this
plus I can here everyone
click on this
plus option to create a new connection.
I will tell you what this connection,
normally we can do that.
First, select this plus icon.
And you see it gives you new collection
here.
It gives you a new collection.
So change the name to its index match.
And then when you've been
index match 11 API dynamic
renaming race
done press in this
press,
can you see it appears here like this
opening
opening and it says this collection
is empty and request to start working.
How many of you got this message
meet.
Meet me so many.
Okay, now
now remember, remember,
I believe everyone uses zero.
Everyone use cheetah print
in general do we
have is super.
I got this.
You need to use selected this API.
You have to select this collection.
Click on connection not on maybe interest
rate.
You selected this API
so that's why you're getting this pass.
You have to select this connection
and then you find this.
So now Bennie intends
to shoot what you have.
What do you have in collection?
This is to get this simple.
Come on.
All the dislike posters,
all the Nasdaq posters tell me what
we having best suit.
This case is great.
Similarly
to keep to keep all the best cases based.
One place
we need best suit in the stream manner
if we have so many API request.
So to keep that exist in one
place, we need collections
industry.
The curmudgeon
having multiple list exists
to put all of them in one place.
We need more. We need best suit.
Similarly, having multiple API equals
to keep all of them in one place.
We need we need collections
so far.
So should we proceed further.
Nice.
So now we are going to create
are forced to request to create a user.
So click on add request,
click on add request
and here you'll see it is asking great.
It is asking for this new request. Fine.
So This request a name you need to change.
Click on this icon and change it.
This request name.
Do it to me So
create a mean user.
Read today's what we are going to do.
So name should be self-explanatory right
next time.
If you did that,
you should be able to understand
while reading the name of the request.
Okay.
This is the request. We are doing this
you can use which gives also.
Right.
But I would prefer
to write a user like this.
So it is very easy to understand.
I prefer like this.
Yeah. Create admin users.
Now you'll see admin user created.
Correct?
Correct. Now.
Now the first thing,
the first thing we need is are base fuel.
So the you this is our base.
You want to
the you this is our base.
You want it right.
Let's take this base.
You want to be from the US.
So we need this base.
You are an and we copy this.
You are in base treated here.
This is my base.
You Are I my You are plus my API location
plus my endpoint
plus my end point three things we need
I shared already in the chain.
If you check
base, can someone please check?
I have already shaded
in the check in the zoom
chat. Yes.
You'll get to your
if your request is not correct
because you have two slashes
you have to slash after.
If we keep it to one
to just one read.
Everyone got this point.
Should we proceed further?
Great. So now we got first thing.
The second thing.
The second thing, it is still this point.
It says because
it says post.
What is this post?
What is this post, guys?
This post is my HTP method
is TTP method.
So click here under dropdown,
click here and select
post method from you see
how easy this tool is.
Select post method from here
one word.
Just think about my situation that
I make poor decisions.
Hold it.
And people like him, right?
They come from nowhere.
All the late hits
certainly
it happens here.
It see, see
geniuses
there also, Einstein, I'm telling you.
And if you tell them that, hey,
if you tell them that.
Hey, don't make noise.
No silver, no No, no,
This is not good at all.
This is not cool.
They are like
they are like shopkeepers.
They are not cool ones, normal citizens.
I see a lot of reasons
you find one, right?
You try to find one.
You'll get 1000 in India.
Yeah.
So now.
Now you'll see.
No, not yet. Not it.
Hold your horses
for your horses.
So now, see, this is just the address
we have so far.
I told you we need to add a body.
It is body but is below
right now.
We noted below.
We don't have body.
So first we need body.
First we need field. Correct.
So you see method
I selected name, I give you what?
And I provided you what?
I provided.
It was get it, get it.
They will give you a guarantee
and they will to wait. Now,
if you don't do this before,
if you tell them this,
they will give you a guarantee.
All right. Now,
now, now, after this,
after this particular point
we have based you on and we have a GDP
method, we provided the mean.
And the next thing is to provide the body.
The next thing is to provide the body.
So just take the body from it.
Just take the body from here. Right.
And put it here like this
name.
Let's create a mini user. This is mean.
We will use grade for our complete API
as did this.
Edwin Munoz
So tell me, who wants to become an enemy?
Who wants to become an enemy?
I mean, do.
It means Lobo and Zema
being three, four and five then is
let me create a new element.
See Lobo, Zema then this Aisha
and any
No. One
less than it, it sounds like.
No, no, no.
So here,
here, here
it. Right, Exactly.
Now, here.
I'm going to raid list in the raid.
One, two, three dot com.
Any user I can make,
any user I can integrate.
So e-mail list in the raid 123.
com and then the password and I'm
going to provide best in the right.
One, two,
three. Right. Just give me a moment
now you'll see guys
raid name email and, password raid.
These three things
we have provided in Jason Volmink
which forward is this?
Which format is this next?
This is JSON format.
Just give me.
All right, fine.
So now, now we have this Jason Monty
with this, but we have a Jason body.
We just got it.
And here here we have to
we have to provide this name,
email and password rate
is name, email and password in JSON form.
So this is my body.
No secrets, right?
Let me copy this.
Go here now C go here, go here.
See body
click here on body guys.
Now focus on this is the body select.
You'll see multiple forms
none form data w WW form.
You are an encoded raw binary graphic.
You will
raid.
We have all this available from here.
From here we have to select raw
what we are against
the raw read in raw in raw.
We are going to select our dropdown
and from this dropdown select JSON
in a c sml html text in JSON
that, we will so select Jason from here,
select JSON from here
in order
for this tool.
So when you select
the Jason from here is the body
which we provided to see the body, we have
the bodies available here.
Name, email, password.
Three things We have found a great
Did you see three things
we found the name imminent password
in the body,
correct?
All right, fine.
At least he makes someone happy
all the same.
It's okay.
I'm telling you not to do this.
Does not register.
Don't use right now.
Read, write otherwise.
Yeah. Otherwise you know it like we did.
Like you all did indeed. Human classes.
I still remember. Don't do this. They go
vague.
So first name, email and password.
Three things, right? All the components.
We are focusing these three things
we have got.
You are? Well, we have got
most method.
We have got
right now after this.
Should we put are all components known as
well this is this is the method defined.
Right. See
what swagger seems to be able to follow
so it crosses name, email and password.
So we provided here
name and password in the morning.
Can you see
can you see?
Yes. Correct.
Only change the values don't change
this part under it will not work.
This is the main
everything read the body defined.
The body defined
when creating the required and replaced
so we can not change the requirement.
It should be seen. It should be as it is.
It should be as is understood.
It destroyed everyone. Yes.
Yes. Correct.
So now, now see one more point here.
It says only there is content type.
What is the parameter content to be read?
So when we talk about content,
I remember we are building to our request.
We are saying this to our requested hey
request, I'm going to give you a heads up.
What is the hype?
So the heads up is the body
which I'm transcending.
This body is not descending.
The body which I'm sending.
The application is all descending,
correct?
Correct.
The body
and sending the application is up.
Jason I'm fine.
So now here comes
and whenever we have to provide
any heads up going to is
going to
go is going to hit us right
in headers here we are going to write
what is the header
content type, content type
and after thing, time after content type,
we are going to write here the value
so the values application slash Jason,
you see this, then this information
also we got from here only the content
can you see this
right?
So now we have headers, we have body
we have base, you are right,
we have methods selected
everything we have read it, just click
send to get a response I Einsteins.
We don't play consume response. Wait,
hold your horses.
Can you go back to the point
this is the header
I know the moment the
why is it click send to get response.
Everyone will send a response.
Everyone click on Blainey.
That's one.
What did you do in body?
Alright.
So in body we provided the body.
Simple, right?
We provided the body. Correct.
This body
we got from here we go from here.
You see this body we got from our. Yep.
From our swagger document.
So from there we prevented colleague.
You understood
there are certain forces
way that badge page have already
given the link for their trade.
This beach link
I think of.
Can someone be sure the link of this page
once again in the group so now we can
have this. There you go.
This will need
that you to get this.
Fine, fine.
So far.
So what everyone
now it just click send to get a response
how we can next we're going to chat.
Is it open source?
Yes it is open source thing.
It is available every minute.
Whenever you get is a very glad
I mean to test.
So one day
your developer will give you a link.
The moment you open the lead, you
you'll find all details in this document.
Why do contain it?
But yes, you need to type correct and
you don't even need to type everything.
It's private input.
So again, it is correct.
It depends on company to company.
When we hear you don't have to type,
you got this data already.
Just just here.
It contains select from the drop down
by to take a greeting.
I don't get this
when everything is
available, you don't have these doing it.
Okay.
All right, guys.
So now see, it's just click
send to get response.
Right click send to get a response.
But we don't know what response
we are going to get anything right.
And we can verify anything because we
don't know what to verify, what to check.
Correct?
Correct.
Right now we don't know what to verify.
So even if it is redundant, great idea.
We see how it's verified. Great.
It says, Hi, Asia.
Well, it is nothing to do
even though the response rate.
But we will verify.
So first we need to understand
what response we should expect here.
This is very important thing.
What response we should expect here.
We have to check this.
I will take this list. We
have you ever seen this part 404
in any application?
What does it mean?
Which normally is when
it's this page not found.
This is based not on 4034 wouldn't
exist in foldable zero
bad request rate.
The moment we see 404 it simply means
begin or region or phone that I got.
It means page is not delivered.
Correct?
Correct
Right.
So what is this?
404403400.
What is this?
This is what we called H 50 B is
status code Internet protocol.
Right?
So according to the protocol
gives you some good
and those code gives you the information.
So what example,
if you are creating a data
or creating a report in the database,
if records created successfully
and gives you one special code
if you agree.
So no, not one bit. There is a problem.
If you're not listening completely,
then you give wrong answers late.
If you get some information
from the database it gives you one
special code.
If you get some
and it gives you some special code,
if you provide wrong input,
it gives you a present wrong request.
It gives you some special code, right?
So remember, we have five cities
one, two, three, four, five.
You see, all the codes are available.
00101102103.
However, I will I will
go double zero is past.
Yes, that's fine.
Let me explain.
But we not talking about
past is of no see here.
I advise you to focus on majorly
two cities
200201202203204.
That is success.
It is in 4210401402403404.
Be failure cities Arab citizens success.
It is because majority of times
99% of times
we focus on two part the post is success
and the second is failure.
All right, so this data is good.
We should be aware about here
is this Boulevard zero.
Okay.
Indicates that the greatest has succeeded
to zero one created indicates
that the request has succeeded
and that new resource has been created.
And that is everything.
So tell me now if I'm going to create
a new record in the database,
be like zero zero or will get will do
21201 created.
This is what we will get right
if my request is successful.
But if my request is not successful,
what would happen?
See valid request for double zero.
That request
could not be understood by this.
So what it means
we are putting some incorrect data.
It means
requesting some incorrect data
for zero one unauthorized.
It means you don't have a permission
for zero domain statement required.
You are trying to access something
that is having a billion gateway,
but you are not making any payment.
You can do this open required.
Maybe not
getting similarly for zero trace
or with an unauthorized request.
You can't access to this particular one
right?
404 page not found for zero five matter
not allowed for example instead of post
you rate so be USD.
No, it's okay.
Maybe somebody in stone can do this.
We know, right?
So if you put is ability
it says 405 method not been known
this way postman knew
that even people will make mistake
even rate writing this part
so they already provided everything
drop down so your next time you don't need
to pay just to select from the dropdown
because they know all nine states
are going to use this post coming to
this code base.
So now tell me if I am going
to create a record in the database,
if I'm going to create a record
in database,
what response should make
go to
correct?
So what response should be expected
based on me
to zero one ready to send the request?
Now everyone
shall meet
that you call
that email address
you entered is already registered.
Fine.
So let's do this and as the neat
and find thing
now you see
it says is status 201 created
also one we don't have this one user
within the database
we do have this user email right
instead of mandatory
because I changed everything
before sending correct command.
So now you'll see we got to zero one
and it says that your request
has been fulfilled and reserve date
in a new resource being created.
Read new resource been created.
So we are adding a user and here
you see the message, see user
and the user details are this.
So this is that email
and the password for the user.
This is the email and the password
for the means of can you see this?
Everyone
right
now, now here, now here.
You see this is this is status code.
This is one of the one
the verification points
we have in the application,
One of the really big points,
not all the verification points is go
ahead.
Go ahead.
Change email and try to do this memo.
And we just discussed this point.
That's why I always explain. Right.
I always request please listen to me
what saying
It says the email and it is to read.
Great.
This is the email address
indeed is already registered.
I changed it.
I told you to change it is still are using
the same one which I'm using.
How will it work
guys?
Did I tell you to change?
It could be anything.
It could be any one.
123. Eliminate that it gmail dot com is
and any that it will be three dot
com something like
I'm getting the 400
and so this is bad request
maybe you you should check your bot
whether this is not correct
or whether this is not correct
or maybe this is not correct.
These are the two three things
you need to check. Next
request and I would check the connection,
whether it is connected
to it, intended or not.
They all look at it.
All right,
fine.
Then why?
Fine.
So now, now, see here,
when I sent this request.
Right When I sent this request here,
I got this data, I got this response.
So the upper body is the request body
and the lower body is the response body.
This is a response when you guys.
Okay. All right, guys.
This is the response body and
from sort of what it is coming gudi
this is the response we from the server.
This is the data we sent as a client.
This is we got from the server.
And now you see if you want to see
this data in a similar format,
see this is a make symbol for
if you want to see in decent format.
This is just an ordinary text
for make this text for me.
You can this data for me
also the one you received or read.
Second thing.
This is one of the verification points.
One of the verification points
we got here.
These are the things
also we can check now.
You see
socket initialization done,
DNS lookup, DCP handshake,
transport starting download.
So see how much time it took
to download for milliseconds
and how much time to transfer
just 625 milliseconds increment
6 seconds straight 6 seconds.
Now you'll see the overall size is just
620 x 620.
Wait, I told you the rest list
requires minimum bandwidth.
That's
why data constant is very easy right now.
Just imagine the condition
if you want to create an admin user
from the selenium
how much time it takes, open the browser.
Navigating to that
you are entering the information,
getting the message, read
it listed times more time than this one.
But if you send API how much time
the API needs just 9 seconds.
That's
why API is the fastest form of testing,
fastest form of testing understood this.
This is our first request which we made.
We got the data, we got desert.
I showed you how to read the results
in API.
Be automated.
Yes, an API can be automated.
We will do the automation with
already iso I think.
And then from my side for this session,
if you have any question, please ask
or else we can wrap up the class now.
Thank you.