As the young guys.
Welcome to the class.
Let's get started in, like, six, 7 minutes
and waiting for everyone to jump on,
and then we'll get started, guys.
Excited to have a fun class today.
Class or.
Today's class is going to be fun.
You're going to enjoy it.
We're going to do a group project
and we're going to do a
we'll do a quiz today in class.
Will see you Enjoy that.
And yet a lot of review,
but mostly the group project
you guys will get in groups of 5
to 6 people.
So if you're thinking already of groups,
yeah, next couple hours
you will be with your groups
and doing an exercise.
So I'm excited to
go through that
with you guys and let's see how it goes.
I'll wait another 5
minutes till we get everyone on here
and then we will get started.
Guys. Let's see.
So do start thinking of your group
members.
Guys, if you are in a specific area,
meaning you are from New York,
you guys can absolutely get along
with individual from New York
and things like that.
So be very wise
in who you pick a little bit later.
Not at this point, though, but still.
All right, guys,
I will just wait another 5 minutes
till all the members come on board
and then we'll get started.
Okay, guys,
I don't know where everyone is today.
They're coming in slowly
and then see, they're welcome.
Everyone, as you guys join.
Perfect.
That's.
You're on the right.
How am I doing?
I am doing well. I'm doing well.
Sorry. Bye, guys.
Your Sunday class got, unfortunately, got
to cancel the very last second, missus.
So she did get a very high fever, though.
So was unexpected.
We did it. No,
we thought everything was really good.
See you.
Only if you only had one Java class.
So she's doing well.
She's feeling a lot better.
We'll see if she will be able
to teach this Saturday or Sunday or not
if she's not able to.
You know, we have other instructor
lined up for you guys.
This in that situation, you never know.
And it might be coed.
It might not be COVID.
I don't know exactly,
but I'll keep you guys posted.
You know,
and yes, sorry about that.
You guys missed your one.
You had only one Java class
and we had to cancel last second there.
I hope you guys at least enjoy today
a bit of programing.
So you will be definitely exposed
to a lot more now very soon though.
But hopefully it wasn't too difficult.
Even if it was, you know, you'll be fine
as long as you practice.
The team members are here to help you
out, supports you, if any questions comes,
anything like that.
So I am glad that,
you know, a lot of you are participating,
some of you not much, but still it's fine.
Yes, we missed you.
She'll be back hopefully by this Saturday.
She will be back so she can continue
with you guys in the programing side.
All right, guys.
I think more and more
people are coming now, which is nice.
I don't know why a lot of people are
a little bit late today, but it is fine
and we will basically get started.
So, guys, today's agenda simple.
What we will do is we will definitely do
a little, little review
just to make sure everything is clear
cut for you guys.
It makes a lot of sense.
And then what the goal is from there on.
I have a in-class quiz for you guys.
It'll be a lot of fun.
You will enjoy it for sure.
So we'll do it in class quiz
and then we'll get into groups
five, six, seven people, maybe
bigger group, whatever.
I'll explain to you
and you guys will have to get together
once you've formed a group
and you guys will do an activity.
The reason why we do so much repetition of
this will a lot, a lot of times I do,
you know, review of this material
and things again because I want this.
This is important.
Even though some people might not think so
much, but SDLC Agile, Agile
especially is extremely important
and it takes a little time for
for you guys to have had it
basically stick in your brain, right?
So we'll do review of that
and then you guys
will do the project with each other.
And that's just the very first project.
You'll do a lot more project in the future
and together also, you know,
this would be a good time
when we do the project today, kind of
break the ice with your team members.
You guys will see each other today
for the first time in video
since the project you guys do
will be video.
So, you know, that will kind of break the
you know, the
you know, the icebreaker
basically for you guys and get basically
acclimated and, you know,
get into the rhythm of working together.
So we'll do that
and we'll definitely do that.
And that way, you know,
I'll give you time.
I'll show you basically
how previous batches done everything.
You guys will spend time on that,
whether we're done
with the review quiz
and everything earlier, it's fine.
But I will basically make sure you were
the one
where Samir Someone sent
me, you ask,
Okay, so we'll basically
get into that and yeah,
then the class gets really
you will focus on the group once
and then the following class.
You know, I will show you guys or Mr.
Diego who takes over me.
He'll basically go over
and show you all that.
So we ready to just do a quick review.
Let's get started.
Awesome. Awesome, Awesome.
Good, good, good, perfect.
Let's get started then.
You guys can see the screen right now.
I just want to make sure that you
see the has to it.
Perfect.
Okay.
All right.
So we covered of course,
we're not going to go to the very
first class, though, but sure,
we can just do it at a very high level.
What did we cover from
my very first class?
What is SDLC?
Just to kind of see
software development lifecycle?
Absolutely.
Who wants to break this software
development lifecycle?
What exactly?
Let's go into the the each phases.
What do we have there?
Let me see if I can show you a picture
we're planning.
Okay, let's go.
Let's break this down.
We're.
We're planning analysis design.
Yeah.
Implementation and then testing,
Integration and maintenance.
What do you usually have over here
in the planning phase?
What exactly is that?
Is my volume too low? Is it for everyone?
Let me check us.
Is it better now?
Okay, I guess.
I'm sorry about that.
I didn't realize.
Okay. Yes.
So what happens in the planning phases?
Exactly.
First, you do the market analysis our way.
If there's going to be
a successful project
or non analysis phase,
we do collect requirements, right?
Great.
People already know their requirements.
What exactly Our requirements, by the way,
what exactly what
what does he mean by requirements.
What the clients want
the functionality man.
Good job, guys.
Absolutely. That's exactly what happens.
Gather there now do we as a testers,
do we start testing in
the analysis part or no? Yes,
remember, we do.
We checked the requirements, right,
against the smart criteria.
So technically
we are doing our testing from there on.
I was a little tricky.
And right then after this
we go into the design phase.
What happens in the design phase, guys
UI, UX, Okay, user interface.
Okay, user experience.
Okay, sure.
That's basically the interface is created.
The other things that happen, user name
design phase,
maybe also what coding language
they will use, right?
What, what, how many servers
they will need, all the backend part of it
basically.
But also remember there are multiple
people involved in that.
We have architects, we have developer
and we have UI, UX individuals.
They all are part of that.
Basically the design part
and the whole point of it is to make sure
in the future understand
whatever the system they're building,
it's going to be, you know, scalable,
meaning whatever.
If traffic gets they all traffic
increases.
You know, the softwares don't crash
or the systems don't graduate.
So they basically come up
with the blueprint,
they come with the Y wireframe.
Basically they come up with, you know,
what language to use, what servers are
going to have all that great.
And then from there on,
what happens once this is finalized,
we go into coding.
Yes, absolutely.
Now, coding is done by developers, right?
Strictly developers.
We as testers don't do that.
But let's say the coding is done,
the right development is done.
What happens from there on?
What do we do as a tester?
What is our job?
What is our job as a tester?
Exactly
as the code from find the mistakes.
That's what we do.
We don't really test the code, you know,
we can't really of course,
when we write coding and everything,
automation from our end, yeah,
we check on code,
but we can't really test the code.
We have to see the functionality.
Are the functionality build first
and what according to the requirement,
what the client wanted,
if they're not right, all the issues
and everything, right.
So when we find all these files
mistakes and everything,
do we go ahead and fix it ourselves?
No. Right. Absolutely not.
We report it to the developers
so they can work on it and fix it.
Usually when they fix it,
it comes back to you.
Check it, make sure it's working
fine and everything.
That's all it is.
And from there on it
goes into production, right?
When the testing everything is sparse,
then it goes to production.
That means it's
basically finally available on,
let's say, Dublin, WW dot, Amazon.com
or whatever it is.
Right. Which are the Web series.
So that means the customers,
whoever you build the software for,
they can actually play with actually
is needs news testers.
Well,
they had some internal issues yesterday.
Well that's what they claim
they could be that whistleblower.
The who knows right this way.
Okay then from from from the production
you know,
some companies will have maintenance.
Not all companies have maintenance,
but some companies will have maintenance
for that project. Right.
So that's basically SDLC.
Now, the approach of SDLC in real
time, right?
What are the two methodologies we call the
roll?
You said Twitter never fails.
You sure They got a high
waterfall and agile waterfall and actual.
Absolutely. These are basically the truth.
The two approaches
Are these the only approaches out there,
the methodologies out there in the world?
Absolutely. In our right.
No, there's plenty other out there.
This spiral framework,
There's so many vSphere out there.
There's so many different ones out there.
I don't know generally who else uses
those, though, but they're not as popular.
Most ones, popular ones are waterfall
and agile waterfall.
Let's just just kind of get an idea
which type of companies
usually or individuals
really use waterfall.
A lot of times you will see on small
projects and government site, right?
Perfect. That makes sense.
When does waterfall work really?
No one they want simple.
Yeah.
When you have very clear requirement
and you know exactly what you want.
Speed is also not the main thing, right?
The quality matters
and the requirements has to be crystal
clear from the beginning.
Right?
That's basically the main thing
to understand about Waterfall. Now,
what are some downside
of waterfall methodology?
No change, right?
That's one of the biggest.
When you can go back once each remember
that, you can go back once
each phase is completed.
Now if you find bugs
that say you are a waterfall project,
can you fix them or no?
Yes. Yes, absolutely.
You guys, when you find bugs
and everything, you can fix bugs.
You cannot change the requirements,
but you can fix the bugs.
Right?
That's a very simple, simple thing.
But I know a lot of people
get this confused, but yeah,
you can actually do that.
Too much documentation. Absolutely, guys.
Way too much documentation.
Sometimes I would say
unnecessary documentation,
but everything is documented.
There's plenty of that.
And what happens is
which face gets affected the most?
Which face do you think it's a first?
Like if we were to think of from SDLC
perspective testing, right?
Yeah.
So testing is one of the main thing
that gets infected more than waterfall
because the first let's say,
I don't know, one or two years, whichever
time they took maybe on coding on other
other phases, that might take a long time.
So you can't really predict,
you know, you know,
or have maybe time the right time
frame for testing.
So it gets affected the most.
A lot of times
what happens when budget is running out,
you know, and we're the last one,
so they might cut corners, right.
Okay. We don't need to test.
We need for testers.
But maybe ten testers were great, right?
They were able to find issues.
So those are some of the pitfalls
of waterfall.
Now, waterfall, is it
still let's say, for
example, is is waterfall led?
How do I put it?
Waterfall is still usable.
It only works in a specific context,
meaning
it only applies better
when you know exactly what you want.
If you don't know what you want,
then it doesn't work
and it can be still used to this day.
As long as people know
how to navigate through it right,
they are able to understand
how that works.
Now we cover basically waterfall,
all of that.
The advantage, this advantage of it,
we cover all of this stuff
before, but
let's see what happens to the next one.
Now we go into we cover and spend
a good amount of time was agile.
So what is Agile methodology?
Guess what are some advantages of Agile
methodology?
Flexible.
That's number one thing.
Yes, the flexibility of it is very
fast, flexible change.
We can make changes, build software
incrementally.
Absolutely.
So that means you have a working software
after a sprint is done.
Basically allow a change, more meetings,
lots of meetings that you saw.
You know, we kind of have tons
and tons of meeting in in in Agile.
And it shows you
that it's a very group effort
built in stages more.
It is a true approach. Yes.
Less documentation. Yes.
Some timing on documentation can be good,
but sometimes
less customer collaboration.
Absolutely. Absolutely.
So there's there's more in
when we look at basically an agile.
Agile is built in in a team manner,
meaning a lot of involvement.
Everyone is basically involved
in this whole process.
When there is isn't a clear picture
that then you are
the this is the perfect methodology,
agile.
See, the thing is, if the customer
is not very familiar, right,
or are not familiar,
so if they don't have
an idea what they want,
I mean, that can happen a lot, by the way.
You know,
you don't know what the final product
needs to be, you know,
because you work with them and you build
the software in piece by piece,
module by module. Right.
They eventually will get
what they exactly want.
And it's better for people, better
for projects when there is a little bit
uncertainty or uncertainty as far as what
they want built, can they get messy?
Absolutely, guys.
It can get messy
when you have a massive project
and the customer is still
is unsure of what they want.
I went through actually a project
like this, which was massive project.
Like I said, the United States
Postal Service.
I yeah you
they pay you sometimes for work and double
the work you keep on repeating
because you're pleasing the client, right?
So those are some things
that can happen in Agile.
I remember there's there's good,
good things out of it, but then there's
some bad things about,
about Agile as well, the pros and cons.
So at the end of the day
when we really think about it,
it comes down to the context.
Each method ology works fine,
it works fine.
But, but you know, it depends on how,
which company, which client,
so many things.
Basically, there's a lot of factors,
but they use waterfall,
they use a combination and they did not
really use waterfall or agile.
They combining
made it into their own version, basically
some things from waterfall,
some things from agile.
Now remember, guys don't be, you know,
shocked when you go to let's say companies
they companies might not follow exactly
100% of agile, right.
They might not do certain things of Agile.
They might customize it
because remember this, these are just
theoretical approaches or,
you know, tested approaches
that, you know, you can use towards
building a software in this fashion.
If you agile, you'll be successful.
These are things, right?
However, you know, the thing is, you know,
companies will do whatever they want to.
You know, it all comes down to that.
I'll give you a good example at Syntax.
We are very agile.
We do a lot of things,
you know, very quick.
If we see something is not working,
we change it, this and that.
But then there are things, you know,
we we follow waterfall,
we have adjusted to basically
whatever works for us.
So you remember this.
Whenever you go to any company
that you work tomorrow, don't expect.
Exactly.
They're following basically word for word
and how it's supposed to be.
Are there companies who do follow that?
Absolutely, 100%.
But then there's a lot of companies,
you know, who add their own things,
terminology that we cover
in which we will go over a little bit.
Right now, you know, those terminologies,
you know, these are the ones standardized
in, as you know, when you're
trying to become a scrum master and stuff.
But, you know, sometimes, you know,
they have their own terminologies,
don't remember this.
Maybe they'll have instead of
spring grooming,
they'll call a different meeting. Right.
So companies will have different terms
and terminology
because they've changed
certain things that work for them
Sometimes.
DEADLINE missed the methodology
in the way of project.
Angry Yes, it can, but at the same time,
you have to look at it this way
Deadlines are important
for when you're trying to achieve,
let's say, developing a project
within, let's say, a certain time.
Deadlines cannot be met
sometimes that that that doesn't happen.
That's absolutely possible.
Just look over here, guys.
We went over this the the waterfall
or project fairly waterfall was this agile
rate 42% nice project
failed in in in waterfall methodology
that means 23%
only 77% is basically a passing rate.
You can see if on a bigger project
23% is a big number.
If you look at it still on a failure
aside, if you're looking at Agile
so remember this, you know
these things happen, they still fail.
Things will happen all the time.
There's no such thing
as a perfect methodology,
you know, It's
just that, you know, nowadays this works.
Maybe in the future
there will be another system
of creating or way of creating a software.
But for now, Agile is taking the
the way basically leading the race
at this current moment. Right?
They have other version of Agile,
like I said, eight different ones.
We particularly focus on which one
those a question you
which one of which part of under the Agile
methodology scrum.
Right.
Scrum is the one that we focus on right.
They are different flavors.
They like I explained to you last time,
like ice is going to have different
flavors, but 70% of them are using
Scrum are the ones companies use them.
They have a little bit different changes
and things like that.
For a hard
you said I'm on Zoom from cellphone
can I switch to my lab done
for how you can do that Just remember that
and log out of it because it might not
let you jump into the laptops.
Remember, the zoom
has their own restriction so it doesn't.
So you can log out and then jump there.
Okay. Yeah.
So there are different
flavors, are there, right, as we see.
All right, let's break down and do a quick
review because remember, pay attention.
We going to play a game.
All right.
So who is the person product owner?
What is their job?
Is the big boss. Right. And
they're in charge of
basically,
you know, communicating with the client.
Right.
What else they do, they're basically
are they are so they're
they are writing the user story.
They are technically should be no business
analyst when we think about agile
methodology
the job of what a business analyst does
is technically
what a product owner is supposed to do.
However, I like I mentioned to you,
I've seen it in a lot of companies,
so we should consider an Agile
that there's a business analyst.
They don't Marmot
They don't pay for the project.
They're the one assigned to the project
supervising
all of that, making sure
the project is succeeded, right?
That's what the basically manager look
one way is looking is like a man, manager,
supervisor is more the scrum, remember
that defines the goal and focuses on
product backlog,
what they can prioritize
and they can do that. Yep.
So that's that's the product order.
Then there's an individual
called Scrum Master.
What do they do?
Supervisor. Coordinator. Right.
Their job is basically to run the meetings
and make sure that, you know,
you test tester developers,
whoever is is basically on track.
You know, they, they cannot fire you,
they cannot hire you.
They cannot do anything like that.
But they can be
the one that you can talk to
if you want to get the message across
to the product owner.
They are the middle person.
They're part of this with Scrum
Master are on your site.
Technically,
we got to give it to them, right?
They can give you a task either.
Now, remember when we talked
about the spring grooming planning,
they can basically clarify
those tasks and everything
and then at the same time
make you guys choose that
a bridge between the dev team and client
like the best way to look at.
Yeah that the money like you said there
they make sure everything goes smooth
that's what their job is to make sure
everything is going smooth.
We're following the scrum methodology.
Let's say they're that's
why they're running all that.
You know, the scrum
was there meetings and things like that.
They're usually the ones, you know.
Yeah. Protecting you from obstacle Marina.
Like you said, they're their,
their role is kind of important
in this field because, you know,
they're the one, the middle person, the
middle person and really understanding,
making sure everything is going smooth
and have a good oversight of it.
I am absolutely recording.
Region All right.
And then always the development team,
what happens in development? You
I should that's the
good it's like you're comfortable working
you have everything successful absolutely
Let's say maybe you're falling behind
or things like that.
They're the one basically pointing out
that, hey, everything is good to go.
Yeah. In the development.
See, we are tester business analyst,
designer developers.
Yeah, that's basically the entire team of
the engineers, testers, beard designers.
They're all basically called
the development team here.
Yeah, that's
basically the typical development
you hear that picture that we talked
about last time product
or as we can see, as you can see,
it's talking to the business individual
end user domain experts, Scrum
master on the side, a little bit lonely
right here where the real workforce
that makes the software happens, right
where basically those construction workers
for building the house right
where the same workers
basically building the software
we have hierarchy in basically
within the software world as well, too.
That's the best way to look at it.
Yeah, we are the real workers.
We're the ones who is doing the labor
work, building the software,
making sure everything is good and smooth,
but not comes into the tech work.
So if we look at it, guys,
the way I remember,
I remember how I explained to you
the example at the beginning
how product is made the same way.
If we look at it,
we're just getting different names
in terms and things like that now.
All right.
Okay. So we covered that then.
What was the product backlog?
Do you guys remember?
Product backlog has all the user stories
in task everything, right?
That's the combinations of all of it,
right?
All the requirements.
Basically the user story,
you remember this before in Waterfall,
we call them requirements.
Now we call them user story.
The time has changed,
but it's the same thing.
Basically the requirements read.
So they're all
the user story is all the tasks
that are broken down to smaller ones.
All the feedback.
Remember that that feedback is everything
goes back into the product backlog.
Do we complete everything from the product
backlog all at once?
Guys?
Not possible, right?
There's it's almost impossible to do that
because you can have thousands of items
in the product backlog.
So we complete those products
basically in a spring.
So what would be a sprint backlog then?
Sprint would be
you've taken some basically
user stories, tasks
and everything from the part of backlog.
Let's say ten user stories, you two
and you're working on those in that sprint
basis to bring backlog would be the
the backlog of just that sprint.
So 20 items you be working. All right.
These are the 20 items
in that in the Sprint backlog
that we'll be working, we will assign to.
Now, someone mentioned let's say this,
the sprints can be how many weeks can it
be? One week, two weeks, three weeks,
four weeks, six weeks, eight weeks.
Can it be longer than four weeks?
No. Right.
It has to be one through four.
It's not max three Now, does
can this sequence change?
Let's say one month
we did four weeks sprint the following.
It can be three weeks or two weeks.
Nope.
It stays consistent in whatever
the company chooses
from the beginning it all
or it will remain the same guys.
It will remain the same.
So the company decided to do it
from beginning of the project
that we're going to have three weeks
since they will go with that
for the completion of the project.
1010. Things change.
Absolutely can change. Companies can.
Let's say they had three weeks to launch.
Sure.
Because at the end of management,
whatever they decide can happen.
But is that happening?
Usually not really.
That doesn't happen. Right?
Burned down chart.
What does it calculate? What does it do?
I showed you in JIRA.
Remember last time.
So burn down chart basically
looks at the progress we have made.
How much work is done.
It's a visual representation. Right?
There is. Let me see a picture.
Visual representation.
We start from
the top needs to end up at the bottom.
Is this important for us?
It just shows us what work is done,
what's remaining.
It's more for management, it's more for,
let's say, a scrum mass in product
owner to look at, see are we on timeline,
are we going to make it?
It's there multiple.
Let's say, for example,
there's multiple reports out there in JIRA
and other tools, but it's a visual, visual
representation of basically
what work is done, what has been,
what is remaining,
and are we going to make the deadline
basically. Right.
So that's what we're looking at
when we look at the burned out check.
Then we have some meetings, right?
We had some meetings.
What happens in a daily scrum meeting
guys?
It's a 15 minutes meeting, right?
It can be standing up.
It can be sitting down, you know,
in the picture to showed you standing up.
But what do we talk in this, what you did
yesterday, what you're planning to do
and at the same time
so everyone goes one by one and talks
about what they worked on yesterday,
what they'll be working on.
And the main thing of is if there's
any issues, any impediments, any blockers.
Right.
That's the main thing of this whole thing.
Everyone gives the status,
meaning testers develop or design
or whoever is in that scrum meeting,
you know, they all do that.
Basically they give that status of that
and making sure that,
you know, we don't have those issues,
any of their issues.
You bring it up over there
so that way you can come to a conclusion
and there can be some resolved meaning,
you know, the scrum master will take notes
if there's any issues
and then have a meeting.
Okay, how can we fix it?
How can we get to the bottom of it?
So that's basically your daily scrum.
Then we had something called a spring
grooming meeting.
What happens in
a spring grooming meeting as
we understand the
user story, we click clear the user
stories, add
the person, take out details to I,
you know, break them down.
Whatever we need to do, basically
by making the main purpose of
is to making sure understand
all the user stories
and take out
any use a story that are unnecessary,
clean them up, make sure you know
we're good to go for future.
You know what you working on
you clarify all those things
in basically a spring grooming
just you know, grooming.
What is the word grooming mean?
We know grooming your cleaning up
and everything.
That's basically what we're doing in that
spring grooming meeting for those users.
Story making it tidy. Absolutely.
That's the purpose of it, to make sure
everything is smooth and everything.
If there's information that you don't know
or we're missing, you know, the business
and is people will contact basically,
you know, client and get that information.
We break it down.
We break down even into smartass.
We're here right Then after this,
we have another meeting now,
by the way, this basically keep in mind
when you have, let's say, for example,
a two week sprint, right?
So maybe at the very beginning you have
a spring grooming and all of that.
Let's see at the very beginning
now in this let's see, two weeks spend new
if you did is for this current spring
that's going to happen right in between
you might let's say on the second
on a Tuesday you can have another spring.
By the way, grooming and planning
meetings, I'm sorry, spring grooming
meeting for the future ones
as well to future springs,
because, you know, they have to clean up
and be ready ahead of time.
So that can happen sometimes you will
sometimes happen
within your regular spring
that's going on.
You'll have another spring grooming
meeting or the future springs as well too.
And remember, it can take time.
These meetings can take anywhere
from one hour to 4 hours.
It all depends on how you know,
if you follow a
one week spring, two, three, four
and how many uses do you have?
All depends,
but typically can take 2 to 3 hours.
Right?
Then what happens in the spring meeting,
guys?
What happens there?
How long is User story is going to take?
Absolutely.
How long is going to take for development?
How long is going to take for testing?
So basically, we're estimating here all of
and keep in mind, these are estimates.
Does it mean they're 100% accurate?
Absolutely not. Can one use a story?
Let's say developers say that, hey,
it's going to take 4 hours to develop.
Does it take 4 hours?
No, it could take longer.
Can you take longer
or less time in testing?
Absolutely.
Here, basically in this meeting,
what we do is we ask
we basically assign
that estimating time for these.
And then within the team ourselves,
we pick which one we will work on.
Basically,
I issue we use, for example,
JIRA is one of the softwares.
There's there's bunch of other softwares
out there.
Rally is very popular one there's mid-year
I as one of the more popular one there is
what else is out there?
HPL PLM was another popular one other
there's a bunch of versions
out there of similar one,
but JIRA is one of the more popular ones.
The one thing, by the way,
just a side note for this, right?
So let's see what you guys go to work,
right?
A user story.
Let's say it says 4 hours, right?
There's just something to remember
on the site.
Okay.
If a user says a story says 4 hours and
you tested this thing in 2 hours, right.
That's great.
You know, just give you a heads up.
You can do all of that
and it's absolutely fine.
But remember,
you might be assigned multiple users.
Three if all of them you're doing.
I had a time just a note.
Remember,
try to when you follow the company.
Let's when you get into the company,
follow along with with the user story
timeline and everything.
By this I mean this guys are
what can happen is let's say a user story
estimate is 4 hours and you do it in,
let's say 30 minutes or 20 minutes, right?
And you get all your user story then
will remember more work is going to come.
But just don't worry about the work
by more user story.
Sometimes what happens
just so you have an idea,
you're going to make the other testers
look bad because they might be like, Yo,
this guy did this in 4 hours
and is making this look back.
You could create some enemies
there, right?
So remember what I suggested.
You go to work, follow along, follow
along at the beginning later,
I'm sure if you want to do it fast.
But remember, go with the flow,
how things are right.
If something takes 4 hours
and you know it's going to take you
30 seconds or let's say 30 minutes,
just drag it out.
That's the best way to do it, because
I've seen this in real life, right?
We have seen others like,
hey, this guy's getting done so fast.
And then, you know, the management is
like, look, you're taking too long.
What's go, go.
Why is this person doing this?
Just to not understand
the work politics, Right.
You'll see that in real life.
You know, when you go to work,
there is going to be work politics, Right.
So take it easy.
That's a good way to look at.
Take it easy and follow along,
especially at the beginning.
When you start off
with your new career, right.
Once you get comfortable and things
like that,
you know, it's all different, though.
But remember, work, politics and things
like that is always there, you know?
So just be be careful with that,
especially at the very beginning.
Be a team player. Exactly.
I remember there
I'll be very honest with you guys.
I used to get use a story.
Sometimes it's says 6 hours
and I got it done in 30 minutes.
And of course, did I'd say I've done it
30 minutes and I dragged it out
because I know for a fact
if I do all of this now, remember,
you can do one thing.
Just a side note, I'll tell you.
Okay, guys, you know,
overachieving is great sometimes,
but it can bite you
and I'll tell you exactly.
I've seen this with
some of our students in the past, right?
I tell them, look, when you do work fast
and you're ahead of the other people,
it's great.
You'll get some very good,
you know, notice that, hey,
you're doing awesome and everything.
But what happens sometimes is, you know,
when you're the overachiever, then
anything in the happened in the future,
they just going to give you the work
and they can expect a lot more from you.
So just be prepared.
If you haven't worked in the corporate
world, that can happen as well, too,
because I have seen this.
I've seen even a student tell me, Hey,
I do my work so well and everything,
you know, but now I'm getting sick
and part of it
because now in the future, you know,
now what's happening
is they're giving you all the work now
because no one else is doing it.
All the burden is getting
so you have to be very careful with this,
you know, do the work,
proper job, but at the same time,
don't overdo it, because what happens is
management
will basically sometimes exploit that.
You have to be very careful in that.
So and you will learn that
when you really work in the corporate
field, you know, just know how to get it.
Not just on the side note,
you know, my friend,
because sometimes work
just a couple hours a day.
Yeah, that's typical.
Sometimes you want to have a lot of work,
you will do a lot of work, and sometimes
you won't
get. Advice?
Yes, well, this this is how it works.
You know, you got to survive.
You know, you got to know how it works
and, you know, get along
with your coworkers, you know, chit chat,
you know, make small talks,
whatever, talk about football, whatever
it is, interest rate,
Those are the very good things
that, you know, Remember this
when you want to go climb up the ladder
and things
like that, you know, if you drink
or you don't drink, go to the happy hour.
You know, get involved in those things
when you're in the corporate feel
is going to help you significantly build
strong chemistry between team members.
But at the same time, you know, it's it's
just good way to also go up the ladder.
That's also very important.
Yeah,
there's some side notes.
I'll give you some more notes
and things like that, that you can do it.
But you know, I can give I can sit here
for hours and talk about this.
If you have a 6 hours, I'm in turning 32nd
before that.
Yeah, I don't do that.
I'm like, that would be a good idea.
All right, let's go back on track, though.
So we have Sprint grooming.
Sprint planning.
Okay,
so then what happens in the Sprint review?
What happens there or Sprint demo
one of the meetings, Right.
So we are basically showcasing everything
all the client members,
stockholders, whoever.
Basically the project building is
a presentation of basically what you built
in the last one week, two weeks,
whatever it is.
So all the software that was created,
you're showcasing that
who usually presents this, right?
Like is it a developer business?
And as product owner
who usually does that?
So there's two people, right?
Subject, same e subject matter expert
that could be the person who's the most
senior, the right who has the great idea
about the system, right?
It could be anywhere.
And that's his or if not usually tester,
usually a senior tester,
someone we call a test lead. Right.
Are the one basically
person product owner.
Sure, they can do it too,
but I've seen usually testers do it.
I remember
I had to do it in front of like 60 people.
It was very annoying.
But you know, you kind of go through that,
you know,
but that that's that's part of the game.
That's part of the job description. Right.
So and it's not very difficult.
You know, you go slowly step by step.
This is what I created.
I click on it literally showing
step by step everything you've done.
And meanwhile,
when you're doing this, remember this
feedback will come, right?
Feedback will come.
Why don't like this, this and that?
That feedback is noted down by business
and this grand master product owner.
They're taking all the notes of what
the customer wants because remember
that feedback is going to go
where you guys
where is this feedback going to go?
Product backlog, right?
That feedback later on
will be turning to user story
will go into the product backlog, right?
So those are
the things that we will work on Iran.
All right.
So that's your Sprint demo.
Now after this, we have one
last final meeting that happens.
And what is that Sprint retrospective?
What happens in Sprint retrospective,
internal meeting?
What worked well, what did not work?
How we can improve
all the things that you talk about.
Yes, it's within internally, like,
you know, things that didn't work.
Maybe, for example, you know,
you got delayed because your environment
where you're supposed to do
testing wasn't working.
The developer took too long
and I was rushed into testing
because you did not
develop the story on time.
You know, you can
you can talk about all these things,
how you can prevent things
that stops you from productivity.
Right?
And also you can talk about good things,
You know, what things work with.
It's an open ended discussion
for everyone,
for the things that are going well
and things that are not going well
and how they can improve. Basically.
You can absolutely be very open here
and complain from mass about devs.
Yeah, you can.
Hopefully devs are good by the way,
when you go to the real world
and you get along and you will work
with developers all the time.
If you go back to SC office
in general, you know you, you would
definitely interact with developers
all the time.
You get to see their job
can be a little bit more challenging,
so you have sympathy for that sometimes.
So guys,
that's basically our quick review.
I think Recovered everything from Agile
Raid seems pretty clear,
but yeah, we cover
almost everything right now.
Let's test it out.
Let's see how you guys
are going to do this now, real time.
Are we ready for a quick quiz?
Will someone ask a question?
Let me see someone have a question first.
Sorry. You said what the.
Let me see. I see a lot of
questions are coming. Let me follow.
Let let me answer some of the questions
and then I'll do that.
Can you tell
please tell that to please can
you do about e w s is a good extra and
yeah I will Amazon web services
all is great.
We will be kind of going over that
at the end of the class.
Not today,
like end of the course basically.
So you get into that
with all organization.
Follow the same chain of meetings
typically the meetings
yeah they usually fall
if they remember this the individual
who you know usually if they're falling
I just there's similar meetings
they followed to very extent
but remember it cannot be 100%.
Sometimes they will add things to it.
It doesn't have to be 100% to the point,
but majority of them do fall like this. We
had 20
right guys.
It would be that difficult.
We're going to make it fun.
Okay, So let me see.
Let's play this game.
All right.
Classic one is
we pay.
All right, guys,
we're going to play this game.
How are we going to play this game?
Companies a work.
All right.
Go to this website.
Go. Who got it?
Okay, you guys need to go.
Hey, I'm not the person I really.
And enter the spin.
You see the website right here?
Who done it?
Now, remember,
you can do this on your phone.
You can do it on your.
I will share right here.
I want a little bit.
So go there and enter the pin
so we can get all the players in here
and use your real name.
I'd be nice
once you guys are majority of you guys
come here, then we'll get started.
I know sometimes a lot of people join
and why, but this is a fun game, right?
So join this guys,
go to cohort dot i.t and enter that pin
so we can get all the players
and we can play a
we have one
game is 4830349.
This is your pin on the screen.
If you're seeing it
then you're right on down for you, man.
That's fine.
And your mom
and we are worried
about where you guys are.
All right.
Now get numbers are coming slowly.
I'll give it about another minute or so
and then we'll get started, guys,
because I don't want to be too long
and I'll keep the pin in here.
So, guys, more people.
Just one guys.
Alex, you said,
can you tell us about rules?
You mean rules
as in in this, in the Agile one
we have Project manager.
Sorry, Game rule. Game rules. Oh,
this one.
This is simple.
You see, right now
what happened
we had so many now is decreasing
is supposed to be decreasing
guys not downward
really want to go God
I'll give it 30 more seconds than that.
And people are getting guys.
I know there's more than 70
people already.
It's I don't know what's going on.
Don't be afraid.
It's okay.
Yeah, we're way more than 60 people.
Guys got it.
When it reaches 70 guys, I'll start.
That's fine.
So more people just start.
I don't know where
the rest of you guys are, but that's fine.
So the member guys go to this website code
page or T dot it.
When you get there,
we'll give you the pins.
Yeah. I don't know what's going on.
It goes up and down.
All right. That's
why, guys, we'll get started anyway.
I'm not sure.
Maybe they'll join in between.
Okay.
All right, let's get start again.
So this game, Let's do this.
Remember, guys, you must watch the screen.
Okay, My screen.
Because the questions
will come here on your screen.
You're only going to see shapes
and colors.
Okay. Those are the way to answer.
So again, the questions
will be on the screen that I'm showing.
Okay.
So let me show you right now.
This hour, you need to go to code dot
i t and then play a game and enter
that print.
What does SDLC stand for, for example?
Right.
The question is here,
the options you have are on your screen,
so select which one.
All right.
There you go. That's how we did there.
Are you right to make sure everything is
good, Diane?
The very first question. Okay.
What does SDLC stand for?
13 of you said software testing lifecycle.
I know, I know.
Your buttons slip maybe by mistake. Right?
But majority of you said software
development lifecycle.
That's the right answer.
It's not software design lifecycle
or is not software driven lifecycle.
Okay.
Some slip your fingers.
That's okay,
but that's the easy one, right?
Understanding how the game works
question will come on the screen
and your answers will be basically
coming on your screen and solve
and you get to answer that Pretty simple
and straightforward, right?
All right.
Next question. Let's go.
We have 20 questions to go.
Who was the faster and not nyah?
Awesome.
And least you Geeta.
I hope I didn't pronounce your name right.
Perfect. Awesome. Awesome.
Now we're in media.
I think more than 70. Now,
which of the following is not?
Remember not a phase in SDLC.
All right, There you go.
That's awesome.
63% of you said performance based.
Absolutely. That's correct.
That's correct. Right there.
Only two three people got it wrong
that by the way,
it's code dot I, you spelled it wrong.
And this saw in the screen.
That's why you're going to the wrong spot.
You are URL is wrong.
All right. Good job, guys.
Very good. Jody.
You guys got it.
So that means we have
what is it, six people joint Should
maybe more will come in the future.
Louis All right.
Louis Number one, that means your look
at Mama G is a four pin place is.
Good job, Maria.
All right, let's.
At which phase of SDLC testing begins.
I remember this question
on site.
Woo hoo hoo!
Wow. We're very split over here
at which phase of SDLC testing begins.
And remember, guys, Yes,
of course we do the physical testing,
manual automation and the testing phase,
but we don't do it in the design phase.
We don't do any development.
We do in the requirements phase.
Remember, that's
why this one is a tricky one though.
But it's good
at least you guys are getting.
So remember, testing starts
in the requirement efficiently when we are
all verifying
basically through the smart criteria.
All right, this one, we could have done
better, but that's fine.
It was a little tricky.
Joseph. Okay. Joseph, one time.
Let's go.
In the question, what is the requirement?
Very simple questions, guys.
Read carefully everything and then answer
it or
all of the above.
Sometimes,
you know, I'm in college or high school.
A lot of times
when you got all of the above,
you just might ask
usually the correct answer.
So remember, it might not be sometimes
what is a requirement, it is a description
of functionality of the target system
is the expectation of users from software.
Product is a description of services
that software must provide.
So all of it makes sense, right?
And it applies to all of the above
for this one, that's the safest answer.
Absolutely right.
All right.
Well,
that has the highest answer for good job,
at least until we know
the following is true
about Agile methodology,
which is true true
all of the above it.
Here is the incremental process
to build software.
Absolutely.
Remember, we build it in spin is a process
where changes are adapted easily.
Yes, absolutely.
Because we get them in the spring demo
and then we basically make it happen
is a time box of true
approach for software delivery
time bugs basically means
is that can sprint right All of the above
and arrested that's
okay guys it happens but overall
good good job on this one.
Better better could have been
a little better but still very good.
All right.
We got we got some
we got changing happening.
We'll see towards the end
who's the winner?
Which one of the following is not a scrum
artifact?
The artifact
you got to live with Sprint backlog.
Remember, on the artifact
side, burned down.
Try this point backlog.
We look at the official one.
There was no.
You grew the story,
of course, part of the sprint.
The stock was specifically
in that category.
There is no use history as theory.
So little tricky question.
I know, but you guys still did
pretty decent on this one.
That's what we went over review, right?
Why I'm doing so much practice because
this thing will take time to stick in
and that's why the group
project is very important.
All right, let's see.
Alan is on top. There you go.
We got a completely new people now.
I said, All right, great, great.
Number seven.
Which one of the following
is not a scrum row?
And therefore we just looked at
this is not a scrum.
Oh, okay.
There you go.
Remember product owners? Absolutely.
There, guys, Come on. The product.
Good is
there is a scrum roll development team.
We test through everyone.
I was the head scrum master there.
We don't have a product manager
as a title in there.
Right.
So there you go. It gets a little tricky.
So now I know majority of you got
got it right.
But still remember Product Order
Development Team and Scrum Master
they're part of the they are
the scrum will product manager however
is absolutely
not are you guys doing so far
out of the contract
that will keep it going.
Who is responsible for prioritizing
the product backlog?
Don't
remember prioritizing
the product backlog.
Right.
It adds suspense.
All right, good, good.
Majority of you got a good amount of
you got a guy who is responsible
for the product backlog, right?
Only one person, product owner
who can move things around testers.
Scrum has no one.
Then there's no project manager
title in Agile.
Remember that?
So product owner is the only one who can
take away your work not accepting it.
Client wants this.
They can basically organize
and prioritize times
meaning okay, what's going to be worked on
in the future?
Sprint Right.
They can be the only one
making that decision.
All right. Good job.
Let's see if Alan, Luis or Jose,
which are the following
meeting, is not part of Scrum
and some tricky ones.
There
is going to be
this little is losing
in rank product review meeting.
We don't have this as part of a meeting.
Right?
See, remember daily stand up is always
their sprint planning meeting.
Is there Sprint retrospective meeting?
Is there a product review meetings?
We don't have such meeting like that.
That's called product review meetings.
We got a money guy.
That's a good job, guys.
Very good
arena for how to write.
Good for team player.
Just hit answers.
Good. Awesome. Awesome.
Let's do a burn down chart shows what
items of want.
Good job, The progress of the work
and futures completed.
Very good on this with the decline
in energy level on the team.
What I hope
that's that was a mistake right there.
Right
so guys good job on this
island. Island is on fire.
It looks like someone's about to take us.
No one is challenging Alan higher
to the podium and say question in limbo.
What is a sprint at the one
in? I know some of the reason
one president said the phone came
okay at time but spirit of potentially
shipping will work.
Yeah that's
what it is is definitely not the phone
carrier in this context guys
it is not directly during the last week
or two of the project
period of high productivity.
No is just the time for a timeout meaning
where basically a product
is created incrementally. Right.
So I know someone
that's someone by mistake
I'm pretty sure pressed
and they grabbed the red button by mistake
but we've got
a tricky out tries through it a little bit
tricky questions sometimes
some easy ones there but some tricky ones.
The reason for holding Sprint
respective is
what is the reason in
why do we hold spectrum
allows the team to take a red dot
so that allows learning that can be used
to improve team performance.
So you hear you thought, okay,
we're just going to take all of the above
and you get the right answer.
Absolutely not the right head.
I mean, this was part of it.
You had build it. Absolutely.
Yes. Allow learning that can be used
to improve team performance.
That's the whole purpose of it, right?
Yeah.
You complain here and there.
But the ultimate goal is to make sure
we get some productive out of it, how
we can improve the process in the future.
That's not an issue.
That's
what you just saw allows, and that's the
next one.
What do we have?
And still feeling
it is meeting that demonstrates
to the product on team
that what was accomplished
during Sprint and
yeah no all of it
I just went overall and that's right
20 minutes ago
or less
what happens.
All right good sprint review
slash demo meeting that's the main
one you have where you're showcasing
what was built, right?
That's what we focus a lot.
Respect, respected, not sprint planning
or stakeholder meeting.
That's not even part of Scrum.
There's the good job so far.
Let's see.
Wow. Luis back
and then Marino for HUD and Bill.
All right, great.
The bill has the highest answer
streak of 12.
You got while writing the runner Bill.
Good job.
Also,
who defines the business priority of every
business?
I'm thinking
right
now on a business priority of every user.
And remember, a product owner is the only
one who prioritize the backlog, right?
They're the one who knows the case.
Customer client wants this
this items to be worked on.
We need to some business priority. Right.
So not the scrum mass and not Scrum team.
Scrum team project manager doesn't exist.
It's the product or a good job on this.
A lot of you guys got it right. Awesome.
All right,
speed testers, back with an answer
or the do we have
what is Scrum Master rule?
That's the easy one
or jab all of the above
this time to work right Ensure
scrum is fully functional and productive.
Communicates to product owner and team
shield the team from external interfaces.
That's the role of what a Scrum Master is
supposed to do the job on this one, guys,
they do multiple things.
By the end of the day
they are a benefit to us
in the delivered straight street,
Asia and street right now to
where are all the user stories
to all of them.
So database and the burn down chart
but really
this is in the product backlog
guys that are sprint
backlog and is definitely not a database
guy it's not.
I know that's a tricky right
there is definitely not in the burn out
absolute product backlog have
all the user stories do I remember
is that accumulation
and combination of all of it
and it's still on top with
looks like we know who's going to be
the winner and is going to come back
with three in a row.
Good job, man.
We need everyone's good. Good.
All right.
What is the time?
Bucks for daily scrum meeting
and and then
they go 15 minutes, not 5 minutes.
Absolutely not.
Not 30 minutes and not 45 minutes.
15 minutes. You know, it's funny.
I see sometimes 76
people have answered them, sometimes less.
Let's go. I've got to go try to attempted
even if you don't get the answers
wrong, attempted.
All right.
Good job.
15 minutes is all I can.
The meetings go over that? Absolutely can.
But according to standard practice
of Scrum, it's supposed to be 15 minutes.
I definitely will.
You will see where time meetings
go a little bit more than that.
All right.
We have only three more questions left.
What is the main
purpose of the daily standup?
You're really
the majority of you got it.
All right. You know, that's not majority.
Should they give US status report this
commission?
No, no, no, no, no, no.
That's not the whole purpose
to share what you've achieved
and all this possible impediments.
That's the whole,
the whole purpose, you know,
just to make sure
we don't have any issues.
No. Added.
Let's see if you're speaking,
if you feel us.
Oh, he's still on top. There you go.
All right.
Looks like
we know who's going to be the number one.
No, that I haven't seen. All right.
My question nine to when is a sprint over
and I
would this to be with you
more?
Well, a lot of you
still got this right, which is good
when the time box expires, right?
That's good.
Okay. So, guys, remember,
the sprint is over.
We have a deadline.
By that time, things are not done.
Let's say this development testing
is not done on a user
story was back to the product backing,
but Sprint will be done.
We don't extend the for no reason.
All right.
So when the time bugs expires,
that means when the sprint is completed,
if deadline is 5 p.m.
Friday, that means everything stops.
So that time everything must be done.
If not, it goes back to product backlog,
some of the items that are not completed.
So good job on here. Alan.
Yep. Looks like you're the one,
you're the winning.
One last question.
What is the recommended size
for a development team?
One eight people
739 less than would be guessed
it was in the slides
by the way.
And then everyone gets
more right?
3 to 9. That's good.
Less than 20 yet sure, but 3 to 9 is
the one we're looking at.
Okay, Great job, guys. Woohoo!
That was it. Let's see who we got.
17 out of 20 was all far.
Muhammad out one second.
And of course
that's going to be Mr. Allen.
I think so.
What are you going?
All right, guys.
Good job, Alan.
You got 17 out of 20 only.
Thank you.
All of you got 17 out of 20
was just the speed.
Yeah, I mean, Ali was very competitive. I
lot of guys will do games like this
all the time.
Time to time,
of course, as topic gets strange,
but I hope you guys enjoyed it Did.
You guys enjoy this game,
right?
Yeah, it's won a lot of people.
It was
it gives a little bit of more excitement
to it.
Right.
All right, guys.
Now what we're going to do.
Okay, I'm not going to give you a break
or anything today
because the rest of the class,
you guys will be now working as a group.
So let me explain to you
what is the next task that we have?
Okay.
So to do this case,
we have a task of this.
Okay?
What we want to do is
I have these some simple rules.
Let me show you.
First, let me show you
what our students do in the past.
So you have an idea group activity, which
let me pick some the two.
Hello, everyone.
This is our team. With
what?
What did I do? All right, good.
Sorry, I say I just called America.
Plus, overseas, we have a seven members
and we will talk about that right off
topics today.
It's a continuous collaborator and
and he can hire us first
and he can fire lodging, I'll tell you.
So he's a very important person
I would like to look at
Role does not have any
I won't go into that.
But let me show you quickly basically
what I want you guys to do, right?
This is 19.
The whole purpose of this activities,
guys.
You see,
I went over the review with you guys 130,
40 minutes reviewing it,
and then we did the quiz over there.
Some concepts are still maybe
not too clear. Right?
What I want you guys to do, right.
This can be within 5 to 7 people.
Remember?
Now you pick each other.
It's going to be activity, right?
I want you guys to pick each other.
Let's see whether you are problem
specific.
Stay plenty.
You got to have to communicate now.
And if someone is left out,
I'll help out over here.
Right.
What you guys want to do?
Get together and then accordingly we have
some basically
the same thing that you went over.
We want to explain each and every part
under one group, right?
So let's say Scrum team
and artifacts will go like this.
If you have six members in a team, right,
you will go each and every one of you
first
talk about this. Okay? We need to explain,
you know, what is a product owner?
What do they do?
What a scrum match development.
Each person participates in this
recording like as a group, basically,
and explaining what they do.
What you understanding
is, can we be nine people?
Yeah, you can.
But remember this.
You might have to pick,
let's say a couple of these, right?
I give you a complete freedom
of which one you want to pick.
But don't do this.
If you're six people, you shouldn't
be picking one, two, three, four.
You should be picking one with six
and that's it, right?
So you guys can pick the team.
And what the whole point of it is speaking
because you need to know this verbal.
You should be comfortable basically
speaking about what a product owner is,
what a tester, what sorry, what
what sprint planning is stand up meeting.
Spend time on this first,
when you get in a group,
what you guys are going to do is
first of all, once you guys get in group,
you guys are going to do this
on, you're going to do on Zoom, right?
So basically the way how people
did their recording to each other,
I recorded them stuff.
They got on Zoom
each person went ahead and explained,
Let's see what a product owner does.
Someone might say, What a Scrum
master, whatever,
whichever activity group
they picked, basically, right?
That's what you can guys
come up with your own team,
whatever you want to call your seven.
We've seen some funny names.
Let me see
what some of the names were before,
but don't pick these names.
But let's see what we have.
Bunker buster
as the software is due to the minions.
Whatever names
you want to give each other, you know,
just get together,
use Zoom, talk to each other.
Here, I'm going to give you this activity.
I'm going to download this and I'm
going to post this in announcements.
Okay?
So I'm going to post this in as a PDF.
That's fine,
guys.
This is your group activity.
Okay, So look at
I'm just attaching this
in groups.
Okay?
That's basically where you want to pick
your, your, your, your caddy.
You want to speak. Okay.
This is you're going to start it today.
Some of you can finish this, but
I want this absolutely done by tomorrow.
Right.
And I'm going to give you the link guys.
You're going to be sharing this.
Let me put this the link over here.
Whoops, Not here,
you guys.
That's
a low pick.
There's so many groups.
Sometimes it gets confusing.
I share this, so let me copy this.
Oops.
Okay.
I put this group in here
that's in the course announcement.
Here is where basically
you gonna record your responses, guys.
So look at the course announcement
when you click on that.
For example,
you were
it takes you to the SDLC
as a response rate.
So what you want to do,
guys, is within your group together,
you know, get together all talk about it,
record your recording by the rate,
record it to zoom locally which are you do
and then you can add your responses
You can either recorded here
or you can basically upload the file right
This allows you flip, it allows
you about 5 to 10 minutes.
If it goes over, it's absolutely fine.
It can be, let's say,
more than five or 10 minutes
because we want you all to do it.
So this is a group activity.
Unless you do not finish guys,
unless you do not
finish, then you can basically try
to finish by tomorrow.
But I want everyone right now to go ahead
and start talking to each other.
Remember, you can do each other or create
groups over here,
get together and do this activity now.
And remember,
if you're a six people, pick something,
either six or if you're five, people
pick scrum ceremonies, right?
If you have four, then
you still see all five of them, right?
If you are more than four,
you're like eight of them.
Try not to go too crazy
with the team, right?
Then pick at least couple of them, right.
Six and four or something like that
and I can explain how to record it. Yes.
So, guys, what you do is when you're going
to do this, remember this.
You can log off from this class today.
Once you get together in Zoom, you know,
you can record it
and you can upload the five.
Now, this allows you to record
over here as well do when
when you click on let me Libya open that
and it will tell you
what the limitation I've seen
if you do the recording through flip
get directly
you see right here and response
it allows you to start recording
if you allowed camera and everything
but the only thing is limited to
you do it at all.
Yeah.
There's a scene in my bedroom
and I want to show you my bedroom.
But anyway, see you right here.
Basically you to record right there.
Once you record it, what happens is
it allows you only few minutes.
So it's better to use
actual zoom in there.
Once you use zoom,
it can be longer than five in 10 minutes
and you can upload the file.
So it gives you the opportunity
to upload the file.
Actually.
So this how we do doesn't make sense.
It's pretty straightforward,
but unless someone is confused,
I want to make sure I am clear on this.
Anyone to join our team?
Remember guys, you can say this.
Alex, Anthony, lock down
whoever it is where the team busters.
Remember, you guys get together,
we need a member of three or four,
let's say, right.
Got to need four. Okay, Communicate.
And by the way, in Slack,
you guys can do each other.
I don't know if you guys know this or not,
but you guys can DM other.
So in Slack in direct message, you can add
people in, start a conversation there.
So I want anyone who doesn't have,
let's say a group or anyone, right?
I can try to assign here.
My hope for our goal right now
is to make sure you guys
have team members.
So Mohammad, the brother and sisters
are in team who wants to join them.
Remember, I want you guys to communicate
more this way because I in the past
we would create the groups for you.
But what happened was
you don't want to break that barrier.
You know, you guys are classmates, right?
So try communicate with each other, right?
So maybe guys, you can say it is New York.
Who's from New York?
Anyone wants to join here?
Let's join. Who's from West goes.
Okay, me, me, me.
Let's join together.
Okay. Virginia guys can be together.
Your group?
Absolutely. International groups.
You guys can meet together. See?
Was in California
the way someone is doing it, right?
Who's in California?
Respond to that comment.
Who's around Texas?
That's fine.
Remember the best way
to get this organized
is, let's say,
Mustafa Common, Virginia tester.
You probably want to comment under there,
right?
Hey, I'm here. Let's join
let's join Virginia test right.
See that some of you when add me, add me.
Okay, great.
Let's do that. Your test or whatever.
And by the way, at the end, if there's
less members, you don't have a team.
Reach out to people.
Guys, can I join your team?
Yes, absolutely right.
Remember,
try to keep it 5 to 7, 5 to 6 people
if you can please.
Who is from Carly?
There are some Carly people so far.
Hard to reach out to
at ish right there.
There you go. You're there.
You guys can be. Is San Francisco, L.A..
Who over here.
Okay. Got three. Need one more?
Someone getting join their team right
there.
Anthony. Still looking for a team.
You can join the Virginia guys,
the local team
want sheriff Washington state you can join
based in California here close by.
Harry Join those guys.
Sebastian, you're from Vegas?
Yeah, I Know,
we have a lot of people in the DMV area,
so you can have multiple groups.
Go see if you're from Maryland.
I see that.
And Anthony, your animal.
There's two people right there.
Right. Join each other.
Let's see.
And Abdul Kazim,
maybe if you don't have a team, join
right there, guys.
Someone needs a Angie, let alone
like she's from a midwest.
They're from Chicago to join them.
Guys, whoever wants to join a
CC, do do that to make it more easy.
Guys tag each other.
We are this this people.
We have these people.
We need two members who wants to join.
Do it this way
that when that when people can join
Amran is by himself
So guys join someone let him in
Eric I'm
Ryan You can join right there with three.
We need the members
to join their in
so remember tag each other guys
comment in there
to the person that we can add more people
just feel you with three people
you should probably added they're good.
You're in awesome awesome great.
Our ride needs one more person
got Angela and Alona.
You can join Ira and Laura and their
group, Gainesville Group that's asking
how to create teen chat.
Just this very easy.
Let me see.
I will show you right now
one second.
So guys, let me show you this quickly.
Oops, Lucy, I
you know,
I'm not a fan of math, but I'm using my
in this class once I get
one of them nice piece of equipment
I issue. Yes.
When you want to do your zoom meeting
amongst each other,
you can leave this meeting.
I'm just here
to navigate people and everything.
All right, So let me change my chair,
my screen definition.
You can see you share it when you do this.
All right, guys,
you can see my screen right?
Right here.
Right.
So, guys, remember,
you can direct chat each other, right?
So, for example, James, let's see here
are, let's say, right
and all the people right.
And you can basically start stars
start a group this way, right?
Once you do this, you know,
you can add people, right?
Add this people and you can start a chat
together this way.
So do that, this way, this way.
You guys can all just communicate
with each other
whether you want to do it
now, later on, whatever you want to do.
But I think this is going to be
the best way.
And remember,
just look at this document in the course,
of course, announcement right there.
And the link is where basically
in the course where you want to add
a click and recorded thing
or upload your response right there.
Sebastian is missing.
Guys, anyone wants to join Ceilidh Group.
Sebastian Join Sheriff's group Seattle one
right there
or Christine you can join.
We can do seven, right?
Yeah you can do seven guys,
you can do seven, you can do up to seven.
That's fine.
I, I live for let's see, join anyone from
Let's see.
Alex is in New Jersey.
You can join there guys. Remember
it can be spread out.
I'm just trying to give you
some suggestions of how to.
Let's see be partizan team
Abdul who needs by the way, let's do this.
Who needs members?
It doesn't have to be Virginia.
You make it.
It makes it.
By the way,
a Bill Shinwari, Abdul Kazim join.
Go and join that team right there. Okay
that's fine
You guys could join us
a us ones as well to
this mention
the teams we're missing people
let's see when you need members
and at the same time anyone or
I mean if you're missing
okay join of them guys
voluntarily say hey, join me.
How can we add people?
Remember, you communicate in your chats
and everyone, right?
So join those team.
When you say you're in your team,
just go ahead and start
chatting with each other.
Yes. If you have your team, absolutely.
You guys can leave the zoom and go ahead
and work on the project right now.
You can create a channel hour
and create a channel
to create a basically direct chat
with each other.
You guys can do that.
You can use DM guys, direct message.
You see on the left side
there, just add the members and start
talking to each other in there
and then send send a Zoom link recorded.
Go, go ahead and you'll be good to go.
Joseph Who wants to adopt Joseph
to their group?
Yes, the money.
If you have your group,
you can leave the zoom.
Absolutely.
If you guys have your groups,
you can leave
this issue.
You can leave.
No. For today, I want you to spend
time, remember, understand
each and every one of them.
And then each and every one of you
need to speak about spring
planning, spin, standup,
whatever you want to do.
Okay, Alex, you have 42 people or so.
You have four people you need to.
Is it due today?
I want you guys to finish it today.
However,
if by some chance you're not able to,
you guys can finish it
uploaded by tomorrow.
So it's in the course announcement.
Nabila, how about you do
this? Nabeel, why don't you
join Alex's
team?
Perfect.
Right there.
And you guys can DM each of the guys.
Nabeel, Amani,
you guys can join each other.
How about that?
So you can be three and then maybe there's
even if you want to do a small group,
there's one right here, terminology, one
which is for people
that can be done.
There you go, Missing members.
Let's see who you are.
Go raise your hand.
Where do you upload the file?
Good question.
If you go in the course announcement,
you see, flip it right there.
I will make this as a point.
So you can see this is
I'll write it right
here, guys.
I appended into the course announcement.
That's where your PDF is in.
Where are you going to upload it?
What happened to your TV collapse?
How many people were in the Ahmed
that was going I guess
I'm trying to break
the ice is like matchmaking over here.
And we were
I used to create teams, but I was like,
let me make them get together,
you know, open the conversation.
Okay, Ahmad, you need a team right now.
Why don't you go ahead and join
Mohamed's team right there?
Go ahead.
Okay.
Alexi And you guys can join Mohamed's team
Sometimes If you have more than,
let's say, four or five member,
that's fine.
Yes, You need to
when you start doing the zoom.
Yeah, just go ahead.
The same way that you joined Zoom right
there, you can edit
and you can start a new meeting.
Once you start a new meeting,
you know, everyone just share that link
and you can basically be there.
Oh, sorry, guys.
Let me let me make the public one second.
Thank you. Well, I will make that public.
Everyone that
should be active.
No, no, no.
You don't come back here today.
I want you guys
to all focus on this today.
No worries.
Okay? Who wants to join the Bulls team?
Anyone missing who doesn't have anyone who
whose by themself?
Let's get real.
Let's get you some two more people
missing members.
I have a group speak now.
So, Mohammed, let me just make it clear.
You depending on your team size, pick
any of these topics, Scrum ceremonies,
Scrum team and artifacts
as DLC or terminology.
Pick whichever one if you're six members,
pick any of these one right here.
So once you pick this, okay,
then you assign each other aide.
I'll talk about product order,
what a product owner does, what
their role is, etc.
Then another person will talk about
Scrum Master,
someone else will talk about development.
And who are the people that Sarah
Yes, guys,
I give you full freedom to pick
whichever one you want to.
But remember,
if you're six people and do not pick
the one as deals
sorry, don't pick the terminology
because there's only four points
over there. Right?
So pick six or five.
Someone can repeat again if that's par.
If you guys want to pick either
organize, you have the freedom to pick
whichever you want to.
Yeah, let me check on the link, guys.
Give me one second.
Let me figure out what in the world
the link is not asking
me one second.
Meanwhile, let me get you together.
I will work on this
one second.
Guys, let me figure out why
the link is not working.
But meanwhile, still,
keep in mind, guys, get going each other.
Let's see. We're seven people.
What do we choose?
Mohammed? Remember,
you can pick any of them.
And remember,
you can add an extra one from there.
When you
leave this room and start a group.
Yes, you can. Let me work on the link.
Let me make it active.
Guys, one second.
It will
actually
important
guys, don't worry.
Just get in the groups right
now. Record your video.
I'm working on the link
and there's a little problem with it,
but you can button next to 3 minutes.
I'll fix it. Get the topic.
Topic is I one was no
guys still any members
who don't have a group.
Please speak up so we can add you.
I can navigate you.
Yes. Or one you can choose any topic
you want to remember.
Try to choose between the group size.
If you're six, try to go with the 613
ones.
It might work
and you
agree is working fine.
I'm just changing the settings
because I think it's not allowing people
to jump on this for me one minute
and everyone in there,
remember,
if you need to do your group, think zoom
once you need to log out of this ones
and join there.
You don't need to be here.
You can do both at once.
I live there in the course announcement,
guys.
Course announcement in the channel
right there.
You'll see right there, of course.
And I was on the left side under channels
is where you're going to see
all the instructions
and you're going to see
at the same time the flip get ring.
But meanwhile work with your team members
get together,
flip, girdling, let me fix it.
Something is up with that.
So I'll I'll fix that for you guys. Yes.
You guys can leave the meetings
and then you can join
you can join your each other teams.
And that's where you can do your
Mahamat.
Try to also DM each other.
For how many members are in your group to
I live depending on your team size.
Pick the one from the from the pdf.
Whichever one you can do the ceremony is
you can do the artifacts whichever
depending you guys have freedom to pick
whichever you want to.
Let me figure out what's going on with the
flip grid.
Guys, can you one second?
Yes, I guess I'm just trying
to work on the link that I muted myself
just for the time being,
but I think it's going to be working now.
All right, guys.
I'm seeing more people joining this,
so that's good.
You guys should be able
to go ahead and record in there.
I see more members join that.
So that means the link is working fine.
Anyone else lost or confused right
anything?
Just speak in here so I can navigate you.
Okay, Nabeel.
Okay, so now all your members, all what
I want you to do the time each other.
Eight Start a group, chat with each other.
Let's say all get together.
Someone will log out of this one,
share a Zoom link grade
a meeting with each other.
Then all of you join.
Basically join, discuss
which topic you want to pick.
Let's say from there,
why don't you select the topic once
you select the topic, then okay, start
recording it.
Once you record that you know what
you recorded,
you can upload the file from the zoom on
or directly in flip it.
That's basically how you want you do it.
And the view
all the members that you talk to,
you can just tag them in here in chat
and then you can start a conversation
with them.
So Once you guys have at least an idea of,
you know what's going on and you can
then start recording it.
So if you remember who
your members were in your group,
so can tag them and then
let's see, okay, It's a hard
or a hard let's see who else was there?
Mohammad, Which group are you in?
Okay, let me ask you this.
Only people who don't have a group right
now just type in, not in the live form.
So I can then give you guys groups
notation.
You don't need to come back to Zoom, put.
Yes. I'm sorry.
You need to leave the meeting
and do a meeting in Zoom with each other.
You group members? Absolutely.
Now you got it.
Everyone from one group, just one person,
Mustafa from the group can record
and then one person can basically upload
for the whole group.
It's easier
instead of uploading separate one. Yes.
Everyone should be presenting
in the meeting. Absolutely.
The whole point of it, again,
is to get you guys comfortable
in talking to each other
and at the same time
speaking about these ceremonies again
every day because a very critical part
of the of the class, let's see
if someone else is lost
and still help out.
Let me do this, guys,
to make it easier for you.
I see whoever doesn't have a group,
I'll add you right now myself in a DM,
so I'll get you guys all together.
Okay. Mohammad, You.
Let's see. Amara, let me do this.
You guys have a group
I can add you to Amara in the Bills group.
Let me do this. Let me.
Let me message you guys. Okay, I'll say
and do this
more.
We'll
get this.
Perfect.
Now you see my message right there, Right.
Okay,
who else do we need in there in that chat
you can add in there.
All right, Omar, Nabeel,
you guys can chat.
Let's add Mama to your group as well. Do.
And in this group,
when guys to get together,
someone just to Centrelink
and get all my thing,
they Jordi everyone right now has a group
and they've started.
But again, if anyone has lost anything,
I'm here to help you get a team,
which is the easier process to do it all.
I think it gives it a challenging,
but we're getting there.
No, Nabeel,
you don't need to create a new account.
The zoom you have,
it gives you an option of a meeting
so you can see the meeting option in Zoom.
So if you have downloaded Zoom in general,
you can use it.
And when you open zoom, you will see
you will see an option of meeting.
By the way,
I shared another link also in in Zoom,
so I might even zoom in in Slack you can
you can try it over
there should work fine for you guys
perfect new link I
put in there guys
you can click on the SDLC all.
We are from the flip grid one.
You can just do it there
for anyone else.
Let's see anyone else
who does not have a team.
A little fast.
Anything.
Let me work with you
so you guys are good to go.
Oh, very good.
If you want to start a meeting
within, let's say
each other,
you can just do this entire meeting.
I mean, that's.
So are you communicating, Noel,
within your team?
Team members,
stop recording this progress.