So let me
begin quickly three topics
which we studied
yesterday.
We are using now in Studio
Java Project
one dictation Project Guide 11 Project.
What is this
legal practice here?
What is method
right
moment is the be the management
tool, right
brand management tool.
Fine.
Noticing our libraries trade,
it captures the dreams, all the libraries.
And what are the libraries
we need to fix? 100.
Excellent. Or do not.
If we talk about then
this moment is a brilliant management tool
which will be used to create a complete
folder structure right?
So basically we need a very
organized structure to work upon, right?
We need a to work upon.
It was we had this had a key there
we define which set of good
we have to write in
which particular portion of
the framework correct.
So it's that simple.
You can understand
grade and framework is from a library
in library for you goes there
there is a separate section alphabetically
so all the book starts with a one
shelf books
starts would later be available in bishop
and so on.
High city rainy days there.
So we generally find all the books that
the library, these books are segregated,
so we don't need to search every book
one by one.
Right.
If we know book is rich Deadpool two.
So I believe the Dominican
Republic Street
as simply go in the shelves
and then I guess it is reached
reject order book.
So it is very easy to understand
if we have an organized structure,
if we have agreement.
Similarly,
we observe this need encoding is what
that is what we came up with
the management do that can do it
as bestowed upon the structure.
And now that
we have this organized structure,
we are using it for a coding perspective.
So the first thing is management tool,
which we are using is fine in Mandarin
right in moment.
What are the advantages we have?
So the first advantage is
we don't need to add
any jobs manually
right?
Mebane says.
I will link to it
all the dependencies that you were
taking here in the form of chart.
Now we just need to edit two
or three lines of code.
Then once you add this code
in one of my configuration files
from this file
and is going to the central repository
and I will page
all the important information
in the libraries from there that you will
when you do it in your project
and have it provide you most advantage.
You don't need to add any jobs manually.
So that had deep processes.
Second thing is uniform.
State uniform is the same kind of origin
is using by every other team member.
So there is no conflicts in using
their different version of the same to
if I am using 73.14,
then everyone else in my team
is also using synonyms with one
or because I added responder fire rate
and they just need to split, upload
the project in their machine, then state
and provide all the dependencies
related to this medium.
And so on other tools. This
relates.
Now imagine we got both folders
in this RC, we got two.
Former is the first is mail
and the second is the best.
If they have a different version
of selenium, then that's good.
It is against the standard
and the one with the culprit he has.
He has to change technology.
So that's why when we created
the only one person who's responsible
to edit all these things
and then that person completes
the code in the repository and others has
two others have to take this code
from the repository and use the same code.
Agreed.
So it can't be like I'm
using different version of the study
using different version.
They can't do that.
Good evening.
City Noise User Motions
Main is for developers
and best is for testing environment.
So which folder we will going to use case
visual computers.
Best of all, it's that simple.
Great. Fine.
So now here
we will use test for
all is
inside test we have java
and inside this to be had
would be which is source just
the ability to mean already.
Yes most would be to determine already
because we don't need to
find in Java we don't what
a one sprints squeak
coding part
for things
and in resources we don't what
non-coding stuff
only good and then we'll just correct.
Excellent. Yep. Just do it quickly.
Get right like 8 minutes to get
and then we'll go further right
then.
I explained one example of could do right,
how it increases the collaboration,
how it and this is a business
that I would encourages
more communication in between developers
and testers and length right
raises.
Remember
the example If there is a new user,
then we can provide 10% of discount rate.
I give the example of two people or more
than 400 phones to explain the code.
The blade will not have to spend anything.
A man was the guy with
whom was the owner of the right company.
Right?
And then instead of providing the code
in the how for a month
and for the way to manual
in terms of language,
you can just put everything
in that example.
So now
here,
because we have some miscommunication
or communication gap, I would say right,
because of using testing
or any other dude, we came up with Google.
We didn't generally write the language.
What does it mean with this
written language?
The language simply means plain English
text, right?
So make a converse.
Suppose
we read behavioral driven development.
What is behavior driven development?
It means writing your scenario or discuses
in terms of functionality,
but it's in terms of behavior to divide.
And you write those and use
to rate the behavior of their discourses.
We use grouping language
now in 39, which we studied,
for example, restricted for keywords
given when and then rate.
I explained all this for current whatever
the precondition, we will be very good.
Whatever the precondition,
we will be happy.
We reiterate that precondition
and the given keyword,
whatever the actions we will provide,
whatever the actions
such as click completion
or send gives operation
or selecting their dropdown operation,
every single thing we will provide with
when word,
when key word,
and if we have multiple operations
to perform, multiple actions to perform
right then instead of using when,
when when other names with use
one supporting keyword and that supported
keyword is and if we have similar
similarly to preconditions,
then I will use end with given
as one given and given like this.
Similarly
for expected output for expected condition
for reasons for verification
when it should not be used then,
but it isn't to be used then.
Right.
And if we have multiple verification
validation values
and we've been honest
so far, so
think
now under is another keyword.
Here it is another keyword
we concretize
under the keyword core feature.
It's what is the key words?
Region
What does it mean as a feature?
So remember one thing
that we deserve to be will write great.
We will trade all of our best guesses
based on their behavior.
Correct? That's what we said.
Wherever we create this test
guesses in this test
consistent on a device.
So this scenario was disingenuous,
which we would write.
I will write them in feature by.
Right.
So the extension of my find
is the heart feature.
The extension of by is not feature
in which I will write
plain English text directly
meaning which and understood to
indisputably one
great
the rates and menu
we use
something
like this.
So my feature find this simple
the way we provide don't be exported
text file
we will provide note feature for feature.
Okay.
Is this clear to everyone?
It's nice.
Let's proceed further
off feature up to
which of that is another
you would go to menu.
So what this scenario scenario
simply means this to case rate.
We are once in a few moments
you'll one best case.
So for example,
there is a user's tool that you
it is a user story number 123458.
So in this user story I am seeing a woman
should be able to search and
in it demos.
Now see now understood one now understand
this admin should be able
to search and employ in a chat
and application what does it mean
if I open the application is
and I should be able to search it
employs agreed.
Now let's see this functionality
first manually.
Always remember
when you test any application rate,
you should use this functionality.
You should check the functionality
first when you need.
Make sure the functionality is working
in the non to implement
in your understood.
And that's what everyone
Nancy,
I am on this page
employing permission
which can everyone see this page
as of no, no I need to search
I need to search.
Employee Right.
So you see here make search option vacancy
and here I get
see to the page
search by name and search of
I can you see this
right
so to this I have here I have do is here
search by me and search mine and it is
categories
and now it could take any from here.
Let's take this idea to search.
So I'm providing this idea
and basically construction.
Correct.
So this is my valid employed 80
and it provides me this particular data.
It provides me this particular data.
Can everyone see employing permission
directly on search?
There is another way.
There is another way to find employee via
name by a name, right?
So we had to wait in Myanmar
and so I would be able to find this
to check.
I don't know who created but see
a lot of local
listing this X, y, z.
This is the name.
I'm going to take this as a name
search.
It's giving with this data with X, Y, Z.
You also
reason.
So now I have to do
is I have two ways to find any employment.
One is search my
lady and secondly, search by
name. Right.
So let me go here on the note
and I I'm going to think
let me go to the node and here I'm going
to read one important thing
I'm seeing.
Everyone knows, right,
how to read user stories.
Everyone knows how to read visitors
to this base in menu.
So great.
So now I'm talking about expedience
criteria.
Hooray to the study, by the way,
he delayed
be rated of study.
Who defines acceptance criteria? You.
Do you tolerate
any person losing
its product
or rate
which defines the acceptance criteria.
Right?
If it is an individual person
indefinitely, developers
can define anything
and that's what it is
in the product owner response
and the responsibility rates
that can define the acceptance quality.
So now here acceptance criteria,
which I see right,
is first search by IED
and the second this search
by name
is entering the exit acceptance criteria
we have on this particular
district street.
Right
When I would consider this acceptance,
it is complete
when I can apply to search rate,
when I'm able to search by, I'll be
or may mean this predictive improvement
from now.
See, the moment I see in the acceptance
criteria I have to
be is to apply in the employee.
Right.
So I have to write the code for two this
and then we have to do is this is nothing
but my scenario.
This is my scenario.
It means I have two scenarios
which I need to implement
and this one,
it means I'm having almost scenarios
to implement race
those in areas to implement trade.
So let's go ahead and do it first,
I'm going to read you the scenario.
One even given means precondition, correct
categories.
So in given I'm going to write here
right as a precondition
for searching of employment first,
I should be able to log
into application of.
Correct.
So let me give a user
opens a browser, and
then maybe get it to a post
first
thing, then end
user is
logged in is an admin
I used and given
also because I have two preconditions
in this case, given user opens browser
and then the user is logged in to me.
These are preconditions right now.
And again,
one more precondition user is on is all
employee needs to reach, right?
Because the actual best guest starts
from searching an employee right now.
Here went my own employee list page
when I am on this page,
this is my employee list,
which everyone can see it.
Everyone can see you create
clean
next. Right.
So now here when I see given user opens
browser and immediately to
and any user is logged in as an admin,
any user is an employee list page.
This is my brief. In addition.
Now the activation starts when user
interface ready employ a team.
The first action I'm going to
provide is in three valid
employee ready and user
clicks on
search option
or search
addict.
This is what we are doing right
and then means now
when and
for how to revive use and
clicking not.
And I'm asking what did
not and not start.
It's not that there's full time scene
for that
there's what I'm saying
it essentially discussed
this this and a day can come with every
and that a keyword trade
if we're performing multiple operation
right
so if I'm having two actions back to back
I cannot use when two times
when use it in an employee only in venues
or placed on certain no
because you have one supporting keyword.
This time we're using and here
supporting advocacy developers to
is to remember like like
then user see
cutting Jimmy we can use it.
We have multiple verification
so we can use that more than one
already.
So it is very easy for you to understand.
Now here you'll see then users see
employee
in the role to
be confronted.
Is this scenario correct?
What I'm seeing generates
quite similarly.
Let's talk about the seconds and then
so in the second scenario.
All right, I'm
going to copy this completes interview.
But the only thing I'm going to change
is instead of going use
that interest will employ
only I'm going to use it
in terms.
And then and
lastly, I'll
write
all groups, groups
nice use.
Proceed from there. Now.
Now you'll see
we have to read all of this stuff.
All of this stuff in our actual framework.
Correct.
So still, we have to keep our framework
ready to exit all these things. Okay,
Now let's
add one by one couple of things
in agreement.
Point
fine guys.
Let's think let's think
from from technical perspective,
from a Q automation engineer perspective,
we need selenium.
It's at any rate,
we need Java
based, we need to Google, we need.
But also, like
I told you, that we will learn
how to parse data from the pixel.
So we need Excel Final eight browser data.
So jobs, for example.
Also we would need
in longer run, we need all these things
or not any
Greek.
So now,
now when we need all of this things, how
we will get all this things right.
Let's take Selenium in Java.
We already have in our project.
One question
can you it again to work feature.
Yeah, you'll get that.
I'm going to explain the feature. Ready.
So like I said, these two scenarios
I can you see you get them.
Okay I need to write this to
and menus in my
project also in my work also
so the place where I have to write
all of this to not use made
this is what we call feature
feature point.
Okay.
I need one place
to read all of this, this fun.
So now first let's make our project
predicated on this mega-project.
Really selenium java we have.
Let's knock them out.
We need cucumber and fine.
So we have one place from the region.
Really? A lot of these things. No,
we don't need to add jobs.
What is that place from where we can get
all of these things based
simple memory repository.
Right.
Let's go to one deposit.
There you go.
So what?
I said, what we need.
First, we need to convert
address.
Let me write cucumber here.
So many great cucumber.
I search for Google in my memory
repository
I got to do to merge
Java and Google merger.
You need in everyone's interest
to convert Java and to merge you you need
how many of you guys can see
now end of
and we can talk with
a lot of
weird guys.
We could
date I'm I'm coming I'm coming later.
Why not should be blossomed further
and this
pretty
nasty case I can see a lot of cucumber
files gives me a lot of cucumber
related definitions See it Make your top
dependencies available here.
Right. So we might get
mistook or I would see confused
which one to use which would be correct.
But when you see all this things feed
you see here it says I could remember.
Can you see this?
Everyone could convert GBM Java.
I go to the U.S.
Google GBM unit in folks.
If you were JVM Java,
but it invokes great differences here.
So we really to do a lot
of JVM Java with I go to the
end similarly
Gutenberg BMG unique with you with Google
these two starting ones we need
but I do work with
I wanted to put the Google unit
Java into Google
and restore
these two dependencies.
We need wasn't created by a mighty well.
I need to ask. And it was.
I'm not sure.
Basically sometimes what happens is of
the higher tools engineers trade
would actually develop
and they provide the need.
It's like there, it happens.
Also.
That's what I'm saying.
They're exporting.
For example, today
you are starting with syntax, right?
Tomorrow,
if you go to job of, let's say $100,000
right there, definitely a lot of companies
will try to contact you.
A lot of teachers will come to you
and then give you money
and take a photograph with you
and use the your program.
The other day we thought this is truly
the genius of our student automotive
that is very like this.
This is what good marketing outreach.
Similarly, they do all of this top three
if they see already.
Ziad is very useful, give him some money
and then we use our local
session.
Would
already so now we would use first Kimber
GBM java OpenID
open it
now. See the most number of downloads
here?
The most number of downloads.
I would always prefer this most groups
4 to 6 6.9.13
because a lot of people,
a lot of people, right.
Showing faith here in this 6.9.1.
Let's use
the same Let's go with the 6.9.1.
Can everyone see this extraordinary one
opening?
If you can see it, then open it.
Simple.
Everyone knows how to copy
the dependance from here
and how to add a dependency
symbol.
Make sure you're adding these
under your dependencies.
Take. Right.
So here, let's add this.
The first dependency we add is cucumber.
Joel Understood.
And this one, the one from yesterday,
one from Rudy.
Now let's go back and take
another one is to merge our record.
We need to merge unit is one correct.
We need to convert.
The unit is one.
So now remember I could convert again.
It should also be I google
for month where you want me to go back
here.
So selenium dependency must do with this.
That's what I'm seeing.
One is from yesterday when you spoke today
we need all these
dependencies right
now we need this Gutenberg.
All right, let's open it
again.
Again. You see, you can do it also. Right?
Uh, let's take a virgin.
You starting today.
What? Your state 6.9.1.
This one Also Jimmy Castro
could add folders to
which one?
But is it 2.4.0?
Now, when I got a look.
So now you see in this part of the
can we use a virgin 6.9.1.
Right.
So we try to keep the same virgin
for the complete cucumber one
one more dependency we need to add.
Right.
So the another dependency we're going to
add is for the tumor unit and Google data.
Do we have 6.9.1?
Yes, we have 6.9.1.
So either we can go with this
most number of downloads, six
total industry or to match that uniform.
This we can go with 6.9.1 s,
but it's up to you which one you're using.
I would prefer 6.9.1
because the same dependency
the virgin I am using for
make it to go to Java.
So let's copy this logic.
It's copy this.
Great.
Let's copy this 6.9.1
without any good
because we didn't update the project.
Yesterday's problem only three read.
Now again,
just copy and paste this to Do you
copy this
administrative. Uh.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Hold your horses.
Wait.
I will tell you to upload the project.
I will tell you when to click on this.
Believe everything. Right.
Let me be the instructor
for two and a half hour trade
and then read everything
for Bombarding symbol.
Next.
We don't copy the code, write it create
and we created the project
it generates automatically.
We don't write anything here
the memo is read.
I know it is read,
but still task is not done yet.
Once we are done with the task,
it becomes blank.
Okay.
Now see, guys, I told you right.
We got to remember also Selenium.
We have no Java.
We now the do we have no correct.
No, no, no, no.
Wait.
Ease grade, please. Wait.
Why you always go two steps further?
What I'm explaining read.
Let's not do so now.
Still we need to add four. Excellent.
Correct.
We have to add the dependencies
for Excel point also.
Right?
Because in future we will use Excel.
Also getting.
But we one
nice nice next year
for next grade we will add two jars.
How many years?
Two years.
The first one is a budget.
Boy create a budget boy
this is the dependency
be used this Apache point common right?
And the another one is simple Apache boy
these are there.
Do we need to read our data or right
or replace
you see access to Microsoft Forward files.
So let's open this
open this and the Virgin
let's see 304.14.1.2.
Can you see everyone?
4.1.2304.
Open it.
Let's see this one copied
from Evan or did a bunch of dot boy, boy
I depicted this
boy Virgin is 4.1.2 copy copied
and this dependency is one
has everyone added this dependency
so is everyone with me.
Nice.
Let's go back Go back into the word again.
Now another we need
Is this a budget boy or big semi
made Apache boy or executed
from here?
Also you see 397 downloads
right for $1 two
Let me click on this 4.1.24 Apache boy
seven schema open
open it
and copy this dependency also right
copy this dependency on entity.
So now you see the only difference
in between these two is just to add
instead of boy just write boy hyphen or x.
And can you see this
not only differences instead of boy
you're writing here boy hyper and
correct
is this correct place
nice nice.
Now now here search for
commons
common or are you
right so
commons I know
this is the Apache John State
Library contains utility classes
it's implementation find filters
competitors everything grade common
Apache common or simple commons title.
I'll read.
So let's take this Apache Commons.
I forced from here
to read the file
and everything in the word and we will use
C 2531 Most embodied on groups 2.8.0
so open this 2.8.0.
Copy this.
Dependency 2.8.0 Commons
by with this dependency
and paste it in the project
pasted in the project.
Nasty guys how many dependency it to us
so far?
How many dependencies we have mixed
lot six
right?
Today we have added five all together.
We have six correct?
Correct.
Now, now
when we have all these dependencies,
it means we have Java in that project,
we have Selenium in our project,
we have timber in our project,
we have Exxon in our project.
We have file later called Commons.
In our project,
all the libraries related to the sector
that we need to work on our framework.
We have all these things here are not
so 2.8.0 and
right, but Nason,
isn't it very convenient instead of adding
this much of jobs, right?
Because if the project increases, right,
you have to wait one for destiny,
two for exclude for commons 24.7
for selenium, maybe some more other jobs.
Enjoy it.
Not only increase
your project size, makes your code
bulkier, also makes it grade.
So it is very easy
to just add simple dependencies right now.
Click on this report icon everyone.
So you see it's reading all the files
and try to get the data right.
Can not connect
on it, which
I'm sure my internet is working fine
again.
Someone please let go of dependencies
here in the chain.
No, that's fine.
You see this big icon?
No problems on we go to trade.
Just try once again loading it
and then it should work.
Sometimes it happens
in creating the connection.
Fine, fine, fine, fine.
Enough, enough jobs in every dependencies
available in the check.
Think
your grades are very much sentimentally
based.
It's something you always want
to blindly like.
Really? Voters.
I say this is too one okay to still break.
Normally it's not okay to still visit.
I wouldn't mind. Typical.
But again,
these are there to fill in issues
for the Apache right?
So for a bunch of what we have to do with
is the reload
are just right click right.
You see this member option
inside this member option
you see reload project option, no problem.
That's great.
Sometimes you get it,
but you're able to copy best. Here it is.
It's already here.
That's what I'm saying.
That it should be go upgrade.
Did you see this apache related
dependencies already there
five six is bested the code in the chat.
If you check it.
Can someone please send the
specific dependencies this to finish this
to opportunity dependency.
Only one.
Most of you that's always there.
So even if you copied, keep it with you.
Right when I needed.
I will ask
can you see one
dialog box coming
right on your bottom right corner? Read
silver bottom
right on record says Configure
plugin click on upgrade available.
Upgrade available.
We don't want to upgrade anything
right now.
It's not a problem, right?
This is just a warning.
This is six.
Warning means that bleep it is giving you.
The problem is actually
this is not a warning.
This is information, but they provide
information in terms of warning.
We're also having,
you know, Einstein brain like you was
experienced, always get confused.
Why are we having so much warning?
This is not warning.
This is just an update.
We don't really get it for Windows.
But on similarly, these are the updates.
All right.
If you're using the order jars
or the dependencies
view of the neighborhood,
so we don't click on configure plug ins.
If you're getting the adoption rate
for configure plugins right,
you have to click on that,
but for which one you're clicking.
So later still what it says Recommended
plugin available for Java I hope come back
Java. Great.
So it means that there's a problem
with adding that you here
in her dependency.
The problem is not with the comments,
the problem is with the one
that she added.
All right
Maryam
is to redirect.
So what needs to be done your data is
your is still the rate
then what needs to be done
where everybody's working their note that
it is yours is also all right.
Do you try this?
What I said right click on your project.
Go into Maven and reload your project
config plug ins.
Not if it is that. Yes, I did.
You did. Fine.
Then please
close your intelligent and open it again.
Sometimes you need to refreshed.
Yeah, it is just an advice.
If your code is working fine then
you can ignore that kind of notification.
All the more issues are done right.
There is still if it is did
not restart computer just
closed intelligent and open it again.
It was just his old effort
for work.
Okay.
Well versed is just click on this
crossword
and index it.
Fine. Nice.
Let's take one more minute.
So did you know she can not read anymore?
Thanks. That's great, William.
Nice. It is for
you also close, intelligent.
Open it again.
It works.
I'm good.
It doesn't like mine or work similar.
Can you do it?
Trade now Silva This commons
this commons version
you visited this particular
dependency
links.
See all of them is more important.
You what should we so does
I put it in the race
just to soak the moisture it amazing
you madam beauty straight
discussing each
of the how to discover radium
Nice.
Yes, you are correct.
What do we click on here?
Oh my math is still great for you.
It is started.
Then what do we click on here?
You don't need to click.
Just open your ability.
Just open your intelligent
and it is still very, very good.
It will
nice.
Now, guys, let's proceed for a bit.
Remember we ended for best in the exam
and we want called create Best in Geeks.
And how many of you guys remember
we edit create this exhibit date
from where we added that.
Let's run Nora
plugins. Great.
Good moment.
We added in the plugin. Right?
So to go into the plugin,
I gave you two options.
Either click on search and search
for no idea run config, no business.
It configuration would be a really strong
embeddable reporter plugin.
We are going to click on file
inside by will click on Settings.
Inside settings will see plugins
and inside plugins.
We will search here right now what
we have to search here, we have to search
timber for java.
Don't use your brain
and use this key to mcclusky
timber for scale or something.
Just see this option for Java.
How many of you guys can see this option?
Everyone can see this option. Everyone.
If it is not installed in your
can you be sure
click on file.
Click on Buy, click on Settings.
And then are you with me?
Click on Settings.
Invite Click on the Settings Option.
Inside settings
you'll see this plugins option.
I don't know.
Certainly
if you have a mac, just search it.
Then in the MAC raid
you must be having this particular version
in Mac,
you must be having this search option rate
or simply perform double shift.
Right.
Double shift.
So in this double shift
you will search here for plugins,
these are the plugins
and when you open the plugins,
you see this option here, correct.
Now here, right,
for the timber, timber for Java
eight
here,
it should be in market place.
Yeah it should be in market based,
not on installed,
it should be in market place here.
Simply
when you write could Google for Java
it ask you to click on install option
like this based on this particular part
is will click on that install it will ask
you for another option called guarantee.
And also I need to download.
There's four times
the medium just I repeated
don't be on installed click on contact
place.
Yours is uninstall.
Please click on market place. Yes.
Yes moment.
That's
what I'm saying when you try to install to
but it will ask you
to install the routine as well.
So yes, click yes on going again. Yes.
We need that also to install as well
and then click here on installs
is to restart do read.
Yes. Yes.
We have to.
What if it is already installed?
Then it's good. Congratulations.
We start to yes, yes to amendment.
It's fine if it is already installed
that it is fine.
What could be better than this
without any pain?
You already have good Google.
What I can see here is basically because
of getting a lot of errors in your Java
and the new selenium, you guys are
so much attached to the error.
So when even if your code is working
fine that they get shocked
by not getting the error. Yeah.
Restart 80, click, restart 80
and then
everyone is different experience
90 people younger.
I completely understand
we should install, but I do understand.
That's why I'm going slow.
Do you think I'm going fast?
Oliver
All right,
so everyone, everyone restart 80
and when you open it, read
and user identically Google.
I would be honest with started that
uh, if it is installed it was going
to finish already and start a moment.
Right? Is there already looking?
Because when you try to install this,
when you just try to install this right,
or even if you type
in right, it gives you
this part going to get so it didn't start.
Can you see
when you select
that it will always give you installed
because you already installed it
with to convert part.
Okay.
Yeah.
Already installed
there's automatically installed
also you will see
it is going to be version one.
No it doesn't.
It just type did it then you
are here or here.
Nice.
So now no doorways.
I am ready right.
So always I am ready.
Now let's talk about folder structure
Also install it.
All right Nicole, do it.
No issues.
We should simply it is just a metro one.
Be great.
So do it.
Not everyone with me this
great.
Now tell me one thing.
In our previous project.
In our previous project, remember
we were reading the properties
using switch cases technique.
How many of you remember that?
So we added all those properties
in configure
properties by correct
and we added one
class called Configurator Class
to read those properties.
Correct.
Now see the same thing we needed here
as with the same thing we needed,
we're also not done.
We need entry. So can I copy that?
My units order and my config folder
from the previous project.
Can I do that
again?
Every building
otherwise can be created user
for heart.
If we created again,
then it will take a lot of time.
Right? So we already have that part.
We can use it
and then I will, I will probably basically
I will definitely
give you the overview of that
again
and everything we have configured ready.
They're going to properties by
we have a function to read the properties
straight
from the config file in configurator
I think created
so that if we keep repeating
the same point three or four times, then
believe me
we will not be able to compete on best.
Right.
So please try to understand
this is the part of your revision rate.
This is not the part of taking
another class for the same topic rate.
So please cooperate.
We have already
I have already got this one week back.
Right. So you should.
I was expecting this answer from you
that already we have revised school here
and the of of of current code
or the next level could follow
so now now here here
we have this two part
common methods and configure it
guys can you see
can anyone see this here
now let's see what
what are the things
what are the things we can take from here?
First we need to configurator
or first we need to consider properties
what we need first and
first we need configured properties
or configurator
first.
We need our properties plain.
Right Then we have the start properties
by then only we can read it.
Correct.
Now let me copy this config folder
from here.
Configuration
related part is in concrete folder.
I'm going to copy this.
Copy the Florida not in me
one D is confident properties
having in this contract
for this job on one job
a yaml that you have to click on restart
week, week, week week.
We are already ahead
week one.
This is non java great.
This is not normal.
So now when I open my project,
which part I have
for non java
resources.
Correct.
So this time my config will go to java
already sources
and the resources.
Simple.
Let's paste it into resources.
Now you'll see insert resources.
I have config inside config.
I have confident properties, but
is this clear to everyone?
Is this clear to everyone?
What if you don't have to by Jimmy?
How is it possible that we don't have
we have to create this file date?
We created this file in an earlier project
so we already have this by.
Yes, correct. Correct.
We add this config under resources
and we copied this medium
from our last project
Saving computer Properties.
Find there.
Jimmy.
Remember we added this
configure properties in the last project
from a stingy entry
because I missed the most class.
But this is not the first class Jimmy did.
Was the last class of custody.
I missed that too.
Then do you mean
you have to rewatch the video?
Right?
Then you have to watch the video
and then you would understand
how we did it.
Now, Now
for reading this properties. Fine.
Let me go to you.
Which class
we are using to redo these properties.
Pre nice
configurator.
Correct.
So you see under
you have configurator I think
any one thing
when we are working on one big application
on one big application though
we need common methods
to remodel them or not.
We need common methods but it
we should so can be copied.
Is you disposed of completely or not.
We can copy.
Okay, so let's copy this.
You this package from me.
Now tell me now.
Tell me this have having common methods
to configure.
This is your non java
And is this your
So let's come here
and where I have to it now
under Java three.
So simply paste under Java
simply paste it in the java.
So now we have got these units job.
See my is structure is getting a shape
now is getting ship started
getting shipped first thing put under Java
the very first thing we got utilities
great days we got utilities here
and everyone seemed
to be built I'm going there.
And so now if you open this,
if you open
this door, we need to change the port
in the common method.
I'm. I'm coming.
I'm coming to their monitor.
Don't worry.
I'm going to give you permanent solution
for this
boatman
ordering.
So now, now, wait.
You see here we are getting this before
my third agreed by this before.
But it is in red as of now. I'm
because it is from my
it is from my best engine.
The when it is I could convert.
When we are working with this dingy
we don't have to double it
working with to do it.
We don't have to add this dingy.
So you're still in this line?
Did it this line? No, don't ask me.
Why are we deleting?
Because we don't need that.
It disappears with your intelligence
name should be
the magic,
intelligent, magical, intelligent point.
It's deleted.
We don't need it. So stupid. Stupid.
I deleted
similarly after method.
Do we need after method?
No, it's deleted,
looks deleted also
plain so from import
one we destroy important
So far so good everyone
nice.
All right Jimmy, if you are missing
the cluster, this is not my fault.
You need to understand this.
And even if you missed the class,
you had Monday, you had Tuesday, right?
You could have voiced all of those videos
for this dingy, Right?
And then we came here because this is not
the part of good Googler.
This is just a part of framework
that we already did in Destiny as a don't.
Right? So please try to cope with it.
If I keep spending time for one student
on teaching the same again and again
indefinitely, I'm doing nothing.
But risking others means time
and at the same time I would do it.
I have to complete our syllabus on time,
right, And to make everyone understood
what I'm teaching.
Right.
So please try to complete
after this 3 hours
you have complete 21 hours
to watch the videos and everything.
Please try to do it.
I am here
not only for you but also for everyone,
right?
So I am very much bullied, very much
cooperating with every one of you.
Please try to be the same with me also.
So there's
there's script.
Alex, There's Craig.
Now then change the board to configure.
What now?
It's fine.
It's fine. See,
let's talk about permanent.
An dinging.
The bottom of config properties
is it's a temporary solution rate.
Today it is in my machine blade, so I am
waiting the bus according to my machine.
Like the model,
the code will be Alex machine.
So what Alex will do,
Alex will provide the part
of his machine here for config properties.
Correct. Alex
After that day.
Let's see with Alex for one,
join the company.
Right. So I won't join the company.
So what would happen?
So one will also take the mark
in his machine.
So again and again
we are changing this thing constantly
cutting, cutting days.
That's what we are doing.
We are just keep changing the things
fine.
Well, we don't need to do it.
The framework says
you have to provide a common path.
That bug will be fine in every once
machine automatically
we are going to define that.
But not
only the but
we will define there
the beauty of three inputs.
Now just understand one thing.
Everyone will be having the same project
in everyone's machine, correct?
No, no, no data repository.
But that's what I'm saying moment right
now. See,
here we are having this particular
framework
can see it.
Inside this framework
we have is RC folder.
Everyone can see
inside is start.
See we have these resources,
inside resources, we have config in
inside config
we have considered properties.
This structure is seen across
everyone's machine
or not. See,
see, maybe users
maybe saw an
idea projects. Right.
And then my project which is then is CRC,
then resources,
then config
then can be stored properties right.
This is the
but now you see from here from this part
each item is is our series
sources config config properties.
This bob is seen right this
this particular part is similar
for everyone
that is getting my point.
This part this common for everyone.
The problem is with this.
But the problem is this part right?
What is this part?
This bar defines video
project is available
where your project is available.
Can you see inside your project?
Once you come inside your project,
then things are common for everyone
in the root path.
So you see we are about
we are bothered about this part
till this part, right in this part.
Fine.
So do we have any functionality
through which we can this path?
So the answer is yes,
we do have this functionality.
We do have this functionality.
Now let me show you how this functionality
works.
Great.
Let me up somewhere. Maybe somewhere
in a simple
John normal Java class street.
Maybe in my Java projects
it we open my normal
Java project.
I'm just trying to show you something.
I don't do anything. This
is this my main method, right?
This.
I'm going to bring something.
See what I'm going to bring to here.
Right?
I'm going to write system Dark
hit property, right?
And here I'm going to write is to see
first user d
I user directory system dot
the property
is the command of system, right?
It is the command of the stock.
Whether you are using your Mac machine
or you're using your windows machine.
Right.
If I write this particular command,
identify, try to predict, see what it is,
what it prints.
Can you see?
It gives me one, but it returns one part
and you see everyone.
Students
What is this book?
What is this one?
This board is the root
part of your project.
You see, my project name is as Dick Matt.
11 Java. Right? So it rebuilds the path.
It returns
the part where my project is available
in the current machine.
When my project is available
in the current machine
right
now, let's go back here to this point.
See, this was the problem.
This was the problem for us.
So this part is seen.
So my favorite one right
I'm going to put is system
dark gate property user data.
Now, if it is running in a machine,
it will does
the path of recovering the machine input
is running in Lumos machine.
It will it?
Does the model knows
machine input is running in this machine.
It will return the path of this machine
plus by two, which is my project.
So that is already same
for all the machine.
Correct.
Now when we add both these parts together,
part one and by two it means the part
of what all of my files,
the files defined in my framework
becomes common.
It becomes common No one
is indeed the permanent solution.
Tell me
so one, let's go ahead and do it.
So now, in future.
In future, tell me you just picked
this particular part from you.
It would close this project.
Now tell me in my project,
will this project location will despite
location configured properties, be seen?
It will change.
The fine
location will be same forever. Right?
We cannot change schema with schema
policy.
Just kidding.
All right.
So now the location of this file
would be seen correctly.
So there is this general framework
we can change the by location.
Okay. It will be in this place.
Now, the box,
the back of this file will be constant.
The part of this vitamin
B constraint, correct?
Is this could case similarly
if we are going to pass
some does data from Excel
find it from any of the file?
The part of that file
also will be construed
right now
you'll get to your favorite topic
if we are going to see the screenshot
summary of all the execution rate,
we will always see the screenshots
of the execution in one place.
So there will also be constant rate.
Just thing from a wider perspective.
Case.
If you're using this framework
for a longer run, we have to use
all of this part, correct?
Correct.
So now when we have to add
all of this part which had a constraint,
it's create a new find new class going
constraints class.
I'm going to create a new class called
Constants Class.
So in constant class,
what I'm going to do right
this constants
classes is still under my utilities right?
Because this is also not my main
part of code.
The things which I need in my code,
I will write code for that
particular part, which is coming under
the category of utilities right.
So now here
the first thing, the first thing,
if my port is not going to change,
it means or despite the
end to make
any entity or anything,
find them in the Java
which would be used
by making it
read,
it means it's menu cannot be changed.
So I want to use it.
I want to use this part in one package.
In one goes on in the complete project.
In complete project.
I need to use this one.
Replace the big project.
We need select related public
static. Why static?
You know everyone right?
Extending because we already
wrote a couple of methods
in common methods and made them static.
If anyone has any confusion,
go ahead and check these methods.
We already have this method sticking it.
You it
so public static.
I'm making it
public stating and create
and then I'm providing it my
configuration underscore file. But
this is my file.
But I'll read. This is my file.
But now remember guys,
whenever you provide any
variables, whenever you provide
any variables are finding
it is the standards in constants.
In your framework,
you put those variable names in code
gets the providing here, right
So configuration file import
configuration from mark
and destroyed everyone.
Now see how we define the path.
I will define the path for just one grade.
I will end up on
just for one C system dot good property.
Right?
So it returns the path to my project.
Initialize it.
It does the path in my project.
Each item is virtually remember every one,
but after each item is batch
what I have to do,
I have to add the path of my project
inside my project, the hierarchy. See?
So what I'm going to write here, my
project in each item is batch 11, right?
I got this block,
but in this job in this batch
11 very small country property 16 minutes
in a Jardim
is batch 11 under each item as batch 11
Should I go
first?
I have to go render SAIC
correct
first, I should go
this RC then under is RC.
I should go
under
under test.
Come on here.
What we have best first in is we have test
under test.
We have our
resources.
Under resources we have on config,
under config we have our config told
these point.
Is this clear to everyone?
No. Now we need this,
but in terms of string
because it returns the string.
Why I'm seeing the string.
You go in your common
methods, you see your passing.
This file partner
dumps of the string or not. Then
it is returning the bottom of a string.
So now, now try to match this.
Is this the part of your project Slash?
This is the part of the hierarchy
of folder in your project,
Correct.
So this
part we got was this term property.
This block
and this part were defined, right?
This pathway defined.
But here, here you see when I use RAID,
just add one keyword called the string.
So now you see the moment you add string,
it will return the bottom
string of one week.
Now this is the absolute part,
but even the absolute part,
which is providing you the value,
it is completely customizable
and it is common to all machines,
it is common to all the machines.
So now this part clear to everyone,
one Mark
and me, this post
this, but clear to everyone.
Nice.
Let's come to our common methods
now Let's come to our common methods
and see how things
are going to change. Now
in my common methods.
In my common methods,
I don't need this particular
but let me put this part.
I don't need this part. Now
then what else I have to do
is I can simply call my constant class
dark.
It's this configuration file.
That's it,
That's it.
Now this is
this is something great common to everyone
days.
Even if machine is changing.
Even if people are changing.
Even if you're not in line with this
changing this code is not going to change.
And if this code is not going to change,
right, it will always return the path.
Wherever
my code is running on that machine.
Correct.
So that's how we will always find this
properties irrespective of big form.
It was but the of machine it is your team
member understood we made it global
according to every single
machine using constants plus
this part we want
is getting
rid of this
so far
is there anyone who has any question
about this particular part?
What we did
is that anyone who has any question,
somebody expert,
great man, nice.
Good to hear.
So after break, I'm
going to give you a very good,
you know, surprise in this project.
We didn't do anything it maybe
we don't need to carry glue carrying.
I will give you a very good thing
straight after the big raid
or six gigs I got from my students
and my friend just put.
But it's the U.S.
idea to see its user.
Don't be afraid
that you can check
your user data.
Correct.
I didn't really get about so user directly
or this is a command trade
instead of user territory.
If you the user dot or is that it
returns on which operating system
your device is working,
which operating system you have.
Right.
Similarly here for user,
if you provide the does
the root part of the project
in which project
you are executing this command already.
That's why we're using this command.
So against the path of your current
project in every machine now in just
here, we need to create
this class which this class
I didn't create any test class anywhere.
If we are using main,
then we should always be a no, no, no, no.
We have to use only user to the same,
the same for
the one between no matter what.
Like I said, I showed that to you.
I brought you not to do anything
just to show you the output.
I use that project.
It just uses computing constants
on these common methods.
This is your common method.
This is just only line. We it.
You'll see not even the complete line be
just this, but
fine.
All right, guys.
So far, so good.
Everyone.
Great.
Let's take a break for maybe 10 minutes.
23, not much break, 20 minutes
and let's connect it.
715 once again,
I think 12 minutes to 11 minutes.
But you can manage eight
because the important things to do
and I'm hungry I don't want and then find
and then take a break for 15 minutes.
You give the reason why
I can't see anything in that you have to
explain.
No, I mean, it is weird.
We think we're doing it very quick.
In my companies,
you go, you have to spend.
It is two weeks,
three weeks to create a framework.
It takes time because it's
not only about writing the book.
It's all about
understanding the 15 minutes.
And from seven five
we are going to start the break break.
So I meant, yes, it's normal.
Everyone takes this much of time
because this is one time activity.
You have to do it with full concentration.
Great.
Everything you have to plan,
you have to add because
things are going to be saved today.
But this is the very quick
and we're doing it very quickly
because in my company,
when I created the framework
already is
we are on day four of a big minutes.
You guys can go for a big commendation
or it can ensure constant speech.
He doesn't start training this group,
constant speech that you
so this can suit.
You know what?
I started the record I started already
think so.
Now, first
let me commit this code in the repository
because people are asking for this.
Okay, so let me do it
now. You'll see the code is available.
Alright.
Many of you were asking the code
what is available in the repository.
And this is the
you are right so let me copy this.
You want to do is give me a moment.
All right.
Let me shared the repository with you.
So there
you guys can also have the same thing
do to guys
getting my great
So now so far
right so far what we did right
we did are common methods right
in the common methods we added my bot
which is constant but right I did one path
which is constraint path from here.
This path is not going change.
Even my machine changes
or everything will change,
but it will always return me the same path
because the location of my vine
is not going to change.
Is this clear?
Great.
Now, now let's talk about another problem.
Great. Let's about another problem.
And now see,
this is another magical time, right?
Under the mitigation
when we talk about this call driver
easy bar or Google Driver easy bar
or better driver or the exit battery.
The problem
with this the problem with this is
sometimes get that Google
driver executable does not exist, Right?
The Chrome executable does not exist.
Correct.
This kind of problem, we get, isn't it?
This type of problem we get students
Sometimes
what happens is the copy and paste it.
We copy and paste this particular drivers
folder here
in this
correct.
Sometimes we provide here and there,
so the path is not available.
Sometimes what happens if you are?
Did your Chrome browser from 95 to 90
6 to 97, 98 or any other one? Right.
And if your browser is not compatible
with your driver,
then it gets screwed every time
you have to update your browser.
Correct? Correct.
These are the problems
you guys have been facing or not.
Tell me now.
No. Five people.
Let's see if five people
are working in your team and.
Five people are having obviously five
different machines.
Right?
So if I people are I think I have
different which it's maybe possible,
then I shall go to the updated version
of the groups and 495
But the another people like I'm around in
Hasim are they're still using virgin
86 thromboembolism. Right.
So the other driver driver
and you guys are using
just a wide.
All right so now
now here see because of this problem
what happened
some time is your driver is not compatible
with your web browser.
Every other team
member is using the different part
rate,
different versions of the browser. Right.
Everyone can use a different folder
structure for keeping their driver.
And if you keep chrome driver,
the good driver or better driver
supported driver rate on each driver
in your one particular folder,
read one particular project.
It makes your code bulkier.
It increases the stability of the
increases the size of your project grade.
This all problems we would be having
if we aid this particular part
of our industrial
industry.
We are having all of these problems.
So now, now in our framework, right,
we have one functionality
through which we can still launch the
browser without the driver
getting my point.
This is the catch guys in the framework.
Remember,
we don't need to add a new drivers folder.
We don't need to add anybody except right.
We don't need to provide all of this box
system property with driver cool driver.
We don't need to provide anything
like this.
Getting my point.
What I'm trying to explain here
students Right.
Then the question is
if we don't need drivers folder,
if we don't need call driver
or to exceed or any driver or be exist
and if we don't, is the standard set
property driver not called driver.
If we don't need all of these things,
then what else do we need?
So the answer is we need one simple
dependency from our memory repository.
This is what we call bad driver manager.
What we need to do is we need one
simple dependency from memory repository.
Go there, driver, manage it right.
Just be the web driver
manager, rate it as a single word.
Web driver manage it.
Got it
Correct
yaml Why you always ask question
one is don't for that I'm coming to
that point rate if you see what happens
is your good your intelligent.
I totally respect that.
But others are getting confused.
Please try to take care
of all of your teammates and colleagues.
Right.
I'm going to that point this driver
manager dependency we need to end now.
You see here
also we are having the driver manager yet
also we are having a driver manager.
What we need with this bony Garcia.
We need this bony Garcia.
Alright, I want Andy Garcia and everyone
see this.
Can everyone see this? Whatever.
Manager You have got Bony Garcia Right.
Open word.
Driver Manager
Open this driver manager guys.
Everyone, everyone
open it or not.
Now we see 3.8.1
is having the most number of downloads.
68 3.8.
right. Just take this 3.8.1
Just take this 3.8.1
Copy this dependency and now you know
better than me how to build in
senior project
just to go under your dependency rate
in this dependency and the here
at this point and see here
I got this web driver manager to
go to
as everyone
is dependency driver manager.
Let's click on this one project
and you'll see this VM
driver
manager is available in your project.
Is there anyone who's getting the error
here?
I remember expecting that.
Great.
And you can close with Intelligent Train
now see now
see the use use of this particular driver
manager.
Very important point.
I see
if I open this, if I open this common
metrics first, like I said,
we don't need this path
related stuff anymore.
We don't need this part related stop
any more ability.
See what I deleted
the system not set proper DB driver
or group load driver is RC driver or DC.
I deleted this point why I deleted this
because I am going to use here
one very good thing called
bad driver
manager.
It's asking for import class.
Let's import this class driver manager not
can you see it is giving me chrome driver
edge driver Firefox driver
either driver or beta driver.
Can you see I use all of these drivers.
It is giving me.
Just click on chrome driver here
and then don't
send up is the command we have right now.
What this one line does right
this particular one line them
driver manager big skip of your browser
whatever the browser you're using
it will give you the compatible version
of web driver which is compatible
with your current browser,
and it executes your script every time.
So now
you don't need to go through the drivers
folder, you don't need to take care of it
or the exit point.
You don't need to be concerned
about your compatibility of your web
driver,
nor the acceleration or rate one symbol.
Come on.
Similarly here also you can change this
to web driver
manager dot Firefox driver door setup.
Come on.
Right.
So if it
is chrome it will use the chrome driver.
It will be inspired folks,
it will use the Firefox branch
is an easy to use
is now no more hardcoded for any better.
No more hardcoded part.
Right case
when the new browser of
what browser has to do with dependencies.
One month
Omron Omron.
Can you be stable driver manager
like this?
Did you take like this web
driver manager take
spending
or not went see
driver
manager is the one that had to be used for
chrome driver Firefox driver Everybody
except by what's the name.
The driver is still selenium driver.
Okay,
we don't need to change this driver.
This driver is the interpreter.
Goodwin to implement.
So these are two different things.
Don't get confused with this.
Okay?
You see you are getting the web driver
from selenium
and you see.
No, no, no.
There's what I'm saying.
It has nothing to do with the ability.
There's nothing to do.
It is automatically connected
to the central deposit rate.
So based on your browser. Right.
It will give you the new one.
You don't need to get a new web driver
dependency code.
The same one will work.
Don't worry about it.
In between work, I'm sure. Sure.
So now you see this web driver manager it.
Why we using this web driver manager
part Alex Because we had a lot of issues
with control or directly
to manage for these drivers
compatibility part.
If my web driver is compatible
with my web browser or the bodies,
correct or not, if the party's
not going to do a lot of visuals, fonts
are going to change according to the file,
every single thing, right?
So to get rid of this problem,
we came up with a solution called web
driver manager.
The first thing is you'll see
in my project there is no not the driver,
no Chrome primary, zero five or nothing.
I hope you Why?
Because driver manager itself
provide the instance itself.
Provide the instance of the driver
which is compatible to your web browser
and attitude
and the students.
And that's why we're using this MLC.
What I work Driver, manager,
Darkroom driver Don't skip.
So it will set up the browser for you,
the driver manager or Firefox Driver.
Don't set them.
It will set up the driver for you
and then you can simply initialize
your Firefox chamber
using your this particular part.
Is it good?
So far what everyone is required.
Great. Great.
Now time to do that insulin.
You want to, uh,
to do all of those things in selenium
and you need to have a big management boot
such as you can see
straight into a dependency.
We should this type of tool
where we can make all of these things
and that is just a
project, this is a frame and
please do I, please.
Do you see the driver spinning is wrong
in your web driver manager.
The spinning of your driver is wrong.
Your right to date.
Whenever you do this,
I always tell you to copy this part.
When you type trade,
you get to see the driver.
So it is giving you their job.
Don't press. Enter and use this.
If you're naked,
then definitely gives you a few mistakes.
Please take look this me
copy.
Fine.
So for any question this
use of principles and success.
Correct?
Correct.
So now, now let's go ahead
and write one very basic feature.
Like Come here, Come here
flows to great for
makes it also we just not
know if you'll see right If you see
what I'm seeing,
I need to take just one thing.
This is given user is open browser
and to each item is
correct and user logged in is an element.
So to simplify
this particular is to generate
user interface by username and password.
When user enters username and password
and user clicks
on login, it
all of these things we can do.
So let's do one very basic scenario, one
very basic scenario
and ridiculous.
What I'm going to explain is here
see for logging part
now tell me now
if I'm going to write in this scenario
like this in feature find it is just one
on Java
it is non Java.
Okay.
And how
many feature I can have in one project,
how many feature I can name in one project
multiple features.
Right. Correctly multiple features
like in here.
So what I will do
the way I created config,
I will create another folder here under
it will go feature.
Right.
So all the features made only
I'm going to provide under this features
database.
So let's talk about a very simple feature
first
and talking about logging
regional logging feature.
So like I said, to create any feature
by what is the extension
we have deployed
guys to create any pie.
What is the extension
you have to provide for me to find on log?
I know where this is
different from property.
We create features under resources
just connect by election data resources
because feature is a known double
bar plate.
This is simple. Like this. Correct?
So this is what plain simple text.
It has nothing to do with Java.
That's why you're creating everything
which is non Java resources.
This is the meaning of our framework.
So now let me right click on the features
folder, go on to new,
click on file again in my building
and I click on Features Order.
Go to new, click on file, click on file
and here I am waiting logging
dot feature.
Remember loading dot feature not features
feature with small if not completely live
great
click.
Can you see one
beautiful gloss created here
with the green icon
to decompress of timber?
Can everyone see this?
Get it.
Got it.
So now.
Now there are
some rules need to get updates
first because this is my feature,
I have to provide the name of my feature.
So see the moment.
I think if this should be the first line
of your feature, always remember
this should be the first night
of your feature you have to provide.
So it is my future.
What you did about what you are saying.
Sorry.
Okay.
Right click on Features Related.
Right Click on Features
Going to new Click on file
and here type logging dot feature.
The only logging or feature press enter
and you will see this right
now. Understood.
Now see the moment I press beta.
It's not taking me
here, it's taking me here.
It means whatever the things
and when you write, these
things will be in my feature all.
Now tell me,
when we were writing this part,
I told you
this are two different scenario.
Correct?
I told you guys
these are two different scenario or not.
And now when I say two different scenario,
right now I'm talking about only log
in feature, right?
So let me write exists scenario
scenario outlines scenario template.
We will use simple scenario as of now.
So again because the way I provided
name to feature, I will provide the name
to scenario visible.
So the name to scenario
is there see embedded
in me
correct.
There is.
Is this correct?
So what I'm doing
the name of the scenario I provided,
it's valid me logging
now here.
Here let me write first precondition.
So my precondition is given
user is connected
to picture and this.
Correct? Correct.
And this is my precondition
for logging in case
I have opened my application,
I have to open my application.
This should be my first precondition.
Is this correct?
Now, after this been
on when a user enters
prelude to me.
So and the password
and user
takes on
log input and then
the main user is
successfully
is this the correct this in any
given is a precondition when in
and are the actions in then is the bar
then is the part right.
Which is my expectation.
Then I can
provide some verification or whatever
I want from
the same thing
we were doing in this dingy.
But with the code now the same thing
that we do here with this fight.
So remember the example of playing
this time with Jane comes, you see, right.
You have to show this particular
feature to them.
I before everyone prefers this,
that's what I am.
The question for you.
Please go ahead.
So this is good.
So the question for me.
Yes, yes, I'm coming.
I'm coming to that point.
I'm going to explain point dude. Okay.
So now the next point
explains the explain.
So now you see here, right
when I'm writing
this feature, find
my steps are highlighted.
Can you see my steps are highlighted.
There's the keyword of Katoomba.
No, no, no.
The keyword of to do what is given when
and then my steps are highlighted.
That's what I'm seeing.
Who is this
loophole?
Great, great.
But don't believe the date.
Why? Because see the steps
I have written over here.
Write this on your unimplemented steps.
But is it unimplemented steps?
It means the code base.
Please focus here.
Please focus here the code.
Read the code which I need to write
related to this particular steps.
Right.
That code
I need to rage at one particular place.
So from there, before going,
before going there,
what I have to do,
I have to actually implement the steps.
This is what we call this step
definition, what we call it grace
days.
This is your steps declaration.
Now we need the step definition.
Remember the example of step
as I told you straight.
So this is a step declaration.
We need steps definition.
Okay, so now for all the steps.
For all the steps which we Right.
This is your Java code, right?
This is your Java code.
So the Java could be right under
which folder
Denmark would be entering the Java.
So let's create one package in this Java.
It's create one package in this Java trade
and this package name should be your steps
should be read and then we'll create
multiple classes or steps.
But for now, this is your steps.
So for my log in religion steps,
I will write in which steps
in log into steps.
Correct.
So let me right here
we create normal Java class
for this particular step
because my log in pages there.
So I will try to, you know, get this text.
This is my new plus.
This is my new class, which I did
so that when I create all of the steps
from here, I will keep all this
steps here inside this class.
So now see,
how segregated is this related to log in.
All the scenarios will be log in feature
related to this feature.
Whatever steps I have, I will wait.
I can find it in log in two steps,
say one place for one thing.
Now come here again.
Can you see this particular option?
It says that I'm based in features, right?
How many of you guys can have this option?
Everyone is having great.
Or or, you know, one more thing to right
click and it gives you the feature
logging in there, feature file
you can delete from here,
you can delete it from here,
you can read from here
or you can run it from here as well.
Just ready to and feature logging.
So when you
actually run your feature,
it gives you pre-made automated code,
it gives you this particular code, right?
You see it says you can implement
the missing steps with this back below.
So you don't need the code you want,
it gives you the code as well.
See the complete code it is keeping you.
Can you see
it is giving you the complete code
to see.
Now just going through the log in steps.
Right.
Just go into the log in.
This is I'm doing good to the log in.
Two steps in here
simply based this particular code
base to this particular code here
and then see just import
all of this keyword.
It is giving you this keyword
when and import it.
Just input all this keywords.
If you guys done it,
everybody's done it every month.
So far so good. Everyone
through the
what happened.
Can you go back to the logging feature
for a second.
Yes, sure.
This is logged into a feature now.
You'll see the moment implemented
all the steps
right
veterans in and you will now my x element
different because different providers
in it please post
those are big support right?
One must be there to help you other ways.
Can you you
right
and even still,
if you're not able to solve your issues
then do let me know.
But sort of in book classes
because it should root for a given
when then we don't need to import classes,
so we need to import this particular
keywords,
these particular keywords.
We need to import all of this keywords.
I'm coming to that
one, Rick
So we have to import it.
The moment you mouse over, right?
It asks you amendment, it asks to do this.
All right.
So far, so far,
everyone is with me here at this point.
Is everyone with me in this point
nice?
No. Now I'm going to right here expands
is which class I have to extend here
for my unique web browser Web driver.
Which class where I'm having
common methods.
Config configurator is the one
that I'm reading the properties.
The. Yes,
I'm going to use my common methods.
Now you see you guys know very well
what is framework
Common methods.
No, no.
See how easy it is now?
See how easy it is.
It says user is navigating to a job
in this application.
It means launching browser
and providing that you
what do we have anything to boot
this particular action?
Do we have anything to perform
There is.
We have it.
What we had.
If you see in my common methods,
in my common methods, we have this
particular method called Browse open
browser launch application,
read.
We have all this pertinent.
So now see what I do
in my in my log in a step it it's easy.
It's not only giving you the audacity,
but it also gives you instruction.
It says right good here
that runs the phrase big
does the phrase above
and to concrete actions it means
this is just explanation, right
good here
to implement this particular step.
So how we can implement this particular
is to simply remove both this claim
from here boot this line from here
and read the name of your method.
That's it.
Since your method is the static rate,
you can directly it automatic and you see
can you see
here now.
Now here.
Alexi, you like it?
Great.
I'm exception.
Just remove this line Remove this line
Also remove this line
then you'll be okay when you
remove this line.
But for straight.
Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
But if you only will want this lines
from here then it will not give you any or
it will not give you any.
Fine.
So guys, tell me, do we have
we have a good to enter
username password,
but we have a code to enter username
and password.
Yes. One.
We have a code right in this dingy
and talking about the basic login rate.
We have a good in this to detect
properties that are.
No, no, no.
You're not using this driver.
Don't find element like this driver
but don't use the same keys.
Similarly, let me show you
here.
In my instant, if I go in, my log in is
do we had this code here or not?
We have this code, right?
So can I copy this? Three lines from you?
Can I copy?
This relates from your base.
Let copy these three things and see
here I'm writing forced
web and the user name
is equals to
demand
password.
Right, guys?
And you see
I write username and password
invalid username password ID here it says
user clicks on login, but to put a log in
related code, I'm going to write
database.
So I'm going to write here
my logging
wants to log in.
Which
is this code correct or not any
is this code correct?
Let's see it.
This user is navigating
to a job in this application.
So here I'm writing open
browser launch application.
Whatever I'm seeing here,
I'm implementing here.
It seemed they were not same thing
anyways.
Then my line says user enters
a username and password.
So here I'm
seeing the same thing on not me.
Here I see user clicks on log in button.
So here my code is clicking on log
in, done or not.
And he
right.
Forget about this particular
part of code is off. Now
I'm simply printing 128
next one
looks
like now see how clean my code looks.
Right. See my code?
It starts here
you see highlight is also one by
because now I have concrete steps.
I have concrete steps.
And if you want to check they'd work good.
You have linked to the code steps.
Simply do just one thing.
Right click on your method.
Right click on your step.
Right click on Go to declaration.
Yes, yes.
I'm going there.
I'm going there. Right click on the step.
Click on Go to Add Declaration.
When you click on Declaration
or Usages three,
it will take you to this particular part.
Can you see
So you guys,
so here you can check directly
the linking of your method.
Now Nicolas See,
I did the same thing right?
I put Semicolon here,
I exploited same gives in the next to me.
Can you see?
I just changed this Angelica.
I think she showed the code, but again,
can you show one more time?
Yeah.
Go into any of the step.
Right click.
Go to go to option
and then declaration or usage
because see, there is a problem
in method coding is copy the correct
the name of the method module from the
declaration of uses.
So you will come here.
Please take the correct method, need grade
from the common methods
and then it will work.
Because I see
the method is not correct method.
The one you have in your common method.
See, we have this method here in common
method.
Great. We have this method here.
So open browser
yet and break rate.
So now, now we have this.
Or maybe do one thing
right after the class.
Connect once again people who have
any problem rate and then we'll see.
We will try to resolve all of your queries
as early as possible.
But don't worry, just give me like,
you know, five, 10 minutes straight,
because I know it's a lot of things
we have weekly we are doing.
So I only do that the class a bit early
and then maybe up to that we connect
which you the link here you can connect
and I will resolve the issue for you.
So far so good.
Great.
Now see
this time this time
when I run this log in feature
it, open my browser,
launches my
You are really into username password.
Click on log in button and then explain
why it's not closing.
Because we didn't add any code
for closing the browser.
You noticed that right now.
Come here.
You see this report?
It says One scenario passed for is steps
four passed.
Total time is 13 seconds start nine 9
milliseconds.
See very simple report nothing much.
So far so good everyone.
Mine was this I have seen
So you need to implement distance.
You need to implement the steps strongly.
I will tell you how to do this with mine
closed.
Why? No, no, nobody.
But we should not add any exception.
We should not give the problem
in longer run.
Okay, Do just one thing.
Go straight.
The code which I just added.
You see all of this code?
I'm going to commit
that it was really big.
The updated code from my machine, right?
Digit code from the repository
and then try to run that code
in your machine
again, the same thing, right?
I just explained I changed this part.
If you see
if you see in log in this step straight,
I change this bar.
I deleted it to Mark.
You're not doing this
I didn't do or what you're using
is still the same name, right?
It will work for you if you do this
loophole.
So far, so good.
Please remove those.
Are you exception?
We don't need to the exception. Yes,
yes, yes.
That's.
That's what I'm saying.
To let anybody will connect up the station
board.
Yeah, no worries.
All right.
It's completely fine.
There is any questions or for anyone?
No, nothing.
You don't have to change your want
anything for the common mistakes?
Rate is removed before
and after my third grade.
And just take my code now.
From now onwards, whatever the code
you are getting from my repository.
Right.
You don't need to change anything
from which are fine.
We will run the course. Mm.
This is just a starting of.
But like I said,
even if you have multiple digital files,
multiple steps, everything make it.
We use one single execution
point for all of this things.
Okay.
So guys, now
so far,
whatever the things we did right,
I know a lot of things we covered today.
We have travel manager, we covered
constant class, we covered rates,
config properties,
we covered log in features, we covered
steps, we covered initial constraints
on your screen.
Yet this is just one night on constitutes
this data of digit code from my repository
I just added the code rate
you will be having all this
in your machine then.
Now what what is happening now?
Write a lot of details,
but easy to understand.
It is not rocket things, right?
We are trying.
We are trying to simplify the things.
We are here to make our job very easy.
But it So I'm not here
to make your job complicated.
We are working on all these parts
so that you guys
can understand how easy this job is.
As long as you know how to implement
the functionality in your job,
how to work on the automation part,
how smart you can create
and play with your framework and
with your application and provide more.
Automation is great.
Your job would be super easy.
That's why I'm here to explain
all of this things.
Guys.
So I think I'm done for my crew.
This class made the topics
we were supposed to covered.
I covered all of those topics.
If you have any questions you can ask,
or maybe we can of decision now, but.