Hey, guys.
So before I'd back before selenium,
this dingy timber
gate database, Jenkins thread,
all of these things.
Remember, one thing here is
you need a basic essence,
right?
No. You can do anything.
So that is your Java.
Without Java, your framework is selenium
distended tuber.
A vague doesn't make any sense.
So first, take Java.
This is for Nancy.
In Java also,
there are a lot of topics available.
Create.
Now you might get confused.
Where to start?
What to take first, what not to dig.
For something like this
file.
So in this manner, in this manner, read.
What do you have to do?
Basically, if you have this complete
java in print of you
prior to today's the topics, for example,
for example,
you take your hosting and modifiers.
Then you take your maybe loops,
complete them.
Then maybe you take your concept completed
and then take your collection complete
and then take exception handling computer.
Fine.
Now, these are
these are something your connections,
the concept, the loop,
your some of the givers, for example,
static
final void
this keyword and you exist modifiers.
If you have if you have these five
six things in your top priority list
from Java, then whatever
the things you're going to learn
in Selenium,
invest in Genki can make sense, right?
Because you see these things
from your eyes, right?
You see if you open your framework, if you
see your selenium, these are new topics.
Every now and then.
Your ability or not,
you're using external keyword,
you're using implements, keyword
grade, you're calling the method,
you're creating the object.
Look on the constructor
to making the constructor.
You're using this keyword,
you're making some of the constants final.
So making some of the methods
static, right?
Like hitting weapon.
So what are those?
These are Java concepts search
you're using right now.
If you keep yourself busy for two weeks
just in program writing,
that will get better.
I need to type in nested for loop
to bring the pyramid.
Trying to.
Does it make sense to spend bullets
Training Logic is good.
I'm not denying.
I'm not saying that even with the null,
prioritize the things and complete
those things
which are on high priority first
and then complete rest of the things
I read.
When you go into the market
and never ask a person things,
they ask things which they need the most.
So we need to understand,
we need to identify the requirement
of the market and whatever market
requires, we have to compare accordingly.
Got it.
For example, it once you go
into the market, people realize this.
But see
Honeywell testing
in your testing raid unit for something.
What is that? Selenium.
So just none.
Selenium, only ten or 11 classes you have,
right? Hardly 11 classes.
You learn selenium.
Basic topics are these rate your driver
park normal driver.
But how you provide correct after there's
some basic commands close click
maximize clear on cookies right then
load words implicit explicit will ever be
you into weight,
then look into strategies on database.
Then select class actions
class window and screenshots.
Click methods, clear
methods and keys JavaScript executor.
There's
Selenium complete.
After selenium you have to
is to make your plane work.
The first test and the second is kick Uber
great looking fine.
You think test uber sounds easy, clean
your java read you
you have java you selenium litigate.
You know you have to but also with you
right just learn cucumber
all the concepts of cucumber
hardly 12 or 13 concepts.
You can learn all of those concepts.
Use them in your living.
This is what you have to do.
That's, that's the strategy
you need to follow.
Based
What do you think about SDLC?
You do this?
How What is standing interest in you?
What you need proves does indeed.
First of all, you don't need main method,
which includes test on attitude,
method, fight in test in auditing
whether one owner the annotations
you need to do this you in a really simple
priority data provider
very very little execution best
and you don't exemplify laziness.
These are the things you need.
Simple is DLC is a manual back, right?
You can take that. You can go with it.
So this is very basic kind of store
on the agenda ceremonies, you know?
Right.
Because this is all about the process
and process.
You must you
I hope
you guys are understanding the point.
What I'm seeing anybody will cover
all of these things in a publish sessions
is because you guys are curious to know,
I'm telling you this
fine guys.
So please start.
Please.
There's the only thing I can see
right as of now,
because I think all instructors
are pushing themselves very hard
to give you the complete knowledge,
to give you every single point from here.
It's your responsibility to understanding,
to gain the things,
to learn the things,
devise the things in the future.
Right?
Just, just watch,
because this is a coding.
But anyway, I'm going to commit everything
in the repository, so just watch.
No issues should support
find Gates.
I hope everyone got
everyone got this part great.
The collections there are
sorry the nodes there in
Jin was about all the four classes of APIs
right
under API.
One more thing.
I wanted to create a module.
You were asking about the touch point
in the sheet in this lately.
If you see those touch points,
if you read the complete line, even touch
point is nothing but end point.
Right?
So even if you ask the question
and you read that line, I think end points
we covered in 20 times in
the class is interface.
What are the end points
in a record or not?
So that point is nothing else,
but it is this end point.
Okay, it is available in the slide.
Also, if you're reading this slide,
if you read the complete line,
you will get the end of the itself
file.
So now the last class
in last class we covered
100 days.
So in the last class we started from
it, we covered the first topic.
What was that
in most common?
Yes, as correct.
Correct.
To tell me to run the collection.
To run the collection.
What we have to do
created first.
Amazing. Amazing.
We already have a collection
in which we are already added.
We have already ended last request. Right?
So here to run the collection,
simply go there.
Say the eight regions
after setting the entry rate check whether
you want to resume the cookies or not,
and then simply run it. But.
But when you run it, when you run it,
it gives you one post.
It gave you one.
And what is this?
This request doesn't have an is
like this request doesn't even exist.
But we will discuss
now after that if we want to run,
are able to request across
multiple environments
such as queuing, such as development,
such as staging in one.
If I have to execute
my API request
or all of these environments
and I have 1000 was in my post
when I should not pass any.
You want to do any environment imposed
when hardcoded in.
Instead, what I can do is
I can select any particular in line with
and from right in one word I can start
cutting
that.
In one word I can start one. So there.
Then we have to select environment back
environment and create
environment.
Then we can provide initial value
first variable,
then we provide some initial value
and then some final. Then
these are the things employed,
correct variable
initial final categories for environment.
And then and then we pass this variable
in our API request in our base.
You are right, we pass this variable.
So to parse this variable in our base,
you are right
how we are crude trace how we can pass
the currently initial in the exact key
we have to provide in this
variable need.
Groups like this.
Like this.
Correct.
You saw what
was it needed
actually,
I thought this is encapsulation, huh?
And okay,
I thought you are trying
to cover something
and you're showing reference or that
encapsulation
is sending to someone with my name.
See people in no, in my engineering.
When I was doing my engineering,
I used to study in news to correct it.
None of them really.
I used to study in used current.
What is the meaning of induced content?
You know what is produced content
which you generally produce?
The another term is induced content.
It comes from induction.
What does it mean?
Simply
if you put two cohorts together rate
do not together at a certain distance
and you related content in one broad
this talk started
automatically getting charged line
because current has been in
used in this chart in this particular road
because of the presence of current
in this or in electronics.
This is what we call a coupling induction
induction and the unit is
a Henry Inductance unit is Henry.
I used to study this in my engineering
days, right in the induced grind.
So here I see that induced current
producing in someone
because of their someone else is charging
automatically in the class.
The phenomenon induction is going on years
late.
One started other will under
that will automatically start
induction.
Nice place.
Well I don't know are like your name.
Exactly exactly induction the best example
if you start a rule
I would always liked his any day.
Fine so now now read me
and we add variables
we would the to add variables like this
also also in the in mind
rank in the environment.
After environment.
We add another thing.
After the environment we added global
variable
be global
minimum rate.
So why why we added right here
global variables Gates
or in point rate.
We have a lot in points in the API right
now we are dealing with enter endpoints.
It is totally fine,
but when you go into the industry there,
for example,
if you are working with some company
like FedEx or you working with the company
like Blue Dart, right, or like GDC,
So these companies rate books with orders,
specific order numbers,
rate of specific warehouse number
should should been number
should add processing time, lot of things.
Right.
So for every single thing,
they have a separate endpoints there.
Then you don't have to write
these endpoints again and again.
And if you want to use
all of these endpoints in your API test,
even 4000 names,
you can simply call those keys.
And next time, if someone is going
to migrate some endpoint
from one to another value,
you don't need to change it 1000 places.
It's simply like passing the baton,
the script, right?
So you pass,
you define the value in one place and then
you provide the key to all the places.
So in this is what we are passing is the
key and the vendor we are providing there.
So if we change the value in one place,
wherever we are provided bank key,
it's going to be put there right?
So in global variables we define the endpoints, we define points, make sense case
Phi Phi
after endpoints in global variable,
we are done.
We call both environment and endpoints
in our script, in our base,
you are here in global variables.
We defined one more thing.
What is third?
Yes, we define
JSON with the right
and the value of the JSON can be
provided is
better
space.
And then whatever
the value from this book,
that's how we provided the value better
space to contain JWT.
JWT eight.
So this time
we don't have to parse specifically
from the authorization.
Then we go, we select from the dropdown
return to content.
We provide the value.
No, this time we went to this
Under headers we provide 1.1 day.
What is that one header employed
to go ready to convert executor
or commission?
No authorization plate is authorization.
We provide an authorization
We passed with double welcome embraces.
We pass JWT
just exactly we passed JWT.
Great.
So in one week Global variables
authorization body responds good.
Everything is done
but still one thing is pending work
is that one thing is binding.
There is
verification
and validation rate
and you need to agree to contribute.
Well, how would you do it works.
So you do the your token is valid for it.
My application will be working.
It will.
It's 90 minutes 80, 90 minutes.
So there is a session for 90 minutes.
You have to perform
whatever you want to perform.
The based token would explain
even investing is also
after every 90 minutes
you have updated book.
If you
talk about banking applications, there
you see a token for available
for 30 seconds, 67,
sometimes 2 minutes, sometimes 10 minutes.
Right.
It completely depends on the company's
architecture.
The companies required
how they want Google to be inspired
in how much time, Even for test.
Yes, even for test also.
Because anyway, we have to test
the functionality first before making it,
you know, before deploying
good on to the production rate.
So the same functionality should be tested
if the test.
But by
then we apply for just 5 seconds, right?
Then it doesn't make any sense
what if it had some problem?
We'd never tested pre
so the same functionality
first should be tested
and then on we would
correct.
We can only change in one place.
Exec Fine.
So verification and validation.
But here here in Austrian,
when we talk about verification
and validation for the APIs, most women
use one libraries.
What is that was too many uses one library
which one listed.
So how to deal with that is again token.
This is
a token to perform the specification
that two candidates
one specific completion
and it happens mostly with OTP
but right exactly exactly.
It uses
let's
try a session like the
produce duties do do do
do do kind of song in Bollywood.
My 23rd no my name is 23rd.
Already changed.
Next time we'll be having this page 333
Read the link
33rd of March 3023
by China's Solution
Library for verification and validation
purposes.
Now, by default, it follows which later
by default it follows
which database translation library
it follows.
BGT Right
now it follows BGT
Behavioral
agreements, development
rate is behavior driven.
Would know now
to use this child solution library
for all the verification and validation,
but was right.
We have to use one object in the postman.
What is that object base
Which object we have to use
beam object to to an object we use.
Right. And with this postman object.
With this postman object, we perform all
the operations, Read all the operations.
If I want to verify anything, for example,
status could be XY.
So which language it supports,
Who made the test
that will verify my
status.
Good job with.
I will write JavaScript content
related to JavaScript.
Then.
Then tell me one more thing.
When it comes to writing the script test
in JavaScript
should edit everything from scratch.
How could it have good quality? Yes.
Why not all JavaScript
basically been recovered?
Christian library.
So this associate library by default
based on binary structure.
So it understands the requirement
in terms of the
it understands
the requirement in terms of we.
Okay, now
is this clear?
I show
fine print
so we don't have to write anything
from scratch
when it comes to writing the test
because Faustman allows us to use
already built in snippets.
What are these snippets?
Snippets are simple is to make
JavaScript is to read them.
Over here we just speak to select.
We can change the name of the snippet rate
change of the function we can change
the need, we can change the status code
according to our discipline.
This is the verification validation
we perform based on status code
now is only status code
that we can really play on.
There is something else
also that you can also that you, if loop
is it only a beast or discord
that we
define?
No, we can verify a lot of things.
For example,
a particular screen from the body
such as we provided in the token
particular
value from the body blade
response time we can verify and related
content.
I we can verify and validate
putting any particular key,
we can verify and validate, etc.
So many things we can very, very quickly
along with the strictest code
there is so far so good.
Everyone
read the next thing after
and when really it was.
And the global variable is
where barometer on
right case
query barometer
and but better than what does windows
write?
What is query barometer
basically
to define the complete part
to define the complete address
to meet the complete address we need
but divided by slash or followed by slash.
When we talk about Slash,
when we talk about slash,
simply the parameter comes with slash is
automatically detect,
which is coming with the bug.
For example,
someone says, I live in America.
Fine.
Millions of people living in America.
What's new and
someone says, I live in America.
In New Jersey,
Amazing.
In New Jersey, you're living fine.
But there are hundred thousand people
living in New Jersey, right?
So in America, slash New Jersey
slash work, live like
slash house number 203.
So what is this, 20358?
This is the house number.
What is this would look like? Area?
Which one is the city, New Jersey,
where you trade.
So this slash is creating the back
end to zero tree house.
There are four people.
How many people for you want to meet
only Zima nor silver for the kitchen.
No, you don't do it.
All those orchids for chance.
And the fifth one is
you want to meet on the zero.
So what you see to zero
three question mark
mean is equals to Zima, Right?
Sebastian
added Right.
So this is what we call bot barometer.
Bot simply gives you the existing
one please,
where most people and these
are bunch of information available,
understand this bot barometer
a big scene to the place
where bunch of information is available
and very bad
and we better allows you to filter
the information,
to specify the information,
to get the unique information
based on some unique identity
so that you can bet you can retrieve
a particular information
from that bunch of information, correct
It. Nice nerdy me guys.
So far in this entire EPA class
four classes with
the class is going on with region.
Is there anything that you guys didn't
understand?
Is there anything,
any confusion, any question, any topic
on Speak Up, uh,
city and owner entity?
When are you planning to go
for interviews?
All three of you
submit
this week in
looking
for you, you Angelica,
then you planning to go for that
same Let's
everyone.
Everyone said that you're no exception.
Everyone.
Lauren Sebastian Nice.
Fine guys.
So now let's wrap up the postman
Light nodes are available in canvas.
Right?
This code is available
with every one of you everyone knows
how to work with, say, the document,
how to read the details straight.
Everyone knows what.
Everyone knows what is broken right now.
The same amount of completion,
the same type of process they will do via
automation in the next three classes,
next four classes,
and those properties
modules as I don't do another job,
nor should we be having
the jobs will believe me in post.
When are we going to change
in global environment or when you need
or it will be update
or to know how soon we have to do it?
We have to
because this is the value value
we have to iterate.
That's why
we are switching on to the automation. Now
are using a convert framework, yet
we would use it for that.
All right,
so now
let's
monikered
fine.
So now see
perform.
Many are listing on the UI on website.
You use tools such as JIRA.
When you write this to get this straight,
you use Excel sheet some time,
but you have some discuses.
Go ahead.
That's how you perform manually to
when it comes to automation.
When it comes to automation, you use what
silly
you have to do database.
Also, given
my sequel
to test
my cycle database
manually, you're using one application.
What is that?
My cycle workbench? Maybe.
Or I can
complete
my cycle workbench or I
could test database manually.
You can use anyone like Oracle.
You can use the company
which one day wants you
to test via then.
Then when it comes to automation,
you used work for database.
No, no, no, no.
To perform automation in database,
you use selenium on
a computer.
Intelligent.
This is intelligent, this idea
that is to perform database
testing what you used.
Come on gdb. C connection.
Something like this.
Oh, come on, man is a voodoo
framework.
We use selenium for testing
for automation.
Right?
So here, here.
Do you use selenium for the database
testing automation?
No. In the global framework, there must be
something very intimate framework.
There must be something
you made a connection
with the connection.
Remember this or not
that you provided a username and password.
Your name is a connection.
You are an inability
in content or properties.
You must have updated
that you are all of the network
and then the username, the username,
the password, something like this.
So what you used, who used duty?
Busy connection. Right?
Similarly, this is one layer printing.
This is one layer making this is manual,
but it is automation.
This is many of it is automation.
Now, when we talk about living there,
we have APIs to build, test a base
rate may only be used most often
we use boost win
rate.
Yes, I understand the Austrian, but
so here, here, when we have to test them
via automation, again,
we have to follow something
in the automation that is
Java progressed
assured
Java Restriction API
upgrade things.
This is library Java.
Rest assured API library
we will use understood
to perform automation testing in India.
Player
Is that clear?
Everyone likes what is this?
Java?
Rest assured API basically
remember
we used this to perform
testing on rest of IT services.
All right.
So rest assured.
Yeah. Right.
We will take sort of one we will take
I'm just explaining something right
now. Yes. Yes.
It's library. Right.
So basically it is a part. Right.
In terms of dependency,
we added Java does the Shard library
and then we will use it the way we use
selenium library test in the library,
Kimball Library, we will use Java.
The library also.
Right.
All right.
Relates.
So now now see
here we are talking about
the rest of Web service
using
read list of service.
This this the rest of
web service basically allows
us it allows
data data to be sent in JSON object
this to themselves allows data
to be sent induced an object.
Remember goes content type in header
application slash.
Jason we were sending the body, remember
we were sending the body application
slash JSON, right?
So remember this Jason object
because we are dealing it automation
now, right?
So we have to talk in terms of automation
and there we deal with object
oriented programing language.
So here JSON object, JSON object
consists of
D and value.
Remember redskin value pair
plus name X, y, z, middle name
a missing last name,
but do something like that.
Current key and value.
So here the entire automation
bar will be around this jism object.
From there
we will pass different types of values.
we will buzz different type of values.
I'll read case.
Fine.
So now, now
here we need to
understand a couple of things
When we talk about this.
Rest assured, I remember this.
The rest assured, rest
assured that I did some good.
So that would be great.
Uh, Grace,
we have our framework, human framework.
Great.
We all have our good Google framework.
And you see this
big this framework, big.
This framework is fine.
So now, now when we have
when we have all of these things
right, when we have all of these things
in a framework here, here
we are going to work with the EBAs as you.
Yeah, right.
For this student,
I know you guys have used to train.
I am going to create in these nodes
only here
I'm going to add for the rest assured
what is to show the people
on read Java are just a short API.
We are going to work with this part. Fine.
So remember your
rest assured.
The very first thing which I would do is
to them synthesis
allows data
to be sent in
JSON object
and then here you are, just an object
consist of
key and piece
key in building this case. Now
this rest assured
is the as in what is this
DSL based in this transport
domain in a specific language,
public domain is specific language.
Remember,
we use Google project.
Yes, we are using it Convert project,
the same project you used for distant.
You use particular one,
the same project you use for database,
the same project
we are using for API. SVM.
This is what we call one project performs
all kinds of testing your API, testing
your printing,
testing the back, testing everything
from just one particular project.
Finally.
Right.
So when you go to the company also, right,
you did this
kind of projects work in single framework.
You'll be having all things supported.
Shall we move for the race
now? What is this?
The rest assured, basically when we talk
about rest assurance, what is this?
Rest assured, remember these is on Java.
This is a Java based
Java based library.
Library to be used to automate,
to want to link
it. Use
Javabayes libraries to automate recipes.
Understood this
fine.
Now the best part is
the best part of this show library.
What is there?
Remember
this java?
Rest assured,
based library by default supports.
But the best part is
this.
The rest assured
follows
behavioral
driven
development
approach.
We really approach.
It means even the methods,
even the methods
which we would be using in just a short
it simply gives me the meanings
by default meanings in terms of given
when then and we are very much aware of
even when they are not.
We are very much aware of given when
and then read.
What is the meaning of given
conditions.
See, everyone knows here when we talk
about rest assured, when we talk about
behavioral during development approach,
there must be one precondition.
What is the precondition
before sending the request
in languages? Fine.
And before sending the request.
First we have to make the request.
Not wrong in this final
phase to say send something.
We should have something. Remember?
So before sending the request
first we have to make the request.
Right?
So given means you have to
prepare the request.
So for preparing the request,
we really use one keyword
calling given
really to use one keyword called given
and descriptively one
frame.
Then.
Then next given is when
then means this.
When means
actions.
Right. Actions.
So what is the action we talk about here?
What we are doing grid operations.
We are performing
operations on heart rate study.
It means
we are sending the request rate.
We are performing operation.
So we call it we call it
making the request
or making the call or
it being the end points.
Everything is seen in one way, correct?
Right.
So given simply preparing the request
when means either hitting the end point,
making the request,
making the call and
clear, so far
easy so far, easy days
getting the essence of this, then
what is the meaning of the keyword
result?
Straight.
So here, here, when we talk about result,
what is the result?
Response rate?
What do you call it?
A solution?
Call your colleague.
We can
relate.
Olga, what happened?
Response Call.
Yes. Not only response squad,
but response, you see.
So we perform lot of verifications rate
with response
code, with value in particular
a body, right?
A particular strain
or maybe the dying, how much time it took.
Remember the value of the key.
These are the modification points
we have the inadequacy of current.
Yes. Correct.
So when we talk about assertions
and verifications,
basically in the response,
it covers all the forms.
We can do
some of them for the verification.
We can do all of them
for the verifications and so on.
There is so far good.
We are not doing anything
additional rate by default
if it is supporting the language,
if it is supporting binary approach
and we are waiting, which are we are not
getting improved and it would be very easy
to make a request
or to send a request
or to verify the response rate.
So even Java rest assured API,
Library is nothing like rocket science.
Again, it becomes very easy
for us to handle this particular one.
35 Now, now let's add this part.
Let's add Java. Rest assured,
Java is assured.
We have to edit from here.
We cannot guess which project
we are using.
Guys We are using which project
Memon of this is reducing memory
in moment.
If I have to add something
that I should add, come,
we have to add in feature creature point.
We have to any longer to examine first
Java rest assured.
Then we do.
We have Java is to show here for student
when my skill kind is not working in
whatever form
I already loaded.
Fine.
So now to add to add this
java, rest assured.
Right.
Open your exam every month.
Every 100.
Now then we should go.
What risk for
never
repository
open the moment And here right.
Just rest assured appear
Rest assured.
Can you see the first one?
This one green and blank whole gloom.
Rest assured,
Java domain is specific language
for easy testing of rest services like
Click here,
click here.
Take the one having maximum
number of download
this one really 4.4.0 something
in this one.
Take this one
or take 4.4.0.
No issues.
Take this also
basically will restrict in your symbol
file.
Please everyone
has everyone confident based on it here
right now.
Reload your project
added on your project
every month.
Right.
No one is going to tell that this is a
now see
it's adding easily out others.
Come on guys.
We are expecting some errors.
We are expecting some issues.
We are expecting some
expecting.
My mind is not loading.
My mind is not working.
Those kind of messages we used to have,
I really miss those messages.
Now, if you feel shy here, saying to me in
them is to be my birthday text,
I would be more than happy
right? But
right
by no mistakes, correct.
Someone really asked me
this eight by your test
always past my my best guess is doesn't
and I was I was unanswerable
I mean I couldn't answer
I couldn't even speak a single word.
I said, okay, I was like kids.
I said, no,
what should I answer to this question?
I don't give it the answer.
I see.
Big 4.3.3 You are allowed to use that.
When all the noise was made
by. Okay, let's proceed further.
Now here.
If you see, if you observe closely,
you should tell the secret one.
All right. So you see it.
It says it allows data to be sending
JSON object, distant object grade.
It means we have to be in this too
short API Java business to be a library.
We have to deal
with this part.
I think.
Correct. In
you are me and Einstein.
Big guys are understanding you.
I know. I'm telling you this
medium.
Yeah. Just just 3 minutes.
Just three minute.
I will. It is in my mind.
I was about to give you a break in seven,
but then I chose that.
Okay, let's add one more dependencies
and then I will give you the cookie
and not let to wait for a long time.
So now see guys here.
It says List web Services announced data
to be sending JSON object. Right?
So for JSON, also
there is one dependency
that we have to take.
What is that dependency
you go to your again,
never bother to appear JSON
appear just again utilizes JSON
open this json
from user opened this json from
these on
are the emergence availability of see
all the it's available and as you guys
rate maximum number of downloads
the 888 this 120160810
big this 1201608 from 2016.
Yes take this one no issue there doing
if you want to take the origin one
take this one
no issues from December 2021 date one
Also we can take
it. Let's listing the updated one.
Let's take the ability to take this one.
Click on this.
Take the most updated
one 5th of December 2021.
This guy is again Einstein.
Instead of giving a virgin number,
he is giving the date.
Amazing.
Now read Jean. Why?
Why this delayed fun?
No more
damage.
Look good guys.
If you are also having this as the rate
reload your maven project
and then it works how to reload
you see even reload options there
if you're not able to see right click
go do
when you get to an option called reload
project, click on the reload project.
It will work to this part of this here,
click on MAVEN.
Did you see this reload option?
Click on this reload.
It will work on three options.
I tell you, I'm telling you right is
still if you fix any problem
then it's be ready by
what if not eight
then congratulations
on release.
So it's seven six.
Let's take a break for 15 minutes.
Let's connect again at 721
and then we'll start right
for our upcoming topics.
So now, now what I'm going to do is first
I'm going to create
another package under Java
crate, another package under Java
where
I would be dealing with my API stuff.
Okay, so let me create one package here.
Go API.
Now my majority of stuff
I'll be putting under API part.
Okay.
All right, guys.
So we'll create one API package here.
Now, in this package, in this package,
we have to write a couple of things.
For example, preparing the request,
sending the request.
Okay.
Verification of response could find
all these things to be able to write.
But this time, this time
we are not going to rely
only on manual stuff.
Everything we have to define everything.
We have to write
according to the standards of automation.
Okay, So in automation, remember,
automation doesn't do anything on its own.
We have to instruct automation,
and he should do this to that rate.
We have done this to a commission.
So now one by one, one
by one will see
how to write this simple test
rate in automation.
First will write simple test
without kicking over
After this.
Whatever the things we got
from this document Document.write,
we try to glom all these things together
to prepare the request,
to make the request,
and then we'll try to send the request.
Look, now
here,
when we talk about rest assured,
make sure one point
we talk about this.
You are.
I remember.
Remember
now this.
Rest assured
this.
Rest assured, considering your base
you are in post So me guys base
you are Well, we have two points.
What are those two points
based? Your role consist of buildings.
What are those two things?
Let me see what it consists of.
Two things or three
things are having busy.
You are right.
So we have base.
You are right? Yes.
And address of this one
location of the API and endpoints.
Right.
But when it comes to this
you are able only
I have address of the server
plus API location
plus API location.
It makes my base.
You are going
if I ask you to show me
where is my base,
you all tell me various members you are.
There you go.
This is my basic order and you see
basically this is my base.
You are right
now make sure
this point whenever you want,
you work with Java.
Rest assured API library
your base you will be considered as
base.
You are
because rest assured understands
this from your base.
You are a will be considered.
Is this you?
What I
this point
Now you might ask questions then what?
What is the point?
I will open also
for now consider this point
Make sure this point
I keep this point in mind your base.
You all will be
considered as best you are. I
will look
fine.
So now, now here in
if I ask you right,
if I ask you to prepare anything,
for example,
let's see the very basic competition.
Basic one.
What is the basic one
in just a short
or to make any API request?
The really basic operation
is to get one employee
simplest one.
Basically,
do we need to create an element of that?
Again?
No, we already have it.
One user we can use that one third,
we can generate a new token.
We can use their admin user credentials
to generate a new token.
We can use that right and then get
the one employee is very busy completion.
We can do it at any point of complete.
So we'll consider this as a simple test.
For example, just to test
one simple functionality in on
Java API,
we've been trained one simple test
or get one employee,
so then we test to get one employee
in order to make a request.
What all are the things we need?
One by one,
Jimmy One by one. First we need
you. What I first with you are
I just said here in Java
rest assured API on your base you are
I will be considered as your base
You want to play
right
with you are considered of this.
You are clean.
Then another thing we need is an opponent
because now you're able
to simply
read case.
Then we need items
basically.
So that's like in headers
we use to headers.
One is for token,
one is for on training.
Remember guys are not end ups.
We use authentication authorization under
authorization, we provide durability.
So obviously we need one more hurdle years
because this is not postman
where we have separate authorization
and there is an ability
right?
We have to be like this.
So base you are right,
we would need endpoint,
we would need headers,
we would need token, we would need
in order to make one request.
Apart from this,
we would need one more thing.
What is that?
We would need
where
the parameter right?
We would need query parameter.
Also these don't
we need the body or if you see
get one, employ someone
so get the client.
Getting one employ means retrieving
the information from the database.
So when it comes to retrieving
the information, do we need any word? No.
We need parameter to specify one.
The right
clear.
Perfect.
Okay,
so now, now, in here, let me go
and let me write this points post.
Go. Right. Simple.
Whatever simple to do.
Get one
I'm doing get one improving
like in body when we create
like normal of smart
amazing,
I get one employee, right?
So in this one employee, we need
we need busy what are right
which is equivalent to you are
and then we need a two point
we need and a point
after and point
we need to produce some inheritance.
We need first for token
and second is for marketing.
They continue to trade
and then we need is ready
ready to on
and it goes.
Things needed.
Now I just told you,
I just told you that a
given is the keyword
we would be using to prepare the request.
It means all these things,
all these things
we would be using with which keyword
given keyword right employed.
Yeah. With which keyboard.
So query barometer.
So when you see query better,
we're just simply means employed.
We will be using
grade, we will use that
I will tell you the when also
I just gave you all the components
you would need.
Right.
And then then
we will use this particular point.
So now what I would do first,
let's create a simple test for API, right?
So let me go here, right
click and here I'm going to write
one class and see
what should be the class name
hardcoded examples.
Simple name
should we follow, you know, memory?
No, no need to follow.
So just just observe and enjoy.
Just observe and enjoy.
Now, here, here.
You see, when I come right
in this hardcoded example,
in this hardcoded example.
Right, we will use simple test.
So just a moment.
This advisory came
first
with look, not
should we extend it?
No, no need to instability.
Fine. Now in this hardcoded example right.
Forced liquidated
simple method public void.
I'm saying the same way
right based
simple matter writing
very simple method correct?
Correct. Today's
in. You see this 71
Fine.
So now, like I said,
like I said right here,
remember my value for my value for base.
You are
and I am going to provide like this
simple
my value for base.
You are.
I'm going to complete it.
This is the value for my base.
You are an honor today.
Student
I'm going to provide this base.
You want to go and see which library
we are using.
We are using which libraries
this to showed or not.
Let me rest assured.
Darn.
Can you see what is the first thing
it is expecting base you on?
I so this is my base you want I
nice Can you see
this is my base
You are rest assured base you are
great
right?
Rest assured don't miss you are right
since it is returning a string.
If you see If you see
it is returning the string.
Let me put it like this.
GDP pool
it slash chat and extended sticks.
Put it like this is typical
in the last letter.
Jordan's index text
or next is less exhibit slash API
since it is returning a string
I have to use.
This is string everywhere, right?
I have to use this, the string everywhere.
So first I have to store it.
I have to store it somewhere.
So let's see.
I'm going to do it in one medieval
constraint base.
What I think
is this correct base?
This rest assured base. You are right.
I provided one value.
This value is nothing but my base.
You are in because my attestation API
considered my base
you are in and this you are right.
So I projected and then I see a repayment
variable called base.
You are for the strings that it can use
everywhere.
I can use it every everywhere.
Understood this part, every
this one understood.
But now
what?
We are preparing the request right
click
preparing the request to get an English.
This is what we have to
get it with idea
sprawling the base you are
busy you are to use for that correct
now preparing the request
to get an employee.
So here here.
Remember we have to use
we have to use the given method.
So the moment you can given given right
this given works
always with one part called
it is in.
Rest assured we are getting one linguist
specification interface
and integrate
this linguistic
specification
generally given method returns.
So what given method returns?
We have to write the part in linguist
specification.
Okay.
So here I'm saying this is the request
to working and making.
So remember what given method returns what
given think what we are doing in given.
Tell me
what we
are doing in given these
No not precondition.
We are preparing the request,
but now we are preparing the request.
So if I'm preparing that request in given.
So what given returns prepared request.
After preparing the request,
I would be having would particular request
which is prepared one correct.
So that request I will save you
request I will same here in prepared.
So this request is specification
generally be used to handle
the returns
of what we are going to get after
using
given given in just a short liability.
So my job should reliably,
if we using and then I'm using
given given this given given
I'm using to prepare the request
after completing the request
this given you would re sends me a request
which is already prepared.
Now I am going to handle that prepared
request in this video and understood
understood this case
file.
So now here, here we are going to work.
See it I or not
rest assured not given imported
the moment imported See it is asking
What do you want Header You want body
you want request.
What do you want? Right.
So we need we always tell me this.
You are right. Right.
We already we will put this
You are to be able to correct
asking
you see we are using it to share with you
and I already here
it is asking for header.
So what is the first hurdle we used
was to base what was the first train of
content? Great.
So let me write exactly the way
we right there.
We have great content tape
like this, the same spreading
and then the value should be the
ability should slash to
applications to some great
students.
Is this correct?
Now now another header, another header
which I have to use is what
another individual to use case
what is required of
authorization?
Is it sensitive? Yes, sir.
The value should be seen.
Then again,
I'm going to put alternative right again.
I'm going to put our in here.
Let me just skip to this point
so that you can see in multiple
so the value should be authorized.
This should be the value
authorization, comma, the value.
So what should be the value beta space?
Should I generate a new know conveys
So generate a new token from here.
Go generate this token.
We got this new token basis.
So I'm taking a new token.
Again, I am defining the point.
I got a couple of issues today
where people were trying exist, right?
The request with older token.
So please don't do it
because the validation
by big time offered token is just last.
So with the new token, everything
now now
here I'm going to provide this value
of token.
This value of token
then not again don't we have to provide.
I see we got header,
we got this.
You are.
Is there a way to automate the indication?
So authentication,
we are doing automation, right?
We is just a started.
So please wait for something.
I will tell you every
we will cover everything
to automatically indication
and everything we have to do.
We have to do a automation.
All right.
So now they we got two headers, right?
We got busy.
You are so now you are IBM headers.
We have three operators, one More thing
we need like preparing the request.
What is there?
We need first query parameter, right?
So here I'm going to write query parameter
is what, is the quality parameter
I need.
I would need employee in the support i.t
comma value.
So what should be
the value of the employee?
Let me check
which employees are working.
Good.
So the first copy go here.
Include this
which works
this one new same
go to
the new employee is going to be
the Google new
working frame.
So this is the employee I'm going to take.
This is the employee
and I'm going to take over here
right.
In case.
So for any question in this request,
a specification,
any question,
this is a simple request prepared so far.
So I just provided a simple request
which is prepared,
but I only indicated
still I didn't perform any action.
So now now you see what we have to do.
Then it comes to perform in the edge
and we use one keyword.
What is that keyword
are into double C by default.
Java is to show use anything.
So inability to perform
any action we use when given it.
So I'm c I'm seeing hey
this is the prepared request I have dark
when when I said not when it got the idea.
Okay he's going to perform Operation
Dart Bridge operation I'm saying
I want to perform great operation.
It is fine if you want to perform,
get operation going.
The end point here,
the way to the end point here, right.
So now we have to provide the end point.
Then we guys where we have the end point,
forget one employ from where
we can get this data
from swagger document.
We go and we copy this part
right in global variable,
all three together.
We got this wrong. So the documentary
now see the moment.
The moment you hit the end point,
you are performing the action
right? Right.
You are performing the action using
when keyword
you prepared
one request using given keyword.
Right?
So when you hit the end Point, it should
it should return something or not.
If you hit the end point,
it should have done something.
What could you return?
It should you done then
it should return. Responds Guys, come on.
What did you return?
Response.
So now I am going to write a
response where
I'm going to see this response.
So now see,
see the linking goes first.
See the linking first.
You made the request.
So this one got prepared request.
When you send this prepare request
and perform action on this end point,
you got the response.
So you handle the response here,
you handle the responses.
Can you see
in this case.
So now, now here,
if I'm going to write a simple statement
where I'm saying you response
dart is this pre
responses? Rest assured interface.
Yes, even request specification
is also the same.
You see public interface response.
Also you see public interprets,
request and response.
Both are interface because it allows you
to have your own responses.
Right.
This response might be different
to the response rate
for also request for request
for request for delivery.
What it is an interface file.
So now now here
if you see guys, I'm seeing this
standard output print
and then print me something the response.
Okay, which type of response
response in terms of screen please.
Printing response
in terms of string vs print
question we have you are what you are it's
you are in endpoint.
So if I don't understand so I'd like us
to base you are
I will be considered as busy.
You are in India
what is this your like. Fine
so far so far in this part.
Any question anyone is going
what is the difference
between two string is it is a string.
So these responses are just an object
that Java is used for
to string convert
as a string comes from JSON.
Alright, fine.
But now, now tell me, can you please
explain is a string general.
I will then sort.
I just experiment in Java.
You use dart to string
to convert something the string
here you are
injecting the response in json.
So in just an
if you want to convert this response,
we have to use DART as a string in. So.
All right. Now.
So now I see we made a request.
We send the request we got the response.
This response we are simply printing
because we want to check
what response we are getting.
Not for one response is the JSON one.
This is not the normal java,
just an object.
It is returning.
We should understand
the type of response we are getting
on it.
Any we are going to replace this one
very good thing here.
Right. I would argue that
just we are just in the beginning is
not tell me if I want to run this bug,
how can I?
I don't see any of the option here.
So we can back on.
Right.
But for ending the tag
I have to write creature by
then I have to create a to there.
I have to call this simple test method.
So many things I have to read
main method. No.
And this one
what works with distance right here
We are not using distance.
So response is an interface?
Yes, response is an interface.
No, I don't know. Fine.
Remember this.
We are using cucumber with
corn.
We are using compare
with generic. Remember
you and I know you before testing
there were written and unique right
so just end list and give bugs
based on unit and unit concepts.
Got it.
So this is the it annotation.
What we have in best in the scheme
is the best annotation we have in general.
And also can you see or object or database
base can you see all are generated?
Click here,
click here.
Now you see an option key, right?
Can you see this RAM option game? Now
let's run this part.
Let's see.
It gave me a message
employee does not exist
or you have provided invalid employer.
Someone must have deleted
this employee again,
I don't know who is the complete.
See? No,
it is not a bug.
Come on guys, please don't use or leave me
at least Why do you using my employer
Let me
work?
No otherwise I will not send in. Is
now see
Now see, guys, it's working
days.
It's working or not.
So it means we can generate,
we can generate
any employee,
we can get any data using the rest part.
Also this part you see be complete
body bigot in the form of string.
Read in the form of a string record is.
Complete body, correct.
When it comes to get the data for one
particular employee, it says employee.
And under this record,
this data, under this
record is due to
so far clear
lines.
Let's proceed for the
no. Now, see here,
if I'm running, if I'm running,
given this using test for Gene,
I'm just simply printing
the response I have got from the request
rate.
I'm simply printing that response.
I didn't do anything extra here.
And you see,
look, when I prepared this part,
I prepared the request.
I had the request,
I got the response and after response
after response here,
if I have to write something,
what I can make,
what I cannot use to the given
when do things done
right is still a
solution is spending
a session part is still pending.
So see how easy it is
you have the your complete response
in one particular
variable called response.
You have everything.
You have everything in this.
Getting my what
raised getting my point.
You have everything in this response,
right?
Easy peasy. Yeah.
So now now here what I'm going to do is
see, I'm going to use the same variable.
The response
got it.
You see, it says Validate table response.
That's why we have to use then Java.
Rest assured,
API is various point to use then
because Java rest assured API knows
if he's using then
it means he is going to perform
some kind of validation
is going to perform
some kind of validations dark
in you see it says assert that assert
that so we have to use this to assert that
no what do you want
you need you want to verify body header
status code, whatever the thing.
So I am saying simple as of now, status
is what should be the status code.
We will get
200, 200?
Is this correct?
So now this time,
this time, if I had done
you see it says one this first
one first.
Why it's not giving me anything
related to this assertion.
Why was not giving me
anything? And
remember, when we talk about assertions,
if your assertion parsed, not binding,
not printing is not a point,
remember assertions.
If we use if your assertions are correct,
it will not give you anything.
If your assertions fail,
it will give you some board
or some information in the console,
the development
so far.
So what everyone
any question in this part
how to make a request,
how to send the request,
how to get a response, anything
good for you.
All right, guys.
So now now.