Okay, So hello, everyone.
Can you guys hear me now?
Okay. I'm really sorry.
I suppose somewhere in my camera setting,
everything just got disrupted,
so I had to adjust that.
Life is good, Murray.
I'm not.
I was there, and you are not.
I thought that you just a left
or something.
I'm doing good for her.
Thank you.
I just said please record.
I am.
Actually. It's regarding.
Yeah, right here.
So I think the camera is good.
Yeah, it's good.
Okay, so let me start sharing my screen.
I'm really sorry.
I was not prepared for this accident.
And by the way, can you guys hear me out?
Okay, perfect.
That's great.
Okay, so what's up, guys?
How have you been doing?
And how many of you are
looking for a job right now?
Yeah, I was planning on
posting them somewhere.
Okay, so you guys are in the job market.
Okay, perfect.
So most of I knew that
you. You had an assignment.
Okay, so a little has an interview
as soon as looking for a job
and you started.
Great.
Okay, perfect.
Best of luck, everyone.
I hope that you guys are prepared and
ready for the market.
I don't see. I shudder.
I say is not here.
And who else is missing
now? Zima is eight good
flying 50 jobs per day.
Oh, my God.
That's going to be happy.
Okay, so today what we are going to do,
we will be starting our AWP session
and it's going to be
most probably two classes.
We will have one today and the other one
is going to be on Saturday.
1050. Yeah.
So before we jump into it,
I want to make sure that we know that
what we are jumping into,
that whatever you have learned so far, AWP
is a totally different thing from that.
It's impossible actually to cover it.
And, you know, even 3 to 4 months
because there is a lot of information
that you need to know in order to be able
to work efficiently with clouds.
But the purpose of these two classes
is that you are,
you know,
the basic terminologies of cloud.
You know, that what is actually cloud.
And when you are communicating with
someone, you can actually talk about it.
That's it.
Don't expect that after learning this
end of this thing,
you'll be able to work on cloud or,
you know, you will be actually able
to deploy some stuff.
That's not going to happen
because cloud is a whole
new volume domain and we have another
six months goes for that.
And if someone
is interested in taking that,
you guys are welcome.
How long is the class?
It's going to be around
3:00, 3 hours for today.
And on Saturday, I don't know, maybe
4 hours, maybe 3 hours, maybe 5 hours.
Depends upon the piece that we are on.
And you need a break at 750.
Okay.
We are going to be having a break
on. It's after one hour.
So it's going to be 730.
Okay, great.
So do
do you guys have your accounts created for
you? Yes.
Okay, perfect.
So the first step is done.
Let me open up the notes
and then we can start.
Okay.
If you do not have your account
created, then
I would suggest
that you create an account.
So I'll
just go typing Google
into Bliss and then you will
have this website opened up,
click on sign in or sign up.
And that is going to take you to the page
where you can actually create an account
on any of us.
That's it.
Just okay,
So first of all, we need to understand
that what cloud is actually.
And then after that, you will be jumping
into some basic terminologies
that you will be hearing throughout
Altoid when we jump to cloud.
Okay, so what is a cloud?
The first question that
we should be answering to.
So what do you guys think?
It's a storage.
Okay, so then what's the difference
between Google Drive and a cloud?
If it's just a storage,
then can iCloud Google drive
a cloud?
Then we should
also call GitHub cloud, right
now, cloud is not just only storage.
We can see that
storage is one of the components
of the cloud.
Yes, well, that's the perfect definition.
Cloud. Someone else's computer.
Yeah, that's something that we can see
multiple of different types of platforms.
E Yeah, close enough.
Okay, so let's
discuss about what is that?
Let me see.
Okay, so basically a cloud comprises
of a storage location, compute power
and a lot of different resources
that are available to you.
But that also doesn't it
are the concept that
what a cloud actually is and
how is it working?
Okay, if it's asking for the payment info,
enter your credit card number.
It's going to charge you $1.
And if you do not do the things
that I told you not to do,
you will not be charged.
But if if you will be playing around
without my instructions,
you will be charged a lot. Okay.
The just create an account
and the credit card number.
It's going to charge you only $1.
That's it.
Okay, So let's start with
why do we need a cloud in the first place?
Let's imagine
that you are working in a company
and you have a project for which
you need a very high compute power.
And let's say
you do not have that kind of compute
or that kind of available to you.
So where are you going to do
rent it?
Okay, Do organization rent it,
know that they will not go for rent?
Most probably.
What they are going to do, they will just
buy you a new laptop, buy you a new PC.
Upgraded something like that.
Right.
So you can fulfill your project
depending upon the requirements.
But the major problem
and that is going to be that
in some other project,
you may need, again,
more resources, right?
So for that purpose, again,
the company is going to have to
provide you with a lot of other hardware
or compute power again.
And it's not going to be just with you,
but other resources are also going
to be facing the same issues
and same thing goes for the server side.
For example, you have a server.
You guys do understand that.
What's a server, right?
So for example, you have an application
that you are running on a server
that is, you know, located in your
your company.
Let's say
it's the service in your company,
but over the beautiful time,
what happens is that
the traffic load increases a lot
and you have to upgrade that server,
but you are not able to predict that.
How much traffic is there going to be
and you will do what
you will just be upgrading it
depending upon the need.
And there might be times
when the traffic is low for example,
let's say a six years oh sorry,
six months a year, the traffic is low
and the other six months
the traffic is high on the server.
But the cost that you will be paying
for that
particular server
is going to be the can't be constant.
You will have to upgrade it no matter,
even if you are
not using its full capacity.
So this is one of the major reason that
people prefer to use cloud
is the use case due
to everyone.
Any questions that you may have regarding
this particular use case?
Okay, perfect.
Okay. So then let's discuss that.
How a cloud was formed,
Amazon and other companies out there,
they visualized this problem
and they came up with a business
that can help the world
and also generate profits for them.
So so what they did is
they created a data center
somewhere, let's say in New York.
And when I say data center,
what do I mean by that?
Okay,
so the data center is actually a building.
And in this building, what they have is
they have
CPU's
Ram and storage
and they are not like
just limited amount, but a huge amount
of CPU that good amount of RAM,
a huge amount of storage that is available
in a particular datacenter.
So they created these this data center
somewhere on let's say New York.
And what they did
is they connected it with the internet
Now to give all the peoples
who are working in companies
or maybe from offices or home
to give them an option,
that whenever you need some resource
you can use the resource
from their data center
and be them only for what you have used
are gold.
They are like 3 to 4 billing methods
that they have on their website.
We will discuss them talking.
So they they just said that okay,
if you want some kind of resource
for your company or individual, use
what you can do is instead of buying that,
you can just rent it out from us
and it is going to cost you very less.
So let's say I'm a person
who is working on some project and I
need a resource and immediate resource
and I'm not willing to pay for it.
So what I'm going to do,
I'm going to connect to the Internet
and access this particular
data center,
and I'm going to connect myself
to the CPU RAM and storage
available in this particular data center.
So basically
I will be creating my own virtual computer
inside this particular data center.
I can access that computer,
I can work on it, and once I have word,
I can choose to quit, that I can choose to
not use it or not pay for it.
And in that sense,
I will not have to pay for extra resources
like my project is also, after six months,
I don't need these resources.
I would not be paying for them.
So that's how cloud saves money
for the people
who are actually in need of it.
Who wants to use cloud or work on
big projects. I
was under the topic all of this pricing.
Yeah, because
what are the projects?
And we still need the data.
So if your project has ended
and did not need the resources,
there are multiple options either
what you can do is
you can say that okay,
I don't want to quit using the resources.
I don't want my data to be lost.
I want it to be there,
but I will not be using your resources.
So do not charge me
until I use any of the resources.
So what they are going to do,
they are going to
keep your data over there,
but they will not be charging you
until unless you accessed those resources.
Once you access them, only
then they will be charging that.
And why is it beneficial for them?
Because they get your data
and you know, in the modern world,
data is money, right?
Okay.
So we have different kinds of payment
policies that we have on lease on demand
and there is a
a detailed listing of what
the on demand pricing means.
And apart from that,
we have spot instances and other
also I think that I'm not going detailed,
but I'll just give you a short overview
from the slides about what they are
and then you can
let me open up that the slide for you
guys.
Okay.
So you can get charge
for the amount of resources you use
and the amount of the time
you use them for you.
You will be charged
depending upon the amount of data
that you are storing
and the data transfer
that you download or upload,
you will be charged on that.
Okay.
For the models you have simple model,
which is pay as you go.
Simply pay
for whatever resources you are using.
Save when you reserve,
reserve your instances for a year
like this means that you say that
okay, I will be using these
resources for one year
and whether you use them or not,
you will be paying for them
and you get a discount in that part
from that.
Be less by using more.
If you are using a lot of resources,
you get a discount.
So there is like different models for
Amazon.
We are not interested in that
because most probably we will not be
the ones who will be taking this to see.
And this is totally dependent
upon, dependent upon the cloud team
to select
that which method they will be using.
Okay, so here's the good news.
We have free tier available
to us on on Amazon.
What is free tier?
Free tier is that Amazon
has given us free compute resources
that we can use
without being charged any amount.
But they have obviously some limitations
and we have like it
best featuring
do it sound 50 hours of Linux and
for Windows also we have t
to my for instance which are free
for one year.
Okay. So I'll share this slides with you.
If someone wants to go in depth of the
pricing model, you guys can achieve them.
Okay. Just give me a moment.
I need to bring my mouse.
It's still some water left over here.
Just giving you.
Okay, So
now let's talk about
global infrastructure that how it becomes
more efficient
and more effective in providing resources.
So when they were building this floating,
what they actually did is
they did not just remain to one center.
So this is the earth, let's say,
and these are different countries
and regions on Earth
that I'm going to draw.
They created one of the data centers,
let's say, in New York, left
the other one.
They chose California,
then somewhere
on, you know, somewhere inside of Europe
and then India and let's
say some in Pakistan.
So they have multiple data centers
throughout the globe.
They all are connected with each other,
all the data centers.
They are connected.
Someone sitting, let's say, near
the data center, which is in New York,
when he wants to access TWC
and have some resources in that,
what he is going to do,
he will select that.
Give me the resource from the data
center, which is in New York.
You can
also select that, give me the resource
somewhere in India or Pakistan
or maybe in New York.
But the problem with
that is going to be that
these data centers are located
very far away from his current location.
So the data latency,
the response time is going to be slow.
So the best choice
is to choose the data center,
which is closest and nearest to you.
And apart
from that, one of the major purpose
of having multiple
data center is redundancy.
So for example,
let's say due to some economic crisis
or let's say some natural disaster,
one of the data center is
not working, it's destroyed.
Still, they are they have the backups
on other data centers.
So this whole infrastructure
of data centers
connected in a manner that they can retain
information, have backups, provide you
different services, storage, compute.
This whole infrastructure
is called a cloud,
not just the storage,
nor does it make sense.
And that's the reason it's called cloud.
Are these wired connections
between the dozens across the countries,
a belt between the regions?
Let's say New York and Jersey, They have
the cable low latency cable
that connects them.
And I believe that between countries, it's
not the direct cable.
Rather, they use the Internet for that.
It's like impossible
for them to lay out a whole cable.
Right.
So when it comes to regions, for example,
to close regions,
if they are they prefer to use
they prefer to lay out a cable between
both of them
because that is going to provide
a very high speed.
But when it comes to some remote location,
which is very far off,
then they connect using the internet.
Okay, So right now
we have IPv4 availability zones.
Availability zones
means that in 84 locations
we have this anyplace available
with 26 geographic regions.
The geographic regions
being covered are 26
and they are planning on 24
more availability zone.
So if you have a look at this particular
map of the earth, you can see that
the blue dots represents the regions
where you have eight of this available.
So it's in let's see,
this one is in Northern California.
Which one is this? Oregon.
I never heard about it.
This is U.S. West Island,
Europe,
Hong Kong, which Singapore.
So these are the zones where they have
their actual physical buildings available.
And the orange ones
are the ones that they will be soon
creating their infrastructure over there.
So they are planning on in Melbourne
and in UAE and Abbottabad,
which is that edge about like
it's in India, I guess it's India.
Okay, perfect. So
this is about the global infrastructure.
And now let's talk something about regions
and availability zones.
So what do you guys understand
by a region?
If I see that in this region
it abuses available,
What do you guys understand by that area?
So whenever we say a region,
it means that a specific region
like for example
Asia, the US you get these are regions
and now we are
going to talk about availability zones.
So let me open up the diagram again.
This time the earth is not,
you know, we're
so this particular thing is
a region
and we have another region
and we have another region.
Okay?
Now, inside every region
we have availability zones.
So what do you guys understand
or think that availability zone
can be
zones?
Availability
zones are basically the actual
data centers
that are there inside, our region.
So this is going to be called
one availability zone
and this is the second availability zones
and in each region.
We can have multiple
availability zones, there can be two,
there can be three, there can be four
depending
upon the structure.
Okay.
So a region
must have at least two availability zones.
The reason is again, redundancy.
If someone is us,
the other data center is not available.
It's facing down time.
The other one is there to back it up.
Okay,
so now what we are going to discuss is
something technical
availability zones are chosen on
the demand of the region.
What do you mean by those
and on the demand of the region?
Okay.
If you are talking about that location,
how do they choose a location?
I have no idea about. It
maybe they're are that okay?
This is
the availability zone, which is
cheap.
So we should have a data center over there
and one of the techniques
that they do use
is that they plan on actually covering
the major portion
on the whole deal. Right.
So in their topology,
whatever technique they have,
they must be looking upon
an infrastructure that can cover
the most surroundings by being there.
So I guess that's the
population, no population.
I don't think the population is going
to be one of the factors in choosing that.
But rather,
did they predict like this that, okay, in
future we need to cover the whole globe.
That's how they move.
They do not like to see, okay,
the population is there.
Let's go over there.
They move in the sense that, okay, in
future we have to cover the whole globe.
So that's how they gradually move on to
from one place to another.
Okay.
So now whenever
we are going to talk about region,
I hope that you get the idea of an hour,
you'll see availability zone,
you will get an idea.
Okay, now I want you guys to do
is sign into your A.W.
accounts.
If you do not have one,
just create one by clicking on
by. Just click on Google eight of us.
Click on the first leg.
After that, click on sign up for me.
I already have signed in, so I think that
will be opening up the same page for me.
Oh yeah. It's not for you guys.
It's going to open up some page,
like create a new user,
create a new user over there.
Oh no, it's not showing for me.
I already have it created.
So just go ahead.
Sign up into your accounts
and your credit card number.
You'll be charged $1 for that.
And after that, once
you are done with this, you can proceed.
And one thing that is important,
you guys do not need to worry
about whether you will be using it
for work or home offices.
Just select any option
that you want to set up your accounts
and we will be good to go.
Okay, Take 4 minutes to setup
and meanwhile, give me 2 minutes to
just have some water because I think
it's almost the time for that for me.
And then we can you
just give me 2 minutes.
So new user besides admin, just.
Yeah, just had a new user.
Not not a you need to create a root user.
Okay.
If you get that option, create
a root user.
The admin one
you do not need to have another
user.
Besides at the now,
I believe that all of you have
created the accounts
and let's go ahead and explore
it a little bit.
So in my account,
if you click on IT management
console, it's going to take you to
this particular window.
Is it the same for everyone
or is it a little bit different?
Yeah, it's same message for you.
Okay.
It can be a little different
because it was just
recently changed their
interface.
This is it does not matter.
It's recently visited.
So this doesn't matter
if you do not see this.
They have just changed the interface.
If you want to go ahead and apply
those changes,
you might see an option above here.
You can click on that
and it will change your interface
to the same one
that you see on the screen.
If not, that's fine.
Okay,
So now let's explore it a little bit.
On the right top corner,
you can see your account ID
and the name with which you signed up.
Okay, Over here we see all the regions
and the visibility zones that we have.
So this US east is the region and in here
we have two availability
zones, one in Virginia
and the other one is in Ohio.
Similarly, we have U.S.
West, another region with two availability
zones and North California and Oregon.
And we have then
a list of available
regions and availability zones.
So I'm going to choose for myself
somewhere in Asia.
So this one is the closest to me.
So I'm going to use this one
wherever it is closest to you.
Go ahead to that one.
And it's going to be mentioned above that.
Okay, You are now
whatever you are going to be doing,
you will be actually doing that.
This particular availability zone
in this particular data
center.
Okay.
Are we good till this point?
Okay. Now
the first thing
that we need to explore is cloud watch.
So in this particular search bar,
just type in cloud watch
and there you'll see a service
named Cloud Watch.
Click on that
and it will take you to someplace.
Okay.
Are you guys on this page?
Okay, perfect.
Now, this is the location.
From there
you can have the estimate of your billings
and whatever resources you are using.
So basically, cloud
watch is just like a meter in eight of us.
So if you click on billing Dashboard, it's
going to take you to a dashboard
which shows the trends off your charges,
your time that you have.
That particular resource
and other options are also there,
like alarms logs,
you can create an alarm that, okay, if my
use this time has
exceed for example, 5 hours
generate an alarm.
If my charges have gone up to five,
create an alarm from me because
I don't want to pay more than that.
You have logs.
Logs just makes the list of errors
and the things that are going on in up.
Yes. So that if you run into an issue,
you guys can go ahead
and have that on that we have other of
options also,
but we will not be having a detailed
look on them because they are like huge.
Okay, now I'm going to show you
something interesting off of that,
which is services.
So in addition to just providing you guys
with the resources,
the Cloud eight of us provides
you also with
a lot of services that it has
so. The services, if
you have a look up on it,
let me click on all services.
We have Alexa for Business
API Gateway
and these are something you attend.
We will not be familiar with, but
let's go back a batch Bullet Billing
Conductor
Bracket Budget
Certificate Manager, Chat bot.
You guys know about chat box,
you don't know about checkbox.
So have you ever visited a website
where like this
pop up opens up saying that, Hey,
let me know
if you want some help.
He had that one.
Now you know what a chat box, right?
So they are chat bots, basically.
They're all bots who can chat.
So let's see that.
Let's say
that Ekaterina is developing a website.
She had one online store
and what she wants is to have a chat.
What I would do and she does not know
that how to set up a chat bot.
So you can simply use
this chat bot which they have made already
and integrate her online store with this
and that's it.
She does not need to write down
the whole board.
She does not need to develop the chat bot
from scratch.
It's already available
for her to integrate
with her online store application,
whatever she is using.
But from that we have.
Let me show you some other
interesting services.
Okay, So
let's go with this one database.
So they have some databases
also available.
One is Amazon document.
It's Amazon, all of its own database
Dynamo DB Elastic, Ashi, Amazon,
these PCs,
these are all the databases that
it has for you guys to utilize.
Okay.
Now, one of the question
is that okay, like there were like
7 to 8 kinds of databases
that it's providing.
So can we get to know of them?
No, we cannot.
How are we going to select
the one that we need?
Well, just go ahead.
Open the one.
Any one, let's say,
and you can read about it
in this documentation,
that what's the advantage
of using this particular database from us?
And then depending upon that,
you can make a decision
whether you need to use this one or not.
So similarly,
any other that you want to use,
you can go ahead, have some study about it
and, you know, decide
whether you need this one or not.
So again, you will not be going in detail
off the databases one by one,
because that is in itself
a whole new domain
developer tools
and user computing groups.
Let me show you.
Machine learning.
Yeah.
Okay.
In machine learning, there was one of the
most exciting service that I
once went to.
No, it was maybe in I am unable to have
that service in front of me right now.
But let's see, I'm going to tell you.
So let's say that you need to develop
an application
using which
you can scan,
detect the face of the person,
and depending upon if that person
is authorized to open up the gate,
you will if not, you will just not open up
that you are supposed
to develop this application
and you do not know how to code.
You do not know how to use any language
to write down this particular group.
You can simply go to Amazon.
They have this kind of application
or service already available.
You guys can use that application
and create such a system
without writing even one line of code
and your work will be done.
So there are like 200 plus services
that Amazon is offering right now
and they are scaling on daily basis.
So if someone
says that I am the expert of cloud,
I know all the services that are there,
he is most proudly lying about it
because that's impossible.
What would be mainly asked
regarding eight of us and then each of you
most probably you guys will be asked that.
Okay. Are you familiar with cloud?
That's it.
I believe that you will not be asked
in-depth about
anything from over here, because
usually the work of a test
or if you are planning for
an automation test or job,
most probably you will not be expected
to have an experience with,
you know, working around with services.
This is the main
responsibility of DevOps team to
actually work with them.
So you guys will not
be actually working with it
on the premises, even even in your jobs.
This is not at all
going to be your responsibility
if you are in a company
who works in a structured manner.
But again,
there can be a company was
not that much big
and they may expect that, okay,
we do not have a separate resource
for cloud.
So you are responsible
for also handling the cloud,
but obviously you will be doing stuff
which is not the part of your job.
Which part is good to learn.
So we will be targeting
one of the service of us,
which is easy to instance,
because that is the one
that is the most basic.
And after that,
if anyone wants to learn
any of the service,
I'm sure you guys will be able to do it
without much of the struggle.
So now you guys,
I think, get the idea
of how good the cloud is.
So this particular course
that we have, these two classes,
how we have structured it,
we have structured it in the sense
that you understand
the basics of cloud, you understand
the terminologies and one service
we will be teaching you in there
that, okay, if you
you should know that, okay,
how you can go ahead
and if you want to work on some service,
how can you actually do that?
So again,
we will give you the methodology.
If you want to go ahead, explore
the services, you will be able to do that.
These two classes.
Okay, Why are we learning it
if you are not using it?
I don't know how to answer that.
Okay.
This.
Yeah.
Let's assume that you guys
are not in an office with a
person who is who works on cloud,
where you have something to talk in
common on the coffee
machine.
Okay.
He might be talking about.
Well, you know, my
my region is down that you will apply.
Okay, What's our region
might be like saying that.
Okay, I'm setting up a VPN in New York.
You are setting up a VPN. Okay.
What's a VPN
that you guys can have a good chat.
Okay. Jokes apart.
The main purpose is that
you don't just like any of the thing,
if you know the basics, if you understand
the basics that okay, let's see
what is a cloud, For example,
if you understand that okay,
what is a cloud and how to,
you know, work with it on the basics
if you want in future to go ahead
and research
on something advanced on it,
you will be able to do it right.
So you might need it.
You might not.
This is obviously not
a part part of our course,
the asset goals that we have.
But this is an additional thing
that we have been doing since March nine,
I believe that we plan on including it
so that if in future you guys get a chance
to work on cloud, you should be capable
enough to start working on it.
Not just like, okay,
we do not even understand it, okay?
They asked me if I know anything
about aid abuse and doctors
as and what was your reply?
Did you tell them that?
Yeah.
Professional.
Okay.
Well,
after you are done with the classes,
the nice answer to this question,
let me tell you,
if someone asked you that,
do you know anything about aid
abuse doctors?
You can say, Yeah, we do know what is it?
Abuse and we do not What is doctors like?
I have not actually worked
with them a lot,
but I do have a little bit experience
working with them, with my crew members,
our coaching and teammates.
We have, you know,
I do have the knowledge about it.
So it's all this better
to have a sense of what
the things are rather than being like,
okay, what is a doctor?
Let's just right now, if I asked you
what doctor, you guys are going to not
be able to answer it, right?
So if a person knows about
10 to 15% of the stuff that, okay,
what is it?
How does it work?
Most probably
he can be put onto that particular project
because now the high knows that will be
he or she is familiar enough to continue
working with this in advance stuff.
So I think that's the whole purpose
of asking that.
Okay, so 730
we are going to be having a break
right now and after that
we will resume our session.
So the break is going to be
for 30 minutes.
Okay.
So I'll see you guys at eight.
Yes, that's right.
Okay.
I'll see you guys at eight.
So I hope that everyone is back now.
And let's resume from where we left.
So we were talking about the services
that it provided us.
So a lot of services out there.
We will be just learning the basics,
identify ourselves with the terminologies
that are widely used.
And one of the services
which is easy to do, instance.
Okay, so now what we are going to
do is
first of all, let's discuss about
the root user, and I am it
because that is something
that you might encounter
when you are working with it.
So when you logged in or signed up,
did you guys see that you got two options
like a log and has root user
or logging, as I am right, you got that.
Okay. So let's discuss about that.
What that is actually.
So a root user is actually going to be
the admin
who is administrator
of this particular account.
He going to have access
to all the services
and all the content that is there on it.
But when you are working
in an organization,
obviously it's not suitable or desired.
They give their workers
the admin credentials
because then they can,
you know, set up machines and work on us
and, you know,
get company being paying for it.
And so the reason
in order to work
this way, we have different I am
to log in
so an admin can create different
and log in users
and in order to see that
how it's done, let's
write down in the search bar IAM
and let's select this iam option
that we get.
Okay.
So under the IAM dashboard
we have different options.
Number one is users
roles, policies and user groups.
So we will be discussing
these four of them.
And briefly.
Okay.
So let's go ahead first and create a user.
So let's say that
you know, sure, each is working for me
in a company and I want you to work on it.
So I'm going to create a user for
okay, so it's not there.
I'll have to create it.
I'll click on Add user
and it says that
I have a user name.
Okay?
So now it's saying that, okay, which kind
of access do you want to give to show?
Do you want to give it programmatic
key access
or do you want to give it password access?
These are the two types of access
that I can give to show you.
So I'll say the password. One.
Okay, So which
password do you want to use, authenticated
or custom password?
I can see that I want him to use a custom
password and I can type that down,
whatever it is.
Okay, so let's make it.
It's not strong enough.
No, it's not showing it.
Okay.
Next permission.
Now it's saying that.
Okay, Do you want to add this user
into any kind of group or not?
So what do we mean by a group?
So this is some user.
Okay, so let's call it
user one.
And this is a group, let's call it tester
and this is I am policy
and this is
I am rules.
Okay,
So first of all, let's talk about rules.
Rules are certain.
Permissions are advanced
that you can have in a policy.
A policy is just like a document
which have different kind of rules. So
you may have multiple
rules in a policy.
Okay.
Now tell me, do you guys understand
this thing that I just talked to you?
I am policy and rules.
Okay.
Now let me write
down a rule for you in to tell you that.
What kind of rules are there
access to Amazon
EC2 instance?
This is the policy that I have.
Okay.
Let's say the policy is access to Amazon.
Easy to instance in there I have a rule
which says that
the user can
have read access
to easy to instance what is easy to do.
We will discuss that later.
Let's say it's
just one of the service provided by this.
So this is one of the rule
and the other rule is the user can have
a right access to easy to
that.
So this is another.
So you see we have created a policy
in which they are different.
I am rules
now. I did I created a user and I named it
sure you know, if
I want to work on Amazon
and be able to work with easy to do
what I'm going to do,
I'll create this policy and assign
this user one, this particular policy.
So now, sure, if the user one has access
to these two rules
that I have implemented,
he can have read access
and he can have right access.
Is it clear to everyone?
Any questions?
Okay, None.
So now let's talk
about groups.
Groups is pretty simple
so we can create a group called Testers.
Now what I'm going to
do, I'm going attach the policy
that I created
to this particular group.
Now, this group, Tester
has this policy of access to Amazon, easy
to instance, in future, whenever there is
a tester who needs this access.
What I can do instead of supply.
Instead of assigning him
the policy individually,
I can simply add that user to the group
and he will have same access
so I can have multiple users
sharing the same policy.
Okay.
It's simple, right?
So next time
when you want to work on
or let's say there is a
your team members
or your team needs says that okay,
you need to work on easy to instance,
go to the cloud department and get an IAM
rule so you will not be asking that.
Okay. Well what are that.
I am rule, right?
Just go to the cloud about
it and see that I need the
I need and I
am user who
can have access to the easy to instance.
What kind of access do you want.
I want the full access so he can just it
and I am rule for you and give you
the credentials to the cloud and say that,
okay, these are the credentials.
If you log in using them,
you'll have access to the easy to install.
Okay.
Makes sense.
So you will not most probably be
creating the rules are adding the users
because that is not going to be your job
part.
It's the part of the cloud.
But I'm going to quickly
show you how we can do that.
So we created that user, not seen that.
Do you want to
add this user to some group?
We can, but we cannot.
But right now
we do not have any user created.
So if you want to add it, add
this user to the group,
we will have to create a group.
So what do you want to name
that particular group?
Let's say I want to name it actors.
Okay, Now it's saying that
what kind of policies
do you want that particular group to have?
Okay, I want you to have Amazon.
Easy to
full access,
so I'll check on Amazon, easy to access.
Then I'll say create the group.
Okay, So now this user has been added
to testers.
Okay, next,
this is something that we will not be
discussing these as is.
This is an option. Okay.
Okay.
So now clicking on next again,
we have user name 31238
Access type management control
Controlled access with a password
and groups is
tester and the policy is
I am user checkbox.
Okay, this is manage policy.
Okay groups this gesture right create
the user will create the user
and it's going to be there. Okay.
So sure you've been created
now if I if I want to give sure
you have the credentials,
this is the link that I'll give him.
I'll send him this particular link.
You can log in using this party, go live
and I'll send him the password that I did.
I don't remember that.
So the lobby using it.
Let me just quickly show you
when I click on this link,
it takes me to
the username.
Three, one, two, three and the password.
If I entered that password,
I will have access to Amazon.
Easy to and no other service
is going to be available to me
using these particular credentials.
So now I hope
that you guys are clear about
the concept of root user and
the but we call I am user
evil.
Okay, so now let's go ahead and
it signed me out, I guess.
Okay.
I have to sign in
IDPs.
Okay.
There you go.
Now, let me quickly go to the I am again.
Okay. Yes.
In that by my email address.
Okay. So how many user groups do we have?
We created one group.
We have one user and that three roles
have been assigned three roles
which lie under one policy.
Okay.
Now what else do we need to look at
by typing the blurred, blurry text?
Yeah, my set is good at six by six, so
I got that
and thank God I don't have to use glasses.
I hate glasses.
Okay, so the next thing that I want
to do, guys, is going to be
easy too.
Okay, Now
I want
you guys to click on the search bar.
Enter easy to in the search bar,
and click on this particular service,
which is easy to click on it.
And in your dashboard
you'll see something like
this.
Okay, is it there?
Okay. Okay.
Before we jump into exploring issue
two in detail,
let's quickly
have some theoretical discussion
about what this service is actually about
and how we can utilize it
so that easy to service provided
by eight of us actually is used to assign
compute resources
using your own computer.
You can actually create a virtual machine
somewhere
the cloud by
using this particular service.
So when you are going to be using
the service,
what you are actually going to be doing,
you will be creating a virtual machine
somewhere in a region
in our availability
so you can access this machine
from your own personal computer
via the Internet and you can work on it
just like you want to
like you can deploy on an application,
you can write test cases,
you can like do a lot of stuff.
And as we will be creating this instance,
I'll teach you step by step
that what are the things that can do?
You have access to it
while creating and utilizing this.
And instead you want easy to.
You have like hundreds of options
that let you
scale up, scale down,
automatically launching
it instance and etc., that kind of stuff.
So we'll be looking upon that now.
Okay, So open up your end of this console.
Let's go go to launch instance.
So when we are single launch instance,
it means that we are
starting a new computer,
a new virtual machine
on the cloud
that we are going to build on our old
so let's say launch instance
and click on this particular option
would save launch instance.
Okay.
Do you guys see this screen now?
Okay, so over here,
what options do we have?
It says that choose an Amazon machine
image
from the following.
And what is an Amazon machine image?
Now let's have a discussion about that.
Any idea
what do you any idea about the images
that you guys may already have?
And it is not a virtual machine.
Actually, images are a little bit
different from that.
It's worse.
No, it's not at all.
The less
Amazon,
Amazon, virtual machine
image.
So throughout the classes of A.W.
s and Doctors,
we will be carrying out this term a lot.
Docker image,
Amazon Virtual Machine image.
And there can be other images too.
So with this in general life,
when we talk about images, what is that
a reflection right.
We can call image our reflection.
Okay, So let's say that
this is a computer
that has some
OS running on it.
And in this OS
we have
different softwares,
let's say Docker, let's say
Java, let's say
Selenium
and anything else.
Do you want to add?
Yeah, Faustman And one more thing
that I want to that
and you also have a game
called resident you, right?
So we have this machine, this computer
which is running, it has an OS and the OS
is that C
It's Linux.
Do you guys know about Linux? Right?
Linux is an operating system.
So creating
let's say that this is a virtual machine,
this is a machine on Amazon
Amazon.
Give us option
to create an image of this machine.
What is going to be an image
image is going to take the snapshot
or a picture of everything
that is in there inside this machine,
all the softwares and the OS
and it will save it in a file,
it will create a file
and it will save this particular image
and it will have all the information
whatsoever
you have in that particular machine.
So this file is called
Amazon Virtual Machine Image.
It will have all the information
of whatever you have
you had in this particular machine.
So is that clear that what's
machine image?
Okay.
Now how does it help us actually,
what's the purpose of creating this image?
Can like predict
this.
We can access it from anywhere.
No recovery. No,
this is just a file.
It does not have any storage, nothing.
This is going to be like
a small amount of a text file
or maybe Y.A..
Okay, So let me tell you how it helps.
So in future,
let's say you want to create a machine,
a new machine.
But one thing is common, and that is
that you need the same software
that you had on the previous machine
on this particular new machine.
So what you are going to do, you are going
to see that you use this image
to create everything on this
new machine
and everything is going to be installed
just the same way
it was installed on the previous machine.
I know your record.
You are just thinking that
maybe you had an image for your own laptop
so that you could have a recovery
for everything that you lost.
Right?
It would have been easier
if you created an image for that.
You just have to run the file
and everything would happen.
There.
But unfortunately we did not have that. So
that's the purpose of image.
Okay, so in New Machine,
we do not have to install each
and every software individually.
We can just use previously created image
and we can
create a new machine that will be running
that all softwares which were there.
So this machine is also going
to be running Linux
Dockers, Java, Selenium
Postman and again in Resident Evil.
Okay, so now A.W.
s by default gives you a variety
of images data do
so choose an Amazon image.
Amazon Linux am I
the personal information SSD volume type?
Do you know what is it? SSD?
Okay, it's solid state drive
basically your hard drive.
So it's like the what's the type of you
are obviously not interested in that.
It's a 64 bit arm processor
and it's there is a detail in it
and that's all Linux
two comes with five years of support
so that they are telling us
that if you use this
it will have five years of support
and the Linux it provides
and some other tools and softwares
that are already
it will show you them.
So you can have either Amazon,
you can have MapQuest,
you can have RedHat.
It's also Linux distribution,
you can have Ubuntu.
Also again, a Linux distribution,
you can have Microsoft even
you can use that.
Okay, I want Windows
so you can use this particular image.
Deep learning.
And this is for
machine learning, right?
So in this particular image
you will see by dark
neurons and other graphic out
adapters available because this is
something related to machine learning.
And again, so you have plenty of images
that there you can use anyone.
So let's if you want to go ahead
with something
that has Java,
just go ahead and search Java.
It does not bring you anything.
So you can also check something
on Marketplace, our Community Images.
Let's search for Java and the demise.
No, it's not there.
Let's go ahead and search for topics.
Okay.
So regarding dockers,
we have some machine images available.
They will have Dockers pre-installed,
so we will not have to install it
from scratch.
Okay. But for now, let's delete it.
It was just to show
you go to quick start again
and we will choose one of the images
that appear in the first place.
So let's go ahead bid
this one.
The first one. I selected the first one.
Okay.
Do you guys have the screen Step
two in front of you
Now, this.
What is there.
No, why? It's
okay.
It was. Yes. Okay.
Now this step allows
us to choose the type of instance
that we want to display.
So Amazon provide us opportunity
to select the size of the computer source
that we are assigning.
We can have a very big computer.
We can have a small computer.
So this is the family
name T Tool d3d3 84 G
So they have the standard family names
assigned to certain machines.
These are the types
the Nano is going to be on,
just the small one macro,
a little bit bigger.
Small is going to be greater
than the obviously micro one.
Then we have medium, large, extra large,
just like the clothes.
So you know, extra large nano.
But I don't believe we have nano boots,
right.
Micro,
small, medium, large, large x, large, etc.
And these are just the type.
Okay.
How many CPU's are there
in this particular machine?
You do not know.
Has one cpu
e do micro also has one small also has one
medium has two large has two extra
large has four
and x large has eight.
Yes, it's just like that.
You are like not mine.
You said you are creating
your own computer, okay.
You are not paying it right now.
You are creating it for free
you will only pay
when you will be using it.
That's it.
Okay.
How many memory do you want?
0.5, one, two, etc..
What is the storage type?
EBS is like no SSD,
but EBS is the conventional hard drive
that it has
Network performance.
What kind of network performance
do you want? IPV six support.
Do you want that or not?
So basically, depending upon your need,
you can select the kind of instance
you want.
And let me show you.
Look 192 CPU's
doing 2 to 800 GB of SSD
network speed, 100 gigabytes.
So this is like a huge machine, right?
You can go for for this machine,
but have your
bank balance
in a huge amount
because that is going to drain it down.
So the free tier,
we are going to choose this one.
This is free for us.
It does not cost us anything to use.
This is free for us for one year.
So we will be choosing this
and we will say
configure the instance detail.
Okay, let me know if you guys
have any questions
regarding the previous step.
If not, then we can continue.
Okay.
Now these are some details that we need
to configure and these take the decision
that there are instance is or the compute
is going to ask you to reside physically.
So number of instances means that
how many number of machines
do we want to launch?
So right now
we just want to launch one machine.
Okay, Now this is a network subnet.
This is something really important
I'll spend some time on
discussing with you
guys that how the network that works.
But for now what we are going to do is
for network.
We will be using the default one
and for subnets
we will be choosing any of the available
one, one T, one, F, whatever
you want.
Okay.
And apart from that,
the other options that you want to place.
And I think other options are okay,
we don't actually need these options.
Okay.
But before we jump into the next step,
let's have a discussion about the network
and the subnet.
Okay.
So how many of you guys have an idea?
What's a network? It's
connections, right?
Yes, exactly.
Routers, Communications.
Perfect.
Okay So when I talk about computer
networks,
do you think it's something
physical?
And by a physical,
I mean something that has matter,
something You can hold something
that, you know,
actually you can see and feel
tangible.
Okay.
So in networks, we have segmentation.
And this network is actually,
you know, we can see that the vision of
a bigger thing into small thing
is called sub networking.
So for example, if we have a big network,
then dividing it into small network
we call it sub network,
but that division is not going to be
anything
that is going to be physical,
it's just going to be logical.
Okay, So let's say I'm just going to
explain you a little bit about networks.
Anyone who is a network engineer over here
or any experience
with networks.
Okay.
Equally, you don't have anyone else, only
with syntax.
Okay.
So networking is what
when I was in
in my engineering university,
we had this networking course,
I guess there were like about 4 to 5
regarding networking
in which we read about signals,
we read about digital
signal processing and DSP
and analog
signal processing and networking.
So it's a very complicated domain,
very complicated.
But people who are expert of these
domains up there,
they are in a lot like it's
the most difficult
and the most viable jobs in the market,
but very hot.
Trust me, I'm not even good with it.
It's very hard
because there is a lot of security,
there is a lot of risk
and everything involved.
So it's a sensitive job.
Okay.
So we will just discuss the
very simple concepts regarding networking.
So let's say that
this is a big network
and we are dividing it into subnets.
So this isolation,
our division going to be
only logical, not physical meaning to say
that this whole network,
let's see, has an IP address.
Do you guys understand that?
What do we mean by IP address?
Okay, so let's say this is the IP address
of this particular network and
let's say it has
like 64 divisions available.
It can be divided up to 64 solutions.
So we can name this one that it's 192.168.
let's say 0.1.
This is going to be one of the subnets.
And the other one we can see that it's
dot two
and then dot three, I can see
and dot for
now, after
creating the sum, that's
what I can do is I can connect my computer
to zero one
and I can connect my second computer to
zero two and I can connect
my third computer to zero three
and the fourth one.
So on.
So are these all computers
connected to the same network?
Yes, they are actually connected.
The same network,
but different sub networks.
Okay.
And now let's talk about VPC.
The whole concept of telling you
this was so that you are able to
get the concept of ABC. Yes.
With Gates.
I'm not talking about Gates right now.
It's going to get complicated. Okay.
I just want to make things simple.
This is something that you should just
understand conceptually
so we will not be winging very much
depth of.
Okay, so A
is cloud a network?
Yes, Cloud is a network, right?
A network
to which on which we can create our
machines.
Right
now, whenever
someone wants to work on the cloud,
can he just go ahead and simply start
working on
or will he needs to create a network
or use a created network by default?
Already?
Let me rephrase my question.
When someone is going to work on the cloud
or let's say he's just say,
let's say using his machine, he needs to
either
create a new network
or use a default network.
He can do any of those things.
So the first thing first layer
are the first division of the cloud
network is called VPC,
which stands for virtual
Private
Cloud.
So what you are doing inside a big
E of this cloud,
you are creating your own specific.
It's a smaller
division of virtual private cloud.
So basically this is one of the divisions
of the network.
So let's say the cloud is 0.0.0.
This is the IP of the cloud, for example.
Okay. And you can have like
how many connections you guys can have.
There's a formula
at least that I forgot it.
Let's say you can have
flash
like this much connections.
So now what you are going to do,
you are going to create a VPC
which is going to assign you some
private cloud in which you
have 64 Alexa connections available.
So this is the first step
of segmentation of cloud.
So if I show you now
when you go to network
what you did, you selected a default
network.
Ah, what you can do is create a new VPC.
If you do not want to use the default one.
Is that clear to all of you?
So what's the BBC?
If I asked you what is a BBC?
It's a virtual private cloud.
And what's the what's the private cloud?
It's the division off.
What does the
how is the virtual private cloud form?
What do we divide?
Yes, it's the logically divided portion
of the actual cloud network.
Okay. So
I'm going to share some
theoretical stuff about it.
So a VPC is a logically
isolated portion
of, the cloud within a region.
So basically a PC
can can be created inside a region.
You have to select the region.
So let me select the region
that we select our region,
Yes, we did in the start.
And then in that region we created
our virtual private cloud right.
That says you can have multiple virtual
private clouds in a region,
but each virtual private cloud
is in a single region.
What does this mean?
It means that
in staying in Mumbai or Ohio,
you can have multiple
VPC is you can say that, okay,
I'm dividing this particular region
into my own virtual private cloud,
like five virtual private stuff.
But you're going to not have this
that you have a cloud, which is virtual
private cloud, and it is like half in Ohio
and half in Mumbai or somewhere else.
You cannot have this.
Okay. So the next thing that we have is
some network.
What's the difference between the VPC
and we peer?
Okay, so BPC is a virtual private cloud,
whereas a VPN is what's a private network.
The detail difference is that in a VPC,
this is something which is going to be
always related to cloud.
You cannot have a VPN
when you are working on like, sorry,
you cannot have a VPC
if you are not working on a cloud.
It's also like a network which is private,
but we call it
private cloud because we can create
some networks in that.
A lot of that.
Does that make sense?
Okay,
so now what we do after creating a VPC
so VPC can login one region.
This is what we we discussed about.
So in this region,
what we are going to have is
different data
centers right?
So let's say we created
this virtual private cloud and it has
it is in a region
and this region has, let's say,
one, two, three, four availability zones.
Our data centers.
So whenever I see availability zone,
it means the actual physical building
in which hardware is zero.
Okay.
Now once you have created VPC, VPC,
then we can create a subnet.
And what is a subnet?
A subnet is so our come off subnet
and it is the logical subdivision
of the network further.
So let's say from this particular net
cloud IP address,
we divided it into our own 192.168.0.0
and it's further division
is going to be called subnet.
So just for the sake of example,
for a crude example, I can see that
all the IP address
from 192.168.1.0
slash 60 are going
be in data center number one.
All the addresses from
1.30.200.1 are going to be into
like this is I'm
just going giving you a cool example.
Okay so these IP addresses can do all but
just giving you an idea.
And 192.168.9.0 slash
16 are going to be here.
Okay. So how do read an IP address.
It means that 192.168.1.0 you can have
from this range up to 16
additional IP address in one data centers.
This which means that the IP address
192.16.1.1
is going to be here,
dot two is going to be here
and DART three is also going to be here
in the same network.
So right now what we are doing,
we are just creating the network,
the subnets.
So let's say
is the subnet that we created.
Okay, let me now show you in the console.
If we see that
we have the option of subnet
after the network
and this subnet says that
either you can use a default
one or a create on
or you can create a new subnet.
So by they have created different subnets
and they have the code for them.
For example 0101e
once you AC five the etc.
and they have also mentioned
the availability zone
in which those subnets are
so many locations.
Do we see or hear
one, two, three, four, five, six.
So it means that I have six
availability zones
which I can select.
So let's see,
I want to select this one default
use East one E
So I just selected one of the center.
So I'm actually saying that hey,
in this virtual private cloud select,
let's see
this particular building,
let's say it's this
which has an IP address
ranging from this
to this is it where we want
and the rest of you,
what about you guys?
There's this thing
making a little bit sense to you
or are you guys lost with the networks?
Okay.
So Hasim is speaking for everyone, right?
Christine Good.
Katarina, Good tenant.
And what about the rest?
I remember, I think, Kasim,
you are the one right to.
Whenever a hostage does not understand
anything, he sends out a doctor question.
Question mark.
Right.
Yeah.
It took me, you know,
it took me some time to figure that out.
I was like, What's this question mark?
But I figured it out.
Zamzam because she did,
cannot have any more smoking breaks.
So I believe he is.
He's sleeping.
And Miriam okay, Miriam is here.
So I believe Miriam is
done with her brain. I need
it still cooking.
But are you going to eat it like after?
Okay. It's a start for you, right? So.
Yeah. Okay, that's. That makes sense.
I thought it was
okay.
You pass off
sugar gas
to the sugar gas. Oh,
well, stay.
At least be safe
kind of thing.
Yeah, I can understand,
but I feel sleepy too, sometimes.
And right now I do.
Okay,
let me share something with you guys.
I just detected this
now. No, no, no, no.
Don't. Don't go to sleep.
Yeah, Just taking a brief
chitchat break
the life syntax.
Yeah, Especially one right?
Life. Life chat.
This is life chat and share this.
Oh, by the way, it's.
You guys have been out of touch, right?
Let me show you something.
The After the rooster.
By the way, I did not had the rooster. But
it was someone else.
I got this
and it was a baby just
I can fit him and yeah, that's
now I bought him.
I brought him when he was like 25 days
and it's like now 1.5 months.
Yeah.
African raised pretty intelligent
and, you know,
they have a vocabulary of 1000 words.
He's a very fast learner, so yeah, I,
I just don't have,
have this now.
You know, I keep him away from,
from the classes.
I don't want him to learn programing.
I'll make him an artist.
Does it know how to good.
Now I know he does it.
I'll not be making him look older like
the life is not good for coders.
Right.
So I'll.
I'll see what he wants to do.
His name is Mr.
Gray.
Not yet. He is.
He's quite young.
You'll learn,
but he is just like 1.5 months.
Right?
So he doesn't start right now.
I'll be not teaching him any other coding.
It's expensive.
It's about getting converted to dollars.
It's going to be
not my master's.
So that is.
Well,
if people in our country
asked us to do these birds
like they are like expensive birds, so
everyone is going to steal them right now.
Yeah.
Trust me, I cannot leave him in the open
because they are going to steal it.
Yeah, I just keep him inside.
So it's like I e
$300. Hey,
I was looking for an owl,
but no, what's the average lifespan?
The average lifespan is 65 years, yet
they live up to 65 years
if they're kept in a good environment.
Now, trust me,
I don't know where to get an owl trust.
If you get any any place or you can buy
and I'll let me know
if you can deliver it to me, I'll Be glad
I love owls,
but unfortunately in our country
they are bad.
They are not allowed to be sold.
I think I so saw one in in a park. So.
But they are hot too, you know, cats.
So I'm out of options.
I just gave up on that.
Please. Well, you can sell it.
Send one of their chicks to me right.
Eagles are good to.
Like I said, next year, if you guys are
here, anyone of you, I'll show you my.
My whole collection.
I'm starting to collect
many of the species,
but it will take you some time next year.
I'm going to show you all the questions.
Okay. So
again, now I believe that we
will be looking at on owls right?
The white ones are good.
These are pretty common, actually.
Yet these brown ones are pretty common
in our country.
I see them
all like if they're 5 to 6 places,
I have actually seen them.
So the white ones are the rare ones.
These brown ones are quite common,
but obviously they are not sold
in the market because I don't know
there is a myth or like it's true,
but people say that their blood is used in
black magic or something.
That's why it's like so bad to be sold
in the market.
But obviously it can be met.
I said that, but that's the concept here.
Okay, So let's get back to it.
Yes, enough of the owls and stuff.
Let's get back to our session
and let's try to end it in 30 minutes
so that you guys can also have
Ali off.
Okay.
So talking about subnets,
do you guys understand
the concept of subnets now?
Okay, perfect.
Now, when we selected a VPC and after that
we selected a subnet,
Do you guys see this?
What does it say?
It says that this particular subnet
has 4091 IP address.
What Does this mean
what does this mean?
It means that you can have 4091 computers
in this particular building launched.
At the same time,
and their capacity is like that
that is another question.
The only thing is that for 091 computers
can be lost, their capacity can be huge.
But if you want to launch
600 in this building,
that will not be possible
because the network is not going to be
there.
Only 4091 options are there right?
Okay. So now
what we are going to do is
I don't know about cryptos, so
no idea.
After selecting the network
after the selection of subnet,
the next thing we are going to do is
click on Add storage.
Okay, Now it's asking us that, hey,
what kind of storage
and what is the size of stories you want?
So we can set the size a GB to 30 GB
so three tier customers can get up to 30.
GB three.
So I to be here
log in type.
Do you want SSD?
GP two assisted GP three SSD.
I want to magnetic
like whatever you want to.
Okay, let's do something Let's keep it
eight because I don't want to get charged
if like the volume type is not correct.
Yeah.
You don't need to know about what
the GP told you between I want obviously
that is like
out of your scope of knowledge.
Just select anyone.
Okay.
So after that we are
going to click on next attack
Configure security group.
This is the step
five is something that will skip.
Okay.
This is something that we do not want to
discuss.
Okay. Security group.
Now we need to have a brief discussion
on security group
and then after that we will be actually
launching this instance.
Okay.
Now let me show you to simulation
that what actually is happening.
So right now we are we
we are on our own computer, right?
This is the computer that we have
that says
someone working on the computer.
Okay, Now
I have a W.
S console
opened up
and using this
I am making configurations
in aid of this cloud.
So the first configuration that I made is
I selected A, B, C.
Right
after selecting
the VPC, I selected a subnet
and after
selecting the subnet
I said that, okay, now
select the volume off the SSD
and launch that particular instance.
So what is actually happening?
The scenes of VPC got created.
We use the default one, right?
A subnet, we use the default
one selected actually a building somewhere
with that this particular subnet
and how many computers were available
for 091.
Right. 409.
What computers were available to us
now and say they were here
we are launching.
How many instances did
we select while considering one,
two, three?
What happened?
Thank you.
You guys just below,
please have some conversations.
Okay, We launch one instance, right?
So this is imagine one computer.
And this computer that we launched
is going to be assigned
an IP address. Right?
You know that
all computers have IP address.
Now, this IP address is going to lie under
which particular
network can you guys tell me
under which network
are which particular subnet?
Okay.
So this particular IP address,
which is going to be there,
is going to be part of
this particular range of subnet
because this is the subnet that is
assigned to this building right out?
Of these 4091 subnets that are available,
it's going to be one of them.
And this subnet is the part of
this particular network,
the cloud that be created.
Okay, This is the only thing
that is actually important
that you should understand that.
Do we need to have a VPC, a subnet
and an IP?
If you understand
this, you are good to go.
Let me know
if any questions are over here.
Who assigns the IP class?
Either Class E, Class B okay.
You want to say that which which
do we want
to assign?
Do we do it?
No, we just select the subnet and the IP
is this IP assigned by default.
Okay guys, is the concept that
why do we need an IP to all of you?
Okay, so let's say the IP address
of this particular computer
is 192.168.10.9.1.
Now it is the part of this
particular subnet.
Okay.
Now let me tell you, why is it important
to have a VPC and a subnet?
And this particular IP address?
So let's see the IP addresses.
192.168.9.1.
Okay.
We all agree upon this
someone or let's say
Katherina or Miriam, I asked you.
I said that.
Okay, you have this.
192.168.9.1 IP address.
Log into your aid of this machine for you.
It's simple.
Will simply enter the IP address
and some command and see access it.
But how is network going to find it
out of millions?
IP address?
How is it going to navigate to the right
It will take a lot of time
if it starts going to each and every one.
Right?
So first of all,
it will say, okay, this IP address
lies in which particular
VPC is a part of which particular VPC
first is going to define the
virtual private cloud.
It's going to say, okay,
this virtual private cloud, this
IP address is a part
of this particular virtual private cloud.
It's going to say, okay,
which region is that?
It's going to say it's
this particular region.
Okay, good.
After going to the VPC, it's
going to say, okay, now one, two, three,
four subnets are there.
This IP address is a part of which subnet.
It's going to say
it's a part of this particular subnet.
Okay, good.
Now it has detected the building
of the detection of region.
It has detected the building
Now in that building.
It's going to go to that exact computer,
very unique to perform some tasks.
Is it clear to all of you?
So that's how
the IP address and the network
subdivision actually
you move through the network smoothly.
Else if there's no subdivisions like this,
will have to like go to first
East, go to all the IP address,
then go to Mumbai, go to all the IP
address, then go to somewhere else,
go to all the IP address.
It's going to take a lot of time.
So Internet is fast,
you know, due to this logical
division of networks.
Okay, Now
security groups.
Okay.
So we know that whenever
there is going to be a network
involved, we are going to have
some security related issues.
Right?
We need to make our network secured.
If it's not secured,
then anyone can have access to it.
Anyone can go into our network
and, you know, hack our
computer and stuff like that,
too. So
security groups are something
that we configured
to make our computer secure
so that only it is accessible by us.
What a security group,
how do they work
and stuff like that?
We will be discussing it in the next class
because I
we are done with Teri, right, for this.
That's enough of theoretical stuff.
I'll discuss it later.
Let's go ahead
and practically launch the instance
SO for now by default, let it be a switch.
Let the protocol, the TCP,
let the port train.
We try to let the source because
the IP address be desk
one and click on the View
and launch.
And after that click on launch,
let me know
when you have this flop up in front of you
so that I can tell you
what to do.
Okay, Now
you need to click on create a new key here
so that RC
gave you a key player name,
let's say my key
and download that keep peer.
Okay, It is a download. It is. Shh.
Shh, shh, shh, shh,
shh, shh,
shh. Because launch instance.
No disturbing sound.
It's.
It's the sparrows outside, not he.
He's sleeping.
Shh, shh,
shh, shh, shh.
Okay, Once you click on launch instance,
go to your
easy to a again.
So you just type in easy to
and click on Easy do.
It's going to take you on the console
and there you have
instance running one.
Okay.
So it means that one computer is running,
one instance is running.
He appears that he downloaded ah, one
volumes is one
you can name anyone, any name, name it.
My key name if your key whatever you want.
Okay So the instance is running.
Let's click on that instance
and let's have a look at state.
So running is the state, but right now
it's status is still loading,
so it will take some time
for that computer to set up lost.
That was build that.
And so all those so software's on it.
It's going to take some time
like two, 3 minutes
and then we will see that
how can we actually connect with that?
Okay.
At this point I want to mention something.
So this is the computer that we built up
inside the cloud on an Amazon, okay?
And we did that using eight of us console.
Okay. Now,
this is a computer that we have
in our home right?
And it is connected to
the router
and then the Internet.
And again, this is connected to
the building
where we have our resource, our instance,
and that building is also connected
to our router gateways.
And then
to our computer.
And obviously
we know the IP address of our computer
that we just created.
Now, if you want to have access or work
on this computer, there are multiple ways,
number one is to use the console
to have access of this particular computer
for that
you do not need any additional software.
You can do it directly to the console.
I'll show you how.
Our the other thing is that
if you do not want
to use it of this console
to work on a computer,
then you need to have a software
called Woody.
It's something like this.
You need to have this in here.
You give the IP address of the thing
that you want to connect.
You select the protocol
on which you want to connect,
and then you open up the connection
and it actually connects you
to that particular computer.
Okay.
Is it you just
And what about the rest?
Okay, guys,
so what's the status of your instance?
Is it
a status?
Is the check that Jack Seth based
and it has launched?
I'll be great.
Now let's click
on this particular instance
and have a look
at the information that we have.
Okay.
So what is this?
It is the IP address of the computer
that you just generate that you just me.
It's going to be different for,
all of you.
This is a private IP
IP for the difference
between public and private address.
Can you guys tell me what's the difference
just Yeah, but what's the difference
between the public one
and the private one?
What's the
actual difference?
Okay, so this public one means
that if you want to access this computer
through a network
that is outside that building,
for example, right now what we are
trying to do, you will have to connect
using this particular IP address.
But if you are not using a network
that is outside the building
and you are connecting to this computer,
then you can use this
private IP address.
Okay.
And let's have some other details.
Well, if you do computers,
Mohammed, if two computers in the data
center wants to communicate
among each other, do they need a network?
I mean, do they need an outside network?
No. Right.
So when they want to communicate,
they communicate
using private IP addresses
so that the communication is fast.
So that's the reason of having private IP.
IP addresses.
Okay.
Now, the important thing that we will be
discussing over here is security.
So right now.
This says that
the IP address,
this public IP address that this computer
has can be accessed on port number 22
using the protocol TCP IP from the source
0.0.0./0.
Okay.
What does this mean?
Any ideas?
No. Source.
Let me repeat it.
It says that this public IP address
can be accessed on Port 22
using the protocol TCP IP from the source
0.0.0.0000.
What's that?
Okay.
Okay. Let me explain it to you guys.
It means that
if I want to access this computer,
I'll have to use the port 22.
What is that? I'll explain it.
I'll have to use the protocol,
TCP and source.
This is important.
This source is right.
0.0.0. Right.
This is an IP address, right?
Is this an IP address?
When the IP address over here is 0.0.0,
it means that any IP address is welcome.
So it means that if you know
the IP address of my computer,
you can have
access to it.
So the machine that I just created,
if you want to access it, you guys can
just by knowing the name of this,
just by knowing the IP address and
just by knowing the port and the portable.
So, you know,
now if you want to connect BGP,
the port of all train to the port
range and IP address is this one.
If I want to make it secure,
if I want to make it secure,
no, I have not made a secure yet.
I did it by choice
because right now what we set,
we said that will be discussing
security groups in the next class.
If I want to make it secure,
I just and to my personal computer
IP address in the source
and it's going to be then only access
from this specific IP address and none
else.
Okay.
So anything else
that we want to have a look upon?
I don't think so.
Everything is fine.
So We can monitor our
utilization of CPU and other
operations of the computer
to this logs, CPU
utilization status check field.
If there is any network practice
that were password
network, our network
and this reads described, etc.
etc..
Now let's connect to the instance.
So I'll click on Connect
and it takes me to this particular page.
So all of you click on Connect,
you'll be on this particular piece.
And after that
I'll click on
Connect.
I hope this one works because sometimes
it just is not in the mood of connection.
So there we go.
We have successfully connected
to a computer
that we created on this cloud
using US console.
We can also do it to our computer,
but I'll show you that in the next class.
Okay,
So when I issue user
Yeah, this is amazing, right?
Easy to use.
Okay, Now this is the Linux machine.
This is a Linux machine.
So everything that you are going to be
working over here is going to be
with the Linux command.
You cannot use Mac with
and Windows and stuff like that.
So do you guys know about Linux,
Any commands?
Do you know if you want me to run
now? There you go.
pWt is there a less let's do LS So
there is no direct.
The system is actually empty right now.
Let's do CD tilde and let's do it again
against all.
If you do the I r let's say
batch level
unless.
Oh, there we go. We have batch 11.
So silly.
Batch 11.
You know we can go and pwt.
So there you go
if you want to install some
softwares on it because this particular
machine image that choose
I believe it does not have pre-installed
softwares, it's a black one.
So if you want to install some softwares
on Linux, it's
a completely very difficult process.
So we will not be doing that
and most probably
you guys will not be asked to do that
even on your jobs
either until you are,
you know, experienced.
You write down in your resume
that you have been working with Linux
because if you write that down,
they are going to ask you
to work in the Linux because companies
love people who do Linux.
So right now what we are going to do,
we are just
going to put it
on it logout
and click on your instance
and click on it again.
And let's do one thing.
After reaching this point, just
click on Terminate instance
that you do not have an extra
computer running on us.
Okay?
So just terminate it.
What is Linux useful for?
Well,
the purpose of using Linux.
Okay, first I would go to your instance,
click on it,
click on instance date and click
on Terminate instance
and terminate.
Okay.
So Linux versus Windows versus Mac was
well, why is Linux distribution
mostly preferred?
Because when you have an application,
develop completely,
you want that application
just to run, right?
You do not want any
graphical user interface.
Why is that so?
Because if you have a user interface
that is going to consume
RAM and that is
going to consume CPU, right?
But when the application is ready,
you do not need any
graphical user interface.
If you develop an application
and run it on Windows
and deployed on the server,
you are paying for extra RAM
and extra CPU
for the graphical user interface,
which you do not even need.
Right?
So your application
is going to require more.
And even apart from
that it's going to be a little bit slow.
Yeah, it's about the cost and the speed
also because Windows
is obviously going to be slow
because it has to always,
even if it's not showing you
the graphical user interface,
still it has to
within its hardware display something.
It has the code running behind that,
that okay,
draw this dialog walks
or whatever is going on.
So when you have an application
developed in Linux and you deploy it,
there is actually no
graphical user interface.
It saves you a lot of resources.
It's actually fast
and is preferred animator.
So whenever you will be actually
working on server, you will see that
all servers have Linux distribution
operating system.
I don't think that
people use Windows or Mac OS servers
and big interest directly.
So that's the reason.
Okay guys.
So I believe that
we are almost done with today's session.
And before we end,
let's do something really cool
and then we'll end our today's session.
So they they can't ease to just
quickly, let's do it just quickly
and then we'll end our session.
Since easy too.
I want to go to the consoles. No.
Okay,
click on launch instance.
Let me know once you guys are here,
go to easy to click
a launch instance.
Okay.
Write down windows
done.
Click on Select.
Select the feature to micro.
Let me know what's done because then
I will click on next configuration.
Okay, The next
the default APC and subnet,
choose any one of the default
subnets that you want to.
So only these two options
have to be selected by default.
And then click on Add Storage.
No changes to be made and add storage
and click on Add
Tags.
I would be to this point, okay,
click on Configure Security group.
Leave it like this by default
and click on review and launch.
And after that, then go on launch again.
Okay.
Now in key you do this to let keep here
and my key RC and acknowledge this
that's it
I good with this done
perfect Now last instance
let's go to our console again
and see where the instance is launched.
Okay.
It's still loading letter load
and then we will connect to it.
Okay.
So I just wanted to mention that now
you guys are already out in the market
and you'll be having job interviews,
you will be going to assessment
tasks and stuff like that, right? So
just whenever you get in an
assessment,
just make sure of one thing that
before
you actually attempt it, because I believe
that you always get some time, right?
You get like 2 to 3 days actually
to perform that particular assignment.
So let's just say that you got two days
to have to perform that assignment.
And it's mentions
that it's regarding selenium.
Ah, it's regarding, let's see, Java,
just open up your notes
and at least revise
the basic stuff regarding that topic
quickly.
Go through the basic stuff that you have
read regarding that topic so that
when you actually attempting
those assignments
you are able to do them
like give you 100% at least.
And whenever you
tag some someone like
anyone from us, like us or me,
just know one thing that we will be there
to help you out.
But we cannot make promises.
You got to be always available because
we also have regular classes going on.
So only if we are able to get up time
in that specific slot,
we will connect with you.
But again,
that is not going to be
under person scenario.
Okay.
Most of our yes, you mentioned
I think it's related to Java, right?
So okay, so let's see if it's available
at any time.
Okay. And most of what can you do?
One thing I think
can you please share the recording
with your all fellows
of the interview that you had?
I think you guys can also go to that
recording and
see the questions for yourself.
Maybe they'll help you
prepare a little bit.
Okay, so just go through this recording
and see that what kind of questions
you may get prior to taking the answers.
Try to research on the answers.
Okay, So
it will prepare you a little bit.
But well, the assignment
that most of you actually got,
it was a little bit hard one.
So I'm hopeful that other people
will having
an easy assignment
posting about the grade.
I'll just let you go with it.
Okay. So
no, I don't have that list.
Okay.
So No, no, I do not have it.
I'm sorry.
I do not have it.
Okay,
so I'll ask so that if you can do it.
Okay, Mustafa, I'll ask this.
I have the link.
Okay, So now let's quickly
connect to the windows.
And after that we go over to Sydney
and wait for you.
Hassan So let's
click on this and then click on Connect
and click
on our DP client.
So let me know, do
you guys have this option available?
I declined, all of you.
You have this.
Okay, download this remote desktop file.
It's going to download for everyone.
I believe.
Let me know what you have downloaded it.
Okay, so we click on Connect
and then RTP clients
in order to connect
with a Windows system that we launched,
the method is a little bit different
than the next one,
so it's opening it up, click on it.
The file that you download it,
it's going to open up something like this.
Click on Connect.
So okay, till this point, are you guys
with me?
Mac users, Are you able to do this?
Mac users?
Do you have the same option
when you click on this particular
file, you need to click on
some already be decided if you want
this.
Okay.
I think for Mac users
to connect using RTP,
let me just just give me a moment.
It's to be similar
to this.
Okay.
So getting downloaded
Microsoft Remote desktop client from Mac
App Store. You
do you have Mac after
this?
Yeah.
Just follow this name.
Download this remote desktop plan.
It will be there. Okay.
So for of you who have it,
the next step that you are going to do
is click on get password.
Okay? It's not available right now.
This will take 4 minutes,
but I believe it.
It will be available a few minutes.
So just go ahead and do this password.
Click on. Okay.
It's going to open up a windows
console in front of you
and you'll see that even if you are on Mac
aren't Windows on Linux,
you will have a Windows system accessible
so you can have
it and Mac OS people who wants to work on
Windows
Go ahead, launch a Windows instant
and you can work.
Or what do I think for today's class
that's going to be it and the next topics
and some information will be covering that
in our next class on Saturday.
And I'm going to now and this session,
the load that I'm going to
just give you a brief overview
for Haswell, if anyone
else wants to have it, regarding
the Selenium read and the rest of you,
best of luck for your coming endeavors.
I hope that you guys will be doing great.
You guys are going to do the interviews,
you guys are going to get the jobs
as soon as possible.
My best wishes are without you.
Okay.
You're welcome.
Thank you. All. Okay.
So talking about selenium, great.
Let me quickly draw it for you.
Okay, handsome.
So I.
Well, Mohammad, I'll figure it out later.
Okay. Regarding Mac,
and I'll let you look up.
I don't know about all at once.
I don't remember.
So let's do it on our free time.
Okay, So selenium. Great.
I'm trying to be talking about this.
Selenium grid consists of two parts.
One is Selenium hub
and the other
ones are nodes.
Okay, So
the actual problem is
on your computers.
It's quite difficult to establish hub
and nodes.
It's it's really difficult
to configure them
to install them
because
they actually
make up separate kind of containers,
separate kind of resources is
because, you know, it is actually most
popularly used for parallel testing,
right.
And cross browser testing.
So setting this up inside your computer,
it is
it can be done, but the contributions
are quite complicated for this purpose.
What usually do is that they either use
the cloud
are they use most of probably doctors,
they launch selenium grid in dockers
container.
What are Docker
containers will get to understand
and study
about them in the upcoming classes.
But for now, I'm just going to give you
the hint
of how silicon grade actually works.
But showing you
a practical
example,
I think that would not be possible for me.
So what happens is that Selenium
hub is the place where you have
your script running,
your script is running here,
and these are the nodes where your
browsers are launched.
So let's say in this particular browser
you have in this particular node
you have Chrome browser launched
and in this one you choose
Firefox.
Then what is so going to do?
It's going to execute the test cases
in parallel
in the Firefox and also in the Chrome.
And if you want to, let's see
parallel test
the same script, same application
in more
browsers, you can set up more nodes.
Let's say you have a node
in which you have opera.
So the hub is going to
also run the script over here.
So basically that's how a selenium grid
actually works.
It's a very top layer view.
I'm going to share some
links with.
You have a machine?
No, that's the whole point.
It could be not.
Machine is going to be the same machine
as just one computer.
And in that particular computer
there is segmentation,
which is not physical but logical.
So it separates these machines.
It makes multiple virtual machines.
You can see, okay,
but the camera's same.
But logically there are like multiple
machines on it and that's how it works.
So selenium great for that.
If you want to go to I'm going to
give you guys this link
and you should
directly go down towards
the point
where, okay, I just want you see.
So we have a hub
and we have nodes, but right now
this particular link teaches you about
how to use selenium pop using dockers
because mostly in the industry,
selenium is used in combination
with Dockers as the configuration on
individual system is not easy to be done.
So Dockers is used to do that allegedly
just go to it A read the code.
The code is simple.
It's not that difficult in fact.
You know what?
When it comes to selenium, Gray is
once you have the grid set up,
the software
set up, that is, which is not when
using a doctor difficult part.
You have
dockers selling image
we discuss about images right
You know what's an image
so you have Docker
image for selenium grid available.
So what you can do,
you can install this Docker
image on the system
and it will set up the grid for you
automatically
so that haseloff configuring the doctor
sitting in with yourself is bypassed
and you have the grid running.
Once the grid is running,
then your whole responsibility
is only going to be read
to write down selenium script.
It is going to be just the same way
you write down
normal scripts,
the normal setting scripts.
The only difference that is going to be
there is
it's in the code where you actually
set the drivers.
So let me show you the difference in code
that you guys can have an idea
and not be afraid by sending in.
Great.
Okay,
so this is just the running of
the this is a selenium image
that they have.
They installed the image now.
The containers are up
and this is the code.
Okay.
So now what they are doing is
chrome.
Optionally it goes to new call options
driver, not set new remote web.
You mark all options
and in doing what you are
they have the local rules for for
for the address of the container
where the selenium hub
is okay and apart from that
everything else is going
to be the same regarding the test case.
So the only change is going to be
where you set the drivers.
Nothing else is different
when you are using selenium.
I hope that makes sense to all of you.
Okay, that's it.
So once you have the Dockers,
you have the selenium grid running
and then you just need
to make these changes
of how to set the driver in your
and your code for selenium strip
and the rest of the things,
they are just the same,
nothing else is there to be worried about.
Okay guys.
So that that is going
to conclude our session for today.
I'll see you guys on Saturday 1015.
Take care. And by the.