I month.
All right, guys.
Let's.
Yes, yes, yes. Actually,
like I said, late.
I mean, you there does go. But
so now, basically, so far what we did,
we understood the concept of base.
You are right,
which is equivalent to your base.
You are held in Java.
Rest assured API,
first thing we cover, like
we know how to prepare the request, how
to send the request,
how to get the response right,
and how to verify and validate
all of the responses.
Right now, when you say verification
for right when we say verification part.
So in verification and verification,
we are not only relying on one
particular type of validation verification
check point, we are very plain
status code.
We are verifying body message, verifying
string in the body, verifying the value
of a string in the body.
Right.
All of these things
we are verify is indeed
right.
So these all are the things.
These all are the things we covered.
Find after this.
A next point which we covered is
integration
of rest
assured API, integration of rest assured
API with
with particular part
with key part right there.
Also we did
so we wrote normal scenarios training
in these scenarios
we are questioning their data.
So we have seen two ways
to parse their data so far.
How many of was
how many was two is the first one is
the first one is why are they is
the first one is there
method
right where we declare the body right?
And from there
we provide their data, right?
Using the methodology.
Second way is
can we escapes using
data table from feature.
Okay.
So either we can parsed their data
by declaring one particular
payload of matter in one particular class
called API payload constant.
Or we can simply parse
the values in the form of key.
And when you've been using data table
from P2P
to industrial,
despite everyone.
No, no, here we are, We have seen this.
But also what is that?
When we pass the data in the formal data
tables detecting migrate.
So it is retrieving key and value
which makes,
which makes maps.
So when it creates maps, I'm seeing
what the data table object
I'm using this object will return
my value as as next flight as maps.
So one key one value together the way
the one that is key value pair mapping.
Right. So we are getting this map.
We keep adding one by one,
one by one, one by one.
Make all the maps together.
That's what we are doing.
Correct.
And if you if you watch the video,
you must have motivated
find three.
No, no, let's do the same operation.
Right.
Let's do the same operation in addition.
So far, we pass the data layer data table.
We pass the data by a normal method.
Remember, we had added
one more dependency called Jason,
so via JSON, also via JSON object.
Also, we can pass the data
because Java allows to short API
allows us to data to be sent
in JSON tournament
data to be sending JSON forward.
Correct?
That is correct.
Or not.
So now what I'm going to do is see here
the same scenario, right?
The same scenario.
I'm going to write again
right this time
I am going to create, this time
I'm going to create the body.
And we declared the employee
in which I am going to pass the data here.
I'm going to see
Jason work through.
So I am seen here
using JSON.
So now see what I'm going to do.
I would, I think, given a request,
is prepared for creating an employee
via Jason Field.
Now what is this Jason
This is something we need to understand.
What is this? Jason Field
Guys, any idea, any guesses
what I'm doing here?
What is this?
And build any guesses
like Excel?
Marty Yes.
Got it.
Got the body from Swag update.
So first first to let me do one thing.
Let me just create this request first,
let me create the stem of this request
and then we will do further part.
So from API donor,
I'm going to change this bag
at the moment,
I'm going to change this date.
I will make it to generate this data.
And then when I run this
part, when I run this bar,
that will
Naughton is not day.
I want to do this.
Don't.
So first we got this request, right?
We got this step for the request
that I bet
I have to add this particular step
which we just created
once in API workflow steps.
Right.
So here, here I'm going to write
this is that I'm going to write
this particular step. You
now see now see here
I'm going to write
a request is equal to given
dark proposed header
where the values would be.
My API
constants
dark header content
comma
API Constants Dark content.
Dark.
Another header.
Again, I'm creating the employee,
but this time I'm going to use slower
shock. No, no, no.
I'm just copying this part.
I could have copy pasted also,
but I'm typing so that you guys can see.
Okay, so now
first for Turner Case
with the given keyword
first header API cons
contain date
and the value is obtained back
after this.
Another header is guys,
what is another header?
We can try API constant start
header for authorization
and then the value of authorization
we are taking from which plus from
generate token steps are broken
down to confirm this.
Now here, here we need to provide body
because we are going
to create the employee.
So here we are going to create the body,
this body, whatever the body,
I'm going to provide it.
We just put it like this.
As of now,
I'm not doing anything because first
I have to make the body.
So now, now if you see,
I go here in my payload constricts
So far
I created this particular method, right?
I created this method.
So I provided this particular part
as a normal string.
You see, basically, you see this
aggravated normally the string.
This time I'm seeing, I am seeing
I don't want to pass this string
because I have JSON
so I can provide my head just an object.
All the vendors, all the vendors.
So the format should not be this much.
If you took the form
which would be very easy.
And what is there for me? Right.
I'm going to a public
static method of this grade.
Static method.
I'm c to create, deploy, or D
system by mistake.
And because this method
is also going to return this train.
So I'm going to write the string
because all of the values I'm having,
it all are in the string, right?
So let's see how I write.
I have to write first here.
Jason
Object.
Jason Object
object is equals to nil
is an object
based.
This is not Jason.
We have already used.
We have already added right enough.
I'm not exempt by remember were
I remember or not.
But are you guys following me as of now?
Fine. So here, here I'm going to write.
See, there's this JSON object
whenever we use the JSON language.
So tell me in just a language,
we pass the values in which one
is know that the structure is
not satisfying.
In JSON,
we pass values in which what is this?
Yes. Maps key
and then you got a key and value, right?
So what is the method
to add the value in this particular map?
So this object is the map.
So what is the method to add the value
map going to put?
C, it is asking for key and value
book, correct?
It is.
It is asking for both D and value
because both are a string.
So here d we can provide from
right based.
We can provide a key from here.
Let's provide the key and the value
I can provide from here.
Let's see, the value is
what?
Again, all we did to put
in the second key would be my employ.
Last name, common value would be my
doctor
object or put
within,
but it would be my name. It's
object.
We should put
right case.
So it is returning me one JSON object.
It is returning.
You want one? Just an object.
So to convert any object to a string,
what is the method?
It is returning with this object.
Now delegates which metrolite call dart
goose not do string.
So what this method does,
this particular method will return
one JSON object in a string format where
I'm having all of these values,
but I'm having all of this values.
Is this clear?
And despite
to do one, please take it.
Please write it.
Everyone.
Once everyone is done with it.
All right, well, that's great.
It's time they think of this
once they are done.
Otherwise, if they fall behind, it's
very hard for them to follow.
Thanks, but
can you please be sure?
Make sure 77
can be a bit true for a second.
Is API workflow or feature API.
But because
the steps.
Okay, from
there you
here we are going to write.
We didn't write anything yet
so we are going to write now.
So guys, buddy, we have created language.
We use creative when we use opposed
one note.
These are two different approaches.
You should be having multiple features
to try when you work in the industry.
We cannot stick to one particular
approach, right?
That's why
we are providing you multiple approaches
and then you can do this or do that.
To do that, great.
If you provide, it shows diversity
in your experience, one or the other,
multiple features to play
fine.
So now here I'm going to write API payload
constants,
start, create, employ body using Jason.
So this time here
I was calling normal body.
Normal body here
I'm calling my Jason body.
Can you see guys
get I'm calling my somebody cut it
now rest of the things
the rest of the things if you see
a list of all these steps are same list
all this gives us
is this correct enemy
list thunderstorms are seen.
Is it is it going to affect?
No. Great.
Because it is just a different way
of passing the data.
But the operation is
anything is going to be see,
it's the operation is team correct?
Correct.
The students
fine.
So now this time, this time
when I'm done with my feature, finally,
when I'm done with my build constraints,
which I created here, write this part.
And then
after this, when I'm
done, my API workflow steps,
which is available here, right,
then what I can do simply
I should go in appearance.
I will run this particular
once in any fine.
So this one, working by any
given object, is prepared
for creating an employ
by a adjacent build.
So this time I'm using Jason below.
Post call is made to zero one verify right
employed created convinced message
employed created in value both matches
we got this employ 80
and this employed is also stored
as a global variable.
Right.
Everything is working final one guys.
Tell me
everything is working fine.
Nice.
Now let's look at the code.
We actually thought we
panicked and before
every single request it is generating
automatically and capturing this.
We are using this
for all kind of a request.
So now see guys,
first way we posited industry involvement
in the multi metatrader method.
We called thinking to be repository
data from data people.
How do we we parsed the data
for creating an employee via JSON object.
No thought we
like two approaches here.
I showed from the API perspective.
One approach I showed that is like
detectable from the perspective, right?
So this is not just
just if I were just one way from kicking,
but we should have to this particular
by to break from the Google participant.
So let's do it.
I'm going to write this scenario, right?
I'm going to write this scenario
workflow part right workflow part
in this one, right employee ID
and everything creates contains.
Fine. Let's take this scenario again.
It doesn't matter
whether you are calling this data
from your
first part or second part
anyway, we are going to change it now.
So how are we going to change scene?
I'm going to let here write to make
to make this particular part more dynamic
when I'm seeing more dynamics
to how first to admit ideas and ideas.
So I'm going to write my scenarios, create
I need, I need
better make it
even given.
Okay, see, this is interesting, but given
our request
is prepared for
creating
and employ
creating an employee with
dynamic data.
So guys see how I can foster dynamic data.
The only thing you need to take care of
is the format of posting that indictments.
First name, middle name, last name.
Don't fasten gender.
No forced otherwise in your
first name it is male and
female.
Don't do this right.
We need to make sure.
We need to make sure
which part we are calling one
by one based upon a generic
creating the employee here you see.
Right.
So what? All are the things we need?
We need first name, last name,
middle name,
gender, birthdate, status, job data.
We need all these things face.
We need all these
things are not for creating the employee.
So now,
now we can pause this data on drink time.
We should not store these things
in our API payload.
Constance Right.
So you mean the sequence minded?
Yes. Sequence maker.
Not here where I tell you that.
Don't worry, I need it.
So first firstly, I'm
going to provide my force
to be as business.
Now see you guys how things work.
Remember, we passed the values
in our scenario itself when we were using
when we are using the killer, like
remember this part of not everyone?
And the second one I would put is
so the third one is the last name.
So I'm going to put this Mike
after Mike,
what is the next thing We have?
Gender.
So gender in for men
because Dennis surrogate
Mike all three are men
according to my understanding point
Now here are
there is no surety for anything nowadays,
but so I'm going to write in
1212 2018
it is both name, last name and then.
Really? Yes. Correct.
Correct.
First name, last name and middle name.
Then your gender.
Then your date of birth after the birth.
Next thing is your employee status.
So I'm saying it is employee.
And then the next thing is your job title.
So I will say you
guys now see this part clear to everyone.
These are the things we provide
generally in the body.
Now I'm providing it in any, you know,
scenario, any issue in this part.
Anyone
let me write it the segment.
So this should remind you that dynamic
to generate the step for us
to see how these things work,
this thing work
to generate the step for us.
I have to go in API and
I have to change this to dynamic
and then I will make it to true.
Now let's run this part,
this one, this part.
Congratulations.
Because this is a
copy this time here,
change it to false again, go to API, work
a step and here in the end simply it is
simply write this one
now. Now if you see
here, what is the next thing we have to do
was to remove this code.
Now Seagate,
it is asking for so many strings.
And you see you guys
see a string string,
two, three, four, five, six, seven.
Right.
So make sure at which point you provided
which is string.
For example, here you provided what
you provided, what the theme
beat underscore or
forced me.
I'm providing the argument
in the second one you provided here.
The underscore last name
in the third one is EMV underscore.
Right?
And then you provided here,
it would be your guys.
What was the fourth thing?
First name, last name, middle name.
And then
gender.
What what would happen
if I did not work here?
Then what would happen?
Not for any database.
Not one of the data will come,
but it will hand it right.
Your gender will be handling
your date of birth,
or your date of birth
will be handled in your gender. One
Right
How Arguments Spouse Goes
The first argument will take
which value the first argument first name,
which venue?
First venue second
which venue would we take? Lugo
This argument we take
which will do first venue.
So if you provide the male here,
if you provide gender here,
then what would happen?
Then your gender become like.
If you provide data, what then?
What would happen?
You don't want to become venues, right?
So please take care of this part
after gender.
That is next thing would be have to
provide is E and B underscore
would be in there scalability
and then we need e and be underscore
and next thing is status
which is status jobs to this correct.
Okay.
Let me split it.
Explore this part. Also
let this part also.
So next thing is E and B
underscore we need is
the job
guys see I'm handling all seven
you all 17 correct.
Correct case
I'm handling all those.
So now now in the multi in the body
how I'm going to write this
that is very important in the body first
first
we have to make a method for this right.
So how we make a method for this part,
that's what we need to understand.
Let's go to the body.
It is the body API payload
constants are two bodies
we have already created.
Initialize
to what is we have already created.
After this I'm creating yet another part
I'm seeing this
public
static which returns this spring.
It is a b load
more than me, b load more dynamic.
But here here what I'm going to do see
using the same JSON object,
using the same this an object you see
the same JSON object I'm using here,
but but I am parsing the string,
the parameters
so the string should be mine and beat
underscored was.
And this part, this part
I'm going to pass.
It makes sense.
Makes sense. Guys.
What I'm doing.
Guys make sense what I'm doing.
So now let me quickly copy this
things from here.
First
is to give,
finalize
C status with status Job
title will go in the job
title, gender will go into gender mode,
they will go into body.
So everything I detail what we are
passing from a feature
by the same detail
should be filled in this particular part.
This students
should be free in this particular part.
Right.
Based
point.
Now I will go in my workflow steps
where
I have to write this particular steps
so guys see how to prepare the request
for creating the employed.
Simple request is equals to
given days.
What is the next thing you have to write
given now without looking at the code?
Tell me, given that.
Come on, stop writing.
Tell me now. Here.
First we are going to make the request
title,
which I get
first, which ends
PPA constants Dark
Radar
on the date
and the value is also from API.
Constants don't contain the
not another header
API constants don't
for authorization comma value
values coming from my token
not grace.
What is the next thing?
Not that body that is
right.
Next thing is body.
So now now in body.
This time
I will call an API below to consider.
It's not which body below
the more dynamic see
it is asking to pass.
It is asking to pass all with a string one
by one.
Correct? Correct.
All the data.
So fine
column was basically and B hostname
comma and B
last name comma MP.
Now MP
after first name, last name, middle name.
Then we need
gender
mark after gender, we need the MP
body Gomer.
Then we need MP
status comma,
then we need MP operator.
Right. And
let's see how many.
One, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, three.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
So far.
So what do we want?
And then just on the part again,
same verification, validation,
everything we can write here.
But right now
I'm going to show you just simple
this request how request is coming, right?
So the request, whatever
the request will be right,
or even if you want to see response.
Also no issues
simply write response is equals to
request or
when door.
The data that we provided in beta file
protected was just
the name of the state. Oh.
Which when you're talking
I didn't get that.
This is
this is the method name inside method.
We used to use an object
India some object.
We are providing the key and the value
we're passing in the value
we are passing from this particular part
on right
already.
And then simply,
once we get this data from here,
we can simply verify
based on the values like this
being.
Can someone be sure this method
let's can
someone please share this particular
method
with an X?
So you guys in this part,
is there anyone who has any question
in this particular part
how we made this law?
The more dynamic any question in this
is a we want done with
writing this particular part, like
should we execute this? Not
perfect.
It's going to be at an edge.
This is fine.
Finally, one,
if you want to see what is the response
we got right.
So no shoes
will go here, right?
Well, making the post code go inside this
and simply
we will write here responds door
to print.
So pretty print will always will
always print
a value which we are looking forward to.
Mine says 200.
Okay.
In which point you're making us check that
nasty case.
Is this the value we provided
then is Mike So again
the similar to work and employed
job better and status?
Is this the same?
We provided another feature find correct
so it means correctly the
days passing this
right.
It is taking their data
from our feature file.
In another scenario
it is taking the data from what?
Just an object.
In one more scenario,
it was taking the data
from our normal data table
and in for the scenario,
it was taking the data
from normal method in extreme point.
So we have seen for
we is now trying to create the employs
the same way you can get the employee,
retrieve the employer,
you can do
whatever you want to do, right? Correct.
So now just just want to show you
one small scenario here. Now,
another scenario really is one
very simple one.
I'm going to show you
three different in a post code, right?
Yes. Yes.
Because in most call after hitting the end
point, we are getting the response.
Some pretty prints, implements
receiving the response.
So after hitting the point
of leaving the post code,
we can get the response the moment we got
the response was to detect the student
the least understood
this point.
Now let me ask one thing next.
Creating the employee
and updating the employee.
So these are same scenarios
or different scenarios.
Different scenarios might be possible
that I'm generating the employee.
A new embroidery is fine, but it struck
When you do that, I have to update
the details of this only employee
which I just generated or created.
Grade might be possible.
I have two of the details of the employee.
Great.
Which is something else.
Simply to update the details.
We have to rely on one
specific information right.
And that information is unique, correct?
So we have to parse that information
like this one
example my employ 80.
So when we pass the employer,
we pass this data.
Where we pass this data
in order to
update the information
we have seen trigger document.
So the document sees
you have to pass this data.
We're
in method No, Alex, the initial
yes in body of the bus
just to see this document.
Right.
And inspect the document,
you would find a difference in the body,
a difference in the body of the employee
and all of the employee.
What is the difference?
Their difference is in one body, employee
ID is mandatory.
Employee 80 is mandatory.
Interpreting the correct.
So now, now let's do this.
Okay, let's do this first.
So now you sent me
here.
Oh, come on, keep.
Recently
we created one particular employee here.
See, this is the employer. But is that.
This is the employer? Correct?
It's. Copy this.
And can you show your API constant?
Sure, Why not?
This is my
API Constants.
EPA payroll constant.
Fine. So
shall we proceed further?
And this.
So first.
First, let's make the body right
for updating the employee.
Let's make the body
If we put it here,
this and I'm going to use
I'm going to use this same object here.
I'm saying here
update
employee body cutting,
update employee body.
Right.
And this part, this part
I'm not going to use from here. See?
Audience would
right
now, guys, what is the difference here?
The one thing I have to add,
which is a part of my body,
which is a mandatory part of my body,
I should see is
raised and me, what is the mandatory part?
One more thing is here in this body,
we have to change one thing.
What is that?
What happened to this?
What is my consumables
output
file?
So not Friday.
All we did not put This should be my
employee I.D.
karma.
This should be my value.
Correct? Is this correct?
Okay, so I'm going to update my value
against this particular user.
Is this one is this one Fine.
So now let's write one scenario.
My body is ready now, right?
This body is for updating the employee
with the body details.
So to specify one particular information,
one particular entry.
Right.
We have to use this particular part.
So let's go ahead and do it now.
So here I'm going to go and write
another scenario.
My system basically needs restart.
Now you can see 19 date is working.
The idea is running on low memory.
I need to close something up.
Let me close this part.
Okay.
I'm feeling okay.
Fine.
So now, after this, after this, I'm
going to write another scenario.
Giving
scenario is
a updating the employee
saying
write
my case.
So I'm going to a given.
Given a request is
for updating the
existing
details.
So then
call is made
to the employee.
Then what would happen is
there's what should be the status called
I should get from here.
Update the employee.
Then the status would for
you being an
should be 200
200. Right.
So now let me right here.
It says
update employee
it's take this part going to render
provide this here
is equals to date okay
my typing must be
right and right
my next bullet complete this to everyone
and everyone completes.
Then once
for to start morning.
It's evening.
Getting a DNA in the morning.
They don't come here in the evening
like it's already 930 by night,
not even evening.
So they come like 7 a.m.
in the morning, 7:30 a.m.
in the morning.
That's when these are times that
daylight saving is over. But
if big if become twice,
it means someone is in trouble
because they never double check.
And if they're double checking,
it means they're going to get someone
put into the hospital.
Days delayed saving
say gains are being modified
really great
in March 2nd week first week global
it's 13th
13th of March golfing.
Yes I can work off my trade bill
second week of November current.
We don't even we don't have delayed saving
but we have to adjust our timings rate
according to the US. Timing.
Next I'm asking.
Currently
I'm taking session from 5:30 a.m.
in the morning after daylight saving.
I could make the shift from fourth
b m in the morning.
Sketty
next weekend.
We don't have plans, right?
I don't know. That's
but I really don't know Even better.
It started better, to be honest.
All people have, but.
All right, fine.
So let's execute this part.
Let's execute this part
and someone share the upgrade
employee body method.
Jimmy, you see here
you can, right?
You know, just I'm giving you by
you can read
done fine.
It's good to pay at any cost.
Generate the steps
we go to this three steps.
Copy this
going to API workflow steps
here after this part
I'm going to write this three steps on.
Fine.
So now to prepare request.
First, today's fundamental reason
for preparing the request
or it is different
reason for automate for preparing
the request would be similar Mark
because because you are is equal to Ms.
you are in. So it would be seen
not only thing, the only thing
we would be changing here is
I'm going to write read
something to find.
The only thing I'm going to write
is in body.
I'm going to provide API below
the constant start of employment
of employee body.
This is the only thing I change
the method, otherwise the rest all are.
The things are same here.
If you see the all are that
these are see if you see this
clearly one
Now here I'm going to write
this particular write response I need.
So for response I have to write a request
for hitting the end point.
Which keyword this
or hitting the end point
which keyword know
yes when
bent to perform action
in order to pick the end point.
No rejection.
We are going to provide date, get
to update the employ we need put
we need input.
And here I'm going to write from API.
Constance dog of date employee you want to
update employee you are.
Is this correct?
So now from the response from the response
which I'm getting, I'm
going to perform verification.
So for verification,
which we're going to use,
then start a circuit
board status, put on 200
clear, always,
always done is always
because I used to ask them questions
when I was in college,
even in my organization.
Also, I used to ask questions like day
in music, the response is equal to return.
Yes, you can call this
because this is just a variable name rate.
You can provide variable
anything but that.
The response with the computer,
all you provide should be positive.
But for this to
the supporting student is to
sorry my rate
by now
because we have already passed it
in each of my
actions. Similar.
Yeah, action would be similar.
Action is similar.
Fine.
Okay. So far.
So what these three methods,
these three steps clear to everyone.
There is nothing like rocket science,
which we are really even.
I know that's the question.
And the operation is very small
and very little.
But still I'm asking again and again.
I even I know what we are doing simply
we are updating
one particular part
we have to change in detail to
and if you want you again,
if you don't want, don't
even if you do this
right, it's not going to affect
because optional trait
fine.
Anyone has any confusion,
any question in this
good guys should
we proceed further in executing
let's go ahead in our people and apart
from here, let's try it
and then sequence to false
and execute this.
Why not now? Please ask.
Please ask me. You go based it executed.
We have updated the details.
The employers right
And this
now further verification
very different Yeah so please check
was distracted the complete employed to
which employee you made If you check Asia
in our API payroll constraints
we provide that specific entry in our body
of these check rate of in your body
what you are working
because already only happen
when you are providing wrong.
So please check that
he didn't to employees then I think
this by forced
we created the data
and from there I provided this
gunning.
Wow got an employee to complete.
Could be a copy paste.
Edit even if it is a part that also
it can be a past.
But what that opinion is,
is waiting around.
But what any point or any piece you want
or even a simple matter to click there.
Also.
All right.
Student So now if you see here in this API
workflow feature, we have provided
updated employee passing data
from multiple different employees, right?
Providing data from Jason From data table
from normal part, right?
So it automatically generating same day.
We are getting the information,
also retrieving the data.
Correct.
And it describes
it. We first commit the code
which we have developed
so far
for handling the data dynamic exit sheet.
Remember,
we already have the code for sent to me,
but we already have a
code for the exam.
So from there, from that particular
method, we have to go in
and we have to handle the keys
and then use right
is released. Yes.
The updated code
has been pushed to the repository.
Right guys?
All right. So now,
now here, here
let me write that
and right,
we are done.