Okay, guys.
So let's begin today's lecture
and today's topic is going to be
good practice.
Okay. So
have you ever seen a piece
of this line about just getting though?
There are a lot of crunches right?
And all those boxes
demolished together,
forming the trunk of the tree.
Right.
That's how trees are formed.
And so you get
branches are very similar to
those kind of branches with the pre has
the merge in the end
to form a single trunk,
a single high plane, are you going
see a single dry top?
Okay.
So first
let's have one question
that why do we need
branches in the first place?
So who is going to accept that
body, this thing?
Why do we need branches
to avoid most conflict? No.
Even if you create branches,
you are still going to face most conflicts
in order to work separate the
and spread information
so we do not mess up the mean.
Yes. Has some very good
to have leaves obey
the no word on mean is good.
Okay so guys
this scenario is that let's let's tackle
this question to a very practical example.
We all use Facebook right?
We are always using Facebook.
So let's assume that the production
code of the Facebook is in the main branch
are the last of us.
So this is basically the code
which is being run on our mobile phones.
This is the actual application code.
So let's see now, Nasser is one of the
engineers and Facebook and Mark Zuckerberg
just called us and say, Hey, now,
so can you just update one feature?
This emoji needs to be updated.
Let's just assume that.
So do you guys think that
this particular code in the Mean branch
Nazir is going to work on the same code
to edit that Moji?
What if he does that?
What are the chances?
What are the risks involved?
What will happen
did not do that
well, exactly.
He should not be doing that
because there is a possibility that he can
he may make some mistake
and affect the rest of the code also.
And, you know, his book loses
billion dollars
and Nasr is fired immediately.
So he is going to stay away
from this particular
branch, make sense.
Okay.
So now what he wants to do is he
still wants to work on that feature.
And it's going to be a combination
of the code one over here.
So he's just going to go ahead
and copy this branch
and create his own personal branch.
He can name a
edit in
the emoji.
In here.
He will write down the additional code
which is required to
update that particular emoji.
And once he has tested that,
then he can open up a pull request
to merge this plot with the main branch
so that the production crew
can have the updated
why when the project team
wants to do that being starting,
what's separate down the folder?
Well, there were branching,
but when they went down
actually
this was most probably due to the servers.
I believe it was not some kind of update.
It was even if it was updated,
then it must be a hardware
level update because of the level up.
It didn't require your applications
to be done.
Okay, so do you guys understand
the need of branches?
Okay,
so we are going to spend some more time
on this because this is important
to understand that.
Why do we need lots in the first place?
So I'm going to give you
some more examples.
Okay.
So you mean branch or in
lots of rocks is your default branch.
It is
also called Master
and it is also calling me, but now it is.
GitHub is updating everything
and it says that it should be called
main.
So your main branch is supposed
to have your production code
or the file code, but
and let's assume
that on this particular means you have
some good some comments.
So this is going to be RC one
that me URL of
these circles are going to represent
our comments, but
let's call it c1c to
C tweet.
Okay.
Now let's say that
there is a new feature coming in
and we want to work on that
particular feature.
Let's assume that it's an automation
script for some application
and it's in it's in the production
there it is be used in real time.
But there is an other feature
that needs to be tested
and it would have to be written yet.
So what do you guys suppose?
What should happen?
Let's say Mike is responsible
for working on that feature.
What should Mike do now?
Mike should create a new branch, right?
He should create a new branch.
So when he's going to create a new boss,
the new branch is going to be created
from this one.
And he will say, that's a new feature.
Okay, what do we mean
by saying that the branch is going to be
made at this point?
It means that all the code which is MCP
is going to be copied in new feature
form belief system. Yes,
it's going to be there in the new field
and then he's going to start
working on updates
and start making new comments.
Let's say he's working on a new feature
and the commit is that C?
C for the numbers don't matter
and just for the ID,
I mean C five and cc6
and whatever updates he is doing,
they are obviously not affecting
the main.
Now let's assume that the
new feature has been tested
and it's
working perfectly fine.
I think we let the loop was the team.
Mike is going to
tell you, Hey look, I'm
done with the new feature.
Can we review it?
Bloomberg is going to say yes, why not?
So Loop was going to go
into the new feature branch on GitHub.
He's going to review the code that Mike
has written as he's the team B, right?
So he needs to review it.
Once he is satisfied,
then he would say, okay, now
the code is good, everything seems fine.
I think now it's
okay to merge it into the mean
so that our production code can also
have this new feature and make use of it.
So then he's going to merge it
into the main branch.
How this merging happens.
We will discuss that in detail,
but for now just
the concept is important.
Okay, so all of you acted as with me
till this point.
Any confusion or question?
Okay.
Everyone is good, right?
Now I'm going to speak about some
terminologies that you may
listen
when you are working on such a project.
So people,
these terminologies
do vary from country to country.
Okay, So some companies may use different
native terminology
and other one different type, but
I'm going to just give you a hint of that.
So let me open up this.
Okay,
So let's say that
if a new feature is there
and for that purpose,
a new branch has to be made.
So this branch can be called
a topic branch because it's a new topic,
it's a new feature, but it may vary
depending upon the company.
Okay, so just for an insight
that if you ever hear some topic branch,
you should not be like,
okay, what's a topic words?
So if a new feature is being
worked
on, we can call that particular branch.
I talked to French.
Okay, so we already know that mean R.M.
is the at true blotch on
in which all we want is
and then we have
one more scenario.
Okay.
Now let's say that
in this topic what when Mike was working
on the new feature
after at this point in the commit six
he faced some issues he found a bump
and his own goal.
This call was quite lengthy.
Everything was working fine, but there was
still bugs that were still there.
He wants to resolve them,
but he also does not want to mess up
with the code that he has with it.
So what should he do at this point?
What can he do?
Okay, so I'm going to repeat the question
again and then you'll
come to the solution and wait.
You would be the person.
The question is that
after making the six commit,
this particular commit still has some bugs
that needs to be resolved.
Everything else is working fine,
but there are few bugs
that needs to be resolved.
This code is quite lengthy
so he made the permit
not used the correct to
because that was important.
He did not want to lose this process
and now he wants to resolve that bug also.
But he does not want to mess up
his own branch
with individual comments
because it is to the most to after.
All right,
it is going to be merged to master.
So he does not want to have
unnecessary comments on this box.
He wants to keep it very clean
and the history he wants to
maintain it smoothly. Yes.
So in order to have that,
what he's going to do is
he is going to create
a new branch at this point
and he can simply name it resolving.
But in there
he can start working on
the solution of this bug
and makes make comments if you want to.
And once he has completely resolved
his job, then he can merge
the correct go back to
topic branch.
Okay.
So did you see that how the creation of
branches is going to save him?
A lot of hassle.
It's going to make his life very easy
in order to save his progress
and maintain a complete clean history.
Because remember,
I told you guys that it's very important
to maintain a clean history.
The irregular commit should not be there
because at the end of the day,
if someone new joins in on the project
are really
it has to be made you might have to go to
some previous commit.
So it's very important to maintain
a good clean history.
That's actually how
that we serve
the purpose of using get.
Okay now the question I'm asked about
can you go to see five?
No, no, I cannot go to see five,
although we can, but we should not.
Why would we go to a previous commit?
Okay.
See 60, correct?
Yes, this is right now
everything that we have,
everything that we are talking about,
it's in the local repository.
We are not talking about GitHub of yet.
Okay.
So if you find that a bug and see it
then will create a new branch, right?
Okay. So this is a very good question.
Another thing
that if he finds a new bug in seed,
he is going to create
should he create a new branch.
So what do you guys think?
Should he be grieving
then he brought or not?
Okay, so let's look at this. Let's look at
the rest
of the questions that I have missed.
Like you have read them
because they are not.
But for now, let me just
explain. Okay.
So even if you now he finds
a new bug in seed,
he should not be creating a new branch.
Why is that?
So let me explain to you.
Because this particular broad new feature,
this is the only branch
which is going to be merged
to make the right Resolving bug
is not going to be most of master.
Do you guys approved that?
It is going to be merged to puppet much.
So what he can do, he does not need
to actually create a new branch over here.
This is all Bloomberg is dedicated
to resolving bugs, although he can.
No one is going to stop him
from creating this branch.
But why do we have so many unnecessary
branches?
Right? This is not required.
You can also
actually resolve the bug at this point
because he thinks
that the bug is quite small
and he will be able to locate it
immediately.
But usually when you are working on
quite lengthy codes and you know
you are not sure whether it's solving
that particular bug
is going to affect the rest of your code.
You need to do some experimentation
like deletion of a class
and you should have a
class are making some changes in your pol
or any any other thing
and you do not want to affect
your rest of code
which is already written.
Then you create a new branch
that's the whole purpose.
So it's not that whenever
you are trying to resolve something,
you just create a new branch.
Rather, it's
more of the sense that you know that
if you will be
making some edits in your code,
your code might be affected
and you do not want it to be affected.
You not want to lose the previous progress
at that point of the merge.
Okay.
So now Mohammed is saying
he can make a branch only he murders
bugs to make that
he can make a branch
obviously murders, but
to make that for the license
and then we know Mohammed that's not that
even if he has not merged it,
he can still create a branch over here.
We have not merge it yet,
but he can create a much
as long as you are not covered by
no need for creating a branch,
as long as you are not copied branch.
No need to click.
No, no, I said that's not the you.
If you want to work on some new feature,
you have to create a new branch.
You are now going to work on Master
Alex.
He can just come in the pool.
We are
what I talk about. Alex
Okay.
Any of the questions that you guys may
have?
Let's say he created a new topic
and it is all about is he now committed
to the main
or he has to commit first in the future?
Okay, so how do I just say that
he created a new type of branch
and then he
he created a new branch to resolve, Right.
And after that,
he is going to commit directly to master
or he is going to commit the topic branch.
He is never going to commit.
Okay, This is not the question.
Then what
if you add another type of mind?
Okay, so let's create
another topic. Right?
So which one do you want to create about
the branch at sea?
Three are
sea two Where where
do you want to create it?
See seven
You cannot create a thousand branch
at sea.
Seven That that is not like that
doesn't make sense.
You are resolving above over here
and while creating a new type of branch
at this point
this is all in about
what do you want to do with this branch?
You want to create a new branch at seven?
Yes, you can create, but not required.
Okay, let's let's do this.
It's not required,
but let's assume that he did.
Okay.
So he created a new branch over here.
Okay, then what?
Let's call it Arbi.
He has new
commit are going to be right here.
Right.
Okay.
So now he needs to commit to this branch
and then this branch is going to be
my topic branch.
You should not directly merge this project
over here because at this one
these particular commits are going to be
skipped and the history will be missing.
So that is going to create a problem.
Okay, Now it's very simple.
Don't worry,
you guys just
I'm just explaining the need right now.
When you go over the example, it's
going to be very clear to all of you.
Okay, So let me show you this slide.
Okay, guys.
So let's have a look at this.
So over here, what is happening
is that this particular John,
he has the idea of a new feature,
as we discussed earlier.
So he just created a new feature.
Branch
started working on this. And when this was
completed demoted back to the mean
and that's it simple
what are we have discussed
in the simulation
so remember one thing
whenever you want to work
in a group project,
the rule of thumb is that
you will never be working on the massive
branch.
Okay, Is that clear to everyone?
Never work on the mean
or the master branch.
Always create your own new branches.
Okay,
Now let me explain to you a little bit
that how you will be proceeding at work.
So let's say that this is a master branch
that you have at work.
This is our master branch
and it contains some comments.
Bananas going to simply
want to present this.
So anything you
what is it just for one member?
No, no, I said that's not a scenario.
I went to this plant.
And when was that?
Just. Just made just for your purposes.
Okay, so this is the scenario
that this is the master, right?
That we have of work.
Okay.
And this code is running fine.
It's in front of
the. Now let's take action.
I say as one of the employer, the company,
and he's a brilliant person
who has to work on
two different features,
which are one
and future do
so I say have to work on two features.
We can one and two.
Now, remember
one thing, guys, it's your choice.
How long number of branches
you want to create.
It's your twice.
No one is going to come to
you and tell you, Hey,
why did you create two branches here?
Why did you create one branch
at the end of year?
What they are going to require from you
is at least one branch
that has that particular feature added
and a code is working fine.
That's it.
No one cares about how your branch of this
structure is for your own sense.
It's for your own ease
that I'm trying to develop this sense.
Okay, so now what should I look?
Is if I were, I showed what I would do.
I would say that,
okay, create a new branch
at this point and name it
future one,
and also create a newborn for this one.
A name a 3 to 2,
and then work on this branch
and parallel
on both different features.
Let's say at the time the I'm done
with working in Branch F one,
so my feature one is complete.
I will tell my team that hey,
it's done, can be merged.
He will say, okay, I merged feature.
One will be added
over the time I'm working on project two.
As soon as the future
two is going to be out of the
hey can be merged, you'll say Why not?
It's working out much
so it will merge the master and the master
is going to have feature one
and you could do both.
And let's assume that in parallel
what is
going to work will be a mark in parallel.
Amanda is also working on feature pre.
So what he is going to do,
it is also going to create one branch here
named Feature Tree
and will start
working on that particular feature.
And at any point in time
this feature is completed here, merge it
back to the master
after the team need has reviewed.
Obviously those conditions are
the same time.
Master. Lucky to work.
Yes, Master will be working and
as soon as the feature is called he did.
The code is merge after the check so
the master is not going to be effective.
So now is this to everyone?
Pretty simple, right?
Let them come to get it in writing.
It's just creating your own branch
and doing stuff over there.
And as it
now, it's your first choice.
How many branches do you want to me?
But we very vigilant about it.
Okay.
Do not unnecessary branches.
Mohammad Yes that is going to this
now you for that we have a separate class
tomorrow dedicated
to how to resolve those conflicts.
How will need view it
if you cannot committed
permit how much movement
I think you want to say
merge it
you can you get
you are making so much in your right.
These are the permits that you are making.
Okay.
So now
the rest of your questions
are going to be answered.
Then you will be doing the actual
examples.
Okay.
But this was just giving you
a brief scenario of the need
and use if this applies.
Okay.
So let's
go ahead and do one basic example.
But that what I want is
I want you guys to open up to intelligent
because you are going to be moving
very slow.
So I really want all of you to be in sync.
So let me know when anything is confusing
because this topic is really important.
This is what
you will be using in your project.
And if you guys do not understand
this, it's going to be very hard
for you to do the actual project
because the doubt we have
you can all work in collaboration,
so all your attention should be here to do
this project.
That's that will be
okay.
Name name.
It's Solar System.
Okay. Sure.
We will start at 1045.
Yeah.
Meanwhile, I just write down the request.
So basically
we are going to be doing a good project.
Okay.
With the name of the
project, one sort of distant
said.
One thing that I want
to mention before we jump into learning
branches and gifts and stuff.
So stuff
I'm going to take
very simple, good examples.
I'm not going to use any examples
from your test engine.
The framework, because
right now
the purpose is to get you guys familiar
with the case scenarios
and the actual purpose
of how to use this particular tool,
which is, okay.
So I'm not going to incorporate
some of the code which is,
which might confuse language.
You keep putting examples very simple.
Remember,
it is not about coding, it's about
actually learning how to use this tool.
So we will not be focusing on coding
even if
we are making any errors or stuff
like that.
Our whole focus will be
how Dave is working,
what are the concepts
that I will be teaching
in the end,
when once you have learned these concepts,
you will be very easily able
to apply them on kind of good.
That's not going to be a problem.
Okay guys, so let's begin.
So the requirement that we have of
our project
is that we have to quickly apply
the basic structure of our solar system.
And let's say
this is only the task of one person.
So it was given to one person
and he would ask that he quickly
apply the basic structure and upload it
because that's the requirement for
the client.
So let's say Mike started working on that.
So what he is going to do,
he is going to open up his intelligent
and then he is going
to simply create a new class.
And what is the limit?
He is going to let the solar system
slide Is
the hierarchy.
So what do you guys just
what do we have in our solar system?
What are the necessities
and basic things that must be there?
Yes, obviously
you guys are to follow slowly.
So number one thing,
you must have a sun, right?
And we also should have the
we should have moon
and planets.
So these are very basic things
that a solar system does have, obviously.
But we are not going to go into that
philosophy as
we are going to have, you know, a lot of
conflicts and discussions over there.
Oh, yeah, planes
and they are planets, not planes.
Right.
Okay.
So this is my solar system
and it has sun, moon and planets.
So keeping it very simple, no black holes,
nothing else for the.
So in the main ones,
what are we going to do?
Right.
We are going to simply write
our very basic code, which is going to be,
let's see,
star system, what should we name it?
What should be the name
of our solar system?
Look, you
because that's going to make you
new for System of.
Okay.
Okay, guys.
So do you think that now
the basic structure is at least ready?
We have not yet decided
how many Sun, Planet and etc.
but we do know
that basic structure is very
we can make a comment right at this point
just to save the backup of the code
that we have heard until this point.
Like I'm assuming
that these specifications are very huge,
like this code was very complicated.
Obviously we are developing
a solar system.
It's not going to be that simple.
And in the main we are also expected
to have a very huge code.
So let's for the sake
of example, let's say that
the let's say that we
are going to make a comment at this point.
So I'm going to open up this an explorer,
go to my solar system
and create a new That's all right.
Get. Okay.
So I really want to ignore
this thought in and out.
Fine.
So what should I do?
Nothing. No, we are just.
I just said that after this,
we are going to make a comment
because I don't want to lose my promise
at this point.
So it's going to be touch dot
yet ignore.
This has created a file
and I'm going to enter
dot idea and out file.
I want you to know that.
Okay so now
we'll get in it.
We may still have an empty repository
after that.
Will do get status.
It shows me that solar system
that I am a source
C are going to be correct.
So this means that I'm successfully
ignoring my
get in and out file
that are going to be do so at this point.
Are you guys with me?
Okay, I'm doing great. Still, guys.
I want you guys
to be with me to follow me.
We should all be on the same page
because this example is really important.
It's like a real time project.
This is how you guys
are working in your group.
Then you should include again.
Yes, I should applaud again.
That's like pretty simple.
If even if the code doesn't matter,
time is okay, it's going to be positive.
But try to meet with it.
So yes.
Okay.
I'll open up my get ignore
and I'll open up my good. So
I have a site
or something that they.
Okay, So are we good, All of us
start with ignore is working for me.
It's working for everyone else.
Most of five is not working for you.
Support is available
for whomever.
It's not working does support me.
Support is there.
Is there rest of there?
And by the way, if ignore is with touch
start being ignored.
If I can show you guys that's space.
Don't get ignored me come out.
Okay.
So if you type in the command,
it will work.
X y, you
okay?
So now what are we going to do?
We are going to be making
our very first kind of make.
Okay, so get at dot
and then get commit dash out.
Okay.
Now I'm
going to be working on a project, right?
So I am not going to be like
randomly just, you know, for myself.
I'm going to name them so that anyone new
who joins in on the project, he can also
I have a very good understanding
of what the comment is about.
So right now let's say that Solar System
basics specifications
added, and
I can see that
some features
now under development
Okay, so I've made my first commit
and it's still if I use get log
I'll be able to see it.
Okay let me know when you guys
what you guys have done to this point.
Up to that.
I'm going to
bother it.
I don't care for it to be that long.
Yes the commit message
guarantee of even 5 to 10 months.
Don't worry about that.
But obviously should not be.
That should be in the description,
but descriptive enough.
July one line is fine.
I'll show you the actual commits on the up
the zip freeze that we have
and you'll see how it works.
Okay, guys.
So it's very important that as we discuss,
we also draw the diagram.
So this is going to be our
first time
that we meet.
Dennis I just added the
I just did this.
I just added the project.
So I was expecting that
you guys are already familiar
with how you can read the comments.
So. That's right.
Okay.
So now we are going to talk about
what we have done.
So right now
we have made this one comment.
Let's call it C one.
Okay.
We're has discovered being made.
Do we have any branch right now?
Master Main on feature.
Have you created anybody?
No, we have not.
So if I sure you want
this.
See this master, Master,
Master.
By default,
if you are starting your project,
then by default your branch is main
master.
Okay. By default the first branch.
Whenever you start working, it's master
is people you
now we are familiar with this information.
What is this? Right?
This is a comment.
It's a code specific to this commit.
It's the output which is me
and my email address, date and time
and what does this hat master represent
that represents
that this particular commit
is in the working directory right now?
Okay.
No, it does not
only want to meet this to me
nice header
pointer mask
or it can point to some previous commit.
Also right now
applying to some previous commit.
Yes. Okay.
So will that sort of yours.
It points to last time.
It would be correct then.
No, it will not be correct and right.
Okay.
Let me quickly give you this example,
because I think a lot of you
are confused about this.
Okay. So let's say in this particular
branch master,
I see my head is pointing to C one.
What does this mean?
Quickly answer me as quickly.
What about the rest of you? We
have talk
about it right?
We have C 20.
I still had this one is the key one.
What does this mean? Yes.
Does It means that in working IP
we have c one.
Okay.
Now does not becomes a period.
It just means that in your working days,
you know,
your head is pointing to C one.
That's another discussion that becomes
apparent and then what to do with it.
But it's it's possible for you guys
to move your head back and get it.
You know, view
your previous comments that you have made.
It is possible
I shared the command with you guys.
I guess maybe I've ignored that in future.
You can try that up,
but it's possible for you to walk
through
the previous comments in the history.
So whenever had this blinding
to a particular command,
it means that that particular comment
is in your working directory.
And by default
it points to the latest coming right.
If you are not forcing it to blindly
either commit by default, it's going to be
it's going to meet.
Absolutely. Just kind of simple
makes sense.
So right now by default,
we are not forcing it to any previous one.
So it's going to be by default
on the latest coming.
So that is how it is working.
Okay.
So let's go back to this diagram.
And right now we have just made the C one,
only one. It
Yes, one.
We can move that back with us.
Yes, we can.
All we can do this.
I'll let you know.
Maybe if needed, but not right now.
I shared the command.
I'll shoot again, but not right now.
That's not important.
I don't want you guys
to be confused with it.
Okay? So.
Okay,
now let's start making our solar system
out of the sun.
Milky Way, dot, sun, z equals to one
Milky Way.
Dot moon is equal to two
and Milky Way dot planets
is equal to three.
Okay,
so now after this,
I guess my solar system is complete.
The basic structure is complete.
I'll run the code
and I'll say, okay, that's working
fine, working pretty good.
My requirement with the plan
set me that basic structure
of solar system.
It's complete,
so should have deployed now.
Yes, it's completed.
So I really want to deploy.
So what I'll do is I'll simply
make this final commit.
I'll say get that dog,
get commit dash and
the basic structure
is complete.
Okay, So now the basic structure
has been completed.
And if I do get logged,
it shows me to commit and had
Master is pointing to my latest coming.
Okay guys.
So this is what we have done so far.
Any questions that you guys have?
So this one.
Okay.
Everything good? I can show the time.
Up till now
we have not uploaded our code to GitHub.
Everything that we have done is local
to our own machine.
We will send it to get help now
so that the end user, the client, can
use that particular code
to run his solar system,
which contains the basic specifications.
Does that clear?
Okay. So just
I'll have a five minute break
and then who is the problem with it?
So anyone who is left behind
please help out each other to come
to this point
and move quickly to see my happens.
Okay, so
we have that.
Okay, guys.
So let's begin from very glad now.
Right now two commits have been made
and now what we are going to do,
we are going to have our code
on the GitHub, make it live.
So open up here.
We have a balance
and let's create
a new representative.
So I want everyone to create their own
repository on their own GitHub account,
name, Explorer system,
whatever you want to make it public
as call theater repository.
Okay?
Now what we need to do is establish
the connection
between our local and remote.
So for that purpose we use the command
git remote at origin with the address.
Right. So It's going to live here.
I can simply copy it.
But the good practices to type it down
because that's how you remember.
Okay.
So that remote at Origin,
the connection has established.
Now I want to make sure that a connection
has been established.
How can I check that?
Get the mode that that's perfect.
And if I want to remove this connection
and add another connection
of a new repository, can I do that?
If I want to remove this
particular connection and connect this?
But it would just be to another
new repository that I created.
And I do that. Yes.
Do you guys remember the command for that
project?
Okay, now,
now the command that is left for later
discussion.
I'll just told you that.
I'll let you know what that
What is this command for.
We'll be discussing that get branch
dash and main.
So what is this command for.
What's going to to
what is the purpose of this command.
So using this class we are naming
the boss
that we will be sending on GitHub.
We are naming it
main. So
okay, now can I name it any other
rather than me.
Cannot name it.
No branch or any and anything?
Yes, I can name anything but right now
what should I naming
name? Why?
Because this is my branch
which contains the basic
our system which I want to deploy.
So that's why remember
only that's why I'm naming it main.
Okay, so now we see that
the name over here, it changed to Main.
It means that
everything that we will be doing
now is going to be in the main
branch. Yep.
I believe I can do that
using the same command.
Yes I can. If I use the same matter I can
master.
I mean are good reference
to the same branch, but GitHub is now
free to use the main instead of master.
So we will be using main.
Yes, you can change it if you want to.
You can change any.
But once you have uploaded it
then do not change the name yet.
Massive software.
But GitHub is looking more and more.
I mean
maybe because of Master
and the police to slavery that I'm just
guessing.
Okay.
So once we have executed it
this then the next come out.
What is that?
What is our next combat
get pushed that's new origin
Main Now can you just tell me that
what could happen if I just use get push,
let it work? No.
Can you tell me that it will not work?
The branch mean has no upstream branch.
It means
that the
boss that you are trying to push it.
This thing that I cannot find this branch
anywhere on the guitar.
So first of all, you have to create that
branch over there also.
So whenever you push for the first time,
you use get
pushed back to our origin main
and the next time you push
you can simply use force.
Now, does it make sense that
why do we have to use git push?
That's your main for the first time.
I hope that's the end now.
So lot of things would be making sense
to all of you now.
Okay, so that's done.
Very good.
Let me open up my
let me press it.
Okay.
Now I have one branch,
which is my main branch
and everything is there. Oh,
well, now, good.
That is because you have get lost
some of it.
Should we get Dash main
most of our.
Do you want me to repeat
that new origin?
Because the first time you tried to push
you have no branch
available on new and more
so you to create the remote branch.
Also you have to let it know that
the main branch has to be there
when you are pushing the very first time.
That's
you use get pushed out for the first time.
Next time you can simply use
get that get push.
It will work.
Okay, so to this one I will done.
Okay, great.
Now let's do one.
Let's do get long.
What is this now?
What is this?
Or just let me.
It was not appearing before.
I don't see any. You just left me above.
But now I see this.
Why is it here?
Okay, so it is showing
us that in working directory
I would I local represent tree
and our remote repository
the boolean or synchronize.
So tell me if this origin slash me
was in front of this particular command,
then what would it have meant
if, for instance, less mean
what's in front of this particular commit?
Then what will it mean?
We did not was the last of it.
Yes, it means that.
Okay, I'll repeat again before just last
name is over here
instead of here it means that
our remote top of the tree is in sync
with the local only to this coming
and the last commit that is
there is not present overview.
Does that make sense to all of you?
Let me quickly
give you a pictorial representation also.
But can
so over here
you can see this
example that are just left master is
here we are as at master is above
this means that the one in this example
is always
synchronized with
the first commit and the second
is not the.
Yeah, a lot of times
are going to be to the door.
We now let's move
probably will be deployed our water system
basically it was working perfectly fine
but what happened
our team did call in and he said that now
client wants you to work on the feature,
a new feature,
and he wants you to work on some.
He wants you to develop
that feature of this particular sort
of system.
Okay, So before we actually do that, let's
see how it will be done.
So far.
Access to it.
What's that, Jimmy?
Are you going to fast?
I believe that you are going
to press. Yep.
Just go down.
We are not in a hurry right?
Yeah, I heard about it.
Do you guys want to break
before we let you have some?
Okay, so let's go for a break.
For how many minutes do you want?
But then let's make it 15.
Okay, let's.
Let's go for 15.
After the break.
We are going to handle this time.
So it's 25, 35 and 40.
Okay.
So I guess that all of you are here
and let's receive that very loud.
Okay.
So I task to start
working on a new feature set.
So first of all,
I want you guys to tell me that what
if I started working over here
and created a new
which contains the feature,
so why should I not do this?
Why I should not start working on the mean
branch?
The feature already exists.
Does it?
Regardless of that
sun is there,
but the feature is not complete yet.
It's just the sun.
Yes, because the reason is
that while working on
the main branch, I may
disturb the previous code.
It's not going to be
that much simple, right?
It's going to be quite complicated
to other muscle systems.
So it's highly recommended.
Never in fact not recommended.
It's a must that you should never work
on a main branch.
That's a no no.
Okay. So what we will do,
we will create a new branch
from this point
and you will name it
feature son or son.
What I want.
Let's name it just son.
Okay.
As soon as I create this box,
all the code that is in see through
it will take a snapshot of that code
and bring it into my new branch.
So let's go ahead
and do that now
in parallel log after.
But in parallel to C2.
Okay.
So if I do give log,
my head is pointing towards
this personal commit, right?
My head, this one,
he can do this, but he's not coming.
So now if I do,
if I create a new boss,
it would be created
at this particular point from the head.
It will be created for this point.
So let's create a new box.
And how do we do that?
Good.
Branch one
star.
Okay, so running this command is going
to do what it's going to create.
The branch, the branches.
Okay.
But I still the main ribbon over here.
Why is that so?
No, that's not the reason.
That is for renaming.
Exactly. So
once we
have created the branch,
then we need to switch to that
particular branch
in order to be able to work over there.
So what we will do, we will switch to that
match using the command,
get check out some
not safe switch to work on.
And now I can see, son,
we're going over here
to you.
How do you know it's lost location
you are in.
It will be
evident.
It will be written in brackets or here.
Apart from that,
we also have a command for Mac users.
I guess
it branch.
And the one with this stack
is going to show you your current branch.
Okay, so Mac users,
you can use this skip much.
It's going to show you a street
son. It's
actually the joker branch
to which you are checking.
You have checked out
right?
Okay.
So tell this point.
Are we all good?
Okay, great.
Now let's open up our intelligent.
Do we have all the code that we had
in the last commit over here?
Do we have all of that?
Yes, we have.
So now let's
go ahead and start doing this.
Let's create a new class.
Let's call it Sun
now. Let's start working on it.
So I'm going to write down
some Cool away here and
I may have the heat
temperature
and radius.
These are key features
that we will be assigned to our sun.
Okay.
So first of all, I'm
going to tell you guys that
never, never
do any additions
to include you, okay?
Remember we discussed that
we are not focusing on the code, right?
So that would be strange.
It doesn't matter.
Know, cancel it.
Cancel it.
Never had it from the intelligent.
Yes. Okay.
Now what are we going to do?
We will go to our main code
and we will be adding our sun over here.
Awesome.
So sun, what should we name our sun
Solana.
Okay, Husband.
Well, that's okay.
When you will be adding,
you already have added.
So that won't create a difference.
But next time,
please try to cancel that option.
Okay, so let's get solar on it.
Features Solana dot he equals to
Jones and let's say Solana dawn
radius equals to
Nicolas and Solana.
Temperature is equal to
Oh okay.
So to this point I'm all good.
Let me know once you are done with this.
No, let it be like this.
You do not have to make string.
Let it be an integer.
I did that on purpose.
Okay, so let's say that
I was working over here
and I completed this feature
and obviously it's not going to be
this like four lines of code. It's
going to be quite a huge number of lines
which are going to be here.
And I ran the code.
I knew some features were working fine,
but a few were not working fine.
I was getting some errors,
so I decided to resolve this error.
But I don't know where the error is yet.
We are assuming
that this is a complicated code.
Okay, so what should I do?
I start manipulating things in this
in this code and, you know,
try to resolve my error over here.
Or should I
follow a different approach,
assuming that.
Okay, I'll repeat.
Let's assume
that this code is very complicated.
There are 1000 lines in this code.
Few of our features are working fine,
but few features are giving errors
and we want to resolve the error.
Okay, so obviously I'll want that
my whole remains preserve
and then am also able to resolve the bugs
which are there.
So what should I do?
First of all, I need to save the school
right.
First of all, I need to save this.
So for that
purpose I'll have to make a comment
on this
particular.
So let's go ahead and commit
the code that we have written.
So one thing we should make sure of,
we are on the same branch
on which we are working.
So I'm on Sun
and I'm going to make a comment on Sun.
So I would say get at Dot,
get comment on
and what's the message
that I should place over here
feature Sun
set items
to be resolved.
Now this makes sense that I mentioned
that there are still errors
that need to be resolved
in this particular feature,
and I'm going to tell you
why it's important to place this message.
You let me know what you that are done
to this point.
Okay.
Now, one of the intelligent thing to do
before we start working
on, you know,
resolving the issue,
one of the intelligent thing to do
is to push our branch
here the good to. Why?
Because it's quite possible
that one of my colleagues
who has some extra free time,
he wants to help me out.
As soon as he sees my comment, he says,
okay, so he's having some problem.
Why don't I try to help him out
and he can download my Branch
on his computer and then try to resolve
the errors that I did.
Yeah, really nice guy.
He is and she is.
And that must be very right.
Absolutely.
We are going to switch again.
So, you know.
Okay. So
how do I send this now to GitHub
pushing.
Okay, so what does the command get push.
Is it going to
get pushed.
Okay guys,
remember the concept that I told you
that we use
get pushed that you are in the main
the first time.
So right now do we have any sun
on GitHub?
Although we have the wrap
but we have only bright sun,
so how will get know to which run?
It has to push.
So right now will you get
push that you are original sun.
And for those of you who are saying
different dash and that is for renaming
the branch okay remember that
officer
everything combined upside to my GitHub.
Let me hear you were there.
If I it.
I see two branches
main and sun.
Okay.
So is that the scenario with all of you?
Okay, now let me show you some
few things on GitHub before we move on.
Resolving the error.
If I click on the sun
I will see the commit that is there
feature sun with errors to be resolved.
It's the code that there.
Okay, I can switch to my main branch also
and it's to have its
it does not have that particular comment.
Okay.
Now let's do one thing
let's create a new branch
at this point to resolve the issue.
Now let's name
resolving
the issue are bug fix.
It's going to be more you know more
good to name of this.
So we are fixing about
okay now
I need to be very vigilant
that I am on the same branch
if I want to create a new branch
from over there
because if I create this
so if I create this branch but fixed
after switching to, it's
going to create a new branch complete. Do
you guys agree with that?
If I switch to Main branch
and then I create
bug fixed, it's
going to be created from this point.
But right now
you want to create a positive tree.
So I need to make sure
that I am to see secret.
So for that I can use get branch.
Okay.
So yes, I am on the sun
and now I can create a new branch
from this particular point.
In order to do that I said get branch
but fix up.
I'll press enter.
I could create the new branch.
Now I need to switch to that.
So for that get shutdown
but fix.
Okay guys.
So I have successfully switch
to the branch
bug fix
and now what
code is going to be there in the bug fix.
Get someone tell me
I open up the simulation.
What code is going to be there
in the bug? Fix
the copy of
the must see tree?
Yes. Perfect.
Let me open up my intelligence.
Let me show you.
Yes. The task.
The same errors.
No. You know, I spent, let's say
5 hours working on this code,
trying to resolve the errors,
find different techniques,
changing the loose declaration stuff.
And finally, I was able fix
my error.
My error is fixed now.
Now, what should I do
once the error is fix? Yes,
we are.
Obviously I run the code.
Okay, so the first step is to commit it
on the same branch.
I need to commit it
so I'll be committing it
in order to save it.
So let's
go ahead and commit this code yet and not
get comment.
That's
the issues in feature
one has been resolved.
Okay,
let me know once you guys are done
to this point.
Okay, guys,
I'll like to mention one very important
help and one very important tip over here.
If you guys accidentally say the doubt
committed,
it's going to cause a lot of problems.
First of all, get
will try to refrain from doing that.
But in some scenarios
it may not be able to save you
and it might switch
you back to your previous launch.
And that is going to create a problem.
It will, you know, mix up all the codes
and then you will have to use testing and
complicated stuff.
So always make your code before
you try to actually
not not get it before
you try to push the branch.
Okay.
The beauty I'd like to mention
one thing over here.
Also, the beauty of branches is that
let's say you are working on Future Sun
and there was still a bug
which had to be fixed,
but you had no time to fix it.
And meanwhile
a new feature is a high priority game.
So you will leave this branch as it is
and you can simply create a new branch
out of it and start working on it
because that was a high priority feature.
So that that makes sense to us. You
that's how you can work on priority
and get your code is safe there.
You can simply start working
on some other high priority feature.
So that's the power
and that's the advantage
that it gives you.
Okay, so
yes, for Hot Menu,
for that, you have to switch to Main
to create a new branch from over.
Do exactly.
Yeah. There you go.
Yes, I'm in the past because
I have to move very stepwise
and I need to decide information
should I get
first and then, you know,
which information should I go second.
So just making that in real time.
Okay.
Is there a way to see the hierarchy
of the branches?
Well, Mohammed, that is something
that I will be teaching you,
but that's a little bit complicated.
So whenever you are working on branches,
I'll always recommend
that you draw your branches on paper.
Okay, I'll recommend that.
It's a little bit complicated
when you go into the hierarchy.
Okay, So let's do gift log.
At this point.
So we see that this is our master
branch and it is updated
on GitHub, This is our sun branch
and it is updated to
but this boss does not have any origins.
Let me sorry, I just left properly.
Meaning that we do not have it on the.
Yes. So with that it will.
So do
you guys think that we need to send this
go back to beta?
No, we don't need that.
Okay guys, now what we are going to do
is something really, really important.
We are actually going to do a merge. Yes.
So because it's a bug fix
and we have fixed it on our local machine,
while we might only want above zero
GitHub, no need.
Right.
So it's also important
not to have redundant branches on GitHub.
All we have was branches
which are important for your colleagues
and for your own self.
Okay. Now merging
because we are done
with resolving that bug,
we want to merge
that particular commit to our sun branch.
Okay.
Now in our lives,
let me give you two steps
to merge a branch
switch to better and branch
use. Get
once they love branch
you want to merge.
Okay. So do not do the merge right now.
First I want to explain shootings.
Okay.
So the code in C3 and C4. It's
quite similar.
I'm going to copy this. Good.
From c4 of guys.
So this is the pool of C4.
I guess you would see it are two smart
oak and the code that we have in C3.
I'm going to place it here and it's just
this, right?
The rest of the classes are standard.
There is no other difference.
Do you guys all agree with that? Yes.
Okay, so now let's
go to our terminal,
and the first step is to
check out
to Sun
and make sure that you are
on the Sun branch by gate branch.
That should show you that sun. The sun.
Now you get large
but fixed
and took
this command, run it and then let me know
and we can have a discussion on it.
Okay.
So first of all, I'd like to like to ask
you which branch is going to be there
on my intelligent.
It's going to be sun, right?
Because we check to it.
Let's open up our intelligent
and have a look at the
is the code
free of errors?
Yes, it is free of errors.
And for those of you who it's not for you,
as you might have not done
anything correctly, I know which step
you missed, which step you did wrong
takes details
from the simple.
Okay, now what we are going to do
is we are going to discuss that.
What actually happened.
So let's read.
What does this say?
It says that updating
and the commit numbers.
Fast forward
fast.
So it is the kind of mode strategy
that it uses
on its own.
It's similar strategy.
So one of the months
that we will be reading,
we will be learning as fast power much
better did some insertions and changes
that is mentioning
that we are not interested in.
So now let's have a look
at the fast of That's
how it actually works.
So for now I don't need these codes.
I'll maybe meet them later, so I'll just
minimize that.
Okay guys.
So it's now we will be learning faster,
much faster than most.
What happens is that
get sent me
some branch which we are trying to merge
and places this comment
over here
and just you create it.
Start pointing towards C for
that's a fast,
slower, much.
Okay.
So in a fast follows what happens is that
get simply some of the branch
that which we are emerging
it picks up the comment on that
and the last comment
in the branch
to which we are merging starts
pointing to that particular commit
which is the final one
noble I'm
going to come to that of.
Is this clear to everyone
that what it is doing
right now?
Okay.
Now the discussion
that we are going to have next
is not, you know, necessary
it is not necessary,
but I will still have this conversation
with you guys because I really want you
to how this merger is happening.
You just you find it very complicated.
Just don't go deep
into that, okay.
So that's just a disclaimer
that I'm going to give you guys.
Okay.
So first of all, I'm
going to ask him a question.
So he stated that wasn't it better
if we didn't create fix
but simply correct our code and submit
and commit in a spell in sound runs.
So how will you reply to Hammer?
What about you guys?
What what will you say to him?
Exactly?
So the answer is that I told you that
this particular code is just three lines,
but we are assuming it's a code
which has 1000 lines.
It's a complicated code
and we are unable to solve it.
And some of the features are working,
some are not.
And if start messing up over there,
it may affect our other features
which are working fine, right?
And we don't want do that.
So that's why I created this scenario.
And as an example,
I had to do this for this simple good.
So right now our focus is not the code,
rather the use case
and how we can use
get to come to the solution.
I hope you're persistent.
Now. Okay, guys.
So let's talk
a little bit about Master Remus.
We will be doing
looking at this kind of merge
a lot.
Maybe the Situation Company wants
to have a larger story
of all bugs and different specifics.
But trust me,
no company wants to have a branch
with the story of bugs
right there in the first place.
They want not have a
What they don't like is
they don't want to keep a story of that
above like.
Yeah.
Okay.
So let me tell you
how good actually does this get.
Remember
The purpose whole purpose of using data
is that it is very effective
in the terms of managing your memory.
Right.
We discussed this in starting off,
but when we were discussing getting
the first class in the second class,
if you do it manually, this kind of stuff
is going to take a lot of space.
If you start to copy and paste
everything, get is very intelligent
and then we management
for harder
and then you are going to make do for us
just, just great
help you guys. So
this is very efficient
in memory management.
So let me tell you what it actually does.
I'm telling you this because when you
looking at the law, you will be seen.
You will be able to see it
instead of placing this command
in front of people.
What in the US. Exactly.
It's simply after secrete, it
creates a point to
and commits it.
Start pointing to this particular commit
which is on bug fix.
This commit is going to be there but
it will appear
as if after secret the next commit.
See for that's
how it is managing your memory.
So just a little
you know behind the scenes beads
but conceptually you do that
get you know moves this commit
down here and starts pointing towards
this is what we will say concept to
okay one more time I will.
So I said that
when we merge and a fast queremos
get behind the scene
after scene three
it simply starts working towards see for,
this is what happens.
So that now what?
So that now
the sea floor does not have to make
a copy of it and place it inside of sun.
That's the reason to save memory.
But we will not go along with this.
Rather, we will say that conceptually
for our own understanding,
we will say that it simply moves
this commit
if of
this that you do all of you.
Okay,
so let's open up our console.
Let's clean everything.
Now let's do get long
now. Let's
try to see the number of comments
that we have.
We have one, two, three, four.
You have four comments.
And if I show you in the diagram,
how many more commits do we have?
One, two, three, four comments.
Right.
We have four commits in the diagram.
Also.
And if I show you
the latest commit
in which the issues in the Future Fund
has been resolved, what it is doing,
it's pointing the hot sun
and the fixed Bo-Kaap
want to do the same comment
at sun and not face.
They are both pointing
to the same comment.
Is this to everyone?
Okay, so now I tried to,
you know, change the diagram a little bit.
Can I do this?
Because we are having four comments.
So can I do this?
Not makes more sense. Right?
The sun is also pointing
to see for the last commit
and but this is also pointing to super.
Okay.
Now let me show you a
quick slide for
fast forward much
so this is how a forward must work.
This is one approach
and this is a separate launch
when the first problem happens
simply that second.
But that whole lot is right
in front of the last two,
which we are merging.
So any number of commits
that are going to be there,
that branch are also going to be there in.
The grass to which we are merging
get does this to maintain history.
Okay, is this everyone?
Are we all good? Them
Great.
So now tell me a scenario.
Let's go ahead with the scenario.
What If our bug fix actually took
1 to 3 commits,
what if this was a sniper
and now we merged it to
the sun?
So tell me there will be key points to.
Battle this three point.
Okay. So what's what's the issue
and when did that read my exact
same words?
The exact same words.
This is the branch
and we created a new branch out of it.
When I fast forward
merge is going to happen.
The other boss,
all the commits of that branch are going
to be simply brought under the grass
to which we are merging.
These are the same exact words
that I said.
So now I'll ask the question again.
There were secret planning.
Yes, it will point to C4
and then there will be C five
and see all these commit
are automatically going to be a part
of Sun branch. Agree
it's going to be something like this. Now
now in your son branch the latest commit
it sees things and get all come and gain
deep history
okay I want your thumbs up
if you understand
faster much 100%
okay right.
It really happens.
Okay now one more concept
that we need to learn about.
Fast forward much.
So we said that
this was
the last summit
of garage
complete points
to the summit
D child
march.
When does
a fast rather large happen in
Westminster?
When does a fast forward much have?
This is bottom
okay so a fast car loads is only
is only going to take place.
It's there and over here
when you created branch
and when we tried to merge it back
the history of that particular
branch was not updated.
So we can see that
when this but textbook created
it remember that we see if the queen
now when you will be merging with logic
that is the history still see three
If the answer is yes
it will say do the fast forward much
and that you
now let's consider another scenario.
And that that scenario
is that while we were working on
but fixed due to some reason
another comment was made on simply
this can happen right there right
this can happen
now tell me
when we tried to merge but fixed to sign
when I fast forward merge happen
get is going to check
whether the history is still complete. No.
Now the history has been updated
and it c files it will say no.
It's not simply no effect
for in this kind of scenario.
In this kind of scenario
another merging technique is used
which you'll be learning shortly.
Okay.
So what's your question? You'll be to
why we
should be the history.
Okay.
So when this was much this was created,
what was the history,
the Latest is to
what you create
when we created this what what
the latest is basically
yes commit this free something.
Right.
Okay.
Yeah.
So that's why it's checking
that whether the history
has been updated or under new commits yet.
So history has
it's I'm going to interchanged these words
so don't be confused by it.
When I say history, I need comments.
Okay.
Is that understood to everyone
now that when a fast forward
merge will happen and let it flow on?
Is it clear to everyone?
Okay, very good. Great.
So let's go down to the scenario
which we were discussing,
and that's the current situation
of our everything
right.
Okay.
Now if you
want to leave bug fix,
we can simply delete that.
And from that we have a command.
What's, what's that?
And someone tell me delete a branch,
get lost ASCII
and the name.
Okay, so we deleted the branch
but fix and it's gone.
Now. If I do get branch
it only two branches
which is main and some
and my code is still intact.
Okay. No, this guy's a left.
He wants to get done with it.
Yes. Delete the branch
and no.
Then get done with it.
So now if I want to remove this
bug fixed,
I'll simply delete it from over here
like this
as this c for going to be the error,
delete it.
I'm not
going to be there, but
okay.
Let me open up my
logs so get logged
in the log.
I see that the sun is pointing
to this particular command
that is in the feature.
Some have been resolved,
but My origin sun is on the commit
feature sun As to the result,
what does this
mean?
There there there was said.
Okay, I'm going to repeat my question.
My question is that had
sun is here
like on the last commit that we need
which is the issue issue in feature
set have been resolved
but not urgent sun is to be just sun
with address to be resolved.
So what does it mean?
Yes, that means that
on GitHub the branch sun is only updated
to this particular command
and this command is not yet updated or do
so if you want to update on Origin
slash sun, which is a more transitory,
we should push this coming out
so that we know who that which command
am I going to use.
Get pushed simply that it's going to work.
So you good that you were asking that
ideally we should delete the branch one
what's most
obvious so you'll be that is
asking that should be deleted
a branch once it's most.
Well this totally depends upon you guys.
Like I do not need that launch right now.
It's like I resolve the error.
I deleted it. Right.
But most probably I will not be meeting
future sun
until I have a doubt
that there might be some new features
that are changes that I still need to make
in this particular branch.
So even if you don't believe it,
it doesn't matter.
It's not.
We do like we Contagios
just keep it local.
Don't send it during more.
Okay. Now to two branches.
May and sun are there
perfect.
Okay guys.
So let's have a look
at the requirements again.
The requirement said that
we are committed to Sun.
How we can that feature
successfully We can begin to.
Yes, we have.
So now
what should we do?
This domain and merge.
Okay, so here is a rule
that I'm going to tell you.
Never merge to Main branch.
Okay, So that's the rule
that you have to implement by heart.
And a lot of you
a lot of you are going
do this and good projects.
You are going to merge in me
and then you request me
to create a new project for you guys
because I cannot undo that.
Okay?
It will not be possible
for me to undo your merge.
So I'm again mentioning it.
Please, none of you should merge
or push in the master.
That's a humble request because that is
going to cost you and me a lot of effort.
I won't be able to merge.
Does that you to all of you
write it down on a notepad
it on just please do whatever
make whatever out of it
and have it pasted on your desktop. Me
Oh yeah.
We only system mean and continue
with the project.
No, you never work in me.
I was working in May.
Now once we uploaded the basic structure
have we yet worked on mean?
No. We will ever be working on me.
Never.
Okay, so now I'm going to teach you
that procedure.
Yes. Come on, dude, just.
Just give me some time.
We have to.
But they are the other requirements.
Can you show me the step where you merge?
But fix that sun
No, Muhammad Unfortunately,
I don't have that.
But so you just missed the whole fun part.
Okay,
So let's go ahead and do this cool request
and let's see that what what happens.
So now I was working on this feature.
I'm done.
And I'm sure that's working fine.
I'll say, okay,
I want it to be merged to me.
So for that purpose, what we do
is we go to create a pull request.
So what's a pull requests?
Upload request is a request to the
person who is
in charge of merging the branches
to merge the branch
that we are requesting.
So open up
the pull request
and then it'll set new pull request.
So we are creating a new pull request.
Okay.
So which is going to be our
base branch, it's going to be made
and which is going to be our branch
which we want to merge.
That's going to be sun.
Okay. After that
it is also would
show us the difference
that we have in the files.
We have like some additional records
in this file
and some of these records in a new file
that's visible to us on GitHub.
And then you say
create upload request.
Okay.
After clicking on create upload request,
we will write something over here
after
the week is posted a message
and then it will go to review. Is
over here.
We are going to assign it
to some anyone to review.
Now I do not have any person
working on this requisite
to give me the all user
so I cannot see anything.
Okay.
But when you will be working on
collaboration, you will see the username
which you can
assign it to.
Yes, I, I have done that.
Asylees here on set you will
the people you want to assign it
to labels.
It's a bug, it's a documentation, it's
a duplicate enhancement.
For me.
I would say it's an enhancement, right?
It's a new feature.
So I placed it
in the label Enhancement Project.
I do not have any project name off.
Let's just keep it empty.
Milestone.
Nothing like this.
You know.
Okay, so after that,
simply click on Create for request.
So now time you guys ask me
about these things that we discussed.
What I did review is assigns labels
projects.
Yes. Okay, good.
And just simply click on Create requests.
Okay.
After that, just click on Little System
again and go back to your main branch.
Let me know what you have done.
Now, what will happen?
A notification will go to the owner of
the app, the who is in charge of merging.
You'll see that there is a pull request.
We will see
pull request one
will simply click on that.
It will show us that
there is a pull request
which is of design.
And if I put my point over the
it shows me the message and shows me that
which what do I want to merge?
I simply open it.
I say, okay,
so this is the conversation that we have.
These are the two comments
that this bunch has.
And I would say, okay, let's do thing,
let's have a look at files.
So I'll have a look at the code.
I'll say, okay, working fine.
It seems to be working fine.
I'm not yet, you know, run the school.
So it totally depends upon me now
how much I trust the person
who has said the code.
I can either download it
on my own system, run it,
and then choose to merge,
or if I trust that person,
I would just have a hard
look at it but not actually run it.
And just much
so that totally depends upon me.
Also you both methods how to do that,
because I do recommend
that whenever you are merging
in your work projects out of the command
that you always do not trust
but verify before much.
So right now I trust myself.
This code is pretty simple,
so I'll say Yeah, good, good jobs.
I say go to the commit.
And over here I see multiple requests
and then I'll say
confirm loads.
So what we did, we most of the branch
into our main branch
and if I show you now the latest commit is
the issue in the feature
son have been resolved
and it contains all the complete code
and the new feature of Sun.
No, you cannot tested on GitHub.
Which version do you want me to repeat?
Because we are.
I said a lot of things.
You have to code.
Which one do you want me to repeat?
The whole request
offer.
Click on what the request has gone.
That's I was a little slow
when we were able to follow
what I did.
Why was a fast
I Unfortunately, the pull request is gone.
It cannot be undone.
I told you, but I'll let you.
Let's do this.
I created dummy branch.
Okay.
No, no, no.
I'll create a dummy by five five.
Okay. But
no one is going to follow me on this.
I sure am.
I hear about it.
In fact, let me use this.
This. This picture. I think that's good.
Okay, so you guys have done it
on this one, right?
No one is behind this.
So. Okay, That is is behind this.
Okay.
So those of you who are over here,
you need to click on conversation.
Okay?
Once you click on conversation,
you will see
this particular picture.
And from this picture
you need to simply click
on most full request and confirm it.
It will pull it.
Okay, So
let me know if it's done for all of you.
How to open up the pool request.
Simply click on pool request
and there will be a pull request
on that and it will open up
the pool request.
I thought that I was going to look
honestly, I caught that.
But unfortunately, I think that I
underestimated
or maybe something
I don't know.
Yeah, okay.
I don't really need it yet.
You know, I was not asked that.
That cannot be true.
I'm sure about it.
Okay, let's do our morning.
So those of you who say I was fast,
give me a thumbs up.
Let's see, how many do I get?
I'm expecting only two or three.
One to
have a set of two.
Three or five.
Okay. I'm sorry.
Okay.
Are you all done with the full request?
Try to.
The most of anyone was left
with a pool request.
We will be doing
it more so don't worry. You
got So we have to just simply merge it.
It's.
We will be doing pool request
a lot of times. Don't worry about it.
If anyone still didn't get the concept
that how it's working,
I'll make sure that you get in
by the end of you doing a lot of practice.
Okay.
Don't worry.
Okay. Yeah.
I'll try to work on that door.
Okay, So now let's go ahead and discuss
this concept.
We get a merge on the
get up right?
But we are not going to leave it
like that.
You understand the concept that behind
which kind of must happen
and how it happened.
We have to understand
the first of all,
I want you guys to tell me that
which my strategy
is going to be followed.
Yes. Okay.
So when I'm merging master,
the terminology used to come, it's
that it's a little bit different.
But for now, looking at this diagram,
I really want you guys to tell
that which strategy will be followed.
Fast forward like that.
So it means that the to
something like this is going to happen
right?
Right.
And I want you to tell me this, that if
there has been another comment, meanwhile.
Well, I will be able to go to
using fast much.
No, I would like to right
perfect.
I'm really glad
that you guys are understanding fast.
So good.
And the last thing about fast Our life
which I want you guys
to, is that it's going to be a question,
is there ever going to be a conflict?
Then you do a fast forward merge.
Don't answer me.
Just think of like
everyone is saying no.
Is there anyone who thinks that
there need be?
Is there maybe person?
I mean, you did that for fun, right?
And my name you two.
Okay, so we discussed that
conflict arises where?
So the
question was that will there be conflict
that our there will be a faster merge.
Will you have a conflict
as you did something wrong?
You cannot have a conflict
if you don't have a conflict.
If it's a fast forward
much, I'll show you.
I'll prove it to you. Why?
Okay, so we discussed that.
When does a conflict, other conflicts
occur then
on one line there was something,
and now on another line
there is something else.
And get us confused
with line to keep right.
This is a scenario
and a positive difference, right.
But we saw that in a fast forward.
Give us simply, you know,
pointing towards other it is not even,
you know, merging in actual anything.
It's not doing an actual merge.
So what do you guys think
is going to be a conflict?
No, it will not be.
So now, I hope that you guys do understand
that no conflicts
and a fast was simply it's going to start
pointing towards your final comment
and that's okay.
So you can see that
your data is going to be overwritten.
The data is going to
be overwritten if you change
if you made some changes
on the same line.
So on the same line in The Boss,
we had no one got call us
and then we merged it out of that
all over again.
Right?
This is what happened.
Okay.
So when there is no conflict
that's must take place, no harm.
That's wrong. That's totally wrong.
Faster modes
takes place in this particular condition.
The scenario you are saying is different.
There might be a possibility
that a faster remote is not possible,
but also there is no conflict.
There will be having a look at that.
No word. Okay, guys.
So I think things are pretty much
straightforward up till this point
and I think complicated.
Everything is going smoothly
as far as ideas.
Now I really want to hear from your side.
Is that the scenario or I stuck
in the branches?
Obviously it's not. That's great.
When are we supposed to
have our next quick?
Is it all in the time
and really want you to tell me?
Because after that
you're going to have no break, right?
And it's going to be class.
It's going to end at three right?
30 minutes.
Rick Seriously, dude, that's
what's up there.
Okay, so those are just six.
Let's meet at
a new light in 20, please.
Not 30.
Okay, Let's do it later. This way.
How about that?
That's okay.
I really want to spend a lot of time
giving you a lot of examples.
That's why
I'm not going to give you, again, give 30,
but obviously that it will come
at some time out of the examples.
Yeah.
So 20, is that right?
So one
look it's not going to 120 12.
116 but yeah,
it's one 1639 and 116
All good.
118 Come on
break two 118 But
yes I said sure, why not.
Tell me what's the problem.
I think I just learned step. Which one.
Well first of all telling me that
at which point you left the class
because then I'll help you.
You're on the great breaker one. It.
I did not see my son and above six
but in the local or under law,
you see them on the local.
Okay so I said you see your
boss that
never sent me this horrible five
seven screenshot
you miss Very.
My son did not fix the lead.
Okay, so send screenshot of your terminal
and then I can suggest you some time
so that you can get caught up.
I saw this one thing. I seen it.
This is going to take a lot of time.
What? Really?
You have to watch this part of the class
because if you left, there are some
resources that have to do.
But the
rest of the steps that will be following,
they obviously are going to be isolated
from this one and then to building.
And you can have this good thing
from there you can proceed.
So I'll teach you how you do that.
Open this link,
closed this repository, and
then I'll tell you what to do next.
Don't disappear that quickly.
I know that you
the next steps on teaching
so let's not do this
because a lot of students
will be confused by this.
I shall just
personally write in the comments that.
But you need to do
all the rest of
to create a new
who on the top
for this project me
remove
the lecture from you
look through
the syntax
you to your
new I would
also you
need to follow these steps
and they will actually give you
the same code as I have
the same permits as I have.
And it would also make
you push your code to get out of here
or just make sure that you create
a new requisite three new
or more preposition and just make sure
that you add this connection to the local.
Okay,
that's going to work from here onwards.
You can just, you know, easily follow up.
Yes, I issues that No, I'll just come back
from the break in five or 10 minutes.
So I should
So in step three actually means that
the client is already connected to
my GitHub
because you go in my opposite group.
So you need to remove that connection
and add the connection of that.
Does that make sense?
Okay, so this is what you need to do.
Just like Alex,
you are able to understand me.
I am unable to extend the person. Mark
So We
need to be more precise about things.
Yes, it has to
what we need to do.
Nothing else.
Just Aisha.
We are on break and I think we are done.
Okay, perfect.
That's. That's good.
Okay, now the next topic
that we are going to dive into is
going to be
still the browsers.
Okay?
But other examples
and other kind of scenarios that we face,
we have to discuss them here.
Okay.
So let's start from this point.
Something fucking do today.
A function is something that
that I don't teach in the schools.
Actually
existing.
I don't teach stacks
the well I honestly meant
that we do not discuss out for free,
but somehow
it turned into this kind of use.
So how do you address
one thing for playing?
I can
give you an overview about
that something that most we really don't
what we need for the project. So
that's why I just to me
maybe I'll see if it needs
to be floated out
Now let's get back to our example
that we were running
and let's try to complete that.
So a lot of practice, a lot of practice
practice.
Let's do one thing now.
Let's switch to our
master.
Let's
start with me.
Okay, So now I am in Main branch.
If I up my intelligent
device, see this much updated.
Sorry.
Like is it updated with the remote
repository?
Is this much updated with that
in what not?
It's not in order to make sure that
what we need to do is get this command
is therefore
making sure that it's updated,
are not updated
or not
with command.
We use to see that our local wrap
as it is updated with the remote
is sent with the remote.
The command for that
that law and one other command
that I taught you is get set.
And what I see, no, no way.
Get facts right, never get fresh
tells us if there is any updated
that needs to be pulled.
So yeah,
I see that my new branch has some updates
which I do not have locally.
If I didn't get law
at this point
I just see two commits and nothing else.
So it's not giving me sufficient
information right?
It's not giving sufficient information.
So the correct amount
that you should always use
when you are checking that
if there is an update in
the remote repository is get fetch.
What happened to get such
system?
Now it's not working.
What have.
Yeah,
I think that is something new for me too
because I never did that check it twice
so. Well.
Okay. Yeah.
So that means that once
we have checked with that, if you do that
again, it's not going to get us app
because it showed us the output
following.
That's that's a problem. Yes.
Yeah. Okay.
Tell you that that's surprising
because I honestly after having every time
that if there was an update
I immediately did the pool
so what are you do that
if there is adopted just the pool okay
is that you do
I want how to confirm that login is done
then to check that on GitHub.
On GitHub receipt from your main branch
you have the final commit
that issue in the future
sun has been resolved.
So it's been
okay.
And so it shows you that multiple requests
from some fixed
technologies, it's done.
You can go ahead and see the cool lot.
So it would show you
that merge is zero.
Oh you guys.
So now what we are going to do,
we are going to update
our local repository
folder anymore and for that simply
get cool.
Okay.
So you need to do this.
Okay guys.
So now after the cool, everything is there
and my
project is update.
Let me know if you guys are still
this client synchronized with me
and then we can proceed to further
plugins.
So let's have a quick look at our logs
and get them all
because frankly we have two branches
and let me see
the command that we have for
the Okay, so this
command is going to help us
look at the branches
in a more defined.
Okay.
So I'm going to copy this and duty guys to
plus $5 because I spend
a lot of time searching for this one
so you can see those dollars.
By the same token.
But this would show you
the basic structure
of this.
You can do stuff like that that would
that would be helpful.
But just give that's one does Yeah.
Okay. So this
particular command is going to make it
a little bit better, but still, it's
a little bit complicated to understand
the processor of and proceed.
But as you proceed, I would try to make it
more clear how to study this.
We will have a look at that.
But for now, this copy does
come out of activity in your computer
and we will be learning it as we
move on to the next month.
Just oh,
I'll I'll teach you how to read it.
Okay.
So the next and the final example
we have is going to be pretty big.
One will try to complete it today,
but mostly be I think we won't be able to.
But still, let's start up today.
Okay, guys.
So scenario
on the project.
So we're system
two new
people
were hired.
So there are two new people
who are hired on this project
and they were asked to do
some contributions on this.
You know, this was a very big project.
It's not a system like system.
So we need two new people in our team.
Let's have some good names for that
monkey.
And then
it's not that one. It's not a
function that you are living, right.
Bob and Jim are to argue that he's good.
Okay, so you don't want to do that too.
I hate that.
By the way, pretending to be both of them
funky and groups.
So funky is here
and is donkey.
Okay.
Now I will recommend that
you guys follow me to
because last time you did that example,
now you should be able to put ten
being, you know, to use that
it's going to be half
if you want to be like
this one at no problems like it.
My main one is donkey with the other.
It's not that one.
Oh, let's remember his name too,
you know, funky
and so funky.
Funky and yeah.
Okay. So we name the
change, the name
for Donkey to Chunky.
It was rhyming, but
he more than come back
Yeah that that sounds in that
okay you guys now a Google
do simply open up this guy and get Bashir
and clone the project for both of them.
So this these steps
are not going to be slow because I expect
you guys
to be very quick in these things get
and we have done it a lot of times
just simply cloning repositories
being the user
funky and junky.
So I have done it for funky now
I'll do it for something.
I want you guys to follow a bit.
These guys have to plug
it back to it now.
So now both of them are having the project
on their system, right?
The Doors have a project.
This one is for funky
and this one is for our friend Sheldon.
Okay,
let me know once all of you are done.
so now the
tasks have been assigned by the team
to both of them to funky
work on Planet One
and for charity work on Future Planet.
You know, like there are two planets
in the solar system, right?
And like, they are a huge planet.
There are a lot of code
that have to be written.
So these two people were given
the responsibility to work in parallel
so that the project
can be completed in time
so the books will close the project
and start working in parallel
on the planets.
But obviously I cannot show you
the parallel stuff
and I'll just had one by one
we working on those projects.
So let's go ahead and first
work on the project of Funky
That's funky,
the output of the
project, new project,
and then I clone it, no file.
So it's going to be for me on desktop.
So documents, desktop and
I that's
the last system.
New will.
Okay, So there I go.
I have
this project is how to do it from
well well maybe configuration file
yes well but
we are not interested in that but now
that's fine.
We discussed that
we are not focusing on code.
The code is zero, which was in the
on the GitHub.
It's here
and we are good enough with that.
Okay,
let's open up our
terminal for
so I need to do else
it's solar system outside see solar system
I'll go into this particular folder
and then I'll see
get status
if you create the new project
or just open that will one person.
I did not create any project, nor did
I open the old instead I wonder approve.
And that opened up to project
which I just closed.
Okay, so for everyone is that clear?
That item will clean up the project
which at launch
we have done this on
in the last class.
How I created the launch.
This one right here
on the storage of the address of system.
Are you all
with me?
Yeah.
I'm also getting an error because
the configuration files are missing.
We have add some population files
and it no disappear.
But as I mentioned
that, just forget it for now, okay?
We do not have to issue on this for
add this in the get
ignore file.
Yeah.
This does underscore stories
for the Mac users.
It's just a simple file that gets created.
It's very quickly just
I wouldn't get ignored this
if that's the problem
for you see you can also
send it along with the comments.
That doesn't matter.
Okay guys.
So I need to repeat this.
Everyone, to this point with me,
do you all understand that
what we are doing,
we are pretending to be one of the user
who is working on the project
and he is supposed to work on planet One.
Okay, so for that purpose,
I closed the project off supporting.
I open up that project in my ontology.
I am assuming that it should not be a hot
task for you.
Okay, everyone synchronize,
read.
Yeah.
Okay.
Now what I'm going to do is I'm going to
show you
guys some.
Yeah. On this much.
So open up the terminal associated
with this user
right now
in front of me.
Right.
Which I'm
getting much less.
But now
we are on the main ones.
And have you guys noticed else
you already have
Main branch.
There are no other branches
but that the scenario
on the GitHub.
I want you guys to pay attention to this
because this is something you will have
problems
when you will be working in the projects.
Okay. Okay.
So by default what I fully clone
by default,
do you only get the main branch
in order to get other branches
on your system?
You have to follow procedure.
And what's that procedure?
We will discuss shortly.
It's really simple.
Well, it's not complicated.
It's simple because
there is a possibility that
the user one, which I am right
now, I want to work on planet.
What do I need other branches?
Do I need some?
No, I don't need that.
So if get
closed,
all those glasses belong redundant.
So it is very smart.
Okay, so don't say that they are making it
complicated if you want to have it.
It's really simple.
Okay So right now
we only have main branch
and we are aligning that.
Okay, now tell me that should I start
working on Main Branch
or should I create a new branch
if I want to work on particular,
I want to create a new branch.
So I would say get branch
planet one
and then I need to push to.
Okay,
so I have
successfully split two planet for all of
switch to planet one after creating it.
And let me
draw some relation
for this particular example.
Also, we have all the commits the account
and I'm expecting a final commit.
Also, we're here for Branch.
Okay.
Navigate in the branch.
It is going to appear out of
in parallel of
this thing.
Merge. Right.
So let's do a branch
error.
Unless they make
planet one
obvious
something, let's go to our ontology
and make sure that you of the correct
users
project were not working
on a previous branch.
Make sure of that.
So how do you make sure of that?
By reading the links.
I'm in funky sort of system,
so I'm sure about it.
I need to work on planet one.
So simply New Java class and throughout it
I'll explain
it why?
So our planet has
most of the Epsilon
Spring color
and its best friend
status, so it has two properties
color and science.
Now I'm going to, in my main class,
looking
at these properties, but
what should be the name of Planet One
that's
always
that?
I don't know what it means,
but I hope that nothing that
let's make it
green, let's
get some science.
Okay,
So let me know when you guys have added
this class and added this features
in your main
engine,
you are faster than me.
Okay, So now
let's go to.
Okay, so it's not a male, right?
Nahuatl.
Oh, let's go to our
terminal
and make sure that on the right terminal
it runs to funky.
Saw our system.
Okay,
now what we want
to do,
we want to make up commit of our code.
At this point.
So get at dot
and get
it graduate and
the features of Planet
One have been added
successfully.
Okay, so the current has the name,
so all of you make the commit.
Now let no.
So that I will draw this command
in my diablo
version
somehow simply get that data
become adaption.
Nothing, nothing works and
then you go last will simply add
the correct size.
Okay,
so now let's run that command
which we learn for
the graphing device.
This is the command
because I don't have this letter
that that big graph one
plug space to connect from
our system.
Maybe I'll be going
here from Quito Central
having an
Excel.
Let's try to understand our level of
so this is the point
where we extracted a bunch, right?
So this is going to always
this particular straight line
is presenting one single
branch.
It's not going to look always
from the start like that.
We are looking upon it
because now after, you know,
merging that we are visualizing it.
So that's
why it's appearing like this. And
it's it will be more effective
if we saw it from the,
you know, style, Right.
Know what we did or style.
This represents one branch
and this title presents, another branch.
So this is what is happening right?
We created two different branches
and we created this graph from
we have created this blend,
one word from this particular commit.
So that's why it started
with appearing above
this.
Okay, so that's how you actually know,
we tried to read this.
It's now as you move forward and show you
that how we can, you know, make it
better, this understanding.
But it's still complicated.
But looking for that one line,
I'm never able to find
a good representation
of this particular branch and stuff.
No, I don't like this one too
obvious.
Know that's the best of
the blank.
One is ready.
It's done.
We have successfully added it to the one.
So now what do I suggest?
What should I as being the user?
I have completed it.
What should be my next step?
Okay, so I'm preparing to be user one,
which is funky.
So what is funky supposed to do once
he has completed his teacher?
Tell me step by step
what should be left first step?
What should be my first step?
How can I open up?
Cool.
Right now
I'm repeating now my first step
after
completing it.
Exactly.
And I'm doing this on purpose because
I don't want asked to be,
you know, missing something
and what you are a project.
So this is your practice because soon
you will do that end of the project.
This is your practice, not
okay. So
let's come out and get personal,
get pushed back to Origin
Planet one.
So what?
You are not entering the correct name.
Maybe the piece Capital.
Okay, guys.
So if I show you at my project,
the grads have successfully been pushed
and see a planet
one here.
Okay, so
let's leave it for now.
And meanwhile let's pretend to be chunky
at work kind of crunch.
So I'm going to close this
code for funky.
Where is it?
This one right to minimize it.
And I'll start working as a chunky.
So I guess with me till this point
we have
uploaded
the branch pretending to be you one.
Now we would be pretending to be the two
and start
working on.
So simply open up your intelligence
file, open
and make sure that this time you open
the other project
that you closed on your system.
Make sure that
okay,
so let me know once you have open up your
other project
and it's going to have no planet one,
why is it clone Planet one was not there.
The boot people are working in parallel.
Okay. And one more thing is
now you have to simply add
the feature planet to for Chunky.
So very similar to that.
A Java class thing.
Planet one outside of Planet Q
And here your characters training
color as playing size
so far do also have some color.
It has some size not in the main code
you will be out of frame,
but do
features, let's say
What's the name of our planet to
this module I'm counting on?
You must in out.
It is going to give us some larger
blade to us
based inputs, but
I don't know how the analysis
radicals
sabbatical star photos equals to
thing.
Let's make this planet
inside.
Let's make it
okay.
So we have successfully added features
for to
and now
we need to make a comment.
But first I need you guys to guide me.
Where is this Latitude?
What's going to emerge from?
My source emerged
in parallel with Planet
One, Planet two.
Okay, now we need to make a comment.
So open up the terminal which
is associated with this particular code.
That is, Are you following me?
I behind because I see no response.
I'm just moving smoothly.
I'm assuming that
you guys are able to call up.
Okay, perfect.
So see the solar system
get at dot
get comment
dash number
and the message I'll place over here
the feature
right to is complete
the and obviously after that,
I would say
push it to GitHub submit
push that hue
origin.
Okay so here we did a mistake
see how
unfortunate of me
the bug on main branch
and no one reminded me
when to create a branch.
Oh that's my fault.
But we are see because
here we are said
because we have not pushed it yet.
So this is
how you are going to be making mistakes
while you will be working on project.
So just make sure that you do not repeat
this mistake. Oh.
Oh. Okay.
So guys,
what we are going to do right now,
unfortunately
you have to clone our project again.
So that's the severity of the issue.
If you do it incorrectly,
you have to do it again.
So a lesson for me as well, It
not at all.
Why is it okay?
Yes, we were all doing this
in the main branch.
I like some.
We were all working in the main runs
as we use it too.
So is is that like allowed.
No, that's not a lot of you
would if you have added but not permitted.
Non you need to look that is
there is a real for you
if you are clever enough
but I'm going to tell you that use
testing somehow
you know just do that. Okay
so we are going to clone app.
Just create a being.
But I'll tell you how to do that.
But obviously
now that for now I'm not expecting
you guys to be able to
do that on your own.
Look,
okay, you guys still
for janky?
We are doing it again because
of what's working on the same branch.
So I'm going to open up the chunky one.
Now this is open in the project,
so now it has means or and so
and the first of what you need to do
is to change the repository,
change the directory
and create a new branch
to get branch
so that it to
get switch
is set up, check out planet to
now you are set to work.
Okay.
I would me let me know
once you guys have cloned their game
and created a new branch planet two
so that we can work
you know
you guys I'm going to be
we deleted the previous repository
of some key
because we accidentally
went in the main branch,
which was not allowed of this.
So we had to record it.
And after recording, you just simply
change the planet of the branch.
Yes, simply click on file
because we will put it.
And from there
choose the location that you have closed
your project, click on it and then hit.
Okay, Nice.
So now let's go with a simulation.
We have a planet to created from sea merge
and let's quickly add
class planet to
this going to have
color
and it's going to have
size, right?
So what are we naming of planet
for gravity
the that
named non-mainstream Pluton is like Pluto.
But then
a planet to
that school type
on that is Uranus is also a planet.
I want to come up with no new names.
You're not creating our solar
and we are creating a new sort of system.
Now let's name it.
So now what we need to do is carry on.
Color is equal to yellow.
Prime dot size equals two.
Okay, let me know once
you have done to this point, can you show
you mean after you finish? Yes.
Maybe this is the main. I have it.
Which then are you talking about?
Main branch.
And are you talking about me Branch
of the planet to
current size of the deficit?
Nothing else.
Okay, guys.
So now this particular user
chunky is going to open up is terminal
is going to make sure for us
that he's in the correct branch
and then he's going to come in
of the now he's going to say, get
add dot, get comment.
That's where
the planet to specification feature
has been added.
Okay, let me know once you are done.
So this form.
What's up, guys? What's what?
What about the rest of you?
Okay, so
now get push.
Matthew Origin latitude
and we are sending this flash
to get up,
so I'll create a comment over here.
Simply like this.
Let's see, six.
So this is what have been done up
till now, right?
Okay.
Now we need to merge it.
We need to merge the Planet one
and we need to merge the planet two
so that utilize two this person
our team right.
So let's say that
we have
opened up the pull requests
and stuff like that.
We have done that already.
We are just assuming
we will do that obviously
and our team we
before he actually holds the code
on merges it you you said
I would like to review it
on my own computer.
So what he's going to do,
he's going to open up his project.
Let's say he was working on the project
that we had in which we were.
We have no planet.
Can we go to that project?
We all have that.
Let's pretend that this is the project
that belongs to the Kiwi.
And he it's his computer,
but let's open up
the terminal associated with it.
So it's idea
project solar System for me,
whatever is for you, let me
once you are have opened
the I don't know this point
all of you know if I problem fast
let me know
because I really want you all to be in
sync with me.
This is an important concept.
Okay, then quickly open it right now. This
you want to write Alex.
Why do you?
I wrote it.
Oh, you found that out.
I really want you to be confident
about your steps.
Okay?
The decisions you are taking,
you should be confident about
that.
I literally.
I literally said like this.
Like there's a gun pointed to my head,
but right.
Fine. I
So now let's see, get branch.
It gives me only the mean and start
get someone tell me why
we got a bit from GitHub.
So what do you guys suggest?
How do we update update
pull that
collect to get that.
It's showing me
that there are two branches
which are planet one and planet two.
Okay, let's do not get full
it that it's already up to date.
What now?
Okay, so here is a little bit concept
that I want to deliver to you.
That's
the only that you got.
Fast forward merge
because you might have done
something different
that should not be considering.
Okay,
There must be something different.
Okay.
So the concept over here
that I wanted to share with you is that
whenever we have a new branch,
whenever we have a new branch on GitHub,
in order to have that locally,
we need to do some different steps.
We cannot do it using full
get code
updates, the code of the same branch.
It does not download new branches
for you in order to have new branches
that appear on GitHub
in your local repository.
First, use the command git branch dash in.
Now the one in the letter that you see
on the branches that are there on GitHub.
Okay.
So if you want to have that one,
you simply
write, check out
Planet one
and it's going to download the Planet
one branch
where you guys group Planet one is there.
So we want to let it one
and we also want Planet two, right?
So I say get check out
planet two.
So now I have downloaded Planet two also
and now I simply switch to get check out
member.
So now I'm on back
my back to my main branch
and if I show you that branch
I have all the branches, planet
one and planet
to download it in my local repository.
So that clear to all of you.
All of these steps have these branches
black one and black two on your system and
person both the screenshot in support.
Yes. Yes.
So let's ask the question noise.
Sorry, I was just busy.
Go ahead ask.
It's a no, it's fine.
Any questions are entertained.
No words
or too like.
Right.
Okay.
Just send me off of the class right now.
You want to.
I okay.
So are we good
for hard?
So they should be go a lot, right?
Do we have those letters?
Mostly.
Okay. So
does everyone synchronized with me
till this one?
Because the next thing that I'm going
to teach you, it's a new concept
I really want you to understand
is this is the major
portion of
merging.
It's a little bit difficult to grasp,
so I need your complete attention.
Take 2 minutes,
refresh your brain, excel in here.
And now let's tackle
to together.
Yes, you can have
the mute.
That's why I mentioned that.
Just to forget about how easy
the syntax is.
Just focus on
the time that
what kind of push is that?
What get.
Yes, I know what's what.
Obviously I do.
Okay then.
Okay.
Please lower the console a little bit.
Okay. So
like, this is just good
enough.
Yeah.
Okay.
With the technical, right.
It's just a one of the players.
Cool in the main class is about ten,
but the class does feel
right and used.
Let me switch to one of the planets.
Like you mean when we switch to one
of the branch of the planets, Right.
Who would in the main class press
about the planet? No.
And I'm of the glass.
Also peers Who said that? Why?
While I didn't.
I'll show you that.
Cause that possible.
If we have another class that works,
it will appear it's impossible that.
It will not appear
mobilized to 2 minutes.
This more than that.
That is passed.
I'm expecting now, hoping
that all of you have joined it.
So I'm going to quickly
I'm at the same that
the class of that planet did not appear.
Not that planet.
You know, this is talking about the class.
So I'm going to switch to
get checked out
planet to now.
I like to open up that
project
and I'm going to make sure that I'm
in the project IDEA Project Solar System.
I have the main code
and I have the Planet two.
So that was not a period for you.
You might have something wrong.
Okay?
You might have skipped some steps.
Okay, so you'll be done.
Do you want me to switch to that one? No.
Here, check out
Planet one.
Okay, Now I will show you Planet one.
So there is a code for Planet
One and class for that
one to.
So, yeah, this is how it should be, right?
We are switching to those blogs
in which we updated the code,
we wrote the new features
and they are appearing to us
as it is, it should be sampler.
One gift is saying
if you are not having this,
then it means that you did something
wrong.
Well, if it did not download, how did it
manage to switch or hard?
And this one shows you planet
one of the planet two, right?
That means that there are no
in your representative.
Okay, guys, so let's move forward.
A lot of time has been spent.
So again, check out Main.
So I'm checking out to meet my main one.
So right now it might encourage
if I show you I only have name
problem so that how can we have all the
branches opened at the same time.
I would you want that.
That's it's impossible to do that.
Yes exactly.
If you check out
then you will be taken to do that.
You cannot simultaneously
open up to branches.
What are you working with?
One hand on one branch
and the other hand on the other one.
Yeah. Sorry,
but you got to do that, right?
So you have to say,
okay, so let's get back to our main
discussion.
This is pretty interesting conversation
that that is going to happen.
I'm really excited about it
and I'm really excited
that you guys do understand it,
so I'll recommend you one thing.
Start doing everything okay.
First, the concept that is important.
Okay, let's
can you guys name the number of classes
that we have?
See, merge
having them name
the classes and see merge,
which is our main branch.
Obviously guys,
the classes that we had,
we had just named them for me.
Please.
Thank you.
So we have some
we have our system.
We have the other one which is
name.
Okay, how do you guys name
the classes that we have in C five
that like Planet one branch categories,
name their.
We just have one expert, right?
Which is planet one. Right?
To be very precise
what extra class.
Sorry.
And for planet two we have almost the same
only it's planet two
instead of planet one.
That's how it is, right?
Anyone who does not agree with me
or wants to stand out and say no,
I'm not saying correct.
I mean, you are every ten.
Q For that, I appreciate your
cooperation.
Yeah.
One upset wants to point a gun towards
my head.
Please don't do that.
The arrow, the planet.
Our solar is doing the main code
like the
this is the solar system class
of Okay, guys.
So if all of you got it
in the first go,
then we are going to get an ugly off.
So let's do that.
I will try to explain it
right here in New York team.
That's why I have this names right?
Okay.
So now tell me that
if I first being a team
lead,
I want to check the future Planet one.
What will I do?
I want to make sure that Planet
One feature is working fine.
I have downloaded the branches.
So what should I do?
I'll open up the terminal.
I do get check out
planet one.
I'll open up the cool.
It has that one.
The password system, the test on
and it tells me first. So
I'm going to copy this for reference.
I'm going to play this code.
LC Okay.
And one is breaking final pretty good.
So I check the planet one.
It was working fine.
What is the next step that I'll be?
Okay, So you guys are seeing that.
I'll check out that tuna.
Okay,
so I take the planet to go to calculate.
I'll have a look at the code
s working good planet two of.
That's awesome.
You know, it's perfect.
So I would say that it too is working
great.
You okay?
So I have this code
just for their accents.
I'll be nice after that.
What do I do now?
I have checked both groups.
Okay, Now
I need to merge them into the main plot.
That's our target.
Now, you think for that? Louder.
You should be sure about it.
So how are you going to watch one of them?
One or something? You see?
What do you take?
One by one, obviously.
Obviously we are going to go one by one.
Okay.
So can you guys
can you guys at this point see that?
Where will the conflict be
when we will merge Planet one
and two? All?
Is it going to be Planet two?
Has anyone else worked on planet
You know, no one bit.
It's not going to be Planet two.
Is it going to be Planet one?
Is there going to be any consequence?
I won't know because no one word on
planet one
except
that one.
Is there
going to be a conflict in me? Yes.
Because then in one added his planet
in main and planet
two also on this planet in name.
So we can literally visualize that yes,
there is going to be a conflict.
If I show you these good side by side,
you will see for yourself, Let me do this.
Yeah.
So now we got to apply one cool
online.
Number 17
We have added Planet One features
there eyes on this line of ozone
you have to by is equal to new planet
to the B
there is a conflict at this point right
candidate C that
okay so this is a conflict
now we all want a conflict happens.
So I'm going to show you this conflict
in real time.
Okay.
So what is the first name?
So first of all, let's merge planet
One with the main.
Okay. So
which kind of merge is going to happen?
Okay, so get this going to check that
when planet one was created
the history was seeing merge
are the last time it was seen merge.
When we applied to merge back
it's going to check
is is the last time it still see
merge yes or no.
So it is still seamless.
The commission of the fast forward
merge is
completed
so a faster merge will happen.
That is the question is in fact,
do we have any conflicts?
No we don't.
Everything is basically override.
So this is something
that's going to happen right.
Okay.
So I'm going to decide this for both. So
what?
Okay, so let's go ahead and do this.
Fast forward much.
I'll open up my terminal.
Okay.
In order to do this, merge,
what should I do
in my very first step?
It's the main terminal.
It's the terminal
which is with that particular one.
Yes, exactly. Get check out me. Very good.
I'm really proud of you guys.
Remember everything.
Okay, the next step.
Give me the commander.
Which commander am I going to write?
Not to do this much?
Get merged so that it one.
Right.
Okay, so the type of merge happening
is fast forward as we discussed.
Perfect. Now
this is something that happens.
Okay, great.
Now it's time for us to merge
the planet to
the members that when this thing was made,
history was seen merge.
Now we are trying to
merge it back to me is the history
the latest test.
We are the latest to make stealthy merge.
No, it's now c file
will ever be possible.
Nil at that is not going to be possible.
Okay.
So in this scenario
then f is not possible.
Get has to
apply other
strategies of merging
which are recursive merge
and some other kind of rebase are either
merging strategies
out there in the market.
We will discuss them in detail,
but not today.
We'll discuss them tomorrow,
but we will be discussing
this particular off market East.
So super merging it
actually we are seeing that what happens.
First of all,
I want to ask you my question to you is,
if possible, is not happening
or is not possible,
is that statement
true or false?
Is this statement true or false?
Okay.
Let me find it
now. Time
true or false?
I guess everybody answer like this.
You guys like we you just
turn we answer like get it.
But firstly, so
it is that if no f if
other.
Okay, let me explain it to you.
I'm saying
that if fast forward is not possible,
it means that history has been G
So the statement
that it is necessary
then there will be a conflict.
It's true or false? Obviously it's false.
We still don't know
whether there will be a conflict or not.
It's not.
And for a conflict, right. Why?
Because in this scenario
you are telling me that if main power
was not present,
that would not happen in any conflict.
Well, now we merge the funds.
And because the merge or any other merge,
no conflict.
Exactly.
Because none of them worked
on the same file, a conflict occurs
when someone changed the thing lines
of the file with a different kind of code.
Right.
So now do you guys get it
that it is necessary that there will be
a conflict is actually a false statement?
It's not necessarily.
Okay, guys, I want to know that you guys
got this concept.
If not, let me know
so that I can explain it to you more
Oak Island and got it.
What about the rest?
Be very open to it because conflicts
you should be
very much clear about them.
I'm going to
help you guys.
So my question, I'll repeat it
and I'll repeat the solution
again.
Okay.
So we discussed that when there is a fast
forward, there will never be a conflict.
First of all, I want to ask you guys,
do you guys know what when a conflict, do
everyone understand that
when a conflict occurs,
if not, is let me know
so that I can also tell that because
I'm assuming that you know what's up
and when it happens.
If not, then we open about it.
Not it's not about the or.
It's about the lines that have changed.
So giving you a very crude example,
I'm going to give you a very crude
example of that.
So this is the example
that you were discussing.
This is the example
that we have in our code.
And I really want to show it
to you, all of you, so that
things become
very clear.
Okay, So this is the code that we had.
And I mean, what right
do you all agree that we have no planet
one planet two in the middle, but.
All right. Okay.
But we started working on planet One.
What we did added a Planet one
class, right?
We added our planet one class.
Okay, so it's like one class
existing anywhere else in the project.
Where have been,
you know, added some code into.
So is there any possibility
that, like, one is going to be having
any kinds of conflicts
now because no one else ever ruled on it.
Only one person wrote it on it. Right.
Okay.
Then the planet person who was working on
that one, he he entered some code
regarding Planet One online
and was celebrating a not right.
Okay.
Meanwhile, in parallel,
the Planet two person.
What he did is that he created
a class planet, you know.
So is there going to be a conflict
implied to Olivia? No.
And now when he
wrote down his code,
he added some good on 16 1789.
Right.
That's the scenario.
So at this point, all of you are with me.
Okay.
Now, when we did Fast Forward
was the first batch with the Planet One.
It simply overrode this code and placed it
over here
right.
Okay.
But when now we are merging,
let it do with the main.
It's going to say,
okay, now you know what?
Online number 16.
I'm like, I'm the one. I'm sorry.
So I'm busy online was 17.
You have added like one teacher,
but over here in London was 17.
You have like two
Priority is equal to New planet two.
Which one to Queen?
I don't know, because when you created
this planet to large,
you had nothing over here.
But when you are trying to merge it
that there is always some code.
Didn't know what to do.
I don't know what to do.
So now do you guys get it
crystal clear that
how a conflict occurs.
Not a theory, not crystal clear.
Come on.
That it should be done to c.
C c c is also for, like the emotions
only.
Like there will be a conflict.
Who who says that
that will do this matter?
There will be a conflict in me
who says that there will be a conflict.
Okay. MUHAMMAD That
anyone who says that, no, there
won't be a conflict
either.
Okay, guys.
So let's prepare for that.
We are the main branch.
We need to merge planet.
Q Right. Let me show you the intelligent
areas
how unemployment here does not exist.
So get merge
planet to
order merging
conflict, fix the conflict
and then come the result
very you know
now it's telling us that
this does your code
in this final come in
and this is the one that is coming from
the brass deck you are much
there's a clash between
value.
What do you
so what do you think we should tell it
to do?
Yes, exactly.
You'll sit in front
and exactly.
That's how
that's how beautifully do people
working on the big projects, same project,
can combine their codes using get cut.
So what exercises might be working
on one feature and the otherwise
another feature?
And when you merge that you can have
both the codes in your
project.
What are the visible victims of conflict?
Well, right. Next question.
That's why whenever you name
your variable, you name them
according to the use case, you do not use
ABC. TFT
Has is there any conflict of available
right now?
No. Right, because we named them
intelligence.
All what these concepts?
No, sorry.
They are not on slides, they are on
B care notes that are shared with you.
So it's not words.
We just use merge to combine the groups.
How did I give you the answer that
coming towards that?
Okay, I did one.
So this one are all of you here?
Yes. This
this is the last step is that you
just keep both going.
You just need this one.
Well I have slides,
but obviously not to the deal.
I'm honestly against slides
having too much information.
They are not good. They are not alike.
It's unethical for me.
It's unethical
to have slides with that much information.
It likely haunts me. So I have
very good notes for all of you
I share with you.
All of you and I have played
with these concepts to explain.
Okay, So don't worry about
okay guys,
don't worry about the slides for now.
We need to end this.
First of all,
let let's complete this right.
We have not yet finished. Come on.
What do you think?
We are finished now? Yes.
You fix your conflicts yourself.
Okay, guys.
So this one, all of you are with me.
Okay, Now
let me show you.
In the terminal,
we have resolved the conflict.
And now what's happening
is to look at this.
What do you see or hear?
Main slash merging.
It means that gate is waiting for you
to make the changes.
And then after that make a comment, merge
or merge to make.
Because right now we did what we did guys,
roommates, geniuses, right?
We added good goals
and this is somewhere
when you most something
get is not going to let you move
from that point
until you make the history,
until you make a comment.
It's not like let the movement ends.
You can do nothing on here.
You have to
you have to now make a comment.
So get
status,
get at DOT,
get comment that
the flat attacks
have been most
successful.
Okay?
After that, everything is all good.
We have made the most of it
and I should get more.
It's there.
Okay.
So now the last thing that I want to show
you is on simulation.
That's how it happened. So
and that it will be good to
we learn that
we should not merge directly
to the main branch.
Yes, but I'm the at it right.
So team is going to merge.
Okay.
But right now I'm just showing you
how you can merge using
your computers.
But this is not recommended.
I will teach you how to merge as a team.
We on github also in tomorrow's class.
Okay.
No one get to these interviews are over.
Tomorrow is going to be a review
you will spend all time practicing.
Okay so guys, we need to do this
simulation.
This is important.
We need to do this simulation.
Okay?
Now, when we have time to merge it
over here, let me just delete this
because it's creating a lot of confusion.
I thought,
okay, now and
we are going to make this here.
It's going to say no, fast forward
merger to other strategies,
but when we must mastered it,
found some fast close.
If conflicts would not have been there,
it would have easily adjusted.
But now as the conflict
is there, it's to now
see that make a new commit
which contains the infiltration of C5
merge that C6
and then C5 is going to point to that
is that all of you?
Okay, great. So now I am expecting that.
Okay, one more time.
So, so now.
Okay, so again,
I'm going to come to that too.
So now what we are doing is
we are merging C5 with C6.
If there's going to be no conflict,
it will simply merge them together.
But if there's going to be a conflict,
it will soon resolve
that conflict.
So that conflict is going to be resolved
in the sense that C5 six,
they both will be merge
and you will resolve the conflict.
Once that conflict is resolved,
your main grudge is going
to be pointing towards the code
which contains the combination.
C five and six.
I like the updated most
code.
Okay. Now coming to
this question, that letter
C six will be included in the history
are not well, that's none of our concern.
For now. There are different strategies.
If we use one, it may include this
kind of like C six and next week
if we use another, it may not.
But trust me, that is something
which is beyond the school blocks
you will be dealing with.
So Let's not go into that.
Yes, you are right about it.
Okay, guys, So
one more thing
that I would like to show you
pretty real quick here,
just to make sure that you have
your GitHub not,
you know, updated to this one.
And tomorrow
I'll show you how you can actually do this
merging stuff on GitHub as being a team B
because that is what I recommend you
that when you are working on projects,
what you don't need to resolve all you see
by writing the others code on the system,
maybe even merge the locally.
That's not one, maybe even do that.
But in your work this is most probably
the only merging on GitHub.
So I'll tell you how to build that.
Okay, so tomorrow, guys,
I'll make sure that we learn this.
And before this, let's we quickly show you
one repository,
the calculator, one
which you were discussing the update.
Now it's going to make sense
to all of you.
And I.
How many boxes do we have now?
You guys will get the idea
that why they are needed.
And if I show you any branch
that contains a lot of information
and if I go to pull request
but of the minor, we're going to try
trying to delete and and and unuseful.
So we call it like seriously increase
the branch to create delete a seven minus
description of the changes need
unuseful time a lot of times
and he has it with a smiley
updated function input list items in
for accessibility
fix primary display bars on that.
Now I know
all of them are there
and you get open this conversation.
We should avoid that using the number
formatting units like he's
giving everything in detail over
you know, there is like
there is a little party cleanup up.
We are
did not imagine but I would like to get it
my before I forget details
and stuff like this and as soon
you have professionals
where this is a microsoft calculator
on which people are working
so you know
this is how
professional works on GitHub.
And is this code public for people?
Yes, it's probably
this is particularly emerging code,
which languages
that do I don't understand.
Okay, guys. So
thank you all for the time
and you will be continuing for
here onwards tomorrow.
So make sure that you guys are advised
and you are trying to
conceptual here.
These are the slides.
I have the diagrams just,
you know,
the rest of the details will be in
notes.
Yes, you can copy
here.
I'll find the best to uploaded in about
one one or 2 hours.
Okay, guys, I'm pretty sleepy.
Take care. Bye bye.