The. Yes.
Okay. So you saw there is. Okay.
So some people used and.
Okay, that's really good. Yes.
You didn't know we can do that.
Absolutely. Right.
Because we didn't cover that. Right.
So there is a lot of different ways
of using X plus guys.
Okay.
So for people who use that, that's
very good.
It means that you guys
doing your research.
Okay, so there's different ways of using
and locating that element as well, which
which I showed you.
I think I showed you to use index thing.
Okay. That's where you can implement that.
And you should be able
to locate that element by,
by using an index.
Okay.
The difference between following seven
preceding siblings,
you need to use one of other. And
the difference between it depends.
It depends on it
depends on your HTML, right.
It depends on your HCM
and it depends on your element.
So if your element
has a following siblings
and you can't locate that element
uniquely,
you want to go to the one that you want,
you can locate uniquely
and then go to the preceding sibling.
Okay.
It all depends on the HMO
and how it's built.
Okay. That's
how you move through the nodes.
Okay, guys.
So it's you need to pay attention
on on the nodes in your HMO
and then decide whether you want to go
to following or preceding siblings
for the videos.
I'm not sure I haven't
watched any in YouTube myself.
And I forgot
there was one guy who was really good.
I've I forgot his name.
I used to watch him when I was
when I was at syntax studying as well.
I forgot.
I'll tell you if I remember that his name
he he has really good class is actually
not Alex.
We know.
So you were confused.
Okay. On the siblings.
That's fine On the contains
Contains is easy right guys
so contains you using contains in order to
to get some partial value
or is that example right here.
Right.
This is the partial value of the
of the of the place holder attribute.
Right.
So there was email or phone number
or something like this.
We only used one part of it. Okay.
So you don't have to use the whole value
when you use contains.
When I was. Yeah. When I was a student.
That's correct.
All right.
Any other
questions, guys?
Walk you through the homework.
Okay. We'll do an example.
Okay.
We'll, we'll do the same example,
but we will do it a little differently
with CSF selectors, but I'll show you
I'll walk you through that homework.
Okay.
We're not going to be covering
end at all because as far as I know, guys,
you can use
and but I haven't, I haven't seen it
in in use at all
because there is a lot of difference
difference what's called ways to do it.
And you can use indexing instead of using.
And sometimes, as I said, if you force
I mean you can use end
and you can use index, okay?
But if you do your research on and that's
fine, that's more information for you.
Okay.
But we won't be covering
and in your in of expertise done
so we had only one class on next part
so I don't want to overwhelm you
with all those ads
and different kinds of ways for X.
Okay.
So that the the,
the things that we learned yesterday,
they should be enough
for you to locate any elements
freely
or any other questions
before we start.
All right.
Today's fun, right?
Yeah, I promised fun. Okay, guys.
So I'm class today. Exactly. Yes.
So bear with me.
As we talked before, guys, we will be
going through the boring part first.
Okay,
But the second half of the class, we will.
We will have a lot of fun.
Okay, so let's talk
let's do a quick recap.
Okay, Let's do a quick
recap of yesterday's class,
what we've done so far and what we know
so far from yesterday's class.
Guys,
let's see.
Yeah,
I tried to give you different homeworks
that are a little tricky so that you guys
can find ways to resolve the issues.
Okay?
Because if I
give you straightforward things,
you won't be able to resolve the issues.
You're just going to be sending
keys, clicking on elements.
Okay.
All right, guys, what about recap
What's going on?
I see you guys passive again.
What happened?
We need some coffee.
We need a we tired.
What is going on, guys?
Okay, Everyone is active. Okay.
What did we cover yesterday?
Guys?
Expats, types of expat, right? Absolutely.
And relative expats.
Okay, so what is an expat, guys?
What do we know about expat?
Okay, it's a locator, right?
And it's a query language to locate the
element uniquely on the web page, Right?
So we said there's two two types of expat,
there's absolute and relative expat.
So what do we know
about absolute expats? Guys
The longest way.
Okay, that's good.
Starts from the starting note, right?
Start from the very top of the HTML
or from the DOM.
Right?
And how do we started guys?
It starts with a single slash
and we have to start from the very,
very top.
Right. Okay.
What else do we know about it?
And we go back and forth
in Absolute Express.
No, right.
We can only go forward.
Okay, good.
So what about relative X path, guys?
You can start from any note
you want in HTML,
depending what element you want to locate.
You don't have to start from the very top,
right?
It also starts with two slashes
or double forward slashes.
Right. And
what what else can we do with the relative
x file?
You can go back and forth. Okay.
You can go back and forth,
which is which
is going to be your advanced X class.
Okay. What else, guys?
What about the attributes?
What did we say about the attributes?
Which attributes can we use
in in our X back?
We can use any attributes
in our x path, right?
So it doesn't have to be ID, name,
class or link tax or whatever.
You can use any attributes you can see,
even if it's a placeholder, if it's
even if it's this on click or whatever
it is, type
any attribute,
you can use it with X path, right?
And you can start at any point
of the of the DOM.
As you wish.
All right. So
what kind of methods did
we learn of in X Path, guys?
What are different methods that we learn?
What are different manipulation scenes
that you can do with us?
There we go. You can get a text, right?
And you can find an element by its text.
Okay.
We'll also learn
how to get the containing value right,
and we'll also learn how
to get the starting value
of any attribute, right?
Okay.
What about the ending value?
You guys?
It's not available, right?
It was available
in an extract version 1.0.
Now we all use 2.0.
So that's why
it is not available right now.
Okay, so let's go over the advanced
X path of what do we know about
advanced X path plus
as a big family, right?
So it's a it's basically parent child
and sibling relationships, right?
So Advanced X
path is based on parent and child
and sibling relationships.
Right.
So if I want to go to a
to a node forward, guys,
and it is my sibling,
it is going to be what
if I if I want to go forward, guys,
not not backwards.
Right.
It's going to be my following sibling.
And if I want to go back,
it is going to be my preceding sibling.
Right.
So what do we know about the parent?
What is the parent class?
What is the
parent node?
Let me actually go in here
so that we can see what is going on.
It is the container, right?
It is the container
which contains the element.
We we want to we want to locate.
Right. So if we're looking here.
So that's input as a parent
which is that div.
Right.
What does DIV stands for.
It's a division. Right.
So this division has a label in here
and input.
Right. How do we know?
How do we know these two are siblings
guys,
label and input?
How do we know
they are indented inside the division?
But if you look vertically
they are on the same level, right?
So it's inside the division,
but they are of the same
at the same level inside this division.
So they will be our siblings.
Okay,
So what is considered as an ancestor,
guys, grandparents.
Okay, what did we say
about ancestors?
Anything above the parent, Right.
Anything above this
div will be considered as ancestor.
Okay, good.
All right.
Okay. Any questions, guys?
Any questions on X path?
Everyone was ready and active.
Yes, that's good.
That's really good.
So I promise
you today, a little bit of fun.
So let's do this right.
Okay,
So let's talk about the CSF selector.
Okay, today.
And then we're going to be doing
some element commands
and then we'll go over the tag name.
Okay.
And the most fun we're going to have about
today's
class is with
tag names. Okay?
We're going to be doing a lot of stuff.
Okay.
So CC selector guys,
is is there anyone who did a research on
CSF selectors?
Let me create
a file
here.
All right.
CSF selector.
Okay, so CSF is a stylus, right?
Okay.
Like x path. It is like x fat. Exactly.
But it is a little bit faster
in finding the elements, right?
So it is a selected
that is related to styling.
Okay,
so does anyone know what CSF stands for?
Cascading styling sheets. Right.
Okay, that's very good.
So let's put it in here.
It's getting styling sheet.
Right.
So anything so for the developers guys. CC
So if you go in here, this here
guys, as you can see,
they are styling it in here.
Okay?
When you, when you inspect the page,
you can see here margins, right?
The box sizing.
So the display is if it's a block or
whatever, they want to display it right.
The text alignment
there all it's all done by using the CSF.
Okay. So all the
design
is being done by CSF by the developers.
Okay.
All right.
So let's move back in here.
Okay.
So CSF selector, we know it is
another way of locating the elements
uniquely, right?
The syntax of it is a little bit
it's very similar to express,
but it has no different elements in there.
Okay, so
say it is
another way of locating
elements, right?
Elements.
So to say on the web page.
So now let's dive into this syntax.
Okay.
So the syntax is going to be simple
because it's going to be so
it's simpler than X path.
Okay, So the syntax in here
is going to start a little different.
So if you remember in relative X path,
we used to start CSF selector,
I mean we used to start an X path
with double slash right in here.
What we will not
do, we're not going to start
with double slash,
we will directly start from this tag name.
Okay?
So it's going
to be tag name and then again
square brackets in here.
So if you remember in relative X path,
we had X signed
before that attribute in CSS selector,
we don't have it.
Okay.
So you could just type in your attribute
directly in here
and that equals sign
and single codes in here and here
you can put your attribute value.
Okay, any questions on this?
So this looks a little similar.
I mean, it looks very similar to export,
but it looks simpler
then the next path, right?
It's easier and it's simple.
Okay.
All right.
But CSF selector has its own disadvantages
and we will go over those in a bit.
Okay.
So let's go
here and try to identify
an element here by using CSS.
Okay. So yeah, so selector,
it's like x path.
So that means we can use any,
any attributes we want in CSS as selector
as well as we do an export.
Okay. So
what I'm going to
do let's
identify this log in button in here.
Okay.
And let's use a type
what's called type attribute in here.
Okay.
So what am I starting with guys
by looking at the syntax.
If I want to see
if I want to write a C as a selector
and here I'll be starting with a tag name,
right?
So button right away
and then square brackets in here.
So we set that we don't have an assigned
before the attribute in here.
So what I'm going to do
is just start typing the attribute
and equal sign single codes
and then I'll to submit.
Okay.
So pretty easy and straightforward, right?
The tag name, your attribute
and that value.
Okay, So let me copy this
and paste it in here
and we check here exactly one of one.
So that means this element is unique,
right?
Any questions, guys, on this?
It's clear, right? Okay, good.
All right. So
an X path.
Plus, if I wanted to identify the element
by text guys, what did we use?
What did we use yesterday?
We use a text method
right inside our X path.
Right. So I have bad news for you guys.
SS does not support that method.
Okay?
If you use the SS, you won't be able
to identify an element by its text.
Okay.
So I'll put it in the notes.
See, SS
does not give and
opportunity to
locate an element by its text.
Okay.
You can do it only, but by using extract.
Okay. Is that out there?
Guys? Any questions on this?
Obviously
not pretty straightforward, right?
Okay.
So now we have
so for
as selector, we have some shortcuts.
Okay.
So if you
if you remember for x path, whenever
you want to locate something by ID,
you have to type it in.
Right?
So there are some shortcuts
for some attributes in CSC selector.
Okay.
And they're given by by some symbols.
So what I will do in here, let me put
shortcuts for C says, okay,
so let's go ahead and start with shortcut
for classmate.
Okay, So the shortcut for class
name guys is really easy.
It's just a dot. Okay?
So whenever you're using a CC selector,
you instead of putting a whole class,
a whole attribute in there,
we can just put a dot
instead of it, and I'll show you
how it's done in a minute.
Okay.
So out for class
name and let's go in here.
Let me see what we can identify.
Okay, so let's do this.
Okay, So this is our I want to identify
this textbox in here by using a class
attribute,
and I want to write a CSS selector for it.
Okay, So usually, guys,
if you want to write down a
what's called
if you want to write down a CSR selector
with a class attribute, you would go by
tag name square brackets.
Class is equal to
and I think it was this one
right form control.
Right?
So there's three elements. It's fine.
Right now we don't really have to have a
what's called.
We don't have to have a unique element.
I just need to
I just want to show you how it's done.
So normally,
if you want to use a class attribute,
this is how you would go, right?
If you want to go with X class,
you want to start with double slash
and assign,
and then you attribute an attribute down,
right?
So in case it's made very easy.
So what you can do in here,
you can actually do a tag name, dot
and class value.
Okay, So this
can be your success selector.
Okay, So let me go back in here.
So in this case, guys, in this case, my
let's see.
Okay, so my tag name.
So let me locate this again
here.
My tag name is input, right?
So if I want to use the class
value in here,
what you can do is just put a dot
and go ahead and write down for control.
Okay, so it located three elements,
but that's not important for us.
The most important part for us
is that we are able to locate the elements
by using the shortcuts of CAC selector.
Okay, Pretty cool, right?
It's it it's really readable.
And it's not that difficult
to write.
It's not that long.
It's just input.
You put a dot in there
and the class name value.
Right.
Okay.
Let me your
syntax
class value.
And I'm just thinking, okay, any questions
on this shortcut?
Yes. That DOT has a lot of class. Exactly.
All right.
Any questions on this?
You wish that?
Yeah, I wish.
I wish we had shortcuts or X path as well.
But they didn't do this,
so they didn't build it for us.
Okay,
so there is one more shortcut for I.D.
Okay, so let's
go ahead and go over that as well.
A shortcut for it.
Actually,
it's it's going to be really easy as well.
So this time that I did
the shortcut for it
in CC
selector is represented by the pound key.
Okay.
Or the hash tag,
whatever you want to call it.
Okay. So
instead of
having ID is equal to the ID value,
what you can do, you can do the tag name,
the pound and the ID value.
Okay, so syntax would be the tag name
found in here and the ID
value.
Okay.
Yeah. It's not a unique.
Yeah, that's fine. Guys.
I just wanted to show you
how it's used for the class.
Okay.
How you can use the shortcuts to identify
the elements by using the class.
Okay.
You need to use the actual syntax.
You don't have to. It's.
It's a shortcut, right?
So you don't have to do.
You don't have to use the class name
and ID the whole CSS selector.
What you can do, you could just use this.
Okay, so it's just two options for you.
Sometimes you forget what symbols
it was, so
you just want to use the attribute itself.
But if you remember them and you
learn them by heart, so that's, that's
how you want to go and it's more readable
and it's really short.
Right?
Okay.
So let's go in here and identify
one element. Okay.
So we'll see.
So let's see this textbox.
Okay, so this textbox has an ID in here.
So what I want to do,
I want to identify it by ID,
I want to use a CSF selector
and I want to use the shortcut.
Okay.
So what I can do in here,
I'll start with a tag name.
So the tag name here is input.
Right?
What I will do,
I will put a pound sign in here
and I need to grab the value of this ID.
Right. So
copy this and pasted in here.
And you can see that
we identified that element.
And this element is unique enough to use.
Right.
Any questions on this?
I hope it's clear
it's pretty easy and straightforward.
Right, guys? So
just put a
dot and
you could just put a pound key in here
so that you can find an element
by its ID or by its closely.
Okay.
All right.
Okay guys.
So now, so yesterday when we did X pass
right, we used some of the contains
some of the starts with
methods
to identify element by its partial values.
Right.
So we're going to do the same
for CSV selectors,
but it is a bit different for CSV
selectors.
Okay.
So if you remember yesterday
we actually were writing
contains or starts with
right in our class.
So in CSV selector
it's completely different.
It's given
those methods are given in
in shape of symbols. Okay.
Like the symbols we use for these.
Okay. These are the shortcuts.
But for CSV selectors,
when you use containers
starts with and ends with,
you won't be able to use those methods.
You will only be able to use them
by the symbols.
Okay.
And I'll show you what symbols we need
to use in order to use those methods.
Okay, so let's go and start with contains
method.
Okay.
So in order
for you to use contains method in SAS,
it's the method within C assess
you will be using the star symbol.
Okay.
Star symbol
represents
contains
method.
Okay.
So how this works is so this is how
the syntax is going to look like.
Okay, so we as usual,
we're going to be starting with tag name.
Okay?
Then we're going to put a square bracket
and then we're going to go
over the attribute that we want to use.
Okay, So
attribute in here.
So this is the usual, right?
Actually used or in here
partial
absolute value.
But the catch in here is before the equals
sign,
what you need to do,
you need to put this star symbol.
Okay?
So whenever you do this,
this will mean that you using a CSV
selector with the contains method.
Is that clear?
Guys, any questions on this?
Okay.
It's pretty interesting, right?
But you just need to memorize these
these symbols, and that's it.
Guys,
it may look a little confusing at first,
but it's really shortcuts in here.
There is nothing too difficult.
Just we just need to
memorize this. Yep.
We can't. Yes, we cannot.
We cannot use text in CSS.
Correct.
So text
only applies for the text.
Right.
But here the partial value,
we're talking about the partial value
of the attributes.
Okay.
We're not talking
about the text of the element.
Okay. So if you see this in here.
So this class has a very long
attribute value. Okay.
So you can use that contains in order
to have some partial value from here.
Okay.
That actually C
in here, what can we use
C contains.
So we used contains for this
for this placeholder.
Right.
So let's use this in here. So
what is,
what is my tag name guys in here
it's input, Right.
So I'm going to start with my tag name.
Square brackets right.
Let's go in here.
So we sat in CSF selector.
You can use any different
any attributes that are available for the
for the element.
So I'm going to use this placeholder.
Okay.
Pasted in here
is equal to
email. Right.
It is not working right now.
Why you guys?
It's not working right now
because we didn't
enter the whole attribute value.
Right.
So here what you need to do,
you need to enter a star or asterisk
sign in here and then you can see
that we identified this element uniquely
and by partial value of this place.
Holder attributes. Okay.
Any questions,
guys, here?
Okay.
So let me copy this.
Go back in here and paste it into.
Okay, so you have a tag name,
you have your attribute.
The asterisk, right?
Equals and then partial attribute.
So, okay. All right.
So now let's do this.
So now let's go over. This starts with.
Okay, It
starts with method in CCS.
Okay.
So starts with in
in insists it's
it's represented by a very weird symbol.
Okay. I'm trying to find this right
now. Yes, I found it.
So I'm not sure what this is called.
It's called in different ways.
So this
right?
Really sure what this symbol called? Yeah.
So whatever triangle it is,
whatever triangle it is on the top.
So we're going to be using this
as this starts with method
in C, Okay.
Symbol
presents
starts with,
starts with method being C assess.
Okay.
So same way, okay, same way
as did with the contains.
What we're going to do.
I'm going to start with our tag name
and put our square brackets in here.
Okay.
I'm going
we're going to go with our attribute.
Then this triangle equals sign, right?
And here we have starting
attribute values.
Okay.
Since we're using this starts
with in here, we will be carried okay.
There you go. It's called care.
Thank you.
Okay, so starting to attribute values
since we're using starts with
we will be
we will be using the starting attribute
value.
Okay.
All right.
So let's see what we can actually
do in here.
See this element
and let's
try to find out anything different.
Okay.
So let's see if we can do this here.
So let's see.
Let's use this type in here, okay?
And let's use the CC selector
by using this starts with okay,
so what is my tag name in here?
It is again the input tag name.
Right.
Again, square brackets in here.
The attribute that I'm using is type.
Okay, so now the current design
is equal to single single codes in here.
And I can just use the first two
or three letters.
Right.
With the starting attribute value
that I have for type attribute in here,
just pass
and you can see that it is locating
my elements uniquely and it is one of one.
Okay, Any questions
on this, guys?
Do I think that would really need
that many?
Not really guys. Not really.
As I said, guys
in our company,
we mostly use x python IDs.
Some people use CSS selector.
It depends, right.
It depends on the preference guys. Okay.
So some people may not like x path,
some people like using CC selectors.
Okay.
So it all depends on the preference.
As you can see,
some people might like the shortcuts
that I just showed you guys,
which we don't have an X path.
Okay.
If we put password instead of pass that,
nothing's going to happen.
It's going to, it's going to locate
your element anyways, right.
So I can do a password.
So it still starts with that expression,
right.
Our, our CC doesn't know that it ends
with that or this is the whole expression.
It sees that it matches the starting value
and that's it.
Okay.
All right.
Let me copy this
back in here
and sit in here.
So now, guys, CC selector,
unlike the Express selector has ans with
method.
Okay, so let's go over that as well
and with method in CC.
Right.
So this sign is going to be your favorite
sign, right guys?
So our favorite sign is
what is a dollar sign guys?
Okay, so after you find a job,
you will see
a lot of numbers in your paycheck.
Money. There you go. Exactly.
So this is going to be
the easiest one to remember.
I think. Right.
Okay.
So this symbol, this symbol
represents and with method and
cses, like same way,
guys, as we have in here,
we copy this.
But instead of sign in here,
we have dollar sign.
And instead of signing attribute value,
we actually have the ending attribute
value.
Okay.
All right.
Not not yet.
That's not the fun part yet.
We're just getting started. Okay, guys.
All right.
Okay.
So let's go and identify some elements
and see.
Okay.
Wonder.
Okay, there we go. See?
Okay, so let's assume that we have
this one, right?
So let's let's find out
by using the source attribute.
Okay? So let's locate that element.
I know we're not going to be having
a unique element in here,
but our purpose is to use
the NS with method for S, right.
So what is my
what is my tag name in here, guys?
It is an IMG, which is an image.
Right.
So what I will do
or actually let's use this.
Okay,
so let's locate the logo guys in here.
Okay. So this is going to be unique.
I think so.
It has an IMG,
so let me put my square brackets in here.
My attribute.
Right.
Our favorite sign in here, dollar
sign equals to let's see in here.
Let's use the last
the last part of the source.
The last part of the source
attribute value. Okay.
So let me use syntax that P and G,
All right.
There you go.
So you can see that
I only use the last part
of the attribute value
by using the dollar sign.
And now what we have in
here is a unique element
identified right.
All right.
Any questions on this?
Yes. All good.
So for as selectors, guys,
you just have to remember these symbols.
Okay, So that's it.
And so worth doesn't work with.
But he works with CSF selectors.
That is correct.
All right, so this is CSF selectors.
It's pretty easy
then expense, right?
But let me jump in here.
But guys, notice
this, that in CSF selector,
what we cannot do,
we cannot identify an element by its text
and we won't be able to go back and forth
like we can do it in X Files.
Okay. Is that clear?
You guys?
Oh, I did class. Okay.
Thank you.
Zero. For now.
Let's create a Java class.
And here.
Okay. The last part was CSF selector.
We won't be able to identify the element
bytes text.
Okay.
And you cannot go back and forth
like we do it an X path.
So if you use an advanced x path, you can
do you can go to parent siblings, right?
In siesta lecture that there's no option.
You can do that. Okay.
And in CSF selector you cannot identify
an element by its text.
Okay.
All right.
So let's have a main method in here.
Okay.
So now let's go over the steps
for the homework, guys.
Okay.
So let me see.
Can anyone
show you the example of the text
for X path?
That's
right. So, okay. Okay.
So I see what you're saying.
Okay, So let's say this element, right?
Log in, button in here.
So as you can see, there is a text in here
so it doesn't have an attribute
and it's not a value of any attribute.
So this is considered as text.
Okay.
So if I want to identify this,
okay, you got it.
You don't want me to go over the whole X
path?
Is everything clear now?
Okay, cool.
All right, let's go back now.
Sure.
The homework.
Okay, So c text.
I think I have
it self. Right. So let's see.
Right.
Okay, so let me get this.
So I'm going to grab this one, guys
place in here.
Then I just need to get the.
Yeah, I know, right?
I know.
I was ready. You just got you.
Just stop me.
Not cool.
Okay.
All right, guys.
Okay, so I'm navigating here, right?
I set up the properties, I launch
the browser, I navigate to syntax project.
So now, let's see
this.
Okay, so we here the home page in here.
So now let's start identifying
all the elements by CSV selected.
Okay,
so what is the first step that we have?
We need to click on start practicing.
Okay, so what I am going to do in here,
Magic Arrow, right click on this one.
Let's expand this a little bit.
Okay. So now here I have
what's called I have a text in here.
Can we use text when using the C selector
guys?
No. Right.
So what we can do in here,
there is an ID for this element, right.
So we can use that ID,
but let's use the shortcut for this.
Okay.
So what is my tag name on this case?
Guys? It's a tag, right?
So I don't need
any double slashes in here,
so I'll simply start with a tag
and what I can do.
I'll put the square brackets in here
and or what we can do in here.
We can use the shortcut
without putting the square brackets.
Right.
What is the symbol for ID,
guys?
Is it a dot?
What was the dot for? It?
There you go. It's a pound key.
Right? Or the hash tag. Right.
So let's put this
sign in here and let's grab
this ID value and pasted in here.
There we go.
So we have it identified one of one
we use our CSS selector
and we use the ID shortcut.
Right.
So let's go back to our script.
So now what we want to do in here,
we want to find that element, right?
Find element.
What am I finding it by?
Guys?
So this time what we have here,
we have a CSS selector, right?
We need to choose that.
And inside the parentheses
I need to paste that value in here.
Okay.
What am I getting in return
when I find an element,
I'm getting a simple web element, right?
Element
store
practicing equal to this.
So now what I will do in here,
go ahead and click on this.
Can I do class attribute?
Let's see here.
Let's try.
Let's see if we can do this.
Oh, in this case, guys.
Okay, so I see what you see.
Okay, so let me delete this.
Okay I'll put here
this dot and
copy this
place. Live in fear. Okay?
What happened, guys? Why?
I am using the class shortcut in here,
and I can't really find out
or I can't locate that element.
Exactly.
That's because of the spaces
we have in here, right?
So that's why we won't be able
to use the class
and shortcut for CSS selector.
Okay.
One, it has space too.
It's really
what's called its really long
attribute value.
So what you want to do,
you want to shorten it
with by using contains
or you could just use it in here.
Okay.
Space matters in class because you don't.
You do not get it
in the container of single quotes.
Okay.
So here you don't have any quotes.
That's
why it looks like everything is a part.
Okay.
But if you have single quotes
and you put this value inside
the single quotes, that should work.
Okay?
And if you put the class and everything
with this square brackets,
it won't work with your
with a shortcut in here.
All right.
Any other questions, guys?
Okay.
It's not the and let's click on this
and start clicking on sample form
demo then.
Now the tricky part comes here, Right?
Okay, guys,
some people identify it by indexing.
Some people used
and write
to identify this element,
which is which is good.
You guys did your research.
That's fine.
So I have a class attribute in here
which is not unique.
Obviously, you can see there's different
different class
and class action values that are the same.
The only thing that is not the same is,
I think this is the address, right?
So if I want to use
a text, guys
from here, what would be
how would I do this with CSS?
Ask us
exactly.
We can't use text words.
Right?
So in this case, let's go ahead and use
let's go ahead
and use the what's called the x path.
Okay.
But let's use the X path with the
with the text.
Okay.
Ends with and starts
with well ends with and starts with.
We're not going to
they're not going to use the text.
Right.
We can use text at all with C selected
no matter
it ends with or starts
with, starts with and ends with.
We won't be using with only
the attribute values guys
do not I think everyone is confused
with starts with and ends with guys.
Okay.
Because you try to use starts with
with the text in CCS which we can't do.
We can try using attribute.
Yes, we can try using attribute a trap
and see if that's going to work.
Okay. So
let's go ahead and do the Xbox.
And here we have an eight tag, right?
And then
let's do this.
This is what is my next step. Guys.
I have my
my eight tag in here.
Okay.
Okay. Yeah, that's going to work as well.
Yes, that's going to work as well
that you've done.
So here
we're trying to use with eight tracks.
Guys, what is my next step?
So I'm using an X path
there.
Okay. Okay.
So if I type in a graph
and here is equal to
and then
I click on this,
go to the next page, you'll see.
Copy this, we copy the values
of. All right, guys.
So why is this not working?
What did I missing here at sign?
Right.
Okay, so let's put a net sign in here.
Okay. What happened?
So we can use this,
But it's not unique, right?
So I'd rather use the text in here.
And let's see how this is going to work.
Okay, So
text.
So let me delete this.
I think it's simple
for demo, right?
Again, it's one of two.
So there is a
let's do this right there and
there. Okay.
So what happened, guys?
If we identified this,
what did I just identify it
in this case,
I identified the whole division
of these elements.
Right.
So if you look in here,
I identified this and this.
This division
has multiple elements inside.
Okay.
So what I want to do,
I don't want to really go
any further
or any up in the hierarchy, Right.
So what I need to do,
I simply have to go to my second element.
So here what we can do,
we can use the indexing
and it's not going to work.
Why is this not working, guys?
Because we have to wrap it up inside the
container, Right?
So let's do this.
There we go.
So now we have one of one in here.
So it identified that exact element
that we want to interact with.
So, yes, the question was here.
That's why I said that this
this one might get a little tricky.
Okay, so let's go in here
with element.
All right.
Simple.
Why It's not working.
Simple for them, right?
Why it's not working for the first one.
Okay, so let's go back in here.
You mean if you do this one
and this?
Oh, if I put one like this
Because there is a hidden element
inside your web page, guys.
Okay, So sometimes that happens.
Developers. This is developers doing okay.
They do what they want to do
in cmd, right?
Yesterday, as I mentioned, guys, they
built this as they want to build this.
And what we need to do is
we need to
identify the element as we want to.
I mean we need to, right?
So it's,
it is unique, but this is not the element
we want, right?
This is a completely different thing
inside the HTML.
That's why it is not working.
Okay.
So this is completely different thing.
This is a hidden element
that we can not see.
Okay.
And we don't need this
because we don't even see
how it's highlighted on the web page.
Right.
So what we need,
we need the second element
and we can visually verify that it is
it is highlighting
that element on our web page.
Okay.
That's why
we're going to be using the second one.
Okay.
So let me copy this.
Simple form is equal to driver dot
find element
selector.
There we go.
All right.
So what we want to do
X path? Yes. Good touch.
Thank you.
X Exactly.
It's new and then
simple in the demo dot click.
Right.
All right.
So we click on this one.
Okay.
So now will land on this page.
So now all we need to do,
we need to enter some text in here.
What do we want to do in here, guys?
So I want to use an X,
I want to use a C selector.
Okay.
I to use the placeholder attribute and
I want to use contains. Yes.
How do we want to do this?
Or let's do this with start with guys.
We will probably add some thread
that sleep later.
Okay?
After we run
and see how it's going to run.
Okay.
So I have my
input tag.
Okay,
so now
square brackets right
place holder.
All right, so what is my
start with symbol?
Is it a star or asterisk or or a cat?
Which one?
Yeah, in the beginning I said contains
but let's do it with starts with.
All right, there we go.
So let's do this is equal to
and then the starting
value right
you can see you could do displays
or you could do please enter
whatever whichever you want to do.
Okay, so copy this.
Get back in here.
All right, So
what you can do
element
just textbooks, list, name it like this.
Right word.
The second element
by CC
X for starts
seventies.
What are we sending guys?
We can see
it's good. It's selenium.
I love selenium.
Let's do let's see. Corbett sucks.
How about that
or moneybags.
Right. That that's that's it.
That's a good one.
Okay, let's do this.
Moneybags. Okay, there we go.
So are we sending this text in here?
And then we need to click on this one.
Okay,
so now what I want to do, let's use a
CC selector, let's use
an on click attribute
and let's use contains guys.
Okay, So
then in here,
what is my tag name?
Attack name is button. All right.
And then we'll have
my square brackets in here.
Let's identify it again.
So what I can do
here on click right
and what is
what is the sign for contains guys
asterisk.
Right.
So let's put this in here
is equal to square brackets
and what we can do with just
to show in here.
Right. Or
you can just do
that in the middle
whatever containing
containing attribute value
you want to get.
You can get any
and you can see that it's one of one.
So it is unique.
And what you need to do.
One element
or find element.
So you say selector is sitting here.
All right,
then what we need to do, we need to click.
Okay. All right.
So let me run this
and see how this is going to end up.
Okay.
This beautiful.
It sounds right away nice.
Okay, guys, why did it fail?
Anyone?
Any guesses?
Okay,
we can add some fours in here, right?
Right after we navigate in here.
Okay, let's see if that's going to work.
Let's wait for 2 seconds.
Okay, Let's run this.
Yours work fine. Okay.
See? Okay,
So where did we end up going, guys?
So we clicked on Start practicing, right?
So now what we did here,
we can't click on simple form, right?
It says element, not interactive.
All Okay, that's fine.
So after we click on Start practicing
button, let's put another
weight.
And after this, let's put another word
just in case.
Okay. Yeah.
It's it's really fast probably.
So let's run this
a working on simple demo.
All right,
there we go, Moneybags show message.
And we can see the message in here,
so everything works fine, right?
And at the very end,
what we need to do is we need to
quit the browser.
Okay.
All right, guys,
any questions on CSS selector
before we go on a break?
Okay.
It's no.
Yes, sure. I'll leave this open.
Okay. It's no questions.
Let's take a break. Okay.
So 15 minute break.
Let's get back at 835.
I'll push the code at the very end.
Okay, guys,
how do we create reports on those tasks?
We will be going over those
a little bit later during the course.
Okay, guys.
So right now,
we don't have to worry about it
because we're just learning steps. Okay.
So we will be learning
how to create reports, notes.
No, not in the canvas.
I'm pushing them to the GitHub guys.
They're all in GitHub.
When you maximize. Yeah, that's fine.
That's it.
Sometimes it works
because of the different
Internet, what's called Internet
speed, right?
So it all depends on some
different various situations.
And it's selenium.
It's you can never predict
how it's going to run.
You always have to give it some time
If you don't have any steps
in your requirement.
Is it okay
if you add some steps by your own,
what kind of steps are you talking about?
Like actions to click on something
in your script?
Oh yeah. These, these are normal.
Your job is to verify some functionality
and it's all up to you
how you want to implement your weights,
your sleep time, your maximizing.
Okay, So your job is to make sure
everything is working.
They're not going to
they're not going to ask you
about how long you've for this button.
They're going to ask
you if this button is working
okay, Sorry.
All right, guys, let's take a break.
I'll see you in 15 minutes.
All right, guys, let's get back.
See, everyone is back.
Okay.
Good.
All right.
So let's go over some now Web element.
Two months.
Okay.
So, yeah.
Element two months. Okay.
If anyone do a research about Web element
commands, guys,
what do we know about Web element
commands?
We've used them already. Okay, Which one?
Which ones did we use already?
Guys, click.
Okay. That's very good.
What else?
Send keys. Right. Okay. There we go.
So what relevant commands are
methods or actions
that we can perform on our elements?
And sometimes we can get an element state
on the web page.
Okay, so Web element commands there.
It consists of several methods
where we can perform actions
and get elements state of on the page.
Okay.
So consists
of several
methods where
we can perform
actions and get
elements.
State
on the web page.
Okay.
All right.
So we've already done
click we've already done send keys.
Right.
So now there are a couple
of different commands
that we need to learn guys
in order to perform
some validations
and verifications on the page.
Okay. So the first one,
when I said
we can get a state of that element, right?
What kind of state of the elements
do we know, guys?
Anyone in research on that?
Like if, if I go to this page right now,
if I go to this page,
what is what is the state of this
login button?
Okay, it is displayed. That's very good.
What else?
Stand by. Not really
the state guys.
So it is displayed.
That's one of them.
Okay,
it is clickable.
Okay, that's. That's very good. What else?
Interactive block.
What?
What would be the state of this button
if I won't be able to click on this?
Great. Right.
What is the state.
Okay, so that's the color, right?
So the color enable.
Okay.
So this this button is enabled
and it is displayed.
Okay. So there's two there.
There are two states
for this element, right?
So there are a couple of methods
that will need to go through insulin.
You okay.
Which is the first one is is enabled.
Okay.
So this is the first method
that we to go through
which will return us what anyone gets.
It can guess what what
what are we getting in return
whenever we use this is enabled method.
We're getting it fully, right?
Absolutely right. So boolean
value in return
and we said is displayed.
There is a second method
and here we're getting a boolean
value again.
And what about some checkboxes guys?
So let's go
in here.
Let's see me actually of this.
Let's go to checkboxes. Right.
So what did I do right now?
I clicked on this.
It got selected, right?
So this the state of this checkbox
is selected, right?
So there is another method
which is called selected.
Okay.
Which will return a boolean value as well.
So now let's go back here,
let's go back and see.
So okay guys,
if I navigate to this page
and I want to enter and we already did,
right, and I want to enter something
and here we do senses, right?
But when I navigate to this page,
we don't know if there is already text
in this text
box, right? So
I don't want to guess.
I just want to perform an action
to delete everything.
So in this case,
there is a simple method to delete.
Everything from any text
box is called clear.
Okay, so clear method.
What is what am I getting in return?
In this case, guys?
Any guesses?
If I clear the text box,
what am I getting in
return?
Okay, now that means what am I getting?
I'm not getting anything right.
So This method is void.
Exactly.
Okay, so I'm not getting anything.
So that means it is a void method.
Okay, so now, guys,
when we entered something in here
and we clicked on show message,
the the message that we entered in here,
it popped up right here.
Right.
So what I want to do,
I want to verify that this
text that I entered appeared in here.
Okay?
But this element that I just
selected in here, it's not interactive,
all right?
You can't really click on it.
You can't do anything. Right.
I just need to verify that this text
that I entered in the text box
appeared in here.
Okay?
It is only visible.
Yes, but I need to get that exact text
from here, which we have a method for.
It's really easy.
It is called get text.
Okay.
So any, any text,
I mean any element
that you want to get text from,
you can use the get text
method from selenium which will return us.
What guys.
What am I getting in return in this case,
we're getting a strength value.
Absolutely.
Right.
So now, guys, there is another method
that I want to mention,
and we will go through this
during our automation right now,
which is called
Get Attribute
an attribute in here.
What do you think it's going to return us
guys?
It's going to return us a string value.
Okay.
All right.
We use get text, whatever.
The text is not tangible. Not really.
No. I mean, you can
you can use get text whenever you want
to get text from the element.
Okay.
It doesn't have to do anything
if it's tangible or not tangible.
You just need if you want if are required
to get the text from that element,
you just use the get text method
and I'll show you how everything is done.
Okay.
All right.
So let me create one class
in here. A
and clear content.
Okay.
So I'm just going to
copy and paste
where is the web order?
So we had okay, it's right here.
I'm just going to copy and paste this
or let me actually
see this.
All right.
So here, let me paste this in here.
So this website, you guys know it's
navigating to this website. Okay.
So what I want to do, I want to enter
my username and password.
Okay?
In here and what I need to do after this,
I'm going to have to clear my texts
that I enter.
Okay.
Can I share?
You should have this right?
Or if you're talking about the link,
I can share the link.
There you go.
Okay.
So we all know what is going on
on this website, right, guys?
So I'm navigating to this web page.
I am entering my username, I'm
entering my password.
So now what I want to do,
I want to clear text.
So now do I have to do
I have to identify my elements
again, Guys? No.
Why not?
We already have a variable, right?
We stored that in a variable
so we don't have to identify this element
again and again.
Right.
So in here, what I will do in here,
I'll give it a pause
so that we can see the visually
what is going on on the page.
Okay, so throw this in here.
So now what
I am going to do, I can do username got
clear and I will clear my password
as well.
Okay, so now let's go ahead and run this
and see what's going to happen.
There we go. There you go.
I hope you saw the difference.
What happened guys in
after we waited for 2 seconds.
So we entered our username.
We entered our password
and then after 2 seconds,
they all got removed.
Okay.
Pretty cool right, guys?
So you entering now
you can clear everything on the text box
and it's very straightforward
and very easy.
Any questions on this?
All clear. Okay, good.
So now let me create another class in here
and just say element.
Okay?
I have main method in here.
Okay, So now we're going to be navigating
to two radio buttons.
Okay, So this is the website
we will be navigating to.
Okay, So let me send it to you.
There we go.
Okay. So what I want to do in here,
I want to navigate to this page.
Okay?
I want to verify that this age group,
5 to 15, is selected or no.
And I want to know if it's enabled or not.
Is that clear?
Any questions on this, guys?
Okay.
All right.
So let's go back here.
So let's start with setting up
properties
right, Like Chrome
Driver and
Forever
web driver.
This is the new
Chrome driver, right?
And now
the driver
gets so
I think posted in here.
Okay.
So we navigated to this here.
So what is my next step, guys?
What do I need to do?
So I navigated to that
to that particular web page.
Now we need to find the elements, right?
So let me do the services, inspect
and let's go here.
Okay.
So I need to identify this 5
to 10.
Okay.
So what is the element
that I need to identify right now? This
is it the label or is it the input?
Which one?
So I want to write
and I want to write a question here.
How would I started
input?
Okay, let's start with input.
Input.
So which one I was looking for in here?
Can I use type guys in here?
So let's see, type
is equal to
radio.
So is it unique?
Goes. No. Right.
So we need to go with another.
We need to go
with another attribute in here.
So let's go with the value
right value and let's do five
things system.
All right, there we go.
So it's one of one.
So now we have a unique,
unique element will locate it.
So now let's go to our script
and now let's identify this driver.
But find
element of finding this by CSV selector
and I will paste this in here.
Okay,
Now let me assign this
a great deal, but
okay.
All right.
So we identified our element.
We assigned it to a different variable.
Right?
So now I want to know
if this element is enabled
right now, what do I do, guys?
Any guesses?
I'm not really. Not yet. Right.
So first of all, we need to use the
we need to use the method.
How do we use the method?
Guess variable that is enabled, right?
There you go.
So a radio button that is enabled,
right?
What is it going to return?
We guys, we said
it's going to return me
a boolean value, right?
So Boolean is a
scuse me, is a radio button
enabled
is equal to this.
Right.
So what I'm going to do,
let me print this out.
Okay.
So if I print this out, what am I getting?
Guess what is it
going to print in my console?
As some people say, False.
Some people say true.
Okay, false.
Okay, that's fine. So let's run this.
Okay, and see
what's going to happen.
Running it here.
Okay. So let's go back in here.
All right.
What did we get, guys?
We got the true value in here, right?
So when we navigate it
right, that means our
our radio button in here is enabled.
So if it's enabled,
then we should be able to click on it.
Right?
Okay, So
what I can do. So
in here, guys,
what I want to do,
I want to print something.
If this radio button is not enabled,
how would I do this?
Okay, if, if, if statement. Right.
So if condition and here
what am I having inside my
if condition
if a variable
variable name
or am I using the variable name in here
the web element name or on line 16
which one
online 16. Right.
Because that's a boolean value
and we need a boolean
value inside our can edition.
Okay, so I want to print out.
Okay, So let me copy this.
So I want to print out something in here.
Let's say whatever it is, right?
So we're printing something like this.
Okay, there we go.
So if so, if I run this right now
is, it going to print this value in here?
No. Right.
Because I have a condition in here
stating that if this is not true.
So if this is false,
only then you need to print this.
Okay, so
here we could do else
and we can print it out.
That enables or whatever.
That's fine. Okay, there we go.
Any questions on how we use the is enabled
method guys?
All right, cool.
No questions. Right.
Okay.
So now I want to see
if this radio button is displayed.
Guys.
See the meaning of enabled.
If it's enabled,
you should be able to click right
if your element is disabled
or your button or your radio
button is disabled,
you won't be able to click on.
Okay, is that clear?
Sure. All right.
So now
I want to see in my console
whether this element is displayed or not.
Okay. Okay.
So it's going to get me another boolean,
right? Is
radio button
displayed
is equal to a radio button
that is displayed right?
And here, let's print it out.
This guy.
Right.
So obviously, if I ran this,
what am I getting in return?
Is it true or false?
I'm getting a true value.
Right.
Okay, so let me run this.
Okay, So we're here.
All right.
So true. Enabled.
Then again, choose.
So that means our element is enabled
and it is displayed right on the webpage.
Okay.
So now, guys, what I want to do in here,
I want to make sure
that my radio button is selected on. No.
Okay, So
in here
we would talk that we have an is selected
method, right?
So let's use that so a radio button that
is selected.
Right.
And we can assign this to a boolean value
in here.
Right.
Is a button
selected.
And what I am going to do actually
let me print out before clicking.
Okay.
So let's put this here before
clicking, then I'm
going to copy this place to see here.
Okay.
So if I run this before clicking,
what's going to happen?
So false, right?
So let's run this.
Okay, well, here, there we go.
So before clicking, it's right
that that means
it is not selected, right?
Because it's not selected yet.
So now
what I want to do, I want to click on this
and then I want to see if this becomes
true.
Okay? Is that clear, guys?
Any questions?
Okay, cool.
So now what I need to do, I simply need
to click on that radio button
and then let's print out
after
clicking.
Then is a radio button selected?
Oh, clear. Okay, not clear.
Right click.
Okay, so I'm clicking and then.
So now what should be the result
in my console guys?
So first of all, when we check false and
then the second one should be true, right?
Okay.
So let's see.
Let's see. I'm running this.
Let's see what's
going to happen.
Okay. So it clicked.
It is selected right now, right?
So let's take a look at the console, guys.
What happened?
So here before click in is false
and after the clicking is false as well.
Why So that means
something is going on in here.
Why did it not turn as true guys
need some sleep.
Okay.
We will need to resign.
What are we really signing in here?
That is a very good point.
The boolean variable.
Right. Okay, guys.
So now pay attention in here.
Why do we have two false outputs in here?
Because we're using the same variable
on line 27 guys.
Okay, What is that?
What is the value of this boolean
on line 27?
Does.
It's false, right?
So after I click,
what am I putting in here?
I'm putting that false value again, right?
So after I click on the radio button,
what I need to do,
I need to reassign this
boolean value again
and I need to check if it is selected
after I click that, but
I click that radio button.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys? Why?
We had two false outcomes.
So now let me run this
and see what
we're going to have.
Okay, so we click.
It is selected right now.
So now if you see before clicking,
we have false.
After clicking we have a true value.
Okay, so we had to reassign this bool,
this boolean value and check
if it is selected again
and then print this out.
Okay.
Any questions guys? Yes.
We need to check after we click as well.
All right.
And then
quit.
Okay, so let me check
one more.
Okay, Guess so.
Let's go back to our notes.
Okay, so we're here.
So there's one more method on for Web
element commands that I want to show you
is this submit method.
Okay.
What what do you think
we can get in return when we use
submit method, it is a void, right?
So we're not getting anything.
So we're clearing.
We're not getting anything.
We click in, we're not getting anything.
Okay, I'll give you some time
to write down the court.
Okay, One
second, guys. Let me explain this.
Okay.
So it's a void.
We're
not getting anything in return in here.
So this submit guys will
mostly be using on
on the buttons like, okay.
Or log in or submit itself.
Okay.
So let's actually try this
in one of the
let me see.
Okay, so we have this right?
So we have this web order script in here.
Okay?
And instead of clicking on log in button,
let me try the one submit.
Okay.
And let's see
if we're able to log in to this website.
So I'm running this.
Let's see.
There we go.
I think it clicked,
but what happened with the
first
ad was too fast.
Probably.
We don't want to try this.
Did anyone get it worked?
Same result.
Okay. Same result as mine.
Okay, let me close this.
We close these.
Or maybe we can try this and Facebook
log in.
Okay, So let's see.
Okay,
So instead of
clicking here, what I'm going to do,
let's submit this, okay, on Facebook
and let me run this
and see if this is going to work.
There you go.
So now it clicked on log in, right?
It should navigate to somewhere.
Yeah. There you go.
So after this,
it went to click on the forgot password
and he quit.
But I hope you guys saw the difference.
Right?
You guys saw how it clicked on log in
and then it informed other actions.
Okay, so this submit most of the time
is use on submitting
something or clicking okay.
Or finishing something.
Okay.
Any questions on this?
On submit.
So submit is like a click guys.
Okay, click And submit.
They are pretty much doing
almost the same thing.
Okay.
But as far as I have read about submits
most of the place
it says submit works better than click.
Which one is preferable?
It's all up to you.
I'm in.
Click is mostly used.
Okay.
I haven't seen
submit actually even at work
there is
no unique
difference between click and submit guys.
They they they basically doing
the same thing on the web page.
Okay.
You can say
they're are like synonyms. Yep.
There you go.
All right.
Any questions, guys?
Let's see
Claire so far.
Okay, good.
So we did submit.
We did all the web element
commands in here.
Not all of them, but we'll be doing
the rest of them right now.
Okay, So what I will do
in here, let's actually
go and do this first manually.
Okay, So I'm going to go to eBay.
Okay, guys.
So what we are going to be
what we're going to be doing in here
is something really cool.
Okay. So let me actually inspect this.
See? Well, yeah, it's
almost the same as I said, right
to submit function.
There you go. It's applicable
for the form.
Okay. And click applicable for any types.
Right. Okay.
There you go.
Okay.
Any other questions, guys,
before we move on?
Okay.
All right.
So let me open up the box in here.
So what we going to be doing in this exact
task that we will be getting
all the links from this website?
Okay.
So I'm pretty sure you can see there's
a lot of stuff going on in eBay, right?
So a lot of links in here.
You click on this one,
you redirected to another page, you get,
you click on some other things, you get
redirected to a different page, right?
So as we can see, there's a lot of
different links on this page, right?
So how can we check
how many links we have inside this page?
Guys, Any thoughts?
A lot.
Can I get the number guys?
How can I get the number of links
on this page
using an aid tag?
Absolutely right.
So we had
a tag is used only for links, right?
So what I will do,
just going to put double slash in here
and I'll put in a tag in here.
How many links did I just find?
Garth? 406.
Right.
So some of you guys may get different
numbers.
It depends on your location as well
okay, so 400
more than 400 links on this web
page alone.
Okay.
So, Kevin, you got four 417.
So sometimes you get different
links
because most of them are hidden as well.
So some of them,
we don't see it as as you remember,
we were doing this homework
and there was two same elements,
but one of them was not visible, right?
So some of these links,
they're not visible as well
to us on the web page,
but they exist inside the HTML
485 on Amazon.
Beautiful.
Okay, So let's go back.
Let me create a new class in here.
Okay. And
from eBay.
All right.
So let's put a main method in here.
Let's set
our properties
forever.
Whenever a
new chrome driver.
Okay, so now what need to do is go
to the
eBay.com, right?
And see the thing.
Okay, so we are navigating to eBay, right?
So now, guys, let's go back in here.
So we have 406
links in here.
So I want to get all of them
and print them out in my console.
Okay.
How do you think we can do this?
Any thoughts in here?
Array? Okay.
Anything else?
Loop. Okay.
That's good.
That length.
So, okay,
before we get into the arrays and length.
Right.
So where do we store these.
So since before guys before.
If you remember, we were trying to do what
we are trying to
locate only one element
and we cared about how unique it was.
Right. And we cared about this.
We really cared about
if it was one of one right,
because we really wanted it to be unique
because we were interacting
with only one element here.
We interacting with more than one element.
Okay, so now
it is time for us to use
the Java data structures.
Okay,
so what do we know about collections guys?
What can we use in here from collections?
What kind of container can
we use to put all these elements in there?
You haven't seen them.
You didn't
you guys didn't cover collections.
How is that possible?
You guys didn't cover
the array.
Did you guys cover list? What
what is the topic you're
on right now?
Encapsulation.
Okay, this is not good.
Okay.
List is only this Saturday.
A lot of time on reviewing the homework.
Oh, okay.
Okay. This is really sad.
You guys,
because we're not going to have fun today.
Okay? All right.
I thought you guys covered this.
This is not good.
Not the end of the class.
I'll show you anyways, guys,
but it would be really good
if you covered this.
So it's okay
now. I'll show you anyway.
Okay, But that's fine.
Okay, Let's do this.
Okay.
So before
we used to find only one element.
Okay?
Before we used to find
only one element.
So now it's time for us to manipulate
with different, different elements.
Okay?
At the same time,
we won't be able to use our race, guys.
Okay, so here's what I will do.
If you remember before, what we were doing
is only finding one element.
Okay, so now, since we have a
lot more than we have than we used to
do, right?
So it's more than one right now.
So now what we need to do,
we need to find multiple elements.
Okay?
So we will be using different
and different elements right now.
Okay.
So I'm going to go ahead
and put find elements now.
And what we're going to do in here,
we will be
finding elements by what?
What am I finding my elements by now?
So if you look here,
what am I getting my all my lengths
by? What is the locator in here
by tag name?
Right, exactly.
So what I will do in here,
I'll do a tag name
and what I can do, I'll just put as
the a tag.
Okay, So pretty simple.
And I'm finding now multiple elements
by the tag name.
Okay. Is that clear, Guys,
any questions on this?
Exactly.
Find element returns only one element
Find elements
will return you a list of web elements.
Okay.
So if you see in here
you're getting in return.
If I can find
find element
A yet
you are getting less of the web elements.
Okay.
So what I will do, I will simply assign it
to a list of web elements in here.
I know you guys didn't cover this,
but it's okay.
So I'm just going to show you this.
Okay.
List of web elements and I can do
all links
is equal to these driver dot
Find elements by the tag name. Okay.
And you can import the list from java.
Util. Okay. Library.
So now guys, what I did in here,
all these elements are stored inside
one container.
Is that clear, guys?
So you don't have to understand
this one for now, okay?
Because you guys didn't
cover this for Java.
Okay, so what I did?
Basically,
I got all those links by the tag name
and I stored them inside the container.
Okay, so now it's time for me to go ahead
and see how many links I have.
Okay.
So I want to print out
the number of links in my console.
Okay.
So number of links in here, it's
not an integer, it's just a content.
It's a list of the web elements.
Okay?
So that's why what I will do in here,
I'll do all links dot size.
Okay, So in array guys,
you use the you used to use
length
or in in strings you can use length,
but in list you use size.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys?
So whenever you use size,
then it will return you the integer okay,
you can't just use all links this variable
because it won't return you.
The number of the
of how many elements you have.
Okay, so now let's run this.
Okay, let's run this and see
what's going to happen.
You can't use length, okay?
Because this is a different data
structure, that's why.
Okay, so we it here.
So now you can see it decreased.
It was 406 before.
So now is 397. Okay.
So if you remember guys
in arrays you use length, length.
So for the list you will be using size.
Okay. So
So yes, for list
you will be using size for arrays.
You use length.
I'm not sure why the number decrease guys.
I'm not sure it's
probably something going on with the
what's called
it's probably something going on
with the website.
Okay. It's not on our side.
We can't really do anything. Goodbye.
Okay So now,
guys, since.
So now what I want to do, I want to print
each and every what
Each and every link in my console guys.
So any.
Any guesses how we can do this?
Now this returns
this size method will return integer only.
Okay, this is not an integer guys.
Okay.
All right.
So now we will be using Java, right?
So now we're going to be looping
through each and every element
inside our container.
Okay.
So now let's
go ahead and create a for loop in here.
So there is one shortcut
I'm pretty sure you guys familiar with
advanced for loop or for each loop right
there is advanced loop.
Regular loop, right? Or
okay, good.
All right.
So there's a shortcut to create a
for each loop.
Okay. In here.
Okay. Yes.
You haven't done for it yet. That's good.
And you're learning encapsulation already.
Okay. Nice. Okay.
Okay.
So there's shortcut in here
to create a for each What you could do,
you could just write down for each
one here and click enter
and you will have something like this
ugly.
But we don't really need that
like this.
So let's just take this here. Okay?
So what are we looping through,
guys?
Links, right? What are what are the links?
So as as far as Selenium objects, guys,
so the link is what?
It's a web element, right?
So what we do and we're looping
through each and every web element,
Okay, so going to put this in here,
but we are all our links
are stored inside this container.
Okay So what I'm going
to do, I'm going to copy this
paste is in here.
And on the other side
we will have a web element
because we are looping through each
and every web element.
Guys, it's not a string, right?
It's a web element.
So what we can do web element link,
and we're looping through each
every
element from this container.
Okay.
So now, guys, I want to
let me actually print out the
the text for each and every link.
So if you go in here,
look, if I inspect this, right.
So is a link, right?
This matters. Our link.
Fashion is a link.
Electronics is a link.
These are all
elements are links.
Okay.
And these are what this music deals toys.
What are these for?
For the elements, guys, it's a link text.
Right?
So now what I want to do,
I want to get the text from each
and every web element
that I have in my container.
Okay.
So now if you remember,
we talked about the web
element command,
which is which says get text.
Okay.
So what we are going to be doing now,
we will be getting
text from each and every
element.
Okay. So
my link.
Right.
Get text in here.
What am I getting in return?
Guy? See, I'm
getting in return a string, right?
So I can do string
link.
Text is equal to this.
Let's actually simplify.
Okay.
So now what I simply want to do,
I want to print this
link text in my console.
Okay, so now let's run this, guys.
Okay, let's run this and see
what's going to happen.
Okay. When navigated to IB.
Okay, now let's pay attention to our
console.
Okay.
Nothing's popping out.
Beautiful. Why?
Nothing is happening, guys.
Any thoughts?
Your computer shut down.
All yours is good.
Okay, that's good.
Okay. Okay.
So you getting a lot of them, right?
Okay, so this is really weird.
Why mine is not working.
Well, Yeah.
Okay, good.
Okay, maybe I.
Oh, there we go. Now we're talking.
Okay, I have to scroll down.
Okay. Okay, Now we're talking.
Okay.
There we go.
So we have a lot of stuff in here,
right? So.
But see, guys in here, what I am seeing
is something empty
in here. Why?
Why am I getting so many spaces in here?
Guys?
Are those the hidden links?
Or they
might be the links with no text on them.
Okay, there we go.
So they might be links,
but there's no text for those.
Okay.
All right.
19 to 21 because we have a container
on line 16 and we want to go through each
and every element from that container.
Okay.
And then what we need to do, we want to
get the text and print that text.
Okay, list is like an array,
but it's a little different.
So you guys are going to cover this
this weekend.
I'm really surprised
you guys didn't cover this.
Okay.
But it's okay.
So it should be straightforward.
It's not that difficult.
Okay.
Okay, guys.
So now what I want to do, I want to print
only the text,
which has an actual value.
You guys, how would I do this?
Am I and Asger
going to have a boxing match now?
Not really.
I'll probably win
anyways, but we'll see.
Okay.
Yeah.
This is fun, guys.
I'm telling you
is this is the fun.
Okay? Yeah.
Ask him on Saturday. That's fine.
Go ahead, guys. Okay.
All right.
Okay, guys.
So now I only want to print the text,
which only has the values.
Guys, how would I do this
is empty.
Absolutely right.
So only if my condition.
Only if my text is not empty.
I want to print that out. Right.
So if my link text
is not empty, right?
Only if it's not empty,
what I am going to do,
I am going to print this out.
Okay.
All right.
So let's run this.
Let's run this
and see if we can get anything in here.
Okay?
We're getting this again.
Okay.
Beautiful.
I need to remove this.
Guys. Right.
Okay,
Move this.
Okay. It's
around this again.
Okay, so now not.
This should work.
Okay.
Navigates here.
Obviously works.
Yep. There you go.
So it's printing now,
but there's no spaces, anything.
So we printed all the
all the link texts which are.
Which have only values.
Right.
So now, guys, what I want to do in here,
I want to print the links as well.
So I want to see the links for advanced.
I want to see the link for sign in.
I want to see the link for register
right by right after this.
Okay.
So can we do this?
Hopefully, yes. Right.
So now, guys, the only
command left for us
to use is get attribute.
Okay, where is our link
is specified in our html
guys under what actually execute
on their address.
Right.
So if you look in here
a trough eBay feed or whatever.
Right.
So see if we have any different ones
of this
see in here.
So there we go.
So we have a trough
and then another link, right?
So when we use this get attribute guides,
it will not get the attribute itself,
but it will get the value of,
the attribute we will be providing.
Okay, Is that clear, guys?
So the attribute we provide
by using get attribute method,
it will get the attribute itself,
but it will get the value.
Okay, so let's go back in here.
So what I am going to now in here,
I'm going to do link dot
get attribute and what is the attribute
we need in here guys.
We need an address attribute,
right?
The link would not be clickable
in the result.
Right now we don't really care
about the click ability.
Right. Right now we are caring.
We care about capturing that length.
Okay, we're going to capture the link
and then what we're going to do,
we're going to print it out.
Okay, So now
we're going to do a track in here because
all our links, any link, will be stored
inside that, a track attribute, right?
So it's going to return me
a string value as well.
Okay.
So now, guys,
what I need to what I see in here
this full link is going to be my link.
And now what I can do in here
is just put some space in here and last
full length, okay?
Only if link text is not empty,
I will print out the link
text and I will print out the link
itself.
Okay.
So I'm running this right now.
So let's go ahead and see.
So if this is going to work, there we go.
So if you look in our console
right now, we have the text
and the link itself
right by its side, right?
So we captured all the link texts
and the links themselves
by getting the text
and getting the attribute values
and printing them inside
inside the console.
Okay, Pretty cool, right?
This was the fun part, but I think Asghar
ruined it because he didn't cover list.
Okay.
But anyways, it's pretty cool guys.
We just, we just written what,
five lines of code in here
and we have this kind of outcome in here.
Okay, so this is pretty cool
working with the get attribute
and get text.
So now guys, we,
you know all the commands, right
for the web elements.
You know a little bit
about the list in here.
Okay.
But you're going to be covering it
in more details
this weekend So
it's not that difficult guys
so yeah here
and then we started actually
using the logic from Java, right?
We're not only doing
clicks and keys and everything,
but we using Java language and building
Java.
Logic's in here as well.
How you will be teaching lists now. Yes.
Teach list So as dark
we're going to be
using a lot of Java. Yes.
So we will be integrating Java
with selenium.
Okay.
So, so selenium
is for you to perform actions
on the web page.
Java is to build that logic. Okay.
So like we did today,
the logic is built by the for loop
and for loops are coming from Java,
but getting the text,
getting the attribute right,
these are coming from Selenium.
So we're basically
using two different tools
in order to have some different outcomes.
Okay.
There you go.
Yes, do this. Do this to us. Go. Okay.
Tell them to at you first
tomorrow review.
I'm not sure.
I don't know what was.
I'm has on his
on his notes
pretty much I'm sure you will be covering
some of these classes.
That's why you're learning Java.
Absolutely right.
Because your whole logic
will be going through the Java guys.
Okay.
Using pairing.
Absolutely.
You guys,
you will be using all the parent classes,
children, neighbors, whatever it is.
Right.
So you will be using
a lot of polymorphism.
You will be using a lot of inheritance.
Okay.
I'm not sure if we're going to be
using a lot of encapsulation,
but you will be using a lot of inheritance
and polymorphism.
All right.
So let me see.
Okay. Homework, guys.
Let me check.
Okay. I need to
log in from here,
look out
and know.
Okay.
Okay. So three tasks for you.
Okay, guys,
Three tasks for you.
I will push the code. Okay.
Any suggestions for websites
to practice to practice Java or
which one?
Selenium. Not really.
You could just
Google selenium practice
and it's going to give you
a lot of different websites, guys.
Okay.
For Java, there are some late code, but
that's that's really advanced stuff guys.
Okay.
So late code.
And then I forgot what the other one was,
but meet code I think it's it's
you need to pay for that.
Yeah, it's been a while.
I didn't really look into these practicing
websites. Yes.
I'll post the course announcements
in class announcement.
Let me explain you what it is, guys.
Okay,
so first of all, what you want to do?
You want to
go to this website which is here.
Okay.
And then log in. Okay.
I put the username and password in here.
What you want to do?
You want to log in?
Okay.
When you logged in, I want you to verify
that this logo is displayed.
Okay?
And then you can quit the browser.
So the second one,
what you want to do is the same thing
as we did for eBay.
But you're going to be doing it
for Amazon.
Okay, Get all the links from Amazon, get
the text,
the links themselves and print them out.
Okay, second one is easy as well.
So now
the third guys.
Third one, what you want to do is
go in here, let me logged out.
Okay, so you want to
go to this page, enter the valid username
and leave the password
field empty and click on login.
Okay.
When you click on log in, verify that this
message is displayed on the page.
Okay, guys,
is that clear?
Okay.
All right.
Seems like you guys like the
like the task, so that's good.
All right.
I'll be giving you more attacks
diff and further classes.
Okay, guys.
So please
complete this until the next week.
And please pay attention
to the collections that you will be doing.
It would ask.
Okay,
so those collections are really, really
important guys.
We will be using them a lot in Selenium
as well.
Okay.
All right.
Any questions, guys?
Any questions on what we've done so far
today
or in general?
Um, sure.
Okay.
So this is everything, guys.
The notes and the notes and the homework.
Okay.
I just shared in the live chats.
Okay. All right.
I hope you guys had some fun today
with these links and everything,
but let actually take a look
what we're going to have next week.
Okay.
So next week, guys,
we're going to be working with checkboxes
we're going to be working
with the radio buttons
and we will be working with dropdowns.
Okay.
So please take a look.
Please do your research.
I'll upload the slides as well
for the next class.
So please take a look at that
and will be going through those next week.
Okay.
All right.
So if there's no questions, guys.
Thanks, everybody.
I'll push the code right after the class
and I'll see you next week, okay?
Have a good night and stay safe.
Everybody.