All relates
Java and
the rest assured
API days
by the use Java.
Rest assured API.
What is the reason behind this?
Why we using
it is an automation duty.
It isn't.
It is a library basic
java based library date.
Yes, it is.
A job is to enable
it to be used to automate.
What kind of MBA is gates to automate
lest it be a
java.
Rest assured,
API is the library to automate.
The list could be at
this point
just a short API.
But now here, tell me one thing
when you talk about the rest
list of service, it transfers their data.
It transports their data in each one.
This could be a transfer of data.
In particular, automate. What is it one to
choose an object or to
them for my create?
It allows data to be sent across
in JSON forward on JSON object.
So when we talk about using
form it or JSON object,
what it consist
based object consist of
key and value both. It
just an object consists of the key
and when you file
now not here
when you talk about Java,
rest assured library because for menu
this type of API has to be
is going to be a lot of liquids
to be a lot of responses
and it to do can be verified.
The tool can be verified
already of the response.
So many things predict.
But whatever that these were,
it was strictly on manual part.
Now we are going to work on the API part
for automation.
So that's
why we're using illustration library.
So when we talk about Java, this library,
it follows one
particular approach
to test in the API via automation.
What is the approach?
What is a book based?
It's BDD approach.
So by default by
the board, just rest assured
it follows BDD approach, very driven
development approach,
fine imagery approach.
Greystone
which gives we should really focus on
when the argument is even more
we focus on given
then that
we focus on these three key
keywords, correct, these three is fine.
So now the end is here.
When we talk about given,
what does it mean
in API industry,
what is the meaning of Google?
Right?
Depending the request, the list
when it comes to when by we use this
in making the request
or simple
thing, the end point.
Right.
And the third one is then.
Then we use for verification or
or response
or rate response.
So this given this demand return something
which we generally stored in one
particular bar, what is that back
base?
When we talk about given
by preparing the request
after making the request,
this given gives us one part.
What is that? Yes, this is
the request is specification.
It means whatever the specifications
we need to make a request
and it'll give you compute one.
So we provide one.
Be able to enable,
be prepared, request late
request.
And then when we heard
that you are the end point
using this prepared request,
so it returns something.
What is that
the response
response
something.
And when we get the response by,
we use this particular response.
Actually the variable response by the user
is variable
to hold the complete information
that we are getting in the moderate body.
The response now from here either
if you want to print something,
we can print something.
If you want to print every single thing,
we can print every single thing
if we want to.
A very particular information
from the body that also we can do from the
right,
we can perform all of this verification
and validation type of operations
using this response keyword,
which is every more
correct.
Well, no, no.
After this,
we added two things in the dependency on
what are those two things?
The first one is
an additional
because this is a library,
and the second one is
just because data would be transferred
in there in JSON object, right?
So we would need to send this to short
and just in the added right pool.
Think of it.
We added this to short notice
right now
it looks to supplied,
so it should be +68
and we are going
to get all of these things
locally.
So the first thing we did was we did
a simple test
rate, simple first, a simple request first
to send it back to
with an all of my database related
methods and everything is available
or not simple that we created.
Simple.
Just what was the simple test
is all about.
That is maybe a simple
that it benefits from to get the response.
Not fine, but the request was all about
getting in
and oh, he is
using API.
Right?
One is specific information
from the database we need for that one
so that either we would be able
to find the data from the data base
for one particular employee.
For this reason.
For this reason
we have used this particular seven
quickest
file.
So what are the things we need to do
is to make a request.
What are the things we need?
Okay, so the first thing is basically
what I now take relates the base.
You are right in Java.
Rest assured, reliability is what
it means.
Simple. Basically you want to write java
just a short API a distance
because you are right.
Is busy. You want and
is busy you want and perfect fine.
After this big need is
we need for this.
In headers we provide two things together.
And what are those two things
was on data
and this is
authorization.
Go ahead.
Or is this.
You'll get the gist of what to put
in this
authorization. But
after this, anything else?
Do we need to prepare the request face?
Yes, we need credit. Mm.
So from the bunch of information,
from the bunch of information
we would need,
what is specific information
that are not public
employees available at a point.
So from those lot of employees,
we need one
specific employee,
one particular employee.
So for that we need quality management
and we need what is better than debate
whether it is an employee
or it is a unique number associated with
or whatever it is, what do we need
that unique part right now?
Now, after this, after this,
when we are getting the request, we got
one request is specific request, right?
We got one prepared request.
That request
we will send using keyword using keyword.
So what is that keyword? When
do we need
do we need something else within?
We need to provide
what kind of command we are going to make
if we are going to make get called
most call along, it will be able
to provide this information.
Right?
So when don't you don't post
don't put whatever
and what we are going to make,
we have to specify that
and then we will provide the value
of the particular point.
Now, no, after this, after this,
when we talk trend keeper,
then you would be using for
verification,
verification and validation purpose
like for verification
and validation
purpose, a certain thing, correct.
Now this one will return
every single thing ready to be provided,
even keyword be provided here
it was given you would be provided when?
Before then.
But are we actually executing anything
till this point?
We are not actually executing.
Ready to execute something.
To execute something, we need some test.
What is that as to which one
we are using the execution point
because we are not dealing with Java min
method, right?
So when we are not dealing with min
method, what is the other part?
What is the alternative part?
We have to, in
the test, find
the best values for this
and the request videos
it from
yes, this is coming from your
do you need not trump entity
now here is
what I'm going to do is see
first thing was think
we need to understand great first thing
we need to understand what is that thing
we need to understand here?
Ghost Major's work.
We need to understand this
and rest
lectures.
Now what is this estimate? Yes.
Is there anyone ever heard
this term we should get
the response is response as a string? Yes.
Correct.
That I will complete contribute because
I'm going to use one very good keyword.
Right.
The period when there is a keyword,
we are going to use three.
But so now remember here
in hand just matters
when we talk about this right by
we generally use this class list
mentor's class.
Remember this class contains methods
for associations.
Hem may just be selected.
This is that last grade.
It contains all the methods
to perform letters.
And so whatever the associations
verification,
validation check points we are doing,
we are taking.
Everything comes from increased lectures
and this work, everything
comes from implicit matrix.
Is it like snippet?
No, it does not like snippet.
These are simply providing the methods.
Read one example dot clear from Selenium.
Dark gate from selenium
don't seem to give promising
like this
line gets.
Now when we talk about Java,
rest assured, I'm telling you
again and again multiple times
I said Right there it is, Java.
Rest assured API allows data to be saved
in this environment or in just an object.
So here we have to take it all
just but
now it is what is the difference
in between JSON and if you like this
just fine,
what is the difference
in between these two
days?
What is the difference
between this distant part?
And this is
what is a method.
One is object need look
amazing.
Which one is object need
for this method for sure.
Remember the first of month is the class
this JSON but
this class that it emit.
And what are you in stumbling?
I'm coming to stumble next month.
Oh need don't come up.
Baklava, baklava interactivity.
Three things I would need to
be ready with that
next month.
Decent but is class
right.
And then.
And then. Here
is some
bit better.
This this is the met.
There is a method
will longs to
disembark the class.
One is a class
and another is a matter that belongs
to that particular class.
In one of the three here.
I mean then I'm coming next year,
hopefully to this summer.
Already it is delayed.
We never have been the same, but
above and below as four.
So in our and above.
But like invited
any point of time forward.
And what if you just want to work policy
based on that?
Then what would a
white
now no basis.
One more thing
you should get on
got a designation.
Maybe it may not do this if or order late.
It will help us definition
spy on a certain vibe be use this term
as when it ends up to get a job.
We should all to connect them
and get it right.
If you say this, they already exceeded
what is my big it same me.
I know them.
Whatever the response,
whatever the response rate we are getting,
just to bring the next particular response
in between.
So we need this particular method points
system standard output printing
to bring something in the console
because blind is use
question is why we use a standard order.
People in
exactly makes sense.
Okay, so guys remember
remember when we talk about system
not older
non windows right we use this
we can bring everything
onto the console what we engage
in using this particular dump
the speed kind of response
speed of operation
we can perform
using one particular matter in space.
What is that method.
What is that better.
So you can write it.
Very good. You
open this here, Here.
Instead of writing this down,
it can very simple response
dart pretty print
response, not pretty print.
Right.
So when you write response,
not pretty print.
It also does the same thing.
This monster printed print, basically.
Right? So let me write it
this print
does the same as
system or all dog friendly
print and you
might
let me first guys create a new token
because I know why this token is inspired.
Already a new book, The Case.
How would I know the point Open is expired
or didn't do it outside because it
got a hundred.
But this user is not for this checker
to generate them.
They get already.
I read this
with the face of his team.
You are absolutely correct.
It happened to tamper the expert
in this game Blackwood
in the class.
Now let's try to run.
After updating the token object,
it might open
base.
Can you see the same kind of response
I got?
But without using the standard ogre
printed?
Now I'm not using system, but
still I got the same response.
Response, not predicament.
Correct.
Is this correct
file?
Fine. Now,
now the next thing, the magic of correct.
So remember days we used this pretty print
command instead of system dot dot print,
and then it will also perform
the same operation which we generally
perform using the standard of printed.
It means printing, the result
of printing the things under the pencil.
Understood
printing the output under the pencil
using pretty print command
understood this.
But now let's see for the mixing
we are going to
we are intimately
I think we're pretty clear
night is the image
or the notion you used with 3D
print amazing.
So here guys, remember we have to perform
all the operations, right?
But as all the operation simply means,
what are those operations?
Digitally performing behaviors,
Great operations, right.
So retrieval done.
I knew other doing operations also.
But right now we did a retrieval
operation.
Let's add something in there
database straight via automation, right?
Manually.
We have created lot of things, but now in
are going to focus on manual creation.
We are going to focus on automation.
Part. It's getting
of. Now let me ask you one thing.
Give everyone
this token which I generated, this token
which I used here right?
Can I use this token for creating
an appliance or for that I have to use?
I have to generate a new book,
How things work for that.
Can I use the same token? Yes, but.
But to create the employee.
See, I have to write a new post.
I have to write the new post.
So I'm going to write the request
I'm seeing here.
Public void Be
So now tell me
this particular part, which is the base.
You are right in this particular
token is under this method.
How can I use that under this method?
How can I use that?
Because it is already in one method.
We have to make it as instance
standard variable, right?
So to make it instance
variable, what we have to do
is I really don't know what I have to do.
How can I make it instance with even
be able to make it static?
Okay,
what if I simply write it here like this
instead of writing it under the method?
What if here
we did work
but I didn't defined as it as a static,
then identified it as static.
Is it necessary
to make any variable instance?
I have to buy a static.
No, but.
And then me.
One more thing. This. Can I call?
Can I call any non static
variable in the static method
denied call any static
variable in non static method.
My method is not a static unknown static
nonstandard.
If I made my variables static,
will I be able to call them?
Will I be able to call
all of my variables?
No. Then why were you saying that?
Make it static
then why already you saying make it static
and we guys
here just instance good enough.
Now here I'm going to provide this value.
Right?
So now see this value
instead of using this particular part,
I will simply use the key.
Right?
I'm not going to use all of this things.
So instead of using this part,
I would simply call this broken
shortcut blade
replace.
We need to work or not.
And what would it work?
Perfect.
So now, now see here
what I'm going to create the employee.
What is the first thing we have to do
is to create the
request specification.
I would see prepared.
The bag of request is equals
to what I do based
with no cost.
If we are making the request
we have to use given given dart
now this
time, this time we have to use headers
constraints, the water.
What are the hurdles to be able to use
case?
The force that I would use is
or think that was true.
That is going to take value.
So what would be the value?
This allegation
application slash to
dart?
I would need another header.
Right.
So what is the end of the database here?
Would be my one
or two.
Right?
My authorization.
So here I would need a simple token
which I generated
which I generated dart
Now to create an employee,
what is the next thing we need?
We need body just to
so we need now another thing that is body.
So let me call this here
already.
Tell me how we can rid the body,
how we can rate the body.
Any idea
from swagger we can pick from here.
Also, we can take we have a body already
available right?
And these are
the things we need in the body.
And so now if I go to my this part
and if I keep this
so this is the body.
This is the body, I would be
perfect.
Let's change the data.
So here I need
first
was named should be normal
and a
you a although it's I in your name
I or you everything will look
nice.
The entire concept of global asset
consultants available
go last name
and then
last name
and obviously middle name is one only.
No one can do this to me.
Even if it is no any.
That would be M because there is this
little word.
Because in the end will
you call people body that form
just copy dead body pasted here
simple business, just copy
the body and pasted it by default.
It takes like this
simply it goes to new line.
It goes to new Line.
So it put slash and by default it is
it is a word by default.
If you want to read,
what do we do with this?
Let's use with slashes,
not renewable anything
because yeah, it could
and leave it as it is.
No, use it on just leave it.
It is just a former
that we are getting that this way again
if you copy by default copied like this,
you don't really get
no now here I'm going to use
it being named be it
because no one in any boat
are getting that security name being
my job
title should be Q
employs to this
well one name default moment.
No it happened
just three years ago when the name
I'm giving you actually 18 named
Fine Guys.
We are making that in so we would need
this new water
which is equivalent to base.
You want it.
So we provided it as an instance.
So second thing so can be
provided is a bit
and so that all data my API except data
from any easy.
Okay so now I have learned my API
in Greek page.
So now here here we have grade based.
You are right we have broken.
Okay.
Is it earlier or given that me
honestly that you want me to change
the let me change it.
But so basically token body headers.
We have all these things right now.
Understand one thing, guys,
when we are going to hit the end point,
right when we are going to get the end
point with this, prepare request
or what would happen,
but hitting the end point,
it wouldn't generate the employee.
It will generate the employee not based
right now, not what I need.
Basically, it will give me whole lot
the whole lot of information
that employee created is reasonably dense,
all the information in that one
particular string with the key.
And when JSON object one key
and when do evaluate what does that employ
and is equals to some APIs.
Correct.
It would talk about the whole body
you will get the message
employed created is being employed
is equal to something positive is equal to
this is equal to this class.
There was equal to this storm, correct.
So now now here when we talk about request
a specification bar,
they preparing the request,
we have to take care of this thing.
Now we ready post
when we are going to
the end point.
So this end point work with response.
So once I get the response
I will be prepared request
not proven or proposed.
Great
request.
What kind of request is this?
Is what kind of request is this
post request?
How we get this information
that this is boss request simple go here.
It will give you this is mostly based on
see this is post request.
Now this simple part
the simple end point compute
copy and be strategically employing
this create employee
database.
First we will bring simple post
will bring simple to get
what is next and building on the response
we would print today.
We are not going to use now this.
But your system got out
and we use something else.
What is that
to bring something to reduce
response time pretty
response not repeating
trend this
First, let's see
whether we are getting the response on
employee created
employee created getting
there is an API working.
Yeah.
And we will perform a a and so first I'm
just trying to show you something so.
It says my API is working fine.
Correct.
Now see
when I got the complete response in
just before we start predicting
right
here, I'm not going to focus on this part
that response
or as this being or something.
Remember we were using in a stronger order
response start as is shrink.
That's what we are like. Correct.
Now here, here we are not creating dark
as is being or something,
but still
I'm reading the same response. What
what I'm getting at is same response. This
what is the reason behind this?
Because by default, your pretty printing
method is giving the particular response
and the string format that we can see
or to the console.
So we don't have to specify the way we were specifying in the standard of printing
logic.
Months
now, after this act, this here
we have to use one particular video.
What is this variable?
We need one variable to store the employ.
And so how we can use
first.
First,
we have to feature all the information
and we have to take one
particular information from the body
of the consolidated,
one particular information we need,
and we would leave
all the information the story.
So now how we can rate.
Remember,
I was telling you one thing
just so font is a class in
which JSON part is an object is
it is a method of the particular class.
Right. It holds the information.
My job is to short API announce data
that will be sent in to some forward.
It seems to that
in just a moment, remember
amongst roommates
remember this are not fine.
So now here
I'm going to use that particular part
just on the method.
I'm going to use JSON, but not really.
We discussed the state. JSON is a class
in which just did this JSON,
but with this parentheses is a method.
So this method we are going to use
and I'm seeing here
I am seeing here one thing
what is this one thing?
So now let me show you.
If you go here
and if you observe it closely, this multi,
if you go in, if you observe it closely,
what is the gist
and what it is using or what is a distant
object is using.
So here can you see this as employ?
You would get capability.
This employee object usage is some object
and in this object
these keys are relevant.
All these keys
are available under this, particularly
when you actually send the data.
It is not employee budget,
but when you actually getting the data,
actually getting the response, you
are going to see this particular employee.
It is nothing, but you're just an object
that is your all the values,
post them the name, last name,
nationality, great job, title,
employment status, employee.
All these things are associated
to one particular distant object
and that object is employee here
in the body.
Right?
So with the reference to this employee
object, we have to specify the data
rate, for example, employee dot first
name or employee DOD employee 80
something like this,
something like this to filter other data.
So so I'm seeing here
I am seeing here
this in this just fine, but Google,
it's doing
okay from the decent part,
which was the complete information under
response, converted to the string form
and then give me the string for work.
So I'm seeing from this employee,
remember this, this get sensitive place
if you use small e here,
it will not work. Why?
I would believe this employee, Don
Roy, or maybe this venue should be seen.
This venue should be seen
as available in the body.
So this employee is
the object is employed.
80 is the key, right?
So whatever the venue is available
under this particular flag, under
this particular keyword and mentioning
here, it is stored there 20.
So do store this venue.
I have to define but variable or not
nice.
This particular part
will return me the employee I.D.
so I have to define one variable or not.
Yes. And variable is of what nature
to hold the information.
Right. So let me right here.
The third thing is I'm going to load
stream
and control I d equals to simple is free
employee.
I includes this employee entity
and it is
willing it work like this
is going to work
like this.
First, let's check simple.
I'm going to put employee right
because I'm putting specific value.
So for a specific value
I'm using this term don't go prepayments.
So this time let me change
this name to see
and it need to be fine.
And now
when I try to generate this employee,
when I try to create the employee,
see what would happen.
Guys, can you see
I got one specific venue here
coming my employer correct or not, I'm
not getting any additional information,
any other thing.
I'm just getting my employer ID,
which I generated that employee
which I generated
and retrieving this data from there.
I mean, you can cross-check this data
from you
see, this is the value generated.
This is the value
Both values are seen with the readings.
Which employee could it
get it
right but still is still here.
One but is it remaining?
What is that
liquid ideal?
Plus we use
this month method
to get
the object
specific information
from the
case.
An object trait
we get specific information
from The JSON object
we need is just an automatic
rate.
Now guys,
this is the time to perform a session.
This is the time to perform a session
right?
Right.
So now see how we can perform
different type of positions.
Remember we were writing their test.
Do what were writing
that does to remember this
object.
So then you are writing them best. There
we use the library.
What is that
for? Writing the test in Postman.
Yeah, see? And remember. Great.
We used to write a session named
We deserve to work on line number 58.
We are using what is specific database
you see pretty print
we're using blueprint.
The response become good response.
So to date one
specific thing I use this term
even though we are not going to use it,
it is just to show you with beam
object it here.
I told you they had to be used,
as they put it, for assertions.
Here we are going to use one
for assertions.
What has all the methods
for assertions based?
One particular class?
Which class?
I just told you.
Implicit matchups
we will use and list images here like so.
Now see how we can use any posting
if we are going to create the employee.
What is what is the status?
What I should expect
if I change it
because we already created
one employee here with your me one.
So this time
then I want you to create a new employee.
I would need new data
just to show you this.
Why I changed the
object.
It is just.
Yeah, I changed to a you Dag.
You guys don't get confused.
Or do you get confused by now?
See this assertion part?
So here in a solution
we can read it by its certain limits.
Begin with certain stages
and validate data in different levels.
How loosely?
First,
we have one particular variable here in a
in a request grade that holds
all the information up as creating
what consent,
which one boards on the information.
After reading into
response rate.
So we will use this response
as the reference point to perform all sort
of verification in validation, to perform
all sort of verification and validation.
We use this just once for.
So let me write
a response dot then
don't assert that dot.
Let's first specify
and verify status report case.
So tell me what is the status
quote? We should expect it
to zero one
because you
know, now let's see,
I'm going to work with my first name.
So this time I'm going to change my middle
name.
Great.
Somewhere we my image,
I want to verify, because if you remember,
we were sending the data
to creating an employee.
And after creating an employee,
we were getting the
status quote,
but we were not getting the correct body.
If you guys remember that
there was a glitch in the API eight.
So it was not showing the current data,
it was not showing the correct data
point of time.
So here, here, let's see.
That was the glitch in the API
bug. Got it.
So here, let's see
whether I am sending the data in.
The same data is
it is returning in the response or not.
Whether that is changing
or the same two days coming.
Right.
This is something we need to do,
but it is something we need to take.
Get on
to this.
So now,
now let's work on this particular part.
I'm going to use it
right here.
I'm going to write response.
No, Then don't assert that.
Don't.
I'm seeing length of the body
in the body check for
Roy Dot
employee
Karma
equal to
or to just to import.
But it's not working or you don't.
It's not see
it was not taking there
do not equal straight I'm
putting this here
I'm going to provide the value
so now see earlier
it was giving me the error rate.
I don't know why it's not taking
what it is from or not increased matters.
Right. So we have to write it manually.
This matters important for
everyone.
This important study
out of g m Grist mentors
these holmquist majors class
we use here to perform
verification and validation.
This generated this
in someone
based in the to the champion good
now C Foster,
let me delete this part from you
and then if I call this one
C it is giving me equal to any C from
majors and list matches.
It is giving me equal
days.
It is giving me equal to right.
So now this majors part is working.
When this is equal to I'm going to provide
simply the of the value would be complete.
It will perform all the verification
sort of stuff.
Then next thing let's see,
I want to really find it.
If I'm sending a body right,
if I'm trying to create an employee.
So after creating employment
message should be in the body.
What is that message?
What message
appears in the body? What is that message
employee created?
Right.
This message always appears in the body.
Employee Fine.
So we need this employee deleted part.
So now tell me one thing.
If I write here like this responds Don
then Don
a certain don the body
should that it embroidered message or not
should I simply message or should it
just message.
But why not employ that message?
Because because here you see this employee
object does it contains
your content,
your message message is something else
and the body of employee
something else that it.
So again, I will call this method equal to
equal to market.
In here I'm going to use
message to message should be mine
employee
right.
Which would be the correct one.
Is this correct one
And now now let's see.
I want clean if I want more things.
What is that thing?
For example, I want to verify here
from groups do this couple.
Remember I told you we can
verify of things in the contained body,
in the responsibility.
We can verify this again
by the time we can verify a lot of things.
Right.
So let's see if I want to verify
which server did this coming from.
Right.
So how we can get that sort of
maybe rest of this.
You are not said
about an English server name.
This is the anchors of the server base.
You are right.
Is the end result of the server.
It's simply like I'm talking
about having your name
and your giving the address of your house.
These are two different things
that is telling me
I already showed you this point
server name.
I already showed. We can get this from
Zima. Yes.
Any do you need to?
Elena Angelica.
I'm not Aisha Silva. Emma
No, I'm talking amongst me.
Look, server names.
Come on, Rio.
Already seen this is closed and it's.
Come on, guys. In our boards.
Too many of you go.
And whenever you create the data, I showed
this console to you inside the console.
If you go right for creating,
the employee is going to say this
and this is the response.
This is the response here to the can you
see in just one say that you get server
you get AIDS powered by
you gets access control,
you get content land
you keep alive connection alternate
every single thing you basically remember
I told you how boutique console
and what are the things we can like.
So it's
not only about one particular stuff.
We can verify whatever we want to verify,
we can verify all of these
things on not and me.
So simply, let's copy
the value of this server,
copy the value of this, Go to our script.
This is my script
and I'm going to read response.
Then don't assert the guard body in here.
I'm going to write server.
Come with
long days.
You are not
new ways or writing them on.
I wasn't expecting this response from you.
Fine.
So far so good.
Students, Let's verify another thing here.
Another thing.
What is that?
Let's take anything.
For example.
Don't do so response.
Don't then not assert their own body
inside body employ
dog I need
I eat and be chocolate
equally to the value should be to be.
Is that clear now see I have five
five installations
but in addition verification check state.
I'm very plain from on
we purposes from all prosperous.
I'm governing the status called the server
the main body
the message right in memory to entities
and be defined individually could
in sequence
of shall we run this not.
This is the request to create an employee.
See, this is the request
to create an employee.
Any question in this part
based on anything
anything that to this training, this could
so far
it's not clear.
No clear right.
See, we got we got a solution
feed by
JSON box so the word doesn't match. See,
this was the expected,
but actually it got nothing.
Can you see
And you see that
it was expected.
What we got nothing.
Fine,
fine.
Let's remove this part for now.
Come in this part
and let's modify this time
see again if I alone.
Yes, yes, yes. I'm coming to.
He will cover.
I will not leave anything.
Not working. Fine. Everything,
guys, is
working fine.
Everything.
I will tell you why
this part is not coming.
I will tell you that
they send me one thing,
then me one thing here.
Right.
The value any one thing here.
When we talk about settlement,
I was just taking this.
Then we talk about of
what is this a part of your body?
Then what is this?
If it is not body, then what is this?
It's Haider, right?
So for Haider,
if you provide body, will it work?
We're seeing in this statement
they'd go and do the body
and check
if there is any sort of available or so.
It says that it wants to know sort
of what it means available in the body.
Right?
No server name available in the body.
So instead of body, what I have to write.
So here I have played guard, doctor, raid
doctor, and this time if I
see not
working
now, working or not then
don't just blindly write the code
or keep your eyes open all the times.
You never know when I'm going to ask what
is getting my point?
How we have created this part?
How did we know? So is infected?
Oh, you go here,
you go here Raid.
You click your header,
click on here.
Then they tell
you see all the information
available here,
all the information available.
Similarly, this is for your request.
If you go here,
if you go here, you will find in the body
there is a server available
in the headers.
That's good.
And you see you get the
I hope you guys got 1.4 times the
do we have always
to manual on post
or we can get all the info from spoken
directly all related information in spider
it's not possible reinforced.
We will test anything.
Remember this
when we perform be a distinct raid,
we perform any kind of testing.
We have to go it menu or straight.
And when you go to menu part
you get the responses
and this is something related to response.
So response
you always get in the Postman post
right From there you verify, you
notice this and then you ready.
But in your automation portals
to when you find
that you did something in the automation,
you must know what you're going to review
right?
Right.
Fine.
So for any question, this is not yet
so far we have reviewed their data.
We have created that record
in their database.
Right?
So from great operation creator
that retrieved
the next one is one of take great delete
obviously will not do because we did it
again, have completed it or something
but they knew how to do it also.
But right now we don't.
We simply created this with the data here.
The device, if we give the rating,
you know how many Einsteins beat him,
they always delete,
they always run that video in their data.
And then we will make trouble here.
Alright.
In the console also shows the
sponsor doesn't respond very separately.
Oh yeah.
And you see they're trained, know
different bodies,
different
this year
and last month and it's just depending
on how soon if you see it is
you and I bought for this method
and for this method
we define it already as an instance
video would be you.
So it is applicable both.
Now this token is applicable to both now,
right
return as a nice the rate
guys.
Can you see we are defined
then that as an instance variable.
So we can use both these things.
Fine.
People are hungry now
they need break and it's genuine.
Let's take a break for 15 minutes.
We'll connect again.
In this case, go to the break.
We created the employ and we go
to the data of the This is what we did.
Correct in one request.
Now now, here
from this operation, distant,
distant rate.
Let's talk about
of getting the guys to me first thing
in updating the employed of anybody.
Is this the same body
we need the way we would be.
We wouldn't need a body, need.
Is this the same body that we need in
a create or that is something that's that.
Also, we have to begin
scene.
We can use it
simply.
Don't you think that we have to use one
initiative barometer here
along with the word
we have guys,
we have to use it right.
What is the reason?
Why do we need to use this employee?
Because there are a lot of employees,
hundreds of employees
available and cannot it
every single message which I have to build
by my request and in this database,
if we have this image of users,
I am going to update their data.
This particular employee and the identity
of this employee needs this employee 83.
So I need to specify
which I want to play with current.
So that's why
we need employ 80 in the book
for data, right?
Which matter we need to use case.
What is the
method we should give
or the method
correct.
Now what is that status?
Good.
I should expect
to wondered why Katrina?
Why 207?
Why not 201
Alex And in Indonesia
we are creating. Yes.
So if we are creating then
it's 201201 is for creating
request is correct.
See, we are simply replacing something
with some data
like we have just replacing something.
So when we have to do something, it means
we are not going to add anything new.
We are just going to take something
and put something in their database
so existing place is already dead.
We are simply updating that.
But there's the only thing
we're doing here right?
You're going to
see now you see the more
administrator Israel,
the presence of it into this class.
Amazing
change in 24 hours from last class.
Good race class.
Glad to see this great man.
Good enrollment.
Welcome.
Welcome back to bed 11 embakasi.
Oh, vegetables, fruits you don't want
your bedroom document battery
bank is just for giving you
the information
like just additional material,
the AC on the gate late.
This is the way you want
to update operation
within project of great operation.
We need to check.
But it never happened.
I was in a bad mood in the class late,
but it happened based
by like.
So we need
we need all of these things, need
to update the employee in the database via
a call right
now by work since
she was nice and had
right
being nice and had
pre doesn't get paid,
you have to become a wide
to get the job
even.
I don't know that
right with some distance
the normal stuff getting a job.
No still that is paid
not that
you have to play ball no
you have to understand
that this is the need of the market.
You have to be aggressive.
And I said that as you don't
just shoot your exam.
INTERVIEWER When I say aggressive,
maybe she is investible.
All right.
I mean that maybe you are.
Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
That's what kind of the market is.
Very good.
Lot of opportunities, a lot of candidates
and also ditch right
Connect.
Silver Connect is his decision
are not only hard work.
Hard work is one thing.
With hard work
you should have a clear plan, strategy,
vision, goal, focus, all these things
and then hard work alone.
Hard work will do anything right.
If I ask you to hit the nail
in the morning with your Hey,
you're doing very hard.
What you have been doing it
from last three years trying to the nail
in the wall with your head fake in
make your hands bleeding.
Right.
But still,
you want to be able to do that. Why?
Because you're doing hard work.
But You don't have a right approach.
Instead, if you haven't hammered, then
it won't take years.
You don't have to make.
Your head is bleeding late.
The simply do it in 5 minutes
and your task is done.
This is what we call
smart work hard work with approaches.
A smart work.
That's what I'm saying.
And expert.
I'm saying that's why we are teaching
how to hold the embassy in a meeting
by engaged.
So now we going to update
the existing employee information.
So let's dig another method here.
So this method here, I'm
going to provide as
of late morning
eight
employees.
So it's hundred.
It's 200 because the information
is already existing in the database.
We are just going to change that
information.
So we are not going to add any new record.
We are going to update the record.
So for updating the record
simply means you perform some operation
in the existing values of the database.
You got some response there that is 200.
Then you're going to add a new record
in the database.
Then you will get to zero 100.
So these are two different things. And to
find.
All right,
so here I'm going to the right of
to the existing
employee
upgrading the existing in person.
Let's see their data
we have but operating existing and
this is the days
we have already got one database.
So I'm going to make a request
request to specification.
I'm seeing people
request is it was to given don't
first we need to raid
broken dot
again one more header
content I
applications no adjacent door
we need body
for improvement
every day without fail everyday
from last two years consistently.
So now
I'm going to upgrade the employee.
So for upgrading the employee details
you'll see one freedom.
You have to add
correct?
Correct.
Okay.
This is this is something we need to add.
Now, tell me, guys,
what kind of goal is this?
We are going to update on the details of
the employee or just some of the details.
If I'm using this part,
some details.
Come on, guys, get using put
go an input call.
We'll some details.
All the details
absence need you need it pretty great.
And if I want to obtain some information
then which
which call should only
batch code
for back
badge is for updating some information.
Remember I give you the definition
of batch code and protocol is updating
the information right.
So let me take this book.
It will take this one from here
based here,
let me go with this from here. Find
not the domains.
Okay?
Okay, fine.
So now this is the employer
and this is the employee
we have to update.
So this time needs change their data.
So data, I'm going to write this again,
and this one should be cool.
Really should be less changes to embassy
this today's
find this today's point employee
this time gets to the employee
and here you can somebody find this
guy is going to see
I have to add one request to the employee
right now.
Now to save this request,
I will get one response also.
So first
I have to use this particular object.
So I'm see prepared request dart Bitcoin
guys which calls work on what
would cooperate.
So here I have to add
I have to add this particular part
would update employee would require.
So let me
copy right
when I got this response
when I got this response list first,
simply print simply print this response.
Simply print the response. All right,
let's
do it.
Working fine. Now
it can be verified.
This police
can we verify this?
But let's take this
how we can verify the response.
Then Dart assert that Dart
did this video not
that is this is body, not body.
Right
so here I'm going to take message pre
message should be equal to see
this equal
to which I'm using is coming from here
is equal to my third is coming from here
image him dressed major straight from him
close to me
just close in terms for harmony
I can be verify
can be verified the status quo alternate
response start then
assert their status code to the position.
Is this correct?
Is this is
verification
validation?
So let's tweet
medium deployed now
after two and a half hours.
So it's working best fast
test first already working
these now.
Now see one thing here. Regards.
See one thing you what I'm going to do is
I have been executing
read this particular test.
I've been executing this particular test,
then this particular test.
What would happen
if I execute on a glass limit?
What might execute all test together?
See what would happen in this case,
everything from
see it since first simple test.
What a game plan
updating
update employee working fine
create employed working player.
But if you observe
how come your tests never happen,
it will fade.
I'm telling you
because the approach is something wrong.
See in this template
I'm using some other employee.
Can you see
and you see this
in creating the employee
I'm using, but an employee
for updating the employee.
I'm using that the employee. Do you see
this is something else.
It means I'm
getting the data of X employee
I'm creating by employee.
I'm updating their employee,
getting my point.
What I'm saying
is this correct approach.
We're getting X employee objecting,
my employee deleting their level,
doing whatever we want to do
is this correct?
No. What I should do,
what I should do, basically is
first I should create the employee
right
after creating the employee,
I should go to the employee ID.
Then I should get this one
employee correct using this employee
database.
Then I will really find their data.
I have to verify the data
and then using this same employee
already have to update their details.
I have
to obtain their details
and then verify that
this should be
the correct approach or not.
And this should be
This is the correct approach.
We have to follow this command.
But if I go here, if I go here,
you'll see it just posted executes.
Which one
is simple?
It execute simple test post,
then it executes update,
then it executes create.
Right now you'll see here
update I wrote in the end
create
executes in middle and some nested first.
The general is one, two, three
but a difference in 132.
Can you see the random sequence
and you see this?
This is the random sequence
and if I keep executing,
my order
does exist in the random sequence,
I will not be able to execute the V
I want to execute because first
I want to clear the employee, right
Then I want to fetch the details
of that employee.
Then I have to verify
the data and then only I
can. Is
this correct?
So now, now let's do this.
Now let's do this.
What I'm going to do is
here.
Here I'm going to write.
So for our job, most likely
we need to look for one record
considered everything books, your list,
the very simple to understand.
Right?
First, we need to add something
in the database to play their data.
Once we add the data,
we will retrieve the object.
Then we will update it to check the newly
elected or duplicate object.
Right. So there.
So we believe that once
you have multiple entries,
then you can perform random operations
are okay from the existing data.
We need to delete this
in the existing data.
We need to update
this in the existing data
or in the existing BW to upgrade the new
something like this when first,
this is the standard of brute force.
We have to create it,
then we have to retrieve it, then
we have to object, then we have to
find this
initial method, the user,
this is the object and
is everyone on the same page
with me?
Any question you need, any question,
any kind of confusion,
anything
I've seen, you've done
a similar done
with the good update implement
guys, can you give me
both?
So now now I have to come up with that
with the strategy there.
First I can create the employee,
then I will use the same employee A
in getting the data
and then I have to use same employee only
interpreting the returns.
Got it.
We ordered the order. Right.
So let's go ahead and do it.
So what I'm going to do
is before the class here,
before class here,
I have to write one particular part.
What is that I'm going to write? Entering
in, you see
in G unit, I have one thing called this
method Order.
There is everyone can see it.
It's method order
from G unit.
In this fixed method orders simply pass
method sorters and we don't need it.
Method orders in default.
It is already working as a default method.
Sorters name.
Assuming this is something we need
what we need method sorters name sending.
Getting.
Now the moment I provide this name,
assuming what it does,
it executes your test.
Guesses this in alphabetical order,
but it does
guys what it does.
It executes your best guesses
in which order?
In alphabetical order.
Okay, so in alphabetical order, what
should be the first thing I have to do?
It is
what should be the first thing First?
I have to clear the employee. Right?
So let me write this method.
E deploy
E create.
Can you see
guys?
I'm seeing E create employee.
And then after this, what I have to do
is by default
it executes in alphabetical order.
Then why it was executing simple.
It was to create in the last
and it's
you see the last execution I did
it executes is first and C last by
file after creating the employee.
The second thing
we should take with the only menu
item is the export we're going to do.
We're going to do a better word,
traceability, right?
Animal traceability.
Then we have to do B part is be as simple
as we're doing this. B
get created employee
Now it doesn't matter now.
It doesn't matter, right?
When I'm writing this method, it's
going to execute alphabetically.
So I'm putting this as B can you see
we get created employee just for you.
Just four years from now, delegates
here This employee advocacy can be better.
We trace it like this
employee
because now is execute
according to the priority
according to the priority.
So remember
first it will execute this part
the moment it will execute receives
one employee, Adi, and that employee
I can use here to get the details
of the employee followed.
Can we do this?
No, no, no, we can't.
That's why it is not.
And there is this clear
what I'm doing. It
now. Not in this part, in this board.
What I have to do is I have to verify
also this employee
because the employee, which I'm getting,
the employer getting it also
it maybe it is coming one,
two, three, four, four, five, six.
Possible or not, that is possible.
And so I am seeing here,
I am seeing here
see get one employee right.
You go here, you go here,
forget one employee in this part.
And when you run this particular
one, get one employee
that you
can you see here, this employee comes,
this employee comes with someone.
E if you create employee,
if you create employee, right.
This create employee comes with completely
the object difference.
See this completely
and this one comes with small giving.
See that illustrates
right.
So now now you see
when I'm creating the employee,
it is also turning even body.
And in this body I'm getting capital
E employee
object, JSON
object, great employer employee I.D..
But this employee objects with capital.
And here I'm getting employee
third employee
here, embroidered employee 80 with small
E employee object with small E, Right.
So when I'm actually when I'm actually
getting the employee details
based on one particular employee I.D.,
I be getting this body.
So from this body, if I were to verify
their data, what I would do.
One idea I got after
creating the employee, another I.D.
I got after retrieving their data.
So do I. Is I got right.
This one is my expectation one the one
which I'm getting is my actual one.
I can verify
what the lady actually did it.
What I do that equal it means today's
based on from the same source
I did my first order expectancy,
but data is coming from my retrieval.
Part one data is coming from my creation,
but I can compare both these ideas
just to make sure.
Remember, what I did
is to
this is I hope you understood
what I'm trying to explain.
Assert equal.
We have used this. We are using this.
Just just an object.
Remember, and measures
to perform equal condition. And
so now see here,
after getting this employee
after printing the data on Sprint right
here I can get
is the concept and yeah
kind of got in concept discipline.
So here here I'm going to read
see from the response
using JSON, but
I can get women's pre
and net pre would be my
employee non
employee.
Read this
correct.
It reads me employee
from getting the date from get gone
because if it was completely
that came from
create call post call
this one is from Google.
So this embroidery
what I'm getting what I'm seeing
is displaying I'm seeing
I'm going to see which some of it
because it is coming from my
coming from everything
so now see this employee
come from this
is this employee
comes from this, not this one.
The one which I highlighted
this employee comes from this
that created one.
Correct.
And this employee, it is coming from this
after retrieving
the information
from data grade from Google.
So now see what I'm writing.
I am seeing
I am seeing one Boolean conditions.
What is the Boolean condition?
EMC Company employee is equal to.
I see when my this employee
there is a matter to go and content equals
with content equals to mine this employee.
If the content of my this employee
and their employer is equals,
then this particular matter
returns true.
So I'm going to write a side
to start a third group
and here I'm going to provide
competing narratives,
competing narratives right here.
Any assertion
through return from
is that clear?
Is that clear false level of verification?
Is this part false level
of verification, clear or not illegal?
Now, after this, what I'm going to do
is I'm to verify the last name.
Also. The first name was the first name.
Last name could be anything we can verify
today.
Omega is the name
which I'm sending from the body.
Where is my body that you go?
This is my body, right?
I know.
The middle name
which I would be sending is a miss.
Let's see.
So I'm seeing what they what their data
you are getting.
I get I want to verify their data.
So simply simply do
just one thing from the response.
From the response using this just last
get this dream.
What is this dream?
So here again employ don't
eat and be nice to be
employed, not empty nasty them.
And this data I have stored
in the supreme as
the moment
I away last name here I'm going to write
assert assert
proof So here I'm going to write
last name again content equals to
this should be this.
If it is true, it returns.
If it is equals,
it returns to otherwise it return sports.
This part
is these two layers of positions.
This comparison of it is equal or not
clear or not
very.
So for this part, creating the employee
and then it an employee.
So a partner to be partner.
Correct.
Now let's talk about C part.
Let's talk about C part, C
part is simply updating the employee,
updating the employee.
So very different.
Instead of passing their data,
instead of passing the data.
And what I should basically is C,
I'm going to pass it like this
first,
delete this part,
delete this part.
And here
I have to provide
more.
Let's
get this part C,
I'm passing the parameter
instead of passing the heart
to is.
Then this.
Can you see? I'm going to update the data.
So this time, instead of passing
my value added value, I'm
passing the parameters, right?
And then I'm going to provide.
This name is C
c simply update employee
based.
What happened this month.
Then an object. Share that name please.
Which then this displayed.
Can you show please last name?
Yes, sure they will.
This is the last.
Don't get confused with this object case
because these are the object.
Yeah. No, no, no.
I'm just c don't get confused with this.
Objects
because you're creating an employee,
so you returning capital E object
JSON object.
But when we're getting the employee,
it returning and private small is
just getting
the last name is assignment
put just one thing
didn't like this from here
so this should be mine
middle name and I'm putting it as
and as here
they should be on
offensive
one but not good observation by the
sweet
who six
who let me know once
everyone is done.
I like the others.
This work done
already by
this point
and this particular one
after creating the employee
this but also
creating the employee.
Right.
Get data from here
now let's go to update employee.
So updating the employee parties
also certain
everyone
I share the line please.
Sure.
Let me use my slack from here on
because my my leg is in the system
and I'm using the different system
in someone patient this length Global
just this length
Asia global.
Let's
let me know guys one zero.
The way to do this
is very clear employer
your line number is even bigger
This is the employee.
See this is the goal we were going to make
on code number eight C method.
So E creating the employee,
B getting the employee
from created employee.
And then the third one is
getting their data from the employee only.
So the same employee is repeating again
and again.
Now, eight
rate,
we already set order
and we're using the same order
here, but those are initialized
within their methods.
So if you observe this already put
it is instance,
can you see
we have been using them also already.
We're using all of these things
all the same. The methods.
There is nothing from the method.
We're providing values.
Fine.
So for these three calls clear,
everyone can
now see
I'm going to copy this particular one
because after updating the employee
also I should need
I should need be caught.
Right.
I should be difficult to create due
to the created employee again.
Right.
So now here I'm going to Right get
updated employee's correct
in this getting the updated employee.
I'm going to pass data
comparing the employee
find on is simply
we can do one thing this time
we can simply perform just one option
right called middle name should be M.
S E and then a solution code is 202 things
and we do it in the get updated employee.
Now see,
this will be my first call
after updating my data.
So here you see I'm updating my data
in this part using MSE.
This should remember the name.
So this is what I'm providing here.
The limits is in this. Right
after updating
again, I'm going using the same employee
and I'm trying to access the data.
Right?
So I'm waiting for calls here A, B, C, D
case.
I made a full policy
and everyone see this part days
protocols could be all in on
any question in this work. Once
students, any question, any confusion
so quickly and our standards.
Yeah obviously
obviously that's why I'm going to commit
this right in the repository.
So this method of ordering is simple.
We're just curious.
Is there any other method
of sequencing their test?
Generally there is other method
we would use framework.
Right now.
I made this class as hardcoded examples,
so these are the hardcoded data
that we're working with.
Right after these hardcoded examples,
we will work on a template,
but from there we create everything.
So we will not be relying on this unique
based, you know,
fix method or something
we will execute according to our choice.
They're done.
So they do it because just to
show you how things work, we
okay, good.
Thank you so much.
We're
should we included
let's execute all this for everyone to
with good and everything
goes quickly and ready to this.
Yes that's what
we started on site for the full range.
Now you'll be able to work.
So let's execute this now. See?
And you see it took eight, B, C,
and D, Now
we buy
employ only is none.
Please provide employee.
Let's check
where they take employee
Yes, correct.
That's what I'm saying.
What is happening
is that there should be some silly words
after reading this
at this point
and the boolean condition notices
we try to do it by heart.
Could it just give me a moment
after there to do the working or not?
Because
we had this one employee.
So this one is not affecting the data.
Basically.
Why this one is not affecting the data.
There's the question, maybe the background
during the API, because
we are able to generate the data.
So first it is creating the employee fine.
Let's let's do just one thing.
It's execute these three. Now see
what would happen
is they're getting their data
decent.
What messages
if this employee record of data
and actually employee not found
okay where it is not finding the employee
so in clear
the employee record their data
from everybody fine
so this returns a story
and it is bringing this part.
It's not the same data I'm forcing you
to upgrade the employee.
Fine.
And the same thing here.
Also,
let's do this first clear to see
whether it is printing this employee.
Be here or not.
When preparing the request.
See, it gets null here
if the idea is not coming.
New employee idea,
it's not taking some issue with the API
because the data is generated,
which is not picking
employee.
And the idea this
is starting to check
just just a fluke.
I'm crying because
well, see
working by now
these are
exceptionally based
exceptionally at the moment
they made extending it works
well I assert is static.
No I was talking about this
basically your own token.
I was not talking about this employee 80.
Right.
I was talking about this too.
Not this one. Right.
So this is something else.
This is something else.
So you guys, their data, their data,
which is coming from one call, right?
That data is stored in one static field.
Then it is populating the data everywhere.
Ideally.
Ideally when I was running two methods
remaining, but I remember
when I don't know when I was running
two methods for creating the employee
and for getting the employee.
So even non static was working
is when we were creating the employee
and getting the employee.
Yes, getting instances
changing instances changing.
So this time the moment I made it static,
the same instances working everywhere.
Now see what it does
basically doesn't matter
whether you provide create employee
at the last part right at the last part
or you employ or you provide get employee
in the first part or update employer.
The first part doesn't make by because you
maintain the order of execution, right?
You made the order of execution
and then you, when you fixed
this order of execution using G unit,
it will execute in your provided
order later.
There's not going to execute anything
according to its default order.
So here, according to all defined order,
it will create the employee first,
it will retrieve the data from
the employee, but from some associates.
Then it will update the employee.
And after updating the employee again,
it will retrieve the employee
and see whether the data is correctly
updated or not.
For where they played the same.
And we don't.
But because of changing the instance
of of instance variable,
which is non static
the moment we made it static,
the steam instance is working
across all the methods.
So the
point, my deep point is
my only point is the
this is my work and you see someone
in right now.
Now the next important thing,
what we have do
is basically what we will do is
we will simply execute
every single thing
raised by via parameterization
and in our framework,
that's what we have to do.
We will use the complete parameterization,
but right the way we were calling steps
when this beta pilot would place
beachhead grid one place
constant at one place.
Right.
Similarly, we will implement every thing
in our framework
and from that framework we will later
be just by whatever
the scenario we want to perform.
Because now we know, given
we can use for preparing the request
when we can use for sending the request
on everything
that you wanted,
the shipping that you ordered,
then we'll then for assertions
we are using implicit measures
for estimated Class one associates,
a very issue with invasion force.
All these things would be known.
It's all about arranging the data.
It's all about attending the code
according to the framework, what we have.
So when you go to the market
and if someone asked you
to explain the things,
you can explain your database, you wait.
But your PPA,
but it means we need to build all three
layers
with the same of framework explanation.
And this go this.
What does it mean? You get the
let me
first commit this code in the repository.
All of you
in Asia.
If you want,
we can run it again no issues or problem
need find
binaries
in the last two CMB.
So these are building the employee
this part.
Right. And these nothing.
These is the same when we we are using be
maybe you're providing a wrong
because after updating the employment
data will change a mistake for officer
should be it
already based.
Any questions in this
students
any questions?
All clear both at
point ten indicates how was the session
was it wasn't one
or a lot of confusion. Yes.
So one Yes, yes we'll do it shorter.
We would really short very precise.
Very clear.
Right.
Fine.
Next time
when we are meeting on secretary rate
there has been an aspect influence of
just polymorphism
better localization
every single thing we will get
and after that will complete
on API part implementation in sector.
Then starting next week
you'll be having your Jenkins part
and after Jenkins part, maybe on weekends
I'm roadshow on weekends break.
No, you guys in class,
I don't know what we do.
So on Saturday will the meeting next week
most probably will be starting
with your group operations group
so I will be there
with you on weekdays
as well And I we both
we take interpretation sections
perfect affect guys.
All right I think I'm
then from my side for today's class
if you guys have any question
please ask and we can from the class
is it just for weekends.
A normal stuff is also following meeting
authorities.
Thank you so much for being cooperative
in the class that is really busy
signing on
and dealing with it and get everyone make.