Right before anyone began.
We tried to look for children.
Okay, know what
I'm to
then is ready.
But I knew what?
No, I know. I'm in a good mood today.
I just came from a function, so I'm.
I'm in a very good mood. Don't watch.
We don't need injury.
I was the mother, right?
And they'd
on the behalf of Ukraine and pressure
conflict.
I am. Yes.
That's like good witness.
Ready now in the class?
No issues, Alexi, you're not late knowing
you look.
But that's not the case.
I had a training in the morning.
I didn't say should in afternoon.
Then I laid out for some party function.
I have to leave someone.
So I went there
and I just came in ready for new station.
No, no, no, no.
All right,
let's start.
All right, guys, tell me,
what was the topic?
What was the first topic in the class
to two recovered
in EPA
students
to to get for the last class
clients about architecture.
All right.
Well, that's
I think we caught in first class.
Yes. Cutting
is one a service services
anyways.
What is lip service this EPA is the EPA.
They all state that over the Internet,
over the substance.
They bills are posted over the Internet.
Web services.
Fine.
What type of how many types of services
the do?
What are the names of them?
The first one is so
and the second is the.
And we are going to work with
we are going to work with
not only list
supports, how many languages,
what are the names of those languages
is so
simple.
Next DML except
on this language is correct.
Why? It's called restful.
I need to talk to developer representation
and state translate
by the point name like this.
Why that is a name Gina or testimonies.
What is what is the reason behind this?
Why we call this framework?
But what is the reason behind this
notice and state?
If I end up on that,
I can give any name right?
Got it. Now see why.
Looking at the answers.
Right? Whatever the questions I'm asking.
RESTful, RESTful.
Great. And restful.
That same thing. Don't worry.
So. Yep, definitely.
Definitely.
This is the name of my generator.
And this. So
now when I see here, whenever
I ask questions,
you are able to recall all those quotes.
It means your understanding right?
It means you understood the topic in
the last class, even in the review class.
Also you've got the points, then split up
and I'm asking
within a fraction of a moment.
I see you guys are responding
to my answers.
That's correct.
No. Who says
that you do a review of a class
and you forget?
See, this is the example, guys,
is just Do you mind that you're forgetting
the things you're not?
Actually. Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
You're not.
You are.
You're able to remember the things
guys, and trying to just,
you know, increase your confidence.
You all have these things memory
or what's difficult
in a Jedi in reality, it's
not that difficult.
You guys are doing this.
You guys are recording
one of these things.
You guys are dealing with these things,
right?
And it's a very good part.
Just review your credential.
You have a lot more than you anticipated.
All right, fine.
All right.
Just full a base.
We are working with big.
Does this rest in based on required
Lisbon to meet, to transfer their data
and supports multiple languages such as?
Such as statistics
such as just on such achievement, etc..
Getting
no when we talk
about so in this table
is that the whole state over
the internet rate
they can host it over the internet.
Thank you very much.
Now on the Internet,
I give you one example.
If you live in a country,
you have to follow all the rules
and the condition
of the particular country.
If you want to make this,
if you're opening an organization
in any country,
you have to follow all the rules
of the conditions of this country.
To run Europeanization,
you have to pay the taxes and everything
according to the rules of that country.
Similarly, if you want to communicate
with any of the member state,
with any of the server
which is available on the eight,
and then you have to follow the rules
and the conditions
to fight over the Internet.
So what are those rules and regulations?
What are those
protocols? What we call that protocol
age. The the
be Hypertext transfer protocol.
This Hypertext Transfer protocol
enable us to communicate
with multiple websites,
with multiple servers, to communicate
with them
over the Hypertext Transfer protocol.
Fine.
So when we talk about hypertext transfer
protocol
here,
we have to understand a couple of things.
What are the functions?
What are the methods?
This is strictly because
and how we can use all of those functions,
how we can use all of those methods
in our API request rate.
By far in these two classes
in the beginning of the third class,
everyone know what is behind,
what is server, what we call request,
what we call response
getting what is web service?
What are the types of web service?
What is so what is the rest of the scene
and list interest?
How many languages it is to support
what is just on,
what is accessible,
what is based, what is HTML?
What is.
So every single thing we know,
we know what HTP is,
but trade hypertext transfer protocol.
Now what all are
the methods in hypertext transfer protocol
so we can perform current operations?
What kind of operations they perform
here, Create operations, right.
So when we talk about current operations,
what does it mean those
create
a degree of date or delay in simple thing,
which if I see in simple language,
if I see to add a record in their
database, is nothing but create operation
to get existing record from
the database
is nothing but a retrieval operation.
Update
an existing record in their database.
We call it update Operation What it means
editing the existing record and to delete
existing record in their database
record embedded operation.
This is what we call operations
Internet protocol that is interesting,
that allows us to perform
all these functions using its own methods.
Using its own functions. Fine.
So now, in order to use its own functions,
in order to use its own methods,
the very first thing we need is bees.
You are by bees,
you are a uniform resource.
Identify it.
We need to use this.
You don't realize how we can make this.
You are right.
What are the things
we need to make the bees?
You want to.
But I'm reading this.
You are a nurse, the education
nurse
and now
when we talk about this, you want to know
what does it mean?
What is base you are in?
Base,
right?
Address
of this of.
And then if we talk about API location,
it means so
the existence of API
inside this.
And then if you talk about endpoint,
it simply means
that we are going to
analyze. Now
after making this base, you are right,
we have this,
you are an API location plus endpoint.
Is this enough?
This is not enough
because you just found the address.
This is the complete address, right?
This is complete interest.
Let me write like this your point.
Not actually method point.
Now, now, now another thing.
If if
I am going
to add something in the database
or I'm going to retrieve
some information from the database
or I'm going to delete some information
from the database,
or I'm going to edit some information
in the database,
depending on the operation, I will decide
what all are the other credentials,
what all the other components
I need to make a request.
Because right now,
if I'm planning to make a request,
I need to have all of this information.
Right? Because you are.
I is just a license
to enter into the import right now. See?
No, see what we have to do here.
So first what we did was
to create an
import, right? We
what kind of employs this case?
Yes, this is me.
Why we continue
doing this.
And what is the reason behind
is that first we created.
Yes. Well, the reason behind
creating the element, employing list is
if we do not have an element embroiled in
who is going to perform
other operations, who's going to provide
and manage the existence of other entries
are the registered users.
State admin
is going to provide all these things.
So whenever we create any system,
whenever we create any application
in that application,
the first ever use that we create
is the admin search,
who is having all the credentials,
who can play in the application
and all the possible forms
industry
names.
So look here, the employing simply means
if we talk about yes,
if we talk about current operation,
this is the created one, right?
So to create something, to add something,
to add a new record in the database,
we need first base.
You want to
We need first base.
You are right.
Then what is the second thing we need?
We need a load
payload, right?
Yeah.
When I say Nas would be this.
You are right, it simply means this.
You are in this API location.
Let's import. Right?
We need a payload recall.
This payload is body.
Body.
So David is in which language
we provide words
we are using, which language
we use,
JSON language,
a wide array of what
we use, just a language
to write a body cutting
file.
Now now when I have this, you are
I guess is one week,
not a language JavaScript object notation.
Right. You can call.
This is a language
and or not answered in long time.
It's been three months assurance.
So even a single word
plus the existence. Yes, she is
nice.
Oh. Chicago, Illinois.
Trade and relationship
and university of Illinois.
It's bad.
And if I'm not wrong,
nice couple of restaurants
have setting their science
promotion.
Nice it's a good idea was actually
nice is to study
one of my studies
now he is going to Newcastle
and two of my spirits
are going to Liverpool and most to be
are going to Manchester
this year, September.
So they would be joining, I think,
I think a foreign country,
they would be joining Formula One,
but I wouldn't be going there
for their internship.
I'm just imagining Right.
How much experience they will get
by working with this one chance
like I know
this Newcastle University is a good one,
Liverpool, Istanbul, just to Istanbul,
but obviously on weekends they can go
going, What's the matter, Right.
Maybe in Manchester or Liverpool. Yes.
Yes. Getting
or did it was
it is like in 17th century 16th century.
Great Manchester is
I think 500 year onwards
any one city. Okay
nice enough.
Fine after bailout after bailout
after bitter.
What is the next ten days?
What are the things we need not to be?
We need to
wait.
We need to have this right now.
After Haider,
my request would be probably really great.
My request really, I think
or not?
No, no. What?
What is the next thing we need?
Keep content papers, Header of content.
I wasn't.
If this is already held up, we have to
continue.
We don't need it. Correct.
We already done with this matter.
We have to select.
So now here I break my method.
What would we? My mother.
That would be my post
right
before save me before sending anything.
We need to understand one thing.
What is we need to understand.
We need to understand that.
What are the responses I need to consider?
I should know what response is correct
and what response is not correct.
I should know, right?
What kind of warning I'm going to get
or even whether I'm going
to get anybody in the response or not.
Every single information we must know.
That's why we have the very
first thing is API status.
Could it be a status quo?
Right?
What is the 1001?
What is portable?
04014024034044202 every single code.
Right.
I would request you to read
like all the cities,
but having the knowledge of 400
to desert one is an important
thing to understand. This
interview
with is that he might ask you for 303.
Sometimes,
but it is just to check your knowledge.
It has nothing to do.
But when you do just
that, it's not a big deal.
It is just for pipeline status, remember?
So you can do it at any point of time.
In just four 5 minutes you'll be able
to read all of these things.
Findings.
Now let's start
removing slides.
Apes, take a squad. Yes, Yes.
You will be having this enslaves us.
Fine.
So now they see what is postman.
Basically, when we're using the postman,
what mostly does
postman basically allows us, right?
It allows us
to connect
connect with the end point
rate in Postman what we are doing,
we are connecting with the end point
and then we are performing
any single operation rate,
every single operation
we're performing from here.
So Postman is
just doing what Postman does,
what most
readers deliver your message,
deliver your card or something.
Deliver to a card.
Somebody write it, connected
with their database.
Write whatever the message you do
to the postman.
Postman Give that message, right?
Take a sign back and then come back again
with the response.
This is what post Windows,
That's the name.
Really ready
to liberate the name of the postman. See
if you compare this name
with the computer.
No comparison and
may not even be
like it When you are writing
some English language in your calling.
It could do amazing Einstein level
thinking no next play
point. No.
No. See, one more thing is
when we are talking about APIs trade,
when we're talking about APIs,
we have two types of IPA.
If you get the two branches
that even if it's branches two,
then why
not coriander?
If you've got a spinach,
it has branches too.
Then broccoli would be the best example.
Lot of branches.
Cauliflower is the best example,
not of branches.
Then why only get your.
Yeah.
If it is distended then it should be lemon
all round 316.
No. And I think that is a starting point.
It is, I think. Why no one knows
right, that this distant this lemon
getting in a type
as big as a vegetable market fine
so now
now we have an API, right?
We have APIs, two types of API,
the right liquidity,
two types of the first is
public appearance
and the second one is
I repeat,
the first one is public API
and the second one is private.
Okay.
Can you give me the example of public API?
My okay,
libraries, public.
How many of you guys are using Google now?
How much money you pay for that?
You're not paying even a single penny
for using your maps.
Google Maps, you're paying this
for your Internet connection rate.
So these are two different things, right?
Cutting through it.
So you're not paying any money
to Google Maps right now.
Tell me, is it accessible to some of you
or all of you?
Google Maps
accessible to.
All right, all of you
know, in Google Maps.
In Google Maps,
you see only your device, current location
or you see, okay,
your friend is coming from that point.
So you can see that
current location is the same thing.
And one goodness,
people are going into the open road
and you see all of their characters
know only,
only if that student only if that thing
which shared his nice condition,
they don't need to do
with breaking.
No, no, no, no,
no. It's a flat because
there is a match going on. Right?
So one beam is one the match.
So there's not stupid search celebrating.
I would say
I don't know
whether you heard about it or not,
but someone said right, that they did
some planning for the regions.
At the same time
someone is planning for the empire.
They are stupid.
Yeah.
Their search match is going on
and they guys are celebrating.
They didn't even play,
but still they're celebrating.
See, there's the height of stupidity
if you ask them what they're going to do
on Monday morning, 8 a.m.
they know that they're not having any on.
Some people with no region
living here, it's conditional.
It's for fun. No, ma'am.
There's for when they're like not for fun.
This is not fun.
If you double others, this is not fun.
Smart people don't come on road.
They don't want to
and celebrate for nothing.
This is just a league
match of one small city.
It's the same
what you can do in Italy, correct?
I know, I know. Stupid
does that every year.
I'm not saying stupid
is that in India only they
people like this that everywhere exist.
Humans are humans.
It doesn't matter which part of the one
you're going to put on risk point.
This right.
And they're sort eager to ruin their life.
Did you try to stop them then?
We agree on you are living on them.
Okay, Go ahead. Live your life.
Not actually living your life.
You're actually ruining your good.
Nice.
It's been it's
funny.
So now now you'll see.
The first one is,
is this firecrackers?
And it is firecrackers.
Guns has nothing to do with firecrackers.
No alcohol.
I am.
How many of you guys are using DoorDash
GrubHub
at this food delivery app?
But when you do that, everyone right now.
Now, the guy.
Them and the guy
who is delivering your food
who is underway,
can you see his location of what?
Can you see his location using Google map
you have to use which map?
The map which is available in the menu.
Correct.
And if you be if you play, then only
you get to the exits opened, Right.
It So that is your private API.
You need to first log in
to your zomato account.
You need to show that okay,
you are registered user
or a guest user on an existing user.
Correct?
Yes. Correct. Same it all, but it's also.
But it's GrubHub DoorDash ability.
Correct.
So you use this type of features
and see map is available here.
Also Google Maps is available in Zomato,
also in GrubHub, also in DoorDash.
But the difference, can you see it
one time to show your identity?
What is that, a district mobile number?
You get one OTP, you have to redefine your
or you did your password
with the application.
Then only
you will be able to use that account.
However, on the other side,
you don't have to provide any information
or authentication point of your right.
It is not indication cutting.
So this is public API
that is primarily EPA.
These are two different things,
but same concept of API.
Understood.
No, no.
When we talk about security in the API,
we need to understand.
We need to understand
how API is keeps security
and how API keeps security.
So there is a cycle of
authentication and authorization
authentication and authorization based.
Sometimes you provide a username
and password, correct?
Correct.
How many of you guys know this thing
takes each item application?
This one issue,
This application everyone knows
if you log in to this particular
application as an admin user,
you will see different Facebook page
with different options.
But if you log in to this application
with a normal user, you will see
different beach,
you will see different dashboard options,
correct?
Is indicates.
How is it possible that this same system
is providing you two different dashboard
for two different logins?
How is it possible?
This is the logic of the API trade.
So here here API should not read,
API should know that
if a log in is the normal user,
I should not provide the access
of administrative.
Did not indicate the admin.
I should not provide that dashboard
of a normal user.
Correct there.
So API keeps security so the correct
accesses will be given to connect people.
Right.
And there is the process
called authentication
and authorization authentication
authorized.
Right.
So now here
let me draw one page to show you
what is authentication
and composition point.
So this is the part one,
this is the part one.
So here I'm going to read
authentication
second
authorization, right?
And now, now here, see,
I'm going to do one example.
So here I'm going to write in order to
in order to write
post on Facebook,
in order to post something on Facebook
and to see the content
and to see the content.
Right.
The first thing what we have to do is
in order to post something on Facebook
or to see the content of the Facebook
post, we have to exactly.
Not so now.
Now you see here, right here
is the first cycle.
The fourth to cycle, we call it
authentication.
Find the one last
one will be your be correct
correct authentication.
Now, what I what it does
authentication does means it
confirms
it confirms your identity
based, it
confirms your identity and
permit you
to access the system.
But I'm with you to access
this is to trade.
For example. Okay.
What is your name?
I shall industry in the region. Nice.
What is your password?
I am a genius.
So both your credentials not correct.
Please log in.
Please come and access your system Right
Like this.
Connect the moment you provide your
username and password, your email I.D.
and password.
It permits you to access the system.
Right?
So it is confirming your identity.
It is confirming your identity.
Getting my point.
When I see
confirmation of identity
and accessing the information.
Right.
Giving you the access to the information
it sees authentication process,
authentication clearance, student
Yeah, I changed a couple of things.
You know, in a Facebook profile
that is this Firebase
authentication part is done on
now after authentication
the another part the another on left
or on left,
what is online?
This is part one.
Fine.
So now here here there is a part two,
There is a part two.
We call it
authorization, right?
So part two is your authorization.
Now, what we do in the authorization, this
authorization always controls it controls
whether whether you are
allowed
to perform
certain
operations or not
to perform certain operations.
But all right.
Now, see,
when we talk about authentication
simply means or to go provide
username password will check
whether you are a part of the system
or not.
Yes, you're a part of the system.
Okay.
We'll give you the log in, will give
the permission to access the system.
Authorization says no forced.
I will check even
you are in the system now.
Let me check
how much things accessible to you,
how many things
you can access to the system,
what kind operations
you can perform into the system,
and then give you the system
access accordingly.
Correct?
Current.
So it's once you enter into the system
as a normal user, right?
As a normal user, that's what I'm saying.
If you enters into the system
as a normal user,
you can do whatever you want to do
with your own account.
You can't do anything else.
But if you log into the system as an admin
user, you can delete any other user,
you can block any of that account,
you can do any of the things.
Right now you see sometimes
celebrities post that, Hey, my, my,
this Twitter account is
blocked,
Twitter has blocked my account out.
Twitter is doing this
is Twitter asking their password log in
and then not yet.
No they have an element of admin
you know accesses.
Right. They own their Twitter.
So what they generally do log in
where to me
or does users in database go there Jake.
Okay.
This user blocking blocked his account
right?
That's correct.
So it's all about authentication
and authorization
accesses should be given to correct
or I would say always did that to Trump.
Here we also have one, you know, same
kind of personality in India,
not one activity of many.
If you have 3.3, I think 33 million,
330 million people in us.
Right.
And you have this much of you
in big pieces.
We are a population of 1.5 billion.
Consider how many big
we have here in India,
closer to 400 million.
Yes, there.
Have you ever been hundred million?
Right.
So in 400 million, if you have not a thing
decreases in 1500 million.
Just imagine.
Well, I'm not the country, to be honest.
I'm telling you, it's a lot. I'm not a big
and I never take credit
of this.
Right.
So even in that 1.5 billion is still
my contribution is zero.
Don't worry.
I got to neither for
global warming, right?
Lugar directly
blame me for the population of India.
I never appreciate anyone.
I never think I know
I'm a motivational speaker.
I never motivated,
inspire, encourage people
to increase the population of India.
I don't do it. Do it.
This is not my time to encourage people
to stay
1.5 billion.
I'm not doing it
right.
Well, this is something new
to look at my every year to think of.
Great, let's motivate people.
Ask them to charge for this class. This
time is going to be a mess for that
they have to be six
one like me and Chinese are always three.
To do it is because it's
correct.
Cutting.
Correct. All right.
Now, when we talk about authentication
and authorization rate, the
motorman
and the BRI, the beehive is a unique one.
We can't show this to any other country.
And this is a unique read.
Once you get it to India, you'll see
out of the box
they out of the SometimesI
when I get shot,
this type of brutal behavior like this.
So this is the world of security, right?
This is the world of security.
Now, here.
Here they always ask for questions
in authentication and authorization
to understand it more clearly.
We should focus.
We should focus on four questions. Right?
If you understand four questions,
if you understand these four questions,
the concept of authentication
authorization becomes crystal
clear from the Philippines. Okay.
So let me give you
one of those four questions.
First is,
who are you?
Who are you? So again, it's
odd. Are you
allowed to access the system multiple
parties
show your eye.
And the fourth is
what excites you
in simple language.
If you ask me to collect these four points
to make a right of this complete
information,
right then you collect the all information
in easy language.
Is this four questions?
These four questions ask Why are you
are you allowed to show your I.D.,
what kind of access you have?
Just understand this question.
And this is all about authentication
and authorization process.
This is all about authentication,
this authorization process,
industrial based, this .11 guy,
the speaker has been just one hour.
What happened?
I hope I hope you guys are not
you know, I'm
not blaming your energy
for the first two question.
The last two will be joined by.
Correct? Correct.
And that's why I gave
you just four questions.
Right?
Just four questions.
Fine.
So if you understand this work,
which is you guys learning
all this bookish definition, right.
Well, this is to help us
in the limited edition part one.
So so here, right here.
Every time,
given the Google definition of bookish
definition is not the best answer,
the best idea.
Instead, if you explain the things
in your own right,
but your own means
conveying the same message
to the original message,
that is the best part of the
It shows that you understood the concept
and now you put it in your framework
and you're spinning in your own words.
Nothing could be better than this.
This is the original version
of your explanation, right?
If you understand this book once,
why you are you allowed show your writing
what access you have and use it.
This is all about authentication
authorization.
Believe me, your interviewer will never
ask a mixed question on this part
right? I
let's proceed for this.
So now we are going to talk about security
because we are going to talk about this
security place,
not the public space,
not the public one, but the secured one.
So here, here, let me give some examples,
not some examples.
Basically, we talk about the applications
of security, secure
application type of security application.
So the one first one, I'm calling it as
stateful application,
what I call in case
genuine up
bank application is a really pretty much,
you know, low level example.
I'm giving
you was kind of an information, right?
And then I think you know level knowledge
fine stateful application
not what does this stateful application
guys let me then you this
let me give you an example.
How many of you guys are
using Amazon in this book?
So if you log into your Amazon
or if you log into a Facebook right
after they ask you for one thing,
what is that?
Hey, do you want to see your credentials?
Remember me?
Seems later,
something like this, they ask you
and if you save your information,
if you save your information next time,
next time when you try to log in,
when they ask you for again,
log in password or they just simply
allows you to log into your homepage
that allow you right
to log in to your homepage, click
simply.
And now it will be captured in the fine.
Now, just keep this one
point in your mind.
Just to keep this one point in your mind,
because now all the information
I'm going to explain from here
on how these things work.
Right. And what are the things missing?
Because there are a lot of different
information available in this concept,
which I'm going to open in the next 5
minutes on a very interesting topic, guys.
I'm expanding
the entire IED free will be crystal
clear to you
if you understand all of this information,
which I'm going to extend into this class
and the models.
Plus, believe me, your perception
when looking at the things that making
us free will change.
If you understand this point. See
see, what they generally do is,
for example,
lipstick and knock, for instance.
Right?
You're not doing this right.
She is trying to exist.
She is trying to exist
to her Facebook account.
To her Facebook account.
Right.
And to violence and occupy in this age.
Why is it so what she does,
she provides that you are in there,
that you are it on that you want it.
She provides her
all right.
He provides username and he provides
password.
Who said she had been saying
he all the times?
Also, she guys please take care of this
brokenness.
She is a
light coming in.
Right?
So not a not great username and password.
He has a new account.
He provides username password.
Now now here.
This is the server.
This is the server under local events
server or browser server.
Right.
This server.
This server has one memory
for this server.
Has this one has one memory.
We cannot remember the guys,
what we call it one
colleague server memory.
Okay, so now what happens?
What happens?
And here, here we had a database.
Right here. We have a database?
No, not a repository.
You can see one database
in normal language, right?
So data is stored here.
Something like this Data is stored.
You know what is happening?
First time
when Hanako tries to log, right?
He enters username and password
after entering username
and password into the server
server first goes to database.
Okay.
See if you enter a username and password
which is incorrect.
Server never asked your browser
never asked you to store this right.
Only in the successful operation.
When you provide
valid username and password, it asks
you to observe it.
Try to log in to your system
with incorrect username and password.
You didn't never ask you
to save your password, but I was.
That is smarter than you.
Great.
So first, what does it goes to database.
It goes to database and takes it database.
Do you have this particular user,
this particular user
with this username and password databases?
Yes, I do have find it returns.
It returns one section 80 What?
It returns one
session.
A session
we call this session in our language is
an admission
granted rate databases yes databases. Yes.
This use existing me right
allow him
allow him to access the application.
Find know what is so what he does,
what somebody does.
So what?
Ask to see your username and password
and it says yes we identify it.
You're a part of this system
and to give you warnings is this
you just do one thing you just save
your username and password here.
Would you like to save
that username and password?
What do you do?
You ask me to remember
your username and password.
If you click on the number of the option,
the moment you click your
you remember the option exceeds
your username and password,
which is already is ten,
which is already established.
The communication
link with their database.
So this connection is always there.
Next time when you open directly,
you go here
and you connect to the server web server.
It connects you with a database.
That's why it never,
ever asked you to enter your username
and password once again,
if you already saved it in your browser
in this room.
This topic so far.
So far.
Just two days later.
Now let's go a process now let's go
a step further. See
when it provides,
when not provide right here
this username and password.
Right there is a server
that is our database, right?
That is a database or month loan.
But she looks good.
He looks good actually.
See, it looks good now
they got to
I just went into it.
You see
now now see what is happening.
This is server.
Now tell me
their database looks like a gate.
Let's make it a proper database
before you it.
I think now.
Now see
just a moment based.
Yeah, maybe so. Now now,
tell me one thing.
If you talk about Facebook
application, right?
If you talk about Facebook application,
how many users you think Facebook has,
how many users,
millions of users, billions of users,
how many is
Facebook has be a thing
that one server is able to handle
all of these things, every single thing,
just one server, low rate,
multiple servers are available.
Multiple servers.
Now see what is happening.
This is your server too.
This is your server.
One stone, one free.
So what happens?
What happens if that is?
A lot of node is increasing on
one particular server,
one particular server.
Your request has been transferred
to another server
by event functionality,
not actual functionality.
We call it
node balancers.
We put load balancers
which are responsible to divert the load,
to distribute the load
among all the servers equally
so that one server
would not take all the load.
Right?
So the load would redistribute
to all the servers.
If load increases, industrial discipline
servers from this point.
So now see, every server has
every server installed would have been
my full time
when you logged in your connection
established via server one.
Correct.
For example,
your connection established was one one.
So your credentials were stored
in just one sort of one.
Or in all these servers.
How it works, Just one sort of one.
In this one, particularly right now,
sometimes you might have observed I'm
not sure where they all do it or not,
even if you stole your information,
even if you saved your information.
Right.
In this case, you couldn't
normally get in this terrible memory.
Sometimes maybe once in a blue moon
or maybe sometimes, like very often,
it again
asked you to provide your username
and password.
Sometimes it happens on raw
and then you must be thinking, Well,
I already saved this credentials.
It must here in my credentials of
in this sort of amendment
and in white is asking
because the first time
when you log into the system
your server one your server
one was there and you created the link
with the server one.
Now no,
because in this system load increases
and because of the increment in the node,
what is happening this time?
Load balancer has diverted your request
to server three.
Now Salvatore doesn't have your logging
credentials, right?
So here here
if you go away a different set of one.
So this server again
goes to database database
and it does different station ID
and after returning different station I.D.
first, when you enter your username
disturbance says, Hey, I do take
your information
provided we get information.
When you provide that information, it goes
here to database, connect with them.
Right.
Take the security now.
Saved your credentials here
and then allows you to log in
so this time again
in the time your connection is available
with the server three,
you will be able to log,
you'll be able to log in and this would
industrial part.
That's how that is how your things work in
is stateful application
because this sort of a memory,
that's sort of what everybody would be
having this server in the state of this
memory is the state to do through.
And because the speed of this server
memory is safe to do
recall it state
full is big, full
stateful application, right.
We call it stateful application
industrial disparities.
That state is set to true.
That's why we call it is full application
guys.
Any question so far?
Any question?
Yes, yes, yes.
So now now I'm
going to touch on another important point.
I'm going to touch
another important point.
Okay.
See, we on this type of application,
stateful application on less security.
Guys, just a moment.
Just a moment based,
can you tell what this to to. Yes.
So this set a lot of memory you see right.
This that a lot of memory.
What we are talking about here.
Right. This server memory.
So when the state of this server
memory is a state to do,
it means this is state of the server
memory is set to true, simply meaning
it is eligible,
it is enabled to store your information.
Right.
So when you make
this server is a state, true,
then we call it is stateful application
in hundred percent of time.
Obviously, if you're providing the server
memory, you have to keep the state of
this memory is true then only
it will be able to store your information
correct that it didn't need to be able
to store your information.
So we call it
set amount of memory is set to true
and when it will be specific to true
because it is dead full application.
Now the point is
this stateful application,
this particular stateful
application is less secure.
Can somebody
guess what is the reason behind this
why this type
of application is less secure
then somebody gets?
What is the reason?
What could be the reason?
What would be the reason behind this?
Any idea that it is public? No,
not normal.
The API is not public.
API is not public.
It on the API is the private one.
That's why it is asking you.
That is why it is asking you
to provide your user admin password.
Now see the reason behind this?
How many server we have?
How many?
Some would be like people server state yet
I'm just giving you four server.
We have multiple server.
Correct now in every single server.
Right. Or in many servers.
In many servers. Right.
Your information is already stored in many
what your information is stored
getting current.
So isn't it that hackers are getting more
and more places, more
and more to like to have your information
right?
They are having more accessible
information in multiple servers.
So now they're don't need to click
and they don't need to access
this database to get information.
What they simply do is
they will hack any of the server,
any of the server,
which is not then because great,
they will hit any of the server
if the phone information of
any of the user, they will simply take it
and they will use it for their own
purpose.
Right?
Right.
Which is similar to the user cutting.
So now what will happen tomorrow?
Maybe you hackers
hacked the information of the normal rate
and the post Twitter account.
The post went well.
You know, they provide one post with
a counter that says I will rule the world
and another day.
And so just woke up and she said a lot
your comments are coming that okay,
we know we know one day you will
and you might be thinking why?
Why they're saying.
And then when she checked for in my post,
someone posted this then she posted
someone egged my account.
Maybe so there is no better
not taking the account
they generally randomly get in
political hacking.
Definitely you shouldn't online. It's
not that difficult.
The ethical thinking is okay.
You know I mean to the point also, I did
several classes over and I ever said this.
Then the class is over.
And look
no right in all your classes
and sending creepy
and then asked this question
and I think
I don't think so now
now this stateful application
and as to why this is less secure,
I already gave you this part on story,
why this is less secured,
less secured information
because of a lot of servers
available somehow.
Now, fine. Now, point let's move.
Let's move
on to the next type of application.
We call it.
We call it is
list application.
But what about today's
is Stateless application.
Okay.
Before looking
guys, the concept of load
balancer is clear.
I like what
you're doing is you're then it's
but that is work
that is headed by database database
under the symbol approach.
Okay so now not when it comes to stateless
application how things work
in this stateless application.
Right.
It's what goes on.
This part.
So here, here, let's see this time.
This time,
because it is already using the baseball.
Great.
So he must be busy with browsing
that information.
So here, let's take another
example, Miriam.
Right,
Right.
So now what he does,
what he is basically.
Okay,
so now here, see Miriam is trying to log
into the information, provides
user name, username and password
and to create she is a user,
she is a user
in, let's say a Wells Fargo Bank.
Right?
She has an account in Wells
Fargo Bank, Right.
So when she has to go in Wells Fargo Bank
now see again, so
will we use against that do here
what But this time
but this time just just give me a moment
This just came here.
I was about to take in.
It's about to I was almost on the verge
to call you.
Fine. So now, see, here.
Here in this type of application,
when use this stateless application.
Remember in this stateless application,
right in this is stateless application.
We do not have many
to log in to log in here.
Right.
I don't have any server memory,
but still I have their database
or I have I have their database.
Correct.
So now how things work this time
when Miriam provides
a user name and password to the server
server, connects with their database,
takes the identity, who are you,
what kind of access you have?
Sure your ID got the permission, right?
Grant the permission? No.
After granting the permission
from the database,
what this person is doing because server
is not going to provide any station I.D.
so somebody is not going to ask
to save your username and password.
If you observe
only this type of application.
Facebook, Instagram, Amazon, they ask you
to provide this option, right?
Save your password,
remember me or something like that.
However, on the other end,
if you talk about any banking application,
right, if you're using native banking,
they never asked you to provide
your username and password to say,
Is there anyone who has
got this type of information
used to remember
your native banking applications?
Wait then never asked you to say
that username and password. Why?
Because they're connected to the server.
Right.
And those servers
and doesn't have a memory.
Those servers doesn't remember.
They did not have any memory. Right.
And because this server
doesn't have a memory,
why would this ever ask to be saved?
Username Password.
It makes sense right?
But remember the option going to Cannock?
Correct.
Right.
So the one I would suggest to you
and take this on priority change your bank
as it is possible
before you see your bank account.
Zero balance right.
Change your bank.
The app can use base 80
but still is this eighties Look
this place.
It is every time
you have to bring the base 80 cutting.
That's what I'm saying.
Because that's what I'm saying.
Every time you're pointing 88
Nice.
But Hunt,
you always think anything anything
you think in terms of company would be a
like she didn't happen.
Everything is
what I do
my experience I have in my plus great
amazing but
guys you should learn
from this
the student see even in this you know
I think should you lot of difficult
topics is is still able to maintain this
creativity that okay how can I put this
compellingly in every single topic
he knows all of these things
even that are still new
transaction numbers but every transaction
got it correct
So now see now see you guys.
Now come back to the topic
in this database
instead of what is getting connected
with the database, despite what happens
because it doesn't have a memory.
So what is not going to support
any session.
However, however, from here,
from will, if
it goes back, if it goes back from here.
So what happen?
It returns.
It returns one thing to the user
that a user go ahead and use your system.
And we call this response
write a response from their database.
And in another language, in another
language is the language, right?
We call it
what we call it
is spoken right now.
What is this token?
This is what we need to understand
simply means
and ever this part
one time password, what it does,
it allows you to provide
your OTP in just 120 seconds
and 90 seconds or 60 seconds.
Right?
Not more than that.
Not more than that, Correct.
I got credit
after 90 seconds on 1.2 seconds.
If you provide
this, then what would happen
then?
What would happen if you wait
after 90 seconds, it will expire.
Then again, you have to generate a new one
again, you have to generate a new one.
The same thing.
The same thing is fretless application
does when you try to log into the system,
it goes to database and it does one token.
The token is having the session
ID in session 80 with expiry time.
Right? Two things.
It has expiry time.
So now this security will expire
at the time initially.
So this you can use
for a particular amount of time.
Right.
That's why you might have observed
if you open your bank application,
you log into the system
and you don't work there for three,
4 minutes or even if you're working after
five, six, 10 minutes,
it says your station is expired,
your station is
expired, it happens or not,
there is.
Then again here to enter your username
and password again, you have to work
on the application by right.
Then why is this happening?
Because of security. What is the security?
Let's see.
Let's say you got one very good
ethical hacker, right?
And he you to account with the token.
So now tell me even with the token
for how much time this user
is able to access your account.
I know this is not memory.
This is not memory.
It is coming directly from the database.
Directly from the database. 90 minute.
And in 91 it is more than enough to rob
the environments.
Fargo Bank right
next to makes one point seconds
90 seconds sixties I guess.
Right.
Or maybe if you are using
intermediate level security application
then maybe 4 minutes.
5 minutes.
Did something like this correct?
Correct.
But most of us, believe
me, we have a lot of intelligent people,
Einstein people, kind of people.
Right.
So if you provide just 25 seconds
to enter the OTP,
they need 30 seconds to read the DP.
Then there it is, I guess, to decide
whether I should put it on
or in the next 30 seconds
to put this six digit OTP.
That's my name is again.
We should consider every single one.
We have 7 billion instruments
on this planet train.
We have to take into consideration
every single one
that.
Yes, correct.
I think.
Why should I give you that example?
My brother, my cousin, my cousin,
the station would not expect
it was still working on the site.
Yes. If you're working
it was actively connected.
But if you keep working there,
right, for 20, 25 minutes after that,
it will expire.
Try this with the bank application.
Someone tried this with the bank
application.
What if continuously
2025 minutes on your bank application
it will get expired and for station in it
they will be there for five 6 minutes
for station
continuous activity of 25 to 30 meters.
Thank you for.
So you only pass authentication
when not authorization.
Authentication
is something we have to pass
and based on the authentication details,
it will authorize
system will authorizes raid.
So authentication and authorization
authorization is relying on authentication
based
authorization
is relying on authentication.
Authentication is something you provide.
So guys this is
is taking less application.
So now even if you multiple servers
12345 server nor balancers, right.
Loan balances is going to divert the node
so it doesn't later on this server
you're going this time
every time you will get a new token,
every time you will get the musician
80 from the database and you work on you,
you work with your system,
you use your system,
you access your system with new security,
with new with the new token industry.
This part
industrial.
Despite today's
fine.
So now let's take a break.
Let's take a break for 10 seconds
or so, 10 minutes late.
I think I'm very much in API.
I'm going to give you more time,
otherwise they should expired.
If I had
to do just 10 minutes, just in this case.
Please, please.
I am in a complete flow.
I want you to learn everything
that you already knew.
Take 15 minutes to learn to take a break
for 15 minutes and others for 30 minutes
break will continue to take class for 2
hours,
will continue working for 2 hours.
It means by your time, 150 or 130
and then it will be clear your class
at 130 will complete your class, say
one hour early, take one third,
you will complete your class.
So for a diverse district list
you have for any of the application
you use, you meet this fitness.
So nobody
because we have our topics
like which are distributed, so forth.
What in the help of a student
for four and a half hours tomorrow
will be able to complete everything okay.
No one my nobody. Today we
you. Yeah.
Not getting disconnected within minutes
great again in 40 minutes actually.
Then do two and a half hour
continuous class looking like
so now
now here
we are going to deal with is debt
less application.
I will also tell you how to work
at this simple application rate,
but there is no point in the
AP of providing a straight,
full application rate is decrease
application, which is dealing
every time we to contemplate we go.
And so now here also that is the main
reason why we created admin user first.
So now after admin user
we will get this token data via
and it will get token,
it will perform all the operations them
will perform all the operations.
So we will get to provide this token to
you are not from the database.
Great database is just a storage database.
It is just a storage
which saves your information.
But who decides whether to provide this
token to you or not?
From the database, it's admin rates.
We decide.
Correct Logic decides
whether to provide you
information or not,
whether to provide you access or not.
And if we are providing access to you,
what kind of access
we are willing to provide.
Right.
So, Edmund, besides this, that's
why now we have a mean right in October
and means
we will going to generate the token
right to perform
whatever operations we want to perform.
So simply authentication
authorization would be done via tokens.
So first we will understand
what this token is all about,
what kind of tokens we have,
which token we will use
and what we have inside the token.
Right.
Let's do a complete operation of this.
You a complete engineering
basically of this token.
Okay, let's start with this.
Let's start with this.
So now, now if I go to my right swagger
video, you see the first
point to be covered
is creating the admin user.
Can you see guys
and you see
first creating the admin user
and then the second point.
And then the second point here
we see is generate the token
guys.
Can you see the second point is generate
token, generate token.
Fine.
So now, Amy, this document,
this document we have already have this
information that this document,
all the relevant information,
what we need to perform and what kind of
what kind of response
we are going to get right.
What kind of response we are going to get.
So remember one thing.
Remember one thing when you are trying
to access the system, grade this database.
Why our server, this database,
why a server is going to give you,
then it is going to give you this token.
So when it is returning the token?
It is returning the token.
It is giving you the access or you are
actually adding a recording database.
What you are doing basically, and
it is just giving you the access.
You're not going to add
any information in the database.
Are you going to record
adding a record in the database?
No, you're not going to end
any record in the database.
You are simply accessing the token right.
And this token is nothing
but some information.
Some information. Right.
What kind of information is this?
Let me tell you.
Client So now the point is, the point is
there should not be the same status code
in response.
What we were getting,
why creating the element user.
There is a big difference
in the status code rate of the response
because here
the nature of operation is different
than what operation we perform in the
creating and meanings of part
industrial,
industrial everyone.
Right.
So now let's look into this operation
from here.
Let's look into this operation.
First base you are.
I would be similar Mark guys base
you are right.
Plus API location is same.
The only thing is changing
is the only thing
which is going to change is
endpoint. Right?
The endpoint is then is the thing
which we will going to change in our base.
You are mark good base.
You are a part
So now simply force take this particular
you want to take all the things
one by one.
We will take all the things one by one.
Now tell me guys, should I create
a new request or same request?
I can continue with What should I do?
New request. Right.
So click here, click on the collection
and it says, Add a new request.
Add a new request.
Fine.
So now when I'm going to add a new request
right here,
the name of the request were Do we
generate
token?
Generate token
or No.
And it's not. Don't do it
as of now, don't do it.
And if you want to do it, you can do us
know if you are done both ways. Are
but don't get
lost yourself in just typing that things
because this is something we are doing
first time. Right?
So I would suggest you do see I am doing
this training base.
You are it
less API location after API location.
I'm going to provide
going to provide this endpoint,
this endpoint see base you are it
plus API location plus endpoint.
Is this correct? Is this correct?
Now come here
and it says which method we need to use.
See, it says
which method we need to lose this
is it just paused.
So I'm going to change it to forced
this.
You want to find an endpoint?
Fine type of method?
Fine.
Now let's read the information.
It says this endpoint will generate token.
Please enter email and password
that was used to create a user
which user it is talking about
admin user.
Right.
Because admin is responsible
to provide that token, right.
And we need responsible
to provide the token.
So we have to provide
the email ID and password of the admin
so that we can bind to database
the database.
I am the admin and I'm going
to generate the token from user ID.
My user can access the system. Right?
So now here, here
you'll see if I'm going to provide
this user name and password for admin,
it will allow me to generate the token.
Now see I generated.
What kind of token is this case?
It says Jason Web token I expensive.
What is this?
Just a token ordinary JSON web
token person takes a chat
and this is only valid for
nice.
Can you see it?
It is only valid for 20 hours
because this is for strictly purpose.
For learning purpose
we get the duration of
expiry of the token is Twitter's.
We kept it intentionally right.
Otherwise, if we just put it to 90
seconds, every time we have to generate
new will complete.
So for us
it means you can use it for longer.
Broadcasting so that it would be easy
for you to utilize
just to now these two points.
If a user has not created for us,
we have to create a new user.
Or if you are not able to remember
the password again, create a new user.
So remember,
even when you perform testing,
when you perform
API testing in most men in your role
or whenever you try to revise
it is always recommended, right?
It is always recommended right? Right.
It is always recommended that
first you create an admin user, right?
And with this admin user, right
this minute user
you have to generate a token. Understood.
So now you see while generating the token,
we got this information,
we understood the instructions
and he after the instructions,
if you see it is asking for the body,
it is asking for the body
and it says body is required.
It says bodies required.
Can you events.
So now now it says in the body,
I'm going to provide email and password.
So I'm going to
provide email and password.
So again, we guys this email and password
crucial and work.
By now.
We added the request on pause to make sure
click on the collection.
This dots click on the collection.
And here you see add request.
Here you see a request.
Click on the collection and add request.
Now now you see generate token
natively generated this pain point.
Correct. We got this body.
So now let's take this body forced guys,
remember this username
and password
is the one we use for creating the user.
So do we have this username
and password or not?
Yes, we do have in not
previously been used that fine.
So now here.
Here to add anybody that I have to go.
Yes. To just that username and password.
So to add the
body we have this option body
in body.
What should I select from your non form
data?
We are to select row after row
after row, select from the dropdown,
JSON after JSON based on this part
based on this place.
See now guys,
see here in this string the email.
So the one we used this is the
remember this email is
what is the name loophole Zima
being transferred in is a strange spot.
Aisha is principal in Katrina
and the students us.
But I still remember seeing copy this
come here pasted, pasted
and here
the password is best in the regular.
Is this correct?
And then I think nice.
Thank you for correcting you guys.
Even in password. Great.
This is work requirement. See this? Right.
So we are not doing anything on one
because the instructions
in one document called Swagger
and we are just following the document.
Right.
And following the instructions
which are available in the document.
We are making this request
right after adding this data,
I'm going to go and click on headers
because inherited here
I have to add one point.
What is think
we have to add one here today?
What is the trend of
we have to add
content type fine
content page.
So what is the content database
application slash just right.
I bought into
header has done
basically what I did
this tartlets were done.
Now See in response.
In response it says it generates work
in response it will generate something.
What does that something
what is that
something that is telling in response
token.
So let's send the request.
There you go.
In this case, we got one thing.
What is that?
We got one thing here.
What is database token?
We got organizer. Great.
Let's make this token right.
Great.
This is their token.
This is the token record
from this request.
No, Every time, every time,
whatever the operation we perform,
we will use this particular token grade
as an access to the application raised.
At the moment, I provide this token.
The moment I provide this token,
it will allow me to access the application
and perform whatever the operation
I want to perform affect
confetti.
Now see now see here
admin can do whatever the things
admin can add or not
eliminate the employee a lot more
and we can update the employer, not admin.
The employees are not
admin can do anything anything great.
They expect to be used
admin, username and password.
You all great operations.
That's why we use admin.
Use ready and password here now.
Now understand this particular token.
Right. Understand this particular token.
We call it
we call it the right
token is this repair
report that we talk about
is take full application
and then we talk about stateless
in this application.
Right.
So now here to this JSON web token
in this JSON token content type,
so you can tell you
what video internal data run
it is the same one, right?
It is the same one,
which is a mentioning here.
You see content type
applications like JSON.
So also put the same thing here
in headers, content type applications.
Let's just correct, correct.
Is this correct?
Nice.
So now here, now see here.
What is this? Just a token. Remember,
remember, we
are going to study three types of broker.
How many types of companies?
We are going to see three types of token.
The first is the first one is beta token,
the second one is Mac token
and the third one is green.
So again,
how dates, dates, we are to make grants
like when we generate the token, generally
we deal with this three terminologies
beta mek, drums and mustard.
The students.
Now this MEK, this MEK is basically a key,
right?
This this it is basically a key.
I'm giving you the really simplified
definition of make token.
It simply means asymmetric interference
between three parties on a client server
and the source.
Right.
It means it'd be a part client API.
So this mechanism requires the
establishment of sharing to keep the same.
Given you exchange in the gig,
it will allow you exist.
So it is not of our use in FBI scope.
We never use bank.
We neither use grants either.
We don't use either
y because grant is basically
used to perform
a specific type of information.
Right?
If you want to transfer the data
from one place to another place
there, you use grants.
So Grant is also out of school.
Mac and Grant,
we're not going to talk about.
So there is just one type of token
which we are going to talk about that is
which token guys that is
beta token to be added token.
So first first we will see
what is this Jason.
Jason there.
Okay. Jason Tokens.
Remember guys, when we talk about Jason
web tokens, right
Always this Jason BEP tokens, right?
Whenever we talk about this token,
this token always comes in three parts.
How many games, how many bugs?
Jason Get tokens.
Always grams, please.
Again, Alexi Gram simply means
if you want to transfer the file or share
the file from one source to another source
in those kind of applications
or in those kind of operations,
you need clients.
So there is no scope of clients
in our testing automation API part
or even in development.
Also be used only beta part.
Okay.
Now when we talk about Jason, them
to console
whether it is against
or if it is a mac or it is a beta.
Jason The tokens always comes
in three bucks, right?
In three parts.
Now let's see, there is a website called
it is a website called JWT
Not Believe It is a website called JWT,
not able or read open this application.
Let me share this.
You want to with everyone
but it's not. You go to JWT
and put it in the message here.
You can use it.
Okay.
Everyone can use a digital duplicate
if someone can post to the same thing
right now.
You got them.
Nice. Great.
So now see guys here we can read here,
we can read about this
introduction part.
So here you see what is JSON.
That token simply simply
we have to understand what is this?
Just some group to be able to understand
this point.
Always remember, always remember.
When we talk about this JSON token
rates, it follows
it follows some kind of algorithms
or standards, right?
Either it is a make or odyssey
or is this is CDC rate.
These are some kind of algorithms
this token follows.
Who provided that key?
Have you ever heard about encryption
and the picture?
Have you ever heard this does not work?
All right.
So when I told you to change your
bank, but it's really a logic
like check.
What is that?
You should be right.
Don't worry. When troubleshooting.
Now, guys,
see in this JSON web token, writing
this JSON token is what it is
to encrypt data
from encrypted form information.
All right, this is some information
in encrypted form or read encrypted form.
So now, see, we did first
simply what Token does, guys, we know it
very well.
What are the two things?
Insecurity based guys?
When we talk about private APIs, Private
APIs takes care of security in two phases.
Part one is authentication
and, part is authorization, right?
So here
this JSON tokens are doing nothing else
but authentication
in authorization, correct?
Correct.
Authorization
and authentication information exchange
simply means it is a part of authorization
also.
Right.
What kind of excuses you have,
what exists.
We should give you this thing now.
Now here you see in its config form JSON
web two guns
consist of three parts separated by dots
in its compact form.
Decent web tokens consist of three parts
separate ID by dots which are header
payload signature
which are header payload signature.
Now you see this.
This should be
this should be the of just a token x x x.
Let me put one more y y, y, y or z z z.
Can you see
can you see this case
right now?
This bar, these three bars every token
must have separated by separated by dots.
So now C windows is separated by dots.
If you go to post men, can you see
this is one part dark.
This is vacant park
dark.
This is part of work.
It means my token is just a token or not.
Come on. This.
You see, these are B minor details
and then you read BD minor detail.
I'm telling you, first bar,
second bar, code bar,
separate ID,
but don't disagree with token point.
Now, what does it mean?
What does it mean
when I see this particular part?
So this is some encrypted form
of information.
Encrypted form of information, Right.
And what this information has here.
So now, see, I'm
telling you, in this token, in this token,
this was x, x x x is nothing but your
header.
Then when we talk about why they buy it,
why it is nothing but you'll be known.
And then Zsa Zsa
Zsa Zsa is nothing but your
your signature.
Your signature header
payload and signature.
Now we have to understand
what is this header?
What is this payload?
What is this signature?
Three things, right?
This. But
all right.
Why payload is equal to worthy
nice apple.
What a genius guy you are proud of.
You right?
You are absolutely correct.
Absolutely perfect.
Payload means body.
Fine.
So now, now, here.
Here was two.
We talk about header.
What is this candidate?
What does this member header consist of?
Two parts.
And therefore that consists
of how many parts guys
and it consist of
two parts.
Great. One plus one byte. Excellent.
Another mainstream, low key and value
according to Einstein.
Amazing. See this?
This is what I call innovative, innovative
mind to trade, sometimes key and value.
I think he said
one plus one is equal to two.
Amazing.
If I was between us today,
I would have come to your home Butterfly
rhythm book and both of you agree
that I would have to do this these days.
You guys did something
amazing
in the book from my show, Guys,
your late William
Wellington's days already passed.
You were never advertised your shop yet
in the right and I would have I.
I could have tried my level best you know
to contribute to your as much as I could
because here I could have,
you know, forced everybody
to purchase.
But Nikola not took a knock.
It's what, a month in a Katrina for both.
Like you're sarcastic, gentlemen.
There's a kind of active truth.
So now, hey, has how many things
and is what they say.
Don't worry. Look,
I'm not going
to, you know, I
think two parts.
Two parts. Here is the first one.
The first one is
what kind of token it has.
Type of token.
What kind of token it is.
First thing is type of token.
And the second thing is the signing
algorithm,
right?
The signing algorithm that is being used,
algorithm used
such as your age make or your RC
or your asset two, five, six or something.
So this is finding algorithm
something, right?
This algorithm is generally encrypting
your information grade,
whatever the information here
that we have, it is something
encrypting, right,
and giving you an encrypted form.
So who is doing this?
This signing algorithm is doing okay.
So the first is what kind of token?
The type of token.
And the second is signing algorithm.
So it is
we have these two things in header now.
See now see this part?
This part is having two things.
Your type of token you're signing
will go to them.
I will show you.
I will show you these also.
Okay.
So first thing clear what is header?
First thing clear.
What is it?
I always use genius to punish.
I never said to devise. Like
if I am in a
serious mood, if I'm talking to a person,
I always talk.
They always make sure that this person is
always counted, should always be counted
from talking to that person.
So I never use this kind of words.
And then one of them, the signing
algorithm consists of what exactly?
The signing algorithm is nothing,
but the algorithms are great.
So basically it is a programing.
You can see that is converting
your message into the interpreted form.
Okay,
so this is the name of this algorithm only
for all the Einsteins.
Again, same thing.
It is no one exception.
Alright, fine.
So First part of token is header.
This second part of token is guys
below or body, right.
Nobody.
So what does it mean what we have in this
or what we have in this body?
Remember, it contains information.
It contains information about
who is the issuer of the token posting,
who is the issuer of the token?
What is the expiry name of this token?
What is the subject of the token?
Who is the audience of this token?
Right, that issue and expiry time
subject of the audience, all these things,
all these things we would be having
in this paper, in this body, right?
Because simply in simple language,
we call it
claims
what we call it claims, right?
Someone is claiming
someone is claiming something great.
So it is claiming that we are
be sure this is the experiment.
This is the subject, this is the audience,
this type of information
we have about this token in payload
here, in payload,
basically it by
then the next thing and the last thing is
we have the third part, third parties
signature,
third parties signature.
So now in the
signature, you'll see it says
fixes.
The signature is used.
The signature is used
to verify
the message.
The message was not changed,
was not changed along the way.
What does it mean?
It means the message
which we are sending the same message
would be the soon to be claimed
right the way.
So it means the token which is generated
does same token we should exempt.
So signature is having all these things.
All right.
All right so you get consider
this is a part of authentication.
Obviously this is authentication
and for correctness
the signature is used to verify
the message was not changed along the way.
Now this is the
this is the time to operate out of
see therefore, what it says are typical
JWT token
looks like x, x, x, y, y, y, z, z.
Now let's break down the token and see.
So here, if I go, let me do it.
Let me open this website
correctly.
Correct.
Now you'll see here they see this token.
First I made empty.
I made it empty. Right?
And now I'm going to copy my token from
my to confront Postman.
I copied my token from post
when I pasted in the moment I pasted here.
You see, it gave me header,
it gave me payload, it gave me signature.
Three things.
And you see
it issued its coordinates.
You can also copy your tokens
which you guys have generated
in your postman
and just put it here in the debugger.
The moment you put it, you'll give
it will give you header
payload and signature
grade signature.
Now see, according to the information
we have seen, I am provided to you
see every information you see that
type of token is what see just to go.
It's this type of token.
What is your type of token based?
What is the table? The token
student's JWT?
Simple.
It means JSON, web, token JavaScript,
the web token, no December token, but
this is just another token rate.
And the algorithm we are using,
is it just proof of the six?
Can you see who is encrypting
my information?
The algorithm signing algorithm, which is
sending algorithm it just to five six.
This is the part of it
that contains things.
Both these things we have seen here.
Now go to the payload in payload
you see right expiry time.
This issue here is this right?
And then after issue, what you see,
what is the subject rate?
What is the audience?
So this is the audience for this user
idea.
Is the audience right?
Who is going to use it? Correct.
So all this information
you'll see in payload or not,
right.
But now I'm going to
because JavaScript
and JavaScript in JavaScript
object notation is a simply like,
you know what
I would see
Labor Day without labor,
like this one in our language,
that is our dessert
curriculum with our the rules,
something like that.
But yes, and please ask,
please ask
explicit, read explicit.
Where
in pain
automate is three four, three nine.
So this is not something we have provided.
This is something just token
provided, but
we provided just our username and password
and all this information
we deployed anything from here.
This is something we got.
And what is this?
This is the decoded form
of this particular token.
Is it idea of that user, correct.
Correct.
So it generates every name
a different one,
obviously, if there is a different user.
So this is the encoded form of information
I've seen
and this is going to be coded
form of this particular token, Right.
So what this token has,
we are getting all this information
from the database it generates
based on the security grade and station.
And it could be anything,
It could be anything.
Three, four, 391, two, two, one, two,
three, two, two.
It could be anything.
It's not in our head.
Okay?
Because you didn't provide anything.
And see here
this invalid signature, right?
It is.
I don't know why, but yet we are getting
all this information, so don't worry.
So hidden question.
Yes, it is.
Ask. No, no.
You just generate token.
You use it.
You perform your operation
focus on the ABC scored bit in that
you don't go home simple.
Like I said, in the first attempt
of learning you learn every single thing
late.
This is something to get a job.
It's for understanding, right?
So it is something great which helps you,
which helps you to get a job.
After getting a job, it's your calling.
They find the easiest way to get the job
done,
get promoted, switch on to another job.
Be like Superman.
Then you can always explore
other ways around the work
getting engaged.
So this is not something you do every day.
It is just for information, right?
Like I said, are when to operate.
So that's why we just included
all these three points, right?
And I'm giving you the information
what every point contains.
So you must know, okay, I'm getting this
just the right.
And tomorrow you never know
if your manager asked you to
educate your team on
API or take the trainings of API
for your team because your team is new
and they don't know how to work on it. A
For hard,
the token is basically a stateless
application.
When we discussed
what is a stateless application,
but we do not have server remedy.
If you do not have server memory,
there is no place to save your credentials
and if there is no place
to save your credentials, database returns
the response to the server instead of
well returns the station ID token.
So this token is nothing
wouldn't exist to be excused
granting the permission to you
so that you go and access
the particular system for a moment
and then
delete point of time.
Okay. But
a new book,
I don't know why, because maybe sometimes,
you know, because of the user's
easiness raid so that the user
just one time and the saved their data.
They don't need to log in again and again.
There's one reading.
And if the decision expires every time.
Right.
You see people use
when I was in our grade,
but banking applications,
they use one, five, six, seven
when it's not more than that integer
unless you are milania
and then you have to transfer
billions of dollars every day.
How many of you guys use your Internet
banking rate?
And for more than 5 minutes in one shot,
how many of you guys
for encryption?
And encryption
simply means order that you are going
to change its language
to see what is in there?
Correct?
It's not going to change the information.
It shows you
that the actual form of information
that is what encoded
decoded meaning right.
Right.
So if the expiry time of the
token is limited,
there's is fine explanation of the time.
It's very time on the token is limited.
So one can not change after decoding
it will be same.
It is just to let you raid.
It is just to let you know.
Tell me when you are using your two EUA
applications.
Right
when you're using it, your applications.
First of all, the use API is for testing.
Have you seen any user
was is doing transactions via API?
Have you seen any user on this planet?
Tell me if you find anyone
was taking this particular part and doing
imposition. Got it. Got it.
This is a temporary token.
I give the example of a banking great.
It's for us to.
So there is data collection
that has been established in between
the UI and the database
from the presentation layer
to the data layer in this middleware,
how data is being transferred.
We are testing this data via API, right?
That's why we are able to see their token.
But if you're using your native
application, can you see the token?
If you don't see
the token, how would you grab this token?
If you don't get this token,
how would you decode this to happen?
If you don't decode this token,
how would you see the different
information in the decoded form?
There's two different things, guys.
We are doing it from distinct perspective,
but in the end, like whatever
you do, you know, with the UI,
because you put users
your way has been implemented, right?
And on the UI part with the website,
you never see these tokens.
They don't get confused in between what
you are learning and what you are doing.
These are two different things.
This is for your job.
This is not for you.
Really. Don't ask me.
Provide me that API offline.
Spargo I'm going to do translation
time using this JSON token, right?
Joe Biden will commit suicide after that.
Don't do that.
If if you understand this part,
it will get my
Americans are going to make transactions
using API based on decent biblical.
Can we just in having three parts
Hey look, we're not signature, right?
He might be thinking how intellectual
people become now in the US saying
these are two different things.
This is a single that pretty good
students.
One understanding my point
I saw No,
no no Silver I'm not getting mad.
I'm just kidding.
I'm in a very good mood like a separate,
uh, no, I'm fortunate enough
I didn't.
All right, guys. Yeah. Yeah.
Then that's what I'm saying.
I'm like, Yeah,
I skipped from there.
Fine.
So now let's see what this request first.
So now you guys see so far
there's some mistake like this.
The best thing, Alex,
that is, does their reality.
We all have to accept,
believe it or not, consider it or not.
One day we all have to lost our lives,
right?
Today's his day.
The model will be made that
no foreign.
If I get serious, I will tell you
when I'm going to get serious.
Because right now
I'm trying to teach you something.
So it it's very essential for me
to maintain the balance of the class
if I just give you all the time,
all the 5 hours,
believe me,
you do not have potential as a student.
I don't have potential as a teacher
to beat except fight.
The worst is strictly is to the point.
Otherwise you guys get boredom
because you're a student.
You will listen to me,
but you will not be an activist.
None of the great.
So I have to maintain the environment
of the class, which is very healthy
so that I don't need to push you to less
than what I'm seeing.
You will always be an active
listener, right?
This is what I do
so I don't get mad.
And yes, obviously,
and expecting a lot from you guys.
Not totally from last three
or four months.
That's what I've been telling you, right?
This is important for me.
That's why I set my expectations with you
from the very first day
because I know you guys.
I don't want to deliver.
I cannot just click on this fifth part,
just click on this important said.
If it is it,
just see what our brain experience will
not trade on them.
No one can think even more.
Think
that is getting very interesting.
Congratulations on this
nice Aborigine emerald custom.
No, exactly.
The one is it?
This is fine.
Answer this for straight Alexa.
I just explained we have to save it.
So once you save it, it becomes paused.
You also, Jacob,
is to get temporary
access to share security information.
Correct, Jimmy.
So you'll see here Jimmy
in this information barred
it says Jason Token is valid for 12 hours
only after 12 hours.
It did not work.
Oh, yeah.
Katarina Correct.
But then when it comes to buy a new car,
I already have a lot of showrooms
in India.
Also trade in you open variable.
One second. Yeah, sure, sure.
There you go. Great.
I have not done showrooms in India
also have been prices are even much lesser
than places in you is great
also import duty I can see
I don't need to go into the custom
check that on a lot of my select is yes
there obviously it is correct
but still the point is I don't know.
I have a new car to buy a new car.
That's the point.
Concerned about finding a car in India.
So. All right, guys.
So now we have talk.
We have generated a token.
So now we have a mini
user in the system, right?
We have generated a token also.
Now, whatever the operation
we are going to perform from here,
we will need this token
so that we can tell to our system
that, hey, system, I'm an admin,
I haven't permission,
this is the token accepted
and allow me to do whatever I want to do
and what I'm going to do,
I'm going to perform great operations.
I'm going to perform great operations
categories.
Correct.
Like I hope your days
that you guys are not getting bored now.
Great.
I see your lot of previous stations and
you guys are not responding deductively.
I can totally understand that.
What is the reason?
That's why I changed this technique
and in the match it ended point of time
in our operations we open for hug.
If it is a stateless application.
No, we have to have this particular find.
Look to
find this.
So now, now let's do first operation
with the help of token.
What is that operation?
From this kind of paradigm,
we created something great.
So let's take an example for any
adding an employ into this.
I'm going to create a new employee
in their data.
So how can an employee all normal users
going to deploy no on only enemy, right.
So now now tell me to add a new employee
in their database.
What is the first thing I need
one way
to create user
would you need for general Token Now
I don't want you to see your
all swagger document, but still instead of
don't use your common sense logging,
there is no log in raid.
We had a procurement appearing.
Now we are not performing
any building forced.
We need bees. You are right
guys.
Come on.
We need a basic. You want a
This is the very first thing I need
is this in base You what I am
what I need
base.
You are in
plus API location
plus and important
plus end point correct
base you are only plus API location
plus endpoint.
Then what is the next thing?
I guys after we ask you what I
this part
is common to everywhere
because the same database
but this part is changing
according to the operation we are making.
So for create user,
it was different ordinary token
it was different now for ending it.
A Right, it is different. Okay.
And the next thing I need is mine is mine.
The node payload simply means body, right?
What what, what are the parameters
I need in the body?
Who is going to give me this information?
Okay, tell me this.
What are the things I should put in
the body I can get that information from.
From swagger,
from Slick
Connect.
After this.
After this. We need
we need headers
here.
Here we need first content
applications like JSON or whatever.
Right?
Then.
Then we need another thing.
That is my method,
which meant that I'm going to use.
So which method have to use instead?
Okay.
What is the reason behind this? Why?
Why I want to use Boost?
Why not other?
Because we are creating. Exactly, exactly.
We are going to add a new record
in the database
to add a new record in the database
we have to use all method.
We have to use boost method. Right?
So all this information we need to create,
let's collect all this information.
So first first let me go here.
We add a new request.
So to add a new request from here,
I add a new request case,
but I should go
click on this three buttons,
then click on add request,
then give the name, create
and create and employ raid.
Create an employ.
Correct.
Now let's follow swagger.
What can we begin
so going see for creating the employee?
This is the one.
This is the one first why
I am telling you to create the employee
Because after creating
the employee will add a record rate.
It means violating the record,
creating an employee, and after they will
big, big venue
will receive this information,
will get this information,
will the information
and after retrieving the information,
will play with it, will update it.
We delete it.
And then whatever the operations
we want to do, we can do that.
It's the main reason.
First,
we are adding a record and the store
makes getting my point
swing.
So let's take this now.
Let's take the let's take the end point
from here to make it complete.
So I'm picking this end point
also adding it here.
I got to complete this.
You are categorized
complete based.
You are going to be gone and then we are
going to select post from here.
We are going to select post from here.
Now see, it says Body required.
It means body is a mandatory part.
And we finished this one more.
The link for this site.
For swagger you need a
there you go.
I think he shared this.
Alex, can you please check?
So now you'll see in this body
what are the things we see guys
guys in the body.
You see all of this information?
Students.
Just copy this body from the
Just copy this body from here.
And where should I post to this body?
Then we
select the raw.
Just the body, which all
Jason
is Twitter.
So now see implied force name.
I'm going to provide the
we have to create a header again
even though when you copy and the header
compared with the header creative
said yes, I'm expanding this range
so that these items are hidden
and providing this simple header
which can be which we can show,
which we can see.
Right.
So even if you create, it's not an issue.
So it's good practice basically
to create headers to maintain those fonts.
Alright,
alright.
So now in first name, great hostname I'm
going to take, give me a nice
then the last name is
you'll get the money, you're gonna
find. Yes.
Yes, yes that is correct.
Not a nice name yet.
The one that I know every time.
I can't make everyone happy, you know.
Okay so the expert leaving
little bit to meet the.
All right so let's take next name is yours
so they live
would be
all going now school another
buying.
No no
I got I got confused here
inter aim for male and F for female.
So now what should I put.
So let me put here F right.
Employ gender is F
and now here I'm going to provide I'm
going to provide here
the employee would be.
So it'll be 2000 and late
17th of February 17th
February
or 18th of February 2000 and employ is
status
is employee right and providing employee
and here I'm going to provide
this data is cloud consent
now 21 years old employee Ellen
child labor law
that's why I just read about it
so I need to know right now.
See 21 or 22, just 20 to do this back.
If someone doesn't remember little name,
can we leave it as it is?
Yes, we can leave it as it is.
No insurance.
We can play with any you know, we it now.
We'll see you guys.
Even if I'm providing this boss name,
last name.
Really rate everything.
Who's providing this data?
It's you.
When you enter your Euroleague,
sign up for free and you provide for us.
Then we didn't name last everything.
You provide data from UAE.
That's
how things are getting stored there.
So things are getting stored in the store
despite everyone.
Everyone around us
put the spark right now.
What is the next thing
after this?
What is the next thing?
We have to look
saying, Come on guys,
first we have to add header here.
Behind that is my
content type
and the venue is application slash.
Jason Right, Application slash.
Jason Right now.
Now I told you one more thing
after adding header.
So far so good.
Everything we have ID based
you are right the method, the body,
the haters and single thing.
But still one thing is pending.
What is that token that we generated?
Token that we generated?
And now what is the reason that we have to
update token every single time?
Because
I'm going to play with the database.
I'm look, I'm going to claim
in the database the database
I am allowed to perform
this particular operation in the database.
So database is not to trust on this point.
What I'm saying database is going to ask,
do you have any proof?
So I will provide the token.
There you go. This is the proof I have.
I got access from your database and I can
do whatever the operation I want to do.
So authentication
authorization is being done via
via your token.
Via your token.
Remember, guys, remember,
this is a stateless application
and it is the stateless application.
We always deal with token stored
in a stored.
So now now see here authorization.
Did you see when debit authorization
and everyone said
select this authorization, select
this authorization
that and here from the dropdown
which token
we are going to use those
we had a token raid.
So simply select beta from here,
simply select the beta from here.
And then this is the token
trying to force to delete this token
deleted.
Make it empty.
Now go where you have generated the token,
where you have generated the token
and copied it from there.
Copy the token that you have generated
recently
because this token
is saving the expiry time for dwellers.
So still, still this token is valid
because we just generated
what is it, time of demolition everyday
you then go
and to create an employ
go and to create employ here.
Right?
Going to create an employment
based nor double course
double quotes is available here
because that data is coming in decent.
What we do see it is in decent forward
suggestion.
Just I just give a look.
So this is the key.
This is the value, right?
So really comes in double codes.
But when you're copying this right, don't
copy cause just basic raw value here.
So this is the value of bitcoin.
This is the value required for industrial.
At this point, everyone
understood this point, everyone
try. Shall we
proceed further now?
Anything else
pending or everything completed this?
Is there anything which is pending
or everything is completed?
Everything is completed.
Correct? Correct.
It's okay.
Fine.
Let's send it
guys.
What is the expected response API code?
I should go here.
What I got is
201201 created.
Is this the correct one
that I was expecting?
See just the most forward
to this particular status code
and it says that request
has been fulfilled
and it resulted in a new resource
being created
right.
And now if you observe closely
in the body of the response,
you got the date of the employee
along with one additional field.
What is that additional
employ 80,
employ 80.
So this is the unique part
in that database or this particular
this is
the unique part in the database
for this particular employee
right there displayed
we all visit employ 80
and whenever you work
with multinational organization
there they ask you can we take
you actually make you actually create.
So we got this data from the database,
we got the I.D.,
we got the message to zero one we created.
Right?
So a whole other way.
You have to check this been me.
It's everything is crystal clear. Jamie,
is there anyone with any note,
whether their data is created
or because we go to the employee
double check by using you?
You know, so remember, one thing wouldn't
clear anything right from here
to let you work.
So even if you try to log in
with this admin credentials,
create the one which we created
in your try to provide log in there.
You would not get the data
because if you do trust or will respond,
that means it is passed right when?
You test differently from the post
when only we will check whether we have
this information in their database.
So we will check that
this is what we call retrieval operation.
Yes, actually it is the same way
how to create
so we can use this credential.
You mean index?
Why would the logic work?
Simon, You are asking from your way
because we intentionally not the way
did this linking to this API
what you want.
That's why
the user that you're creating in the API,
it will be as it is in the API.
We provided
specific details, the specific
linking with the you way we knew it
experience when you know the way to create
log intelligence here for the enemy
and they will use it intelligence in you
and they will do whatever operations.
And if they have any argument in the class
with someone,
where does the UI verify
from the database?
Yes, I'm getting a UI benefit
from their database
cutting, but it's all about
you always limited the access, right?
You always do with the emphasis
in the end.
So maybe I missed the question.
Well, do we need to clear the things
from Postman Mustafa?
Do we have any other options?
And then simple.
Okay, we have see,
Postman is basically an API
to write to, even to work with the
I mean for what purpose. Up.
That's, that's what I'm saying.
See your selenium is available,
your website is available,
your database is available right now.
Who is creating the connection in between
your website and your database API.
Right.
So API is sponsoring the reader correctly
or yeah.
Who is providing the data API.
So whether API is providing their data
in the correct connection
name is working
properly, not be able to take this or not.
We have to check this. Right.
So from UI, can we just API? No. Why?
Because then that would be your selenium
testing, your whitelisting
and rejected from the database.
No. Otherwise
that would be your database testing.
Then what is the be
the way is to test something
the middle way grade
and to test something in the middle way.
We do not have any UI available,
so if you do not have any UI available,
we would make trouble.
We will not be able to perform
in existing.
That's why we need one tool
that will ask us to provide this thing.
This is UI for us.
This UI is for our help.
Right. Be happy.
Honestly, it was risky in the market.
If you don't want to use postman,
use the RC.
We have Tosca.
If you don't want to use this, use Tosca.
We have soap. You don't.
If you don't
want to use this useful point,
if you have not all of these things,
this is free of course, but use this one.
That's why people in industry
use postman a lot.
This is the purpose to take the connection
that has been established.
When we thank you so much.
I am just great, sir.
You're always welcome. I
know there are a lot of books in this API.
There are a lot of books in this API.
But yes,
because we are generating the data,
it will return the same use
of 80 employs 80.
If we create a new data,
it will create new employee.
Don't worry about that.
Our books in the application.
But the intention behind this
I repeat once we proceed further
because we don't have to best only happy,
but we will see some books also,
they don't want.
So far so good.
Everyone
there to encourage encouragement.
Nice and great.
So now, now see
my but in API you are beating sequel.
Excellent and people are so smart.
They used already
my sequel workbench in the followed
that for employees
is having the same employee.
Maybe they are not bothered about API
but what we are teaching yet
and what we're learning in
the API delivered by a sequel,
we're committed for their sequel.
But next,
what do you do in selenium classes?
You perform Java.
In Java Review, you will
you learn destiny and destiny.
You think about sequel. They
don't do it.
They don't do it.
The classes for 24 hours
after that you have 24 hours.
They then these things in those 20 hours.
Okay.
Yeah.
Just trying to learn connecting dots.
Exactly.
If the application is the instance Vega.
Yes. If there is a token part,
then token parties or will always be in
only stateless
custom bid.
Send your query to Alexa.
You also want to try
Alexa,
Should I open my
My sequel will be mentioned. You?
No, not sorry I.
I'm. I'm just kidding.
Doing. It's good, right?
Okay. Right. Select star.
It wins from other people.
Aside from one particular agent,
it just employ the database.
Right?
And then you have to provide
a valid keyword
when you given on
what one particular keyword is employed.
The employee can take proposal
to put in there and whether you'll get
the option. Okay.
But I don't know, I guess you guys do
because
it's suitable.
So now, now understand this first,
first what we did was
first what we did created means that
but with the help of this admin
user, with the help of this admins use it,
we generated a token kind,
we generated the token.
Now this is one cycle
that we have completed.
This is one cycle
that we already completed.
Does not expect expected to be enough
cycle.
Please come back.
It's enough
once to be submitted.
Your status
focus here something important.
I'm going to be excellent.
So now this element in dendritic
token part, we are done with great.
We are done with this part
now. Now what we did,
the first thing is we created
we create an
we create an employee, right?
We create an employee
by now and mean
consider your current operations.
You're working in the industry, right?
And you are the first one who is going
to perform any test in the right.
If you try to retrieve the information
without creating the employee,
your DSW database
already already have nothing.
It would be divisive,
nothing. It has nothing.
So with your retrieve,
operation will work.
You are trying to update the data
in the database with your update operation
Work eliminate your retrieve operation,
your update operation.
And even if you tried
to delete the database
but it work database will return.
I don't have anything to delete.
Right. Same. No.
Right. Exactly.
You Could have used capital.
Millions of. Okay.
So it all depends from here.
It all depends from here.
With this you don't create operations.
Paused
We have to add a record in the database.
So once we have something in the database,
we can either retrieve it
right TGT or delete it.
Correct
correctly days.
That's
why intentionally to make the cycle work.
First we created the input
plus to be known as the criminal logic.
Why we did it
gutting it
enables us to use remaining methods.
So after this what we will do, we will get
this created.
Employ.
We will get this create an employee
carrying
activities
that will get this created employment.
And then after this,
after creating this data,
we will update will update this employment
rate based.
We will update the employee content
after updating the part will get updated.
What is the reason behind this
why we are doing this?
First, we are creating the employee way
of getting the employee.
Then we are updating the employee data.
We are getting the completed employment.
What is the reason behind this
One guy is
to check whether that same information
has been updated
against that particular employee.
Not or not understood.
Understood.
And then then we have another information.
See, did I do is to update any employee
how many was
how many ways to do it?
First, either
I should update all the information,
post them with a name, last name,
gender, date of birth, employment
status, employment category, job title
everything, object all information.
Or I can do another to keep false name
brand name last
name as it is just changed.
You don't work, just change update it.
It means update
on issue details of employment,
partially update
employment current
and then get their details.
Get their details of
it right so do is to update
do is to update first fully
update second
is partially of good correct? Yes.
Correct. Correct.
Correct.
I'll come to that window
and then we will do
delete the employee.
We will do delete the employer
and then we'll see employee gets deleted.
So we try to access the information
from the database.
Database will return.
There is no found against this employee.
It means employee
has been deleted from the database.
Employee has been deleted from that.
It is correct.
That is correct.
Create update.
Update partial delete.
Get information we are doing already here.
Right all the great operations
now we are in this.
Creating an employee enables us to perform
all the other operation,
getting the information, deleting
the information, updating the information.
It is only update
partially updating the information.
All these things is ending.
So we use a big gizmo, we use talking.
I think they use you don't
we don't see everything.
You programed it
if you just created an employee, right.
Let this employee survey images
for one or two days
and then we will update its information
right.
Don't be so harshly that newly created
by would not pitch.
Look what I would tell you.
The difference would been, wouldn't that
great?
I will give you the difference
and we can put it back right now.
Let's stick to the gig and then we'll see
what and then we'll see which.
Okay.
And then
and then a lot of other operations.
For example, what about the users
I have in the database because I know
people are
people will definitely apply this trick.
They will use this to me.
They will create hundreds of employees,
none of job everything.
So we'll see, get all employees,
whatever the employees we have,
it will perform this data to an operation
because we have these links.
Get all employees.
They will see that after this.
And we'll see get job right
for all the employees,
all the job titles available there.
And then we will see get employment
status, all the employee status.
These all are the things we will look
at this all are the things that we look at
going to
categorize
purpose.
I thought we doing all of those today.
Yes, we are going to do all of those. But
Google, we got a way to do all of those.
But don't do the
but what made you think mistake?
We are not going to perform
all this today.
What made you think this?
I'm still here with you based.
You wanted to know why would I bounce?
No mark at all.
Fine. Right?
If I bones break,
you guys will become 4 to 1 in individual.
I or goodie
or great.
You got it.
And then you got it.
Actually,
what what is happening is here late of
what is happening here.
I'm going to cover
every single point. Right.
But first, it is important
that I should give you the proper outline
that these are the things
we are going to cover right now.
The moment basic we are going to cover
all these points, right, is
going to stick it in and we
think
this much information in one day know
people get frustrated
with the hook one by one.
I think it's just we didn't get employed
in that in the response.
Yes, that I know.
I know that
I know that nobody is is something.
Right.
I'm telling you, these are intentional
books available in the API.
Okay.
If we gave you rate,
if we give you only the happy box
that everything is working absolutely
fine and, then you go into the industry
and they're on your retail program
to get such kind of responses
and you'll think there'd be just
something else.
Now here we are getting something else.
So first we have to check how to play
with this or defect.
eBay's
fine,
fine.
Yeah, that's great.
That's great.
It's like more of a than Atlas.
Everyone is dancing,
laughing, sending horses,
something that great.
So now.
Now the next operation.
The next operation.
You see, we created the employee according
to the topic, according to the page.
What is the next thing we have? Google.
After creating the employee
would know first to get created, employee
first to get created employed urging
a Luna has seen it Katrina
to update for us to be able to check
whether this particular employee exist
in the database or not.
Rights of slaves get created
employee See here
I believe I did it on
it is no option to
see create employee
and then get create an employee, right?
So first we have to create
get to be created employee
and then we can think of operating
the employee, correct?
Correct.
So now, now let's come to this point
to get that created.
Employee
What is the first thing we need guys,
come on screen
X to get the creation employee
What is the posting need
to base you on? I
basically want to create
what it does take anything we need.
We need body.
Okay,
fine.
Now tell me why is when we need a body.
We need body
when we have to add another base.
You are right.
Means you are an
API location plus end point.
So we got this to add
something in their database
to create a recording their database,
we need body.
So here, when we are going
to get some information from the database,
do I need to have a body?
That is their difference.
Nobody. Right now.
Let's go to Swagger.
See, when I open the swagger,
it says, Get one employee days.
We are going to get all the employees
or just one employee.
Just one employee.
So fine,
open this bar, open this part.
See It says
query.
This is not the body. Like
we forget the difference.
This is the body. You see,
This is the body.
And here it says, is tranquility.
Understood the difference.
This is a barometer.
What kind of barometer?
Query. Barometer.
So now, now we query barometer.
Why any barometer?
What I need, I need employee I.D..
I need employee 80.
If you go in, create employee,
it will say, can you see employee I.D.?
This is the same employee
and see this a screen and this is strip.
See him or not see him or not.
Right now
the question is, do you have to create
a request all the time, make up and create
inappropriate.
You can just add
this is the best practice.
Do we just to cross-check?
Just to cross-check?
If you don't want to do it, that's fine.
If it is working fine, no issues,
but if it's not working fine,
then you are the one to blame, right?
Your managers will ask you,
did you check after adding the employee
that it was the right?
So just to keep us safe,
it's better to run one more
on which time it takes
just based in seconds.
Right.
But it can save up from.
Right?
Actually, it happened in my organization.
One of my members right.
And she was doing this. I answered her.
He said that the retaining ability
to check.
Yes, sir.
Everything I checked,
I turned out to be ready for deployment
and that because we are ready
to get more than ready.
That's what he is not confident.
She said, Yes, I'm confident in a way.
But Hope was predicting deployment
does deals when they're on site with check
and before production deployment
I will check EPA once again.
I point what he was doing.
She was just adding an employee.
She was not cheating.
Not he employed a customer.
Basically it was a transportation act.
So she was just keep adding
the new customer she was getting.
But she didn't check whether the database
is responding correctly or not.
EPA was responding
correctly or not. Great.
So she was adding the order number.
She was getting the customer stock number,
she was getting the phone number
in every single thing,
but she was not checking.
And we came to the opposite like 5 p.m.
in the morning right? Right.
5 p.m.
in the morning is late,
almost evening, 730 in the US.
So basically from USA,
that is the best time to provide
the maintenance time so that even the
is down for two, three, 4 hours straight.
No is going to stick that much because
people are sleeping at the rate that's
why we do have early morning deployment
from our late evening during US time.
Right.
I was
relying on
her because she was one of my superstars,
my team and other team
members were also doing good.
I went to Office Order team in the morning
by August to perform some API testing.
She performed.
I got the reports, I made it.
I sent it to the list that get fine. Now.
These are the important features we have.
These are the requisite features we have.
We are done with all of these points
on the checkboxes I've checked.
Go ahead and deploy
the moment we deploy in
both production deployment
testing a guy from our team only.
Right. He found it.
So the data is not going to be of data
from the application.
That is some issue with the API
on the production. It happened
so I should or should know when I used it.
Here. I'm having my coffee.
It's already early morning, 730
and I'm here till 430.
I think. Make one more coffee.
I'm coming to get ready.
Will meet this.
Then I went there
and it was I think
I think it was Tuesday
morning or something
and on Thursday she got the information
that he
your project has changed.
You will be working a different project.
The normal part of this project.
So I don't need it.
I don't need it that this
I mean with my team members I need
if I'm asking them to come to my desk,
if I'm coming to your desk,
that is more than enough.
This is more than formal working late
then.
So I'm only going to go 17 people
right now.
Right.
17 people in 2000, 20,
I fired 79 employees,
79 calls I made to tell them that, hey,
this is the last day of your job.
You will be on notice.
You're serving for 15 this.
That is normal to one.
So despite this, and then you'll be going.
So just, you know, start
preparing for the interviews,
look for other jobs.
Right?
Sometimes it's important every time.
You can't be nice to your employees,
otherwise they make you start taking it
for granted.
You can't do it
in, not allow them to do it.
You should not actually, you are.
They're not doing the diligence.
You are there to deliver the things
according to your customer satisfaction.
The customer is the one
who is going to pay you for the job.
Right?
So that's my here.
I'm repeating proficient this.
I'm being very nice to all the people.
It is my job because I want
people be ready for the market.
But once you go into the job,
you will see this reality.
When your manager, your scrum master,
your product owner,
your even stakeholder
to be very strict, to
why would I make a bee,
why would I pay for the coffee?
There's no point.
There is no point to be the coffee.
Whenever it is, please
bring It is free In my office,
in my community, it's always free.
You can take in number of times is coffee
and the soda and milk Any time.
If you want to take it for 15 times.
29 stinking. I used to get it.
How many of you always want me to?
How many of you guys want one to?
Everyone knows it gets
one that is basically like chocolate
powder, right?
Chocolate powder.
To make your milk more tasty.
You just put it there.
It has some nutrients. Drink.
You pay for coffee. No, I didn't.
I did.
Yeah, correct. Correct.
You have got a chocolate
or the cocoa powder thing.
So what I used to do when I use Goodwill
District, I used to carry a small box
in my back having this one because milk,
I am going to get in my office.
Okay.
I go there.
I take one milk of one big glass plate.
I put my the get it for some time.
Drink, drinking, drinking
milk is, you know, healthy for you
and your studio and the top
if you're taking it for free, be
receiving it for free.
You just have to buy your
the one with the powder.
So that's what I used to do
when I was in the office.
There's work that is us.
Okay. Okay. Got it.
All right, guys. So now, now, see,
here they.
We need to get one particular employee,
and every employee is associated.
The one employee,
which is unique to a person,
which is unique to a guy, correct?
Correct. So this should return.
This is the expected functionality
from the API.
If I'm providing
what employee issued return their data
against that particular employee rate
against that particular employee.
So now now see, I don't need body,
but I need a stream that is employed.
And so from there
I can give the employee D
And you bought
from creating that employee, right?
So just go here
and this part creating an employee part
copy this work important it
markets told me this is important
something great and now
oh come on
for us to be able to end the request
so let me add a new request for get
one employee
correct get one employee in here.
I'm going to provide for
post.
I'm going to provide
this part.
Then I'm going to provide
And then then you'll see here, right here.
Bannon's I got so in
it is asking parameters
for query parameter.
It is asking for one guy is
query barometer.
Can you see everyone?
Students
query better with the rate.
So just tell me in this query perimeter
key and value it is asking.
So this key and value is what?
What is key
and what is benefiting from here?
And do I need to provide any JSON or no?
No, because it is no more disclosures
and for me it is simply a query parameter
that I need to pass.
So what is the query barometer?
The first is employ 80.
This employee 80 is the G fine.
So I'm putting it here in the key
and then then it is asking for value.
Fine.
So see, I'm
going to take this value from here.
Copy.
Now, now, if you observe one thing, my
you are going to changed
C check
it, you observe are you are least changed.
And now after this question mark
after this question mark.
I got this I.D.
I got this value, key and value
after the question mark,
what is this question one
Then also, I will explain it also.
I will explain I will explain
every single thing to you guys.
Now. Now this.
You are
it is fine because you want to explain.
Adding the parameters is fine.
Selecting
the method is great for you to select.
Get my by because we are going date
be created employee from the database.
We are going to get that created a break
from their database.
That's why we are using
get method with this
you are in with this key
in the new beer trade.
We don't need body,
we need to add headers.
We didn't. We need to deadhead it here.
One header we are going add. Right.
What does that header contain?
They seem a similar number
when simply do so.
Now see that is dead
We what is header weird
exactly
when I am here in my previous days.
Till the time you get your job offer,
I will be with you.
I told you this so. Don't do it in media.
Which had to be a big
student
content. But
application slash just separate.
Right.
Another thing we have to add.
What is that?
I told you from now onwards the operation
we are going to perform.
We will perform
all those operation using token.
So how do I do?
Good.
Come on, students, how do I token going
to authorization part from here?
Be able to select
beer token
and here I am to provide my token.
So the token available here on the site
is to complete
this token is to copy this token
go here and then simply pasted
simply this to
so far any question
so far so what everyone
nice.
Let's send this information
now. See, guys, we got the data.
We got the data usually on
we only spent and we just not body.
Yes not usually every time every time
engagement there
we only use parameters not body.
And there is a reason behind this
because while fetching the mission,
retrieving the information
from their database,
we have been what information I need
so which information I need need
permission of one particular employee.
Right.
So I need to provide this query barometer
because this is my query,
but I don't want to add a recorded.
The data is expected.
We need 48 now use the information we got.
But at the same time,
when we got the information is for Kisha
Nel, Cuba, who is this duty?
And we honestly
who created this employment
assignment.
Why do we need content types then?
We don't need a one
then it is a restricted this.
I'm putting it right.
So if you don't want to use it,
don't use it.
And is the culprit
This guilty is the shortfall of your deep.
I know who did this
Amazing.
Maybe for hot
couple
nights. No.
Then is
Simon. Bye.
Fine. So now see?
Now see here. Here.
There's what I'm saying.
That's what I'm saying.
See, it is returning me.
The employee against the employer lady
laid against the employee.
It is returning with this part.
Correct.
So it's supposed to become what a nice
innovation. Green.
Great.
The logic make.
And then you provide this algorithm.
Excellent.
Now, see, Isaiah, right.
If you test
if you test only street as good
case, understand this point.
When you are getting the information
from the database,
what is the API status code you need?
What students code you need to test?
No, no, no.
Getting the information me 200.
Right.
So now according to the status code
that you are getting
from the database
against this particular employee,
based on the status code,
your application is working
fine or not.
But actually if you go and deep
dive to the body there, you realize
that your application is reflecting
not providing the data, but database.
But data is not the one you are looking
for, right?
But data is not the one
you're looking for.
Now let me try to get another data
employed.
You provide it
and what it employed someone changed,
I think not sure.
Can we get some of that employee?
The point that we're trying to do this
was 260508.
So now regarding Zeta Mick Jagger, right
men singer,
super costar of This Must be Dennis.
We employ 80
introduced with other than employ
80 are Jimmy.
It depends on this particular part
your swagger not doing
great it depends on this document.
We got this mandatory parameter
from the swagger document.
Right?
So if it is available in swagger document,
then we have to follow one document.
That is Vega.
That's
why we are using yet employed. Great.
So we are not doing anything
from our side.
Everything we are doing
based the swagger document,
the information, the instructions
we got, inspector documents.
We're doing all of these things.
All right, All right,
fine.
So now, now, after this.
After this.
When we created the employee,
when we the information here
right now, what we have to do
know what we have to do right?
That means what we have to do first thing.
First thing, when we are working
with this type of application,
we got one employee.
That's why we provide equity barometer.
Now, tell me one thing.
If I want to get the information
for all the employees
available in their database,
do I need for the benefit of
why, why we don't need query benefit?
And in that case
generating
because it just brings everything we need.
We are calling we complete table right?
Are calling the complete employee.
So if we are calling
the complete end point,
definitely
we don't need that due to right.
We don't need the detail at all. Fine.
Now let's further.
So the next thing is next thing
we are going to perform is to go
get date
on employee's
good.
All employers is like this.
So now tell me for
getting all the employees which matter.
We need to use.
You will see when one movie
in the Bollywood movie three idiots
there is a movie.
Good All is a dumb is there?
All is with great every time
many of the all is well it gigs.
I got to the point here so see
now here this request
you are this request you want and we need
all the information, right?
All the information we need.
That information should be taken
from one document called
We should get this information
from swagger document.
Correct?
Correct.
So now, see, to get all the employees,
I have to go here
to get the employees.
I have to go here.
I have to take this particular end
point from here.
I can get the information.
Now, you'll see in
I'm with this embedded meters.
If you see here,
it will see one employee A
that I need market in this parameters
it is see
I don't need any better.
There's a difference.
There is no barometers required point.
So for us, let's take this base.
You are you from
Let's take this base.
You are right from here.
Edit Next thing we need guys is
is this
particular You are aligning
this particular you are aligning.
So I would put this you are in
I will put this.
You are in here
Now tell me what else I need.
Simple,
simple content trade
in me is do we need anybody
this is not the
vineyard authorization, right?
So authorization we put SBA token rate,
we put as beta token,
correct?
Correct. Being a token we need fine.
So now the better token
we already have where we have
we generated this token here, right?
We generated this token here.
So let me copy this particular token and,
and let me base teach.
So I'm going to based this token
I'm going to based on this token, see,
I've bested
now what else I need.
So notion
that everything is available
now, I need to have the information
on what I need in the response.
Note We need key and value of good.
That's the main point, right?
We don't need parameters, right?
You see, I you if I'm looking here
it says no parameters on correct.
So if it sees no parameters,
what does it mean?
No value.
We have to provide why we need parameters
in the previous one
because there was via specifying
one particular information
from the group of information.
Right now here
we are going to target the complete group.
So we are not going to specify
any particular information.
We need all the information
categories.
We need all the information here.
That's
why you are not providing this part.
So now, after adding this part
authorization, ending every single
simply click think.
Still, we are
performing the retrieve Operation
data retrieval.
So again,
I will get the status quo to double zero.
So now you'll see
all the low, more than 80.
We get the information.
So how many employees we have to tell
who created this one?
By the way,
who created this blunder?
Then, as I need the list,
I need the list of all these culprits.
By Monday.
So let it before Tuesday class.
I'll make sure
I do justice to all of the main
a Lucia
mystery.
My title origin came out in the market.
When I do great.
No see all this 103 employees,
we get great.
We got all this 103 employees.
Correct.
You guys see all information available
If it means
we got the complete information right,
We got the complete information here.
Understood.
Industrial of this case.
Fine.
So getting one employee, getting multiple
employees,
both on same nature, one is retrieving
one information, one is retrieving
complete information.
Understood this point.
Retrieving lemon submission, retrieving
complete information.
Right.
This is the only difference. Correct.
But status code is C
and the specified information
is the credit parameter
which we provide in our request
when it comes to specify
one particular location, one
particular of information I want to check.
Sure. Alert in New Jersey
for small
and don't know. Just
please take care, Alex.
Please take care.
Fine.
Same.
I don't have any alerting.
No, no, no.
See, guys, we are done with this.
Five requests so far.
Can you see everyone?
Now we need to convenience
stores from here every other day.
It's a normal thing for us.
Nice, Nice.
Boston beauteous lady you are.
We have a break then, is it?
What do your time rate
with the wrapping of the class anyways?
Rates are going to be a break.
That's what I told you to do
in a half hour continuous class
so that we can cover their timings
and we can see this happen.
A little break.
This happened our break rate.
What we take generally between what is
for 20 minutes when it's over 80 minutes.
So that 30 minutes break rate,
we get over it taking industrial
no break right now
rate cutting
because there is a power of rate
that is a power warranty.
Eight hour time, 2030 rate that's why.
So it will be like one our leaders point
I'm saving that one hour
so I'm taking any break rate
so it will be like to
do not do 3 hours power off in India
not in India basically get it just
place when I'm leaving or because this
you know of BP the DC generator
other transformer basically
their transformer store
not been a year and what amazing idea
I talked to the prime minister
tomorrow morning
you must be sleeping notes to India
so I like the
transformer got busted in the afternoon
break so we've got massive
power thing and currently
Jersey but I know
our prime minister is great e-books
24 seven grid
65 this
so basically
they are using the alternative line
but in the night they went to work on it.
So that line will also be
will also be will not be available.
That's why
I'll replace let's cross out for
now. Currently
and no
I know there
are no it will be back in 3 hours.
Yeah Alex I know
and I know
who has written this pontificate.
Imagine that you can achieve an book
every day
in which article there was book
fight.
So now CEOs get part
post what it means creating an information
in their and retrieving
the information from their database
from the stateless application.
Clear far or not.
Is it clear to everyone
right.
That's nice.
No. Now, here I'm going to show you
just a glimpse.
If you're working with
is full application or right.
guys.
In our case, we got the results.
It is incorrect.
Yes, is I will tell you right
how to put verification, assertions,
validations, everything you need to do.
Check every single.
Right now we're focusing on EPA responses.
Right? So it's working.
If you are working with a stateful
application,
stateful applications have tokens on one
is paired with application,
doesn't have tokens.
Then we have to rely on what?
So instead of what we do, we provide one.
We provide credentials, right?
We provide credentials
simply username and password.
So if you are working
with your stateful application
but you have to rely on username
and password, that is the credentials.
So what do you have to do there
you go into the authorization, right?
You're going to the authorization
you select.
The value from this
dropdown is basic authorization.
What you select
goes from here.
Basic authorization, right?
So from this basic authorization
you have to enter your username
and password here, right?
Once you enter your username and password,
then you click on it.
It will work.
Alright, again this using this username
and password is spot, which is an impulse.
What do you have to put you?
Admin username and password? Right.
Create user username and password
that when you have to put here.
All right. This
what does this what again not remember
we have discussed about instead of full
and instead less application.
Right?
So it is stateless application.
We are dealing with tokens.
These are JSON tokens.
We are dealing with this tokens.
Right.
However,
if we talk about a stateful application,
then we should not rely on tokens
because we do not understand the tokens.
Writing is stateful application.
So we had what? Roberta
Who is this?
Someone cool?
Name one.
They did last name also Main.
Yeah, he must be.
When they die nobody will be back.
And job title is Loser.
Oh, we're remote.
Which is as soon as people
when you have to deal with token
disease is stateless.
When you have to deal with username
and password, this is a stateful.
All right.
So in your swagger document,
if you see any endpoint
that requires you to provide,
that requires you to generate that token
within a fraction of a moment,
you will understand this is
the this is stateless application.
And in your struggle document,
if you see there is no point
for generating the token that
you have to provide username and password
for basic authorization log in there
you will understand within a fraction
of a moment the application.
You are going to work,
you are going to test the API. It.
This application is having
the nature that is strictly
understood.
Fine.
So now, now here.
This is how we deal with basic username
and password.
Correct? Correct.
It's cutting.
So now if
if you work see here, here
if you work with this part, if I provide
see the moment it is giving me
it mean Johnny nor William admin.
What it is
is it's not from where this data is
coming, right.
This data is coming from where did me
exactly
Exactly.
This data is coming from keys.
So now the next topic,
which we are going to
learn is
we are going to learn things.
Cookie's not the one.
We eat it in the breakfast.
It is cookies, ethnic items.
Yeah, get shader and that makes us memory.
The temporary memory cookies are same
rate is correct.
I knew a lot of cookies on the we
can so guys to me.
Any idea about what cookies are.
Yeah and ones that were dinged
for the same rate
so now I see
let me give you a first example
nowadays of nowadays if you see you go
and you search for something
in your browser, right.
For example, you open your code doesn't
and you search for the Nike shoes,
You search for Nike shoes.
Where we deal with the stateful is good.
Full application.
I showed all your aid
in your authorization,
so instead of selecting tokens
from the dropdown, you select
the basic one and then you provide
username and password.
So that's how we deal
with this particular part.
Understood.
Understood. This
file.
So now,
now when we talk about the cookies, right.
So remember you go and you search
something on your chrome
browser, your shoes, right?
You want just one or two shoes
and suddenly you have
you go to work or
to do you close your browser,
you you just wind down
next time fuel on your Facebook
or you open YouTube.
You see advertisement about this
Nike shoes
and, you know, shoes
have and even observe this.
So any one more question
Do we have to choose which method to use
or which industry to continue? We
we have to
we have to see
first nature of application,
nature of application, right.
And yet
that is a part of the air and air.
And then you don't want to wait
for the console.
So here, here, here
you see, you know, that's what I'm saying.
So we always exempt cookies, right?
We accept cookies.
So then while accepting the cookies,
we are ready to share this information.
We are giving their consent
that okay, we are okay
if you share information, right?
That's what we do, guys.
That's what we do or not.
Sometimes it doesn't even ask.
Right? So what? What is happening here?
What is happening? How the system knows
that we should
give you this type of suggestions.
You're looking for issues
How how system knows it.
There should be a special algorithm first.
First algorithm works on data.
Algorithm works on work.
If there is no data,
algorithm doesn't work out.
Correct. So algorithm works on data.
So the data is coming from where
in technical language
cookies are simply
is small blocks of data.
What are cookies?
These are small blocks of data
created by a website
that are were created by web server.
When you try to browse something in a
particular website or some deep drive.
So this block of data on your computers
or on the other device
which you are using by a web browser,
it stores that information,
it stores that information.
And as to this point,
Jimmy, please correct me
if I'm wrong.
These cookies are small block of data,
small block of data
created by a web server.
What is your web server?
Your web browser, Right.
It is connecting you to so many things.
Correct. So that is your web server.
So this cookies are available
in your browser.
You see if you are getting your username
and password
in Chrome browser,
trying to open it from the edge browser.
It will ask you again
to provide username password.
Why is that so?
Because you see it in chrome.
You didn't see it in edge, right?
So different web server rate available
on your application's browser part.
When you are actually interacting with
so many applications you are searching.
So we need permission.
The database from the global web page
understood
this part first.
So what cookies does, whatever the
information you have, it's towards that
you're searching history, browsing,
history, likes, dislikes,
every single thing available
in this cookies, in this cookies.
Is this, is this clear?
So the point is.
But Hunt, is this clear?
No, but so now the point is
why these cookies are storing
all of this information,
why these cookies are supporting
all of this information?
A lot of reasons,
a lot of reasons behind this.
See, first reason
The very first reason is
you don't need to log in again.
You don't need to log in again.
Correct? Correct.
It consumes your information.
You need to log in again and again.
Tell me
and will, you don't need to log in again.
Second thing,
they can transfer their data.
They can transfer their data
transfer your history and they can use it.
They can use it for
advertisement.
But it was
great.
It transfers their data collected
also can supposedly information
or utilize it information
for advertisement purpose.
Right.
So now now algorithms come into the
what algorithms do year
algorithms takes your data, right?
Read your history, choose shows choose.
All right. It goes into the database.
See all the details of the issues, grab
this information,
show it on to the web server.
It shows every information
where the ads enable the.
Now you see all the requirements of
this stored
industrial this
how things work
students is this clear?
How things work in the cookies
based on any questions.
So one read
no questions like Zima
good exit
exam that goes towards the non
normal owners
good cookies are already storing your data
algorithms is baking the data
from the cookies right
separating you, bringing down
to several pieces understanding.
What is your search history Choose
then goes into the database,
grab all the names on the issues,
put it in your browser.
You see that data.
So algorithm simply filtering
your browsing history from the cookies.
Their data this algorithm got from great
and then providing
you the agreed basement rate
read.
So now here, here you see
if you are searching a lot of information,
a lot of information right
there is everything available
in the cookies, correct?
Everything available in the cookies book.
But you get the details.
You get this advertisement
to get this information,
not for all the information
you search for,
you searched for,
but for only a specific
point of information
such as product, groceries, cards, rate,
or some videos or some movies
or some accounts like this kind of things,
which is business related,
Which is business related.
Okay, What is getting my point,
which is business had for example,
if you go and check, how do you generate
as a how get my assistant number
next time
it will not give you rate to generate
it is just a number agency name
or many things
because this is something else.
This is not their business right.
But if we search for watches, eyeglasses,
specs, shirts, shoes, right.
Any other thing.
And definitely
it'll give you a lot of suggestions.
It's a So now I understand how important
these cookies are in more than one
That is another type of cookie called
third party cookies.
Third party cookies. What does it mean?
What?
YOHANAN Yeah, that that's what I'm going
that's what I'm coming to.
The point we are telling to third
party is cookies.
What is this, cookies,
third party cookies.
So basically,
basically what it does is simply, simply
this third party cookies, stores data.
But since this data, other companies
ship our data to other companies.
Okay. Wow.
So we go on this one
third is two things I need to work on.
First is also large window for Alexa,
and the second
is to declare the cookies illegal for you.
So on Monday
we will work on these two points.
Definitely.
It is all about advertisement, not equal.
It is all about business hub,
liquidity Hub.
Right.
So you see what third party cookies does.
Party cookies is basically an agreement
to two companies, right?
One company
says, right, definitely do this.
So one company says
we will collect some data for the users
and we will send this to table.
You get the privileges.
Another company says point,
give this data me in the billions
we will use of my own some prediction
algorithms, but it is linked.
Fine.
So that company says, all right,
you use your prediction algorithms and,
then we will show your data.
But the application point,
there's billions of dollars.
Who is giving who is giving the data?
One company where this data is collecting
from, from us,
we are accepting the cookies
the moment we exist in 20 hours.
Is it legal? It is legal.
It is legal.
It doesn't even there's
there's the meat problem.
You know why this can risk committee
rate of gold.
This guy, Mark Zuckerberg, there they ask
why you are playing with the privacy.
Remember
this monitor carbon has been called there.
They were asking that question next.
That's the main reason.
And without confirm,
you can't connect to your single right.
So now you'll see when it comes
to third parties, cookies, rain,
how things are working.
Let give you the best example.
This is the most used a search
engine nowadays.
Google on this planet.
On this planet. Great.
When you search anything in Google raid,
it makes the collection of the worse.
And today we have got this much searched
for this particular part right?
So for one particular part,
we got this much search, most used search.
It was data collection,
data engineering, data scraps,
trade data, predicting data.
In years of working here,
they are collecting the data.
So every minute, every day,
every month, every year, every end,
they're going to be collecting their data
from search engine, from Google Maps,
from Gmail accounts, from YouTube,
from all the places, from Google.
And I
we put all the things in there.
Great, great.
This is your density,
but Google can see your data and Google
see it obviously great YouTube,
your searching history, browsing history,
your every single thing what what you are
buying your seat on Google browser.
Everything is available
to Google right now.
Right.
So now you see all of these things.
They enable this part.
Great.
So now here you see they put microphone
right in the Google so they
they can voice your record as well.
They can record your voice is running.
So they have your voice.
The moment you put fingerprint,
they collect fingerprint
gunning, they collect your fingerprint,
they collect your voice, they've collected
all your browsing history.
They have your name,
they have your location,
they have every single thing about you.
Now, tell me
your data is being already shared
and you have been sharing
your data, have been sharing their data
with Google every single moment on
every single moment.
You're sharing your data with them,
correct them everything.
That's why Google Map GO provides.
Google provides
the API that created the API.
Explain to all over the world if you want
maps of
Google how many houses their streets,
their people, their locality,
their every single company.
First of all, to create the map made
to create an application like Google Map.
What you have to do,
you have to put a satellite in the space.
Then you have to collect the data
for all this space
that you have to into the data
and you have to make an application.
Then you have to send it, isn't it?
And then the obligation really
in the very time digging deep.
Right.
So what they generally do
is to simply create application.
They hire base from Google for Google,
they integrate their API
with the application.
Now they have all the flexibility,
all the president is from the Google.
So Google is building
this kind of space to work.
Google is selling this API
to this application,
to all the application
to all the companies now
millions of companies
are creating the application.
They are purchasing this API.
And the best part is
it's not a one time deal.
And then giving this APIs
to other companies.
What Google says you come, you want to use
how many times my API one hit
wants one click, so extend one click point
one $0 on me tens or maybe five.
Think.
Let's see, I have three for one click in
one application is average.
It's average there.
This application
make a hundred calls every day.
100 likes every day for one means $5,
one application, one
day making $5 to Google.
Just consider this.
Let's take a was case 1 million.
eBay's sold one day five for nothing.
This is the business
for Google, for nothing.
This is just one part.
And this is the worst case,
even if you're doing nothing, nothing.
Still, they're making like millions
on it is happening
because of cashew, because of cookies,
industrial, despite
everyone.
Exactly.
Most of including.
That's the problem we all have.
We are shedding their data every day
but still complaining.
Don't share my information.
No one going to share the information.
You've already
share your information with everyone
right?
Right.
Based
any questions?
Okay. So far, global. You seem silent.
What happened?
If I use them
in a once?
You're not among us to get a job.
Let it be first. To get a job.
Anything can work.
All these things.
All right, Lucas.
Sorry to disturb you.
So I find this so I think.
Great. We have covered enough information.
I know it has been two and a half hours
without a break, and I would say to
you guys,
learning is also extracted here, right?
So we have covered
half an hour right from the Briggs
because we didn't do any break or they 20
minutes and 10 minutes pretty great.
We didn't make it.
So I think we have enough
if you have any questions you can ask
or maybe can have a bit class, no
split screen points.
I know that you know Schwinger
so saved them.
Saved them.
If you're saving right, it will work.