All right.
On the stand, Steven Hopkins
read a couple of Nelson Mandela's stories.
The great
unknowable phrase, we never peace
all of the legends seen in the glass
screen.
Let's start the commercial.
So now, starting 20 minutes,
I'm not going to beat you.
You would like me to open up a project?
This is a project you.
It's glass of selenium.
We have great.
Is this the right
particles?
Right.
Let's start from the start,
guys.
When we already have this dingy,
then why do we need to use it?
Firstly, start with the basic requirement.
It's a game of supply and demand.
Demand is there.
Then we have to use supply at a faster
rate.
We need cutting.
So the main point is
to increase,
increase
transparency or
reduce the resulting molecule ether.
This is
actually the definition of framework
you're seeing.
Empathy is a tool is of not or to reduce
to reduce communication death rate.
It is the way I am explaining rate.
Even if you see here,
even if you see here,
these details are different
than what I think.
You always find their definitions.
Even though these points are very small.
But if you use these points
in your interview, if you use these points
to explain the concept, believe me,
these are unique
points.
Unique.
You need a unique explanation.
And this is the one you're looking
for, right?
So please take care of this points.
And whenever you go to the interview,
just follow these notes.
I'm not talking about job or selling them
because I don't teach, right.
I didn't need to take part.
So what I'm teaching.
I'm just asking you
to follow this particular part of it,
to increase transparency or reduce
communication.
Get divorced.
These are
we had this problem in earlier frameworks.
That's why we came up with
the new framework to give a second thing,
because it supports
it supports we really or because
it is in language, right?
It supports the language.
So easy, easy to understand for
ethnical, it's
right
not only for technical,
but also for technical.
Another important point,
right?
Another important point.
When you lose good language,
you'll see this logging feature, right?
You know,
let me tell you one word about it.
From the kind
we use this particular scenario
as a menu in this is
we can use rate
we can use this scenario as a test case.
So now now let's say tomorrow
you become a lead rate user.
And I hope I wish that you guys
will get reported as our guest.
So, so ignite your management will ask you
to have an effective solution.
What is workaround.
So that is the workaround.
You can suggest a key in menu testing.
We will follow that language.
In working language
we will rate all the test.
Is this correct?
Now when you read all that
is because this isn't working,
which is tips are already available
in your scenarios, correct?
Everything that scenario explains
your one best case.
Understood.
In every test case,
you will be having multiple steps.
Now, when it comes to automation,
you need to read new scenario.
At this point, no.
In that time what you can do
now, just open your manual test case.
Do your best to see
who is available current.
Just copy those scenarios from there
it is due to you.
Simple linking from your testimony
is meant to be.
Your automation script is also available
whenever you create in a test because in
you always get one is ideal
not what you did with this because 80
correct Easy 101 DC 102103
something like this.
That is because I really know
you can provide in your test scenario here
right so now whatever just is
because you're executing
it is directly linked with
your test is in Gita.
Obviously it's a part of later discussion,
but again, I'm telling you
so that, you know, you can at least
visualize the things, how you can make
the things connected as a lead,
because your responsibility,
if you make this process,
this complete cycle, your entire project,
your big data company is
going to rely on you, right?
So understand
you don't get the salary based on the
what did you do?
You get the salary based on the value
you added to the project.
You get the salary based
on your significant role,
how significant you are for the project.
There are a lot of extras on the label.
No one needs a,
you know, really good test,
but if you can bring some additional value
addition to the project you're working
on, that same company is going to rely on
do things remember?
So it's more of building
a positive character, right?
The energy to get it in the industry
next would be a learning
file.
Already supports
ability building language easier
to understand for non-technical people.
Also thing to focus on any user, right?
Why? I'm saying it focuses on any user.
Remember when user clicks
on log in, written
when user knows username and password,
every given user is navigating
to a Jeremy's application.
So what is this user user user
you see available here?
Why do we have this user
using that all the next?
Because this particular language
we need to
combine is based on users, right?
It always focuses on end user perspective
things from a user perspective, right?
There's the main part of this be
the functionality understanding
based on a user as a user.
Correct.
Because of this reason,
a program should satisfy the user.
Correct.
You're making the software for a users
getting customers.
The customers are not happy that say we do
have you existing
user acceptance this right as a user.
Right? We work as a user, we
operate the application, we use
the application.
Is that the end user?
And then we believe outputs or sometimes
what happens.
A company provides
multiple people trained from the industry
or from X-Y-Z location
and deployed access to the application
before deploying it
right into the market before go,
and they provide it to
then ask them to provide the feedback.
Just use this application.
If you're lucky enough one day,
maybe you know Amazon will buy you
and then they will give you like $500
or $1,000 just to check that application.
User application is a user.
It also happens, for instance, basically
all rate focuses on user
so as to why do we need to use we, But
everyone
nice right now
forget about framework, forget about
we are just underspending on particular
what is it framework it's on me.
I will take care of the entire framework.
I will explain you.
Every single piece of business
was are distinct.
It does include the way we understood
best into as a tool.
Now I'm explaining it.
It is a right because students
would be confused in between framework
and consumers one by one.
And picking first to begin
and then framework plain things.
No, no.
When I say that I'm going to write my best
guess this grade is in use.
So what is the least in automation
using do.
But I have my best guess is
what is that
is what is the name of that piece.
See can your find which file is this
you the
be nice
if you're just getting to mastered.
I'd like I think some of Nelson Mandela
Nelson Mandela got in the class
feature might
be use feature by
you right are best estimates
cutting the rate our business menus.
We need beta in order to commit framework
and it can be have late
equals two menus in one picture by
you just begin to rate
the meaning of scenario is basically one
best guess you're going to define
in that particular list
gives you device in your feature.
But so now let me show you.
You'll see here, great.
Okay.
I did
not if you see here read
this scenario comes under this
particular feature getting
any now tell me
I can have multiple scenario
in which we can
I have late table feature
inside this particular part.
No right.
Because you consider this as
a big scenario is a big user story, right.
For example, log in feature.
So any log in feature
you can have the usual mean,
you can have invalid log
in, you can have admin log in,
you can have normal employee log in,
you can have is a lot of log in scenarios.
You can have current it.
Let's see the error
verification validation part.
So force time to enter correct username
wrong password.
One best guess can be said this.
This is one test case.
Aisha, this is your one best use grade.
And here this is using best scenario.
So internet.
You can only debate this cases on board
or consider it as a user story.
So in one user
you only because scenarios or not
you can have.
Right?
So now, for example, if you have well,
it was an invited password.
One scenario in when you lose an embedded
password against A
that you write in
that he was indeed the password,
the blank person that you give
the username will blank.
And the password for cementing
all these scenarios are related
to login functionality or not.
Yes, they contain.
The title of this menu is
when you can change,
it's up to your competition and therefore
everything is completely up to you based.
Okay, so now remember, whenever
we talk about this feature by date,
whenever you work in the industry,
the users to you get read
this feature file
would be the name of getting user story
and then all the best uses.
The spin that news you would be having.
This will be the part of your one
particular feature by,
for example, if you see here
that on my notes I explained to you
this particular two points
like this particular two points getting.
So my user story was a me should be able
to search and employ
in a job in this application
right?
Based on me.
It is correct or not.
Okay.
Now now you see here
when admin should be able
to search and employ a Jarvis application.
So there it is. Users voting.
I have acceptance criteria for two things.
It means I can search my employee
using to use my ID by a name current.
So now these two are my scenarios are not.
These two are mercenaries, correct?
Fine.
Now I need to know what this
and how to use in one feature
file on or do I need to create
multiple features for this?
No, I don't need to write
just one feature.
It would be enough for me.
Correct. For
so long feature image
and really right to test
iterate this to use in feature fighting.
Can we look at image translation with that
and just in the
it is a part of eight months,
but we will learn their story.
I mean I'm a transition participant
based on Kubuntu
where based on minimal translation,
based on external every single thing.
A lot of things are coming
out right now.
We are going to talk about a couple
of other keywords into that space.
So remember whenever we write scenarios,
whenever we write scenarios
in the scenarios, that is a particular
format we generally follow for
follow one particular following
that forward is occupied
by one thing that is keywords, right?
So in these keywords I have to write
particular part one example
if I am using given keyword.
So what is the meaning of given keyword?
It simply means I have to write
precondition, precondition
with given keyword.
Similarly, if I am writing when keyword
what I have to use,
when keywords, is there a way particular
to automatically
make a jump from other keywords
We are we are creating
or the code for the assignment, correct?
For instance, definition.
I'm coming to that point.
I'm coming to the end point, right?
No double bind the country but the code
we need to consider in one night,
which it is okay, we can rate
we can rate what example if you see here
in my log in I provide when I use a valid
the username and password.
Right.
So the way we are performing
admin username and password
which actions we are providing correct
also rate I will rate when we proceed.
Go to the we will perform
username password it click on log
in better everything in just for one.
So if we have read the feature,
why we have to copy the good.
Everything okay?
Why do of the feature by
If you are changing to this training
this particular step, then yes.
Then yes.
What do you have to do?
The steps
which is going to generate that step
you have to replace
and you can keep your code inside.
It's time.
I will tell you how things work in the
This could be a part of everyday you that
file.
So now when to perform actions
actions
that is another keyword causing why
we use database
Bob Aisha
basically right
we were told to never do that.
For example if there is a jumbos
in any of you ever been an integer?
There are 15, 20, 25 steps are available
in every steps
you have to perform the collections rate.
For example,
you will get a couple of times.
So this to many of your really quite late
people puts in one
weight multiple bootstraps of video people
from political collections, correct.
So even if it is not recommended
but it is very glad when some things
that you have been make
okay and this is the see guys
that is
a bit can be used with all the steps
to aid
normal editing this video question.
So basically the point we talk
you'll give my what you're
looking for a simple word supporting actor
supporting day simple
right
that can be associated with any other leg.
Right.
So what I'm saying
basically is of the actual definition
read the actual definition
is something else that is nothing
gold ideal in the industry.
Keep this point in your mind
that is nothing.
Or it's always because
late in when things are practical means
you can always customize the things
according to your requirement.
So be a professional right?
Be an experienced in public,
an experienced person.
You example would use that
you put into the home.
We will try to push for the example
you gentlemen, I'm going to write.
I'm going to accidentally deposit ideas
in one bite and you're not in.
And when do you write this?
Before starting the employee training.
So it is almost a
you know, the most data wants to work
there will get you a lot of things
more quickly
right now
when we you then you would
in simple it's correct
so then that's the main reason
why I always focus
and give more distress
towards the practical explanation
because you guys did work or some of you
lazy many work in the industry.
Great words need to understand one thing
what we learn and what we implement.
These two are different things.
How many of you guys will keep
proficiency?
I'm not talking about writing district
in any industry.
How many of you guys are working
professionals?
Women working menial?
Majority of you guys?
Correct.
It doesn't matter
which food you are working in. Right.
Or responsibility or dealing with
any one thing from your own experiences.
As I've been working in the industry
for from last five, six, seven or we would
use based on you actually implement
those voguish definition of what this
then is
do you follow all the
ethics of professionalism when you have to
appreciate or when you have the motivators
by your teammates
or your peers? No.
Right.
Sometimes you have to go out of the works
of majority of times you have to think,
okay, from your experience
and many of problems is made matters.
This professionalism and ethics.
I'm not against this professionalism
and ethics, but this bookish definition.
We can't
we don't rely on this part correct.
So remember, similarly,
when you work in industry,
if you completely I learned
how to write reports professionally.
Great.
Nice. Congratulations on that.
And send one certificate to your you
the report grade certified report
generate the most.
All right so
remember think
whenever it comes to explain or print
this kind of things on
with as long as it works correct
got it right always extremely professional
and professional
people never explain location information.
Keep this thing in your case.
We are professionals.
We never will explain bookish definition.
Yes, the negotiation is revisions
and it is then it is more good this move.
That one.
We will explain.
But then what is the difference?
How you integrate your experience
with your explanation?
That creates a difference.
That's what I'm here to teach you.
Understood.
So far, things are going pretty easy.
So far things are going slow based.
All right, now tell me if I'm writing
only this particular feature.
By the way, I promote this, particularly
typically if I want to execute
only with this feature,
but can I give my code
non first?
You didn't get my question.
Only the feature I'm embedding
here and it's not straight mythical people
giving a quick information slide.
I'm giving you detail information. Right.
We need to implement
definition.
We need step definition.
Remember the concept of interest
declaration and definition.
The on not
so what is declaration just skeleton?
Nobody.
What is definition?
When you provide body right.
So here
when you write this actual scenario
this is just to hallucinate
you're you're just declaring the steps.
You're not actually implementing trade.
So now let me show you one thing.
Let me just intentionally
create a new stipulate.
You can intentionally create a new script.
So let's say I'm going to create over
the distinct only given
the user is what is
intentionally emulating this.
Okay taking it.
I think
now Siegfried
Whitefield it is a step undefined
you can implement them
we missing steps right with this
to do what is giving the code
also to implement step
it is telling you which is undefined
see it says
now missing implementation
right now that we copied is a step here.
I'm going to show you a couple
of information which is very important.
Let me go in my log in two steps.
Right and hit me.
Copy this.
I'm going to delete it anyway.
So see now,
now, if I go here, right is gone.
It's not related anymore.
Like I told you that Me If I want to check
the implementation of this,
I can get it deleted from here.
But what?
How we can.
How can I check right click on the step
go to
and there is a declaration plate
when you click on this declaration.
See, my gazette is coming here.
Public void user underscore is underscore
x lazy.
Let me do one more nine days
in case if you missed it.
When I click here, go to
a declaration read in declaration.
So when they go into their declaration
right here you see
it's coming here user underscore
is underscore lazy bugged
but if you see on log in that end user
underscore is underscore x, y, z.
No, no.
But here it is
taking me to this particular path.
It means more.
Is this step
linked to the Western scenario?
Or this could link to domestic edu
dysfunction link to in edu
or this is linked to my selecting
this particular method.
The function
which I have written over here.
It is linked to myosin manual.
So what does it mean?
It simply means when you write here
anything, it is different in the consumer.
When you write any state in the consumer
leads,
it's a Java code.
It is generating what is Java code?
Now, if you come here and if you
observe it closely, tell me a public void.
What is this?
Public means access, modify it,
void means non written bait method.
User underscore is the notice code.
X-Y-Z Z is method name
and this is open clause method signature
Curly braces block of code
where you're going to write
whatever the actions you want to perform
from this particular method.
Is this Java or not? The
So now answer to your question.
Right let's put in was asking the question
maybe
I'm not sure the name
I didn't write
it was asking it to create a Java place.
So sorry we cannot create a java
by using cucumber, but the code
which we need to write it out
in Java place that we can go to.
So that would be clear.
You think
if you have the steps in one scenario,
you simply click on it, generate
all the data steps
that you can cross,
Correct?
That it takes.
Can you see now, see
what kind of explanation of explanation
it is giving the information
provided by us.
It sees right code here, very helpful.
We can write code here that turns
the phrase above into concrete actions.
The phrase about which phrase
this is the phrase.
So it means this particular part
is linked
to this particular part, correct?
That's why it is being read code here
that does the above freeze
into concrete actions.
Now we have to perform the actions, right?
Whatever the brands we are explaining,
it is all of these.
We have to give the definition.
So to provide the emission in Java,
we need a function.
We need method
just because we need the method, it
creates the method,
it gives us this method.
And when we already have this
method, this is the time to write the code
so that we can actually perform
the actions.
What we're actually
just defining in our feature
is it clear
is students
minds now?
P And also if you see for this exception,
right, if this exception from particular
audio could convert Java bending
exception, nobody is available next.
Next is finding exception
read.
Just give me this just give me.
All right.
You're so tired already.
It's only morning Saturday morning on
then you're already tired.
All right, fine.
So now here.
Here.
Any kind of code we can implement, right?
Yet the window. Agreed.
And I appreciate it. I respect suspended.
So now, here, you see, I'm going to write.
Simple. Could see.
Hello, file.
Now I provided the body.
Doesn't matter
what kind of code I'm going to provide
right.
Nasty is what I'm explaining here.
This code I have written correct?
Correct.
But in actual my log in
feature,
you'll see it comes on the first place.
It comes on the first place.
And in my log in step, it is coming on
the last step of the last implementation.
Will it work?
Experience.
Good.
To my question, I am defining it here.
Write it first place.
But actually implement it last place.
Would it work
a little?
Said no and I say yes.
So it wants to use it should?
I think so.
Now. Now why explain the linking portion
now? See?
But even code will always have a priority.
Oh, then it's not about the priority.
Let me believe you.
Kimber works on implementation
just because you have to contribute.
It says that removal clearances, removal
clearances
before this, given bed removal clearances
where you see the right amount
does move that clearances
because you already have this calibrates
in the end of the
this part or a menu
that is successfully loaded.
You already know when this and you put
in the extra one, you just remove this.
Now negates the concept of implementation.
When you right click here
go to declaration or usage.
So when I go on declaration,
it is stating within this particular part
it means all order doesn't matter
implementation make this.
If at this point ending the definition
in the feature fine, it will get executed.
Now order
Date of execution defines from here.
It defines from here.
So it doesn't matter
which place in which class like implement.
Take the body of this method.
As long as the method body is available,
it will execute understood to,
but will definitely execute.
So order of definition be based on
the person implementation of the method,
not based on the position
where we actually defined this part
already
understood this point.
Everyone
declaration usage is not available, but
if we are not actually
clicking on any citizen, click
on this particular part.
See the way
I'm clicking here right on this
and then I perform right click
and then declaration.
You will see your clicking
this exquisite place.
There's the problem
or requirements.
So what I'm saying is it depends. Great.
The execution need to be based
on the implementation of step.
If you're implementing the step,
as long as the step
definition is available in your project,
your is executed like a Kimber.
It's not depending on the position
where you are actually defining your.
If I'm defining this given step
at the last place, in most of definition,
big doesn't matter.
As long as I am providing this,
The definition that I provided here
in the last place,
it will definitely work.
And as to so the execution,
depending on the method, the body,
the implementation of the step,
not on the execution and not on the order
or the position of state,
when we placed it.
Yes, Correct.
These methods are independent
of this method.
Similarly,
this method is independent of this method.
Correct.
It's only the order we are defining here.
This is the only order we are defining.
You understood
us to not
get. No, let me be rigid.
Let me be clear.
I don't need this method.
It was just for the explanation I created.
So I'm going to delete it.
Guys, before deleting.
I'm telling you, I'm
going to delete this particular part.
This is step because we don't need it.
We implemented it just to show you.
Okay, we deleted from here
and let me take it from here
is from from both places in my step.
Two steps also in from my log in feature.
Also.
So I told you to remove
this from the above portion
you remove from the normal portion. See?
Let me do it for you here.
After this then you have
another curly process to put it like this.
You have one more curly braces
here, remove this braces, not this one.
Otherwise you will get the other.
There's the issue you have.
Please check the code word you guys
are doing and how you are writing.
It's clearly showing that
you have a problem with your can leave.
This is Please do it now.
I imagine initial file
cutting
scenario can be different sequence.
I'm not sure why
it doesn't need to be proposed straight.
The support. Don't worry about it.
Just do proper just because you know
it is a very silly mistake.
I can remove it here in the classics
and normally I will handle this things
instead of making some small mistakes.
And you don't need to be worried about it
when things are out of control.
Then on the other side it the way
they can handle this because always.
All right, there is no
All right, let me rephrase it.
Otherwise I will handle these geniuses
here will point the one.
All right.
Let me clear.
Let me create another picture by right.
They could create another feature
fail here in time.
We've been the name of this feature Employ
Search Dart Features
Database Employee Search Dart features.
Okay.
And why?
I'm going to write an employee search.
If you see in my notes
I identified scenario as the user story.
One, two, three, four, five.
Then I have those in any
and everyone see this.
Now let's write a scenario here.
So I'm going to write feature
find LLC users
20 123456 is definitely employee
and here I'm with direct scenario
so search
the search employ by I
first I'm going to search employee by I.T.
All right
so let's create one scenario point
given
user is
navigated to
it is application
the job premise sweepstakes application
course owns me.
Follow you as well, sir.
Not the one number
you don't need to follow.
We already
hurry then I'm writing here
first,
then me for starting the employee
by adding.
Great.
I was expecting actually this point
from you for searching the employee first.
What I have to do
long.
Do we have any method for logging?
Yes, we do have.
Well, is the method that you.
Can I take all this bullet points
from you?
Promote me.
So let me copy
this. Policy steps from here
and simply is to give
categories.
This is what we call called reusability.
Next time, if you are going to create
a new scenario, just for the points
you and your scenario is done,
Isn't it easy, guys?
You don't need to write anything
in this table again and again and again.
Getting
Yes, yes, yes.
Correct. Kick
Ember is all about copy copying
right now after then.
Right.
Nobody paid this page
but then was not completed.
I have to wait when user
maybe gets to
employ in this speech.
Let me show you this.
We open on application first
more than
27.3.
Can you see this?
First, what I have to do if I am on
dashboard page, create by default,
it should take me to this particular page
coming from this beach.
I have to go on bin
and then I have to click on employee list.
Correct? That's correct.
First employee bin and then employee list
and then only I will see
my employee is too big
for me.
So I have written over here.
You see,
when user name begins to employee
list page,
I will make these steps create
also and here I'm going to write
with the user
enters
appended android I.D.
and end user takes on
virtual button
and you see
raw information is
is displayed.
Is this correct?
Is this the correct scenario or not
correct scenario.
Fine.
So now first let me create
steps for all these highlighted systems
and then I will keep
all of these steps in an employee.
Such is steps plus again,
it's created
so far.
Any question
anyone has any questions for you.
So I think is we're going to head within
those body gates.
Before the break.
We can we go in and then one more thing.
It's my humble request to use this code
and see a lot of people
I have been applying to this on the issue.
I've seen their machines.
They're doing it my code, even for us.
And believe me,
the quality of code is good.
You actually included this
one. It
added running
scenarios was not employed in my eighties.
Why is this so?
I need to check this.
Should we also mention how to navigate
employee list page
one user name? Yes.
Shouldn't contain big M.
I didn't implement the code like I said.
Great.
So when I say user name,
we gets to employee speech inside
that particular step, we implement
the code for clicking on emotion,
clicking
one employee list option following.
After you create this new you would
you have another log in steps like
yes Jimmy.
Yes. Yes.
I that
we will create we will clean.
Okay so now we execute this menu first
I it is completely fine.
It is completely fine.
Delicious.
Now you see here
it is giving me all this step straight,
which I am missing.
Can you see create
navigates to employees to page index?
Well it employed Click on search
button and users see
employee information is displayed
is it search the meters road package
solve one Yes everything you
so you there 17 here
let me copy this right and here
let me create another Java class for
employee such race
employee statistics
create.
Now I'm going to based here all the steps
I got from this
Now one thing
one thing, one thing to show.
You see, I provided here a can you see
and a user clicks on search for complete.
I provided your ID,
but when you go in your steps,
you see it says when it is no and
you observe so far what I see.
If you see here, it gives you end.
But here
actually it implemented automatically.
Yeah I
obviously know if I'm raising the point,
this is because I'm going to explain.
Correct.
I'm not going to leave in between.
So why is it so?
Because.
No, that's completely fine.
I'm just kidding.
So now why is it so?
Because this end keyword,
like I said, we are using it
and the supporting cast
as a supporting cast.
This is not the mean keyword, right?
And it always gives
you only main keyword, correct.
If you put it with then it gives you then
if you put it with when it gives you one.
All right.
Great.
Another thing,
if you seen employee
statistics is the post
a stable speaking user name
begins employee list page
by because my username password
and everything is available here.
Great. So let me copy this.
The steps also following two steps.
First, if we completed the steps to
take me pasted here,
why does giving me the error eliminate?
Why this error? Yes.
Correct.
Because these methods are available
in my common methods
and I'm not using this
extensive keyword here
now and it is gone now.
You see navigate to a gentleman's
application.
Enter submitted admin username
and password clicks on log in button,
maybe gets to employee list page.
Fine.
So first I have to implement my good here,
but it makes
let me write that element.
And same option is equal to
take me.
Take the look at the efforts
from here for the option
to find do
now going to take
88 is a part of the attribute
a lot this is attribute this is value.
Remember color coding the purple one egg
and this one
attribute this one value.
Let's take the value from here.
So I'm going to write right.
I'm going to write Driver Dark,
find element by
door I.D.
And this is my
is this correct?
Now what I have to do,
I have to click on promotion.
So bin option don't click.
So password everyone
I'm going really slow
but it's
after clicking on this theme option.
I see I see employee list page.
First
I have to click on employee list page.
So let me find Yes, we can see that
I have to take the spirit to leave
very hard.
Now use it.
Bin Menu rate Employee list.
So let me pick this particular one
and here
I'm going to write web element.
I draw a list option is equals to
very dark
point element by dark I.D.
in here I am going to provide
and then employee list option don't click
now we implemented
it is a step or not should we navigate
to employee list page click on option
We got employee list option
Now we are on employee list page.
Correct
so far so what everyone
is that anyone who has any question
related to this particular point, no means
no next point here.
Next point I have to click on valid
employee but employee, right.
So let's see,
I have to take the locator
of this particular
peak, such
exists.
It is equal to GMB search party.
If we did again from here
there is I can create x
but also we can create see as selector.
Also since I is directly available.
So to save your time, I'm directly
taking it.
Don't ask why we are not creating
the expectancy assistant.
We can do that as well.
So I'm not the culprit.
Okay.
Web element
search my I got it right here.
So finally made by no I.D..
This is the i.t.
Now know what i have to do here.
Simple.
I have to send the data,
so search by the same keys.
And what is the id?
So I kept it somewhere in my notes.
If we check,
this is the data, so let me check
for whether it is working or not.
If I put this employee in search,
they you it is giving you the data, right?
So it is employee bank
and then simply find a duplicate search
option.
Right.
So web element,
search button in sequence
to try to find anything and I don't i. D
in case if it is available. Let me check
search why it is available
stick this I'm taking this from here
this and I'm coming to my screen
sometimes if I changing
it will ask
why are you doing this so fast?
So I'm telling you, okay, in your command
to make you there so you can go there.
Search button.
Don't click.
So first of what everyone
is that
unique want It is unique.
This is the application we have mine
shows to well, let me check
this.
The best place to check using the example
one only
where you're showing to 80.
I put the next
better.
So it is 80.
Oh guilty.
Forgot it.
You put that next.
So what based is not available?
You did this either.
You can take name value of 88
three things and then you have a good
forget about this part.
The user employee information is displayed
the verification button. Why?
Because we are going to use different type
of position in particular.
So right now our focus is
not as the shift, our focus is on the step
definition that we actually implement
because I'm going to looks as you
information
is displayed
displayed on the page
because there
we used the stingy annotations.
Remember it's been stingy.
We use just in general patients
in Katoomba,
we have separate
kind of locations that we will be using.
So that's why I'm not implementing
any annotation as of now, I'm
going to implement those annotations up
something that clear
front.
So far, so far in this code,
any confusion
connotations?
No, there is no connotations
or take this in any way already.
And some of this method and again,
these methods in new words or
in each of the last line, why not?
Sorry, this is the point.
Now let me go employ search.
See very good looking scenario.
And so I have shall we implement
and I should be executing
things
let's it
and it's going to be feed
it's speed
eliminate
by its speed.
Now let me explain just something
like many people
inheritance is not possible in duplicate.
Well and as one duplicate
and it's duplicate
we did something at all
I get the I know what we did.
I know what would be like this.
I'm explaining guys why multiple
inheritance is not possible in Java
because yep
because for example,
if you have E method in your E class
and method in your B class
in your C class is going to take
the proper deeds of from either the C.
If you are calling this method in class,
right, then Java will get confused
whether to take this method
from class E or from
class B.
Nice. Tell me. I don't know.
Is it correct or potentially
it is correct.
Now, now just keep this concept in mind
and here comes you write one.
Is it going to give one user is blah,
blah, blah.
You implemented,
you take the one piece the same step
you call somewhere and you provide
the same is the definition in two classes.
This is your log in two steps.
This is your employee.
So just
now when you're actually calling
the scenario, so Google to get confused,
did you ever get confused as to
where should
I go and take this user is navigate
to to H&M.
This application is two.
Should I take this step from employee
search step skills
or should I take this
step from log in the steps?
Plus understood.
We are dealing with the goober
with the help of which programing language
we are dealing with,
which programing language Java.
So Java always get confused
when we have two things.
Java is very loyal, always stays with one.
Understood.
And this one right.
So what? You got it.
So when we saw this problem
that if we played one particular step
in one particular class,
we don't even need
to define this step again
and again and again.
So we are simply going
next grade in one class
and let's just call those steps again
and again in every feature.
But you don't need to copy paste it.
Every other step would employ statistic.
So what we will do, we will simply delete
all these particular part of log
in the steps from this particular class
because people already have these steps
in the steps class.
Right?
So let's do this part.
Correct. Now.
Now I am having unique is steps
only one is there definitions
for log in every single step.
Having
a single is still between issue correct
that it?
Yeah Alex be already dedicated
now let me go here
on employee search and let's see see still
my scenario is
and so let's go ahead and implemented
and execute file
that it gave me correct
now see it's working fine
yes so when I Neil
but you asked question early that's
why intentionally I told you to wait
because I was about to export next to you
if I on on night Question
from where did you copy ask Glenn code.
I was reporting standard
from common methods A nasal identical B
anything in the last line? Good.
I wrote everything correct.
Arsenate is working or not.
They tell me
it works.
It works, but it is a complete synonym.
No, because my browser is still open.
My problem is is still open.
So let me write one thing
here. Just one more is different.
Implement. I'm going to write.
Then user flows
rules the
browser
correct.
The same mistake,
the same mistake and I copy it.
Also make
and I copy the same mistake here as well,
because I'm going to implement
just one step for this fight.
So there is a step in this monster
log scenario.
So it wouldn't be much I find we got this.
Could any reasonable.
Yes, Yes, please. I will.
Before the break I will upload the code.
Now this use then to close the browser.
It's up to you.
If you want to keep it
in, log in, keep it in, log in the steps.
If you want to keep in employee
structure steps, keep there,
but make sure you're
keeping it to just one piece.
So I'm keeping it in my log. A space.
All right. Let me
know you guys for closing the browser.
Do we have any code
gone from common methods?
Fine. Closed browser. Right.
This is the matter to be correct,
we need to get the steps.
What we missing? Yeah. Alex. Yes, correct.
We need to run it. No.
Another way.
None. A little bit.
Every time we have to run the code.
But yes,
there are ways to simplify the execution.
So next time when you run, you run
only the particular code,
which will give you a step.
Not all the code.
We will come down to that point.
How does it know?
Without the code it has to log?
Without the code,
it doesn't know anything without the code.
See, this is automation.
It does what we build trade.
If we are not seeing anything,
it's not going to execute anything.
How did it link to log in code?
You deleted?
The log in code is correct.
I deleted the log in code from here
from employee search.
Right.
But I didn't believe anything
from employee search.
You see, it is coming from here.
The execution is done through feature
by and in feature by.
I again explain.
I'm going to explain to this part.
It is depending on the implementation.
So when it starts execution,
you see this board is designed
already implemented as any matter
in which class it gets implemented.
But it is
it is implemented somewhere, right?
So first
my feature file will execute this system.
Then there's a step, then business step,
then business step
and so on to my master's degree.
But in my last step
it gets executed in the store.
So now I have to, like I said,
if you put it, make people places,
you will get duplicate the step
exception, correct.
So you have to place reject one place.
I placed this particular steps
in my scenario
because it belongs to a log in page.
So any log in two steps defined.
But I can go anywhere.
It is best practice to
to use the code from different classes.
Yes, we have to use the code belongs
to one particular class.
We have to take the code
from the particular class.
Now, let me tell you why we need this way.
For example, tomorrow
you have 100 classes, right?
And you're executing the code.
Your code fails only to some X-Y-Z
class 54th class.
This building in the 54th class,
if you keep all this code in one class or,
you know, just to mess up
the code of multiple classes
in one place, isn't it hard to identify
when it comes to
fixing the code?
Isn't it hard to identify
which code unit to fix me?
The file will be huge, right?
A lot of scroll
up and down everything now.
Now, if you keep everything
right in the separate places
now, while looking into here,
you know my code is spending on which far
log in page. Fine.
Just going to log in the steps open
very very small amount code
available check which code is not working
and either fixed spend saving part
understood.
That's why we have different systems
so that if you answer
this are in the same page,
you have scenario events
and then you search
employee by page
normal.
And we cannot do this.
We cannot do this
because this feature file explains.
Right.
This feature might explain
the scenario log
in scenario break is a different part.
I can have my people scenarios
related to log logging.
What example log in.
Similarly,
I can have invalid admin log in.
Similarly, I can have negative log rate,
so multiple log in related distances
belong to one particular feature template.
Similarly for employing such see,
I have redundant steps for search
employed by i.t.
Now what I'm doing.
Let's see.
It is
it will make things more clear this time.
I'm going to copy this complete scenario
and here I'm going to write
such employee by name.
So now can both scenarios I have
because today.
Because today yours yours actually is
steps are not implemented.
That's one
computer code.
Don't worry.
You'll be having this code
so that it will work.
Now, tell me in this code
how many things I have to change,
how many steps I have to change
According to my scenario, such employee,
my need
Just one.
Which one is one, right?
So instead of providing valid, add
what I have to provide this time.
Relatively simple.
Okay, so let me write what it is.
Instead of this I'm going to employ
name correct.
Now see what is very elegant.
It is highlighting this particular step
because
even if you remove just one word, one
even put it from inside it
played, it's not going to change
because it's going to change.
So now we need employee name.
I'm going to provide that
this time.
This time, if I
want to execute this particular scenario,
I have to execute it to generate.
This is going to
get in case
liquid would go.
This is template
index with an employee name, correct.
It is here today.
We got this particular part.
Now tell me in
which class I have to copy this code.
I have to implement in which class
know employee search, employee search
that's automated what I can keep it in
the last position.
Also gives begin
people last position
implementation matters.
Not all of my participate.
Now let me go here and see employing me.
I need to a point.
So let's see.
It is giving me the IFB.
Is this correct?
If we take this by the
I'm going to write
that my
name is it wants to try a third element
by the I.D.
This is the idea I'm going to provide
name same piece.
What is the name?
I copied it in my notes. Correct.
This is the name X, Y, Z.
First, let's check
whether it is identifying or not
with this neat.
Yes, it is giving me the data. Correct.
So let's do it.
Let's take this part here
and put.
So first of all, this
student's
grade.
So now this time.
This time, right this time you'll see
it's gone.
Not and shall we execute
both these scenarios in a single shot
or not?
That is, we can. How? Let me show you.
Can you see here
also I got an option for the feature.
It means when I execute
my complete feature, see if I execute
my complete feature.
It's asking for search
to run the feature employee search
box. Should we.
We should.
We should
share should must read this for later.
This will add.
I will give you the executive meeting
of this board one day.
Cookies Best
of actually when I was giving
decision rate in one company
and there is a
related to some items part in the next
an English language testing system.
So nag put the awesome question
and then I explained this forwards.
There is a story I do that one day
and then you will never
even if you forget that English language
ranking one
forget this code words
see it execute in the first one.
Now it is executing the second one.
Yes, sir.
Correct.
Yellow one break.
I'm going to put it,
sir. I got 8.5.
Been listening, 8.5,
reading eight and speaking in 818 writing.
That is my school.
All right.
Can you guys
see those in areas to past 18 steps past
eight now,
if you can correctly and also you'll see
all the 18 instead of 11.
Then I paused and
cutting
so far
is that anyone who has any question
if yes, please ask.
Meanwhile
and the quote from the repository
for simply
are It's more easy
to get missing the steps or format.
Just delete this
or duplicate the steps from your log
employee Search page
and then it will work.
It just keep the steps unique.
So we already have
those as displayed in a log in.
Then we don't need to take the steps
in our search class.
Also.
So just delete those steps from there
and then you'll be good.
Okay, You'll see.
This class record is available now.
Great. Enough grade.
Yes. Yes. Not yet. I know.
Just give me one more minute
and then maybe on from the invite.
It's been three
year. They've been from like.
I'm just asking.
So everyone can get this thing so right.
So if everyone is understanding
that it is great
good is can we get guys
code is available in the repository.
You can go ahead in the break.
We just take
the updated code in your machine.
Once you get this code base
implementing trade to running.
We definitely ran because we created
now this code in such a way
that we don't need any extra
dependency straight from your machine.
Everything is now related
to central repository.
You just need to give digit code.
Good luck.
All right.
This let's take a break now.
Point
is that we will make no
audio recordings
so far.
Is there anyone who has
any kind of confusion in this code?
No confusion.
Good.
Now let me go in
to this particular part. See
how things work.
Basically, let's say
you have one feature by Blake
you have to feature for people
who have difficulty understanding
this part step definition is demonstrated
and they can do this for you because
you have lot of the steps definition
by correct.
For example, this is your log in steps,
this is your employee.
So two steps,
maybe tomorrow you will be having
another one called the baseboards steps.
So many steps.
You are writing this in any given
in the username password, click on log
input to verify their day's work.
Fine.
Enter username password.
Click some log important
verified their dashboard
Search the employee disasters disasters.
See you implemented this step.
See it now remember the package
you provide.
It steps.
The package you provide is steps right?
In this particular package,
it will search for all the ways
for these steps.
We will search
only if we find the steps unique in your
this particular package in all the classes
it will execute.
If it finds duplicate,
it will give you duplicate method
exception duplicate exception
dispute.
So far.
Is this part clear to everyone
what I'm explaining?
So duplication works for same package
only are not any.
We should have just one package
for all the steps.
Just one package.
And in this package we rated,
unless there is a platform
we're dealing with.
All right.
For example,
if you are working with the web based
application rate, you will be having
just one package in one project.
If you're working with a project
that supports your API
distinct data as distinct
and then you'll would be having multiple
steps packages one to support API
one is for your best buddies per database
and how these packages work.
So I'm going to take them.
Okay, let's see
now what is happening here.
The problem is still seen with me.
Which problem?
The way we were executing best
is this investing grade.
We were executing this consistent indirect
direct distribution.
At one time we executed one class
similarly year on.
So if I see my feature right,
I am executing one feature at one day,
isn't it?
This is what we are doing, right?
We can execute one picture
pilot one time in that one feature file.
If I hadn't made it possible use,
I can execute all those multiples
in that needs cutting.
But if I want to execute do feature
based with the existing
set of what we had in the integral
to feature
once in a single shot
with the existing board, what behavior
exam?
No, this is not destined
so right now we do not have anything.
We do not have anything through which
how indeed
we do not have the exact opposite.
I let me repeat my question.
As of now,
whatever the existing setup we have
can be executed to feature
inserting one shot.
The answer is no.
Right?
Parallel Sequential No.
It is a sequential execution
basically even better.
Let me repeat again, unless we have
a separate machine for that.
Okay.
So we'll focus on sequential execution
the way we had,
their testing did not exist in testing
when we talk about to do,
but we have a last
let me put this point first,
put information
to implement
in the core for
steps
and feature.
Right now
we are going to talk about another class
now as good check with someone
if you got very long that
class right now.
What is this run of class?
Remember,
this class is a configuration file
which is considered as the bankable.
All your execution part.
Every single thing will be done
by this particular class code
at another class.
And this student
understood this.
Everyone
months.
So in this class we are going to check
what all are the things we have.
Okay, so let's create one class cluster.
Should we go ahead and create class days?
Let's create another class.
So I'm going to write here like in Java,
let me create a new package, right?
Let me create a new package called code.
I can be having multiple different
classes, right?
Right.
I can. We have multiple classes. Remember,
based and do
not examine this move
to take similar regulation or exam.
And similarly I can have integration,
dinner, smoke rendering and so on.
How you do that for now,
just understand one thing
all that unless we will keep
in this particular package.
Okay, now
let me create one class called
in another piece.
We added another class.
Now look carefully what I'm doing.
I'm not writing any code inside the class.
Remember, I'm
not creating anything inside that class,
but I'm going to write everything outside
the class, above the class.
I'm going to make
understood.
We are going to create another class
in a class.
I'm not going to write anything
in the mean block.
I'm going to write about that class.
Now, what are the things
I'm going to write above?
The initial
first thing,
like I said, we are working before class.
This should be before class.
But it's important.
Like I said,
read.
we are going to work to deliver.
But a unique
remember extended was also derived
from the unit grade.
So here to do what we will use
with the generic key.
This particular point in your mind.
Okay, we are using a G unit and a student
friend, so here I am going to write
one particular part
going at the rate and one bit.
So when I'm typing in that it is another
class likely to administer some feature.
I know the link
between this sort of feature
is that to go over that, another class
is basically execute all of it.
We just like, okay, give me
linking is already there.
Right this way
we are able to execute ordinal class.
So on the picture point, great,
because link is already done.
Remember to go declaration or usage plate.
So when you go to declaration
additional usage
you'll see the implementation.
So that is linked point.
So now when I provide at the recommended
you see it is beginning from RG
No Junior did not run this document.
We can you
so we which package it is referring to.
J you need one.
Okay.
Remember we are using to compare with unit
now in this direct relevant option.
I'm going to write
a goomba dot class
all right by because this j
and it will execute make good Googlebot
based on this particular class.
So this is the student takes time to write
in the regular with the timber dot plus.
Understood.
In this one line of code is that anyone
who has any kind of confusion
mice now now
the goomba is not that smart grade
good goomba and dude it is us fine
if we are going to execute based on
the class called Katoomba dot class.
So what parameters
we are going to execute?
Not just think about the test
and do not examine by that data.
Provide occasionally class
name, group name
grade parameters
whether we want to integrate in parallel,
read every single thing listeners
we provide all these options there or not.
So those were destiny options.
Those were listed.
The options current logic is steam
implementation is different.
We are going to configure in this class.
There we head didn't do not well,
so we were using test in the options.
Now we have to do better than that class.
So we are going to use options. Right?
So here we will write, iterate
over options.
Can you
see now these options are coming from
I ordered to do or J unit there time Z
we are using with the names of options
like let's open
this could give more options,
put this better.
This is
in the sort of we want what I'm doing
in what options
right now, what are going to be options.
We are going to define
whatever the options
we are going to explain here
based on these options.
My this class will execute
all of my scenarios
correct.
Let's do it.
So what is the first thing I should look
forward to?
The first thing I should look forward to
is my feature.
I want to execute either one feature
fine or all the feature files
in this being good.
Sure, this is what my target is.
This is the target I'm looking. What would
I want to
execute my all feature files
from one place.
So that is my place.
Know how I define feature here?
See, I'm going to write features
and in this features in double course,
it will ask for the back.
So the bot tell me what is my feature
called Case in my project
where is might be different
in my project
is should start from your to see correct
in your options.
It should start from your based on a C
and there is some C you get EST.
Correct.
I noticed you get resources
and resources.
You get features
content under features, right?
If you just keep if you just keep slash
and keep it right like this,
it will take all the feature,
find all the feature by
and it don't want to execute
all the feature.
I just want to execute one particular,
one particular.
So just to keep
like this log in dart feature
or just write like this
and deploy
employ
search feature
windows tool
industrial guys.
Let me execute one by one
blade one by one.
So first I'm going to read
non import feature.
Correct. Let me execute this part.
Now see,
even if I'm editing all the options here
and you see I'm
getting different option here
it is it is asking for request.
That is it
means my implementation is correct
because what I said
I'm going to run my Google class.
So this is meant to do more remote class,
which I am going to execute.
So then I am going to execute
my particular class.
It should give me the option
in front of the class only.
So it is giving me the option here.
Now, based on what options
that I'm going to get here.
You see,
these options could give more options.
I will provide all the options.
One moment
I will explain all the options. Right.
So first let me execute on this class
from here on
so you can execute during a is an A-plus.
Let's execute this virtual meet.
Now see
now see it is giving me the options.
It says that step user is navigating
to autonomous application is undefined.
Right.
But tell me one thing.
This is a step
and all this is this user interface.
My user name clicks on logging button
and the user is successfully logged
in user, close the browser.
Every single thing,
every single thing is implemented
or not any
everything is implemented.
But even when I have
every single step implemented,
when I try to run my remote
class, it itself
there is no step definition found.
What is the reason?
Because this time,
see, let tell you the difference.
For us
to let me execute this from here, right?
I'm going to execute from my feature plan.
It's working fine.
And that means it's working
absolutely fine.
IT So is there anything wrong
with my code?
See, it's
just one scenario. Five is deserts.
But is there anything wrong
with my coordinate?
There is nothing wrong in my good
might with the logic.
Now me explain
what is the logic behind this?
This is my configuration part.
This is my configuration file.
Correct.
And class will not execute anything
until and unless we explain
to this particular find that hey,
you have to execute this
particular feature, right?
Or that particular feature applied or only
feature files from the particular part.
And you have to look forward to search
for the steps
implemented for this particular find.
In this particular place.
It made a big
we have provided to our donor class
for this particular feature
by which I'm going to execute
you have to search for the steps
which we have implemented or deployed
for this particular feature
by this particular place.
All right.
We have to turn this double basin,
do anything on its own.
It's all about the instructions,
the command
vector to convert, then only to execute.
Sort of good understood.
So now now how
we provide this information,
how we provide this information to.
Our class C, that is a word.
There is a word.
Let me first put a comma
if we are going to provide two things.
First, we have to provide cover.
I put call my here
and I'm going to write another word.
Go blue.
What?
I'm going to radio this
10 minutes, whatever written in blue
and in this blue, in this blue,
I'm going to write
the package name of Create My Steps.
This is the name of my package
where I have all the definitions
now. Understood
who was asking the question?
Can we have multiple steps diminished?
Maybe not.
The then is
correct
now understood right then is see,
I still remember.
So now here you see
when I provided this blue part two steps.
This is steps. Now make it to work.
Options will specifically begin,
but it's not good
practice.
It is a good practice.
It is the best practice actually,
which we are doing.
But particular steps for one particular
big for all great.
All the steps classes
should be available inside one package.
Okay, just the package index.
In just the package
you can consider, you
can understand this example like this
in one rule, how many were regular
for your clothes
too? That's great.
Then you have to create
two steps back. Just
one rule one How many more should we have
in one rule
one? How many better to be here?
What I at
Nice. And in this area.
Then you should execute everything
from feature file only and
are known as.
You don't need to use glue multiple times.
If you do it then it will be duplicate.
You know, keyword error.
You will get here.
So I'm not getting by.
We use group deployments.
The ladies is then I think you have
more experience than me in this part.
I don't have even one word of my whole
Got to go to everything.
See, that's what I'm saying.
These are
the options are providing correct?
Correct.
So when we provide the options
this features, this blue are the options.
Don't tell me.
Have you ever heard this word? No.
Maybe in school.
I mean, colleges, glue.
Stick something.
Alexi.
Glue means to stick
something red to be used in particular.
Jenny Step one
component rate.
We use this, we use it for
want to put things together, correct?
To stick something. Why? To do better.
Take this word like a bit big this word
because it glued your steps
with your definitions,
with your picture by a rate
already is.
When does the meaning of this word
So now when you provide this option, blue
is equal to stitch than would happen.
What will happen after this is see
in your project.
Let's say you have package one.
You have package to your package
three, package for eight
and then you have in resources
folder and the resources features folder.
And under this one
if to every so many points
when you run class and you provided this
blue keyword
for let's say will be for package, great.
So it will not search
for this particular part.
Search will narrow down to only before
and here only it will ask
for all the implemented steps
in this particular push.
Correct? Yes.
Great. Great.
Very good months. Good job.
No, it is not a class in business
in this blue.
When I provide the name of the package,
I have to provide not that class,
but because in one package
I can have multiple.
Like I said, according to this particular
portion, we are writing everything
in different places
where the basketball to one feature.
That's what I'm going to explain.
I'm going to spend the newspaper.
Just give me a moment.
First, let clear this
and then I will come to that point.
It's not completely it's
just a starting read.
So now see, this time what I'm saying
to my two options, my class.
Then go and execute this log in feature.
Now on two classes, remote classes.
I do find any steps
then this it or structured
under this particular package instance.
Okay. Okay.
This made me to me
first
to see what
is working now.
Working absolutely fine but from the
the class this pen
now you see here but another class
logging feature Well it admin logging
now can you then you just connected
with the test and delivers
sort of first class in class method.
Remember this kind of output
we generally get objects making steps.
Correct?
They remember interestingly,
when we were getting the results there,
we were seeing the suit name and then
the class name and then the method name.
Similarly,
we are having another plus inside end
class, the feature of feature file inside
feature file.
Which scenario get exactly.
Okay, now
now let's do a little bit more here
instead of this, I'm going to execute
this time employ such to check
all the scenarios of my employee search,
whether it is executing or not.
Okay, So I'm going to execute
all the scenarios from here.
Let's go ahead and do it
now, see if
those in any ways can you see here
in the report it took two scenario
search by 80 and search by me
in order to see one by one.
It will execute both of them
would happen.
Application is burning slowly, I think.
Yes, everyone is executing
when I execute, don't
execute.
Going to be correct there.
No class is the very good part.
But in that class, once I'm done
with that in a class,
then you'll be just blown away
in last batch.
Also, what people generally do is
whenever I create,
whenever I
create their is this, I prepared
their data ready to execute something.
Now, like you genius,
they are also genius.
They are also using the same this data.
When I'm explaining before execution,
everyone executes the scheme as data.
Now whoever executed first
that is writable
for others for others
it's the copied ones are spelled this.
It ain't my best because it's not working.
I didn't even execute
they just because already failed.
And they're blaming like my best guess is
that kind of intended intelligence level.
I have to hand that something
like when we are executing, when executing
something, they let me execute first
so that we won't face
this much of the application
and then I will give you time to do this
once I'm done with the class.
All platforms yours,
go ahead and play with the application.
24 seven
But I know this explanation
is not going to work.
People will execute.
See a month exposed,
no minds first execute, then explain
what caused it.
So it's working Great. Casey.
Proud of you boys.
Nasty
work, but everybody in trouble right now.
They executed.
This is the name of my feature, correct?
This is my feature
search employed a research employee
by name boat Best because this past
place.
Can you see what it says?
Cost cutting.
It means my runner class is working
absolutely fine
now. The invention
of creating the runner
class is to execute all their test cases
on the feature files in a single track.
This has been mentioned,
general looked and
eliminated.
This is their intention to execute
on their best guesses
in a single shot.
Fine.
Now let's do just one modification here.
Instead of writing this employee
search card
feature, just to keep it blank,
just keep blank.
Now, what happens when you keep a blank
here like this
when you provided the bot inside to see
is the resources
features mesh.
It simply means under this folder,
whatever the features you have, if two,
three and four
and so on, it will take all the features,
it will take
all the features and execute
all of those features.
The moment you provide just this slash.
Now let me show you.
Let me show you the moment
I'm going to execute
with this normal slash, just a slash.
I'm not going to provide
any part of any picture.
I see.
It took the first feature is start
executing the scenario.
Don't execute anything.
Guys, please.
I'm late.
I think next time I will tell you that
I'm going to explain
and I will simply execute.
Now I have to make a trap based
local from the work site.
No. How would you complete the look then?
There is more important
first scenario execute.
Right?
Both scenario execute
this website.
What can I say about this
particular website?
Hundreds of people execute
hundreds of scenarios every day on this
and this that state
simply saying yes, exactly.
We available
will double.
This is the next website.
But I think my explanation
is that find
now you'll see here
you'll see your boss Lane
explains everything.
You're so smart
more time the current danger
nasty guys then I executed
first it took this part Do you see?
Let me close this
Are these two feature minds I have read
The boss name is us.
One, two, three, five Employs such.
When I open this picture point,
I have two scenarios.
You'll see it is executed.
This is my log in feature inside
log in picture.
I have this particular one scenario.
It got executed. Correct.
It means
I really like pregnancy.
Good schooling.
What grade.
You should excellent ABC.
I will be here.
Let's see.
All right. Can you see guys
this part?
Right?
So now we execute
all of our feature files from here on.
Correct?
Correct.
Ready to learn something interesting.
Now, shall we proceed further?
One mini question please
ask given if you are a micro question,
people question it. No.
Question Ask.
Do we need a comma?
Yes, sir, we need a comma.
If they don't provide comma,
it will give us the error.
See, it gives us the error.
Can you see?
All right, sir? You're most welcome.
Fine features.
We are
are the ones I should write.
It gives us the extension.
Steps are missing.
What actually are
The steps are not missing plane.
So like I said, in automation,
we have to tell everything to do
but is not very smart. Right?
So to ask us it, okay, if
I'm going to execute this feature, fine.
Where should I find this type definition?
So wait, you have to find
all the step definitions inside.
This is steps and we use this where to use
implements to stick something.
So stick something means what is detour?
Step the Venetians with your feature
and that's what we provide in general
plus is an auction of cucumber and so
it is going to execute and this could not
Yes, yes.
Correct. Correct.
That's what
we are going to translation see
so far
what is happening is see so
but what is happening?
Let's see.
I'm going to implement another scenario
in my logic, Right.
I'm going
write another thing here in my body.
I'm going to create another scenario
where I should think
if we take any scenario for error
verification.
All right,
or any scenario for normal user,
we have one user like this.
See, where is this?
We have one user, correct?
This is my enemy user.
We can have another normal user.
Also, let me show you what is that user?
So my another user name would be g
H, Johnny one,
two, three, four, 5640.
This is in
the password would be 6125312344.
I will share this username password
also with invalid credentials. Well
one, 2345600.
Then it would be
fix for.
Let me create another user.
No issues in me
and truly
let me create user for this batch.
So I'm going to take name is Z.
My initial would be Zetia
and the last is
the one and it's exclude
the mark.
Fine.
And this is the employee 80
degree same the state employee
state.
Now we added this employee
current
where
the username and password I forgot to wait
I'm going to take this as
in order
when he was sending.
It's data.
11234.
It's not making find issues.
Let's do one thing first.
Liquidate the scenario sign
with great scenario valid
is this nugget.
When I say easiest login,
it simply means a normal user.
Okay.
Now when as a normal user,
it means once you log in
with your admin user,
you get all the admin bugs and everything.
So next time
I want to use as a normal user.
So there I need SS logging user. Fine.
So I'm going to take given the user is
user is never Chatham's application.
My first step would be same fragrance,
but the change would be here
on my second step.
So I'm going great
and user interface valid.
E is this username and password correct
categories.
Is this correct?
Students
Fine.
And then simple.
The user clicks on log in,
then successfully log in
and close the browser.
I'm not going to edify anything
so I'm just going to keep things like this
because I know
intention is to create something else.
That's one.
Find close the browser now
see what is happening.
When I'm when I want to create this step
first, I have to be in the bane
of executing the complete scenario.
So whatever that is steps are available
before
before the step which is unimplemented.
All these steps will execute and then only
it will give me this particular path.
Getting.
But it
for example, in this feature future,
if I come in, if I execute this valid
as this log in, so what does that mean?
First,
it will open the browser unnecessarily.
It will launch that you wanted
and then only it will give me this
a step.
It will give you the missing step point
I got.
The missing is
I don't need this as of now.
Right.
I really could.
You coming?
What is this abbreviation
means it's a normal.
Use it as a sprint for normal user.
All right.
We call it
the user's username. It's Just a moment.
That is not full formal basis, but yes,
it is. Easiest, simple.
Fine.
Now, guys, see, right now I am having
just one or two lines in this scenario.
Again, even
if I have one or two lines
or just taking some time, just imagine
the scenario where I would be having to be
in or 20 lines in the future.
Right?
And then on the 22nd line
I am on, it will give you the missing step
and then it will I want to implement
the steps for would the second one
then do I have that much of time
to execute 21 steps unnecessarily
and then to get the code when 22nd step
is? Think about the big scenario.
We don't have that.
Which of got it
then what is be working on for this.
So overseas we have been working on
based on
the information, the code
which are going to add now,
it will take only those steps
which are unimplemented.
It will give you the definition only
for those steps which are unimplemented.
Once you are going to implement
that steps,
once you're done with the implementation
of those steps, then only it will execute
your quite understood.
And let's put this
let's do it
first.
Go into your class, go to another plus.
Another important point
which we are going to add here is
is desired, is
command going to try to
create.
Now see, I'm going to add one by one
all the information
features, right?
We use
to provide
the path of
all the feature.
Then you
is this where we find
implementations for
all the
steps.
So here,
here we provide
on the
auto package
where be find
on this
device is this information helpful.
What I'm getting in there in a class
so that next time
when you devise it,
you will get this information. Okay
now for trial.
See, it is giving me two options.
Again, it would make it right.
And by default it says it is false.
And then
if I keep it false, what would happen?
See, it is great
if I keep it true, then only it does not.
I'm telling you.
What is the meaning of this false
First, let's make it false.
What is happening here
Now? Let's see.
Have implemented unimplemented state.
It might be just like correct
coordinates.
I want unimplemented
the steps in my feature by
I don't know in which feature file.
I have unimplemented steps because
internet class and providing the model
features.
Let's say I didn't reach feature base
in every region.
I have ten scenarios so only not
I have not use grade in hundred scenarios.
Maybe I have 500 steps in those 500 steps.
I really don't know which one is
implemented and which one is unemployed.
Cutting And to be honest,
if you are working with AJ,
you do not have that much of time
to go and check all of these things
manually, right?
So you have to implement your code
in such a way that your code will scan.
Can you stand here? You log in, feature
man, it's already in
data, possibly.
Did you check? Did
I just read one step?
I just did one step.
Did you take the of digit code
from my good
digit one?
Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
I'm going to upgrade this code
in the good again.
Not really.
So here this is the one line just
I did just one make.
Okay I didn't do anything else.
So guys
see I don't have that much of time.
Do a scan and verify the things manually.
Correct.
That's why
in the middle class I am providing dry
and there is a bag called.
Right. And what does it mean, dry it?
And the first thing it does
when you make it to the menu
by default, it is poised.
By default, it is display false.
But when you make it do the first thing
it does, it is stops your actual execution
based.
Please, please don't. Right.
When I'm explaining something to this
damn import
the code you can always get
from the repository.
These were the by value.
Keep pushing yourself
on writing the code businessman.
It was doing right.
If I'm explaining something,
it is important here.
In the end, the thing which you will get.
You're putting your time there. Please.
This part
when I say client is equals to do
it means the first thing it does it stops.
You're actually execution.
What does it mean, actually execution?
If you keep executing, you're in lost
by taking this as drive
and is equal to blue.
It will not open your browser
on it.
It will not execute.
It needs to actually stops by it
quickly, scans all the steps
that you have, all the feature phones
that you have, and it will change.
It will is again, whether all the
steps are implemented or not.
The moment you make
it right, it is equals to do it again
through all the beach it applies and check
which steps we have implemented,
which is steps
you did completely alright based on that.
So if one step was not implemented,
it wouldn't know.
Even if all the steps implemented,
it will not do that.
So I recorded Brian Unger.
I will show you which we wrote.
We the moment you made it through.
Like I said, it stops.
You're actually execution now.
There is no actual execution, right?
It will just the of save
every single step in your steps package
already.
That's what I'm saying.
There's what I'm explaining. Great.
If you had 500 steps and you don't know
how many steps you have implemented
and you need the body of those
steps, how would you do that?
Do it.
Either you do it manually or you make it.
It is equal to to.
If you make it read, it is equal to two.
It will give you these step definitions
how I show you not see
I made it right and is equal to true.
I know I have
what is the unimplemented in my log
in feature, right?
Correct. Correct.
So now you see now
you see if I had run here from the note
plus what it had what it is happening
did it executed search employee
by eighties search employed by me
did it executed
it did what is it
gives you rate is a big year
did it execute this very log
in very long in no detail secured
or it didn't I got this right in here
this one I got right
as of read my because it says
this is it is unimplemented.
This step is unimplemented.
So it shows us what's wrong. Got it.
Got it.
Now, let me copy this.
Let me show you once again.
Let me copy this a step. Right.
And because this is a part of my log
in, so I'm simply writing in logging
rate, simply in logging.
I'm not writing any code.
Any code as of now, I'm not writing.
I'm simply doing it here and that's it.
Basically.
Now. Now
all of my steps implemented,
all of my steps implemented this to
let me go to management last again,
let me go to the classic
environment.
Plus here, if you see great environment
plus here, what I'm doing is
keeping client is equals to do
what I still do
and this time if I try to run
again,
no actual execution, but it gives me 40
for every single scenario
it is giving me big.
What does it mean?
It quickly scaled all the steps
that I be in my feature file.
It found the steps
for every single feature funny, right?
Everything is fine this way.
It is giving me on the same rate
instead of 15 seconds.
Correct.
So now first thing what it does, it
quickly checks.
Second thing, it saves your time
that you are spending unnecessary.
You executing those.
Let me get you
to a gentleman's application,
launching the app providing the user.
Right.
So now your time sealing part.
Understood.
Is it best thing to implement?
Is this thing to implement?
I still
it is right
now. See now see this time
let me put it here.
Enforced the definition of this.
If we did it to do
it really
quickly, it's game All good again.
All good steps.
Whether they are
implemented or not. Why?
We didn't start with that nozzle.
That's why.
Boss, delete you to the problems.
They will give you the solutions.
If we just give you the solutions,
you will never think of the problems.
Right?
So first show you the problem and then
we never did the solutions and didn't
unless we realized the problem
later.
Global warming.
Now, when we are facing the problem,
we realize the actual value
of pure oxygen or the value that
similarly in of course,
also once we introduce you the problem
and then we give you the solution.
So next time, if you encounter
because it will never be white or black,
it will always be
when you go in, you're being practical
like Bill always is problems,
and then you should know
how to get rid of those problems.
That's why intentionally we right
we create this curriculum in such a way
that you are not only the solutions,
but also with the problems.
Great.
Fine case. Second point here.
Right.
Second point, if
it is set to say to do it
starts
actual execution.
If it is good, it stops actual execution.
Understood.
Now to execute my best
guess is what I have to do.
I have to make it false
right now.
When I make it false, this time
it will execute because now
my actual execution will be as it's
the moment
it true my actual execution stops later.
I need
Let's run.
See it's working point correct.
It is today's
all it to
because it's not executing flawlessly.
Right. Just one command.
We need to provide.
It is going to execute.
This is what we call
magic the nation right.
We declared destiny to take minute.
Now we are making it more easy in there.
We need to include bag rate.
The methods include exclude categories.
So many things.
Right?
Class name became named world class name.
There is no such kind.
Provide the path of feature point
we can call when the execution
all and has the power
to stop indication order.
I mean execution.
Yet Bryan has the power rate
it is two is it gives me
or we can call the execution
amount murder to be execution
rate going is in you can call it
when you said try it on is it going to
do is what we call quick scan
or rate
for request
the any question?
No, no, no.
I'm your only
call rate angelica
record is you regarding it is
going to be fine
a lot of lot of things
a lot of things are going
a lot of things are coming on the
we don't worry about it case.
So so far so good.
Everyone.
Yes. Okay.
Now see now
see intentionally, intentionally.
I'm going to execute
just one particular log in feature rate.
One particular feature different
Nikola by your code is not running.
Did you take the origin code
from my repository?
Let me just add this to code
also first, where does getting digit
audio steps will work?
It is a guarantee.
That's why it is a scanning. First.
It will make sure that
every single step is implemented
and then only it will execute.
What rate?
So let me push on.
So this code
in middle of the class also, right.
And try to fix it during way.
But that's when void forces by default.
Right.
If we want to actually execute on code,
then we have to make it false.
So whenever see
what is the standard procedure first,
whenever it does tinetti
just to make it clear that it is equal to
when you make this right
and is equal to true equivalence
and gives you on this to finishes
right in case if you miss
one stick definition again running
it will give you
it gives you all the experience,
all the sticks implemented.
It gives you an
is this a dead step implemented?
Then make it right
it is a good is an execution.
It works and it works well enough to do
the implementation bullshit.
Right. So first
what Brennan's straight.
The moment you make it draw
it checks this this depth
along with this particular linking.
Right.
So linking of your by the steps
with your step definitions.
Right.
Got it. Got it.
So it works on linking all the links.
It should check if link is available.
Connect if is not available.
Not getting paid
and not only not getting it
link is not available if is incorrect
and also it gives you the link.
Then go ahead and put this
particular stitch to create a link.
Connect your linking checks.
Correct. Linking checks.
Connect these two things
good and is linking check
not the code which we have written
inside this obviously great.
Not not not therefore
that we have couple of assertions
right for that we have so many things in
we skip of feature points.
Yes ma'am we can
we can I'm coming to that point
also don't put I'm
coming to that point right
fine so far so good.
Let's discuss one more tag. Right.
We discussed features so far.
We discussed glue so far,
we discussed thread and so far.
All right, let's discuss one more day
and then we'll take a break
so that you can digest this part.
Okay? Exclaimed
Now. Now,
when I actually execute this part, I see.
When I actually execute.
Remember this?
Obviously I show obviously
how the locators syntax will work on
Google page.
It's a common sense.
So now see here, right now, right now
in this console,
I am having a lot of information
available.
Correct.
Some of you guys are having
more information,
some unreadable
getting to right in So many things.
So many things you will get.
Mine is pretty much clear, right?
Mine is pretty much clear.
But actually, actually,
when you actually execute it,
you get a lot of information and majority
of that information is just irrelevant.
That It tell me honestly,
if you get a lot of information in person,
how many information you read,
only one or two lines.
You don't really complete information.
Correct. Correctly.
You you don't really complete information.
Right. Exactly.
So Now,
now you'll see
everyone here is waiting for me.
Correct.
So now see here what I'm going to do.
I'm going to add
another deck called Monaco,
and I'm setting it to two.
Monaco is equals two to the moment.
The moment I added
this particular Monaco is equal to blue.
It simply means that it will remove
all the unreadable and irrelevant
information from the console.
Keeps your console clean easily. It.
So if there is any any unreadable
character or any relevant information
coming
while executing the code in your console,
it will remove all that information
when you make Monaco.
Is it going to do it is true,
since my console is already clear, it's
not going to remove anything Anything.
But let's do it.
Let's execute
with this monochrome equals to proposed.
So if in your console, if it
is having a lot of information,
a lot of information which is not good
or which is error limit read,
we're going to use that word also.
But it is also coming.
There is another keyword called Pretty,
which we are going to use don't with
another word, which
we are going to use this pretty soon.
Soon it will come.
All right.
Now see, it got executed. Okay.
Since the information
since the information is very limited.
Right.
It is giving me all this being
so not any unreadable.
Correct. That is a limited information
only the relevant information
it will give you here.
All right.
Well, replaced
with the
like.
So far, so good.
Great, great, great.
Let's take a break for 15 minutes.
Read again.
It'll be a smooth transition for 15
minutes and after 15 minutes will connect.
Right.
And then I'll give you a break
for 5 minutes in between
and after that revamp of the class. Okay.
All right
so okay, so far.
Today's so far, so good.
Is there anyone who didn't understand
anything?
Nice? Nice.
So let's take a break for 15 minutes
right after we connect.
Once again, race.
All right, So let's start now.
Jimi's is asking, can you please
explain briefly
simple language I'm using
by default, dry is false
when I'm saying by default, right?
It is false.
It means it's not going to impact on
anything
on your normal execution
by adding a correct.
It's not going to mean
it's not going to affect
on your execution portion
when it is false.
But when you make it true,
it is your actual execution.
Why it stops your actual execution,
because instead of execution, your screen
rate, instead of your executing
your actual script,
what it does this time, it will simply
is take all of your steps
it will simply scan all of your steps.
All right.
And it is going to pick quickly is against
or look at the steps read,
but it quickly begins all of your steps.
It will check
whether we just did was implemented
which respect is not implemented.
If any is is not implemented, it will give
you the step definition of that one.
You can simply edit
in unit step definition, but
if every step is implemented,
it will give you all the dream extension
and would not
try to invoice
months.
You're most welcome, sir.
Now here
here when I'm writing
monochrome is it was to do so what it does
basically right it
it needs
the console to
output for the timber
test right is having some
irrelevant information
then we set it to go through
it simply.
It simply removes
all the information,
all the or I should read.
It simply removes
all the irrelevant, irrelevant information
from the console, from the console
underscore always monochrome is equals
to blue
student.
Now let's talk about
another keyword trade.
Whether it is now actually
the Stuart is no more applicable
and it is deprecated right but
just for the information point of view,
I'm explaining you this keyword we call it
is three is equal to two by default.
This is trade said to do.
Okay.
So when we say string is said to do,
what does it mean?
See, it is simply
you can see right simply you can see
it is alternative to your grain.
What is it?
What is it case?
It is simply sorry of people stain or suit
for sake of this data. This
if by September
15, 16 hours every day.
I can't imagine why I said
that I would be up to that
memo.
It's monochrome, not nano chrome.
It's a spending mistake.
Please check your spending.
That's why I always said
I got a blank 22 again.
Yeah, I'm coming to that point.
I'm coming to that.
When I did come to point, it's Monaco.
Renee, please take the city
now. Now here
is is equals.
Strict rule is simply an alternative
is simply an alternative to your driver
word writing those random checks limit
all of your steps are actually implemented
or not correct?
Correct.
This indicates the implementation
estimate of all distance trained similarly
similarly when we talk about is trip
is equals to blue, right?
What it does then you actually executes
when you actually execute your best guess.
Right.
It checks all the skips,
which is undefined, which is different.
That's why the main reason
for making it deprecated we already have.
Right.
And that's why we don't need a strict
Is it super understood.
That is the main reason why we don't need
a strict is equals to true
because we already have Brian
understood.
I understood
the simple way to have
the method is of same color
but didn't make any sense.
Remove it.
Fine. Now.
Now let me do another important thing
here.
Cutting
so far even Brian is equal to false.
Yes Right?
And is equal to false now as well
because we are actually executing.
When you want to execute your best guesses
you have to make
Drennan is equal to false.
When want to check all of your steps
are implemented or not, you have to wait.
Brennan is equal to two.
I made this point
it would be easier to do.
It stops action execution train.
So to perform actual execution,
we have to make it false.
Okay, let me write it.
Execute script.
It should be
to make hard decision.
It's not a solution.
It has nothing to do with the assertion.
So please just check the definition.
But yes, just for a memory purpose
if you want to.
Related with those such in part
you can write,
but a is a completely different topic
that we're going to work on here.
Okay.
Related to the fidelity to the steps,
you can say the position,
but for the good
we will use separate part of positions
already.
All right, everyone,
for now.
Now what I'm going to do is
I'm going to more clarification Blue
mode.
If I am me, it is optional.
Unable to
answer your second question first.
I don't know.
Eleanor, can you please put it in
your syntax support so that they will see?
I'm pretty sure this would be very added.
What I can see you can be stood there
and then you will see that from the
front.
So now
I will answer to your first question.
When we were actually executing our
find it from here, Peter quite straight,
it was taking the code,
so linking was available from here.
Correct.
But when you go with that, a class
so it has nothing to do,
it has nothing to do with the linking
of your feature point, how
the feature file is linking
with your steps here.
It will ask for the specific things.
For example, it is asking you to execute
which one particular be jumped, right?
Similarly,
it will ask you for where to find steps
grade to make your search narrower.
It is asking everything is specifically.
These are two different things.
So it is not optional. It is not optional.
It is mainly predictive
to provide the blue party.
Okay.
If you don't provide a blue pass,
remember we had to stick with Venetians,
but still we were not able to execute.
Right?
So Blue Point is my decree
we have to keep.
Right.
If you don't put this blue bar
and you showed this code
to a technical architect, it won't work.
Public cluster extends loading steps.
Oh, Login is steps.
Why you want to extend
log initiatives here and
what log instances to do here.
Tell me one thing.
What we have been logging is steps.
Yeah. So that's what I'm asking. Alex.
If you're going to extend
your log into step, remove the permission,
what kind of information?
I saw one, like I said, my
console is already pretty clean grade,
so that's why
it is not taking any information out.
If there is any in unreadable character,
irrelevant information.
If someone has in that case it removes.
Okay.
No, they look all right.
So next in me, in case grade,
when you have a benefit,
your file and you have been classes,
what do you expect every single class
and no.
Then if you provide simply package name.
Is it a good idea or extending classes in
one class is a good idea?
Which one is the most appropriate
approach and easy approach?
See guys,
we read this code to simplify right
our execution process,
to make our process simplify,
to make our process very simple.
We use all of this in one spot.
Otherwise always have very little business
to correct.
We can go with X, y, z option,
you can go with ABC option with one, two,
three option rate.
But again, if it is not according
to the standards, it does not mean
it is of no use.
Industrial place.
Nice. Nice.
Now let's see,
let's do something good theory,
something very important to show you. Not
I'm going to write.
I am going to add grade one employee,
but I'm going to do I'm going to add
one employee in the application setting.
After that, I will tell you,
create the beauty of this cookbook.
You will be amazed.
See right click on feature
and I'm to create a new feature
by calling Add
employee Dog feature.
This is like feature and employee
dog feature.
So here's what I'm going to write.
I'm going to make feature is dead
employees connect.
I can add one employee to employee
three employee.
Let's see multiple scenarios.
We would see one scenario make one thing.
Okay, so what is the posting I have to do
scenario.
Scenario.
Right?
So I'm rating maybe
one employee from
from each employee.
I'll replace what I'm doing,
adding one employee on my feature.
So to add one employee first, what
I have to,
I have to internal user name password,
click on login button right then
click on my option.
Let me show you the functionality
first.
Log in
as an admin
because only admin can add new employees.
Other employees cannot connect
more.
What you see
I click on and after clicking on
there is an option called an employee.
Can you
you see case everyone
So now now
in my log in page in my log in page.
Can I take the two steps from here.
Right I cannot take
this is the user navigates
to employee list each way
because in business
because clicking on employee
is not an employee option.
Correct.
So even though if I have a team option
beat there,
I can look at one for that, activate
another.
Okay, so let me add this
four steps post here.
Good visibility concept.
I am saving it. It would be engaged.
Is there any time saving activity time
you don't need line seven.
Yes we don't need lane seven but in future
we will going to add associates
their time using VPN.
Okay.
Now see, I'm
going to wait here when the user
clicks on
the option
option,
you use a
and is this correct?
Not yet. I'm writing
user interests
first name and first name and
last name.
Then the user
clicks on
see important
reason,
then employ added
success.
Correct. And then maybe one more step
for closing the browser.
So then use that to close the browser.
Let's take this a step.
So then user plus the browser.
Now tell me why is this time?
Do we know how we can create the steps
for this only
without actually executing them?
We noticed Wait, how we can do this?
Let's go to that another plus right now.
I'm not going to execute this log
in feature, but for the entire back page,
for the entire package I'm going to make,
branding is equals to true.
So now it will quickly
scan all of my steps.
How many steps are implemented?
How many steps are unimplemented?
Everything be correct
Categories.
So let's go ahead and execute it to post.
Remember, it will only work when you
exactly during middle class blamed.
Don't use your training, execute feature
and put everything into it won't work
and then see three feature points
it identified
two feature find said
okay so it didn't get any error.
This feature finds busy error speed,
so just take the scored
user clicks on team option and employee.
We're done everything from here.
I'm going to copy this particular code.
Right.
So let me copy this. Steps in here
and I'm going to define the
So here.
Now I'm going to define. All right.
One particular thing, see,
Dragon is equal to group rate.
Let me run this part, not run a class.
Executed all the steps I took already.
Go into your go into your steps.
So let me add
another steps called here and
employee steps
correct and employee steps
and here I'm going to paste all the steps.
Not any four clicks on team option,
but we have this.
Look, this will not
we do have short list an employee feature
that you go.
It can go. Thank you, sir.
It's come to this guys
so far any question in this part
what we do
so far any questions?
No questions.
Shall we take the code?
That would be the code
for employee option from here.
Where we where do we go for promotion?
You see? There you go.
This is the promotion.
Let me
take the code from here and pasted here
it is giving me the error for driver.
What should I do in this case? Yes,
I have to experience
mine for common purpose.
Simple.
Another locator I need for added employee.
So let's go ahead.
Take this employee part.
And we caught this copy
and then I came here
with element ID
and like
sequence to try
to find many brand photo I.D.
This is the idea provided it.
We put myself here
and then an employee
don't click.
So far.
So look, everyone
nice.
It's quiet here
now I need work in me.
I need this particular part force
name, last name.
Right. And click on the option.
Fine.
It's click.
Here it is giving me ideas.
Post me.
I'm writing here
one element.
First name is equals per driver.
Don't find that in bygone IED
form.
In here.
The first name I'm going to provide.
Let's see.
I'm lost in an employee steps.
Man Where did you lost? Tell me.
These are the employee steps.
I'm not going to proceed further.
Tell me what you spoke in.
What is the issue
as well?
What is the issue here?
From where did you did all the quotes
nasal or how would you read this to me,
how we generated the steps.
That is how we generated the distance
command.
A man, Aisha
medina, has seen the man, Christine Lugo
Right.
So now what
we have to do when you add this
employee feature, right, you have to go.
Can you run that?
Because once you go
in, you run that last, right?
Just to make this right,
it is equals to true.
When you make this right is equals to
to execute this particular class.
When you execute in this particular class
you will get the code in your console
like this.
Once you get this code in your console,
copy this code
from your console
and pasted in employee steps.
That is the only thing we have to do
right now after this.
This beam option we already used
the already used in our employee
search systems.
This employee wouldn't be identified
just now.
This first name be identified
just now I'm going to exhaust.
And then also here similarly, right
now, you
know your good password.
Great.
You're welcome. Welcome.
So let me take
a modern Nancy.
No, like
for me.
Let me take the last name also from here.
The last name is my ID.
Last name.
But anyway,
last name is equals to driver or
point element by got a
last name.
Same keys. Right.
Never seen these names, correct?
Correct.
So now
it would take my name.
And this is the last thing I need
so far.
Any questions? Students
Three steps
we have implemented one two steps.
We copy paste those steps.
We execute the code.
We identify the code.
Let's proceed further.
Now we have to click on Save button.
We have to click on same button.
So let's go here and find this.
And also we got another article.
We did it fine.
Let's take this and put it here for
delivering.
See where it is able to drive
again.
I'm leaving this part.
As of now for associates,
I'm just rounding the employee and
just the guys so far.
And this is steps.
Any question
or everything is going to be one, then me
All good,
good, good.
Two times. Good break.
Let me go here see now my
every step is implemented correctly.
My every single step is implemented.
Let's try let's try to run this particular
fine now.
But on this particular point, I'm
intentionally executing this particular
fight
because there is a reason behind this
and employee note feature.
First, check
whether all these steps are implemented.
So I'm making Brighton is equal to two.
First, let's check.
It won't take much
it gave me thing
now means my steps are implemented.
Let's make it false
now run the actual class
in error.
The employee not
wait.
Got it. Cannot be intentionally edited.
If I give you the time,
you all will execute.
Now you have a me.
Now go ahead and make this side slow.
Go ahead.
And actually this gives it
some explains in the million times.
I don't need you I think you did my
I have done from my side.
All right
Martin problem
needs eight one solutions great so match
11 needs some unique ways.
Yes, ma'am.
Now I'm going to post this code.
I'm going to commit this code first.
Yes, it's one user only.
That is because we added one user on you.
Got it.
What kind of
now is of a liberty of days?
24 seconds write code is available. Yes.
Or big to the next malicious games
when we will understand it completely,
it really will make life easier.
Said Hey, just give me
one, two, three, four.
More classes after this. Read
hardly four classes, maybe four or five,
and then everything
would be completely understandable.
Yes, yes.
That everything is here.
Everything is yet I'm waiting.
I'm posting the slides also.
You see. Great.
I provided this late.
Let me show you In the course.
If I go for batch 11, you open the files
in the files.
Because the last one
was properly explanation of the framework
created the basics of.
But why?
So I consider the class
two as the class one.
That's what I
read.
Showing something else
we will create.
We will create multiple
multiple classes to including.
So now you'll see on Thursday
I provided as cucumber class one Redis.
You see this people provided.
So it's already here
and I will continue to play
more slides.
The system definition right
to do by next update.
We are still learning the specs. Correct?
We are still learning the text.
See, let's let everyone complete
and then we proceed for
your elements.
So basically, like I said, right,
if there is an any unreadable
and in the console they don't need to be,
but otherwise it will keep your console
as it is.
If it is already the console,
you are good.
Okay.
Are non-negative with me,
no quiz with me, just homework.
Alright. So you do homework.
You do practice three.
I have feed trade and I provide basically,
you know I'm here not to give a lot
so homework
when indeed grade beat something
efficiently
really when they check
all remains.
So you're happy with the more binary
now wait.
Oh yes, yes. So that is the object.
I will be taking your session on Sunday
will be taking or session or Tuesday
Wednesday and Xabi
Alonso will be taking on Thursday.
So important to you.
Once I will be available, I'm
going to need you to be working in there.
But if I take your to be one more name,
then just think Tuesday, Wednesday
already sessions, then Saturday, Sunday.
And if I make Monday, Tuesday,
Wednesday, Thursday again.
And then just one day paid in
then against it Davidson businesses
So it's late I'm leaving with my 11
even leave I don't think session imagine
even though it misses the chance right
in the middle back to the other classes
So there is no labor done.
It's all about where I'm wasting in you.
Labor, not investment.
Okay, So is everyone scored now working?
Definitely.
I would beg your sedation strike
and I will see what I can do in this case.
Everyone ask for Katoomba, Aisha.
Everyone ask for Google. Believe me
specifically, they're asking the inability
about candidates is yes, they said okay.
We went to an interview segment,
maybe assign someone nice.
Would big
the one that is you.
I mean, I know this name so long,
but it's a good name.
Just this addition. Last number is yours.
Fine.
Now, see,
see, another important thing here.
Then you take name of,
it's you.
And if you find a job of managers
think a computer would be used
for implementation. Great. Michaeli Great.
But to be honest, grade,
if you go in the market nowadays
and you ask for manual testing,
you won't even believe me.
Even if they want you to work
as a manual to the
We ask questions on automation
In interview,
they've been asked if they are Java,
they will ask know Selenium.
Gilbert Extend is a database
my skill database API everything.
And then in the end they will give you
an excel by to rate that is
they need
Superman
blade in the providing is a watchmen
that's what industries are doing
is this tool.
I mean I know this is weird even
when we hired people rate of menu testing
because our senior management says
hey we a person who is excellent
with people book and sometimes I think
why do we need a person?
Most people framework anyway in the end
we are going to give me one example
by the way they're test case is right
but it's going on in the market.
So that's why we have to ability
from all the perspective.
Okay.
And it's not going to happen.
But most of the times, many other times
you will get a job
and once you join rate,
there will be two scenarios.
Either they will give you
the good repository. Want it?
Go ahead, game the code.
There will be some good decisions,
knowledge transfer decisions
of some of the
some of the employees of your company
who is working already on yet you pass the
you the way they knew how things work.
What is the project of the code?
What is that a framework.
Everything that is wants in any
you will understand that you will learn
that and then you will write your code.
In that particular
scenario,
do you go to the company you joined?
The company, closed it, you have a
meeting, second day of a meeting.
Today you're meeting with your manager.
Your manager would say, Hey,
we do not have a commission.
That's why we hired you.
Knows that entity,
No said entity to the student.
That's why we hired you.
Because we do not have any permission
already.
Now we are relying on you
to setup your permission process.
So first thing that expecting from you
to create a plan for commission
make the framework is start
writing summer commissions
provide some B or C proof of concept
is considered Demo invite all of us in
your name will send us an email
and then we'll see how things work.
These are the two scenarios
we'll be having in the industry.
What do we do then?
I am here to invite you here.
I will explain.
It depends on it.
It depends.
If you're working for the bank,
then they will give you like
maybe 20 days
if you're working for a new project.
Right.
And yet they hired you
as an experienced person,
then they will give you more than one week
or two week.
But there will be by the time every day
gutting.
So they're making.
You could be familiar
with the new project, right?
Could three days.
Getting a job is difficult
and the job is not that difficult.
Once You get a job then anyhow.
Somehow you will survive in that.
You will survive in there.
And even if you faced some issue
that we are a here, why do we right.
But to get a job credit was the bait.
Remember, it's always
the first is every time
difficult to open once
you open the box to the in that bottom
is clear
cutting
fine.
Let's come to this point what I was
explaining See,
I have one feature right here.
I have one feature point here
only non. If I see those scenarios.
Two scenarios
for one scenario, how many scenarios?
I have a super
students.
Five Duplass.
Duplass what five Noble one scenario?
An employee
whose scenario here in employee served
and do scenario enlarging feature.
So two plus two is equals to four,
four plus one is equals four
pi and behave three feature phase
change
the database.
This is what we call spoon feeding
and this would
this Getty.
So now,
now, now we have three feature points,
five scenarios.
But the problem is the problem is
when I'm going to execute
with this portion,
with this portion, with this flash
break, with this glitch,
it will execute all the five scenarios
in a single track,
all the feature points,
all the five scenarios.
It is when to execute.
Now, let's think about the situation.
Smooth,
best guesses, integration, best guesses.
Maybe are working.
Let's see if we open this
in your sprint one rate.
Currently it is going on to sprint one.
What is the ideal
duration of your sprint days and
two weeks?
This is your sprint to
three
sprint for sprint by six.
Here you need five scenarios.
Here you edit things, images,
you may get 15 scenarios for example.
So by the end of Force two sprint,
how many scenarios
you have in your framework
days by the end of August five,
but by the end of the weekend,
Sprint culminates in Adios.
You have to be
by the end of the sprint three How many
scenarios you have now in your bucket?
30 No.
Now your lead came when your lead asked
how many scenarios you worked
on this particular of sprint.
Please execute.
I want to those only those
who completed in the spring three
Currently
when looking at this particular part
that are looking at this particular part,
can you see is there any place through
which you can execute on those scenarios
and leave
the remaining 51
with this existing part?
Can you see anything
you think means there is no segregation?
There is no reason for everything
that you make another package included?
No. What I really would option
this give you more options
is find the use bag.
Use Dag.
So find. Come here.
Right. Come here and ready.
For example, I want to execute.
Only those scenarios
belong to my best guesses.
Industrial only
those scenarios belong to my best guesses.
So what I have to do?
I have to write your entry.
Spoke
for after eight days.
Here. Let's see if the red
application, for example.
It could be anything.
Similarly go in another class.
Also another feature also
give them their take an important entry.
Let's see.
This is my integration.
You take this one also.
This is also my painting.
This one also.
This is also what you see integration.
Correct? Ready?
Where to be ready?
We come here.
So now I grouped all of my scenarios.
Got it
raised.
I know which scenario is going to smoke.
Scenario is going to regression with
scenario is going to one
particular battery.
I grouped all of this in that is on the
every scenario is grouped here.
For example, if this scenario
is a part of your regression
and you're working on this scenario
in your current sprint,
it means you're supposed to add
to text for your simplicity, correct?
Correct.
Right.
So now here what you would do,
simply just read another day
and play like this
another day and provide like this
another take and provide
something like this,
whatever that you want to add.
You can simply add multiple to the
in that you understood
industrial base,
you can add multiple or your one scenario
based on this type of extension
makes sense.
Makes sense.
Yeah. I'm going equally.
I'm going make big still.
I would feature but you say still
I would be able to go there.
Sequence doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter.
Like I said, it's
all depending on the linking it.
Timber is worked on linking part
three.
So now for example,
I have a multiple take rate, multiple data
everywhere.
Now let's go to another class.
We don't need to do anything.
Just put one more comma
and there is another take on things.
Double quotes
the way in which you want to run.
Smoke point.
I misspoke.
Which one?
You want to run?
Regression find to
and so on.
Understood.
So now see this time.
What about this
index? It is deprecated.
It is deprecated.
I already told you.
You see,
if I put it here like this is
it is equals to true.
Can you see the call.
Same rate.
The main which is getting this
district is equal to two and false.
So it is deprecated.
No, we don't need to rate. That's
what I'm saying.
We don't need to.
So first like that idea takes will
identify the scenario
based on that you re
provide
a right to the
features.
Three Just
how to convert duplex
first moment, let me complete
the one thing and I will come with it.
Why you always ask questions
a step further.
It ultimately makes other students
confused.
Okay, so I'm just taking everybody
into consideration.
Yeah.
On the last the last point played,
the last thing which we are adding,
for example, featured is the mask.
Then we don't need to add a comma
because in the last we don't need a comma.
Now don't use your own statement.
Everyone put full stop.
In the end, it will not work.
Keep it as it is on read and might.
Some people will use their brain
and then say Oh well, and put full stop.
No, I know you're good at English,
but don't do this here. No
features blue
in monochrome text
so far.
Is it okay everyone.
So far?
Is this okay?
Nice.
Should be executed.
Now let's see now what is this structure?
What sentences?
Sentences in the feature?
I'll go all the feature points.
Big check the steps
for all the feature points.
Remove all the information,
which is an element
from consortium and execute
only those scenarios.
Having this is moonpig great
great guys.
Let's execute.
Execute this.
How many?
This was Grace.
Do videos.
Sebastian, come on.
This is the feature for any name.
No one says none.
Guys, let's arrange a meeting.
I would like to see
every one of you in person.
I will definitely complete this,
even if I have to get all this.
I have to pay a hefty price
for the tickets.
And they need to be.
I want to meet everyone.
I mean, nice guys, nice beyond
imaginations, Great.
No, no, that's fine. That's fine.
If same location connect.
No, no.
I asked because I didn't.
I didn't ask in your
system how many times it executed.
I answered here only in my system
because I'm showing my system.
So obviously I will ask you
to look at my screen
and then how many executed it,
seeing it specifically here, it overall,
it wasn't executed.
Right.
It came
and then it shows the method name also.
That's what I was asking.
Someone says none.
And I was shocked that here
I can see the result.
Here is the name ME.
Someone says to read this one point
B initial log in.
Sure.
See, this is what we have.
Log in picture
is the best.
Me is the best quality.
Excellent.
What he does what you did today.
Make another?
Yeah. He.
It's going to be nine zero. Good
And then he didn't add it It's big
this fine
so far so look
everyone
sitting
time to learn
another important stuff. No,
no. Come here again.
Going to the class.
I'm executing a lot of things.
Like,
where is my report?
I am executing the art of things,
but that is my report.
Where do you see any where the report?
No, not yet.
Generated, Maybe Target?
No. Now see, what do campuses do?
What is very smart to go overseas?
You don't need to look anywhere
about the reports, right?
Anywhere about the reports.
First, you have to generate the report.
What have to do.
What we have to do
is we have to generate the report.
And when we actually generate
the report right, we will define it.
This place
report should be generated. Okay.
So for now, see what we are going to do.
We are going to add one
plugin in the options again, comma
prepared me see
what I'm going to do and plugin right
then open and close this is because
we will actively people like it straight.
That's why I'm reading you just one thing,
not your favorite word.
We are going to use the first word.
We are going to use as
what we are going to use
pretty
why we use this
pretty keyword regenerate the report.
All right.
On rainy days in logging,
we this word PDB now the
yes yeah
now again I'm going to use
and see what kind of report it will report
find when I say been targeted
by what name could go very dark.
I'm going to generate a report.
We also use ugly.
Then you will get ugly report.
Don't blame me.
So here is the estimate report
I need in target.
So the legal.
Can you see this target folder?
Everyone?
Can you see this target folder
right inside this target folder.
People in particular.
Not a team report.
Okay.
In the use
another category. No. For one. No.
There is an
intention to do this in target
I any of that.
I will tell you
what is the intention of using in future
in other classes that I repeat.
Yep. Yep.
Yeah. Yes.
So now now this time
when I execute my good
to see this time going to execute so far
any any question in this plugin pervades
what I'm doing
for you just to basically board.
After that we will clear
we will generate multiple reports.
Very good.
But for now, just go with this report.
No, see, I'm going to run
again.
Where did you get the link in 25
bullet.
I did get this target for that.
It is generating
it generating automatically.
Yes, yes, yes.
I will commit.
I will commit nobody.
I'm just showing this thing. Good.
So now see, it got executed
so 130 line number 25 this link.
There is no link.
No one.
That's what I'm seeing.
See, I need a stable report.
So I wrote a story.
I need a target folder.
So I wrote Target
and then I provide in target folder.
I need to do HTML report.
So I put slash HD with made bullet.
Where did you get the target folder?
It's generated by default.
It is not in your project.
It should be in your project was taken
days after executing.
Let me reload my project from the disk.
When I did my project
and when I open my got to beautiful you
can you see
Nickolay non negativity
non-gaming point everybody there does
see good position is going on rate
everything is going very smooth
you're one word can destroy everyone's
piece
take up this
I'm going to be
a friend of the zoo Every other animal
train would get distracted
otherwise we'll be a lion each others
how to crawl.
It's also works with driver.
Why do you need report wilderness? You
I got team behind everyone.
What do you mean
by trying to become better team?
I have better.
So you're executing it
Employee feature please check in
employee feature with that.
This is not.
I believe you do not have this look. Did
you put up two features?
Only read the manga we made nauseous.
We got this good to fresh
geometric pokemon but in their target
folder right?
Right.
Just right click on this report.
Right click on the report
open in browser Chrome.
And then you did the same thing.
Almost your entire group, the same thing.
Be right click open in browser,
open it in Chrome.
Now you'll see.
Now you'll see this part.
It says it is past scenario.
Great.
This is name server
operating system duration
could be paused one scenario
for scenario three
I would know. See
which scenario is bundled.
So the login feature is must beg
and then it is smoke deck light scenario.
Well lobby.
These are all the steps right?
It shows me the operating system.
Mine is an event.
I don't know whether it's
not of digital 11 or work Spy.
It is
60 forward processor So this point now
see every step red.
You see the green peak.
It means every step straight.
It is green, it's clear.
And you see
now only, isn't it
the correct report to share it
with your management in causing death
culminate this because as you execute it
in this particular discipline begins
and please show this report
it is already to this right now.
Let me do it
now. Let me do it for ignition.
Big week.
It means it means the people
after small create.
When it was searching for smoke,
two in one it got smoke in four.
It didn't get the smoke.
So these are total fights in one.
One did good.
Now see what I'm going to do here.
I'm going to change this day to.
Integration,
integration, and now
I'm going to execute it.
How to open? Yeah, I'm.
I'm going to show you
just now I'm going to open another one.
Just give me a moment.
Make me insecure.
Discord first.
What that means, according to their take,
it means it was searching
for all the scenarios for the smoke bag.
And in those scenarios
it got one smoke that would mean
one in the meaning for one unknown
because there was no input we provided
whether it is integration or work.
Yes, it will.
It will. It will.
What regulation in my guess is smoke
doesn't
because Nick, what are you need to wait
and it is because as the
smoke went explode is not running
or maybe you didn't provide penalty.
So once you put where you provided
the light.
No, just put you
keep your part in features slash
and then it will work work.
Yes. Yes,
we can do that. We can do this. I
what if we
rename the smoke one
and then again for the duration.
The decompression will reportedly
want know that they would want they want.
But we don't need to do
all of these things.
That's what I'm saying.
We don't need to do all of these things.
We have lot more good options
in decompression.
It was just I'm telling you
one options are the one thing.
Like I said, after a couple of time,
after a couple of glasses you will see
and then you will get confused.
Which option I showed you was
Every option is pretty nice.
Yes, correct. Try.
So this time,
if we go ahead and do the project
from this
in that I'm going to open it.
So see now Alex eight click
open in
browser Chrome.
Now can you see
there is an employee feature employee
search feature logging feature
right now
you'll see execution somebody then menus
for only one unknown
because one was selected to smoke correct.
So it fine not infotech integration
and you see
open this,
open this right
it gives all the right things
open this one also you'll see
both those scenarios available here
right with regression take they open
this one also, it gives you the detail
of this scenario as well.
So now every single scenario,
along with the detail of every step
and with this status,
whether it is buzzword made available here
in this achievement report, so far,
so good.
Everyone
is that anyone
who has any question
in this particular code,
anyone who has any question
question, we're going to get it.
This isn't going to
don't don't do anything.
No, please, no, don't respect.
They're not the beginning.
We will be able to.
And I do mean that a lot to remember.
That's what framework is all about, right?
It doesn't need your intelligence.
It needs your focus
right.
If you know what are the things
you have to implement in the framework
next.
If I keep the meeting,
the code name names in the class, ma'am.
And it would be difficult, right.
But like we're doing
after training every single step.
So it means it seems like I'm
committing the code, but there's like a
you I'm going.
What happens is
sometimes if I come with the code
and let's say something slipped on my mind
and the code is incomplete,
then everyone get an incomplete code.
So this is also dangerous.
I mean, we should not do this
content on this.
We are done with the complete task,
but let's do it for now.
Fine, fine.
Because we do know everything is okay.
This should be possible for that.
Is it one type of report of the auditor's
report also.
So one, we do this one by one, right?
So I was about to expand this point based.
Right now we have only one plugin.
Great for the reports.
In future
we will add more plugins for that.
We will add more plugins
for different because this
why we make extremely poor.
Do we have any other option?
What can we make?
Except for the board?
You need to take simply.
Oh, you learned one credit report
or something.
Read to me on this word. Yes. Yes.
You remember that report?
Actually the final report
this that asking the question in this word
and excel by No, sorry, we do not have
any API to call this kind of things.
These are the forms supported
by good conversion rate.
So when we say the forward
supported by what we can do
only this things,
we can not create any excellent report
automatically.
Right.
And again, unless we have an API come
and Ms.
Word has nothing to do with it.
No might be a quite poor thing.
And for in this word alright it is.
Even though it is a ms.
word online
and this word based top application.
But to get it is not integration of Ms.
word with your particular part.
That's when nowhere
but you simply can generate just one word
that we will generate.
We can generate a multiple
they get in Greek.
Okay, so these are more graphical
reports, right?
You see this information.
Right. It's pretty much clear information.
What we are seeing here,
this is very pretty much consolidated
information.
Now, if it does this is prepared for,
if you call this estimate,
it just put these things details
into that forward and gives you
this cutting, cutting.
So simply we have to use this
general report is of no
industrial so far
which link
are not it is it is
it belongs to my local.
You also have this link grade.
You also have this link in yours.
So we can't share this report
link to anyone, right?
We can take the screenshot of it
and we can put
any. It's going to be work on your local
to get the consolidated report.
You need to execute it
locally, Put it in one report.
Take this to be paid
for your global report.
We have another tool great for that
we don't have to was
we have to stop
executing everything on Google and
we have to institute everything on cloud.
That's what we have to do.
So for cloud version, we have separate
reporting structure there.
We just click on cloud
and it gets automatically
same to everyone, but everyone there.
It's a different sort of that
we already have known for.
They will talk about that, but also.
Okay, great.
Now basics. So focus on basics.
It's going to be work
on your local network is going to
find instruments.
Shall we proceed for that?
So far everything is clear,
Everything is good.
So now,
now see, now see what I'm going to
write to keep this up.
So keep this here. Also
from here onwards, change should work.
No, no, no. You shall.
You should. You must.
You will share, should, must, will.
All right.
We can share them.
Yes, yes, yes, we can share with.
We can share with everybody
all of this things.
How we can share the
current
with half of my brain.
Are you guys tired?
You need a break for one minute,
60 seconds
with our break and then we'll start.
Okay.
Let me stop the recording
frame.
Very interesting thing.
I would do this.
You see
any any
event, talk about
these five steps in.
These five steps
right in this length to determine
how many steps are gone.
First,
for example, you see here, given you
that is never going
to a gentleman's application,
given you that is maybe going
to duplicate him as the politician getting
now witnesses.
When you letting this video
is this username and password
and here it is been user interface
related admin to username and password.
So this this step is common among
the initiative was not common.
So we have to find we have to find
let's see another scenario
just for consideration and see.
Let's take another scenario.
So this in any undertaking,
I'm taking another scenario here
that it really should find.
This scenario I'm thinking is
not just consider for a reason.
Right.
And another scenario, anyway,
just to explain, you
know, expert mobility,
I'm saying in employee.
So something this something like this.
See how many scenarios I have no guys home
in this scenario, scenarios I have
foreseen and use
in this all scenarios.
Do you see my starting a step?
You see my starting step is can you see
here is a step business steps.
And after this step,
my next state is different.
Enable is in any correct
correct.
So when my from the point from the point
where my steps is changing,
domestic is different.
It means from this point I will keep this
code as it used in my scenario. Why?
Because might be possible
when my step is changing.
That after
the next step will also be changed.
Right?
If the step
is standing, it means code is changing.
But before date, whatever the steps I see,
these steps are common
here, here, here also.
And you know these steps are common.
So it doesn't make sense
to write a step again and again
and again in every scenario.
Isn't it a good idea if I have just one
something where I put this particular
step in one place and this is step
will run for my entire feature? Why?
Mark my words,
I will keep this step in one place
that will run for my entire feature.
It means only applicable to this feature
by not for all the other feature points.
Make sure this point the support everyone.
So now
then about no common feature.
So that's the problem with you
know on just let me complete
so now
now when you realize and when you see
when you see any step
which is common among all the scenarios
in particular
a feature find, you identify that step
you have to keep that particular
step in one keyword
guide big.
What do you have to do
to keep that state in your income
and the industry? This
Now see what I'm going to do now.
See what I'm going to.
Let me delete this step from here.
Now, we are not going to a
we are to reduce the code.
We are we are moving to reduce the code,
to increase
remove this, remove this
and remove this.
So on the same thing you can do
for any number of scenarios.
Understood.
These two scenarios are just scenarios.
It has nothing to do.
So I'm going to delete
this in any case. Now see
this background part what it does,
this big chrome
will work for this scenario.
So first how it works that we should
if I write something in background right.
So if I'm writing the
step common
and then I have similar you
and then I understand that you
scenario one and scenario two.
So what happens?
First,
it will execute this background step,
then execute this scenario, then again
execute big time
and then execute this scenario.
It means before this finale,
you in this scenario
this is steps
will execute in this background
will applicable
for your particular feature.
Find this to this point
big ground is applicable
to particular feature.
Right
which will execute before every scenario
almost like before method kind current
thing getting background
understood.
Now companies employ such feature that
you will see the actual essence of this
not in me.
These are steps changing
when you are implemented employ
and when user interest will employ me
before this.
How many are common?
Five is steps are common, but not any
day cycle.
Steps are common.
Just remove this five steps from here
and put it in the
big task.
Remove this five steps from here.
Now see, my scenario gets shorter,
isn't it?
So that way if you have multiple
scenarios in each five and then you see
a lot of normal seamless steps, rate them
available, This is exactly what I wanted.
All right.
And now you've got it right.
So now what
if this so much cleaner
getting to correct?
And that's what I'm saying.
If you allow me for a couple of classes,
you will get every single
answer to one of your questions.
All right.
I still remember. Take a screenshot
method.
Strongly
believe that I will definitely implement.
I still
remember maven part compiler source.
I will explain.
I remember all of those points,
but if I extend those points as of now
it is of no use.
So there is a particular series of steps
that should follow.
Index would be one of the great
so far so good.
With this point students,
can we jump in slip common lines?
No, no. It should be in the flow.
See, this is the flow
and then it is coming, right?
This is the flow
and then it is coming straight.
If you jump in between,
then you're breaking the flow.
And if you're breaking the flow,
it means you're playing with
the application in an appropriate way.
So it's not going to work.
It's not going to be in there.
All right.
Then you have something for the end
line to use or close the browser.
We are going to go in there.
We are going to hold your horses. Read
one thing, one thing, background in
background,
and no point of editing background.
As of now, the only native drawings
because we have just one scenario
after something will add
nasty.
Nasty.
Let me execute this log in scenario.
Let's check
whether it is executing or more
so intentionally.
I'm going to write this logging
non feature
and here this is the regulation take.
If we copy this, take and put it
in, put it.
Here is the regression.
It also read
what a beautiful horse
the manuscript.
Nice look, It is small.
It is a killer.
Very cute
case.
It is equal trade for both the test plane
validates
it executed for both the test
with background keyword.
So background keyword is applicable.
Let me put this into the notes.
It only moves
in there.
Another class trade class.
I did all the things, the features
I extended definition is available,
the new definition is available.
This it in
both bags
linings is bring everything is available.
This reduced definition is this then
make it
applicable
only for
feature length only for
one feature. Find
your own
common is on all this is
so you can
you should log in which feature yes
shows of is to get you
now guys see
you will see this one
additional error here
can you log in picture
this are additional error.
No everyone
click on it
click on it and you're just given use.
It is navigating
to a gentleman's application.
See it is showing you
what this states is available
here, which is going to execute this one
and this one.
Similarly, you go here,
you will see this steps are available
here also.
This is steps are available.
I don't have they did
what are you here to execute
you get the
data.
Congratulations
then error doesn't matter. Yes.
Yes. Correct.
It is just additional info I'm giving.
Great.
But if you know
the meaning of become blank, there's
more than enough
nosey guys here.
Here in this is step
background is steps are different
but when you go in employ
search here you'll see background
the steps are different correct.
Why is it so?
Because your background is changing class.
A feature to feature
one feature is different.
In another feature it is different trait.
So actually in our bedroom
we are identifying only those steps
which are common among all the scenarios
in one particular picture place
in one particular feature.
Right?
No, no. If you have just one
just because then what is the reason?
Good big company.
Like I said, among all the scenarios,
among all these scenarios,
if we have steps common Yeah, yeah.
That's
what I'm giving you the clarification.
So when we a common two steps in one
scenario, we can not have common states
minimum rules in areas
we need to have made some things
which are common, which are not common
streams.
So far so good.
Everyone
come with this code.
Also a beautiful one.
Massive.
This is what we call real will be
excellent.
Fine guys.
So I think I'm
then from my today's session
if you guys have any question
you can ask or we can have a big plus.