Fine guys.
So we are in the class Board of debates.
Right.
So far in the remaining three classes,
we have underscored all the basics of MBA.
What are the operations
we have to perform and we can perform.
What kind of exercises?
We need to perform those operations
via MBA?
What is public MBA?
What is private API?
What is biggest?
How we can understand
is a strategic protocol.
What all under methods
we have in the protocol, correct?
What is payload?
How we train the body in the decent?
What are the other performance
rate your API accept
and then in the response what all are
the things we should look forward to?
What are the API is pretty good.
We should go with how we didn't
generate the token.
What is a stateless application?
What is stateful application?
All these things we have covered so far
in these topics, what we have covered
in the last three classes.
If you guys have any question,
please ask our
we are going to start this class today,
not only from the guest
but also from Awakening region
so that the banks which we are going
to cover in activities class right.
That you guys won't be any problem
to this.
That is getting my point
could be more explain fine
but you have to guess for me
if you had give it to me
in that I'll explain again
and prefer chocolate one
all rain.
So let me start from here.
This is what we have in class before.
Will start with it again.
Then we guys cookies from third party.
Yes. Excellent.
The moment I started the Class
Einstein mindset comes in the picture late
one cup unsalted butter low soften
one and a half cups,
sugar, two large eggs, two disciplined
vanilla, two and a half cup glory.
Amazing.
There's some women cookies
and install it in our software, right?
So that we can capture all the data
and then use it for prediction algorithms
so that we can use them for advertisement.
Amazing.
Nice.
Maybe you are the most strongest candidate
in this base
to become the next president of us, right?
See the mindset exactly like
Donald Trump.
Like is when things alone getting
fine.
All right.
Very valuable by them in the class.
Critical.
Also, Google nice
then it's
kind of
looks busy fine
but it is then is really
learning of the
nice loading
today we needed the most I know so loaded
Whenever I ask you to have my ready,
just come.
Uh, yeah.
I like your favorite ones.
No, I.
Katrina,
I was about to ask yourselves, but.
Right.
So your normal exception yet
also my favorite one.
I was about to ask you.
And suddenly your beard.
That's great.
I'm in a very good mood.
That's why I didn't is to load it.
Yes, ma'am. Yes, if I got a haircut.
Thank you.
Thank you, ma'am.
Exactly. Exactly.
Every single student in this class,
all these 92 members,
you all are my brothers and sisters.
Don't worry again
by well, let's time
already.
So tell me, what was the first topic
we covered in ideas for this class?
What was that?
Nice.
Let's take to the Class
Tom Specular topic.
What was the first topic we covered
exactly
the process of authentication
and authorization.
This is something extremely important
that we need to understand, right?
So the first thing is, the first thing is
authentication and
one crazy
authorization point is
what is the meaning of authentication?
Or both are seen authentication
or authorization.
No order not seen. Right?
So what is the difference?
What is authorization?
Let's start with authentication first.
What is authentication?
Sticking it to verify?
Is your identity correct? Who you are
getting
it verifies
it really buys your identity
and who you are.
Are you a on the system?
And if your database returns
with the response that, yes, this
particular user is a part of our system,
then authorization comes into play
right after verifying your identity
authorization, we come straight.
So what is the meaning of authorization?
What exists?
You have correct.
What exists you have for the system.
So basically,
I told you yesterday four questions
you need to ask yourself
when it comes to authorization
and authentication,
what are those four questions?
The first question is who are you?
My I am. So help us.
Yes. Show your ID.
Correct.
I will allow you to access the system.
Yes. Are you allowed to access the system?
Find out the question.
Exactly.
And the fourth one is
what excuses you have.
So what exist You have.
So these are the four questions, right?
This is nothing but the crux of your
authentication and authorization process.
Right?
If you know these four questions,
it means you are covering your compute
authentication and authorization process
or experience
clear.
How is this clear?
Is this clear?
Perfect.
After that, what was the next topic?
We covered?
Token.
So guys, tell me when we deal with token,
whenever we are working with
work to work
with, is tech less an application?
Is Stateless Application
Stateless Application.
We need we need tokens, right?
We need tokens to work with stateless
application.
We need token. Fine.
Now, when it comes to token,
how many types of token we know
three types of tokens we have, right?
Three times of what are these
three types of token
is the first is beta.
Correct.
But the second is make tokens
sixth position next is Mac
token and the third one is grants grams.
Right.
So the beta, the Mac and the drinks,
these are the three types of tokens
we generally deal with.
Stateless application party.
Correct?
Correct. Fine.
Fine, fine.
Now, after this,
after this BNA Mac and Grams,
tell me which one we are going to use.
We are going to work with beta token.
We are going to work with beta, but
now tell me guys, how are we choosing
the tokens based on what?
Basically based on your application.
All right.
What is the structure
and the architecture of your application
and what kind of token
your application accepted?
So the majority of application,
except the beta token,
when it comes to API testing, remember,
if you're dealing with your UI part,
when you're working with web applications,
you will not be able to see any token
you're not be able to see anything,
any excuses, rate anything.
We only see all
these things when we work with API.
Getting my point will be
fine.
So in beta token, in better token, we have
we have how many books we have,
how many, but three parts separated
by, separated by full stop.
Right.
So we have three parts, right?
Three parts separated by dots.
What are these three parts
we have?
Then we have been Node
and then we have signature,
right?
We have three parts
per billion and signature file,
not aggregates in header
for the further in header.
We have two parts.
What are those two?
The first is the most is type of spoken
and then the second is
algorithm
is assigning algorithm rate, assigning
algorithm algorithm it is used.
So I think algorithm statement
right
now, after this, after this,
when we talk about header
to be happy load in our book,
So what is Node
rate?
We have several claims in it.
We have several claims in it. Right.
So what are these claims?
We have first issuer who is the issuer.
Correct.
The expiry date, 80 days expiry time.
Then we have subject,
then we have audience.
We have all this information.
Now, when we talk about signature,
what is signature
rate, we find that the message
which is actually conveying
has been conveyed correctly.
And it was not changed, right?
It was not changed.
So verify that the message
that the message
wasn't the change was wasn't the change.
While can be
right guys
now tell me when the when we talk
about the fourth thing header in this
we got one part type of token.
So what is that type of token
we are dealing with?
We are dealing with JWT, right?
JWT means JSON, RAM token
case.
Kazim I is this point in yesterday's
class as well
that we have
a very less amount of information here.
That's why I didn't put it in this blue
check art.
But yes, after that class
I will definitely put so to date
in this class I will definitely put
excellent and superb.
It looks delectable,
mouthwatering, delicious, amazing
place.
You need more synonyms a little bit
on rainy days.
So just some web tokens.
So far so good.
Everyone
screams
cool place.
Some one is so cool.
Amazing.
All right,
Best now after this. After this.
When we actually got the token,
when we did Hold on.
We are we were thinking all retirement
like continue, please continue this.
If anyone wants to join or not,
you guys can also go ahead.
So by the time I completed comes,
it would be great.
You finish everything.
I know, I know.
You know,
you guys are expecting a collision
from honey.
All right,
So after the JSON, the token rate
when we actually created the token
by creating the token,
first thing is we need credentials
which credential we use.
We use admin credentials.
Right now there is there is a logic behind
this, but what is that logic?
So Wednesday when we talk about
create operations, right,
to add something in the record
to better record in their database
to delete a record from their database
or to update or play with their data,
which is available in their database,
but even to retrieve some information
from their database. Right.
This all under the operations,
you can now do a normal use of.
Right?
You can not interrupt anything
with the data or interpret
the data related to any of
them. One, you can't do this
right?
Right. Okay.
Only only one user can do
all of these things to me.
And always remember
when you test your application,
majority of times, 90% of times
the very first test
you perform in this environment,
you use admin credentials.
It doesn't matter
whether you talk about your white part,
you talk about API bar
to talk about your database part, right?
Everywhere, everywhere.
You know, in my admin user, you verify
it, checks all the functionalities
and then for a specific type of scenario
after that,
you use a specific type of users.
Is it
is indicates to fine.
So that's why for generating
the JSON were broken here
in both
when we are using admin credentials.
Right
so now once we got the token once we got
is just a token, what is the next thing
we have done when we got the token then
after getting the token,
what is the next thing
first?
First, we are considering that
there is nothing in the database
available, so if I have nothing
in the database available first
I have to add some and that determines
that I need to get that value
and be able to change the value,
delete the value.
Whatever the operation I want to perform,
I can perform on that particular value,
which I'm going to do first
if I don't have anything and I'm trying
to access their data from their database,
it doesn't make any sense to me.
Right.
So should we close the backup before work?
Backup forward, create in order
should because to become.
I didn't know you don't need it.
You don't need to do that.
This is in your and your data right
You can do whatever you want to do
and they always give you, you know,
the distinct beach, the listing page,
basically requesting the data.
So then you should not claim
to be production here looking to load.
But we always see that is there is data,
everyone knows it right
And we perform our testing
using tested only
we never used really on testing.
Yes you can consider that there dumping.
You can consider that
fine.
So now now to create a user,
to create a user,
what is the next thing you have to do
based on to create a user to post?
We need to read Swiger document
to get all the instructions
and the information
from the particular document
that what all are
the things we need, right?
So to create a user,
be a user,
we need first thing what we need based.
You want to write, we need this other.
Then second thing we need to work
on that.
We need to create an employee
that would be more relevant
to create an employee
base.
You are right again thing we need is
able method
type of method.
Fine.
Then we need
to be load or body
onboarding.
Right?
Then we have to understand
what are the things we need
to boss in the body.
And after that
I have to provide headers, headers
not after header.
We need to provide authorization, right?
So there is a having pools in there.
We will use authorization and right.
And in authorization
we will provide the token
correct.
These are the things we need
to create one particular employee.
Understood.
And once, once we get once
we are generated,
the employee created the employee,
we get the spawn squad.
What is the response?
What we get after ending
a record in the database, we get to zero
one created
as gets to zero one
created event. It.
Now after getting this,
after creating the record, the next thing,
the next thing we will do is get an employ
get and I'm not saying I'm not saying
get all employee I say get and it means
just one employee getting.
So just one employee is the one which one.
The one
which we just added in the database.
Correct.
Microphone
and see what happened
to one of the initial
names.
And I already went to everyone.
Now Vendor All right.
I have started to
speak slowly. That's the way
right?
No, no, no issue that next. No issue.
It's totally fine because it shows
that you are actually listening.
For example, Stephen, by the way.
Thank you.
Fine.
Grace
was was further.
Exactly.
That is exactly.
No, sorry.
No room for sorry.
Late. Late, late. Exactly.
Only BS sake.
So when it when it comes to get
an employee rate, when it comes to get
an employee information, tell me guys,
what all are the things we need here.
What is the very first thing
we need to get an employee
base?
You are kind of this.
You are then
we need a type of method.
Type of method.
What is the type of method?
This is great method.
Then we need it.
There is nobody, right?
We need parameters. Which better minutes.
Angelica.
Which parameter?
We need? No, no.
First remember, we need ready
parameter.
We need query barometer,
and then whatever the value
it is being defined, there,
the particular value we need.
So it is a great parameter.
We need correct.
I will tell you what is getting better,
which I don't,
but we will cover this in today's class.
But I hope you understood it
at this point.
Basically,
what type of method query parameter?
What is the next thing we need?
Yes, we can use header also,
but this is optional because here we are
not providing anybody.
So we can use header but not not many.
Demand query
could be anything developers put in there
that yes, in Equity
barometer did this query barometer.
But remember one thing I assure
that when we talk about
a specific identity to any user,
so the name could be multiple
date of birth could be seen.
First name, last name we didn't
name could be same job title,
position designation, nationality
could be same employ.
I could not be same.
It should be different.
It should be unique. All right.
So here when we are seeing that, okay,
I need information from the database
or database with ask, I have a lot of
information which one you need.
So I we did
this is the particular specific
identity of the information
I want to date, Right.
So that particular identity
we need to provide,
which is unique in the database,
what is that uniqueness.
The uniqueness is your employer ID,
which is unique to every single employee.
The moment you change
an employee, ideas of change getting.
So that's why we will need
another thing is here. Here
authorization token
we need authorization to continue correct.
Now tell me guys here, when we talk about
response, what is the response we get?
So whatever the query in.
So I got to be used.
Got it.
Know what swagger is are viable of API
blindly follow the document,
don't use know
follow the follow document whatever the
instructions you are getting from there,
just take those instructions, implement
it, you verify the design and then going
in. I'm finding validating the
and providing more
and more complete from the testing.
Say there use this don't
create requirement from your own
requirement from did something
to zero zero. Okay.
And this is the status code
API status code in response we get the
if we are getting this particular one,
we will understand it.
All right, fine.
It is working. Absolutely. Okay.
Got it.
Everyone, after this.
After this, we got one more thing.
Get all employee correct.
Get all employee.
This is also we did yesterday. Then we
would read it or not get all employee.
Right.
So again, again, we need
all of these things except just one thing.
What is that we don't need here?
Query better.
Why we don't need query better
and we don't because
we are going to target
the complete bunch of information.
I don't want any specific information.
I need all the information.
So when it comes to ask
for the complete information, we not
we are not going to provide
any query better.
Correct.
So here also in response, in response here
also we will get what
do the one zero
or just to scoop.
So now now if you look at this particular
part here,
if you look at this particular
part so far, what we did here
from the credit operations
we created, we retrieve this through
the not right
quanta.
Is this prudent or not?
So how many left
just to
complete this joint APAs or was
let's compare this to an eBay or
guess. Yes.
Today is the last glass
of your manual API.
From Tuesday
we will start your API automation.
Rest assured
how we should
to check the engine employs
to avoid the errors later on.
That is good.
I will tell you that API with Java
just gathering them.
You play with Java.
All right.
Very simple one.
Believe me. Yes.
Correct. Correct.
Correct.
For the API classes,
but for automation. Right.
If we keep working on manual,
then definitely will not be complete
API classes.
But we can automate.
I am I not I think with correct based
with complete coverage
with full explanation, with exact
information, with proper satisfaction.
Understood.
So don't worry about reports.
I'm taking care and I will take care.
So now.
Now the only one or the one operation
is left for gaining the employee status.
You'll see if I go
and if I open this particular part,
you see, get employed
and get all employee done
these to remove any good job title
and get employment status.
It is no one exception.
It is not one exception.
We have to use simple different end point.
That's it. Because this is a good one.
So let me copy the this you want.
I promise you
I go and I am going to add
new request.
Go get.
What is that?
You get employee status.
Fine. So
get employee status.
Let's take first
this one, then get employment
status.
Fine. If we change it to employ
maid, that's good employment status.
All right.
Next week we have to generate a new token.
Yes, I still am coming to that point.
Do they already provide a token?
I didn't draw it to contract,
so I'm coming to that point.
No, no worries.
Nobody. Sebastian,
At least you are a week next.
A good part.
So tell me, guys who get the employment
status, What are the things I should do?
Anybody?
Students
Do we need any header which is mandatory
doing it Authorization.
But my token, which I created yesterday,
having the expiry time
for how many hours?
12 hours.
So it must be, it must be the new one
which I'm going to use
because this one is already expired.
So let me generate the new token.
See, I got new token.
This is the new token which I
generated correct,
The new token which I generated.
So let me copy this new token
and let me based this token here.
So what I will do straight from here
better be token.
And then here I object this token.
Fine.
Let me quickly
update this token everywhere
because my token gets expired
from all the request.
Right.
So just to avoid any conflict and we would
claim
so now, now you see now you see here
when I object to my token headers body,
all the things,
whatever the things I need to get
the information, everything I have
now tell me when I get the response,
what should I expect in the API or discord
in this case?
What should I.
I should accept 200. Okay, got it.
So let me send the request.
See all the employment status
you see here.
Independent contractor freelancing,
0 hours, contract, part time employee,
seasonal employee, summer time
employee, active employee contract.
Everything you see
here, read all the employment status.
We can see correct
you guys can use, see everyone
point.
Let me save all of this information post
here.
Getting it is getting over somewhere.
Right right.
Fine days now now let's go a step back.
Alright, let's go a step ahead.
So what we have to do is after
create operation done
after create operation done
after retrieve operation done right, just
one more division operation is remaining.
What is that?
What is see case employment
status is done.
We are going to get only
the job data correct.
The job title is pending.
So let's complete this job and also first
and then we will proceed further.
So you see
there is no parameter required here also
right in the response code.
Also you see
there is nothing required, right?
We just need to select the type of method,
the end point and the base.
You want to do this all we need.
So now if I go in my postman,
I'm going to add a new request.
And the request name should be Get the Job
opens.
I'm going to provide it here.
This right
race token I can pick from here.
So this is my token.
But recently, recently
dendritic token I have
I have to select a beta token
and then I can simply update this locally,
replace anything else
I initiated to get information.
Anything internally can be
stressed.
No. Right.
So now forced to let me
save it and let me send this
in. You see we got a status quo 200.
Okay.
All this is the gate issue, right?
So in get request we are just retrieving
the information from their data.
That is correct.
When they're retrieving the information
from their database,
we don't make money
when they're not sending the body.
That's why
we are not providing any header.
Then the content type of my body
is applications slash
Jason
because we are not sending any content.
So when there is no content that is void,
it is optional if you want to,
but it's not going to affect anything
if we are not going.
But we can yet. That's what I'm saying.
If you put it, it's not going to affect
if you don't put a smart way.
Okay.
Finding it
quite so far, so good guys.
See, Doctor. Doctor 57.
Dear 60 all Doctor.
Now I got you with Mr.
Drivers To date,
B is the master technician.
No need to hand without getting
ready to do a job.
Okay. Right.
Okay, guys.
So almost redundant. Get banner.
Let's go to that part operation
update one.
Which one?
We are going to proceed with the No.
Now we are going to make the third request
put in bench judging.
I'm going to that point now.
So now I'm going to work on two
update the update the information
of created employee, the employee
which is already created there.
I'm going to update the information
of the report.
Correct.
So now see who will tell me what
all of the information
I needed, what all the components
I need to make that request
for updating the
information of an employee
who will tell me this
swag, obviously.
Right. So let's open the swagger document.
This is the swagger one, right.
Can you see where the update
information available
when you see the update employee
information?
This book one right
this put one open this.
So now first first, let's take this base.
You are right from the first.
When it is based, you are
no, no.
Understand one the authorization token.
Obviously
we need authorization to continue
right now.
Guys, understand one thing.
If I'm trying to update some information
in their database,
it means I'm exchanging something.
I'm just changing the information current.
There is some information already
available in the database.
Now what I am doing is basically I'm
just trying to update
particular information,
to update the information in the database.
I have to send something again.
If I go do anything, what would I say?
Getting
so I have to send some information to them
or not, Right?
It means when I see I have to send
some information to their database,
what does it mean?
It simply means I need to have body.
So what I need, I need payload or body.
Got it. Now, in this body, what we need
because regard or do
we tell you what all are
the things I need in this body?
I cannot decide on my own right.
It's my God who is going to decide this.
Okay.
Okay, fine.
After this, after this.
Since I am sending the body,
I'm sending the payload.
There is one more thing I need
that we need ahead of this time.
Right?
And then type of method.
We need type of method.
We need
these are the five things we need or not.
Now we will consider the response.
See what would be the response of there.
That is something we need to understand.
So here first let me go to Postman and
let me add parameters we need.
I'm coming to that point.
I'm coming to that point. So at request.
So here I am going to add double date
update employee details I need.
So that is the point that you
this is the point.
This is the point I have to get isn't and
right now, guys, what kind of request
I'm going to send from you?
What is the type of request
I'm going to use, what method
I'm going to put my card right.
So put method.
I have made it available automatically.
I made it available now
here, after adding the put
method, the next thing is, see,
when I open this bar,
it says name in terms of barometer.
What we need, guys, is this barometer.
What is this body?
What we need
guys body.
So now the question I want to update one
particular employee information,
not all the employee's information,
because at one time
information
deleted one particular employee.
I will update only that information.
Right.
So if I'm going to ask
or need one information
on one employee, I need one specific data.
Right.
What do you observe
closely in the body itself?
Your swagger document says provide
employer.
Isn't it a unique identity
based?
Isn't it a unique identity? Right.
So here first let me put this bar.
Let me put this part
in my notes in the body.
So this is the body I need.
This is the body.
I need
in most cases.
Right?
So now you'll see here
I need body from this site.
Fine.
So let's copy
the body going to your most men
under body to select guidelines for body
control.
From here, Jason
is to be stood here.
So now, see, in this body
I have to send some data.
What should we do with the rest? Alliance.
For example, if you want to change
a status only your name is.
I'm coming.
I'm coming to that point.
I'm coming to get on board with it.
Now they see this is their data, right?
In order to update.
So first thing we do highlighted
particular information.
What I have to do first,
I have to provide my employer I.D., Right.
So let's see for creating an employee.
Let me create a fresh employee here.
See, this
is the new employee I got, right?
So let me just use this employee here.
Here.
This is the embroidery at work.
Now, let me change the first name.
Let me change
the first of this time, then this,
and then
right
in Katrina and again
in 57 point,
the middle name I'm going to blow.
It is it's
made in the last
no last name should be an X
and the middle name should always be.
This time I'm going to change.
Ten days earlier, B provided F
so now I'm going to provide M
Right. And the date of what?
Also I'm going to change to 2002
and nine date of
right to went and connect
employee status.
This time
we're going to change the employees
to dissuade
so we can change to anything, for example.
But let me change it to implement small E
fine and
then job it so this time job right
it should be cured.
Understood. Raised.
We changed every single thing, isn't it?
We changed every single thing here
in this part, in this part.
Inequality.
Any question in this part of this.
So here,
if we live stream, it won't change
or it will change to spring
than what we have two months.
When you read Asia and the value
is nothing but the district can be changed
or need name or not state on
how does it what it will take to explain
how we can skip some information.
I'm working on one part
it is update the employer ID details.
I'm not working on this part which says
update partial employee details.
I'm telling you to hold your horses
for some time
so that I can explain one point and
then I will switch on to another point.
So by the time you have to hold
your horses, get in my points two days
late,
then it's
fine after the class.
Then this week send me the invoice that,
Hey, you hired me from last two months.
You didn't pay with a single penny.
And there you go.
This is my invoice.
So we are fine.
So now, see, guys, there are two ways
to update the information in the database
for the employee.
Do this post.
You change every single thing,
make sense.
There's one user that is correct.
You have to be a department
that takes one so that.
All right.
So now, now, here either you change
the complete information of the employee
or you change financial information
of the employee to this.
So first one, first one,
we are going to check right in this.
We are going to change
the complete information.
We're not going to change only partial.
The first one is complete information.
So when you have to change complete
information, you have be used automatic.
Which party of details goes to
To change the complete information,
you have to use the method.
Right? So now,
now I'm going to work with put method post
standard request.
Oops.
We did a token
nothing.
Let me take the token here.
Let me put it here
and then take me put the header also.
So here that is what is
and that is what I'm going to place.
Dummy value applications.
Let's just
write country name this time if I send
you'll see here I got request
called employee record of due date.
Now see now see everything is changed.
Can you see Bina and Miss
Alex knew that Employee gender Male
employee job title
Q were employee's quarters employee
everything is working or not
and you'll see here
the messages employee record updated.
Is this correct or not?
Dates I'm going to change the complete
information, not just one part
of the information, right?
The complete information. I'm changing.
That's why I'm using record.
That's why I'm using record,
right?
So for any question in this,
everyone, anyone,
Marina, I always see you just one answer
from your side that gives business
why you never ask question.
Speak them.
Ask if you have
you updated
is almost created a new employee right?
You know that what happened right?
When you work in one company
and you suddenly left the job after
three months they assign your employment
employer to someone else, right?
They do it. Why? How they do it.
They change all the information.
Simple,
but they keep the same employee, right?
So they're told
they can delete the data from there
and they can update the same data
in that particular piece.
Right?
Because when you work
with the organization, I was
I think I should show you the embroidery
in the embroidery, you got to pass.
Remember, I showed everyone the two parts
and the employer in the back.
One is the white card, right?
That is the Xs one.
I see this, right. So
so there there in that particular one,
this employee.
Right.
The white one, the back one.
Do you have a lot of a lot of money?
I think maybe like going to pay
$30 or $2 can generate that one because
because the Xs one, having the magnet
inside it does get it inside this right.
So they can't generate for every single
embroider new one if they already had rate
is available, they provide this
to another one assigned to another one.
If the employee is normal with
the organization, it happens like this.
Okay.
It's not like you're working
with ABC organization today
and you left the job after five years.
When you're going to join again,
the same organization.
It's not like your idea will be same
employee, what you used to use earlier.
It will be changed right?
Categories
of employee is right.
So now, now, remember I told you
first to create the employee,
get the corrected details,
then update the employee
and get the updated employee
does remember the chart
which I showed you yesterday.
Okay.
So now now here.
Right type of matter header
the responsible upgrade the information.
Right.
So now if you see the response we got here
is is
is guys 200, why is this so
why is this so we sent a body right?
We sent a body.
So it means we were sending
we were sending somebody.
But still we are getting to 00201 that
not a newly created.
We are just doing some changes
in the existing record
train 201 is for creation rate.
Yes 201 is for creation 201 created
Creating something.
You're not creating something, right?
You're just doing some changes
in the existing record.
So there's services.
Okay, whatever you need to explain.
So we're giving you 200.
If you are going to add a new record
in the database,
then only it becomes 201,
ending a new record in the database
industry.
This part strings
nice.
Now here, I'm going to get this employee
and I will go in, get one employee part.
Right.
I will update this employee 80 here to get
the exact data and send this request.
Now, here you see, I got this data.
The can you see the updated
is it possible to create new employee
with book
with book you cannot create a new employee
because the employee
you already provided it.
Right.
So in this employee and if you see sort of
right
if you provide the same employee here.
Right.
Whatever the data
you are going to provide,
it will get updated against this
employee 80.
Right.
And when we talk about create
a new employee's implements
creating the new employee.
So you see here
the embroidery is generating.
No, the simple message you're seeing
is employee record updated.
It's nursing employee created.
So you guys, when you create employer,
you get this message employee created
and you get always this employee,
the newly created employee 80
But here when you're trying
to update the information it says employee
record updated and there is no employee
and it is providing in your body
correct.
So put information. Correct.
After updating the information,
we retrieved the updated information
from the database
that is also working perfectly fine. Are
guys there that is also working for you?
So far so good days.
So far, so good.
Now let's proceed for the let's
go a step right now.
Your best question so far.
What if I want to update some information?
I would want to update some information.
It means sorry.
Can you get can you go over again?
You just look to the idea
intended on the get an employee cutting.
So what I did Sebastian here
I got this employee from here right?
I put this employee in this part here.
Right.
So then then I can check
because this request
is available to check this specific user
in the database.
Right.
So I'm taking the data
which I updated against one
particular user with the same data
I'm able to get from here or not.
So That's why I have updated this employee
and I checked
and it is giving me the updated data
which I just updated.
It means my API is working fine
and that's good.
So now no, for me not working.
And then he replaced check.
Why is this is not working?
What is the issue?
What is the issue that you're getting any
any. I'm waiting.
What what is that issue you have?
Can you please tell guys
maybe you need to check this
this you are right.
You are trying to get it in
create employee, not one employee.
Please check your base you want
it is a problem.
You are trying to get the end point
of having create employee
you should provide is employee aid
and this value
of the employee only engaged one employee
not declared employee.
Otherwise you didn't ask you to provide
put or post right.
So please take care of the base.
You are right. That is correct.
All right.
You're targeting you're targeting
the wrong one.
Is trying to correct it
and then it will definitely work fine.
So update employee reduced job titles,
employment status, get all employee
get one employee,
create an employee,
generate the token, create a mini user.
These are the aggregate list
we are done with.
So far.
Now, the ninth one we are going to work
with is badge on.
When I say badge, call simply means
I'm going to update financial information.
I'm not complete information. Right.
So here, if we tried to update, we update
information, information of an employee.
Right.
So now again, again,
I would need a couple of things.
Right.
What are those things?
Let's check from this document.
So now see, when I click here,
it says update employee details.
This endpoint will update
portion Employee needed.
Please enter required requirement
automate people instances
to update in employee information.
For example, when you see
what you're seeing in the note,
please enter employee I.D.
as it is compulsory
to identify the employee.
It is but obvious that if I'm going
to update even a partial information,
I need to specify against
which particular user.
I'm going to update this information.
It doesn't matter whether I'm going
to update complete information
or I'm going to update your information.
Right.
Whether it is complete one
or whether it's a partial one.
I have to specify a particular identity
in the database
against this particular user.
I'm going to update this information.
Right.
So it is saying please enter employee ID
as it is compulsory to identify employee.
Please provide all instances when new
or only desired instances to update.
What does it mean
if you want to update some values,
so provide only those values,
not the complete values.
Then please remove the rest of
the instances that should not be updated.
If you don't want to update
all the other one.
For example, you want to just update
the post in the middle name the last name
a list of the things you don't want to do.
So just remove them.
Keep this three along with the employee
I.D., which is compulsory.
To specify the employee,
please remove come off the last instance.
It means I will continue that work.
Okay, so now this is the body part.
We got current cutting.
So first first I would go in my notes
and I will write here
the very first thing
I would need is basically
now you see
now you'll see here
the type of method I'm going to use is
nice.
What is the type of method
we are going to use now?
So we are going to use Edge method, right?
We are going to use batch method.
Fine.
So now in batch method,
do I need body or not? Yes.
So we need to be what we call it.
Body. What is the body?
This is the one point.
This is the body and after body.
Do I need header or not?
So you'll see
it says applications.
Let's do some country I need great.
Then.
Then I need authorization token
also this one not
addition token.
I was going
So now you see this.
You are right
from where we can get the base you are
first
select here
and then put it here
after this.
After this.
Simply connected with the end point.
So this is the
this is the end point.
Then EIGRP of method is batch payload
or body is this header
we will update token we already have.
Right.
So now now let's make this request first.
Let's make this request first.
I am going to update some information.
Right.
I'm going to update some information here.
See what are those information?
I'm going to update.
So first, I would need the employee I.D..
So what is the employee?
This is the employee.
I'm going to provide this employee I.D.
because I want to change their data
against this particular employee. 80.
Right.
So let's change only first name
with element, last name,
address, remove every single thing.
Every single thing.
Now, now, guys, tell me.
I'm saying
there is an additive in this body.
What is that?
And is.
Yes, yes. Correct.
In the last
we should not have any cover trade
in the end,
we should not have Common Core.
What is basically in between all values.
Right. Not in the last.
So I'm not going to provide any comma
in the last.
Right.
So now let's update the force, guys.
Give me one. Very beautiful.
The example.
You know, you told me
Ora and now school
did fine or a good book.
What is the last name?
It's not should be okay,
great.
Milan. Fine.
Then you got to spot.
By the way, Katrina,
you don't do words,
but for whom to do names?
Whose names
right?
And what is a best word in the bylaws?
And amazing
Alexis's middle
name should be low for you.
Let's keep it lol.
All right, fine guys.
No point
the employer is basically the one.
I'm specifying
that against this particular user I'm
going to update the details now
because I'm going to update
the body should information
I would need first to name.
I would need last name,
I need middle name only.
These three things
I'm going to update in the body.
So now you see my request is completed.
My request is completed.
Now I am going to update this information
here.
So the next request I'm going to make is
update
option is
made update audition information.
So now first let's select the method.
What is the method?
Nice edge. Let me select fetch.
Second thing I need is
base.
You are
this is the base you are
then 30 authorization.
So let me take this token from here.
Fine.
Now I would need this.
What is the rendering new?
Let's
application slash
Jason trade application slash Jason.
Now I would need body Right.
So I will click here I would go and
and here I will write
this particular body
which is already here with me
so far.
So we're just
and Katrina's is the rule which rule
the raw looking for
everything completed or is there anything
which is still pending right.
That's totally fine, but it's my mistake.
Actually, I'm missing just fine.
So now let me save it and let me sending
it says Employee record updated
successfully.
Employee record updated successfully.
Right.
So now you'll see one more thing here.
Did you object? It has been in there.
What is this?
Come on,
dude, you objected this bend and lol
and were only middle name got updated
only middle name got updated.
But remember one thing to observe in
in the response.
You got those little one this time.
Not true. There was little.
That is the main difference.
And we interview question
What is that difference?
Input and badge.
So our difference is first you update
complete information, you have complete
information input, but you update
partial information in batch.
However,
when you update complete information
input,
you'll get to double zero status code.
And when you update modified information
by a batch, you'll get to zero one.
Understood.
And that's true.
And this is the bug in the API.
You see, you give the name as you give
the name is good
you got then you get Malama
right as a last name you got
when you provided with the allowance.
It gets updated only and will correct
adding.
Can you see you guys? It's a bug.
Yes, it's a bug. Correct.
Job title.
Oh has emerging droid.
Don't worry,
I didn't blow it.
This is not my.
Let me just change it right away.
Let me just change it
right away from here.
Now see middle name
got updated to my little friend.
Can you see
it's still my little friend.
I don't know how this API is working.
Why even? I don't know.
It looks like
this is a bug in the API.
If this happened, it disappears.
Not working. Yes.
You get updates what we wanted to show you
right then.
If you're getting this
Facebook are responses in API.
The key
people keep updating the same input.
Oh. Might be the reason it is a bug.
So let's.
Let's do it. Let's do it.
Let me create one employee.
Don't create any other one.
Don't. Don't do anyone.
Okay, I'm going to create one employee.
Please don't do this
I'm going to
get this data
and I'm going to update this information.
It's now
see, it says employee
record of record successfully.
But here
the data I'm passing is not showing here.
This is something else.
Can you see
can you see this case
right now?
Employee record of digit successfully?
Yes. Correct.
Correct. Correct. Fine.
So now now we got
we got this complete details
of all the employees.
If you see right, complete
due dates of all the employees
and how we are playing with the data.
Right.
Whether it is a post operation. Right.
Whether it is a post operation within
it is a gate operation,
it is a boot operation.
It is a batch operation.
So for so far, we did
what is the fifth thing.
We are going to make no case.
The fifth thing
which we are going to make is
yes, yes.
Correct. To delete the employee.
Now the only operation pending
is to delete the employee.
So now let's see again.
Again, I have one point through
which I can get all the information,
but is that slider document right?
So now and should we check again
with great method?
Yeah, sure. Why not? We can.
We can if we take this,
if we go to get one
employee, let me update this employer.
Let me send it
and I'm getting this data now.
Can you see 26110?
Yes. Currently
we aim you as team and you see the Alexi.
We must all Yes
best practice we should for
final.
Yeah no copy Exactly
fine based
So now the next thing is
we are going to delete the employee.
Now see, we're about to complete the
operation of the can you see?
Then you must be thinking is still
we are done.
We just within a half hour. Right.
What we will do for the next 3 hours.
I have a solution for the course.
We're going to.
No, no, I have a solution for that.
I don't want
no practice. The
project, no plan, no project.
Still, we have just done
with the basic operations of Baby, an
advanced operation is still pending.
Hazim, please check that your browser
to said what I could not understand.
Check.
That is an error with your base.
You are right.
That is an error with your base
you are a base check.
So now we're picking up over my
earlier look.
Correct.
Even I don't know how this is working now.
See, forget one employee.
They will get the details of this specific
employee from their database
or to delete one specific detail
from their database.
What operation looks similar on
similar approach?
I'm not getting the detail
of one particular identity
or deleting that, but
I really don't understand
what has been written.
But the picture is
superb.
Vladimir Putin faked a basement
slide in the sticks.
What we have been repeating again
and again that we had a bug in the AP.
This is what I'm saying.
We have a bug in the API, right?
So if you come across
this type of behavior in the application,
you should report it to the developer.
No, that's fine. Alex Then explain.
You're fortunate enough
that he's allowing you to speak to the
So enjoy, or at least you can speak
a lot of things, right?
They didn't speak from last many
again, authentication
authorization, BNA token probate,
which is valid only for 2 seconds.
They fine.
So now now this document says
this document says very good document.
Right.
What it says we have to delete employee.
So to delete to to delete the employee
what all our information we need.
You see,
it looks exactly like a gate one employee.
Did you need one specific identity
that is unique to the database
you're going to delete in their database?
What is that unique data?
Obviously
in 4 minutes.
Then it's in 4 minutes.
Maybe in five, 5 minutes.
Maybe in 10 minutes. I don't know.
But they will definitely.
Having a breakdown.
So now, now
I am going to
I am going to add a new request here.
And that request is
delete, delete employee.
So now, guys, see,
first I have to select which part
here.
First, let's make it first.
We need a base unit
that is basic after base.
You are right type of method.
So what is the type of method we need?
A type of maintenance. Delete
after this.
After this.
Do we need body place?
No, we don't need body.
We need query.
We need better.
Right.
We need qualified and we didn't hear.
Then what else?
If you are passing query parameter,
do we need any headers
guys?
Do we need any headers?
You know this is optional break
so that is optional.
Unit authorization goes.
We need authorization.
Okay.
So these all are the information, right?
I need to delete the employee
from the database.
Fine.
Let's get this data from here
next. This data from here.
So first
this part
and then
select the end point.
So this is the end point
and then query barometer.
So what is the query?
But I would have
I need to see it says employee, right?
So I would rate employee
and then we will see the response
what is the response code
I will get from here?
What is the response code
Okay, fine.
So let's make this particular request
in an Austrian.
So now I'm going to create a delete one.
And here this is you.
Based on this.
This. You want it contained service.
You wanted it
plus a location, plus a blank.
On this three, it can be four.
Then we don't need header,
but we need authorization.
And the one which we need is be added to
can it be added?
So find a school here
and let this added to control
here and it's to file
now. We need to order this.
We need query better and we do
so the query parameter
is already available here.
See This is not waiting better,
so just copy this way better barometer
and then the value.
So I am taking the same employee 80
which I had.
Right? The same employee.
I will use this employee
file,
I will use this employee ID here.
Anything else?
Guys, I need to
know what?
Are we ready to send the request for this?
What?
We must see.
Yes, I will show you.
Employee does not exist
or you provided invalid employee entity.
Amazing.
Now you see guys what is happening?
It says employee does not exist
or you have provided invalid employee It
exists.
404 No, no, no.
I am. I have only deleted.
Now you see here is
status is for zero for not phone
right.
The status is for zero four not one.
Why is this? Yes.
Pending is at all correct.
Many good spending is wrong.
I know.
So now.
Now this is status for zero four
not found a means no data found
no delegates who have gone
has gone through that part.
Who has gone through that part?
No. I see no nothing.
No. What was deleted?
I am only I have only deleted
API status code read for zero four
when we get for zero four -200.
Okay.
I have 400 404 now we'll get rid.
Let me do it for you once again.
Now see now see guys
it says employee employee deleted.
Now you see.
Right. Employee deleted.
Can everyone see guys
can everyone sees it says employability.
Your request method must be deleted.
Uh, this is part of normal.
What?
Can you please change your request
method from get to delete
you didn't provide
to get delete method right?
And then you're already selected.
Get bored.
That's why it was not working.
So now you'll see guys here.
Now here. You see what we are doing.
We have provided this particular data
to delete the employee.
Right?
So deleting the information is fine.
Now it says is data scored 200.
It means the data you want it to delete.
You have already deleted this data.
So what the spirit does this.
Okay, 200 requests is successful.
Now if you want to check here this time,
if you want to check,
what would you gain?
Employee does not exist
or you have provided
invalid employee eight
Not sending anybody.
Alex Alexi why do not read Because
want to weaken restore
but not with the API.
We're not with the API.
There is no method for that.
So remember Alexi here.
Please don't employ 80.
Been.
We are doing
your service.
Please provide employee
then provide employee here
or delete.
We need parameters
authorization in header.
No Alex there's four times
they for delete.
We need parameter query parameters
an authorization
not data.
It wasn't for zero 44.
Now it is 404.
This is for get remember
this is for get bad request.
It means your system
not able to find anything.
Right. So this is the expected one.
This is the expected one.
Right. So different messages
we are getting.
I know because again,
this is a glitch in the API.
This API is a lot of glitches.
We have to understand
despite the bad request,
because the once
you delete everything from the database,
will your database
be able to find the data? No.
When it is not going to find a reader,
it will that you request rate
because you are trying to send something
which is not available.
If somebody must send something
which is available.
For example, I created new employee.
This new employee I
created
and this time going to send this to.
So now this is the correct request
at the moment I provided
this is the correct receipt.
It is returning minor target cutting
connect again, it didn't need to do here.
Can you see this?
Everyone?
Right.
So now now here to delete the employee.
You get this message.
Employee delete it right.
Sorry. One more point.
So we get 200 or it's delete.
Not what did not exist.
It does not exist.
That's
why I sent Alexa to read the eBay code.
I give you the site. Right?
If you know what is the meaning of 400.
Right. It will understand it for so.
Now see is what happened
when you send to delete request.
Right?
You deleted the data
or deleted data from database.
Right.
When you delete gender data from database
dataset returns or get 200. Why?
Because the operation
you wanted to perform the operation
you wanted to perform,
you completed with the operation.
Right.
Those one does
find can start break monument.
Just wait for 3 minutes and then you have
just 3 minutes.
So now VRC deleted data from the database.
You want it to be deleted frame deleted.
Next point
200 is okay for that rate for them now.
Now after these, you're
trying to search the information.
Why aren't getting it employed now?
Something
which is already deleted from the database
is no more part of your database
and you are trying to search
on that parameter which is not available.
The database you will get work
you will get for 040 bad request. Why?
Because there is nothing available
in the database for that.
But getting my point
getting them one way so posted
deleted this by you got 200.
Now you're trying to access
the information where I get it right.
It is not work
because it is checking something
which is not already available
in the database.
So what is this clear to everyone?
Guys,
when we talk about current
operations, that's why I stopped.
You know, we'll see
when we talk about current operations
we created or not
crib the information or not
we updated the information or not
and we deleted the information or not.
We are done with all four types
of explanation.
Correct.
Operation is done.
Yes, exactly.
Exactly.
Then at that point of time, you have to
check everything on completion.
So better to digitally.
Right.
So now now the basic is done right.
The basic operation is done
in this raid,
in this next three and a half hours.
Right. In this next 3 hours, I believe
I will take you to the most interesting
part of the story.
This coming 3 hours
will be the really exciting journey.
Right?
So let's take a break now after break.
Once you come back,
everything would be interesting, right?
So that would be very easy things
and interesting things we are going to do.
So after the break,
we do all of the stuff.
What is this?
What is glasses are for three.
How many people do you have right now?
Fine.
So now, now, here
we have covered all the operations
after discrete operations. Right.
Let me tell you something.
What else you can do here? The best thing
when we talk about the postman
and we talk about postman here, two things
you can do.
First,
when it comes to verification, part
verification
and validation, part,
we should not rely only on the status code
red guys.
You guys getting my point?
We should not rely only on the status quo
because we have seen
if there's a glitch in the API,
then we get this code correct.
But there is always a problem
with the response guidance rate
in the body of the response.
We always see some of the problems.
Correct? So
even though the
message seems to be a status quo,
but still the details
which we are getting in
the body is having some problem
right? Yes.
So now the first thing I should show you
in the postman.
See, whenever we make any any request
and we get the response rate,
we get any request
and we get the response here.
What we have to do is
the very first thing.
Can you see this console part?
You guys in the bottom left, bottom
right,
click on this console.
Now just see this response.
Get one employee 26112. The latest one.
We need 26112.
Can you see
all the responses are available here
if you see all the responses are available
here.
Eight Whatever the request we have created
so far, all the request you see
now, Hazim, this is the console.
The console
just click on the console
and you'll see all of your request that.
Even with so far
lazy, are you able to see this part
now? Now click on any of this.
For example, the latest one, right?
Ballistics one.
What we did,
we get the details of the employee.
Now when you open this,
this is the response rate.
This is the response.
So it says request
to headers was contained.
We provided application JSON
authorization.
We provided builder token user agent.
Is this but Austrian?
We are postman, right exempt
everything was to token trade
and then see the response headers.
These are the items
I'm talking about in the response.
See in the response
you see these headers we have
in the response been headers, right.
All these been headers. Great.
What we have and the response
you're going to console and here you see
these are those response headers mundane
for date of February.
Right. This is their time
server is Apache Xe powered right.
Every single thing is invocation is store
no must rehabilitate fragment
things are available you can
you see this again you see this okay
and then the response
party is available this
the response board is available
this you see.
And so
the employee explains
that Then we then every single thing guys
see today's date, Sunday, 28th of January.
This is the time for the postman server.
Wait, so
now what you can do is instead of
just following,
relying on the status, good,
you can go here in the response body.
Right?
And from there
you can verify some of the feeds
or the privacy of bonds and everything.
Right.
Or if you want to see whether it is generating the employee or not, you can verify
if you want to see.
This is not closely my past bit
that I'm getting this post remote.
Not you can verify
it means would be value.
You can verify in this particular part
how they will discuss.
But this is also the operation
of verification validation.
We can perform in Postman the second thing
you click on your Postman collection
to click on the collection of this
is everyone can
click on collection.
Now what do you have
in this collection, guys?
What do you have in the collection?
Tell me
everything.
Read all the request
you have in the collection.
Right?
So now Postman says
if you want to run your entire collection
in a single shot there also you can
you don't want
you don't need to run one at one time.
Another request
and then another request and a no,
go ahead,
create collection and collection.
It will work again.
Similarly to your best to suit.
So if you want to execute your suit,
remember in terms of this disorder,
you have all the test cases. You
just run your test.
So it works for all the test gives. This.
If we talk about training class,
we provide bags like vision and smoke.
So whatever other does
this belong to that particular bank?
It executes all of them.
Similarly, here, this collection sees
if you want to run,
you can run this complete collection.
Can you see these are an option here
or from this three
Also click here
and you see that I'm collection
and collection, right?
So now see what happens.
Click run collection.
It says
it will run, create
a user generated token and then create
employee gained one employee
get all employers, get employment status,
get job photos of digit employee returns,
updated partial employment admission
and building them
right next. Can you see this?
Everyone
now here exists aberrations.
What does it mean
when I say iterations speaks
limitations?
Basically how many times
you want to run your collection?
Five times. 18 times, right?
Multiple times.
So right now keep it to one only. Right.
We will run it one time.
It says delay in the time.
It means after every iteration
how much delay you need.
I don't want any delay because I'm
going to execute just one thing.
If you are passing the data
from any of the refinery,
passing the data
from any other freight, no.
So there is no data.
If you want to see of responses,
click on this checkbox.
Right. Keep variable values.
We don't have any variable
as of now when collection
without using a stored cookies
or save cookies after collection.
Run again cookies coming to picture
You want to save your cookies
after collection run.
Let's save disabled
because my data is not good science.
That is no formula of making,
especially on relaunching because.
Right.
So definitely
I should not be bothered about this part.
Let's run collection.
Can you guys see
it says this request does not exist.
This requester does not have any
does this request does not exist.
This request does not exist
for all the request.
It is saying the same thing.
Can you see
based.
So what?
What is this?
This what this test is all about?
See if I had an event on it from here.
Right.
See if,
I run it from here. Let's see this one.
If I had an individually, it is running
fine. See?
Let we cleared one template
from here that would create new employee.
This is the employee record
working for fine.
Correct.
But the same thing if I'm going to run
my collection part
from this particular part
the collection, it's not going to run
if I'm trying to run,
see if this does not have any test.
What is this
test they will discuss on this test.
All right.
So far, individual requests are done,
but there are no test
which we are executing.
There are no test which we are executing.
Right.
So now we have to focus on this part.
So good things, good things first,
we will not allow
our to create best
and use it in the postman plane
requester.
You are to lose impedance that provide you
what simple
now? No, before this.
Before this.
Let me just explain
you Let me just explain one thing here.
What is this
query benefit?
Anyone knows what is query, but it would
instead of going to get request
and check first,
this is all about get request only rate.
Otherwise every single one I'm
every single one.
Right. I'm getting
see this is the response in green.
So that means it is working.
Mainly the parameter required
to run the query subtest,
take care of the slider, document
what it says you have to follow.
Exactly the request
which is available there.
Right.
If you don't follow this, am
great.
So now
the first one.
No, no, no, nothing, nothing.
It's a simple.
We are also using the same thing, right?
You can your message right
Someone just post your message
in this index of is available
she was available then will help you make.
I know there is a small query to business.
The mistake you are doing is put in there.
If we look, it's not a big deal.
So now here is query better.
And we told you something.
We need to focus.
And there is another of bad
and we done when we talk about is
thought better
what is the second one.
The second one is both better and better.
The first one is query better.
Now understand the difference
in between these two
query better.
We want better parameter. What is this?
See, when I open this,
you see the parameters are coming
after the question mark
and you see
everyone see the parameters
which are coming after the question mark.
So when they're coming after the question
mark,
it is come, it comes with the key and
well knew what
query parameter comes
with key and value board.
So wherever you find G, whenever you find
a value after the question mark in your,
you are will record this type of parameter
as query barometer.
We call this type of parameters
as query parameter.
Then after the question mark
you'll get D and value mode, right?
So once you're done with your base,
you are a right after today you provide
or it provides basically question mark in
whatever the value is coming.
After the question
mark, it says query better. We
did not separate stuff,
but basically
it is defining the whole path, right?
The segregation is before that.
This is the part of the question mark.
This is the parameter when combined both
it makes a single list.
Is this clear?
This part is what is clearly parameter.
Right?
So now another one
let me show you.
I open Amazon.
Can you see this Amazon?
I opened
I click on for two years now
now here you see when I click on foot
we're after Amazon dot in slash Q
slash came in you see
it didn't start with question mark
directly forced slash came
right or
let me give you one best example for
that I'm writing here
let's see
so now if you see images right
if I click on the images option,
I click here.
I select this image.
Now you see here, right, It says Google
dot com slash search
and you see slash search, Right.
So the moment you keep for further,
you keep adding one thing
to think three things, right?
It will keep adding one more slash
with your request keep adding
one more slash with you request this one
find this one will add the request.
So whatever the parameters
you are asking with the slash,
recall them fourth parameter
because in part parameters
we don't have to provide any question
mark, any key or any value.
You simply define the bond in back,
but just creates the things it provides.
You ready the complete
but it see the complete month, right?
For example let's get prime
so you'll see
landscape was using photography fine
So now when you open this photography
right in the images or in the all right
you are seeing this particular one
will all
dot com in Google dot
com you perform some search in search
you performed
what landscape the source is this range.
So then after question mark
right after the question mark you see box
barometer comes query
barometer comes in opposite single slash.
What comes there gives the mark parameter.
So in Google under search,
you made this operation correct.
This is when this is the sort of
search is better and better.
Google right.
So under Google in search,
you perform this operation.
So Google dot
com was the initial thing we provided.
And then when we provide the
search option, the board gets added
automatically by slash.
So whenever whenever something comes up
with Slash, whenever
something comes up with Slash,
this is part parameter
that adds to the path.
And whenever some comes with question
mark,
we call it as query barometer in the month
for example, Google dot com
slash search
slash log in something like this.
This is your bot barometer, right?
But if it is coming with Mark,
employee I.D.
is equal to 1 to 3.
Then again when it was performed
by using something like this.
Right.
Because they come after the question mark
they are your query better.
There
is this clear difference
and we've been very open and.
We did a lot better.
There is this clear.
Now let's let's try to do this.
Let's try to do this.
I'm going here and I'm writing here.
See HDB
equivalent of a slash
H&M sending index data.
NEG same things.
Thanks dot net.
And here I'm going to provide
some index API slash
slash, API slash.
I want to provide it all
in all,
get all employees right,
get all employees door HP
slash.
I'm saying cloud
cloud consultant.
Now see what I'm doing in this particular
set of I'm going into the EPA location
and then all the employees that I see get
all employees, BHP,
I'm providing cloud consulting slash rate.
Yeah, that's fine. That's fine.
I'm not going to search anything.
I'm just showing you right now.
Okay, so here, this would be
your little white cloud consultant,
Rain. Cloud consultant.
So now here
you see this cloud concerted part.
So this is basically the main you are
after this slash.
It is extending the path of the API.
Then one more part of the API location,
then one more part of the end point here.
Also, if you want to specify
the information or rate
among all the employees
I need only cloud consent, then fine.
So now this part returns
all the cloud consultants is our database.
This part returns
all the Cloud consulting.
Correct
is if we provide only this part.
In this part,
tell me what represents the highlighted
one will return What
all the employees right.
So now after this, after the slash.
If I provide cloud consulting, then what?
It will return.
It will return only
cloud consultants, right?
Whatever the cloud consultants
we will be having in our database,
this will return all the cloud consultants
after
Cloud consulting
if I want a particular one.
So four are good thing
one particular thing.
I need to go with query management
after this.
If I want to specify
one particular piece of information
from the bunch of information
I have to rely on query with.
If I want to define the complete font
so that I can access all the information
available on that.
But I have to rely on but better.
So now
here, here, if I want to provide indexing,
hey, I'm seeing
in all the cloud consultants.
In all the cloud consultants,
give me the one
whose page is due zero eight, for example.
20 and I'm seeing the gender
of the particular person is
these women.
So now see, I'm
just defining this part, right?
This is my this is my world based,
my query barometer,
and this one is my body
barometer so that I'm getting equity
barometer, correct.
Is this correct case?
Any question in this part
query buried with any question
so far, strings
all clear?
Yes, Correct.
Now, you can verify the same thing here.
Also see in this part
your address of the server,
then your API location after Slash,
then slash gate
one, employ it because these are
your parameters coming in the fund.
So these are automatically
these are correct
that exists
after a cloud consultant can do it
one more time.
Yes, ma'am.
So for example, if you see in the cloud
consultants, you are trying to target
a complete bunch of information
by a month barometer.
But now in an old consultant,
let's say you have
then students, 13 employees,
then cloud consultant, you have
you want to get just one
cloud contracting, which one
you need to provide the specific identity.
You have to build that.
Okay, I need the cloud consultant
who is having the edge going the engine,
but always having the priority 1 to 3
and having the value for five six.
If you provide this type of information
we call this equity parameter
squared again at any point of the month.
No, I don't know.
Remember, this query can be
inside the part where you are.
You are having the data.
For example,
if I provide this 2820 during remit here
press index API, will it work?
Will it work?
I don't know.
No, it will not work.
Why? It will
not work
because it's a simple like in the water.
We have all the clouds
and you are trying to find on your bank
and not find that. Why?
Because they are already available
in deep water.
You have to open the wardrobe,
then only search for it
if you are starting somewhere else
you're not quite on right.
But it
fine.
I hope the example was relevant.
I just thought of that examples
I giving you.
You find
the problem.
So please explain and point the time
you read this point to touch point first.
And with this.
All right then and then we will.
Which one is end point.
Which one is editable Indian
this practice and applying
the method read the last part of the
you want it and what is the point of the
then when you read it in The Postman
Postman is here.
Mm. Surveyor is touch point.
I'm expecting answer you.
Can you just explain it and we will warn
Simon.
First I need to ask
first I need to ask why I need to ask
because this is something irrelevant
to the topic.
And if I spend my time on something
which is irrelevant supposedly
to ask where
he got the information from straight.
So this is my duty. Let me do my work.
It is extremely important for me then.
Me, sir.
Yeah, exactly.
That's what I'm saying.
So you should tell your people
by themselves.
We are not wasting their time
yet Ahead of their time.
Right.
The bind which I'm occupying
and I'm taking, I'm trying to cover more
and more topics for you, Right?
So please don't tell me that
you're wasting time here.
If you think so.
If you think so, that we are wasting time.
Is let me so I can go in fast.
I can explain the things bust
this do let me know.
That's
fine, guys.
So now, now, so far,
how many of you guys think
that you're
wasting their time in the class? Now?
You find Fine.
So now, now you'll see here.
You see this particular point, right?
When we talk about sending the collection,
it is asking for the best
rate.
So that's what I wanted to ask him. Right.
So that even I can give you
this is this touch point.
I never thought anyone
no one got this question
in the interviews.
This was completely in the living thing.
So I just wanted to ask him.
I can make his concepts clear.
I was just trying to help him
so that next time, if he did something
like this right, then definitely
you should know all the things, right?
So that is the way to clear someone's
doubt.
That's what I am trying to do.
Fine, Because if he doesn't have
a complete information and if I did know
if I all he has to do somebody me
and he does someone, indeed
he will identify that.
Okay, this is totally irrelevant
to their topic, right?
So please don't get it.
Don't take it.
Otherwise I'm just trying to help
this people because they do some 50%, 25%.
They need them need point in
and the applicants are genuine.
But it's our duty.
It's my duty to explain them
what is relevant, what is the relevant.
So first there's get them some work,
let them complete some work,
have some identity on their own,
and then maybe I'll explain.
Fine, guys.
So now, now, so far we did this.
We tried to run the collection,
but they didn't ask for one thing.
What is that thing?
It asked for best.
So what is this best?
We need to understand this, right?
We need to understand.
What is this test?
What does this all about?
So first first let me tell you this
here approach
for if we are testing
ten, the first thing when we talk
about approach for the API testing,
what kind of testing we're
performing in API
are amrut functional testing.
What is functional testing days.
Tell me, Simon, what is functional testing
UI testing is functional one
this is non UI testing, right?
API is non UI.
There's been so we perform
integration testing.
You need a
rate rise.
This is integration distinct.
Now can somebody tell me
what is integration does do
in somebody.
Yeah. Silva Yeah I.
Mean I don't
I would share this not with everyone
The rate
we have one piece of application
we are trying to add
another piece of application.
So when we are trying to add another piece
of application writing,
merging this two portions
in one application we have to test.
But if my existing
as well as the new, what parts are working
or not in the application.
Right.
So when we integrate those two things
and then we try to test this part,
we call it integration.
This right,
we call it integration testing.
So now, now here,
let me write first one user story, right?
What kind of user story
you generally get in the API testing?
See, first
you have to create an employ, right?
And then get the created employee.
This should be.
But don't we also check the function
of the application here?
So when we talk about functions,
what does it mean?
Input and output?
We are verifying the connection links.
We are verifying the API status.
Good, right?
So we are taking the connection that has
been established in between that thing.
Right?
And the server is working absolutely fine.
All right. So create updated index.
What I am saying,
the primary point is your API status.
Could you perform this API instead?
This could be testing anyone.
No, you don't break,
you don't in there did indeed
that was you perform this to 00201404.
This is what you build in the database
guys.
Yeah, that is based on me.
Do you checked?
Yes. Got it. Got it.
So there is a difference in between
distinct
API, distinct database, distinct
in the first form of testing
when you have to deal with the UI
by the website, you always make sure that
okay, if you're entering the user name
right, this being username is updating
can be user name.
So function be is linked with the look
and feel the great part, great
right with the great button.
But here here in API
testing we're taking the integration
that the data keeps adding
into the application.
The link has been established,
the connection has been updated
and now when we are sending
some information, then we are creating
some information
not with the UI part but with the API.
But that is non-US by right?
So from here
I'm able to get the successful messages.
What does this success with messages
these are your DBA is status called
right
getting my phone case.
So there is a difference in database.
You never test API part in API
you never guessed
you born in UI, you never tasted Facebook.
If if we were performing the same approach
in all that region,
why do we need to distribute relevance?
Makes sense.
Things make sense.
Then why do we need to test entry levels?
I have seen integration testings,
implements.
See, let me give you
a very simple example.
You have a login page.
You already have a log
in pending a replication,
you are testing
your login functionalities working.
Find your positives
about your negative scenario Blank log.
Everything is working fine. Now.
The model your developers have ended here
in module or in employment.
Right?
So now your application head as do module.
So post is module module
and the second one is an employee module.
And here you had just one module
that was a log in modern.
So now after adding this
an employee module in the application
you have to perform testing to make sure
there turnaround in module as well.
Is your employee.
Both modules are working absolutely fine.
Mark.
This is what we call integration testing
on industrial.
Now after this what we have
you have to verify there
we created employee, correct?
Correct.
So now here, verify
the created employee is part
or all existing employee
Now is you guys existing employee, right.
It means that your data should be
generated
in this specific location in database.
It should be like your generating the user
and it is generating and will work
normal user. This should not right.
It should get updated and created
and added in the right place in database.
Alright. Alright.
And that update the employee after this.
We need to and again
we have to get the updated details
of the employee,
updated details of the employee.
This is the user story we generally take
for the complete scenario
and then we will simply
return or share the partially.
We will update the employee.
After partially updating the employee,
we will simply verify
right, verify what all are
the things we have modified that generated
verify that job data,
fight the instances. Right?
Any instance we can verify the instances,
any other thing.
So this must be my users. Me.
So now you see I'm will be everywhere
this verify
that if I have been five points
give you see
if I have any point.
Can you see this
without performing test in the postman?
We cannot verify
or we needed any permission.
Everyone agrees with the point.
Everyone agrees with this point.
I'm not fine
now let me check your knowledge between
then me here.
When it comes to test
a particular piece of application,
when it comes to test a particular piece
of application witnessed in how amendments
Windows ten Division one linked windows
didn't
you in one linked with the student staging
and when we pre-production
and when we test in certain mind
with this Dingwall environment,
we saw it in production environment,
right?
Depending on your company,
the structure you can decide
whatever the environments
you have correct or not.
Correct or not either dam or QB or
staging or pre-production or cert
or on or production.
These all are the environments, right?
These are the environment
generally organizations here,
depending on your company,
depending on your client,
depending on your architecture architect.
Right.
They can decide how many environments
they want to have.
Sandbox Is this the environment?
What is this?
They one sandbox?
I've never heard
about this type of environment.
Anybody? Not anybody.
Nobody.
Anybody is not in the article that
sandbox, not metaverse.
Maybe
they gave the name to their environments
metaverse or something like this
playground to create something like this.
They provide these are the normal ones.
What exactly do environment for developers
do you in mind linked or do is
is standing environment
very different stages
pre-production environment
exactly that the public of your production
environment on which we perform immediate
testing right before the deployment
certification environment is what note
this performance testing
something like this quality environment
is what also need you in quality
if we need to.
Good when we say But like I said, we don't
need all this environment at one time.
We can have two, three or four in one,
which makes two weeks, not one.
And the studio.
Now if you want to give the name of your
environment to live ours, you can do that
if you want to give
playground developers, you can do that
and call it playground like this.
So you can have millions of names
on the environment tree.
These are the genetic one, common ones
which I give you
So far, so good.
You made the same leg stage.
Q Well, you mean not understanding
design, user experience testing
you will be is not in the staging you
it is not in staging.
If there is no pre-production,
then it is spreading.
Otherwise it will always in production
you would
find point.
So now,
now just look at this point right now.
Just come on.
How long?
Just look at this point here.
He had built this point, isn't it?
This environment
case.
This is environment of not
any more.
Okay, see this point?
This point is same here.
Also here, also
here also zeros everywhere.
The environment is same great
deal slash API or similar
not between
seen what
if you consider this is a Q in
when this is a Q and when you have written
100 request,
how many requests you able to do?
100 request in only 100 request
you updated?
This part isn't in mind
whether you want this is a minority order.
You updated this part everywhere. Correct.
Now let's say you have to test this theme.
You are in the same API.
Is this same APIs you need to test
in development environment.
What what do you do?
What would you do?
Will you write another hundred
API request?
Will you write 300 more days?
Once again, query parameters once again,
everything 100 times.
No, you simply select
the environment, which environment
you want to test in.
This is the only thing you had to create.
So how we can add the environments,
how we can add the environments.
Right now
we are going to work on this part.
We are going to work on this part.
Can you then everyone see this?
I'm going to hear
everyone's ideas.
I can use.
I can everyone can see it.
Right click on this.
I can click on this. I can.
It says No
environment variables right now.
See you exist. Environment it says.
But right now that is new environment
variable.
Can you see it
from the heart?
I didn't see it.
So now first click on a link.
Click on Edit.
In this no environment
variables, click on Edit
Now click on edit
and provided initial value.
What is the initial value?
That initial value is
this your
you are in to the environment.
You're you are to the environment grade.
So this is the initial value.
This is initial value.
Can you see guys this guys
again know what it click on this icon
click on this icon right
click on this icon and then select this
initial value and provide provide the
you are all of this
great beginner
development environment or skewen lineman.
And then here
we are going to provide name.
So the name I'm going to provide
is Gilly B's.
You are paid.
This is the business you are in.
Guys, remember I told you base
you are only consist of two things.
You are L plus API location.
It is no end point available here.
Can you see
there is no end point available here? Base
base. Can you see this
so you can provide this Q web based.
You are all paid fine selected.
Selected trade selected.
Fine.
So now in the current event
you also provide the same
initial and current value
board should be same board,
should be same great
rate or should receive, and simply
simply say it
first, save it first.
So now,
now you'll see here are new word you.
Maybe you are,
maybe you. It is new Watson.
But I hope you know
how you are going to work on this, right?
This is the variable. It is the value.
This is the initial value.
This is the current value you provided.
Right.
Simply out of it.
That's fine
if it is autofill. And then explain.
So when you provide initial value.
Finally, that is also
defined.
It should be defined before you find
it should be defined.
Now. Now you click here, you click
here, right, and you select this.
Q Interested in what
made you select you?
When you select here,
you understand when we trade, fine.
Now, whatever the environment
you will see, you will find those
in my media, I will tell you,
because here we have a value.
Can everyone see this value?
You can add multiple environments, guys
you can add.
Then you will test environment.
So here can you see here?
Can you see you just changed his name to
you understand one
or let me write like this
Q a q e environment.
I just changed it now.
When I changed it,
you see it June Me So this time, this time
you see I'm getting this queue environment
and in this do it.
And when we,
when I'm selecting by default
am getting this curious you are it or not.
Did you see
I'm getting this curious you are in here
or so now
now everyone see this Q eight environment.
This new environment is having
this do it based.
You want rate this to a best
you miss, you want to
anybody want to see this part.
So now what we will do first
we will update this value.
We will update this value here
in all the request.
So now we don't need this part.
What we need, we need the environment
which will save the date
which we set there.
So what is the environment
related Environment,
This one we're getting, you see the
you mouse over now what you have to do
double Kali braces value, double click
basis.
Right and keep this end point it is
so now you see this is the battery
reprised one
and the moment you provide this Q a q A
you are in when you like defining
a static variable here, right?
So now see this curious.
You are the moment
you go to our operation here
it says this is the initial value,
this is the current value.
Is this the correct one?
Is this correct or not based on
first first, let's check first.
Let's check whether it is working or not.
Let me say it
is already registered. Right?
Email address.
You have already registered point.
We can create any other user.
Let me go here.
Let me provide to now see
you'll see working fine.
201 created
201 created it meets my
this particular variable is working
absolutely
fine or not nice
now now let's update this particular part.
This particular part
in all the request First, did
this particular part
in all the request saving
use this one here also
here on
we updated this information
everywhere you see.
Where did you copy
what the shortcut to call it.
I will.
I will can you should unwind. Yes.
Now school.
Where were you when we creating this park?
There you go. This is like you a base.
You are a reader.
This environment variable
rate.
What a shortcut to call it.
Goodness, We are not.
We state halfway done right.
Half of the base is still pending
now as well.
Can you see from we got this you would
miss you are in and we provide you
so to pass the parameter
make sure this building is correct.
Right.
You can also payment with the after
double curly braces
when you type it gives you this addition.
So because in the value
also you provided is double quotes.
Can you see here I didn't provide
double places like you are.
Providing the welcome references
in the variable.
Don't provide to welcome this Alex.
Otherwise it will not work.
Fine.
So now, now, now.
See, just to check anything.
Anything. Just check from see
working fine.
Great big this one also it
this one also batch.
This is also fine
because see why it's not giving?
Because we already deleted this employee
object.
Partial employee returns in the body.
These important things don't do right.
We have the next one is six.
One, two, six.
So let's take this post yet.
There you go.
See the object successfully.
Correct.
But now
the correct.
Fine.
Now let's go a step further.
Now you see, you'll see here
one more thing I have one more thing
I have, which is common.
The value is not changing. What is that?
I should not call this update.
Partial employs didn't BHP
update embroidered? BHP
delete employee dot BHP?
I don't want to boss like this.
I should not. But actually why?
Because if the model I'm 1000 delete
what is right
delete EPAs I'm requesting
I'm making 1000 delete request.
If someone changed the end point,
then what would happen?
I have to change it 1000 places right?
So I should not be in a position of there
if tomorrow
someone didn't just make you
what you want it right now in terms of
and when I'm very much sorted,
I have to change this.
You are elected one, please.
And from there the key which I'm
passing in April that exist, it will work
fine, Right?
So I'm going to save my when it comes
to provide the values of the environment.
So bom
bom comes from
one what he has imposed with
speed object model design,
but is a framework great.
It's like in particular,
unless it is a particular design.
But is that one simplistically
for encapsulation?
Then you created these
and you keep your data see?
Right. So no one can change it. Fine.
Similarly,
when we talk about these endpoints,
when we talk about this particular points,
what we have to do in this
case, click on this icon again.
And this time they're not going to deal
with all of this in one means
like this time we have to deal with
global variables.
We have to deal with global variables.
So my all the endpoints,
my all the other stuff
comes under the category of global.
And this
industrial disk.
So now, now see how we can add
the global variables here.
So first for us to click on this
great icon everyone can see
at next,
click on the American,
see here.
I have to provide this part,
create user, create user.
So from there, I got this
guys.
This is the create user rate.
So let me right here.
Can you repeat, please?
Sure.
You click on this egg,
can you see someone?
Yeah. Don't worry.
What you have what you don't have.
It will sort it out. Don't worry.
First click on egg, Leak on egg
and then here for straight.
The variable name is Create user.
Create user.
And then I see an export button
is that able to export it
and we import the whole event.
First, don't look for the shortcut,
at least for a time.
We do what I'm doing.
Okay, so take this first do from the
egg, this first menu from here
create user.
It is for admin one.
Create user is for admin,
one create employs for the normal one
and then provide this and you
provide this value selected here.
Okay.
Selected to enforce the
guys I provided variable name.
I provided value and the current commit
you clear
one endpoint any point
and I selected the checkbox.
Is this clear?
Yes. If yours is empty there,
why am I everything from scratch?
Not then.
The second is in writing. Generate token.
So now go here, take the second endpoint.
Generate token.
Take this one
pasted print select
select generate token
player.
Everyone
there is to end points we have ended.
Can we do same with body elects we make
the meeting
we are going see we are still halfway
down.
We are going Yeah, we can do everything
with anything on this planet.
We just have to have some patience.
So. So we'll go this
is everyone doing this with me
based? Yes.
Okay.
Now the next thing is.
The next thing is we have to write,
we have to break,
create, employ, create employee.
Do we leave their name default?
You should leave their name
default, create employee.
So here, come and take this create
employee part, this part
create employee.
And then update this particular behavior
created
right
after this. For
date one employee.
So just type it again.
One employee go here
take this particular part of
one employee
and then based this value here,
select the checkbox.
So paused whether it is create admin,
but it is to name it create user.
Yes. Correct.
Correct.
If you want you can give
this name is create entering user.
That is also it's a you know,
is it more simple?
No, it's fine create a user.
Is this okay now
if you a man would be use clipboard.
Yeah.
Here also I can use clipboard
but right now because of I have to give,
you know, really low level information
everything will spread index
by typing this.
Otherwise
otherwise,
you know, I can also take this data
from here in this state.
So to help everyone, I'm doing this.
Did all employees
go take this particular data
to get all the employees
and I'm going to put it here.
Did all employees
fine and get employee status right.
So here you see did
all employees employee status?
I think this one.
So Dick
the get employee status from the one
and I'm going to put it here
then update employee information raised.
I'm going to be a big employee.
There is update employee is which one.
Hello
update employees which one post
put badge which one.
No, you got put your badge badges
but partially employee
so I just got this new
similarly big bunch of digit employee
delete employee and gain job papers guys
please take this one news.
But no, that's fine.
Thanks guys.
Please don't. Please complete this.
And once you are going to let me know
you got that
super fast.
Like it up in plain done Jimmy Done City.
Dan Zimmerman for all Update Employee
Partially updated Employee
delete Employee.
Get job papers
for everything you ever done.
Amazing. It's amazing.
I'm just mesmerized.
Jimmy says it works.
He looks in a different mood today.
That happens,
guys. Done
is that anyone who is still left
yet. I'm not.
I'm just giving time for everyone. Right?
So it would be
all right.
So I'm giving time so
that everyone can get this things updated
right
that great.
So now, now at this point of time,
we have added all the global behemoths
right?
Replace all the global Beliebers
now just to save them first.
So click on this save option.
Click on this option post Fixing
saved everyone.
Now, when you click on this icon,
this time
it will give you all these people
see all the global variables
and you can you see
these global variables
are having all the endpoints.
All the endpoints, right?
And here you are
having this particular environment.
If you want to add multiple environments,
you can add
multiple environments, no issue and go
right?
No, no, that's their split.
I'll come to that point.
I'm going to explain all.
Is it 100 days?
So far, so good.
Everyone.
Great.
Let's take a break, guys.
Let's take a break for 10 minutes.
Maybe. And I'm
are our joint account
things that maybe you could only hear
what is going on in the world.
All right.
So so far, so far what we did here see
in this base, you are right.
Right.
We provided our environment
like this slash, whatever the is
we have, we provided like this.
This is exactly what we did, guys.
Correct?
Correct.
So now now what we did,
this particular part
also we provided in global variables,
including slash, including slash.
You'll see here if I go in my post
and if I click here
this value in blue slash also
and you see
these values include slash answer.
So Dennis, coming back to your point
right, you were writing this part
with Slash in between guys.
Then we knew we needed to slash
and when we
we don't need, we don't need.
So now what we will to simply see this
and then this is the variable.
Whatever the variable
we are passing the end point.
That's it.
So now, now update this particular part.
You're not opposed to it.
How first
big this value for created
a mini user.
Create a main user, go here
and instead of writing this particular
mark, create
a mini user.
Find create admin user
mind worked without any input, yet
it wins because see this is just a
you are a great.
So when you provide this video when it
considers everything without double.
Yeah.
But it should provide because this is
the variable that we need to provide.
Fine.
Now what is the shortcut for curly braces?
Shortcut.
Curly braces.
Then you
now see
it is giving redirect token rate
so I can call the generate token.
And here also it gives me
you would miss
you are it so this you are a value
Let me take you want correct
shortcut for card levers is a shortcut
I don't get
I didn't get the question on
would it simply shifted
Take that and
shift and break it that's
that's the way to create the levers.
I mean shortcut for you just based it on
I pasted the value not the Charybdis.
Yeah I didn't.
I didn't. That's what I'm saying.
So force to save it
then save this part.
And now here, here
after creating the employee
right here also first provide this
sees create employee.
Take this data and save it
create employee
now similar similarly here
get one employee part so go here
and then ready to get
good employee.
Get one employee.
See? Thanks.
I think you're trying
and after this going to get all employees.
So just update this thing, guys.
See how I'm operating the perimeter,
get all just type what you're looking for
and it will give you
if your values are correct,
if your values are going to.
Right.
So here again, get employee status.
Then here
I'm going to get the job status
after job status
here, I'm going to provide
for update employee, right.
So be right here.
Update employee
This one is for see
partially updated.
Employee
This one is for
delete or
now let's try to run this.
Please provide Employee 80
So since I have provided this data,
tell me guys why
it is not working.
Why it is not working
is because because when I predicted
this barred their data here
their data from here is gone.
Right?
That is no query barometer which I am
passing from my global variable.
So to parse the query parameter here,
I have to write what I have to radiate
underscore.
I think this is the value correct.
And here I can provide
the value of a created employee.
So let's take this value
and we will provide it here.
Fine.
See? Now, see
what happened?
I deleted that employee.
I didn't need
working.
Fine.
It means my you ordered in my one
employee quotes that I'm working fine on.
Okay. See
guys, are they working
fine or not?
Everything looks good.
We get all employees
you can even cross-check while
sending the request to see working fine.
Did job creators update the employee
so for that
you have to update this employee.
We just update the employee from here on
point saving
this belongs so see
now guys is
still one thing is pending what is that
there is one thing is pending
what is there any barometers?
I don't think so. Parameters
that we need to see.
We already provided the parameters of this
to you.
Token.
Token we have generated.
It is valid for 12 hours. Right.
So we don't need to generate the token
delete employee parametres.
Well we delete employee
barometer is something
less how to give or
delete employee parameter query better.
We have these.
These are the things we can sort it out
at any point of time.
So this is not a big deal.
One thing to remember,
we wrote one user story
we wrote, but you have
you will need to update 1000
tokens, right?
We don't
believe me.
We don't need any help.
We So now, now,
now the next thing, what we have to do
is the next thing, what we have do is here
we will simply verify
and validate the feeds.
Whatever the response we are
getting, we have to verify and validated
and how we can do it.
So if you see if you see here,
there is an option GOI test
available, can you see the best option
available here?
Everyone.
So here
Faustman says if you want to write test
for verification and validation,
write your test.
Even in manual testing also.
So the way we write code
in automation is doing
Postman allows us to write code.
Anyone in manual, as Gwen
understood this,
understood this, remember,
remember
when we talk about test in Postman
So here, here in this post,
when we have to write a script in,
we have to write a script
in JavaScript language
now which programing language
we are going to use based
JavaScript.
How many of you
guys know how to read the JavaScript code?
No idea. None. Not me, not me.
Regularly, no issues,
although I know it is called
Google Need and copy paste.
I know when I am, but systems don't
google mumble. Right?
And unless someone
fluent.
So now.
Now here in JavaScript,
let me tell you what your postman
postman says.
You have to write your
the script in JavaScript language,
but even if you don't know
JavaScript, don't ready
just to let me know what you need.
I'll give you I'll give you a reading
the code
Faustman says I will give you an email.
Good.
So just know that it are one
no going to give that name right?
So now here in this post,
the best quote is
you just you should know what you want.
Postman gives you everything
you can verify, validate your fields.
You can be the status school.
You can write your district
even for writing the test.
You don't need to write the programing
languages script.
Just call
and it will give you already prepared food
for the school district.
Everyone.
This part JavaScript, the language
which we use to write the test script
in order to it is JavaScript.
42nd thing
what ever whatever we do, whatever we do,
they will use an object called e m
What is the name of the object
been in the screens for
almost 20?
Horstman
Lane Horstman Can you see
So now,
now here let me show you one thing, right?
Let me show you one thing.
Go here and I am going to write
one thing here.
Try library,
try library and you see.
Nicole Long Right, So you'll see here
this is the part.
Try library, try a solution library,
main post main use,
Try a solution labeled form
verification and validation points
right the way we use unit assertions.
We use test in assertions.
Similarly, here
we will use GI as solution.
Now ask me what is the meaning of chain?
Everyone knows it right?
This is GI
E Exactly.
This is the assertion based
community,
not this chain celebrity.
This check
object.
But so this GI library GI,
a such a library
was to be used in this book
and called it everyone
writing.
Whenever you get time,
you see all these things,
you will find everything
in this library partly by default.
It is available in post.
We now what this library does.
So we will use this beam object
to perform all the assertions.
What kind of assertions?
Whether my
status code is what I'm expecting or not
is correct or not.
Whether my state, a school
district or not,
even if my status code is correct
in my body, I'm getting a bright idea.
Mark Let's say employee
what I am getting first name or not,
but I'm getting middle or not
or I am getting last name or not.
Okay, fine.
I'm getting middle name now.
Stimulating. Funny.
Is it like plugging it?
It is like plug in,
but it is already everybody close to me.
Fine.
I'm getting employed
if we need a false name.
William Last name is mine
for we go to this particular.
Value or not,
we will limit once to this value or not.
Last name is equal to this bendy one,
isn't it a video demonstration?
If we are performing Now tell me guys,
this is what we do or not any
guys.
This is what we call assertions
verification and validation check points.
The same thing with performing Selenium,
also known.
I hope everyone is getting my point.
What I'm trying to explain here
and excluding the industry, fine.
Let me explain it again.
Using this child duty child child library.
I'm seeing this is my state school,
but I'm not verifying that.
I know
right now I'm not.
So using that child name, I will verify
that this is the school is 200 or not.
Also, we can verify in the body
we are getting employed or not.
We are getting employed.
Middle name or not,
we are getting employed.
Last name or not, we are getting employed
but simply a solution.
Alex How we do a solution assert,
assert equals assert
or assert to like this.
Okay,
this is simply assertions. We are done
right.
So now this is
the first layer of assertion that we get
a status code is correct.
On the second layer of assertion,
I expect in these keys in the body
hardly or position, I'm expecting
the values of these keys in the body.
So for example, last name is visible sign,
last name is visible
are the last name
value is the last name value and done?
Yes. The meter then correct.
Otherwise not correct. No. Understood.
What I'm see
silver now understood
what I'm trying to explain.
Now see now We'll see how easy it is.
First date one employee.
I have made this request.
I want to write a test.
So first I have to write that.
Okay, I will verify
my status code is 200 or more.
Right?
So tell me for getting one employee
what is the successful API status code?
When I consider
data API, explain what it is,
what should be the status?
Good. It is 200. Correct.
It should be 200.
So no, no.
Let's write
and let's write our first test
for this particular part
our first test for this particular part.
So like I said,
we will use JavaScript language
using beam object using beam object.
So how I can write can you see
what is snippet option available here?
This one is snippet
option available in this case.
Go in this snippet
option and select from here.
Select is status code is 200.
Can you.
It says a status code code is 200
and you see it
click on this.
Simply click on this.
And the moment you click on it to see it
gives you already written test
in. You
see here, simply click on it
and it gives you this particular
status code automations available.
You read this is the test is script,
this is the test
descriptive
only everything was So is it like this
now see, now see,
I told you this beam is the object.
This the test.
So this is destiny.
You can change this name
according to your case.
For example.
Point and see really fine.
When you find that the
is data scored,
it is similar to your scenario name.
You're providing the names of verify
this data score is so it says beam
door responds dot to have a status 200
is this written in JavaScript?
Yes this is JavaScript language
so function simply means method.
This is the name of your method
and this is the code
which will find your history
discord, whether it is broken or not.
And that's good.
Is this underscore to be one?
Whatever.
See, let's let's run this time.
Let's run this time for specific
and then then send
right
in does not exist.
Who deleted this employee?
Come on.
Wait, wait.
I believe that you would
no see guys here.
No. See,
someone is always messing with 80.
You work on connect.
So now you see Lubo.
Sorry no one see this are going to it's
going to snippet and there is an option
called a status code.
Colon code is 200 and you see
colon code is 200.
So just select this one, click
on this particular one
and then you get this data in this part,
you can change the name of the method.
This is the name of the function
you can change, right?
And once you change
the name of the function, this is the code
that will identify and verify
that this data is doing this.
And then see,
we don't forget to see after received.
When you click send,
you will get this resolved.
So now here you see when the
multi cookies
headers and Easter results
and you see dates distributions give
everyone.
Now click on this just results
click on this distributions.
What is this it says verifying
that their status code is you'll see
code is you write 200
and then simply send it again.
Now states is verifying
that the status code is 200.
So now you are providing verification
validation check points.
Let's see, I'm going to change it
intentionally.
I'm going to make it feed.
I'm writing here to zero one
Sigma is what I'm doing.
I'm going to make it feel
I'm writing to zero one here.
Can you see every 1 to 0
one simply sending
those is verifying that the status code
is 200.
Assertion
and expected response is 201. 200
is empty.
Today's the same kind of assertion
we provide expected
an actual value right?
Right.
So now when you provide
this is the correct 100
and then when you run
it will radically verify
that the strictest code is 200.
Correct?
Correct. Wow.
No. Now, see now see here.
If I want to verify something, something
here, what I have to do, zero one.
So fine. Let's go into that test.
It's going to test and select here.
Select.
The first thing it is is data scored.
It is two. So is this correct?
Then I'm going to check 200,
but I have to change.
This should be
this should be 201201.
And then
and then simply simply let me change
this particular part in the body
when I'm going to change it.
Good. Three, one, two, three,
seven.
Send it.
So now you'll see this
resources is strictness
code is 201 and the statuses
boss can you see
and you see this guys
I hope everyone is understanding
what I'm trying to do here
now now let's go up
state made here to school
and step four to the mix.
The next thing which we are going to do,
what is that thing that see,
when I'm using this particular part
to generate the
I'm getting 200 fine.
I'm getting this 200 totally fine.
Perfect.
But I can't rely on the state discord.
Remember?
Remember this case?
I can't rely only on status code
because sometimes
we have seen in the API
that even if my status code is
if that is a problem with the body,
there is a problem with the body.
Right? So here we have trust issues.
So what we are going to verify I'm seeing
fine fine, let me write test.
So in their test first I'm grading here
and okay,
you are returning my 200 point
return with 200.
I don't have any issue, but
but here I want that in my response.
Body 200 is the first condition.
Second condition in my response body.
I need to
I have to
check whether you are generating the token
or not.
Right.
So here
there is another method in this nipple.
It's called response
Body response Body can banes stream.
Can you see the is
this part contains a string, click on it.
Click on it. Right.
And he and it says is trying you want to
search so what I want to search
by is what I want to search.
I want to search token simple
I want to search token prime see would
now see posted check is there
discord is 200 is there discord is 214.
Second, it will check after
getting that body in the response body
whether this particular value token
is available
or not sent.
Now see it says body matches is
green is status code is daunting.
Let me intentionally change it.
I'm token one now see running
it says is there discord is 214
but Baltimore just expected
is this one but you got token one trade so
see it is working absolutely fine
cutting, cutting, sending it will jump.
And then you see what is the most
you guys getting my point.
You obviously this is just inserting
because here this token comes May
this is the value, the same value
we have to pass here.
This is the key.
So guys should always be the stream.
All right, guys.
All right.
So now here in the node, I have to write
in those daemon
the use
be object.
Write
this in
the JavaScript language here
cause when you
try library for assertions.
Right.
So remember always goes to mine
comes with comes with
the in java script. They'd be
great guys
we all can
see it comes with built in JavaScript TBA
and after this here beam is the object
what is happening
Beam is the object.
Of course.
Postman Beam is the object of postman
that allows us, that allows to use,
that allows us to use different methods,
different methods available
available in API.
Right guys.
So now what are these different methods?
Beam dart, extreme
beam dart Global.
You see here, if I go in my postman
and you see this 2 p.m.
not expect
anything like this beam not response
rate right,
but expect beam not response
beam not to have beam or best
all of those things beam notice
this one Also
these methods is a part of industry
in big JavaScript API.
Right?
So here beam dart est
is the next one and then beam dart
request is next one.
Not like this, but I think what you
write based beam dart expect beam global
beamed or test beam dart request rate.
These all are the methods.
They are some more which we use every now
and then bombard send
request rate and that is beam
I believe is that at the vibration data,
something like that beam directly.
So these these are the methods we have
in beam beams supports all these methods.
All right.
All right, guys.
Now here, when we talk about
when we talk about try a solution library.
So we need to understand
what is this chai?
What is this chai Association library?
This is something we need to understand.
Okay,
so now when we talk about chai, a solution
library basically will be right next
to provide verification
and validations in the post.
We have to use chai a solution.
So by default you can read the same thing
in the website
also since we are in the class.
So this is my responsibility
to tell you all of these things.
So remember, remember
Chai at a social library, right?
A social library
supports
it. It is a text.
The way it has been implemented,
it supports
reducing text only.
Right?
So now why we use Brigid's in this case,
the what is the main reason behind
it is index
going again
by you
to reach out is data.
It is that enable it is easily readable,
easily understandable.
So your child library read
even though you're not getting this
as a as the in one word you see.
It's very simple response to have status.
So in response we want to have the status
that is 200 we are expecting
in the response of text that it should
include token, it should include token.
This is what we are doing or not.
Great.
Still. Yes.
Correct. Behavior driven development
becomes more than known.
I people can understand right now
let's add at least one best in every one.
So if we are creating the employee grade,
what is the status quo?
Should I click?
What is the status quo?
And I should expect to create the employee
201201 or get one employee.
We have test four create employee.
We have test
for getting all the employees
go here and anyone from here.
Right?
So let me take the same one for two zero
working fine.
See would
get employee status again
going to their test,
use the same one, see
all the great methods
having to double zero.
All right.
If you want to send any verify
any particular field
that also you can write,
it is completely your base
input input also raised
guys golden badge so wonder 201
Updating the complete information
of the employee needs.
Come on guys.
Updating the complete information.
Right.
So after completing the updating the
complete information, the status is 200.
Right? So I'm going to see over 200.
And when we talk about badge, then
for banks, this should be 201.
Here you can change the values.
For example, you're updating the position
information, right?
So when you're updating
the partial information, right.
Do you have to do
but I'm reading the partial information
if I know what is Dick anything.
Right. Big anything.
And then according to the things
which you are taking,
you have to change your expectation
and you have to change your expectation
values.
Correct?
Update Partial employee information.
So this should be your
it should be Roy underscore it
saved
doing this for
this information.
So you're also providing this
on your question
what kinds of saved
job title
employer status Get one employee Fine.
So now every single thing is fine, right?
I'm also
right.
delete employee
intentionally updating the token.
Yes. Yes, we are doing great.
We are doing that.
So this is the token. We got the new one.
So let's make it done.
This token.
Every everywhere
names.
Please don't use my email. Okay.
My employee
is don't use this.
So now,
now everything is completed, right?
Everything is completed. I have here.
You see all the test I can see
based on their test
I can see here and always tell me
this test symbol is green.
Every right.
So now, now tell me, are we in a position
are be in a position
to run our collection, not
just first?
Tell me one thing.
How many times
we are generating the token,
how many times
you are generating the token?
Multiple times.
I mean,
every time we are generating it, right?
So now let's see what we can do
going to these headers
right this time.
This time, instead of going from here,
going to the headers
and here in the header right.
Authorization rate.
Authorization What?
We should wait here.
This is can
you see what I'm reading?
Authorization. Okay.
Now in authorization,
what I am going to do see,
this is the value of my token.
And what kind of token is this?
What kind of token is this?
Reader Token. Right.
So can't we pass this bearer
token as my global variable
days so that
next time I don't need to change
values everywhere.
Okay, Just one place. Change it.
So go here
click on this icon,
click on edit option here.
Simply write JWT
and then here
when it comes to go away the value.
So how we provided the value first
first here we have good right
virus space, the value
beta space value
player.
We want them to
base clear
go into global variables
via clicking on icon,
Click on Edit in global variables
Under global variables,
add one more variable JWT.
Provide this value as beer space.
Beer is based.
You can see it gets updated.
So simply saving
simply saved after saving it.
What you have to do is see here go.
You don't need to select
anything from here right.
Going to the body,
going to the header and here write
authorization
authorization.
This part.
And here Google
simply provide JWT in
you case here provide JWT JSON token.
So this value will be phased
from their part from that bar
next time you have to update their token.
Just updated it one place and it will get
updated everywhere automatically.
Save it
now. Please send
working fine days are still
employed, created
is still working fine.
So now let me quickly update
let me quickly update this bar everywhere
going to headers,
click here on authorization part
and then simply
a W to see
go here,
select from here, not go into headers,
link here and write for authorization
and then simply g w e. See,
this is one time
activity that we have to do,
but for next time
for it will be able to handle that thing.
So next time,
if we are going to change to token,
we have to update it
just one place and it will work. See,
now you see
every single kind of constant
sort of get across this.
Yes. Connect kind of parameters
that we are passing from one place.
So next time we don't have to change it
1000 places.
We just change it one place.
And these things will get updated
everywhere, correct?
Everyone.
And as everyone goes
now, now this time,
this time, what I am going to do
is I'm going to run the connection
because we are done
with every single thing.
So I'm going to run the collection,
but I don't want to delete the employee
so I can exclude this part.
I don't want to generate a new token.
I just generated a digital token
so I will exclude this smart
admin user, exclude this part also.
So let's run this particular version.
Understood.
And this could implement what I'm doing
there is I excluded
admin user because I don't want to create
again, I don't want to create
token again, I don't want to delete
my employee as of now.
So I'm excluding them.
The remaining big ones
will be the part of my collection.
Now let's run
now you guys see
guys see here.
Nice.
It says create employee boss status.
Go to get one employee.
Really find their The status code is 200.
Get all employees 200 here
it says a status got 200 but in assertions
it got 404 not found right
and in badge in page
it says expected response to have a status
could do zero one
but got 200 but got 200 right
so now now let's fix this error
first come here try to run this
See it says employee not found.
Employee not found.
That's why Let me in.
I need to it.
It's working fine.
This is the employee can
go here
and update this.
He is a made this data employee, not 406.
Now let's try run this code
again.
It says employee not found against
but the employee 80.
What is the reason
now this should work
now this should work. See,
I go and I click on line collection.
I don't want this. I don't want this.
I want this run.
Now see, all this is working fine.
Just one is failing.
So let me update this one.
Let me take this part from here.
This part and put it in the body.
Because in my body I'm not changing it.
There's the issue
I have to change in my body.
Also, employee saving.
Now, this time, if I had
run this particular connection,
I don't want the user generated there
to delete the employee simply right
now. See that it's all pass
guys all boss
right there.
So when you create your entire distinct
right
when you create your own API goals,
the best thing is
the next time you come to the office,
you just open your boards to me.
Click on one command,
it will run all your API is
check all the responses for you,
all the users.
It is just a click of it. Now
everything is ready.
You said to create a new token
find generated and put together.
One is simple
admin user one name activity.
Isn't it? Very simple.
Tell me now.
See one more thing
I would like to show you in this post.
I don't want to see only the status quo.
201 Instead I want to see.
Okay, I'm getting this message
employee created
or what if I'm getting employee created?
Message
then only I will check and I will see.
Already
everything is working absolutely fine.
So how we can check it? Go here.
Go here.
Right.
Copy this particular part from here.
Or you can call it directly from there
also and basically iterate.
So I'm going to write here
really fine
that the message is, is
message is visible. Right?
So what is the message in terms of text?
I need to employ
employ, create,
read, employ, created saving.
This time run this simple one query
going to this resource.
It says verifying that
the message is visible so it is passed.
Can you see this one is passed is status
code is 200.
So this one is also must
guys.
So voiceover
What is the bricks be used for?
Verify response body contains a string.
This one responds body contains string.
Real welcome.
So guys, everyone completed what.
We did.
Everyone understood what we did.
Let's do another collection
one last time is are still
the collection is limited to time
because we're talking in this.
It will last for time.
Let me add one more point here. First,
let me open generic to complete it.
For example,
what example I'm seeing right cannot see.
For example, I'm seeing, hey,
I know you're generating that you're
creating the employee in the database.
Okay, Absolutely fine.
But but you are taking a lot of time.
You are taking a lot of time.
I don't want this much time.
I want you to create my employee
in 500 milliseconds.
It means employing 5 seconds
if you are not able to create
or even just one second,
1000 milliseconds,
if you're not able to generate
my employer, create my human brain,
what If I'm signature in one second,
I will not consider you
that your application response
time is good
if you put the token in headers.
Do we also?
No, no,
we removed it from the authorization.
That's why we put it in others.
So for that you'll see
it says the response time is less than 200
milliseconds and you see
response time is less than 200
milliseconds.
Can you see guys, another snippet here?
Guys, can you see another stupid snippet?
You click on this, click on this.
And here you are taking that
okay response time.
I should see it.
This should be less than 800 milliseconds.
So just change them and you do it fine.
You change them a little, do
this time when you think
it says response time is less than 800
because the total time
was 551 milliseconds and you see
deadline 5 to 7.
I see.
We have taken this line from here.
Jason, I'm sorry, contains the string.
The response body contains string snippets
in snippets.
Can you please check
rate and this the nine line number 1911
we got from your response
time is less than 200 milliseconds.
This is the name of the function.
You can find it here
and you can change simply the value
here, the value which is going verify.
Another
thing you can verify what is the header
we are passing?
Let's see, I'm passing the header
which is containing.
I am seeing
I am sending contain ap delete.
So please check in my header
content type is available or not.
So see, I am seeing content present.
So in the response also told me
that I'm getting content type or not.
I can take.
Let me run it again.
How many test for this can you see now?
So in headers
if I go I see content date available.
So this content night
in the response of the body,
my paste is verifying content type.
It is verifying it is on state,
it is verifying message is visible.
It is very
plain is to underscore this stored
content.
I recognize
students
any questions or
this is I am creating it in way
I'm not working with any 80
this is the create employ.
How did you add the second one?
When did the messages as well?
This one Well, what
one with this one
Herman you find.
So here you see it says response
body contains a stream
the scene when you dig
and you just renamed the method name.
That's it.
You can give any name,
whatever the name you want to give.
I give that name and I provide
the message, which I want to verify simply
this one in header we are seeing there.
The content type of my body is just right.
Similarly, I didn't get that,
but how did you run all your methods?
The same thing, man.
This is what we called winning collection.
Simply going to collection.
Click on this three dots,
Click on collection.
Select
what all are the methods you want to run.
So for example,
I want to run this six seven methods.
When you do the one you want to include,
click on them.
The one you want to exclude.
Just don't pick them and simply run it.
See, it is working for all this
for everything.
It is working fine.
So here
when we are taking this content type,
it simply means the body
which I'm sending is having decent
of export and import rate.
So one will work on the business.
Wizards simply say work at eight.
It started with the
can you show the test for create employed.
Why not so that you
so now we
we divide this content in headers
because the response
we are getting in this body
the response we should
is also having this content type.
But there is just an example I gave you.
If you want to verify something else.
For example, in the response body,
you want to have poisoning
type closed to create content,
a duplicate header.
Just read response, not text to include
so in the response it is.
How did you save on dry?
You should not be.
You should see we don't drive in your post
when you already
created a workspace inside your workspace
you have this collection.
We can simply export this collection
anywhere.
Right?
So this is going to click moment.
So you better.
Basically it is collecting to
it is connected to the Postman Cloud.
Right? And there your workspace is mixing
and if you are
exporting to some place
simply provide that you are
right
in that you are ready to provide anywhere.
Right.
For example, here's
the share collection rate
because this is not the city,
this is not the status quo.
This is the name of your function.
Just change in lane number.
The status code is 222 to 0 one.
So it will give you a square disco.
This 201 is checking
in. You see that city?
No issues
could not save
your request.
Invalid character
inhaler content authorization
JWT. Please check the value
is take the value there for saving
the correct sequence
of creating new collection.
Find in this find Definitely
So to create a collection
here, let me write.
Create a collection
was to take on
an icon
and name the collection
in the list you need.
All the necessity
is in
that request
and the collection.
Click on
three dots
and select
the here
Next number of
vibrations
Delayed Dying here
exclude
include
list.
This is
and also
then in spite
I'm going to pause to create. No,
now you have every single thing
available here.
All right, guys.
So far any question
I think we are done with the postman.
The manual testing of API
we are done with.
Is there any question
If you have, please ask.