Soon.
We're calling
and you guys hear me? See the screen?
Everything is good.
All right, Perfect. Perfect.
I mean, we are good to go.
How's everyone doing?
Are you guys excited
for your second class?
All right.
Any of you, by any chance, looked at
what Agile is?
Some of you did.
That's good.
Okay.
Even just a little bit of.
Even if you just watched a five minute
video, I think that's good enough.
So you will have an understanding.
We'll go quite into it today.
We'll cover a lot of terminologies,
but trust me, guys, don't freak out
if you don't remember all of them.
Over the next six months,
this will become very easy for you.
So if it seems like a little too much
terminology,
you just don't get scared by any chance.
Agile.
You know, in the tech world,
you know, sometimes very simple things
are complicated because of different
wording, right?
So that's what happens,
unfortunately, sometimes
very easy things because of the wording
and the vocab is very different.
You know, the lingo is always different.
So it kind of throws you off at times,
but it can be very simple things,
agile. That became my philosophy.
Absolutely. We're going to get into that.
Yeah, just just a lot of terminology
and you will get used to it.
Agile
is probably going to be more important.
Waterfall was great
to know how it is though, but
because a lot of industry
and the industry, a lot of companies
are going towards Agile, so it's important
to know some of the terminology.
But before we get into it, let's do this.
Let's do a quick recap.
What did we cover yesterday?
Let's cover quickly
what we cover yesterday.
We'll go for this, spend about 10 minutes
on this, 15 minutes, and then we'll
jump into
Agile.
So who on to get started.
Okay,
we did Waterfall and we cover SDLC, Right?
All right, so let's do this.
Let's start off with SDLC.
First of all, what does SDLC stand for?
The software development lifecycle.
Okay, great, great, great.
Now it has some phases.
If I'm correct, right?
What is the very first phase
in the planning phase?
Right.
And we talked about the planning phase.
What really happens in the planning phase,
Something would be a meeting
with the customer.
Yes, Well, very beginning,
of course, in the planning phase one.
Part of it is they do market research,
feasibility study.
This will come basically
from the client itself.
They will understand.
And if something, let's say the product
they want to develop,
is it worth it for them or not?
Then there's an individual
that works with the client.
The customer, right?
We call him client and customer.
Who is that individual?
Very good business analysts.
Are you guys becoming business analysts?
Is it, you know, Right.
But is good to know what they do,
What what do they do?
Basically,
what do you guys think what they do,
they document, read,
they gather requirements.
They basically pick
the brains of the customer.
What exactly they want. Right.
And they make something called a BRT dock
and business requirement document.
Those are basically what is not.
Let me ask you, what is a requirement? It
what is
the requirement?
What the client customer wants
basically Absolutely.
Is the functionality.
Remember that
now we're coming into the tech world,
so we'll try to use more tech
related words.
So functionalities of the system,
the target system
that the customer wants, needs,
whatever is the right.
So that's basically
what that requirements are
and that the job of business analysts
to gather all of that
document, all of that, right,
they are the one documenting all of this.
So they will have a conversation
with the customer.
We call the customer, we call them client.
You know, they do the talking.
They do all the different type
of requirements.
You know, they grab all those details.
And when they write all those details,
that's something that we're going
to be working on in the future.
Now, they could be talking to listed
the business, corporate individual
or also the end user.
What do I mean by the end user?
Basically, the people actually
who will be using it, Right?
So the example yesterday I was giving you
that I worked for United State.
Well, I was working on a project
for the United States Postal Service rate.
I r t
would meet the corporate business side,
but then the end user will be the people
actually at the post office.
Right.
Who are running basically the post office
or the post man, you know,
those are the end user.
We were just dealing with the customer
in the sense of the business side,
but the end user are the ones who actually
get to play what with the software.
It's something you creating,
so you're picking their brains,
stakeholder, other management people,
anyone who's a very,
let's say, experienced individual
in that field or in that company,
whichever it is, right?
You're picking all their brains
to basically get all the feedback.
Now, this picture
I showed you guys yesterday,
how the requirement gathering can go
sometimes wrong
and this is a very true scenario
and we look at it in the tech world
today, we're going to go into a little bit
of project failures and etc., etc..
So you kind of get an idea
that job of is the job of a business
analyst.
Important guys
on a 1 to 10 scale.
How important is it
if the ten heads of that?
Ten. Yes, absolutely.
Because everything starts
from there, right.
So if the customer explained, let's
say a swing with three outermost steps,
you want to call them or seats,
you know, that's how they explain.
It's the job of the business analyst
to make sure they get
the requirements precise enough
so that we we can develop them
a system that they exactly one.
But what happens
unfortunately in the tech world
and it happens a lot of times
is how the customer by explaining
how the other rest of the team
might understand might be not exactly
what they think they were building. Right.
So a lot of time gets wasted on this
if this is not done accurately.
That's why I said this picture is a true,
you know,
of fact of, you know,
what happens in the tech world.
A lot of projects
that fail can be like this
and it can start off
from from the very beginning.
What is a good way for a business analyst
to gather requirement
using what type of creator area
you would say smart radio, Right.
Smart basically means specific,
measurable, attainable
or relevant and time based realistic ones.
You know, things that make sense.
You know, a customer can require
want you to build some crazy
new application that's not even possible.
Or maybe whatever it is right.
But, you know,
it's the job of the business analysts
to make sure that the customer understand
that, hey, we can actually do this.
We cannot do this right.
I give you an example.
Yesterday's well to that, you know,
our company, Hewlett Packard Enterprise,
got this project that the customer
wanted to be develop in one year.
And we knew from day one it was not
possible as a three year project.
So, you know, it's important that,
you know, it's
we get the right requirements
and those requirements can, you know,
can tell a completely different story
if it's done the right way.
Right.
And you can come up with a very successful
project.
But, you know, the requirements have to be
clear, it's not important for you
in the sense of gathering the requirement,
but you are still involved as a tester.
What are we doing?
When do we start beginning testing?
Tricky question and see,
do we start testing after
the development happens or do we start
at the beginning in the planning part
when requirements are gathered, new
Agassi You got a little bit confused.
Yeah, it's good. I'm glad.
So yes, of course you do.
The actual coding and everything,
you know, you do all that.
But when we get the requirements, you
remember this, guys, You remember this.
A testers job is to test
those requirements.
The is basically
your putting your input from day one.
Of course, you're doing all the coding
and everything later on
when the development happens. Yes.
But without let's say doing actual
technical or coding type of testing,
we call this verification testing,
basically checking the requirement.
Are they correct?
Are we giving it a different angle?
We look at it from different perspective.
Maybe they missed something great.
So remember this one
when a business analyst basically
gathers requirements straight
from the client, they go back and forth.
You know, those requirements are
then brought to the team, the entire team.
They are meetings on these
and you will be attending these meetings,
especially the project is brand
new right at the very beginning.
You'll be attending those meetings.
The business owners
might be going over each requirement.
This is what the customer want,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, etc..
There you can look at those requirements
to be like, Hey,
what about did he,
the customer want this feature as well?
Do we miss this?
You know, you're basically analyzing,
breaking it down.
See if you're missing anything there.
So we technically
start testing at that point.
But this testing, when you call
this, is more verification
of the documentation
of the basically the requirement.
So it's not actually doing
coding in manual in automation testing.
So it's happening there.
Is it possible waterfall to.
Absolutely, it's possible.
The same exact thing.
Remember this we as Tester,
we're there to break the system,
so we play around with the application
that's created in multiple ways.
We do everything
so we get a better feel of it.
So we're always in the habit of,
you know, like like I said yesterday,
we're like detectives, right?
What was looking from different angles
and that's what we do.
So when it comes to basic
these requirements and these requirements
at the beginning is gather
and you are involved in these meetings,
you can analyze this thing.
It doesn't have to be that you come up
with, you know, some flaws
or maybe some things like this that, hey,
maybe you missed this requirement,
but it's important that, you know, you
you as a tester
is involved in that and analyzing
these requirement and looking at them.
You could use the same smart criteria
as well, too.
So it's not your job exactly to
to get the requirements,
but to look at them, analyze them.
Absolutely. You can do that.
All right. So now the planning is done.
What comes afterwards, guys?
The design phase, right? Okay.
What happens in the design phase?
What exactly happens there?
The architecture of it. Okay.
They design the wireframe, they go
someone use the wireframe.
Lifeson is basically the picture, the,
the whole style of it, actually,
you know what? Let me do one thing.
Let me show you what a wire film
looks like if you haven't seen one before,
let me see Wireframe.
Then you pull this up. There you go.
So right here, quickly, I just brought up
you see wireframe, right?
These type of design.
Just look at this one.
A wireframe right sign in here,
it goes here, etc..
This is for an app, for example. Right.
The layout, the mockups.
This is what a designer is doing.
And they're trying to also make sure it is
nice and clean the entire process.
You know, it looks esthetically easy.
I look esthetically looks fine
and at the same time easy to use.
Not this is what who does this part of
basically coming up with idea?
What is that individual call,
not the architect.
Great
UX UI UX user
interface in user experience.
Yeah those
you'll see sometime you call them,
you might hear them as product designer.
This is actually a title and individual
who does this.
So this is what they're doing.
They creating this.
Now an architect is thinking of,
okay, honey service do we need
And they will also have, let's
see, conversation with the developers.
Which programing language
are we going to use for this project?
You know, there's different
programing languages out there is Ruby,
there's Python, JavaScript, Java,
C++, C-sharp, so many languages, right?
But the team, the technical individual
decide, okay, this we're going to
which database we're going to use.
So a lot of
this is happening in the design phase.
And also very important to understand
is in the design phase,
they're also thinking of the future.
Is the system going to when, let's say,
more customer comes, will more traffic
comes on the system,
Are we going to be able to scale it
by scaling means, can we upgrade?
Can we handle all that,
you know, traffic and things?
So from the hardware perspective,
the architect we're looking at so quite
a bit, you know, they involve multiple
members are involved in the design phase.
We as a tester are not really involved.
Yes, we might attend the meetings.
No, but
we are not doing too much in there.
Yes, I live yes UI in UX
UI UX you will always see UI with a slash.
That's usually the title
of a product designer UI UX.
And you will notice,
I think when you go the higher
they call them product design designer
do test.
You use hacking tactics? Not really.
Security
testing comes a little bit different.
is more of a cybersecurity approach.
They will do it.
They're called penetration testers.
They will do that. All right.
So now after the design happens, wait,
what comes along
after this
development implementation now?
Are we developing as testers in here
as well to
say it's a yes or no?
No, All programmers, right.
Developers, software engineers,
whatever you want to call them,
they have different titles. Right.
They are the one then basically
are the one coding,
making sure whatever the picture is UI,
everything comes to light.
Remember I said the skeleton
is that that the design basically
and putting the muscle on a skeleton
is what the job of a developer is.
They're doing all of that.
So they're bringing that UI, UX,
all of this
that you're seeing, for example,
these are just images, right?
They're bringing it to life by adding
code behind all of this.
So right now the signing button
you will click on, it's nothing,
There's nothing but the coding
that we add, CSS, JavaScript,
all the different coding they do,
they add behind it, it becomes to life.
That's what the developers do, right?
So after the development is done,
what happens afterwards?
Testing? Absolutely.
You guys come in to do the testing.
That is your job by this point to test
the system, making sure it's working fine.
What happens if you find some issues?
Do you fix it?
Do you as a tester, fix them or no?
Good job, guys. Yes. You don't fix them.
You report it to the developer
and they fix it.
We never fix any of the bugs.
We just report and identify.
That's where our job stops.
Basically, fixing the headache
can be a whole the developers headache.
That's their job to basically fix
all of that right now after this,
what happens usually after all the testing
and everything is done, we go live,
we deploy, it goes to production rate,
production basically means it goes live.
And after.
When it goes live, yes,
there is some maintenance afterwards, too.
It depends.
Some company does maintenance.
Some companies don't do it
at all. Depends.
And maintenance
means that log system is up and running.
Maybe they'll have two or three
people just keeping an eye.
If something goes bad,
you know, they'll fix it.
But usually when something goes live,
it goes to production.
This this will have basically
a little bit of maintenance.
Will a tester be similar to a copywriter?
I'm trying to understand
this more as an analogy.
I don't know what it does,
to be very honest with you.
So I'm not sure I'm
sorry about like happily that
when a copywriter does,
I really don't.
Okay.
But it basically doesn't
make sense, right?
It makes sense after the production.
Basically we're going into the maintenance
by remember,
some companies do maintenance,
some companies don't do maintenance.
That's why
I didn't make another slide for this.
I just put it in the picture.
Okay, it's there.
That's fine, though,
but this is what happens.
Planning
allows for design, implementation,
testing and means is
this is software development lifecycle.
So this overall is the key structure
behind any and every software.
Now, I explained to you guys yesterday
something called Waterfall.
So what do you think waterfall is?
When we brought Waterfall up
to buy,
what do we see our methodology, Right.
Methodology of development.
Yes, absolutely.
I mean, this is basically a companies
way, a process that before
they're following SDLC. Exactly.
But they're following it in their own
fashion, their own way of basically
creating this software.
Now, when we say methodology, right, look,
a company can do things
in whatever fashion they want to.
It's an approach.
Yes. It's an approach of SDLC,
how they do it, how they do their meetings
when they want.
They can make changes.
They can make changes
whatever they want to do, basically.
Right.
So what were some of the advantages
which let me ask you this.
When do you use waterfall?
When it would be a
best time to use waterfall in
small
and simple projects, when you also have
very, very clear requirements,
Very key to understand this,
when there's a clear picture,
when quality, not speed.
Right. That's very important.
In an agile, we going to we're more
focused on speed, not so much on quality.
And I'll explain to you that later on.
So when the client won't change much
scope, the project is more straightforward
forward, easy
to understand, easy to manage.
It's a step by step process.
Can it work for long projects?
It can work.
But again,
you know, your your your very beginning,
your requirement has to be very clear.
The one thing in waterfall rule
you mentioned
is the disadvantage of it
is you cannot make any changes.
That's one of the biggest
this is management, right?
It's a step by step process.
Once a step is completed,
you cannot go back.
So let's see, design phase is done.
And in the development phase,
developer thinks that, hey, the design is
not done in the right matter.
Sorry they can't change anything now.
Then it goes to testing.
Now in in waterfall, when we find bugs
and we find flaws,
are they going to be fixed or no?
Yes and no.
Someone said we are 5050. Yes.
Now remember this guys, when we are in
waterfall, still as a job, as a tester.
When we find issues, laws rate.
Those can be fixed.
The only thing that cannot be fixed
or change is requirement changes.
Remember that you will find bugs,
you'll find bug.
They're going to fix it.
But a requirement changes.
Let's say for
example, a feature. Let's see
o'clock
in feature, let's say time
processing one right is on a page
on the left side of of a page,
for example, it wasn't working.
You told developer fix it,
but it should be on the right side, right?
That would be a new requirement
to be on a different page
or different part of the application.
That's a requirement change right?
That's not allowed.
So remember
this, bugs can be reported in waterfall.
Absolutely. And they're going to be fixed.
A lot of people get this wrong that,
hey, you,
when you find bugs in a waterfall,
you can fix them.
So that's not right.
Bugs can be fixed.
We just cannot add new requirements.
So we look at it.
One thing that happens is a lot of times,
guys, time gets cut.
Shorts toward the end always happens.
And they rushed testing
one time and budget
is basically cuts
who decide which method to use.
Well a lot of times
it's the upper management that decides.
At the very beginning, though, remember,
let's say,
for example, Bank of America
hired Deloitte or Booz Allen Company,
of course, experience individual from,
let's say Booz Allen can suggest
we would like to create this application
using this methodology.
Or maybe let's say that the client can say
we want you to make this
in a waterfall methodology or this
So those things are decided
at the very beginning and more
on the top management I tester developer.
Yet we don't have the authority
in that sense that comes from the program
managers up top who decides and work
really with the project
gets said they're the one deciding that
so basically are too risky
change of course we went over this but
this is a sequential process as we see.
And yeah, one step is done.
You cannot go back majority of the,
you know, government agencies,
they are the one who use waterfall
private sector all to use the waterfall.
But not as much as basically when it comes
down to the waterfall methodology.
So quick recap.
Does it make sense?
Can we move on guys,
after this and get into a new topic?
All right.
So if someone didn't understand,
hopefully with a quick
recap, it made sense.
So let's move on to today.
What we're going to do
is we're going to break down
basically what is Agile, what is Scrum
Fear Framework, Scrum Artifact
and some scrum roles basically.
So we're going to go into
another methodology which is more popular
a lot faster.
You will decide if it is good or bad
after knowing
some pros and cons about it
and you'll understand this.
So let me ask you this
before we get into tech.
I like to bring some other examples
right through you guys.
Which restaurant, a fast food restaurant
do you enjoy with a fast service?
Let's think of this.
Tell me some restaurants
that has a very cool process.
You know, McDonald's, That's fine.
Chick fil A is okay,
but think of it in the think of Agile
where, you know, when you go
in, you get your product and you go out
and now a Chick fil A
Walmart does not count as fast food
as subway or subway can be looked at.
And I say subway or let's say Chipotle.
Right.
Did they stick out to me more?
Now, of course, McDonald's.
I'm glad that you bringing McDonald's
if you guys haven't watched this movie.
It's called the Founder.
Do watch that movie talks
about how McDonald's became
massive because of their of their process,
how they change internally,
how they became fast.
Yeah, that movie.
I love that money.
I'm sure you love money. And the movie
so you don't get it shows
you're very insight into all of that.
Right.
But Chipotle let's talk about
just Chipotle or Subway, right?
Why I like Chipotle and why
I picked Chipotle out of all of them is
just think of the church
supporting their process.
What what makes it so amazing?
Why do you guys think
Chipotle is so successful?
One of the reasons they're cutting
invented the assembly line type of thing.
Basically cheap and good.
Everything is in front of you.
You're going to line.
You pick your for example, let's say,
first of all, one of the beautiful thing
about Chipotle is
you can see the entire kitchen,
what they're doing,
if they're using gloves or not, what's
which is nicer.
You can see all of that.
But you go like an assembly line, guys.
You go and you pick your bowl or let's
say, I don't know, burrito, whatever.
You pick all the items and right behind
you are
their customers are coming
the same way and out the way you go.
Basically right now, of course, after
Chipotle they you know more restaurants
came and everything they follow
the same process cilantro, rice and
I guess are making you guys hungry
already.
Right.
But if you look at it, you know,
and if you look at it from the
the way how they operate, it's very quick,
very fast.
And you get exactly what you want.
And out the window you go basically,
it's a very fast pace now, if you compare,
let's say Chipotle led to, let's say,
a different experience rate,
let's say, I don't know, Olive Garden.
Right. A dining restaurant, for example.
What is it time for you
to get food in a dining restaurant?
Let's see.
How long would it take?
20 to 40 minutes.
30 minutes sometimes. Right.
It takes a lot longer.
What we say? Who makes more money?
Let's say a dining restaurant
or fast food?
More like fast food, right?
Because they're serving a lot of customer.
They're doing a high volume.
They're doing at a very high volume.
Now, of course, they experience
in a dining restaurant would be a lot
different in the sense
you were romantic or this and that.
Whatever special occasion.
But at the same point,
if you look at it, two different concept.
One is serving a lot of customers, right?
If you want to serve a lot of customers,
you cannot make a customer where customers
wait 20 or 30 minutes week.
That's that's why fast food
chains and restaurants, you know, they
they're making a lot of money
because they have a process.
They have a entire
process that's, you know,
worked on.
It has been improved
over the course of years.
And they can serve a lot of customers
through that process.
It's very fast rate.
So when we think of that, you know,
when we think of Chipotle,
we think of Chipotle as as Agile,
where we're going to go in
to basically a more into the
the technical part.
But think of it as more agile over the.
Now let me give you another example.
What is guys
which car do you guys think that is
probably the most popular or car brand
that's the most popular in the world.
There you see the cars everywhere.
Any part of the world.
You go into Hondas or Tesla,
as someone said, Tesla,
but no Toyota guys, Toyota,
Toyota, Toyota, Chevrolet.
I yeah, but more if we're talking on
a global scale, I think Toyota wins the
the game in there.
Remember guys
Toyota was one of the very first companies
in the 1960s that kind of use agile
process in their assembly line,
in their production facilities.
Right.
That's why they're able to churn out
so many vehicles.
And when you turn out
so many vehicles and things that age,
the cost becomes very low
because you have so much surplus of it
out in the market.
Right.
They're able to they're able to produce
cars at a very low cost.
And even the maintenance of a car
like Toyota is very cheap
because so much parts
and so many Toyota's are out there.
Right. It makes it very cheap.
But what is the success behind Toyota
is because they use more of a lean,
agile process in their assembly lines
at the very beginning.
Today,
we're going to find out some meetings
and things that, you know, you will do
when you're in an Agile project.
For example,
they used to do similar ways in the 1960s.
So remember this Agile?
What were we going to learn today?
There's not only applied to it,
it can apply to any industry
and it comes way before that.
In the sixties, like I said, is
when Toyota utilized Agile methodology.
So it basically,
you know, really changed the game
of how they produce cars and how many cars
they were producing get the
Uber equals 90% of Toyota.
I'm I'm sure.
Well, they're very reliable cars.
You know they're they're cheap
and they're and good quality cars
that they last for a long time.
Okay.
Let me give you another example,
just so you can
basically get the bigger picture
and then we're going to start jumping
to more agile.
Now, if I were to basically let's say
I have a customer, I give this example
every time I do this class.
So let's say I have a customer
who places an order for manufacture,
let's say,
I don't know, a table, right, for example.
And the customer gives me
the specifications.
Wait, I want a table that's wooden
with four legs green legs, whatever it is.
Read all the specification.
And two weeks later, for example,
it gives me, Hey, I want this table,
custom table to be built in in two weeks
and it's going to cost you.
I'm going to pay
you $200, let's say, for example.
Right. So let's say I work on the table.
Everything I put the color,
put the pieces, different type of wood,
whatever it is, I do it.
And let's say two weeks down the road,
I give this to my customer
and the customer is not really happy.
They're like, Hey,
you're wasting my two $200 on this table.
I don't like it, right?
Go ahead and make changes.
Most likely
what the the manufacturer of the table
would say, basically, okay, you know what?
We're going to charge you
another 50 bucks for making these changes.
Wouldn't that be very similar to,
let's say put it this way, more waterfall,
right.
Very similar to waterfall approach
in, let's say, creating a table right now
if we were to do this in a agile
manner. Right.
So let's say I've been given a two weeks
time frame and $200 budget,
so what would I do? Right.
Let's say on the on the third day
I call the customer, Hey,
customer, you know, I've chosen this would
which what do you prefer
Which material let's say.
Right.
Which type of what are you preferring?
The customer might say, okay,
I like this one better.
Right. Let's say, for example,
I like this type. Okay, great.
You've selected
this type of wood for me to go ahead
and let's say peruse the table.
Okay. A week passes by, right?
And then I give a call to my customer
and be like, Hey, by the way,
these are the legs.
They're looking green color
or let's see a blue color, right?
Or would you like to change them?
Or what do you feel like about this?
Right.
Let's say the customers say,
you know what, I think I don't like this.
I think I would rather have blue
color, let's say legs for this.
Let's say table right now.
Okay, No problem.
Okay.
So now because they wanted some changes.
Just letting you know
that is going to take
instead of two weeks,
it might take two weeks and three days.
Now because of, you know, let's
say some changes going on that you want.
Okay, Let's say two weeks and three days
passed by.
Now, remember this.
You talked to the customer a few times.
You got some feedback. Right.
And by the way,
I know we're not going to charge too much.
The bill will charge you $230 instead
of, let's say, 200,
all which was previously because we spent
additional three days customizing the.
Now, would you as a customer, rather
pay 30 bucks
more and get exactly what you want?
Or would you rather pay $200 and start
from all over scratch?
Majority customer will pay $30 extra.
And yeah,
it costs a little bit more though, but
they get exactly what they want, right?
Because you got involved
with the customer, you involved them
and basically got their feedback
and made changes.
Now the customer's happy,
cannot say anything they way
you didn't build this according
to my specifications and we do great.
So think of that now as agile, right?
That is what Agile is.
You got the customer involved,
you got the feedback.
Even though DEADLINE got pushed back
from two weeks to two
and a half, let's say,
and it cost a little bit more.
But the end result is very different now
in Waterfall, if, let's say, for example,
the $200 that you all paid for
the let's see the table
and you hate it completely,
they got to start all over.
It might cost $300 additional or 200 more.
Right?
So this is a good way to compare how Agile
and Waterfall is, just the involvement.
On a very basic level.
Does it make sense, guys?
Continuous improvement.
Agile. Okay. All right.
Yeah, I'll try to break it down
in a non-technical way.
Get the picture and then you will see less
related to the tech war, right?
So let's break down exactly what is agile.
Let's look at that bookish in definition,
right?
Let's see.
Agile able to move quickly.
Everyone knows that easily.
I t definition Agile is a time boxed
iterative approach
to software delivery
that builds software incrementally.
The key word is incrementally
from the start of the project
instead of trying to deliver all at once.
So just look at this picture here.
This a big rock
and we have pebbles, right?
Rather give small pebbles to the customer
instead of giving a major
big rock at the very end right?
So when we talk about Agile,
we're doing this.
And the very important thing to listen to
is a time box, the term approach.
What does that mean
is that you build the stock
or the
the product in small amount of deadlines,
let's say in a very small timing,
which I'm going to explain to you
in a little bit, a little bit more detail.
Right.
Agile came as a solution
to the disadvantage of Waterfall became
instead of a sequential process,
Agile was an incremental approach.
We remember it's doing everything.
We still see what is doing it on a very,
very small scale.
Instead of spending two months,
six months, seven months
is developing this
following all the processes of SDLC.
But in a short amount of time
the teams start off
with a project design,
then begin to work on small modules.
Right?
The module is done in weekly
or monthly sprints.
I'm going to clear what the word is sprint
and the end of each sprint.
The project priorities are invalid
and tests are run.
So when we talk about now Agile,
right in Agile
we say if a project needs to be done
in specific sprints,
what we mean by sprints
is basically the timeline, right?
So a software, you cannot build the entire
software, let's say in one year, right?
So you have to break that one year project
into sprints.
By sprints we mean is is a time
frame is the time frame, right?
When we say one week sprint,
that means the software
is some part of
the software needs to be built in one week
and then customer needs to be sure
what's built, get feedback, etc., etc..
So in Agile
there's only four type of sprints,
one we expect two week sprints,
three week sprints or four weeks.
It depends on the companies right?
Basically
when a company says that we're going to do
we have a two week sprint,
that means everyone is given
the task for two weeks
to be completed by that specific deadline.
So the following Friday in two Fridays
is basically
when we're going to be finished and
then we're going to get our customer well.
So remember the word sprint.
If it's more than four weeks,
you know, it's not really agile.
When we go to
when you guys go to real time companies,
you will see companies
with either do one week or two weeks.
One week is a little too fast,
I would say.
But there are companies who do one week.
A lot of times you will see
two week sprints in three weeks sprints.
That means that, you know,
you will have two weeks
to do all the work,
do the coding, development, everything
and you need to will be finished
within the deadline of two weeks.
If you don't finish in that day,
you know, you have to
then finish that at a following sprint.
So what happens after the sprint is done?
Guys, you have to show what the customer,
what you have
develop in those two weeks
and get that feedback right.
The same way I gave you the table example.
So remember this
everything is done in Springs.
Now one thing is whenever you join
a project, great, tomorrow are
the sprint time.
Do you think they change
or they remain consistent?
What do you guys think
know?
So if, let's say the company says
we're going to follow Agile methodology
and we're going to build this software,
let's at the very beginning
we're going to follow a two week
sprints cycle basically.
No, it won't.
Basically the entire project
will go on to experience
for the entirety of the project.
It never changes.
It doesn't mean that first, let's say
two weeks, you guys did all the projects.
Now company has decided to do three weeks
or one week.
No, whatever they said from the very
those are the schedule.
They're going to go on
for the entirety of the project.
So remember this the sprint is consistent.
It never changes.
So if your company is doing a three week
sprint,
they're going to do three weeks
for the entirety of the project.
They're not going to be doing one.
Let's say one sprint is three weeks.
Next Sprint is four weeks.
The following is five weeks.
No, never, no, there's no flexibility
in there in that sense, actually.
And remember,
if they're doing five weeks, six weeks,
they're not really following Agile.
Now, one thing, remember this Agile,
what I'm going to explain to you
is the what we go through in details.
These are the rules that needs
to be followed to do in the Agile way.
But remember, a company can change.
They can come up with your own rules.
Remember that?
What if they can finish
in a specific frame?
Good question this year, if they can.
Finishing that for sweeping
that test needs to be completed
in the following sprints.
They can finish it.
They can be easy
and I'll show you what happens in
and how we play around with this.
But it has to be if they finish, yes,
they go up, though.
It goes back to the backlog, which
we're going to cover in a little bit.
It goes back to then.
We worked on it at a later time, too.
So now if we
look at these sprints,
allow for bugs to be discussed in fixed
the customer feedback is in Co Inc before
starting next sprint.
So you see a sprint is done in two weeks.
We got some feedback,
we showed what we've done.
Maybe customer didn't like what we did.
They can add changes and those changes
will be implemented in the next round
of work, let's say of two weeks,
which would be, let's say a sprint
right.
Okay, I got it.
I got your idea. What you mean.
So remember this, You're working
hand in hand with developers.
So let's say you have a two week
sprint, right?
The developer might be coding,
you'll be waiting on that whatever tasks
you're assigned or working on. Right?
You waiting on them to finish.
Meanwhile, you might do other work
to see you work hand in hand.
Let's say it's the last week and two days
left and the developer hasn't finished.
What you're supposed is this.
This is something you bring up
then in the media.
Hey, I have only this amount of time left
and I'll talk to you about the meetings
and things like that.
A little bit later
we'll make a little bit more sense to you,
and I kind of show it to you as well, too.
But yet use a
you don't just wait on the developers.
You work hand in hand.
Companies
do change a little bit sometimes, but
you work hand in hand basically.
So this is agile.
Now, one thing just to game to agile
makes sense already.
Probably, probably already
think that is awesome, but
there are some pitfalls to it as well too,
which we will cover in a little bit.
But before I get into this too,
what is the manifesto of Agile?
Just to got to give you a little bit
of background of what Agile is Agile.
As I said, you know, in the Agile
process started even from Toyota
in the early 1960s, but in 2001,
a lot of these top developers,
people, influential people
from the industry of software
development, tech world, they gather up
and they came up with this idea of agile
right in this meeting,
an idea basically these,
you know, profound
people who are influential,
they basically came up with the idea
that, hey, instead of
what are the things we can change,
they compared it to waterfall, right?
What are the things that we can change in
how we can make the process better?
So individual interaction
or comprehensive?
One thing I didn't mention too much the
but in waterfall
there is a ton of unnecessary
documentation maybe to someone
they might think it's important,
but there's a lot of documentation
and a lot of paperwork
whenever you're doing a waterfall project.
So their idea was like, Look, we shouldn't
focus too much on documentation.
Instead, we should have more interaction
within team members
and basically maybe the client as well. To
the end goal should be basically more
of a working software than again,
more of exhaustive documentation.
Why the reasoning?
By the way,
documentation is heavy in waterfall?
Because look, in waterfall
the projects can be for five years, right?
Or four years. Right?
Every phase
everyone wants to secure themselves
the design phase wants to do
all the documentation, everything.
Hey, we did everything right.
We did everything accordingly.
They develop mean testers.
They do a lot of these unnecessary
documentation,
which I'll talk a little bit later on.
They make all of these documentation
because later on when the project
and you know, you have all the paperwork
and everything there to show the customer,
Hey, we did everything right.
So there's more of that in the customer
collaboration versus look at this
with nego contract negotiation
in Waterfall, when a project ends,
let's say
you want to make changes and everything,
you kind of have to write another contract
for me to do all the changes you want
and probably pay me a little bit more
money, right?
So that's what they want.
Responding to change
then following a direct plan, basically,
meaning if boosting technology,
let's change, adapt
instead of whatever we set in stone
in a contract, we must go buy this.
Right? That is not the approach.
So this idea came in early 2001
and from there on is when we start seeing
more agile slowly coming into the software
development industry, basically
less document is
more meetings, definitely
a little bit more meetings in here.
So let's look at some things
when to use adjust
when there isn't a clear picture
of what the final product should be.
This is very important, guys.
Remember when I showed you that picture
of requirement gathering and everything?
A lot of times, guys,
when the customer seems uncertain
or doesn't really know
it is the best process
to use or the best methodology to use,
because with the feedback and everything,
you know, you kind of get
what the customer want
when there's really a big picture.
Now this is also very important.
I'm going to clarify this
when rapid production is more important
than the quality of the product,
and I'll give you some examples
so you'll understand this one.
Clients will be able to change
the scope of product
when rapidly changing standards.
Okay, so what does it mean?
What do you guys see
when rapid production is more important
than the quality of the product?
What do you mean?
What do you guys think? Why?
This is very important to understand this.
What happened in HP
when they want to beat the game?
Look, it's also very important
to understand in the current world.
Let me give you some good example
so you kind of get the big picture.
Okay, release product
and fix bug on the way.
Yes, that's the way to look at it.
Let me ask you this.
Microsoft, Apple, all of these companies,
do you guys think they're waterfall Paul
or IBM or Amazon or they're Agile?
Which one do you guys think?
Agile. Right.
You're able to say Agile now.
Why do you think they're agile?
What makes you think why do they or not?
Waterfall in more of an Agile approach.
What what do you guys think?
The reason it's
competitive, there's a lot of,
there's a lot of competition, you guys,
a lot of competition and technology's
changing all the time, right?
Think about this way guys.
Still, if Apple was not competitive
with, let's say, Android, the changes
in everything, releasing so many things
every time you would fall behind.
Let me give you a very good example. Okay.
On the app stores, for example,
for companies that are very,
you know, let's say
Uber or Lyft or whatever,
when you see those negative reviews,
let's say the one star reviews
and everything, do you think they care
about those reviews?
They do companies
that are more agile, right?
They actually care about you
because your customer is telling you
this is not working right, blah, blah,
blah.
It's a Why do you guys see
so many updates to an app?
Have you ever understood this?
A lot of times there's a lot of bug fixes,
a lot of things that customers
want an improvement
rate feedback has been given.
You see all the time
there's an update available for
for your phone or some apps and everything
because through that updates
they are changing this things still,
if they're not going to be
competitive guys, these guys,
they're going to die out for example.
Then when we talk about competition,
let's talk about something
you guys majority we can relate to, right
In the world
of social
media, Instagram was a picture app
and then something came
like Snapchat stories and everything.
Right now, Instagram, Facebook owned,
they wanted to compete with Snapchat
and they want to destroy them.
And what did they do?
Does anyone know what they copied?
The story mode, right?
They copied the stories from basically
from Snapchat, the exact copy of it.
Now, why did it?
Because look, guys they're in competition.
You have, let's say, ability to user using
Instagram and then let's say Snapchat.
I had about 200, 300 million user.
Now with the new it's
you can call it copying and everything,
but you know, they were competing.
They were like, Hey, if we want to
stay relevant, we want to succeed.
We need to copy kind of
and come up with a similar things.
Now, when we look at it
in the current market, they're not focused
on even, let's see, Snapchat
now they're competing with Tik Tok.
No one but Tik
Tok is going to come out of nowhere
and they're going to become
such a massive thing.
Now, officially, Instagram announced
that they are no longer
a picture based software or app.
They are more of a video app.
So now their new thing is reels, right?
So you see competition is killing
these guys.
They have to be up to date.
If the real software or the real
feature of Instagram is not doing
well, people are going to jump on the Tik
tok right along the competition.
For them to come up with these changes
all the time, they can not swallow
Waterfall guys.
Absolutely not possible
if they're going to waterfall
waterfall methodology, they're done.
So they do.
A lot of these companies are fast paced
because keep in mind
there's a lot of competition, but
at the same time they want to be relevant.
If you want to be relevant
and be ahead, you have to adapt, guys.
You have to adapt.
Look at companies that did not adapt.
Nokia, BlackBerry, outdated, right?
Outdated. They dig.
They completely got destroyed.
They should have.
When Apple came up
with a touch on the issue of Oprah,
they should have launched something very
similar right away to be in the market.
Right.
But see, that's one thing to understand
the big picture.
So for companies like this,
why this is important in coming
back to the point when rapid production
is more important than the quality.
Because for companies, think about
the original Facebook, how it look versus
how it looks now, it's important
for the companies to put the product out
and will fix it along
the way, will improve it,
but we need it to be out there
because there's a lot of competition.
So main goal is to bring
something, develop and put it out.
We will fix it. Over
time, bugs will be found.
This in that customers will tell us,
Hey, what's wrong
or what needs to be fixed right?
So for a lot of these agile based
companies, you know, that's what they do.
They want their product to be out there
instead of waiting five years
or a few years back.
You know, it's not the right approach.
So quality is not important.
More of the speed of it is more
important here when it comes to Agile.
Maybe now it'll make sense
why a lot of these companies
don't care too much about the quality
at the beginning.
Of course they care about the quality,
but they want to be out there first
because too much competition technology
is changing and they can change it.
If you're looking for perfectionism,
it's not going to happen.
You know, it's just not going to happen.
You waste more time.
You need to be out in the market first.
That's what we talked about.
The evolution of technology has to be
because so many things are changing.
If we don't stay up to time,
you become obsolete and outdated, right?
No. Look at big companies are blockbuster
Kodak, all of them.
BE We're not keeping up
with the competitors.
Maybe their approaches were wrong
or whatever they were doing.
That's why they're gone.
Larry So this tells us basically why Agile
focuses more on the rapid production.
And a lot of times, like I said
over at the beginning, when there isn't
a clear picture, a lot of the customers
don't know what they want. Read
I remember how Facebook used
to be different.
Absolutely. Absolutely.
Now, advantages of Agile
guys allow for changes.
Agile allows for changes to be made
after initial planning.
Changes can be made per client request.
Basically, look, the client is paying you
millions of dollars.
They have the see to change things
any time they want to.
Sometimes it can be very back
to the project that I'm talking about is
when I was working with HP
and we to go with our to our USPS client.
Man, those guys were idiots.
I'm sorry, but those guys were not smart
about the managers or the people,
like I said, who were in charge.
They were making changes every two weeks
like crazy, like whatever we built,
and they were scratching out.
Of course, HP is not going to care.
They're getting millions of dollars,
but developers will sometimes get
basically a little discouraging,
like what in the world?
But remember,
the client is being millions of dollars.
You got to listen to what they want.
If they can make up their mind,
that's their thing.
But at the end day,
you're pleasing the client here. It's
so very important to understand.
At the end of each sprint
project, priorities are evaluated.
The client can add their feedback for the
next sprint to get their desired product.
That means whatever was built basically
within two weeks
will be showed to the client.
They don't like it.
No problem.
Okay, we'll change it if it costs more.
Whatever it is.
Now remember, this client is happy.
They're getting what they want.
Sometimes it can become a little costly,
but at the they're,
you know, satisfied testing completed
at each testing at the end of each sprint
sure that the bugs defects are caught
and taken care
that means we are building this product,
big product piece by piece.
Right. And we do testing
and development on each piece.
We're not waiting for
the entirety of the product to be finished
and then doing testing, very big.
Important to release product
at the end of the cycle.
Product is launch
at the end of each cycle, all the testing
and development is completed
before going to production. Now
technically they can launch the product
after two weeks if they want to.
Let's say they made a login page
or a home page where they can launch it.
Companies tend not to launch everything
after the end of the sprint.
They technically can.
They will combine couple of streams,
so it's a more of a bigger picture.
But they technically can launch it
if they want to.
Right.
So understand that that by end of that
two weeks, if everything's good,
this product can go live meaning
it can go on.
WW W and what our website is,
it can show up over there.
Customers might not launch it
right after two weeks, but they had
big can basically any sprint one week,
two weeks, three weeks, four weeks,
they usually come back. That's usually the
the trend,
but they can do it if they want to.
Now let's look some disadvantages.
There are some disadvantages.
We actually sorry,
I think there's still a
focus on advantages
I thought we go to the additional
advantages again are people interaction
that we looked at the agile manufacturers
face to face conversation regular
adaption to changes in circumstances
and late changes is welcome.
So this advantage
now this can be basically so basically
every speed is going through SDLC.
Yes, basically UI at the beginning
they're more involved design phase,
but they kind of phase out later on.
But yes, basically requirements
that they're all the things are happening
in that small sprint, small little one
on a very small portion basically.
Now there are some disadvantage, right.
Less importance to given to design
and documentation that does happen.
I like I said, design gets a little bit
not as much utilized
maybe at the beginning of the project,
but later on their use of design does not.
But documentation.
Documentation can be good,
but sometimes it can be bad
if you don't have too many right.
Unclear requirements
leads to a messy project.
This is very important.
Unclear client requirement.
You need to do a messy project.
Remember
Agile said that Hey, it's more for people
who have no idea what they want,
will work with them.
The same example I gave you, right?
My our client us
because they didn't know what they
so they would make changes all the time.
Now that can sometimes lead to messy
project, right?
Because the client doesn't know
or their expectations are something else.
They wanted something else
and they do not communicate.
Sometimes it can lead to a messy project.
It can become very confusing.
Remember,
we are in Agile, a client pleasers.
That's what we care.
As long as the client is happy,
will do whatever they want.
But sometimes the clients can be idiots
if they don't know what they want
and they making the changes a waste.
A lot of time and money.
But at the end of day
they are aware of this.
So there are some pitfalls to that,
to bigger and complex projects.
Difficult determine
the effort estimation at the beginning.
What does that mean?
Is that, look, when the client
is not very certain of what they want
and they are not sure, it's kind of hard
predict that, hey, this project
will be done in one year or two years
because, look, they can be very
they can they
they might not have an idea
if they unsure of what they want.
It can turn out to be a very long project
because they think
the of their professional.
Yes decision.
Well remember for every company
you go at a higher rate let's say
let's say you work at a bank
who makes the decision the teller makes it
or the bank branch manager rate
more like it The branch manager, right.
Let's say for example.
So the same thing, of course,
they will listen to
the people developer tester, but
remember project managers, product owners,
you learn some of these titles.
Now they're the one making the decision,
but of course they'll have a conversation
within the team.
But at the end of day, priority,
same thing applies into
when we go into I.T.
You have managers director
so me those people,
they're the one who makes the decision.
So which one do you guys think
is better now?
Now that you have an idea of
waterfall and agile or
will you be agile?
But the key to deciding which matter it
comes down to the context of the project.
Remember this.
This is very important.
If it's going to change rapidly,
choose Agile.
If you know what exactly
you need, choose waterfall.
So if you really look at it
guys though it again it comes down to
what what
the project is, who the client is. Yes.
In reality, if you look at it, Agile
looks a lot better and it can be better.
But keep in mind,
Waterfall is not a bad methodology.
It just only works in a specific scenario.
It works better in specific circumstances.
So it comes down really there to that
for government waterfall, for private
sector agile, that's typically the case,
but also depends on the client.
Can you do an agile waterfall?
Catalina Absolutely.
That is a great, great way.
Notice you do
you remember this company's remember this.
They do not follow all the time
100% of agile or waterfall.
They can mix and match,
they can add things in it.
I usually I made up my own words.
Some companies all exaggerate,
which is like
they have some things from waterfall,
some things from Agile.
This happens all the time too.
So remember this.
Some companies I've seen where they have
two month sprints.
Well, if we follow exactly Agile
what it's supposed to be, there's
no such thing as eight week sprint.
We only have 1 to 3 or four companies
do that.
The project that I said was I was on
that was more of a waterfall
and agile combination
because we did not really finish on time
and things like that.
So companies can mix and match.
And remember, this is very common as well.
Two companies have,
they can come up with their own terminal,
they can do whatever they want to.
These are just best practices out there.
If you follow this way, you will be
successful and you will know how to
basically handle a project.
Can things change?
Can they add things to it
that are not part of Agile Waterfall?
This absolutely they can do
is their project.
Whatever they want to do.
They could add terms
that we have never heard of.
You might go to a company where let's see
today we clarify some terms.
We'll have a completely different term
for that.
Well, they came up on their own right?
So that is very possible.
All right. Does it make sense?
Are we clear on Agile
that we have a bigger picture somewhat.
All right, perfect.
Perfect.
Now, of course, we're going to
break it down a lot more in-depth.
But before that,
let's look at the project failure rate,
Waterfall and Agile Failure and Success
Project Failure.
Look at this guys.
Waterfall on a smaller projects,
11% failure in their medium
sized projects, about 25% of projects
fail.
It's a big chunk.
Large project, of course.
Absolutely we're talking about 42%
projects fail there on waterfall,
especially those billion dollars
projects that I talk about.
There are a lot of these you guys know
Obamacare project that I said
that was one point something I'm
not sure was an agile, a waterfall,
but it was a big project
that failed, right?
So big project, huge risk.
When we combine all of this, we are
what add we got what, 2070?
We have 78%, 78%.
Guys, that is a high
percentage of projects failing overall.
But if you look at it,
Agile is not like bulletproof.
There is some fairly here smaller one.
We have 4% medium to medium
project 11 and 23%.
Look, that's still a decent high
number, 23% project four.
So it's not like, you know, again,
I want you to just understand this.
A lot of times maybe the the project
philosophy or methodology could be great.
But again, if your management is horrible,
it's going to is going to end up
basically failing.
So there can be a lot of
reasons for the failure, but
we get a better idea of project failure.
A lot of times
the bigger projects tend to fail
and a lot of the government projects
we talk about numerous,
you guys can research it, lots of project,
millions dollars, 100 million, $200
million projects failed miserably because
sometimes they follow the waterfall
methodology, they have bad management.
So many things can be basically set
calendar.
All right.
So that's just to kind of give you an idea
of what Waterfall
Agile success ratio is now
what we're going to do.
Yeah, exactly.
Eugene That is a still a high percentage
if you look at it.
But remember, again, there can be
multiple factors or why a project fail.
Now Agile to remember
is the big word Agile methodology,
but not agile
have different versions of Agile.
Okay So what we're going to look into
now, sorry, it comes down to again,
remember that it comes down to
who makes the decision at the same time
depends on the project.
It's up.
A lot of companies,
like I said, still are using waterfall,
especially on the government side.
There's not really make sense.
But keep in mind
what you know here, I guarantee you guys
enjoy the people out there
in the management in let's say government
agency don't know this
that I can guarantee you this.
I remember this.
You guys are learning a lot of things
right now.
A lot of people don't know these things.
By the way, this is a harsh reality.
But when you go to the real world,
you'll see that.
And you might not believe me today,
but when you get to see and work
with government, private sector,
you see things that makes you like,
why is this really happening?
But you will see that
can the client choose the method?
Absolutely.
They can do that. Yes.
Can the client also change in between?
They could also depends.
It really depends
maybe on the contract basis,
but again, it comes down to remember this.
This game is all about making money,
right?
So one company like HP
wants to make money.
The other one was giving money.
Remember,
government is a printing machine, right?
So remember these these these choosing
of which methodology happens.
It comes from the very top, right?
It comes from the very top.
And they're the one deciding all of this.
Now, let's not get straight track.
We have a lot to cover today, Agile.
So when we talk about Agile, by the way,
there are different versions of Agile.
The best way to look at it
this way, it's ice cream.
Ice cream has different flavors, right?
We have chocolate, vanilla, strawberry,
everything, right?
We have different flavors of ice cream.
So agile is ice cream
and agile is different.
Flavor can be scrum, bon, Bon Scrum,
Bond priesthood, extreme programing.
All of this, the most popular 70%
of the companies used Scrum.
That is the most popular.
We're going to focus on Scrum today,
which is the most popular one
basically to use.
So look at this.
Remember Agile, the big word under that
umbrella, you have different flavors.
And one of them is Scrum. Right?
When we talk about this,
why so many different flavors
or different version came?
It came all from this meeting
at the beginning.
Remember, everyone came up with the idea.
Some will have meetings, someone have less
meeting, they'll do things.
The whole process, do things fast.
But these ideas
by these different people came
and some of them came
with a different version of Agile.
And now we look at there's actually
more than the one I'm showing you.
There's actually lean Agile
now there's scale Agile.
Geez, there are so many of them right now.
But the most popular one,
like I said, is Scrum,
and we're going to strictly focus
on this scrum and Kanban.
Another version of Agile
has little bit less meaning, very similar,
but some changes.
I don't know because once you're
a Scrum master, which you'll know
later on what it is,
you will know all the different one,
but we'll focus strictly on Scrum.
But remember there are
so when you go to a company, right,
someone asks you which methodology
your company use, you can say
you have to say Agile scrum.
Don't say just Agile.
I just come by defining it.
Okay. The company followed this.
Like I said, 70% of the companies
follow Scrum,
so we'll focus strictly on Scrum.
All right.
Make sense, guys.
All right, Perfect.
We can move forward now.
I'm going to basically funny names.
Yeah.
I'm not really sure who comes up
with these names of the common bonds
from extreme programing.
To this day,
I still don't know what in the World
Extreme Program is, but it's a version.
I have no idea.
I could care less
because I have not seen anywhere
or someone using this,
but they might be single companies.
Scrum is a framework.
Yes, that is one
of the frameworks of Agile.
I want to see the scrum on and everything.
Maybe they're similar.
I don't know why the name came with there.
There's some changes in there,
some some changes in there.
You have to do
a little bit of research on that,
but they're all of them
have a lot of similarities
and there's some differences too.
Yeah.
So Scrum
is also following the rules of Agile.
Now you see, guys,
what I'm going to show you right now
within Agile, we have certain things,
some people, right?
Product owner, Scrum Master,
we're going to look in all of that,
let's say in the scrum barn or something.
Maybe you might not have
some of these meetings, right?
So they're all very similar
with some differences.
Agile is there guys?
Agile is the philosophy.
The practice in implementation
would be of that Agile
philosophy will be Scrum, Kanban, Scrum
Barn or any of those other one.
The actual implementation is Scrum Kanban
or any of those and 70,
like I said, is using scrum
and Agile is the big picture
the philosophy of how it needs to be done.
That's what we looked at this picture
right at the beginning,
the Agile Manifesto, right,
what it should be.
And then in the implementation
they came up with the different flavors,
different version of Agile.
Does it make sense guys?
All right, perfect.
Okay, so now what we're going to do,
we're going to slowly break it down
and we learn Scrum. You will learn it.
So it might be a little bit
too much knowledge today, but we'll see.
Now, this is Agile.
Let's see how it is.
I'm going to just show it to you.
But this is exactly what happens in Agile.
You can take a look at it
for a minute or so, see if you understand
what in the world is happening.
Any idea you will understand
after I'm done with everything.
But let's see if you guys get understand.
Does it look complicated?
Yes or no? Yes.
No. Kind of.
Okay. Yes. Okay, It's fine.
And so what I first show this,
everyone gets scared.
So it's really not complicated at all.
When we break it down step by step,
all of this
is going to make sense to you,
is going to make a lot of sense to you.
But right now, it looks very complicated.
If I were to look at it
and I didn't know anything about it,
I would be freaked out, too.
But don't worry,
I'm here to explain this step by step.
Right.
Working as
are we going to use two different software
for testing this and all the same.
You mean like different testing to now
you should stick with one or whichever
it is, though
you might have different tools
and things like that, but you stick with
the ones
the company wants to hire you for.
Okay,
so now what we're going to do is look,
Scrum is an Agile framework
for completing complex training.
It is applied to any project
or product effort right now.
Basically, we're going to break down
exactly what happens in the day of,
let's say, of
Scrum framework, of Agile.
Let's say
I ensure we're going to get to that right
now, the backlog part, right?
So it's divided into three
different modules.
You can set rules, artifact
and semi rules are basically the people,
right, who are involved in this agile.
Remember,
like I told you at the beginning,
for some reason, I don't know why,
but they make complicated.
They come with it terms and lingo.
So that's why some people get confused.
Basically are the people who are involved
when we talk about artifacts
are some very important elements of agile
that makes it very special.
So we're going to
look at basically break down
what does product backlog split in backlog
burned out charts
are that we work with all the time
ceremonies, right?
Ceremonies.
It's a fancy word for meetings.
That's the best way to put it.
Meetings, All of these spring grooming,
spring planning, spring review,
all of our different meetings that happen
when you an agile environment, right.
But they call it ceremonies.
Don't ask me
why how they came up with no idea
they could have just called meetings
but they didn't right
So what we're going to do
is we're going to break down
each and every one of them,
and I'll actually show you real life
right here,
which I'll show you guys in a little bit.
In JIRA, how it looks like, Right.
How it really looks like.
So you
will get the real picture of how it is
and how you work will be basically
a distributed and how you do the work.
Right.
So we got to basically break it down.
We see top guy right now is product owner.
Who do you think a product owner
in this Agile scrum
framework would take A wild guess.
It can be the client.
Have you guys ever
heard of Project manager?
Yes, Right now in a
what are we going to Agile?
We don't use terms like Project manager.
They don't exist.
Maybe they will.
Some companies mix and match,
but basically that's
what the product owner in Agile is.
Look defines the item in the product
backlog, which I'm going to explain to you
or manage project features and release
to optimize our clients,
that kind of thing.
Great.
Or why Return of investment
dealing more with the client, right.
They are the one.
Remember that
they're the top dog for this project.
They're the one who are communicating
with the customer.
They're the one dealing with the customer
what they want, doing all that
they can remember business analysts is
just a person that might do the paperwork.
But remember this
when we get into the tech world,
you have hierarchy as well too.
Just like you would go to a bank,
you have teller,
you have a finance person,
you have a bank manager, right?
So in the same way in the tech world now
we have an individual who is responsible
for the success of this entire,
let's say, project Great.
That individual is product owner.
He is the decision maker.
One person
defines items in the product backlog,
which I'm going to explain to you
a little bit and show you.
That means they are the one who can see
what we need to work,
what things
we don't need to work on. Right.
Prioritize feature
according to user and stockholder needs.
That means after having conversation
with the client, let's see.
So let's say from HP,
let's say I was a product owner.
I had a conversation
with the other stakeholders and everyone
from, let's say the client said
the top management, whatever they want,
I can prioritize guys
after talking to blah, blah, blah.
Joe you know they want this feature go,
So let's work on this.
They're doing
can change of feature and priority
or every spring that means they can move
things around in a spring
what needs to be worked on,
what needs to be not worked
on, what can be worked at a later time.
We don't need to work on it.
Accepts
or rejects work from the development.
They can say, Hey,
what are we built right here?
I don't like it. Developer
You spent two weeks on this thing.
What we did? No, not good.
This is not what the client want
to scratch all of this, We can start over.
So remember that they are the big boss.
They are the top guys.
They are the one who talks to the client.
They're the one meeting
while they do all the jobs of basically
what a business end is supposed to do.
But let me explain this.
Now, this gets a little tricky in reality
when we talk about Agile, right?
Agile Scrum or any of them, the title
business analyst does not exist in this.
It's more of a waterfall thing,
but a lot companies,
I would say
probably 90% of them has a title
someone called Business
and who gathers all the requirement.
Actually
the person who's supposed to be agile,
who is supposed to do all that paperwork
and get all the documentation
is supposed to be a product owner.
And the product owner
does that to gather the requirements.
But a lot of times, like I said, 90%
you'll see in companies
they will have a business analyst still,
even though
it's not technically part of Agile, but
you will see that in almost every company.
So don't be surprised by this.
But they are technically
doing all the job of also
what a business and is does,
but they the big boss.
So usually
they don't do a lot in some companies.
Maybe the product owner will work
on those requirements and things do.
But a lot of times business analyst is
with them, they're doing all the things,
but they shouldn't be doing that.
But anyway, just to so you know,
from the real world, that's how it works.
Does it make sense?
Do we understand what a product
owner does?
Nobody can fire you.
Product owner can do that.
Remember, they're in charge
of the success of the project.
They're the one communicating with the,
with the clients, whatever.
Now, one thing, guys, one thing,
just to make it a little bit
does the job of buyer.
Yes they're supposed to they might not it
remember that they might not do this
so they're supposed to
some of them do actually do this.
One thing can happen sometimes.
Sometimes.
By the way, in some projects
the product owner can come from
the client side and be the one in charge
to have supervision over that.
That can happen sometimes.
So instead of, let's say the product owner
from HP goes over there
to, let's say, talk
to, let's say the client,
maybe sometime the client can pick
a product owner, hire and be like, hey,
have oversight, sit at Hewlett-Packard
in an office and watch
and do the things that can happen
sometimes.
Do remember this.
A lot of times it's, not usually
the client side bring a product on.
Is the company that's building
usually have their product order,
but it can happen to you
when you go to real world,
you might sometimes see that I have
some may explain that product orders from
supposed to be from the company we are
but it's the other way that can happen.
It just doesn't happen too often.
So just be aware that when you go to the
we will sometimes things are a little off.
It can happen, right?
But yeah, they're the one
usually controlling the project,
the one communicating,
guiding the requirements and everything.
And meanwhile
they have a system to help them out,
but technically
they should be the one doing it.
They're the jack of all trades.
Well,
they're the business people, remember?
They're the top manager.
Remember one time, by the way, guys,
a product owner does not have be
P or is product ownership.
People?
Yeah, a product owner does not have to be
that technical, by the way.
You don't have to be there.
Good communication.
They have some certifications
and things and management though.
Maybe you work in I.T
or maybe you have in some time,
let's say a project manager, right?
Some of them are technical, some are not.
Meaning they might not need to coding
and things like that.
Their job
is basically the business need to be.
They're working more on the communication,
making sure the client is happy etc.
so getting all the things from them.
So this is the product order
that is basically,
for example about the fish
eye issue.
What is your question, by the way?
I wouldn't
say Michael, it's the easiest job
because one thing I can tell
you, product owner is always busy
in meetings in 8 hours,
probably 5 hours, 6 hours.
They have meetings, depends on projects.
So they could be listening to the client.
This is not all time.
Sometimes it can be later adding to.
I remember that the product owner that we
had in my project, he was sick and tired.
He's like too many meetings, right?
So it depends.
Remember, sometimes they can be easy,
sometimes it can be a little bit
overburdening.
For me, it's still not clear who
the product which part of it is not clear
to you.
Asia get stuck in an issue in which
what are you not getting?
Product owner is the think of it
like in waterfall or something.
Project manager
Someone who controls the project.
A manager. Right.
When you go to a store, for example,
let's say you go to a CVS raid.
See there's, there's a manager
who hires fires
people, tell people what
time to come to work, everything right.
He's the big boss.
He controls that store, for example.
Right?
The same way in I.T.
Product owner is that top level management
who is in charge of this projects?
That is the person.
He's the head of the project. Absolutely.
Does that make sense?
I don't mean Jody.
We got it, but I want to make sure
I actually got it too.
He is your boss. Yes.
He or she is your boss.
They're the big boss, right now.
Underneath them
there is another person, Scrum Master.
Now we're going to learn a scrum Master's.
Yes, that's correct.
So then under the
product owner is an individual
called Scrum Master.
Now these guys okay, ensure scrum
is fully functional, improves quality.
Who is Facebook peer?
Who knows?
They have thousands of projects.
So within internally they have it.
Remember, guys, a company
could have multiple projects, right?
Multiple hundreds of project.
It doesn't mean
that I'll give you an example.
When I was in HP with the PAC Enterprise,
one of the project just in my floor,
we were maybe two aisles of Cubicle
and that was our UPS project.
The aisle next to us
was Department of Defense.
There was Army, there was Nasser.
There could be thousands of projects,
remember that?
And each project alone
can have a team of product owner Scrum,
master developers, all of that.
So don't get it
confused that it's one person
that controls the whole company, Right.
Just to make sure that you understand
this.
And there will be a lot of projects
out there.
Sometimes you might work
on two different projects.
That means maybe
you have two different product owners
because you might be
working on this project
and they might need you there too, right?
Yes. Paul is only in charge
of a certain project.
Yes, that's correct.
Can the product order be change one?
They can absolutely be fired
if they're not doing the right work.
Absolutely.
It all depends.
Yeah. Okay.
So now we know what a product
or a top tier guy does.
All that communication
is with the business thing. Guy.
There's the requirements as well to
we will
have those creating 1 billion roles.
We are part of the development team,
which I'm going to explain.
Okay, so now we know
product one underneath there's individual
Scrum Master.
Okay, this is important to understand
ensure scrum is understood in enacted.
Okay, I'll explain to you.
We should use the team
for external interviews,
communicates to product owner and team
does not make decisions for the team.
So a Scrum master is basically now
a supervisor.
Think of it this way.
Remember a manager you have in a
in a store or a branch, let's say,
and then underneath you have someone call
a supervisor or a coordinator, right?
A supervisor usually does
not fire you, hire you mostly manager,
but make sure everything is working
fine. Right?
Because remember, the top boss
is not going to come at the very bottom
to talk to someone, right?
They have remember this in it.
We have hierarchy as well,
product owner, Scrum Master,
and then the team right there.
Right.
So yeah, you can look at that
as assistant manager,
but not really are
let's say a coordinator, right?
So now what
The job of the Scrum Master is,
their job is basically to see, hey,
develop.
Are you good, Are you falling behind?
Is something wrong?
Like why are you not finishing the work
or whatever rate tester?
Are you good?
Is everything. Let's see.
You have a complaint, for example.
Hey, I want to raise
or let's say I want to do something right.
I think I'm
not going to be finished on tap.
You don't go directly to that
topic, to the product owner.
Let's see, I'm a developer. Some. Right.
You don't do that.
You would bring up your concern
to, let's say a Scrum master and Scrum
master will be the one takes it
to, let's say for example, to the product
owner Scrum Master also at the same
time is the one now in the team, right?
Remember product owner
could be always sitting at the client side
doing the meeting Wahoo in the back end
where the development is happening
to keeping track of everything. Right.
Are we on time?
Are you following
are we going to finish in two weeks?
Right.
Basically that's going to be the scrum
method.
Their job,
they don't have to be technical.
They don't have to be doing any of that.
What their job is, making sure,
everything is going accordingly, smoothly.
Are we finishing on time?
Do you have any problem?
If you have any problems,
you bring it to Scrum Master
and they'll try to find a solution
for you. Right?
They're Also the one. Yes.
They are supervising the team. Absolutely.
They're also the one who runs
all the meetings.
So all the meetings,
a Scrum Master run them.
All right, guys.
So we're going to have a meeting,
blah, blah, blah. Mr.
Whatever developer.
What did you work
on? Yes, you're okay. Blah, blah, blah.
Remember, they cannot fire you,
they cannot hire you.
They cannot tell you what to do,
but they can supervise
what's going on, coordinate
what's going on.
You have any problem?
You have too much work.
You falling behind.
You don't just call this a product owner.
You talk to the Scrum master.
They're the middle person. Remember?
They're the very middle person
who is overseeing kind of everything,
running all the meetings, are making sure
everyone is aligned, finishing deadline.
If there's any problem things either
let's say I'm stressed out or something,
I'll be the one talking to a Scrum master,
not to the product owner,
because one is at the very top, right?
The Scrum Master Nguyen Coaching.
We just supervise the Scrum Master.
A lot of times
I've seen some business analyst
becomes Grand master,
but they don't have to.
They absolutely don't need to know
any code or anything like that.
They're the co-hosts.
Yeah, Yeah.
They don't have to know any coding.
They don't have to be very knowledgeable,
the technical side.
But they need to have people skills.
They need to know how to work
with people, right?
They want
they have to be good in communication.
They need to understand how things work.
They need to keep the team
motivated at times.
Remember, a lot of times Scrum Master is
always like a motivator too, by the way.
Right? They're doing all right, guys.
They would add games to it
to make the work easier,
basic, make it more flexible.
Right.
And their work is I would say Scrum
Master is a little bit easier.
Yeah.
So this is what they do it again
at the end of it.
You have to remember,
don't make any decision whatsoever.
They have knowledge of the scrum.
They're the one involved in this. Right.
They're the one handling all the meetings.
They're checking up,
see are you falling behind?
They're checking all the schedule
and everything.
So they definitely have the knowledge,
but they don't need to have knowledge
of how software
is need to be done. And manage.
It doesn't need to know, for example,
how you do coding.
This is got to know their Hey,
do you know how to do this?
Can you get it done? That's
what management does, right?
They're not really management,
but they're like supervisor.
They don't want to be a scrum master
In the future.
You can be
who does the job of appeal
when they're absent.
A lot of times, if in the company there's
a business analyst, they could do it.
Sometimes a Scrum master it all depends.
Dubbed the product owner can delegate
responsibility to a scrum measure
or let's say, for example,
a business analyst,
business analysts, you know,
they kind of know what's going on there.
The one communicating to.
So sometimes they are the better fit
the more than a scrum
master because Scrum masters
really the one talking to the client.
Right.
Business analyst and product owner,
they are the one
anyone who is in project
implementation process.
Most yeah. Majority of people do. Yep.
Are we clear on
what the Scrum master does?
They are your supervisor.
You bring your problems, anything to them
and they all start
checking our
we on time finishing in our sprint.
Remember you have two weeks sprint. Right.
So they're going to be looking
just to Hey, are you guys good?
Why are you falling behind
or you're falling a little bit behind.
Okay,
let me get you some work or something.
Let me talk to a developer,
Whatever it is they do.
And remember, they run all the meetings.
They are the one running majority
of the meetings sometime prior quarter,
but majority times
they are the one I remember.
Coordinator slash supervisor.
That's the easiest way to look at it
without confusing it too much.
Right?
So now we know who the product owner is,
who the Scrum master is, right?
So should take a break.
Okay, let's finish one
and then we'll take a break.
Okay then in the in the in the Agile
world scrum,
then we have something called development
team.
When we talk about development,
it does not mean just developers.
It means basically testers
and developers or programmers
and business and designer, all of them.
So we come under this.
Now we are the development team.
We call ourself cross-functional team.
So developers are their testers
are they are maybe are designers.
They our business and as they come under
the development team now
select the spring goals
and specify workers will explain that.
I'll explain
exactly what this is in the later slides.
But basically remember this
we are the one who are doing all the work,
everything is
basically testers and developers
are part of the development team,
demonstrate spring result to
product order meeting the development
tester and developers.
Whatever they build,
they show it to the product owner.
This is what we created.
This is the software that we created
in the last two weeks or three weeks.
Whatever it is, we manage it.
It's something sprint backlog,
which I'll explain to you in a little bit.
Yeah, the real workers,
the real work is the developer,
which is testers,
developers, business and designer.
These are the real guys.
These are the real heroes.
We are the labor class.
Put it this way,
We are the workforce of the software.
That's the best way to look at it.
We without us, the builders, nobody can do
anything without testers and developers.
The project is a fail
because you won't have anything to show
they are the construction workers, right?
They are the guys.
We are the guys who develop everything.
Because you so remember
the development team can be anywhere from
this is what, 6 to 3 year
can be 6 to 7 around damage, right?
We are the builders.
Yes, they are the one design
the spring goals
in work, which I'll explain to you
in a little bit in the later life.
So remember we clear
what product owner is, what Scrum Master
and the development team
who who are part of the development team
and just reiterate and then we won't break
us us mean who testers
and who else developers to programmers
let's say programmer
let's say software engineers, testers,
business analyst, designers right.
Let's see this now comes
and this as a development
team. Yep.
So all the real workers right now.
All right, guys.
Now next up, we're going to have,
of course, more terminology.
We're going to clarify what this picture.
But let's do this right now.
Let's take a 15 minute break and then
we'll get back and then we'll get started.
Remember to remind me to record.
All right, guys, I'll pause right now.
Come back.
What is it, 834.
So come back at 850, please.
Any questions?
By the way, before we go?
Any confusion, anything so far?
Not clear. Okay, great.
All right.
Perfect.
I'll pause right now
and then we'll get started at 850 here.
I watch some some highlights.
And anyone watch the Ufa Japanese game,
by any chance?
Yeah.
There you go, Jimmy.
There you go.
That Renaldo score goal at the end, Right?
Just the highlights.
Barca lost three zero.
Interesting.
Very interesting today
yesterday as we're going to
I don't know how many soccer fans we have
but it's a nice a nice game today.
All right.
Anyway, let's get back to it.
So now let's see, where did we left off?
We covered what product order was. Wait,
what is product going to do?
What did they do?
Is the head of the project
great manage the product backlog.
They're the one who can change
the features.
In fact, they're the big boss Absolutely.
They do everything or the betas and more.
And that's a good way
to look at it. To Project lead. Yep.
We don't use project manager in
in what's that in an agile scrum
but kind of what they do
they might do a little bit more
but still then we Scrum Master.
What do Scrum Master do.
Who was manager.
They're the supervisor aide
They're the one who are basically
giving you the guidance
and things that they can.
They tell you what to work on.
By the way.
No, they don't.
They don't have that part
and they hire and fire you
know, they can do any of that.
They they have no decision making power.
Remember that.
What if you have any problem, anything,
anything have,
you can basically bring it
to the scrum master and they will be.
Yeah, they're the messenger between,
let's say
the product owner and the team.
Basically they're the middleman.
And the other one,
they're also running all the meetings.
They're the coordinators. Right.
They will try to inspire you.
I saw someone say that right?
They try to make it.
You know,
everything is fun and everything.
You know, all of that stuff.
That's their job. That's what they do.
They like the interaction.
So let's just look at this and
the last one we had, the development team.
Who's in the development team.
When we talk about development team,
6 to 8 people to really
be testers, software developers, designer,
most likely know all of this.
Maybe architecture,
you can put them in there.
But when we look at this picture,
guys, let's look at this picture, right?
Product owner, right.
Who are they talking to?
The business owner.
That means someone who gave them
the project, say, for example,
they're also talking to the end user,
right?
Let's say and use it.
Product and business
owner are from the client side.
For example, people who use it,
they're the one you see,
they're the communicator, right?
They're the one who communicate, use.
You don't see the arrow down over here
or the Scrum Master.
No, they're basically doing all the stuff
of what a bay is supposed to
do, basically, but had more, for example.
And they are the lead.
Basically,
a business analyst cannot find hire you,
but a product owner can do that.
Product owner is not really a contractor.
They're just the more
the head for the business from, let's say,
this team who got hired to talk
to the other team who they're building
the product for, right.
Like I said, sometimes
the roles of Scrum Master right here
manage this can process remove impediments
let's say any problems
anything comes along
they're the one who you bring it up to.
They will take care of it,
for example. Right.
And this is the development
you see Dev created that dev
you have architect business
analyst can be someone else as well to.
Yes. They're the one
controlling the project, right.
They're the one, you know,
who is communicating to the client.
They are the one
because look, remember guys,
the Q8 cannot call the client right here.
They can't do that.
They they're not going to,
of course, in a meeting.
Sure they can, but they don't
have the interaction right away there.
Or Scrum Master
does not go to the end user or something.
Someone from the team
has to be the representative.
Right.
Who can speak, let's say,
on behalf of the project
or get good feedback for the project,
whatever it is, basically
controlling the project.
Yep, they might work on budget,
sometimes they might work on
some of those things as well too.
And that's what a project or product
owner does.
So do we understand what the whole
Scrum team and how how it looks like?
Who the people going to be involved.
Does it make sense now when you go to work
and let's say you're in an agile
environment, you know,
just remember product owner, Scrum Master,
that's what it is.
The development team, all of those.
So pretty straightforward.
Now these are the players.
When we talk about an Agile scrum,
these are usually the thing.
Let's say
you are, for example, in a waterfall,
you won't have a scrum master.
They don't believe in
waterfall, does not have a scrum master,
it will have a project owner,
so say project manager,
but they want to have a scrum master.
They might have, let's say,
some other titles.
You might have a manager or developer
might have a development manager.
They all have different titles
and roles like there.
But when you look in an Agile scrum,
this is what we have right here.
What you see here in the picture basically
slowly coming
together and trust me,
if it feels a little bit who's domain
expert and agile
domain expert can be someone, let's say,
who for example,
from the client side, right?
Someone let's say.
Let me give you an example
of what I work for.
Let's see.
When we used to talk
to. Let's see. Whoops.
Eusebius individual, a domain expert,
for example, from the end would be
someone who worked, let's say for 30 years
at post office or they know so much.
Domain expert means are people
who are who have been there
for the longest from the beginning to end
and they literally
can be anyone but someone who's been
with that company or someone.
So you want to pick their brain.
Let's say we're building
a new project, new software,
and we know from the end user
are someone who is experienced person
who's been there for 50 years
with, let's say, this company.
We want to talk to them because their
opinion matters, because they are the one
who knows exactly
what's going on in that industry hands on.
So they could be literally anyone,
you know.
So you talk to those domain
and that's basically
what the product owner will do,
maybe talk to them.
And I remember we used to have meetings
where we would talk to individual
who were from exactly directly from post
office, very senior officials, you know,
who've been there for a very long time
because we were building a software
for postmen and, you know,
post office staff and individuals, Right.
So we wanted someone from there,
someone very experienced who can also
give us some idea.
The Scrum master looks at lonely out
there.
Well, it's not that.
It's just because they're
they're not the technical person.
They're not really developing anything.
They're not firing, hiring anything.
So they're on the side basically.
You know, I just supervising.
That's what they're doing right.
Okay.
So we covered now all the roles work
basically what the will product
owner, Scrum Master job.
Now we're going to get into something
called artifacts.
These are very important things
that you will work on
when you are basically in an agile
environment.
What does product backlog means?
What do you guys think
the word product backlog mean?
What do you
what might you think that maybe
information
the footprint, let's hear back quote,
okay.
Okay.
So a wish list of all design work
on the project,
prioritize by the product quarter.
What does that what do you get
the press to do?
So someone got it right.
So all those requirements, right,
for example,
all those requirements
that needs to be developed and tested.
Right.
All the combination of all the product,
all the basically
what we talk about,
all the things that need to be created,
you know,
they're coming in a product backlog.
Remember this?
A project might take five years, right?
It might take five years to do let's do a
there might be so many requirements
that need to be completed and finished.
Right.
A product backlog is the combination
of all of them.
From there we take a little of piece of
that we're going to work on
later on in complete the right.
So it's a combination of all
the basic work that needs to be done.
Now, one thing to remember this, before
we were using the word like all of these
are basically not basically they are
these are all requirements
that needs to be completely meaning
created and basically tested.
But now when we come to Agile,
we no longer call it requirements anymore.
Now, remember I told you they did
change the words, same exact thing.
Now we're we don't call them requirement.
What do you guys think is
called any guess anyone knows
user stories
and then smaller ones are tasked though
now instead of calling them requirements,
we call them users stories.
Exactly.
And when you break down, for example,
user stories
into smaller chunks,
then we call them task grade.
So I'll show you some real examples.
You have some idea Exactly.
These are actual user stories.
So let's just
look at one of these pictures, right?
Let's just see what it looks like.
As a user, I want to see tables on page
so I can engage with this content.
So let's say this is a user story.
When a developer looks at this as a user,
I want to see tables on the page
so I can engage with context.
They Need to now come
with the functionality and develop this.
Whatever this users
truly want us to do, right?
They need to make that into life.
This is basically what the developers do.
Remember this in the tech world,
developers and testers,
we're given
task, let's say for two weeks, right?
Those tasks,
our user stories, requirements
that needs to be developed
and then they need to be all tested.
So we're calling those user
those requirements now user stories right?
Let's say, for example,
a user wants to sign up to Facebook,
a user wants to view the latest updates.
We are dashboard so they can get a better
understanding of what what is in place
a user wants to be able to post status
updates on the go.
These are the things that the customer
wants.
This is what the business
analyst went ahead and wrote down
that is what the customer wants for
their new system that we're developing.
So developer ABC, go ahead
and develop this
and then we are going to test this.
Does it make sense?
Do you understand with remember,
this is all of what the customer want.
These are the functionalities
now needs to come to life.
So all these you see one, two, three,
four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
Right.
These are all basically all those users
doing all the requirements
that needs to be created
and might take five years from now.
Let's see, can we do a
do you get the picture kind of somewhat.
Okay.
Let me let me show you
now how it looks like in real life.
And remember this,
when you guys go to work,
you will have some software
that you're going to be working on, right?
You will get access to JIRA, for example.
You guys will be working on this
in a little bit,
probably in two weeks, three weeks.
When you guys do manual testing, you
be getting access to this, You see this.
So whatever,
you go to work, for example, right?
Let's say you check your emails
and everything you do
and then you have your task, Wait,
what am I going to test?
Is are they going to send me an email? No,
absolutely not.
That's not how it works.
They're platforms out there
that are project management, basically
product management, software where,
you know, basically all the tasks are.
So let me just select a project.
For example,
let me select this one to receive.
I can show you
this.
So for example, this right?
This is now all the work
that needs to be see backlog.
It's basically product backlog.
You see right here.
This is something called
Sprint number six.
And I'll show you this now, this one is
all the items that you see right here.
These are basically use street
that hasn't been worked on yet.
They're going to be work in the future,
for example.
Right.
Let's say in Sprint number six,
that means active.
Let's say work is going on two weeks
or three weeks sprint, whatever it is.
These are all the items that need
to be finished and completed.
That means they need to be developed
and tested
within, let's see, the two weeks time.
And when we're in the tech world,
this is how we basically see them right
by the time of the deadline. Right.
All this you see right here
to do in progress in and done.
They all need to be in the done section
they must This is a way
for us to basically or the team
to see the progress and manage it.
These are all the things that need to be,
for example
you see it
you're seeing across crossing them.
They're completely done.
For example, to do
that means a developer hasn't even started
working on this industry.
They're going to be working on it in the
they're going to make all this
whatever this description is,
they're going to make it into life.
These are all your task lists. Absolutely.
That's the best way to look at it.
And when we took a look at all
the accumulation of all the user stories
that hasn't been worked
on, there are in the product backlog,
does it make sense
now that you see visually what you see?
For example, for example, let's say
tomorrow you're working on this project.
Let me deselect some.
Let's let's see,
your name is Vladislav, right?
You will most likely get five, six,
seven or six users be assigned to you.
So let's say
when you log into your software,
that means in two weeks you need to test
all of these user stories.
The developer has to create them,
they will develop it,
and then you will test it
and you later on will Basically,
when you're working on it,
whatever you're doing, you move it.
No, it's not scary.
You just you're seeing a lot of wording
and everything that you don't understand
at this point.
A lot of different technical things.
But it's very easy.
It's very easy, but you get the picture
right when you go to work.
For example, your task will be,
let's say four or five of them right here.
Let's say in this project, I'll go here
and see.
This is in a current sprint, for example,
or let's say, and
I just kind of build and see Sprint to me
when Sprint number three, for example.
Right?
That means Sprint number three has
a lot of things that are being developed.
Remember this, this is just
for a sample example of purpose right now.
Right in the past
there was a sprint number two.
And remember, it's not one person.
This is all of the work combined.
You see Sprint number two,
that was done in the past.
You see they're done.
Sprint number four, backlog, all of this.
Now, this is good.
This is a good side.
I mean, to scale,
let me open up a different project
because you guys
are going to get scared, not
me to look at something else.
These are all projects
that are students then.
So you'll be doing all of this too.
So you'll be working with all of this.
Let me find simple statements.
Fine. Look.
Okay, perfect.
So backlog, right.
So who's the person who can move from,
let's say, backlog and say,
hey, guys, in this sprint,
let's add some of these things,
let's work on this thing.
Only product owner, right?
So that means only product owner has
the access to move something confirmed.
You see right here,
I just moved this and I moved it to.
Let's say for example, see it will be
moved back backlog to blah blah, blah.
That means they're the one
who can move only product owner,
no Scrum master, nobody.
They have the right what needs to be
worked on, what needs to be not worked on.
So let's say this user story
is not being completed a product.
Whatever the situation with this, this too
complicated claim isn't a way a product
owner has the right
to take it out from there
and put it in the backlog and be like,
Hey, we'll work on this in two weeks
or in three weeks.
We'll on it later on.
So this is
how tasks are basically broken down
when we go into, let's see, work
rate, for example, as an army user
should be able to add different membership
and requalification, blah, blah, blah.
So this is what the developer will see.
Okay, I need to come up and figure out
a way how I can add membership
and blah blah.
So they will go ahead.
For example, develop all of this,
whatever this you just really want.
Because remember this this user story
is directly from the client.
This this was given to the business
analyst,
the business and created this user story.
You guys don't create any of this, right?
The business owners or product owner
created of this.
Then later on, the developer
will be working in creating this later on.
The same thing that was developed
might be assigned to you as a tester,
say let's say auger
and you will have to test this later on.
How you keep track of the statuses is you
look at it
for example, here
you see into doing progress done.
You see it in
indifferent fashion when, let's say
for example, a developer is going to start
working on this use story.
He will say in progress Right,
I'm going to start work.
And that means me as a tester
because this user is assigned to me
as well to also,
okay, when it comes over here, then
I can go ahead and start testing right?
So this is a software
basically project management tool
that visually controls
what you will be doing.
All of this now this is all agile,
you see, you see Sprint,
you see the different words in here.
You visually see exactly
what needs to be worked on
and what's the status of
it doesn't make sense.
Now, visually that you see
what's going on.
Not too difficult, right?
I would say that means it's basically
very basic
stuff, even though at the beginning
my looks a little complicated.
But if you look at it's
not really that difficult.
So product backlog backlog is the entirety
of all the things
that need to be completed
that need to be worked on.
And in how long do we do by the end?
What's what do we do with the timeline
that we we work on this thing?
What is that called?
Sprints.
Sprints is basically we do
sprints can be one week, five weeks,
six weeks, eight weeks, correct.
So let's say yes.
No, only 1 to 4 weeks. No, eight weeks.
1 to 4 weeks. Right.
Only 1 to 4 weeks.
Timeline is fixed. Remember that.
It doesn't mean
that it's going to be one week, one week
next week is going to it's not
whatever the company choose
either is one week, two weeks, three weeks
or four weeks.
All companies,
JIRA, not all companies use it.
JIRA is very popular.
A lot of company uses it, but a lot of
similar softwares are out there as well.
Do A lot of similar ones out there.
Now there is a microsoft
DevOps is out there.
I forgot a tool out there, Azure DevOps.
There's a lot of them out there, but
they all are very similar rally rationale.
Once you learn JIRA, for example.
Literally guys,
when I first played with JIRA, it took me
one hour to figure out everything.
It is so simple.
Very simple, right?
So a lot of the tools are very similar.
They just made by different companies
and everything.
Yeah, it's like allocation
when maybe you've used Monday
dot com or something like that.
Very similar time. Great.
Using the task
and I think that's basically what it is.
Duran Duran software is different
now at least in of the company
they have different softwares
JIRA has different version.
There's one for documentation, one is for
software development and such as well to
So let's
look at oops, did I go too far ahead?
So we understand
what a product backlog is right now.
What do you think a Sprint backlog is?
What do you think that means?
There are two different things.
There's one called product backlog
and sprint room.
Exactly what needs to be done
exactly in that sprint.
Remember, product is the entirety
that needs to be done right.
But we cannot work on the entire
let's say, for example,
whatever everything is,
we can only do some parts of it, right?
So let's say there are six items
we might be able to work
only on two of them
in, let's say, a matter of two weeks.
Right?
So items pick from the wish list, product
backlog by the development team, execute.
Do this better, prioritize
by the development team.
Each user
still will be assigned points now,
which I'll explain a little bit later.
But basically in sprint backlog is you are
working on exactly what that sprint is.
For example, we pick the items from here.
Let's say this is the product backlog
right now, This is the sprint backlog.
I know for a fact I don't care about this
and I'll be working on this.
These are the items
that you working in that sprint.
So that means all of this tasks, let's say
our company has a two week sprint.
This all needs to be completed
within two weeks.
That means by the end of the two weeks,
let's say deadline is Friday, 5:00.
Everything must be here in the done
section.
Everything must be here
If something is, let's say,
missing, for example,
let's say I'm going to do this.
Let's see, let's see,
Let's say we did all the thing.
Developers worked on everything.
Everything got in a done section.
This item was not,
let's say it was in progress, but
5:00 hit deadline
and we're not able to finish this.
Then what will happen, guys,
when we look at this, this item,
whichever that one was, they'll push it
back to the pop product backlog.
And later on,
the product owner will decide, okay, one,
we can work on this in the future,
on which spring we can work on.
And remember this.
The other thing,
whenever you are showcasing,
let's see whatever you
develop right, For example,
all the
features that you develop
and use your keys into the client,
all the feedback, everything that's coming
along, where do you think it goes?
Does anyone have any idea
that you know,
where does all the feedback comes back?
It goes back to the product backlog.
It will be added all over here.
And yes,
the people will decide whether it goes
in the next spring, the following spring,
whenever whatever comes.
Right.
Let's say the feedback with the changes
the client wants after
we did a presentation to them, right,
they'll come back to the product backlog.
It goes.
Remember,
this product backlog can be massive.
Let me just show you another one.
Let's say, for example,
let's not look at this one, but
look at this product
backlog versus the other product.
But this is just for example,
you see there's a lot of items here.
So product backlog keeps on getting bigger
and bigger because all the changes
and things like that
that are being requested by clients
goes back to that product backlog.
Sprint backlog is exactly what
we'll be working in that two week sprint.
Basically nothing because we don't care
about anything as these six items.
We're basically pick
from the product backlog into spring back
and we're going to be working on that.
That's that's basically
exactly the same thing if you look at it.
It's just the items
that need to be worked on.
We call that a sprint backlog.
Does it make sense?
Got is it crystal clear
any doubts, any confusion?
Okay, perfect. Perfect.
In some companies,
guys, maybe you've seen some shows
and I think some companies,
what they do is they actually do it
on whiteboards as well
do now you can do it.
The digital version, let's say, for
example, through software, through JIRA,
what a lot of companies, what they also do
is just for visually may be all right.
Tasks like this stories
you see that these are used
to do in progress in testing spring.
Right.
Just to move it around
just for visual purpose.
Some people would do,
some companies will do it.
Maybe you've seen this.
Have you ever seen this show?
Any of you have seen Silicon
Valley used to be on HBO.
You have
then you definitely have seen this.
You've seen those developers
go and move the tasks, right?
They do it on sticky notes, right?
So is another visual way of seeing
what the progress is.
Remember,
is just having a visual representation
of what the progress is right now.
What a Scrum Master would. Right.
Let's say, for example. Right.
It's the end of the week and there's
items in here like less in progress
going to do.
The Scrum Master is going to go back
to the developer.
Hey, by way, buddy,
DEADLINE is on the on Friday of 5 p.m..
Why are you being behind?
Do you need some help?
Are you behind?
This is what they do.
They look at the progress of it.
What's going on? Are we on time?
Are we on track and things like that?
This is what a Scrum
master on a day to day is looking at.
And of course, at the same time
running those meetings, basically.
Now there's another visual way
of looking at backlog in progress
committed in progress done.
There's another example
of it, different softwares out there,
but they all are basically
doing the same thing to short attraction
of what's going on.
Are you on on the right path?
Basically, are we on the right
path of completing on time?
Everything you see right
here needs to be by the end of the week,
needs to be here in the done section.
If they're not in the done section,
they go back to the backlog
they'll be worked on in the future.
Make sense?
Clear, guys.
Easy, easy, easy.
Yeah, they just look complicated,
but it's easier.
Then the other thing that we saw over
here, let's see, what was it then?
There was something called a burn down
chart.
Now, this is not really for you.
This is more for management.
But let's leave it.
Let's see what up?
Burn down. Chart this. Right.
So a burn down chart.
This is one of the reports.
Reports that basically is an agile.
Let me see.
I can look in here reports we see burn
not just been reports
and I mean this is charts to determine
the progress of the trail on the spring.
The team should answer
following question every day.
How much work remains
has been in this team on the spin
on is the team on track
to finish all the work in space?
Should we add work rate?
So this burn down charge
that we see usually starts from the top
end is to basically any.
It is not that important,
but just to understand it
basically a burn down chart are just
and there are some other reports here but
burn is probably one of the most important
one basically tracks to progress.
Now this is more not for you,
it's more for product
owners can measure just to keep track of,
Hey, what's going on?
Are we on track?
Like this is not correct,
but usually starts from the top
and it basically changes.
Let me see.
I can find another one that's a little bit
more better constructive. See
figure eight to
choose.
You don't have either.
But anyway, let me just go back to this.
Okay.
Anyway, not so important,
but you see how this this chart looks like
or let me go back over here.
Well, typically, whenever let's say
you're falling behind when you're moving
all these let's say, for example
to do it in progress, all this thing,
what that chart is basically it's
a changing life chart that changes, right?
It goes up and down and everything
you want basically from the top to down.
You want it to come down.
It basically shows the Scrum master
and product owner what's going on.
If it's this chart is going like this,
it goes up.
That means some issues came on.
We need to go up.
It's just a visual representation
of the progress.
What is being done
and is being calculated in a chart.
Is it important for you guys?
Not so much if you really ask me, but
just know that an engineer might ask you
what is a burned down chart?
You just tell them, Hey, it's a chart
determines the progress of this spring,
what's being done, what not done,
and how much work is remaining.
That's all it is. Nothing fancy.
Don't know why they call it spring
burn down chart.
They make it complicated.
But this is what exactly it is, though.
And there are more charts out there too.
They're more reporting out
there as well to let me see
all the reports
see their different control epic.
I generally, if you ask me,
I probably know only two of them in here
and I don't care about it
because I am not a Scrum master
or a product owner,
so I wouldn't really care.
But this is just a visual representation
for management
basically to see what the progress is
and they're calculated
by looking at this spring burn.
So Scrum master and product owner
most like is look at it,
Are you going to care much about it?
Not so much,
but is good to know what it is now.
Do we understand what a burn down
chart is?
Does it make sense?
It's just calculating the work, remaining
very straightforward, very simple,
Not so much important
for testers and developers,
but important for Scrum, Mass and product
owner just to know what's out there.
Remember, if you look at JIRA backlog,
you'll have where the items are,
let's say the sprint status
visually in a way
see reports and then there's releases,
which I'll explain a bit later.
Not too many features
I hear, and it's very, very easy.
All these softwares
are very, very similar.
Ensure assures
the progress of the project, right?
Absolutely.
Is showing the progress of the sprint.
Usually what's going on there,
they try to break it down springs.
So you know, if you're basically
on the right track or not and keep in mind
that's the Scrum master is looking at
if someone is falling behind,
can I get them some help,
do whatever I can for them.
So we finish on time. Basically.
That's what basically
is happening over here.
So now we covered let's see
rolls and artifact.
Does it make sense
so far in the rolls artifact?
All of them.
Product backlog, spring burn down chart.
Is this by any chance let me ask you this
and give me an honest opinion.
Is this complicated
yes or no?
Not really. Right.
It's not really complicated.
And I guarantee you that majority
what I'm teaching right here,
if you want to become a Scrum master
and get a certification,
they teach you this in two days, charge
you anywhere from 900 to 1200 dollars.
And this is pretty simple stuff, right?
And that's how much they charge.
They go more,
maybe a little bit more in depth.
Good, but simple.
Overall, this one is it's
just a lot of terminology,
different terms,
basically but it's very simple.
Catalina, for spring backlog,
what spring burned out is just a chart
progress cheating spring
backlog is remember
of what items you were working strictly
that spring backlog is that cumulation
of everything spring back.
Let me just a few things
you take from the product backlog
and you can develop that.
So very simple, very easy.
If you look at just a little bit
too much terminology,
what is the similar term for artifacts?
I'll put it this way, important items,
That's the best way to look at it.
It is a folder that holds
all the pending does.
That's the way to look at it as well
too. Sure.
It's basically yeah, that's a folder
that holds whatever needs to be completed.
Absolutely Abdoul.
That's a good way of looking at whatever.
Make it easy and simple for you.
Works fine for me.
Okay.
Now what we're going to going to
the very last part is ceremonies.
And remember
I said it's basically meetings.
That's the fancy way to look at it.
The ceremonies are just meetings
now in in Agile.
There are a lot of meetings there, right?
A lot of meetings that we're going to go
over.
Spring grooming, spring planning,
Spring review,
Sprint retrospective, daily scrum meeting.
Okay, let's break down
what each meeting is
and remember, you will be participating
in these meetings.
So it's important
that you know what they are.
Let's see.
Okay.
Spring Planning, backlog,
grooming or spring grooming?
Same thing. Daily stand up spring demo.
Now, later on, I think it's going to make
sense to you when we go to the picture.
Let's start off with the first one.
Let's start from the bottom. I don't know.
They're not in the best order,
but let's start off with the daily up.
Okay? Which is which one?
It starts from the daily scrum meeting,
which is also called a daily standup.
So in Agile scrum,
the very first thing during the morning,
guys,
you always have a meeting, always
and usually 15 minutes
long is a meeting that happens
in that 50 minute long meeting.
Okay.
Scrum Master is basically,
like I said, is the coordinator.
They're the one who basically
is going to ask each developer investors
what you did yesterday,
what you plan on doing today.
And also,
are there any impediments, any blockers?
Update of a Yes, absolutely.
Update And usually the way you're looking
at the picture is typically like this.
Imagine this guy's a scrum master.
Each person, one by one goes.
Yesterday
I worked on user story, blah, blah, blah.
I got finished with it.
Today I'm going to be working on this one.
Whatever I'm working, I use a story.
One, two, three.
And I have no impediments.
Meaning no blockers.
I don't have any issues right now.
The reason of this meeting
is not the meeting.
Asset status is not just to spy
on your micromanagement.
No, the whole point of this meeting is to
see if there are any impediments,
any problems. Right.
So let's say, for example, let's say
our deadline is Friday and today's Friday
and I'm working on a user story,
for example, let's say as a test, right?
But it hasn't been developed
that the developer is taking too long.
I remember this first,
something has to be created
only then you can test you, right?
So if the developer does not code
on, let's say, on a future,
how are you going to test it? Right.
You can't.
So let's see in this meeting
you can bring up this right.
You can say yesterday as a test array,
I worked on user story three, five, six.
Today I'm going to be working.
I have remaining 1 to 3 user story,
which I need to test.
However, my impediment is
this is the last day today and developer
or whoever the person is.
Yeah, I'm waiting on you, buddy.
You're taking too long.
This is the point of it.
If any problems comes,
you want to discuss this in the meeting
because you have the developers,
the developers there, the team is there.
And what the point
what a Scrum Master does here.
They will take notes here.
Okay, The test be your user story or
something that you need to test is behind.
Let me talk to the developer. What is
why are they all standing?
It's called a standard meeting.
I don't know why
it's called a standard meeting.
It can be done standing up.
It can be done in a conference room
sitting down, but
it usually takes 15 minutes.
Can it go all 15 minutes? Absolutely.
It can go over 15 minutes.
All but typically 15, 20 minutes.
You try to keep it short.
Everyone goes give a quick status.
And if there's any problems,
they try to make sure they work on this.
Now, in this meeting,
there are some people who love to talk
and there are some people
who love to talk.
Right.
And a scrum master will usually say,
you know what, This is a
they call it what do they call it?
This is a parking log item
they call a parking lot.
I don't know why they call it,
but that means that, hey, this whatever
your issue is, let's talk about this
or do a separate meeting
because it's a longer one. Right now.
We need to go.
Everyone needs to give the status right?
Yeah. They don't use their phone.
Maybe that could be the reason. Yeah.
Sometimes not all the testers,
they maybe one representative goes there
and gives the status right. What?
But typically this is what you do.
Yeah. It's something
that's basically taking too long.
And that happens by the way,
it happens all the time
where someone likes to talk so much like,
Geez, okay buddy, let's move on.
You know, people give their status.
Yeah.
All right.
So this is your daily stand up.
So when you go in the morning, right,
you check your meetings,
so you check your emails and everything,
and then a specific time lapse
in 930 in the morning,
you go to conference room or whatever, or
maybe on a Zoom call
and everyone gives the status, right?
That Scrum
Master is the one initiating it.
So they able to say like, All right, guys,
let's start our scrum meeting today.
Jon Developer Let's say, for example,
could you tell us what you worked on?
Yes. Jon would be like,
Yeah, I worked on this, blah, blah, blah.
I'm working on this no matter what. Right.
Thank you.
If there's any notes, any issues
he brings up
or she Scrum
Master will basically take the notes
and then most likely
come up with a solution
or bring it to a product or after everyone
goes, gives their 30 seconds
one minute
whatever talk and that's it and move on.
So this happens every single morning,
every single morning.
Very first thing you do
when you go to work.
Yeah.
After check your emails daily
stand up 15 minutes long.
Can it go longer?
Sure it can, but typically is 15 minutes.
I remember in the company that I worked
at, it used to be 30 minutes.
I have no idea why
they call them some agile,
but they were not really following because
30 minutes is not according to Agile.
But remember I said people can adapt,
companies can adapt, right?
So does it make sense?
Pretty straightforward, right? Sprint
daily stand up.
So this is what you will do.
You will get used to this.
Very simple.
Now let's see,
what were some of the other meetings?
Okay, let's see. Yes.
Sprint grooming.
This is very important meeting.
Okay.
So let's say, for example,
we did daily training.
So let's say before a sprint
starts, right?
Maybe you have some questions.
You at these user stories
and you have no idea.
Let's say let me open something.
Don't get scared
or anything in my look complicated.
Let's see.
Let's say, for example, you has a
developer is looking at as an admin.
I should be able to change
employee details, blah blah.
I have no idea
what in the world you want me.
Let's say you don't understand
this, right?
Let's say this user story
and your developer tester.
You can't understand a word
what the business
and as a product owner has written
or you have some confusion on this.
For example, you have a meeting for this.
Now, this is what happened,
spring grooming meeting.
So this is before the spring starts.
Or sometimes you do this meeting
ahead of time,
the future sprints before a sprint start.
Let's say you're going to start
your new sprint on the 22nd, right?
Maybe on the 18 to 19,
you do sprint grooming meeting.
In this meeting, first of all, development
team, that means testers,
developer, business aspect,
master, product owner, everyone is here.
B Sprint product owner and team represent
arrange it in the middle sprint time.
In this case planning and fighting term
that happened on the same day
led led by the product where the involves
splitting big item into smaller
smaller ones, reiterating back
items to be more expressive,
deleting obsolete or no more neat items.
Right.
So what happens in this meeting in spring
grooming basically
when you looked at this one right
this picture here
some user stories can be massive, right?
That might take a long time.
So what happens this sometimes is like,
you know what, let's split
this between three or four people
or let's break it down
into longer time so they can
they can break it down.
But the main thing that happens
in this meeting, you're trying to clarify
and understand
exact what these user stories are.
Maybe, for example,
let's let's let's go back here.
You in the product backlog here,
you looking at this one,
maybe this used to use a story
is not accurate or needs more details.
Right.
In this grooming meeting, the grooming
meetings can be two, three, 4 hours long.
They can take long.
As long as it takes.
Before you start working in a sprint.
You have to understand everyone needs
to understand what each user story is.
Maybe a developer question,
maybe you have a question, right?
I tester has a question, right?
So what you do in this meeting is clear.
All five basically all of this right?
To understand I might have some question
I might not understand is used to it all
product owner in business and said hey
can you tell me what in the world is this?
What am I supposed to do?
If you ask this, you clarify.
Maybe you would delete some users history.
Okay, this doesn't make sense.
Let's take it out, guys. Whatever.
So in this meeting, spring grooming,
you are basically clarifying
and understanding all the user stories
before you get to actually work on it.
Right?
Makes sense, guys.
Pretty straightforward understanding,
making some of the user stories
that might take a long time
into smaller ones and really understanding
and asking questions and things.
And I remember when you guys joined
the project, let's say at the beginning,
don't be like, no one is expecting you
to know anything at that point.
At the very beginning, when you join,
it might be they will give you some
because you're not familiar
with the application.
But here basically what we do,
we are understanding
exactly
what is what we're going to create.
If we don't understand, we clarify,
we take out things, we add things,
we add more details, we add pictures,
whatever needs to be done,
and this is amongst
the entire chip can take 2 hours,
it can take 3
hours, can take 4 hours, can take 8 hours.
Depend on how long sprints.
All right.
So let's see if we have a two week sprint.
Maybe we'll take 3 hours.
What if the company has three weeks
sprint, right?
That means there's
going to be a lot of you stories.
More like it's
going to take four or 5 hours
in this meeting.
You're sitting down. Yeah.
Only the daily stand up.
Maybe you are standing up.
This is where you absolutely started
sitting down.
And you have a projector.
You're looking at the user stories,
trying to understand something.
If you sleep, you're not doing much,
you understand everything.
But whatever, you know, you get the.
Point is just to clarify all the user
stories, the requirements
right before we start working on them
and questions come along,
you might not understand something.
Developer might not have started.
Maybe the business analyst and product
owner wrote the user story in a
I don't know, in a poorly written
English guide.
You might want to clarify that.
What in the world you want me to do?
You asked these questions here
in the spring grooming session, basically.
So we cover this Now remember
spring grooming look pre confusing,
but it's just a meeting where we clarify
all the details and break down
some of the user stories
down to smaller ones.
So we cover daily scrum.
Then we did spring grooming.
Well, shoot, let's go back
then we're going to have spring planning.
The order is a little out of whack.
Let's see what comes up this.
Okay, now we have another meeting.
So now that we have understood,
for example,
what the user stories
we understood what they are
Now we're going to go to another meeting
that is called Sprint Planning.
Now. And Nicola,
I don't know why they call
it standard me, but a lot of companies
do do it standard, right?
So now that you have understood
all the users pre, now there's a meeting
called spring planning the same people
are going to be the happens
at the beginning of this year
the Sprint team
meeting to discuss user stories in task.
What do they do here
they are basically now in this
sprint planning meeting
all the let's say sprint
what's the sprint backlog
is identified
and actually created basically.
Right so here finalize we finalized
basically all these user stories.
We finalize all of these in this course.
We understood
now we finalized some of them
and now we're going to do something else.
An important part
is to estimate
what do you guys think that means?
Take a wild guess. Yes.
This is very, very important part.
Estimating meaning is, okay,
all these usage that he was team.
Okay.
Remember this a sprint is
let's say two weeks, for example.
Right.
So how much work should you get,
let's say for two weeks?
How many hours are there,
let's say in a working day, let's say in a
in a week,
40 hours rate, 40 hours of work,
basically go for,
let's say, 9 to 5 full time job, right?
So two weeks
sprint would be 80 hours. Right.
So now what they need to do
is they need to identify
how long each user story going to take,
write
each user
story because they need to assign
that work to individual,
let's say developer and tester.
Right?
So in this sprint planning,
what we do is we break down the story.
So. Right.
For example, let's look at this
as an example right now.
Okay.
Some companies use points,
some companies use hours and days.
It all depends on the company.
One could meet one point,
could mean in a company
it's a small use, a story
that mean it's not going to take too long.
A medium could mean three points.
Let's say, for example,
it will take a little time, maybe four
or 5 hours, but it's nothing difficult.
Five point could mean
it could take a lot of effort rate
or sometimes what they could do.
Each user story can basically gets
a timing.
Who creates user story?
Guys, answer this question for him.
Who creates user stories?
Product owner slash business analyst.
Remember that people and business owners
who are the one taking
all the notes, write
all the done by business owners, right?
So remember people in business
and so the one creating this right.
So now what
we are basically doing in this meeting
after we have clarified all that
the user stories,
we got an estimate we got to give it
and in the we how it works is this way.
So let's say for example each user story,
let's take
for example
this use history right now, right?
So let's say Scrum master
we'll this up on a projector
and show it to everyone right guys
you guys understand this user story
developer and test you understand.
Okay, great.
Now developer
first developers will go right
They'll ask each developer,
let's say this for developer, developer,
how long do you think it will take you
to develop this user story?
Some might say it might take me 3 hours
to develop this.
Okay.
Now, remember,
they're guessing at this point,
no one knows how long,
but you're estimating at this point,
another developer might say
it might take 5 hours.
Another developer might say,
I think it might take 8 hours.
Okay, everyone, to give a different time.
Okay.
The product, the sorry,
the Scrum masters to be like, okay, guys,
each of you gave me different timing for
how can you explain to me
why you think it takes 3 hours?
Can you tell me why it takes 8 hours
after the explanation?
Let's see. Each will give.
All right, guys.
Now, each one of you heard
what you guys think your opinions are.
Now let's go back again.
How long do you guys think so?
They will go back each and every one.
Each developer will go and say, okay,
I think it's going to take 4 hours.
The other might say 5 hours.
They might say 4 hours.
Okay, let's do an average
guys is going to take 4 hours, right?
So now they will give four hour time
for this user story
that the developer needs to develop
and create this.
That means he at least 4 hours, this user
story has at least 4 hours of work.
Right.
Then after this, what happens,
do you think?
Now, remember,
that was the time for the developer
testers will give their own timing now.
Now the testers will go and say this.
Okay, Remember, sometimes development
can take a lot longer than testing.
Now the timing would be separate
for testers.
So this will have, let's say, for example,
developer time.
It'll have a tester, tap testers go.
I think it's going to take me 4 hours,
some of my samples and take 5 hours.
Whatever they're using,
they'll give explanation
and then they'll come to an average.
Okay, It's going to take 4 hours for you
guys.
Well, so now in this meeting,
they're going to basically, guys,
let's go to spend backlog, right?
They're going to go each and every user
story that they're going to have.
Each and every single story
is going to have a developer time
and is going to have a testers.
How much to test right now,
this task, this this whole estimating
and everything's been planning
could take a couple of hours,
2 to 3, 4 hours
depending on how many users story.
The more it is, the longer time will take.
So now you get an idea, guys,
when you go to 9 to 5,
you're not just coding 24 seven,
you're not 40 hours of coding.
If you have a lot of meetings,
you have a lot of other things going on.
Remember that maybe some time
the entire day can be spent
on just estimating things
like that. Right?
So let's go back over here now.
Once you time everything right, let's say
it's going to take this long to develop
or this long to once that time is given,
right, then what happens is
each team
member, let's say developers,
be by themself.
Okay, I'm going to work on this item
just to make it sure that it's 80
hours, right?
You pick the items you as a team, right?
Each and every person need that product
order
need a Scrum master assigns
you usually the team itself.
Let's say there's a senior developer.
Okay, guys,
I think this is a four day long
user story is going to take me a week
to develop this.
I'll take this.
Since I'm a senior person,
everyone picks themself.
Usually that's I was when you start
at a new company, you're brand new.
You have no idea.
Don't worry, they won't make you pick it
because you don't know at the beginning.
They'll give you okay
you John New person, you work on these two
or three users story.
They're easy at the beginning,
but you as a team, for example,
each person picks their own one.
So testers, testers might say, you know,
I think I'll work
on this, this, this user
story values during values story.
Okay, great.
Someone else will be like,
I'll work on this one.
So you yourself pick all of these
which stories you're going to work
when you pick them, for example. Right?
Whenever.
Let's say the sprint starts,
let's say sprint planning.
Everything happened on the 20
of September, let's say the following day.
22nd is when the sprint is going to start.
That means developing testing.
Then you will come when you come to log
into JIRA, all the user stories,
whatever was assigned,
let's say that you picked
will show up in your, for example,
in your dashboard.
Right.
And that's how you work usually works
like, does it make sense how this works?
It's a very democratic process.
If you haven't seen so far.
It's very democratic,
very involved in here
where you much in what everyone say,
what they want to do,
what they don't want to do,
whatever it is.
You know, it's a very team effort,
you see, and no one is assigning.
There's no micromanagement.
But at the same time, they're trying
to really do team building work,
try to do everything,
give enough time to understand things
and not make it pressure.
They want to make efficient
with these meetings and things.
Supposedly everything's supposed to go
smooth and you have an understanding
and you can achieve this stuff.
So this happens in the sprint planning.
So what did we cover so far?
Let's see, we covered daily standup,
which is the 15 minute long meeting.
Sprint, GroupMe, where we basically
understand the user stories.
If we need to delete them,
try to understand,
take out things, make smaller,
use destroy, meaning smaller, task.
We do all of that in sprint planning.
We finalize exactly all the user story
that we're going to be working on.
Also, we're estimating
giving it and everything.
And then at the same time we're choosing
which items
I'm going to be working as a tester
developer at the same time as well.
So we cover three of them so far.
Pretty easy,
am I or not already challenging.
Easy, right? Pretty simple.
Just a lot of terminology,
but it's pretty simple analysis.
Soon you're going to understand
this picture that I showed you,
so it will make a lot of sense.
Okay.
Now, basically, let's say
Sprint will start.
Let's see.
You've done all your meetings, etc..
Everything is good.
You've done
all the estimation, everything.
Now sprint the start two weeks.
So basically go
by two weeks in the two weeks.
Every day you have daily stand up
and you're working, blah, blah, blah.
You developing your testing every day.
Now what happens
after the end of the two weeks?
What do you think happens?
Review meeting.
Okay,
so now we have Sprint demo slash review
meeting, right in this meeting,
not everyone is here, right?
So developer scrum, massive business,
all of you, the client side is here.
Maybe they'll come on Zoom
or on site, for example.
And this happens right after the spring.
And here now typically led by a RSM
EY or Tesla.
I'll explain to you what it s
I mean subject matter expert.
That means someone who's
a very senior person
who's probably from the beginning of the
or the project, someone who could be
a developer, it could be a tester.
A test
lead is usually a very senior tester.
Right?
So let's say you're
I've been in this company for four years
and four or two other testers got hired.
They're junior people
under automatic testing,
someone who's more in charge,
a more senior. Right.
So they're one
usually leading this meeting.
Right now, in this meeting,
what happens is what ever was developed
in this thing by hey,
let's look at a sprint.
Whatever was in that section, right?
Let's say supposedly
everything is done right.
Everything that was created,
we're showing them a demo.
We're going one by one
and showing them, okay,
this is the new functionality created.
We added a login page,
we built a posting page, blah, blah, blah.
You go one by one
and show it to the client.
You show it to exactly what you created.
Usually a tester does this.
Why the tester usually showcase this
because they're the one
who is more experienced
in playing out with the application,
finding flaws and everything.
So very easy.
A test lead,
usually that's a senior person.
So don't expect when you go to work
that you're going to be doing it
so they'll get freaked out.
They basically show step by step
what they've created
a bit added, I don't know, a login button
or Instagram button.
They're going to show that
that's all it is.
Very simple.
It could be on a zoom,
could be a Skype call,
it could be on WebEx or can be persuade.
So now you show them basically
what you are creating step by step, show
all that.
And also what happens in this meeting.
In this meeting, for example, the meetings
like this, the team members,
business analyst, product owner,
developers, maybe even not us,
for example,
we want, but they'll take the notes
if the customer is giving feedback.
Okay, I don't like this.
I think this shouldn't be here.
It should be at the bottom of the screen,
whatever they want.
Right?
So all that feedback, they take care.
All that feedback they take
and they're going to put.
Where do you think that feedback
is going to go?
Whatever the customer doesn't like
or want that changes the product backlog?
Absolutely.
Is Going to go into the product backlog
and most likely
we're going to work on the future,
maybe the next sprint or whenever
we need to work on that.
Right. For example.
So this what the spring demo slash
sprint review is where you're showcasing
whatever you created,
you're basically showing it to the client.
They like it.
They hate it when they see
you take feedback and that feedback
goes back
and do this product backlog in the future,
most likely in the next sprint
or the following sprint.
Basically pretty straightforward,
not too complicated,
but usually how it works that don't expect
you guys to be leading the meetings.
Who takes the notes most of the time?
Product owner and the business manager.
Remember, they're the one who makes
what the user story is, right?
Business analyst is the one
usually writing a product one.
It helps out as well
do so. They're the one taking the most.
Maybe some time, you and I developers
and tester can take notes.
But remember this we are not the ones
writing these user stories.
No, we don't do all this.
This is the job of product
owner and business analyst.
They're adding all this stuff basically.
So now this meeting is done.
That means the sprint
has completed At this point,
while we give the feedback, the feedback
will come most likely the product backlog.
Then there is one last meeting.
A lot of meetings,
a lot of meetings, one more meeting left
after everything is done right.
And that meeting is called Sprint
retrospective.
Now Hugh, who is attending development
Team Scrum Master product
on a business that right after Sprint ends
all the following debt.
Now in this meeting,
you can be open here, right?
This is internally.
There's no client or anything like that.
What worked, guys?
What didn't work type of issues
and problem came up in the sprint
what things we can improve,
what caused the problems
you're basically expressing
if something went well, great.
If something didn't go well,
why did it happen?
It's internal meeting.
You could even say things.
Guys, we've been overworked work.
I think we need a happy hour.
Literally, you can say anything.
I even one time I got fed up, I ask for
a raise in my meeting as added a raise.
Otherwise,
maybe you shouldn't be doing that.
But still, what is this like?
You know, in this meeting
you can express yourself,
You can express yourself and say like,
Hey, look,
you know, developers, you guys
kind of heard us last time, you know,
you guys took so long and testers,
we were all crunched up the
you can expressively openly
basically say things in this meeting
and what the product owner
and the scrum master what they're doing
they're basically writing down
all the things they want.
You do want to hear from you, right?
So you remember it's
all collaborative, right?
So if something didn't go well or you guys
were really stressed out or something
about the project, whatever
you expressed this in this meeting
and the whole point of this is
to make this team functioning well, right?
So how can it function?
Well, they have to hear your concern.
You have to bend down.
So if you want to vent out
you went out in this meeting that, hey,
you know, this is too difficult, whatever
it is, you know, you went down on this
or you give suggestions, things
that work, things that didn't work.
And this is strictly internal.
There's client to anything like that.
And the goal of this is
how can we improve in the following what
what things we did
well, what things we can improve,
and what are some concerns from the team
members? Right.
So it's an open discussion and sometimes,
you know the Scrum master product
winners, they'll make sticky notes
and things like that.
So now do we understand what's going on?
Can this get hostile?
It can be usually doesn't, right?
Maybe someone got upset or something
sure, comments can be made,
but but it usually doesn't get a hashtag.
But this is all the meetings
that we have in Agile Scrum. Now.
I'm going to go back to this picture
and you're going to understand exactly
what's going on.
So let me break this down to you.
Eight inputs from team management,
meaning the client comes to the product
list requirements prior,
prioritized by business value, etc..
This is your product backlog right here.
Then you went to spring planning meeting
as to how much can be committed, deliver
whatever, etc.
There is no sprint grooming here,
but still sprint planning happens.
Right now a sprint backlog is created.
That means one block was taken from here.
Backlog is broken into little small pieces
and basically given
to all the members now in here,
I don't know why it says three days.
Maybe they have a four week sprint.
But basically right here,
the list end up happening every 24 hours.
That means another meeting is happening
and the whole sprint is in 30 days.
At the end of 30 days,
you have a sprint preview.
That means what you from this into that
then you have a sprint retrospective
and this whole cycle repeats again.
Now let's
look at it in a easier form format,
product backlog, sprint planning
happening, right?
That means Sprint backlog was created.
That means items were taken from here,
Scrum team daily scrum happens,
the whole thing happens,
product is basically made, Sprint review
happens, a demo was given increment
Sprint retrospective happens
and the whole cycle repeats again.
Now do you understand the picture?
What happens in a in an agile scrum?
See we identified each
and every single part.
What does bring back?
What is this?
What it's been all the different meetings,
who are the main members
and what comes up? And yet
what is an incremental increment
is what you make a product into.
Small timing in small module plane.
Remember this in, a sprint,
two weeks sprints.
We created
some part of the application, right?
And then we delivered it right.
So you making it into small pieces.
Remember this picture
at the very beginning,
this picture here
incremental you making in waterfall,
what happens?
You build the entire project
and then you show it to the client.
At the very end,
we're building this project into small
pieces, into small in this small sprints
we accomplish and we're getting feedback
This way towards the end.
The project can be a little longer,
it can go overboard,
but still customer is satisfied,
their feedback is in there.
And this how basically we're
is there any meeting
for bringing all applications together?
Could you elaborate a little bit on that?
What do you mean by that?
It's actually very easy, guys.
When you get into the real
it's pretty simple.
I know.
I didn't understand your question.
If you don't mind elaborating,
is there a product? Yeah.
I mean, we had meeting
where we talk about it, but remember
the entire project, we can talk about it,
we break it down
to these small sprints
because it's impossible to.
Tackle
the entire project all at once, right?
So they break it down and that means small
sprints and I altogether.
Yup, exactly. So that's those agile.
Now this is has a lot more
a lot more involvement in here
overall but yeah that's it.
Any question is there anything you did not
understand about Agile so far
any confusion
anything.
No, not yet.
And guys
remember this don't feel overwhelmed
if there's a lot of terminology to this.
Okay, guys, in the next six months,
you will hear these words so many times
it will make a lot of sense to you.
Trust me, it is not difficult.
It's just a lot of terminology. Right.
But when you play with the JIRA board,
when you play with all of this
and everything,
it'll make a lot of sense to you.
And keep in mind you will be working on
JIRA, making user stories
all this things later on.
User story is a requirement.
Okay, Product backlog
is that requirement in that
entirety, meaning all of them combine
all accumulation of all of that.
So bunch of thousands
of users points. That's it
usually.
Dennis Yes, some companies have
sometimes some companies will have
a little bit different structure,
but you have to wait for the developer
to be remember this, you not just sit
in, you will still have later
you learn, you'll do manual test case
and then you go automation.
So you'll still be working.
Is the business on the client?
Yes. In this picture that I showed
you last time, that's the client, right?
Same example I give you HP,
also the development team and everything.
Client was united
supposedly over you making the product for
is the business owner. Yep.
The product owner
communicates to the business owner.
That means the ones you're building for.
This is the entire company and the team
that's hired to create that application
for business owner or whatever company
they're representing, for example.
Does it make sense?
All right, so guys, that was it.
That was Agile.
I know there was a lot of terminology
and if you didn't get everything,
no problem, guys.
It will stick in your brain
over time in six months, trust me.
Repeated.
And we'll go this quite a few times.
No questions, any questions, anything.
They did it all in piece sprint.
So this there so is there any your time
where the bring the whole software.
I know all of this is slowly
basically coming together
remember everything slowly
you think of it like this right.
Facebook has a new feature that comes out
next week.
Great.
You'll see that later on.
So slowly, all that pieces come together
for you.
What you can
review for coding class at the moment,
if you want to just look at
look at the calendar.
If it has,
what is Java and things that you can
we will give you, by the way,
the instructions for
the installation and things to wait
till tomorrow and Friday.
You can follow that
if Sprint is completed and review is fine
and then it goes to the production phase.
Yes, I'm right, it can go.
But remember what I said.
A lot of companies decided not to, let's
say every two weeks, make it live.
Can it technically go live 100%
after the Sprint review happens?
It's good to go.
It can go, but times they don't. Yes.
And by the way, there's no class tomorrow
since it's your first week.
Review will start from next week
because in review classes
we doing the coding reviews
and that's going to come from next week
by the way guys.
So guys, that's all I have for today.
I don't have anything.
Again,
if any questions, please do ask. But
it's a simple process,
not too difficult, a lot of terminology,
but it's still very easy.
And remember, again,
if you didn't get some of it,
it will make a lot of sense to you
guys later on.
All right.
I will see you guys on Tuesday.
And on Saturday, Mischelle
will be teaching your first programing.
So get ready, guys. All right.
Thank you so much, guys,
and see you guys on Tuesday.
So we need to start apps for Saturday.
Alex Just keep an eye on the course
announcement.
We're going to share the video
and give you announcement in there.
All right, guys.
Goodnight, everyone. Have a lovely day.
And any time any questions, come
just either tag me or put in support ones
and I'll be happy to answer
if anything comes later on, guys.
And by the way,
it should be all online already.
Or maybe in the next two or 3 minutes
I'll make the slides live over there.
Okay, guys.
All right.
Have a go. Going. Not take out one, guys.
Goodbye.
Yeah, guys, no class for tomorrow.
Someone asked already? Yep. No class.