All right,
let's get started.
How is everybody doing, guys?
I hope everyone is doing good.
Having fun with selenium, right in Java.
Hope you guys now covered collections.
I ran this list
all right.
Okay, good, good.
Because we're going to be using them
today.
A lot.
I'm good. Thank you.
I hope you guys completed the homework
for Selenium as well.
I hope it was fun.
And it won't confuse with homework.
Okay, Got it.
The first round.
Okay.
All right.
Any questions from the homework, guys?
My questions should be good.
All right, good.
All right, so let's do a quick recap right
as we usually do.
What did we cover last class, guys?
Just selectors.
Okay.
What do we know about Season selector?
What is it? CSA selector. You guys.
What do we need it for?
Okay, we can't use text.
Okay.
In comparison to what?
What?
Where can we use text? What?
What does it mean?
Select CSA selector
is another locator
that helps us locate the element.
Okay, good.
Another way of locating elements
on the web page.
Absolutely right.
And what does it look like?
It is similar to which other locator
like X path, but it's faster
and it is a little cleaner.
Right? So it's more readable than x path.
Okay, So
what did we learn about CSA?
So what can't we do?
We set
we cannot locate an element by text.
If you want to use CSA selector.
Right.
No text.
What else? There. Okay.
So it has shortcuts.
It has shortcuts in identifying
that idea in class.
Right.
What is the shortcut for it in class?
Guys?
Okay. It's Dot, right?
That for class
and the
pound or hash tag, whatever for it.
And we also said that you cannot go back
and forth right
in the inside the notes, inside the mail
if you're using CSA selector.
Right. Okay.
What about the methods, guys?
What about the methods
that we covered for CSA selector?
What?
How can you manipulate the values
of attributes?
Okay, We talked about
contains.
Starts with and ends with.
Right.
Do we have and switch and CSA scars?
Yes. Right.
And we don't have the next path.
We have the SAS.
And what's the symbol for ends
with in CSA selector.
You guys.
It's our favorite sign, right?
It's a dollar sign. There you go. Nice.
What about starts with
starts with the carrot sign.
Right.
And what about contains?
It is a
asterisk.
Or it is a
star. Right.
Okay.
Sounds good. Okay. What else did we cover?
Last class, guys.
There we go.
So we covered some web element commands.
Last class as well.
What kind of element commands
did we cover?
Last class, guys.
Is enabled.
Is displayed.
What else?
Get is
get and web element commanders.
No. Right.
It's not a web element command
because we were using get
whenever
we want to navigate to a website right.
So we also have is selected
well we covered get text
right
and we covered the get attribute value.
Right.
Okay, good.
And we also we also also submit, right?
Correct.
And we also did one task
where we got all the links
from the eBay website right.
And we used what locator did we use
in that example?
Guys?
What locator guys?
How did we find all the links
inside the eBay guys?
We use tag name. Right.
So we identified all the links inside
that eBay website by the tag name.
Right.
So the tag name is a it's
going to get us all the links
and then we started inside the red list.
And what we did, we looked through each
and every web element.
We got the text
and we're printed everything out.
Right. Okay, good.
Any questions from the last fast guys?
Any confusions from the last class?
All right, good.
So today, what we're going to be doing,
guys, we will be handling
checkboxes and drop checkboxes,
radio buttons and the dropdowns.
Okay.
So I hope you guys
did some research on this class.
So what do we know about checkboxes, guys?
What is checkbox or what is the radio
button on the website? Guys
Collection
of forever
that have us or the elements by its index.
Okay, good.
What about checkboxes and radio buttons?
CheckBox typically lets us
choose multiple elements.
Radio boxes. Only one choice.
Absolutely right.
So we have checkboxes, right?
Which
which are the elements on the website.
They give us some options to check. Right.
And in checkboxes, what we can do,
we can select one
or more options
if we want to do that in radio buttons.
What we
it is
almost
the same, but it is options as well.
But we need to choose only one option
from there.
Right.
And Button is something you click
you put the check on.
Okay.
Difference
between radio button and check box.
You can select radio buttons, mouth
one radio and multiple for checkbox.
Exactly. Okay.
All right.
So this is what
we're going to be doing today.
And then we will be covering the dropdowns
as well.
So handling
checkboxes and
radio buttons.
Okay. So
check boxes of Philip Ball
and radio buttons are clickable.
Okay, probably.
But. Well, they both
they're both clickable and they're both.
Philip Well,
I think in terms of selenium technicality.
Okay, So in order
for us to check anything on the check box
or to check anything on the radio buttons,
there is two ways of doing it.
Okay.
So if you have only one
checkbox on the page
or if you have only one
radio button on the page, what you can do
is you can identify that element
and what you can do.
You could just simply
go ahead and click on it.
Okay, So that's one way of doing it.
But if you have multiple choices, right,
if you have like four or five checkboxes
or four or five radio buttons,
you need to choose between those.
What do we need to do in that case, guys?
How do we handle multiple elements?
Last class.
Okay, you do find elements, right?
What are you getting in return?
You get that list of web elements, right?
So once you have that container in hand,
what are you doing next?
Guys?
So you have that container
you need to go through each
and every element inside that container.
And then you need to
you need to perform some actions.
Right.
Last time, what we did,
we got all the links.
We saw them in that container, right?
We saw them in the list.
And what we did,
we looked through each and every link.
We had some conditions.
We got the text,
we got the attributes right,
and what we did
were printed them out inside our console.
All right. So let me put it here.
If you have only one
checkbox or
radio button, you can just
click on it.
Right? And
if you have multiple choices,
then what you can do,
you can store them in a list, right?
Store them and list and well,
okay.
And then perform any actions
you need to perform.
Right?
Store them first
and then loop them through conditions.
Exactly.
So this is what we're going to be doing
in our next
example.
Okay.
So let me create a new package in here,
and I'm going to create a new class
and I'll name it as
demo.
Okay?
See, there should be checkbox.
Okay, There we go.
All right.
So what we're going to do, guys,
right now, so
we will be navigating to this website
and what we're going to do,
we will be interacting
with these four options
that we have in here.
Okay. All right.
Any questions
before we move forward, guys?
Okay, good.
So what I'm going to do, let me just
copy this
and what's the password
and log in for what?
We don't need any log in passwords
and any any credentials
to go to this website.
Right.
It's probably
you're talking about this one.
This is different
and this one is just selenium.
Practice website for syntax. Okay.
All right.
So, okay, before we get started, guys,
so every time
what we have in here,
we put our zero inside this get right.
Is there any other options that we can
we can have this URL in a different place,
guys.
No, no, I'm saying,
is there any way we have this URL
in a different place?
Okay, a variable. Okay.
Where can we store that variable
class in array?
We can store it in a string, right?
In a simple string.
So do we want to store it in here?
Like, say, string?
Your role is equal to this one, right?
And then just get this in here
and paste it in here, all right?
And then we can do this.
So if I do this,
what kind of variable would this be?
On line 11 guys?
What kind of variable am I having
exactly?
We have a local variable, right?
Absolutely right.
What if I want to take it
to another level, one level up, guys.
What kind of
what kind of variable
would I have in that case?
I would have an instance variable, right?
So that means if I,
if I want to create an instance variable,
where do I where
do I start? It?
Inside the class and outside the method.
Right.
So we have this method right now,
right?
This is our main method.
So what I need to do, I need to store this
inside the class, but outside the method.
But here when I start,
this seems like this is not reachable.
What's going on, guys?
This static?
Why do I need to?
Why do I need to make it static?
Because I have a static method.
Right? Exactly.
So my main method is a static,
so you can only use static
static variables inside this static
method.
Right. Is that clear?
You guys
do static or.
Let's do it public static string.
Okay.
There we go.
Any questions on this?
All clear. Right.
So we're storing it outside.
Now we have a static variable euro
and just calling it inside the line 13.
Okay, so now we have a URL.
All right, So we navigate there.
We navigate it here.
So I want to interact
with those four options that I have.
So let me inspect this page.
Okay.
So now I need to identify these elements
and then I need to
I want to check some of them.
We don't know which ones yet,
but let's identify them first
and then we're going to figure out
which ones we're going to check.
Okay. So here,
this is my option, right?
So this is my option one.
And I have different options in here.
So how do I locate these four elements?
What am I using?
What attribute
am I using in order to get these
for this
class?
We don't have class checkbox, right?
We have class of this value
and type of the checkbox
or this class.
Okay. Okay.
So let's try this. Okay,
so let me do this.
I may open up this selector.
Right.
So let's do div.
We have class in here is equal to
checkbox.
Right.
If I do this,
how many elements do I have right now?
I have six. Right.
So how many elements do
I need to locate Guys
I need to look at four.
Exactly.
So if you look,
if I go through each and every element
that I found right now,
you can see option one, two, three, four.
And then here I have this checkbox
and I also have the checkbox
at the very top.
But I don't need these two extra
checkboxes, right?
So we need to narrow down our search guys,
how would I, how would we do this?
We need to change something in here.
What can we also use?
Can we use the value attribute? Does
input
okay, we need one of four, right?
So if we have a class in here,
so we have.
Okay guys, take a look at this.
We have this
type of checkbox,
we have class of this KB element
and we have value option one, which one
can we use so that we can only find
four elements. Guys
value.
Okay, so let's try the value and see.
Okay, so we have an input in
here, have value and we have
option one.
What happened in here guys?
What could do contains.
Yes, but
here I only found one.
Okay.
So without using contained
without extending my x,
is there any other way
surge. Okay.
Said to use the class. Right.
So yes, let's do class
and I'm going to copy this
pasted in here.
All right.
So what do we have now, guys?
Have the right elements right now.
Guys. No.
Still. No.
Why not?
Yeah,
let me go through the elements right now.
So one, two, three, four.
And it goes only
through the elements.
It is one of four.
This is what we need, right, guys?
We need only these four elements, guys.
Okay?
So we are trying to interact only
with these four options.
Is that clear, guys?
Why this x path?
Why this X path is going to work for us?
Because we want only to work
with these four elements, okay?
We want only these four options
and we need to interact with these four.
Okay, So I'm going to copy this x pack
and go back to our code.
Okay.
So now it's time for us
to identify the elements
and then we need to store them
inside the container.
Right?
So driver, start
this time we're doing
find elements, right?
Because we're trying to interact
with multiple elements at the same time
and we're trying to store them
enough in the list.
All right, find elements.
What are we finding it by?
We finding it by X path
and just going to pasted in here,
finish my statement
and then what I will do,
I will store them inside the list
of what elements of this option
checkboxes.
All right,
so import this element in here
and import the list.
Okay. All right.
So we have this right now.
So line 18,
we have a container of web elements.
So what is my next step?
How do I see how many
how many elements do I have
inside my container right now
we can simply do
list size, right?
What is it going to return to us?
What am I going to have in return?
Guys?
I'm going to have an integer. Right?
So integer to do size is equal to
option checkboxes, dot size.
And let's print it out real quick
and here and let me run this.
Okay, so let's run this.
What am I going to get in console guys?
Okay.
We should be getting four elements, right?
So let me go back in here.
There we go.
So inside my console, I had four.
That means in my container
I have four different elements.
Right? Okay.
All right.
So now what I want to do,
I want to go through each
and every web element,
and then I want to click it
one by one.
This is the X path right here. Right.
So now what I want to do,
I want to go and create a loop in here.
Okay, So for loop, right?
So I am
looping through
these through this container, right?
And what am I looping through, guys?
What are the,
the things that I have in my container?
What are those?
They are web elements. Right. Okay.
So I'm looking through each
and every web element in here.
And I could do option.
And what I can do is
my next step is going to be what guys?
So I'm looping through each
and every web element.
So now what I need to do,
I just simply need to go ahead and click
on that element.
Right?
So what I'm going to do in here, guys, I'm
going to pause this
for one second so that we can see
the difference how this goes.
Okay?
Because if I don't do this, it's going
to go really fast and it's just going to
check all the checkboxes right away.
This way we're going to be seeing
how everything is running.
Okay,
So I'm going to run this and let's see
how this is going to go.
There we go.
So we are we checked all the checkboxes
by using one for loop and we just collect
each and every element.
All right. Pretty cool, right, guys?
Any questions on these
or of these?
All clear.
Okay, so let's go back in here.
So now what I want to do,
I want to click on option two guys
out of all these for what I want to do.
I want to click
only on that option for option two.
How can I do that?
Any guesses
in loop
will get the text.
And then what we can do is if condition
get value
web element two one okay,
so we can do that, but
that's going to be a hard coding, right?
So what if what
if this option two goes somewhere else?
What if this option two goes under the
option three or it's going to get messed?
Then our web element
one is not going to work, right?
So if you if you want to interact
with these four elements
by using indexing, then
no matter when it's going to change,
your code is not going to work.
Okay?
So that's going to be considered
as hard coding and in the future
it won't really be a dynamic, right?
So you have to keep changing your code
once anything changes on the on the
user interface. All
right.
So now let's go ahead and get the text,
guys, okay?
And see how this is going to work.
Okay.
So when I get the text
from the web element, what am I getting in
return?
I'm getting a string value, right?
The string, as do this text, is equal to
option,
get text right.
And now we need to have a condition here
so that we can click
on one of the checkboxes. Right.
So I have in this condition and here
if my text
right equals to ignore case, that's fine
equals option to
right only then what I will do,
I'll go ahead and click right.
So once I click, what do I need to do?
Guys?
Do I have to do anything else in here?
It goes.
We need to break the loop right?
Or we go
to break the loop in here.
So let's run
this and see what's going to happen.
Okay.
Seems like it didn't
seem like it didn't click.
It didn't work, right? Why?
Any guesses, guys?
Why this didn't work?
No, we're getting the text right, guys.
So if you look at that, if you
look at the text, I need option two.
Right?
There's no dashes in in the text.
All right.
So if you look at the text in here,
there's no dash.
There's no dash in here
and there's no dash in here as well.
Any other thoughts, guys?
Look at the element
which I am locating right
now, guys.
This finding option one, it's
one out of four.
Yes, exactly.
It is a checkbox only. Guys,
look at this.
If I go if I navigate to the label tag,
what am I locating now?
Now I am locating the whole option one.
Right?
So if I move to input,
I am only locating the small box
that is in saw on the website.
Guys where only locating the small square
it doesn't have text or anything.
That's
why whenever we starting to get text guys,
it's not working for us.
Is that clear guys?
So right now if I want to get the text,
it's only getting the square, small square
that I can only insert
the check inside it.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys?
Any questions on this?
Okay,
so now, since I am only getting those
those small squares.
Right, but I need to have a condition
anyways, Right.
So instead of a
instead of getting to get to X right.
Instead of having a text, what can I have
that I have a condition for
get attribute.
Okay.
So if I get attribute,
what what attribute would I get
in here?
Value.
Right. Okay. There we go.
So now let me go ahead.
Instead of getting the text in,
let me get the attributes of value.
Okay.
So what I will do, get attributes
of a value right?
So this is what you say.
Yes. CheckBox
value, right?
So in here we place it in here.
So now what is my value attribute value?
In here it's option dash one,
right?
So now I need to fix it in here.
I need to put X and now let's run
this and see if this is going to work.
There we go.
So we navigate it.
So now you can see that only option two
is clicked
and it's checked right now, right?
None other options is checked.
So we wanted to check on the option to
so now we can check option two in here.
Okay.
Any questions, guys?
I'll clear. No questions.
You sure, guys?
Is everything clear?
Only one clear.
You guys passive today?
What's going on? Guys?
What happened?
Seems like you guys are not having fun
with Selenium anymore.
Okay, Okay.
Okay, Focus.
All right, so this is how.
This is how we handle the checkboxes
and radio buttons, guys.
Okay?
So and even if you go to work guys,
you will be seeing the same implementation
where you store everything in the list
and you try to loop through it.
You have the condition
and you click on any
text or value you want to click.
Okay.
So this is pretty generic implementation
and usage of how to handle the checkboxes.
And the same way it's going to be
with the radio buttons as well.
Okay.
You could just what you could do, guys,
you could just pay attention
to what I'm doing right now here,
and then I'll give you a time to type
in, right?
So I'll give you a couple of minutes
so that you can
you can type
that's going to be better for you.
Okay.
All right.
Okay, guys.
So if there is no questions,
let's go ahead and start
talking about the dropdowns, guys.
Let me see.
Actually
see this
here.
Okay.
All right.
Guess what?
Let's talk about the dropdowns. Okay.
So what do we know about the dropdowns?
Did anyone do any research?
Is what's dropdown
how to handle the dropdowns?
Anyone, guys, any guesses on dropdowns?
Oh, assuming everyone left
or everyone fell asleep.
Okay, guys,
I need you to be a little more active.
so that I know what is going on.
Otherwise I'm just going to be explaining
to no one whatever it is.
Right?
And we're going to just go without
no questions
and we're going to finish the class.
And I'm not going to even know
what's going on.
What uses a HTML tag?
Okay, What is the dropdown guys?
Do we know what the dropdown is?
List of web elements.
Dropdown is like a selector based on
predestined options.
Okay, so it's a list of options.
Like it's like a menu.
All right, so you open it
up, you see multiple options in there
and then you can select any of these
right?
Okay.
Predetermined.
There we go.
All right, so a dropdown is just a menu,
right?
Or again, it's a container which
contains some options
where we can go there
and click or choose
any options that would like.
Okay, so let's go ahead
into our notes in here
and for the up downs.
Right?
So the dropdown is
a menu,
right.
Which
gives us
simply
to select
options.
Okay.
So you can select either one
or multiple options
for checkboxes.
Yeah. That that's this should be enough.
This as I said,
checkboxes and radio buttons are
they have a generic way to handle, right.
So if you have only one checkbox or radio
button, you could just click on it.
And we do know how to click on the web
element, right?
But if you have multiple, then you need to
store them in a list loop through.
You will have some conditions in there and
you need to perform actions accordingly.
Right?
All right, cool.
All right.
So for the dropdown is it's a menu, right?
Or a method
which allows a user to select one or
multiple options, right?
So gives us opportunities.
Select, let's say one or
multiple options.
Okay.
So you could say select.
Because in checkbox
you check in in radial buttons,
you are checking that small thing as well.
But in dropdowns
you need to select an option.
Okay.
All right.
So now, guys, how many types,
how many types of dropdowns do we have?
Does anybody know
if three types?
Okay, What are those?
Now, this is the way of selecting, right?
So these are the way
of selecting the options.
But I'm saying the
how many types of dropdowns.
So let me put types of
dropdowns.
Yeah, I thought it would be one,
but it's not right.
Okay, so we got two types of dropdowns.
Okay, guys, One of them is single select.
One of them is multiple select.
Okay, so single select
and multiple
select.
All right.
So single select, pretty obvious, right?
You can only select one value
from that dropdown in multiple selects.
You can select multiple values,
one or more values from that dropdown.
Okay.
So now let's talk
about how to handle the dropdown.
Okay.
So and handling
dropdowns
in here.
Okay.
So first option is easy, right?
As we have done in checkboxes and radio
buttons guys, what you can do in here
simply right, you can click on
dropdown
and click on the option right
as you're doing it manually
clicking the dropdown, you expanding it
and clicking on any other option.
You are selecting that option, right?
So you can click it twice
or the second way of doing it.
What we can do is
we can handle the
dropdown by using a select class
from Selenium.
Okay, so using
select class.
Okay.
So we'll be going over
how to use a select class.
But first of all, guys,
what we need to make sure is
we need to take a look at the HTML
before we do this.
Okay?
So if we encounter
any dropdowns on the web page
and we want to go and use the select
class, first and foremost,
what we need to do
is we need to inspect that page.
We need to try to locate this dropdown
and we need to make sure
that this has a select tag.
Okay.
So if you don't have a select tag
whenever you're trying to interact
with the dropdown, you won't be able
to use this select class from the selling.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys?
Okay, cool.
So if we look in here, we can see that
this specific dropdown,
it has a select class.
I mean select tag in here.
So that means we can go ahead and use this
select class which comes from the
Selenium Library.
Okay.
Before we do that, let me put it in here.
Right.
In order
to use
select class,
we need to make sure
our dropdown as
select tag.
Okay.
Once we made sure that our top down
has a select tag only,
then what we can do is
we can go ahead and use this select
class from the Selenium label.
So what I'm going to do,
I'm going to create a new class in here
and say
top down
and links.
Okay, our
main method is here.
Actually, let me copy this
and paste it in here,
but we're going to need change
the URL, right?
Does everybody have the URL guys?
Okay, good.
All right.
So we're navigating to that page, right?
We're navigating to that page.
So now it's time for us to
locate that element first.
Okay, So what I'm going to do,
I'm going to go back to the page, okay?
What I will do, I will try to locate
the dropdown with a magic arrow in here.
And you can see when I expand this,
when I expand this select,
you can see that we have all the options
under that select tag.
Okay, So what I can do
is I need to
I need to locate this element first.
Okay, So in here
we have this ID for this dropdown.
So I'm going to be using this ID,
which is really reliable right now.
So I'm going to copy this
and I'm going to go back
to my class in here
and I'll start finding that element.
Okay? Driver
find element
ID and paste this in here, right?
So when I find the element
I'm getting in return
a web element here.
And what we can do is
a dropdown equal to this.
Okay, what is going on guys?
Why, why is this throwing me in there?
Exactly why? I need one more
of the parentheses. Right.
Okay.
All right.
So now, guys,
before you use the select class,
you need to first
make sure that you have a select tag.
And then what you need to do is
you need to lock that
dropdown by ID,
by any locator you're comfortable with,
and you need to store it
inside the variable off of that element.
Okay, so now what I am going to do,
I need to create an object
of the select class in here.
Okay.
So what I will do simply
the select select is equal to new
select.
Okay, so
close this.
So now guys, you see it's not fully
compiling in here
and is complaining that we need
we need to add something
inside the parentheses.
Right.
So whenever you're using a select class
inside the constructor guys of a select,
you need to provide that dropdown
you're going to be interacting with.
Okay,
So in this case I have this web element.
I have this dropdown
that I need to perform some actions on.
I'm going to copy that variable
and I will paste it inside of parentheses.
Okay. Is that clear? Guys?
Any questions?
All right, let's see
why we created an object
because we want to perform
some actions on a dropdown.
Okay.
So in order to interact with the dropdowns
guys, we need to use a select
class from Selenium
in order to use the selenium class.
What we need to do,
we need to create an object of that class
only then just for the dropdown.
Correct.
Any other questions, guys?
Select is just the object.
Yes, select is just the class guys.
Okay, so let me actually see
if I can navigate there.
There you go.
So this is the class that we will be
getting the methods from.
Okay,
so we created an object of this class.
This class is located inside our
what's called Selenium library.
Okay,
select one item.
Select the first one.
Okay.
You need to
you need to imported from selenium.
Okay. Yes.
It requires a web element as well.
That's why we paste it in here.
That's why
it will locate that dropdown first
so that we can paste that
variable in here.
Okay.
So once we have that
object on hand guys, now we will be
interacting with the dropdown
and we will be selecting some options
from there.
Okay, So now let's
go ahead and talk about
how many ways we can do
and we can select the options
from the dropdown guys.
Any guesses?
So some people said there was three ways,
right
when I asked for two types of
drop downs guys.
So there is three ways
of selecting an option
inside the dropdown.
So one of them is selecting by index,
selecting by visible text
and selecting by value.
Okay, so three ways.
So selecting
an option from dropdown
will be done
three ways.
Okay.
So one of them is by index,
the other one is by
visible text, then by value.
Okay, so three ways guys.
First is by index,
by visible text, whatever
we see on the dropdown options, Right.
And by the value attribute in here. Okay.
So you see these value attributes.
So these are
which we are going to be using
for the values.
Okay. So let's go back
inside our code and go through
those ways one by one.
Okay.
So since I have an object right now, what
I can do, I can use this object, right?
I can use this object and start selecting
any options in there.
Okay.
So what I can do, do select
when I click a dot in here,
you can see that select
by visible text, select
by value and select by index.
Okay,
So we'll start by selecting by index.
Okay.
And what we need to pass in here,
we just need to pass an integer in here,
right?
So we, we have days dropdown, right?
So we don't have a lot much options
in here.
So what we can do is
let's
go ahead and select any of those in here.
So let's see three. Right.
So if I put a three in here okay guys,
if I put three in here,
which day am I going to get selected
in here?
Tuesday. Okay. Some people Monday.
Oh, Thursday.
Okay.
So I'm having a third index in here.
I said the elements
that they don't start here
from zero.
You don't service.
Oh that was okay.
So. Okay, okay. Okay.
You talking about the X path?
Okay, so an x path is a little different.
Guys in here, it's a little bit different.
Okay, So let me run this and I will
explain to you what is going on in here.
Okay.
So let me run this.
So there is a lot of different answers
in here.
Wednesdays, Tuesdays, Monday, Sundays.
Right.
So let's run
this and see what's going to happen.
All right, So I run this.
So now. So now
it's selected Tuesday.
Okay, So now, guys,
what I was talking about
when I was talking about X path.
Okay, okay.
Let's say
when when you are trying
to locate the element by x path
and by its index.
Okay, So just think about it logically.
When you do.
Let me see.
So let me open it up in here.
This selector.
Okay, so whatever x path it is, right?
You have this tag in here,
you have everything in here, right?
So now what you need to do,
you need to pass something in here, right?
In order to identify this by index.
Okay, So logically, you guys,
if you think you can't
really identify the element
that zero, right.
So logically, if you think you cannot
really identify that element zero
because your element you starting,
you start to count the elements from one,
Right.
But it's still cold as indexing in here
and it's different
if you go to the technical
and you go to the coding part,
the indexing starts from zero.
Okay. Is that clear, guys?
That is a little bit weird. Yes.
But when you go when you try to talk
about the scripting itself,
your indexing is going to start from zero.
Okay.
This is not the Java language.
This is not it.
This is just an express
and this is how it works.
Okay.
And it's just a query language, right?
So don't get confused, guys.
It's just indexing.
Whenever you're doing, whenever you do
an export, you start from one.
Whenever you go to your code,
you start from zero.
Okay. All right.
So now, guys,
I selected the third element in here,
and now it's selected the Tuesday.
Okay, So let me go ahead and open this up.
Okay.
Why did it selected?
Choose it If if my day start from zero
guys, take a look at the HTML
that we have right now.
Please select in here guys
is an option as well.
So you look at the tags in here
inside the select, I have options, right?
So whenever you try to select something
by using a select plus,
it will look for options in there.
Okay.
So if you look at the very first option
that we have, it is it says please select.
But it also says disabled guys.
Okay, So please select is also considered
as an option, but it is disabled
because you won't be able to select a
okay, is that clear guys?
So is
what's called
Please select will be your zero
and then after that
you will start from 1 to 3
and go, okay,
that's clear.
Okay, good.
All right, so now let's go back in here.
So we selected that select
a Tuesday, right?
So now let me actually put a
some import in here so that we can
visually see what is going on.
All right.
I'll just put it for one second.
So now let's select
an option by the visible text.
Okay.
So what I can do simple, select that.
Select by visible text.
Okay, so what do we want to select guys
one day, Wednesday.
So Friday, right?
Friday is a good day, guys,
because the next day is Saturday,
so we don't have to go to work,
but you guys have to come to class.
So sorry guys.
Which they wish that.
Yeah, that's what I,
that's what I just thought about guys.
Okay.
Thursday is a small Friday.
Okay, let's do Thursday.
Guess.
Okay, so let's do Thursday.
All right.
So when you do select by visible text,
you obviously need to pass
a string value selecting by index.
You need to pass the integer in here,
selecting by visible text
you are passing the string in here.
Okay, so let me run this
and see what's going to happen
nowadays.
Good day.
Until graduation.
I thought you guys were enjoying this.
Yeah. Okay.
There we go, guys.
So it's selected Tuesday now?
It's selected Thursday. Okay.
I hope you guys saw the difference.
What was going on inside,
what's called inside the dropdown
Java on Saturday. Sunday.
Not fun. Okay.
Okay. To complain to Oscar.
Okay.
All right.
Okay, guys.
So we selected the Tuesday by index.
Now we selected Thursday by it's text.
So let me give it
another second
and let's do select.
So now let's ahead and do the last
way of selecting the web element.
I mean the option in here,
selecting by the value.
Okay.
So when I select an option
from the dropdown by the value guys,
you need to go ahead
and get the value of the value attribute.
Okay, guys, is that clear?
So you don't get this text.
You need to get the actual value
of the attribute.
Okay, guys, is that clear?
You want to type the code? You mean
of the value?
Yeah, you can.
You can type it in. Yeah.
So if you want, let's do a Sunday now.
So what you can do, you can put here
as the value of the Sunday.
So let me run this
and see what's going to happen.
So there should be one Tuesday, Thursday
and Sunday.
Right.
So because we're selecting
three different values Tuesday, Thursday
and now it is Sunday.
Okay.
Pretty cool, right, guys?
So there's three ways of selecting
and we know all of them right now.
Any questions, guys? Any questions?
How to select any values from the dropdown
guys?
Is there a preferred way for dropdowns?
Yeah.
You mean the selecting.
So the preferred way is always go
probably by the visible text. Okay guys.
So that's going to be the most safe way,
the safest way for you to go and select
some values.
Okay. Yes.
So what's the difference between by
selecting by value and visible text?
So I will show you here, guys.
The text is the same
and the value is the same.
But we will be go into a different
example, guys,
and I will show you
what is the difference between these two.
Okay.
All right, guys, any other questions?
All right.
If there's no questions,
let's take a quick break.
Okay, guys, and then we will continue
handling different, different dropdowns.
Okay.
So 15, let's get at 830, guys.
All right, guys, let's get back.
All right.
And continue
on our dropdowns.
Let's see, back home, the people we got.
Okay, cool.
Okay, guys. So in the first half, we said
we'll learn
how to interact with the elements
in the dropdown.
All right?
And we know there's three ways
to select any
options from the dropdown
by index, by visible text,
and by the value.
All right.
So now, guys,
what if I want to get all the options
that are available
inside, this dropdown space,
How would I do this
is multiple.
We'll show you if if you can select one
or if you can select multiple values
on that dropdown.
Okay.
So that's
a little different method in here.
So I want to have all the options
available inside the dropdown.
So what we can do is there is a method
with which we can use,
it is called get options.
Okay, so what I can do is select
the right get options in here.
Okay, so what is this going to return me
guys?
Let's see
what what am I getting in return?
Is it going to return me?
Only one web element.
I'm getting the list.
I'm getting options. Right?
So it's going to return a list of web
elements in here.
So what I will do,
go ahead and create a list of web
elements in here.
A list of Web element.
I'll say all options.
All right.
And import the list.
Okay.
So what I am going to do?
Let me
comment this part out.
Okay.
So now I have the container
with all the options in here.
All right?
So I want to know how many options
I have inside my container.
Now, what am I going to do in here, guys?
I simply need to get the size right.
So integer
size is equal to all options
size.
And what I can do,
I can just point this out.
Okay, So let's let's run this and see
what's going to happen.
There was no one here.
So how many options do we have here, guys?
We have eight options, right?
Why do we have eight options?
But we have seven days, guys,
because the first disabled option
is also considered as an option,
even though it is disabled.
Right. Okay, good.
All right. So now, guys,
what I can do, what I want to do,
I want to get the
the text from each option,
print it out, and then select one by one.
How would I do this?
Guys?
Okay, I'm getting the text, but what am I
what do I need to do first, guys?
How am I going to reiterate
the same step guys?
We a four guys, right?
So what I will do, let's create
a regular for loop this time, guys.
Okay.
So integer four
is equal to where do I start from? Guys
start from zero, right?
Zero one Which one
does?
Okay,
okay, okay. Okay. All right, guys.
There we go.
Java zero. Right.
So we just talked about it, right, guys?
So. So let's go.
Okay, so let's start with zero.
Okay, Let's start with zero
and see what we can do in here.
Okay, So
zero and then
is less than the size we have, right?
And then I
plus plus because we need to be
incremented by one.
Right. Okay.
So what I need to do, I want to print each
and every option text
that I have inside my dropdown.
So how would I do this?
Guys?
How do I get the visible text from
from these elements? Guys
get text.
Okay, so let's do string
option text, right?
Is equal to
all options.
Seems like I don't have get text guys.
Why not?
Exactly.
Sorry, we have to get
high. Right.
So we iterating by using a regular
for loop right now.
So we need to in
we need to insert here and index.
Right.
So we get the AI and then we get the text.
Okay.
So now we have an option text in here.
What I can
do. Let's print this out in here
and option text.
So let me run this
and see what kind of options.
We get.
All right.
I mean, this.
Okay, guys.
So if we look at this here,
so we got all the options.
We we even got the option,
which is disabled, which is select, right?
So we got all the days in here
and we've got the disabled as well.
So now what I need to do, I want to select
each and every option in that dropdown
in the interval of one
second guys,
how would I select any, any option
from that dropdown in this loop?
Guys, which
which way would we use in here?
Select by index.
Why are we selecting by index?
We don't.
We don't really need to use regular
click right.
Since we already have an object
of the select class, we can use those.
One of the three
that we just talked about right?
We using the regular loop. Right.
That's why we can use an index, right?
So what I can do is select
select by index and we can simply pass
the integer I in here
and I will give it a second
so that we can see
visually what is going on
when everything is getting selected.
Right.
So let's run this and see
what we're going to have.
Okay, There we go. Sunday
and Monday and all the days one by one.
And here.
All right, there we go.
So we selected everything one by one, by
giving one second of intervals
so that we can see everything.
What is going on? Facial. Right.
Pretty cool, right, guys?
So we could do it by regular full loop.
We can do it by
the advanced for loop
and we're going to have an exercise
where we can do it with iterator
as well. Did you guys
go over the iterator as well?
I hope you guys did. Okay. Good.
Okay. Nice.
All right.
So, okay, guys, any questions?
Any questions on how to get the options,
how to loop through the dropdown
or how to
select any option from the dropdown.
Pretty easy, right?
So you create an object
you use whichever way you want to use.
Three ways that we discussed.
You want to get options.
You can store that in there
in the list of web elements
and then you loop accordingly.
You select according.
Okay.
All right. So
let's see.
Okay, So now let me create
one more class and let's do one test here.
So the method
is part.
Okay, Let's go to Amazon now.
All right, guys.
So we are on Amazon Web page.
So there's a lot of different elements.
So there is one dropdown
that we have in here,
and what I want to do will be
I want to interact with this dropdown.
So now this dropdown has a lot
of different options in here.
Okay.
So what I do,
let me inspect this page.
Okay, So what I want to do guys,
I want to
get all the options
from the job from this dropdown
that I just showed you guys
and I want all the options
printed in my console.
Okay. Is that clear?
You guys
clean
and prime dropdown.
Oh, this one.
Okay, let's see.
Okay, guys.
So that's a good question actually.
So in here, guys,
let me make this one small.
Okay, so we got this one right?
So this is considered as dropdown because
it has a lot of different options, right?
But if I go to the Prime,
do I have a lot of options in here?
Guys?
No. Right.
So this is not a job done. This
this is just an element.
Okay.
So and if you pay attention to this guys,
so if I go to this job down in here,
in order for me to see
the guys, I need to click on this.
Okay?
If I don't click on this all dropdown,
I'm not going to be able
to see any options.
Okay?
But if I go to the prime,
I don't even have to click on it.
I just hover over my mouse and you see
the additional pop up comes up.
Okay, So if you're dealing with dropdowns
guys, dropdowns will have different
different options for you.
Okay, so this is considered
as just a regular element.
And I will I will come to this point later
during the course, guys,
how to handle these kind of elements.
Okay. Yes.
It doesn't also have the select tag.
Yes, that is correct.
Okay.
So we will be dealing with
this kind of elements later in the course
where you don't have to click.
You could just hover over your mouse
and you will see different,
different elements.
Okay, what's here for the dropdown?
You have to click in order.
You see the options.
Okay. All right.
So you click
on the dropdown next to America Slack.
Okay.
Yes, we okay,
so I don't have to click on this, right?
I don't, I didn't click,
so I just hover over my mouse and it up
and it comes up in here.
And if you want to see this one, okay,
so this one, let's open it up.
So this is this doesn't, is not considered
as dropdown as well.
Okay.
So it has,
it has like languages in here. Yes.
But it also have it also has different
lengths in here as well.
Okay.
So if you if you working with dropdowns
you will have only
one type of the options.
Okay.
So if you see in here
you only have like departments.
Okay, so these are the departments
you need to work on.
These are the options of your departments.
Okay.
But here you also but here you have your
what's called the language.
You have some other links and
you also have changing the country region.
So this is different, right?
So this is
this is considered as just an element.
Okay.
This wouldn't consider as a dropdown.
Okay, good.
Any other questions, guys?
So if you look at this element as well,
you will see that here
we have different different things
and I don't have to click on that.
Yeah, it can be a menu yet.
Yeah, this is just a
I'm not sure if it's language menu
or whatever menu
it is, but here you see it
account and list menu,
right in here.
I don't have to click on this.
I just hover over my mouse in here
and you can see that you list your account
and you need to sign in
and all that stuff.
Okay. All right.
So what I want to do, guys, I want to
I want to get all the options
from this dropdown and
I want to print it out inside my console.
Okay, So we are navigating to Amazon.
So what is my next step in here?
Help me out and here goes.
Now anyone?
What is my next step? Guys
list?
Okay, what am I storing inside the list?
Sorry. Okay, find the web element.
Okay, so find the web element.
So if I find this web element,
what do we know about this? Now?
We're going to use the select
class guys in here.
Or what are we going to do?
It's not select.
Why not?
It has a select tag, right?
So that means we should be able
to use this select class
right before we store everything in the
in the Web element.
I mean, list of web elements, right.
So we need to what we need to do.
We need to identify the dropdown
itself, guys.
Okay. Like we did in the previous example.
So in here I have my ID,
right?
So what I'm going to do
is get a copy of this idea and I need to
check if we have a select tag, right,
So we have a select tag.
So that means we already know that.
Okay, so we have an idea.
We have a select tag.
What we can do, We can use select class,
right?
This is what you need to think right away.
Whenever you are dealing with dropdown.
Okay, so I copied the ID.
We have a select tag,
so I'm going to go back in here
and I'm going to create a web element
web element
categories, dropdown
or departments dropdown,
whichever you want to name it.
Find element by ID.
All right, paste this here.
There we go.
So we have our element
stored inside the variable right now.
So now what I need to do,
I need to create a select object, right?
Since we have a select select tag now,
we can create a select
object in here.
And what we do, we paste that
variable inside the constructor here.
Okay. Is that clear? Guys?
Any questions on lines
18 and 19?
Okay, good.
So now what is my next step, guys?
So what I want to do,
I want to get all the options.
I want to print them out
inside my console.
Okay? So we could get the size. Yeah,
we could get the size.
But would it be
necessary for this task? Does
no. Right.
So we could just start storing everything
inside the list.
Right.
So let's of
web element.
Right.
What we can do options is equal to select
that get options.
Right.
And don't forget to import the list.
Okay.
So we have all the options
inside the container.
Now, what we need to do,
we need to iterate
through each and every of those elements.
All right.
So now this time, let's use
this advanced for looping here.
Okay.
So I am iterating through all the options,
but I am also iterating through each
and every web element.
Right. Okay.
So we have a for loop in here.
And so now what I need to do in here,
guys, now I'm not clicking right,
I just need to print it out
inside my console.
Guys.
Okay, So we need to get the text.
The string
option
text is equal to
option, get text.
And what I will do,
I will print out the option text.
Right. Okay.
So let's run this and see
what we're going to have.
Okay.
Here. There we go.
So let's
go back and expand this a little bit
so you can see each and every option
inside our console.
Right? Pretty cool. All right, guys.
So now we've used regular for loop
to get all the options.
Now we can use the advance for loop
to get all the options as well.
Okay,
Nice.
At 40 miles an hour.
It's easy, right, guys?
Or Probably
or probably you guys are typing
and listening to me at the same time.
That's why
it seems like I'm going to fast.
Okay.
I'm going to push the code anyways
at the end of the class guys.
So if you don't if you missed something,
I could just go back.
You can really type in
or just wait until the end of the class.
I'm just going to push all the code.
Okay, guys,
typing, answering, listening.
That's good, guys. Multitasking tasking.
That's very good.
Okay, guys, any questions in here?
Okay, so now let me show you
the difference
between selecting by visible text
and selecting by value.
Okay.
So, okay, guys, in the previous example,
we saw that
the text, the visible text and the values
the same.
Right, like Monday, Tuesday, Sunday,
whatever it is here
we have audible books and originals.
But you see that the value is different.
Okay?
The attribute value
is completely different in here.
Okay.
So if I want to select let's say
let's let's say
I want to select Alexa skills in here
and I want a selected by value.
Okay, So what I am going to do,
I am going to copy this value, okay?
I'm not going to touch the text in here.
I'm going to get and copy
this value of the attribute
and go back to my script after.
The for loop.
What I will do, I'm going to select,
select by value and what I will do.
I'm going to paste this value
inside the parentheses.
Okay, So now let's go ahead and run this
and let's see
if we can select value.
Okay?
Running Amazon.
So we go, it's
probably going to print everything first.
And now you can see that
dropdown has changed guys.
You can see now it is Alexa skills.
Okay, I hope everyone saw the difference
what was going on.
So for the for the visible text
you are selecting the text
that is actually you see for the values
you need to get the attribute
value of the value attribute.
Okay.
Is that clear?
Guys, any questions?
I hope now you see the difference
between the select by visible text
and selecting by value.
Okay, good.
Okay.
There's the codex.
10 minutes for you guys to type it in
and then we'll continue.
Okay?
Exactly. Also,
the text will be in a black color.
Exactly. Yes.
I mentioned that it's better
for you to select by visible text.
Correct?
Sure. Okay.
So selecting by value.
Right.
So what you need to do in here,
if you're selecting by values,
you need to get the value
of the attribute in here.
Okay. Whenever you selecting by
whenever you're selecting by visible text,
this is the text that you need to get.
Okay.
The value,
the attribute value of value attributes.
Okay, it's a little confusing, but
you can see here
you need to get this value
and whenever you selecting by visible
text,
you need to get this text in here.
All right, guys, any other questions
before we move forward?
Okay.
I hope you guys are done typing
and we can move to the next example
that I want to show you.
Okay. All right. Let's move forward, guys.
So let's talk about now
multiple select dropdown.
Okay.
So I'm going to open up
a new Java class in here
and say
multiple down
have main method in here.
So let's go back
to this.
Let's say, okay, so here
guys, if you look
at this multi select
list, Okay,
So if you look, I can if you see in here,
I can select more than one value
inside this
multi select list. Okay.
So this is it's not really a
like an actual dropdown.
As you can see.
It doesn't drop down in here,
but this is a list where you can see
where you can select one or more values.
Okay, so this is considered
as multiple select dropdown.
Okay guys.
So whenever you are able to select
multiple values inside the list
or inside the dropdown that is considered
as multiple select dropdown.
Okay.
Oh, we're working with this now and,
and what we will do is the same way
as where we were doing with the single,
but we will be having some different
or what's
called different methods in here.
Okay, so
let's go ahead and get started.
So let's go back actually here and
copy this, paste this in here.
Okay.
So in order for me guys to start
interacting with a dropdown guys,
what do I need to do first?
So I navigated to that page, right?
What is my next step here?
Get the elements.
So we need to find the element
first, okay?
And then we need to check
whether it has the select tag or no.
All right. Okay.
So a magic arrow in here.
There we go. So this is my element.
We have a select tag in here.
Yes. Right.
So that means we should be able
to use select class in here.
Right. So I'm going to expand this.
You will see all the options
inside this dropdown.
Okay.
And we can use it as well in here.
So I'm going to copy the value of ID
and I'm going to go back here
and I will create a not this one
RGB element
variable, these states, Right?
Yeah. Okay.
States dropdown because the drive
or mind element
I and what I'm going to do
is this is
okay.
So we figured out what was the idea.
We have a web element variable in here.
What is my next step now
we need a select object, right?
So select
select is equal to new
select and inside the constructor.
What I am going to do this
this self down variable.
Okay, so now guys, so I have an object,
I have my variable.
What I want to do is I want to know
if my job down is multiple select or no.
Any guesses?
How would I do this?
There we go.
So we have a is
multiple method
which comes from select class.
Right? So what I can do in here
select that is multiple.
Right.
Which will return us
a boolean value in here.
So boolean
is multiple
is equal to this.
Right?
And what I want to do,
I just want to print this out.
Okay, so I print this out right now.
What am I getting in return? Dice
If it's if it's a multiple select
that I'm getting a true value.
If not, then we're getting a false value.
Right?
But in this case, since we were able to
select multiple values already manually,
so we should be getting a true value right
as we did in our console.
We have a true value.
So that means our
our dropdown is multiple select.
All right.
So now what I want to do, I want to get
all the options
from, from that dropdown
and what I want to do.
I want to select each and every
what's each and every option
from that multiple select dropdown.
Okay.
So now again
we're going to be looping through
some of the options.
But first, how am I going to,
how am I going to get those options? Dice
when I need a list?
Right?
And what I can do is select that
that option, which will return me
a list of all the web elements
inside that dropdown
element
options is equal.
This.
Okay, so what if guys I want to more
if I want to get those options
only if my dropdown
multiple select us.
How would I do this
if condition right.
So where do I put this?
If condition go?
So which line? 27.
Okay, so if,
if my dropdown is multiple right.
What am I going to do then.
I want to get the options only if there is
only if that dropdown is multiple.
Select does.
Then I have to get everything in here,
cut it
and we need to paste it inside my
if condition.
Right.
So if it's not multiple
then I'm not going inside this condition
and I'm not getting any options.
Okay.
So now what I want to do in here,
I want to create a for loop, right?
And I iterate with each
and every web element in here.
Is that clear, guys?
Any questions?
Okay, No questions. Good.
All right, so for loop in here,
so I am iterating through options
container, right?
And each and every option
that I have is a web element,
right?
So now here
what I will be doing,
guys, I need to get the text
and I need to select
what's called.
I need to select each and every value
from that
dropdown.
Exactly.
So the next step for me
would be getting the actual text from the
SO string
option text right is equal to
select.
No, not select
option, but that's the text.
And so which way in here
am I selecting that?
How am I supposed to select all the values
guys in here get?
I But
why would I go with indexing in here?
Guys?
Okay, we don't need indexing here.
What do we need in here?
We can select by visible text,
and from each iteration
we make, we're getting the next
the next available text so we
can paste that inside that method, Right?
So select the select
by visible text in here.
And my visible text
is the option text variable.
And let's just give it
that kind of a pause
so that we can see
how it's going to select right.
So let's run this go.
So you can see that
we're selecting each and every value
inside that dropdown one by one.
Okay, Is that clear, guys?
Any questions?
Pretty cool, right?
Okay. So selecting a few from the.
Okay guys.
So what are we doing here?
We're getting all the options, right?
So on line 27,
so we have all the options in hand.
We have it in a list of web elements.
So now all we're trying to do
is we're trying to go through
each and every option that we have, right?
So once we're doing this.
So on the first iteration,
what I am doing,
I am getting the text of the first
option,
okay, once I get the text in there,
what I do is selected by the visible text.
So on my first iteration is my text guys,
if I get the text on my first iteration,
what is my text?
My text should be California, right?
So when it's California, what I am doing
is here I'm selecting by visible text.
So I already got that text
and I pasted in here.
So every time I iterate through my
for loop,
I'm getting a new text in here guys.
Okay,
so that's how I am selecting by visible
text of the text of the text
that I got right now.
Okay.
Immediate
the idea on line 21. Yes.
So all we needed
is the idea of our job done.
So if you look in here,
this is I am selecting my drop down.
Okay?
And since it has a select tag,
we can perform these actions
by using select class.
Okay.
So if you want to stop or New York. Right.
So you're getting the text.
You're getting the text.
So what do you need
to do in here? Guys? Just
just give me some ideas.
So if I want this,
I want to stop in New York, okay?
If condition and then you break your loop.
There we go.
Easy, right, guys?
So you're getting the text every time.
So once you get the text
in, that text is equal to you to New York.
Then what you need to do,
you need to write that loop
and that you're out of your iteration.
Okay.
Any questions, guys?
Okay. So there is one more thing.
That one thing that we can do with
multiple select
dropdowns,
which we cannot do with single select.
Okay, So since we can do
what's called,
we can select multiple values
inside the
inside the multiple select dropdown.
What we can also do,
we can select these values as well
okay,
so what I'm going to be doing in here.
So since
if we go through this
iteration, we're going
be selecting all the values, right?
All the options in that dropdown.
So what I want to do, I want to d
select one of the values
and this selecting is happening
the same way we selected.
We select our options.
So three ways guys by index,
by value and by visible text.
But what we can also do is d select
all the options right away.
Okay, so let's go actually
to the class notes first.
And so in order to select
to B select
any option and drop down.
Okay, so you need to first
make sure that your dropdown
is multiple select.
Okay, so
now option in dropdown,
make sure your top down is
multiple select
okay and the methods you can use are
I think it was the select
value
you can
select
visible text
and select index
and you
select by.
I mean we select all.
Okay. Okay.
So first of all guys,
if you want to d select any values,
you need to make sure your dropdown
is multiple select and.
These are four methods
that you can implement
to d select values from the dropdown.
Okay, so.
So what I am going to do,
since we already have the select
object in here, will you select
and will do this select by index
and let's do index five.
So if I do index five,
guess what's going to happen in here?
Which one is going to get these selected
with Texas, Ohio.
Okay, what else?
Okay. Texas or Ohio?
Okay.
Okay. All right. Texas or Ohio.
Okay, so let's run this
where we go.
So we selecting everything in here.
There we go.
So we we selected it by index of five.
So here it's going to be the Texas value,
which is the selected here.
And what we also can do let me
comment this out
and lets you select everything right away,
okay, So let me run this.
We'll see how this is going to look.
Okay.
Selecting everything again
variable and then these selected
everything one by one, right?
It starts from zero guys.
No, no, no.
It's not going to start from one. Okay.
We talked about this, right, guys?
X plus you start identifying
the elements with X path from one
because you cannot say,
hey, this is the you can say that
this is the first second element, right?
So think about it this way.
This is the first element.
This is second element.
But if you go
in Java or if you go with Selenium,
you will need to start
your indexing from zero.
Okay,
sure.
Let's put that down in notes
indexing and Express
starts from one.
So indexing starts from zero.
Okay.
All right.
Any questions, guys?
Any questions on dropdowns?
Okay, so let's do one more example, guys,
with the iterator.
Okay?
Since you guys already know
what the narrator is,
you guys know what collections are, right?
So let's do one example with iterator.
Okay?
Iterator
here.
So let me see.
Okay, So let's
actually go ahead and get for instance.
Okay, So let's go ahead and
copy this
code sitting here.
Okay. So we are navigating to Amazon.
We know the ID of that dropdown, right?
So what I want to do
guys, I want to check if this
if this
dropdown is multiple select
or not first guys
and if it's not multiple select
only then I need to go
and start iterating
through each and every option that it has.
Okay,
so what do I need to do in here guys?
so let's get the boolean value right.
So still boolean is
multiple is equal to select.
That is multiple.
Right? And
my F condition only if
only if my value is false guys.
Right.
Only if it's not multiple select
only then what I want to do,
I need go ahead and start iterating.
So if I do this
in here so I need it opposite, right?
So I don't need it is multiple
and I just need a exclamation
mark in here.
Okay.
What is better?
It's always better to have.
It's always better to have
variables, guys.
Okay.
Like if you remember with
we were doing web element
combined with is selected, right?
So we had to we had to check.
So you already had one variable
so you don't have to check it again.
Okay.
So it's going to it's going to increase
your we use ability in the future.
Okay.
So what is my next step, guys?
So now we're trying to verify
if it's not multiple select.
So I want to get all the options now.
Okay.
So we need to list we need a list of web
elements again, right.
Web element
in here, options is equal to select.
Get. Right.
So we have
options in here.
So what is my next step now, guys?
So we're not using any for loop in here.
We're going to be using
an integrated right.
So what is the nightmare right here?
First of all, guys,
what is it going to help us to do?
Okay, loop for collections. Okay.
So what is an item?
Is a class Is it an interface?
What is it, guys?
It's an interface, right?
So how do you create
an object of that interface?
Can I do
iterator is equal to new either later goes
can I
read really?
So if
I want to create an object of the iterator
or any other interface,
how would I do this guys?
So cannot directly.
People say yes, come on guys,
you guys should know this already
should implement
user interface.
Okay.
I was in last topic.
No you should.
You should know I interfaces already.
Right guys?
So my question is how do you create
an object of that interface?
Guess
new item later.
Okay.
Okay guys.
So you can't create an object
of the interface right.
If you want to create
an object of the interface, it should.
It cannot be directly right.
So it's either
you're referring to a different class so
that you can get an object or you cannot
create an object of that interface.
So. So right now
what I am going to do in here,
so I need to
iterate
through through the options, right?
So what I'm going to do options dot
iterator in here
and what I am getting in return,
I'm getting an iterator in return, right?
So I iterator
the web elements do
it is equal to options that I the writer.
And then now
what am I going to do in here guys?
So I have my iterator,
I have my list of options.
So what are we doing?
So now we need a wild loop, right?
So while what am I having in my condition?
Guys, while
there should be something going on, right?
While I'm stuck in ahead
and there is something,
I'm going to go inside this loop.
Right.
So while it has something on my next step,
only then what I'm going to do
I'm going to go inside.
Right?
So if I go inside this loop,
what do I need to do, guys,
I want to print each and
every option again from that,
from that
dropdown guys.
Okay?
So any time I step inside this loop,
I need to find web element first, right?
So what?
This is going to be
my dropdown option, right?
Is going to be equal my next step.
Any time I step in that,
I step inside this wild loop,
I need to get the next element
and once I have that element,
I can get the text of it right.
So option text is equal to
drop down option that that text, right?
And then we simply
print those options out.
Okay, So let's run this and see.
We can see all the options in our console.
Okay.
Step back and see here. There we go.
So we see all the departments
inside our console, right?
So pretty cool.
So we did all the ways, right?
So we did for regular for loop
advanced for loop guys.
Now we did it with iterator
or interacted with different different
elements and options
in the dropdown.
Okay guys,
one more time going over this, right?
So okay, line 24,
everyone knows it's not multiple select
only then we're going inside the line
25th, right?
So in line 25, what I'm doing, I'm
getting two options,
storing them inside the list container.
And then
from there guys, what I need to do,
I need to iterate
right through each and every element
that I have inside that container.
But this time
I'm not going to use for loop.
I'm using the iterator. Okay?
So when I use this method of iterator,
it will return me the iterator of the web
elements.
Okay.
It's like doing this list of web elements,
but this time it's an iterator of web
elements.
Okay?
And we have a variable for it. So now
here, I'm not using it for loop,
I'm using a while loop
where it requires us
to have a condition inside.
Right.
So here,
when I'm iterating,
whenever I'm stepping forward,
if I have anything, if it's not empty
or if it's not null
or I have any values when I step forward,
only then what I'm doing I'm
going inside the line 28.
Okay?
And when I go to the line 28, my next step
is going to return web element.
Okay, Why web element?
Because I have an iterator of web
elements.
Okay.
And once get my single web element in here
on line 29, I can simply get the text
from that Web element
and I can print that option
out inside my console.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys?
Any questions?
Okay. But
all right,
guys, any questions at all from dropdowns,
from whatever
we've done so far in selenium, guys? Yep.
You just need practice. That's good.
And I'm going to give you
a couple of tasks.
Okay.
So a couple of homeworks for you guys.
So this is going to be really good tests
in here.
Okay.
So let me check
what I have for you.
Okay?
All right. Okay, guys.
So first task.
Okay,
so you need to go to the Facebook page.
You need to click on create new account.
Okay.
So let's do this together.
Where's Facebook?
Hey, right here.
Close this one.
Click on Create new account.
You're going to see this pop up, right?
So what I want you to do, guys,
I want you to verify
that the month dropdown as 12 month.
Okay, Day dropdown has 31 days
and year dropdown has
116 year options.
Okay.
And then what you want to do
is select your date of birth
and then quit the browser. Okay.
Is that guys?
Any questions?
Okay.
But so the second one guys,
what you want to do in here.
So first one is yes, verify
and then select a date of birth
and then quit the browser.
The second task
is you going in to the page.
You need to fill out the whole form now
and click the sign now.
Okay.
Put any fake names. What you want to do.
It doesn't really matter what select
the birthday, any birthday
you want to select in here
and then what I want
you to do is to use the list.
Start these what's called
gender radio buttons in the list
and use them and manipulate them that way.
Do not just go ahead and click.
Okay guys, please use.
The list of web elements
as we've done today
with checkboxes and implemented that way.
Okay, so fill out the whole form.
Click on, sign up, quit browser.
Okay. And then here,
go to eBay.
Okay, let's go to eBay.
Okay, Go.
Okay, let's go to eBay in here.
So from all categories in here,
what I want you to select
was that in here,
computer tables and network in
tablets, tables,
computer tablets,
networking selected from here.
Okay, click
on search and verified the header.
So I click the wrong thing.
Okay, Let's go back
all categories, computers, tablets.
Right. And now click on select.
And actually I'm in search.
Okay, So when you search,
what I want you to do, guys,
I want you to verify
this header appear in here.
Okay?
Is that clear, guys?
Okay, good.
All right.
Three pretty good tasks
which will allow you guys
to do a lot of different
manipulations
and interactions with the elements.
Okay.
Yes, I can post this in the
course announcements.
See that?
Okay, guys.
Yes, I'll push the card.
But before we wrap up.
Okay, guys, so I have a question for you.
So in the element, Web element commands
guys that we have covered
last class, right.
So there was three different
methods is is displayed
is enabled and is selected.
Right.
So if I want to see that the element is
enabled,
I'm going to do is enabled, right?
What if I want to verify
that the element is not enabled?
How can I do this?
Guys,
we have is disabled guys
wouldn't be easier to use.
Yeah, right.
Is disabled
would be really convenient if it existed.
Right.
So it doesn't exist guys.
So the first
the first option
that you guys had, the solution
that you put.
Yeah.
The solution that you put first
with the exclamation
guys that is the correct way
of identifying that.
The element is this if it's disabled,
okay there's no option is
in selenium.
So that's why you have to report
that with an exclamation mark.
Okay guys.
So be careful of these kind of questions
this is
this might be one of the interview
questions that you may get.
Okay.
And we will be going over more
more interview questions,
guys.
The question was, if you want to identify
if you want to verify the
element is disabled, what you want to use,
what you can use, well,
that would interact with.
And so then what would be the most part
of Java that would interact with Selenium?
All of it. Okay.
So the Java that you're learning right
now, it's going
you're going to have all of it in,
in building the framework.
It's not only finding elements
and performing actions, okay?
It's maintaining your framework,
it's reusing this.
It's not hard coding. Okay.
So all all the Java that you're learning
right now, it's going to be very,
very useful in building the frameworks.
Okay.
All right, guys.
If no other questions, then what we can do
can wrap it up for today. Okay.
And I will see you tomorrow.
And please for tomorrow, guys,
take a look at the pop
ups and iframes.
All right, guys, have a good night.
Everyone.
Please make sure you practice
and I will you tomorrow.
Thanks, everybody. Bye.