All right,
So from here, guys, we are going to start.
Yes, I already started.
It started already.
So now for the class
to let me open our notes
first,
we will quickly recap all of the concepts
which we have learned yesterday,
and then we will proceed further
with the new concepts, with the new topics
which we have today.
What are the remaining attributes of this
distance you are going to learn today?
We will going to work on all of this
things one by one, by.
Okay guys.
So first, what is test engine?
Currently we are learning testing visa.
Yes, this is our tool
and framework, which is based on
annotations.
Correct
categories.
Right now we are learning test
and as a tool we are not learning
testing as a framework as of now.
Right.
So this is just a tool
which we are learning right now.
We will definitely implement
the framework part also, but right now
we are learning it as
a tool. I remember this case
by now after this interest in D as a tool.
If we are using,
why are we using test engine?
This is extremely important to understand
guys.
Why are we using test and
when it comes to automation
of the best application,
we already have selenium
when it comes to programing language.
We have Java with us, so to me
all the setup is there.
Then why do we need testing?
Yes, to make our life easier.
It provides
multiple options
for execution,
which can be
integrated
easily
with the name You write,
for example, on post condition
preconditions.
Right.
Enable and disable priorities.
So these are the customizations
and multiple options
for the execution list and duplicates.
We can simply integrate
all of this things with ADD
in selenium,
the code which we are writing.
Still,
we are writing this code in selenium.
All right. The methods we are using
static, correct?
Right.
So do have some integrated option
to advanced features.
Right.
In order to utilize all of those advanced
features, we need this synergy by.
Let's talk about the loopholes.
First, I am writing without testing.
Without testing G.
No priority is available.
No priority for execution
sequence. Right.
Earlier, we had to execute
all the test cases in a single shot.
Right.
In one class, if I'm executing,
I was able to execute the whole class,
but I didn't have any option
to execute the things
the way I want it to execute right.
But then testing did came in. Testing.
This is if you have different test cases
you can better case
all of those test cases
so you can maintain
the sequence of execution
according to your wish,
according to your choice,
according to your requirement,
you can maintain
the sequence of execution.
That's what you can do in this, Right.
So without testing, you wouldn't have
any priority for the execution sequence.
Second thing,
no way to exclude kits
from execution.
Earlier, we didn't have any option through
which we can exclude artists together
include artist guest.
Now we can have this
or we have this option.
Why? Question What is that option?
Enable and disable option.
Right.
Starting
no reporting structure.
We were just executing the things,
but we were not getting any any report
right.
We were not getting the total time
it took for the execution.
How many?
This we have executed,
how many files we have executed.
What is the result?
How many test cases buzzed?
How many test kits?
This will eliminate test
because this to skip.
We did not have any kind of arrangement
in selenium
to get these kind of detailed reports.
But now when it comes to test
and even we have implemented
all of this fast indexed
and we got this facility, we got this
feature through which we can get
this kind of detailed report,
right.
That's why without test we wouldn't
all of the things with test in GB,
you have all these things.
So far we learned this thing, right?
I'm not taking a session right now
because the session part is still pending,
right?
Half of the sessions
with video study off of the session.
We will completely know
one by one will see
and direct test annotation.
Then with days.
What kind of annotation is this?
So today's
execute test cases
we must write.
Our method are method
with the test annotation.
Correct.
If I'm going to write any method,
if I'm going to write any method
without a direct test annotation,
I will not be able to execute
that particular test.
Guess.
So at the request, annotation
is the most important annotation
in our entire test tool
as well as interest and depend.
But remember whether we are talking about
code or we are talking about framework.
Our main goal is execution
and for execution we always need this.
A direct test annotation near
word.
Please ask What
do I need to?
What should I repeat?
Okay, fine.
Got to. All right.
So without a direct test,
if you are writing any method
and if you try to execute
when you'll be able to execute that method
or that particular test, guess
which doesn't have this direct annotation.
Can we do that? No.
Second thing,
because we're using a direct test
annotation, so are all of our
methods are annotated methods, right?
Because we are using annotated methods
here or execution with iterate test
annotation, we will not use the method
for our execution.
Correct.
Second thing is we will not use Mende
method for our execution
because we have a direct test annotation
here.
Right.
We will
we will discuss on this point also.
Now it's like anything else,
how many at the latest annotation
we can have in one class, meaning write
as many as we want according
to the requirement one to infinity.
Correct. Great.
You must have learned this range
for right?
Quite good.
In school.
Grade one to infinity. Okay.
As many situations,
as many numbers as we want,
we can write this at the latest annotation
with methods in one class.
According to article, we correct
less at least one
we should have In order to execute more.
We can have as many as we want right now.
After this.
If I had some methods,
if I had some method to request annotation
and some methods without it
that it just annotation,
would it work?
Okay, class will execute,
but only those methods that execute
that have the request annotation part.
Right.
That categorized then let's talk about
it will only execute that test right
before method.
What is this guys?
Before method is also one annotation.
We learned yesterday
fine.
It executes before
any test or before every test.
Before each test.
Before
for each as a precondition.
We can also call it precondition.
Can we call it precondition or not?
Yes, we can call it precondition.
If you remember, we put our code
for launching the browser, right?
Launching the browser before that code
and also navigating to your end.
We put that code in before method, iterate
before method.
Great annotation. Why?
Because that was our precondition.
That was a precondition.
Remember, guys, this part,
let me show you.
If you go inside, the logic is right here.
If Sydney read it before method,
we have used
this annotation to launch our browser
and to navigate.
And you are right,
this was our precondition.
So we put it inside of precondition for
now. Let's go ahead
as a precondition.
If I have been tests,
this precondition will execute 14 times.
If I have to be intense, executes
for 15 times before
all the test case is right,
then the next one was after method, right?
We extended that also after method.
How we can call this part automatic.
Right? It executes.
It executes
after
every test
as opposed to condition.
Right.
This is at my post condition.
So after every test, yes.
If I come across any requirement
which I need to execute
after every single test,
guess what I will do?
I will put all of those code,
those pieces of code
inside my iterate after method annotation.
Right.
So it will execute
after every single method
which is having this request.
And if they should clear
now after that
and then before class,
what is it?
Just the one it executes before class.
Okay.
Let me ask one question here.
Let's say I have two classes, right?
Logic based and best in class.
This two class and I put this day before
class insight, this dingy test
and you class here.
So tell me if I'm going to execute
logging test will execute
before loading this class. Also
again, let me repeat my question.
This is my best in class, right?
I put it today before class function here
and I'm trying to execute this class
so that iterate before class will execute
for this particular class.
This is my question base, but it execute.
No, it will not. Why?
Because before class is applicable
only for the class.
When we are writing
this particular annotation. Right.
So it will execute
right before the class gets executed.
Which class where you have mentioned this.
Iterate
before class for the specific class.
This annotation works so it
executes once
before the class
executes.
Right.
Similarly,
we have edit after class annotation.
So why we use after class annotation?
Okay, one more thing.
What kind of conditions we can have?
What about
we will
we will go through
that part of the security we have.
We have it in a bucket.
So can you think of a situation
which we need to put in this
before class and right after class, any
practical situation
or condition that you can think of
while you are working,
let's say on a project
and you think this is the condition
I should put in right before class
or after class.
I gave you one example.
Remember?
Right.
So me opening the browser is available
for all the methods, for all the test.
So if we open the browser,
just take one thing.
It will not work.
Great,
because I have like 16 just to get this.
So intent is to get this
definitely opening the browser
just one time is not a good option
that it is my remaining main test.
This will fail.
So remember in this think this is this.
If you are writing some data,
if you are trying to pass some properties,
those properties, those data
you put in one file
and that can read in
this before class annotation
got to got it right.
So in that part this properties file this
this data file and you can read
in your address before class.
So before even actually starting your test
execution,
you will be having all that data ready,
which you will be reading in your domain
in ten or 15 or 20 days to get this right.
So this is the exact condition
which you can put inside
your at the rate before class on rotation
rate.
Similarly, if you want to close the file,
then it after class is available
here, go ahead and use it.
All right.
So it executes once
after the class executes
the database.
And then I test before my third
after method,
before class, after class five annotations
We learned yesterday.
Right now, what what was the next thing?
What was the next thing?
Which we learn, I
should be sure.
So let's say should if you have,
nobody is before a chance.
We have attributes.
Remember,
there's ten attributes.
Yes, I think so.
Let me give you one example here.
Let's say you are working on word
task, right in your project.
You have a task
that you have to perform log in operation.
Right now, when I say log in operation,
it simply means you have to enter
user name and password.
Then the next one is you have to add one
employee in the application just to add
one employee in the application,
you have to pass your first name.
Last name.
With the name, the condition is
you have to perform both this operation.
You have to perform both this test
because this execution on Chrome browser,
you have to
test this operations
on your test environment, right?
So that you are all of their test in mind.
This Chrome browser name
everything you cannot pass
directly hardcoded in your project.
Right? Right. No.
We are writing hardcoded data
in your practical life
you will not pass data hard for it.
I will say no later than the session.
Only today only we have this topic
in our pipeline to tell you.
So you have to parse this data
from some fight
right from that file
if you're passing this data.
So for launching the browser,
for selecting the browser for us,
for launching that you are enforced,
you need this data.
If you need this data,
you have to read one file with your list,
all of this data, right?
But you have kept this data.
This data is stored in some file
to read that file
because your code is in a read
before the method.
This is your precondition
to launch the browser.
For launching the browser,
you need browser name unity you are.
And so before even before method,
you have to read this file.
So what is the best place to read this
file from?
You can read this
file in iterate before class.
So when
you put this condition
of reading the file straight before class,
what you will do it
will read to complete data of this file.
Now when you go read before method,
remember there is the execution sequence.
First iterate before class executes, then
be formatted, execute,
then your actual test execute.
Right.
So now before class,
you're reading the data from the file.
Before methods.
You are using this data as a browser name.
As a you are everything
in your actual test.
You're using this username and password
from this fight, right?
So that's why you can put these
as a practical example
inside your address before class.
When I say reading the face,
reading the data from the clear
is this clear to everyone?
Students
by the now
we have test and
attributes here with us.
All right.
What was the first attribute
we have learned yesterday?
Priority. All right.
What is the default value of priority days
by default,
priority is 6 to 0 for all that.
This is. All right.
All right.
One more thing. Before
go into the priority.
If we do not have any priority,
on what basis?
Your test
to execute all of your test cases
in the alphabetical order.
Right.
It follows alphabetical order
to execute your test.
Guess it's fine.
I don't want this alphabetical order
so I can better taste my test
because according to my requirement,
note of total should itself
political based. Yep.
All right.
So now, next thing by default,
the priority is set to zero
for all the test cases,
right?
Whatever the test gives us, we have
the priority is set to zero.
It's up to us now which priority we will
going to provide to all of our test cases.
Remember, we provided the priority
according to our choice.
Priority one, two, three, four. Right.
That was my defined sequence.
User defined the sequence of execution
and test indeed follows
this user defined sequence,
whatever the sequence I want
to define correct in the priority,
we can do it.
So that was the priority
we know yesterday.
What was the second attribute?
All right, fine.
What was the
second one enabled
right, by me using it. But
to include
or exclude our test cases in execution,
let's to update
is because I don't want to execute
all of this to get this in a single shot.
So what I can do in this case,
I can execute some of them.
I can execute.
I can exclude some of them. Right.
For example, smoke test, regression test,
or any of their test rate.
So inclusion and exclusion is depending
on one attribute that a good name is in a
book by default, by default,
every test case is enable or disable.
By default,
every test case is enable to true.
If we need to exclude test case,
we have to stick this
false.
The moment you write
enable is equal to false.
It will not be a part of your execution.
Correct
by Wednesday.
That is not answering today.
I remember
he was asking so many things yesterday.
When is he
agreed to that date?
I want you to provide genuine feedback.
Am I going slow now? Yes.
I really need this.
I really need this. That's
what I'm asking.
So, Pop.
All right, do let me know, right?
If you think that I'm going fast,
If you think you're not taking anything,
do let me know.
Thank you, sir.
All right, guys.
So priority.
No, he is not
for testing.
Do you
attribute was priority enable disable
that third one did we use was
what was the third one we used
as version correct
bemused assertion.
Fine.
What kind of assertions
we have seen yesterday?
Assertion is all
two bytes.
No, I am talking about the category
so we used yesterday hard assertion
right?
I explained to you what is hard assertion?
What is our decision days
it the moment
it finds
an address
it stops
execution
and will give us the
breakpoint right?
Right. Next.
The moment it finds an edit,
it starts execution
and it will give us the breakpoint.
Also on.
Let me right like this a
it gives us
the breakpoint where it was broken.
Correct. That was the hard decision.
Which class
we have used for our assertion,
which class we have used
a third class
from where we are
getting is a third class.
We are getting this
a third class from testing.
You know, no java utils.
We are getting this from testing.
Let me show you once again.
There you go in the section right
when you put here,
just going to the import
and you will check
or repeat test and do not assert.
Right.
We are not using it from Java dot utils,
we are using it from test and you only
recognize.
Okay, fine.
Let's go ahead guys.
Let me show you just one more,
one more table
part assertion, part attribute,
and then we'll switch on to the next part.
So remember yesterday
we have seen one assertion assert dark
assert equals, right?
Why we use that assert
thought assert equals
because here if you see
we were comparing two values, right?
We were comparing two venues to verify.
That's why we used assert equals.
But if there is a boolean condition,
if I want to check one boolean
condition, let's say I want to check
the existence of the element.
Can I use then
assert daughters are equals. In that case,
if I want to check just one boolean
condition.
No, we have to use assert, not assert two.
So let me write that.
But I'm going to it here. Assert
or assert.
So boolean condition.
So what is the boolean condition
I'm writing?
Welcome attribute is displayed
right?
Assert true or false?
This is the boolean condition.
If my this condition is true.
Remember I told you yesterday
if we are using assert
assertion is parsed,
it will not give you any message.
It will let you execute
your remaining piece of code.
Right.
But the moment it gets an error,
it distorts the execution.
So here I'm going to print
simple data that is
my associate is false.
Fine.
I'm going to write it.
Enable is equal to false.
I don't want to use this one. Fine.
So just one I'm going to
execute now, let me run this.
This is the hard assertion, right?
The second method of assertion I'm using,
but still this is hard assertion.
We are not using to solve position.
Remember
working fine.
You see, I got this message.
My assertion is parsed
Where is this message available?
This message is available
on main number 37 by
remember
it follows top to bottom approach, right?
For execution, it means my line number 36
got executed fast.
That's why my cursor went to 37 nine.
Number eight.
And that's why we are getting this message
here.
Right guys?
So a third dart,
a search tool is another assertion.
Method assert, dart assert equals.
It is another assertion method clear.
Is it clear? Is
great.
Let's move forward now.
Time to learn something new,
something more interesting.
See, I can see one problem with this hard
assertion days.
What is that problem?
Let me tell you
what example
I'm going to work on one entering
scenario.
When I say including scenario,
what does it mean?
Because it means I'm going to perform log
in, I'm going to verify
their state
dashboard page
and then I'm going to perform log out.
It means what?
The user came
by a log in verified dashboard
page user went out by a local operation.
Write this three thing
if I'm going to log in here
and I got the error here
and I put her decision
to allow me to execute this part
in this part, no.
Right.
But my code is extremely important
and I want to execute
my complete piece of code.
I want to execute all that written log
in verification of dashboard page
log of all this becomes
I want to execute right.
And I want to know one thing, how many
errors I'm having in this scenario.
When I say end to end, the scenario,
it means from log in to log out
every single thing it must include.
So when I say entering scenario,
I need some kind of assertion.
I need some kind of assertion
which allow me to go ahead
and execute complete into one scenario
and it will give me the report in the end,
it will not interrupt me in between hard
assertion.
I have a problem with hard assertion.
What is the problem if error comes on line
number two and I have 200 lines of code
to execute, it will not allow me to
execute remaining what may be eight lines.
Right.
That's why I was expecting something else.
And then I found one more kind of
assertion that might be going
stuck.
The solution
right now, one more flexibility,
soft assertion voice.
What is that flexibility?
Let me get
your log in is big right?
Fine.
Or let's see, your log in is passed
it came here
your verification of dashboard pages thing
it is
your verification of log out
is also feed point
it close the browser.
It opens the browser here
the precondition in the post condition.
I'm talking about more soft associated
does soft assertion executes this code
then executes this code, then executes
this code, then
execute this post condition
first precondition, execute
all these three
and then post condition In the end,
it will give you the consolidated report
which says, Hey,
your login was passed,
your dashboard was filled,
and the point of sale is this your log
code was built.
And the point of it is
this is your total execution report.
Now, your all the methods got executed.
Take your entire piece of code
word executed.
It was not interrupted inbetween
by the assertion, even though it was paid
right, even though it was not fulfilling
the condition of assertion
it was allowing.
It allowed your entire code.
It allowed you
to execute your entire code,
and then it gave you the report
after the execution.
That's what Soft Associate does
consent clear to
everyone what soft assertion does?
Why we should use soft assertion
is that anyone who having any problem
with this definition
what I just say.
All right,
let's implement you guys, then.
All clear. That's good.
Let's try to implement this first.
I will give you a very basic example,
and then I will give you the same example,
two examples I will give you,
because the concept is important.
I'm going to write you saw
a solution,
one, because I will give you two examples.
So I'm writing soft assertion
one and soft assertion that,
okay, let's say my first is string.
I'm writing sorry.
First I'm going to write my main method.
This is my method.
Now, not mine
method actually unaffected method.
I'm writing here
a solution
is right.
So you guys, what I'm doing here
are test case.
In another test guess question.
Where do we need hard assertion then?
We need hard assertion.
We're a strict check is applicable right?
Vanessa is strict objective simply means
I don't want to execute anything
if the error comes at this point of time.
Right. I don't want to proceed further.
First, take this error, fix this error
and then go further.
Right.
If there is a strict check,
points are available in the application
and I know after this
that is not a much important code.
Right.
This is the more important point
which I want to verify.
Then we have to use hard session,
but it wasn't there.
Scored bandit.
Let's do it. I'm going to write to string.
The first one I'm writing
is expected to spring is equals to
batch and is
one of the best batches.
Then it's frame stake
and when I'm writing is this is expected
that it might actually spring
batch pain is
one of the
batches fine
then you go
whatever use it.
I implemented
all right and so then we use hard solution
there are called our code
and our verification validation
check point is very strict.
It means I don't want to execute
further code
until unless my this code works right?
Sometimes you get this kind of conditions
in your project
for example of your log in part
if you log in part is not working
correctly, what you execute your dashboard
verification or load functionality
or any of that thing.
This is a blocker, right?
If user is coming on your application,
if user is using your web application
and he or she is not able to log in
to the application, isn't it a blocker.
Right.
So there if you use soft assertion
and you try to execute the remaining code,
which is not that important,
for example local verification
or some other verification,
it is of no use.
In that case,
you have to use hard assertion.
I'm being honest,
my log in functionality works fine.
You should not proceed for further. Right.
So we have to identify the requirement
in which requirement
to be able to use
soft assertion and data requirement.
We have to use our decision.
All right.
Okay, guys, let's proceed for the
good work.
Good work.
Now see
how decisions how how
we'll use the asset class in the hard
decision base.
We simply wrote assert assert
equals assert assert group right.
We got the assert class directly from test
and in the soft assertion
using software solution in test
is slightly different than hard assertion.
Right.
Guys, I'd like to invite
your complete assertion here.
Sorry, not as I would like to invite
your complete attention.
Okay, fine. My
when you are so much
focused on to their topic,
it happens some day.
All right.
So now see, I'm going to write here
soft assert.
Great.
Now, you see, when I say soft assertion,
it's a soft assert object,
darkest in deep thought, asserts, correct
I'm going to use this soft.
This is the class that I'm going
to use a soft assert class here.
Now to create the object of this class
that makes it I'm going to write
the soft assert is equal to in Java.
How we create the object
with nil keyword right
positive
bindings.
Is this correct?
Tell me all java developers,
is this correct or not?
You actually definitely
looks right to this operate.
Well, thanks.
All right.
Now see, guys,
I created the object of my soft position.
Now I have to use my soft position. Okay.
How can I use this off position?
See, soft assert dart,
Whatever the methods I was using there
I can use here on the soft assert
assert equals.
Can you see
us articles
as they're true also available
assert equals also available?
I'm trying to.
I'm trying to compare to values
to get that right.
So which one should I use?
Assert true or assert equals
assert equals
point.
Let me take my strange from here
and I'm writing
expected comma
lecture
correct?
Is this correct?
Now let's proceed for the
I'm going to write here say just to show
you just to show you one thing.
See again I'm writing soft assert dart
assert true.
If condition is true,
then I'm going to get to.
But yet I'm passing
intentionally is false.
This condition
now to me when I'm saying
assert, assert true,
but here I'm getting false
bullet.
True or false?
Really positive can be in this condition.
Correct or incorrect in this case
it is pain
because I'm trying to get to
it is incorrect condition right now.
Let me put one thing here.
My code after
false assertion
right.
I'm going to copy this.
I'm going to stick to my code after
second session.
Let me pick one more.
I'm writing
soft assert dart, a third false.
But here I'm passing two as a condition.
So I'm writing here
my code
after
third assumption
and then again
I'm writing soft assert or assert
false.
Make it false in this condition.
True or not
the fourth condition
my code after
for the session
guys tell me fourth
condition is floor not line number 24.
Is this correct or incorrect?
Minus minus plus false. False.
True simple right.
This time it is correct.
See, I'm expecting false.
It is giving me
false statements. Condition two
When condition
is false, then I'm expecting to end.
It is giving me false like line number 18.
This condition is incorrect.
Then line number 21 I'm expecting false.
It is giving me true again.
Condition incorrect.
Line number 24.
I'm expecting false.
It is giving me false condition.
Go minus, minus plus. Correct.
For conditions.
I've mentioned to you guys for conditions
I've mentioned here
in this for three are incorrect.
One is correct right this now tell me
now tell me my code for these two
from line number 22.
Line number 24 is extremely potent
but before that I have to verification
point here.
If I use a harder solution,
if I use harder session,
will allow me to execute this code.
Also, if I get any error here. No,
but soft position
allows me to execute
my remaining piece of code
even if I get an error
into the very first assumption.
But this is the basic advantage.
This is the main advantage
of using soft solution that you can have
in number of verification and validation
check points
in your single test case,
and it will execute your complete code.
It will perform all the verification
and validation operations
for all the check points that you have
mentioned by a solved assertions.
Right.
And in the end, once you're done
with the execution, it will give you
the collective report of all the execution
logic
guys.
Getting my point.
Okay.
Okay, let's proceed further.
Still, the code is not completed days.
Remember,
it's still the code is not completed.
Right.
I'm going to write one more thing here.
Let's say string
new expected is equal to
is last
assertion.
This code will also be passed. Right
now. Now, what is the V?
What is the way to guarantee
consolidated report?
Soft assertion
itself will not provide anything.
We have to provide one particular method.
We have to provide one particular.
We have to collect one particular
method from soft position.
Right.
Why using this object software.
So we need collective report.
So the last statement,
make sure you remember this point.
The last statement of your estimate that
this is your right, the request method.
Right.
This must be
your last statement of your test.
Guess what I'm going to write
if you don't write this statement,
you will not get any report after that.
If you write something again,
it will not work.
So it will collect the report.
The moment you write this particular statement, the statement I'm going to write
solve, assert
Doc, let's start on
this.
Assert all is the method I'm going to I'm
going to put the media
to collect
right
next to collect
all the assertions, information
we need to call this assert all method.
One more point.
This should be the last statement.
All your tests last.
The statement should be this one
soft assert assert all.
Is it clear?
Now let me execute it.
Can you see what the thing is?
We know this assertion failed.
But still I got my message,
my code after first assertion,
my quote of the second assertion
microdot for the third assertion, my code
after the photo session.
It means for every single statement
printed right now,
let me show you the actual magic here.
Click to see the difference.
The following assertion assert failed.
The following asserts Failure means more
multiple assertions like Go below,
go below and check which one.
If this batch
then is one of the worst batches,
but all batch
ten is one of the best images.
Correct?
Can I guess my first failure
it was expecting true, but we found false.
That was the second failure expected.
False. Right.
And we were getting explicit false,
but we were getting to three assertions
failed it.
Give me the information
of this three correct.
Guys, are you getting my point?
You'll see it expected
false actually is true.
Expecting true, found false.
This was expected.
We found this part only
right here.
If you'll see here,
it says on line number.
This line number this here
also line number.
This.
If you go to this complete data, go here.
Right.
We will get the complete data
from this off the
like if we close this assert.
Plus this is my soft assertions
we generally use.
So can you show the end of your code
again?
I didn't get that.
Yes, sure.
There you go.
Simple with the object. Soft assert.
You have to call this assert all method.
That's it.
Is it clear to everyone? Students
So what?
Any note, any question
Now let's actually implement
this Let's implement
it actually energy and application.
Right.
So I'm going to write here my second
class guy. So
astonishing, right?
Someone was asking to put the commands
also with the method.
So wherever I think that this one should
be, remember I'm putting the command also.
Okay.
So what it do it does basically
whenever you prefer
this code in the future
you will remember that all this code
is associated for this particular company
and we are using this particular
method for this reason.
So it will help in some somewhat.
I can see some minute by.
So now let's try to implement this code.
Yes. Correct. Correct. It is true.
See it is giving you
that is expected. True.
But following the false expected
best in is the was the batch.
But all this expected.
This is the last session but found
this is last assertion with the gap.
Okay so all the solutions are just giving
you both the expected value
do is but its actual value.
Your concern is more informative
you'll see that.
Thank you're.
Most welcome.
Let's go ahead guys then
might start a solution
to I'm going to write
wave driver driver first
because I'm going to use my
it's out in this application.
So instead of writing this complete
data, I'm going to copy
some of the information
from my log, in part
from my business.
Yet first,
I'm going to copy this before method by
then I will copy
two point
this part also
and then after method also
by now here, here
I want to put a multiple assumption
intentionally.
I'm going to put multiple assertion here.
Yesterday
we had one log in class eight logging test
that I have copied this code from.
Again, somebody please post this code
from log in, test in the break.
Thank you, Jamal.
Thank you.
Now I want to use my soft assertion
right here in my actual validation.
Right.
So couple of validation and verification
checkpoints intentionally
I'm going to make here.
Some of them will fail.
Some of them we will pass. Right.
And then we'll see how it works.
Let's see this.
So first thing I'm going to write here
in the validation of
validate log in right before
even writing this username and password,
I'm going to write my validation of title
inside this same test.
Guess I'm breaking
the human resource management system.
Right?
You'll see this as the title
for like,
can you see this human management system
right?
Intentionally.
I have written here
the Human Resource Management system.
Now I'm writing
new string
Driver, not dictating
what I'm going to write like this
because I know it will fail, right?
We know it will fail.
So I'm going to write it.
My software start
as let's use thought this time
as equals to new start the start by
soft or dark
assert equals
actual common python
expected write
this code for sure will fail right.
Nice.
I know.
But still before
after verification of title.
What I want
I want to execute my log input.
All right.
So inside my log input,
let me put some more
verification checkpoint right here.
I'm going to write
this.
Welcome.
The good part. Right.
So I'm going to write it.
Let me remove this
soft door.
Assert to
let me write, assert
false
welcome attribute dark is displayed.
I'm expecting false.
If it is returning true from here
it means again my verification thing
right This second assertion
I'm going to put here.
Let's take the third assertion.
I'm going to write one string
my strings is
things is wants to
welcome attribute,
whatever that text is available there.
I'm going to copy this text. Right.
And I think the string
expected fixed.
So let's say
welcome attachment should be there.
Right on. Welcome text.
Welcome admin should be there.
I'm writing simply me
or let me.
I'm going to write
welcome item one two, three.
Again, I'm going to write soft
Start.
Start equals
my text and my
expected text.
All in all, how many test cases,
how many assertions
they three assertions, right.
But all of them three are going to fail.
It is for sure.
Correct.
Okay, fine.
Now, the last district.
My I'm going to write here one thing
in my statement
of all the assertion,
then what should be
the last statement of this part?
Which meant that I should consider
a third point.
I'm going to call this assert all with it.
Now, see,
I'm verifying my title,
even if my title is there
or it is something else,
it means my best guess.
This fine is still I want this script
to perform logging operation.
It is performing logging operation.
Then it is verifying
it is with defined my text.
First it will check the display.
Find if this place did.
That is fine. Or let me put
this point
before the assertion part here.
After this two assertions
I'm going to expect
and then I'm going to take the value,
even if all the verification
and validation check points are fail,
I want my results.
I got to write.
You want this one?
I just wrote it as a text on
you said this
one should be the actual one.
The first one.
All right.
Got it.
You want this, right?
Correct.
Okay, fine.
Now, if you see here, I have three, right?
I have three assertion points.
This is my precondition
so I don't need to mention
my precondition will definitely execute
my post condition will also execute
my test gives will also execute.
But I want this complete test
to be executed.
Right. So let's execute this fight now
and you
see performance log in operation.
This is paid right.
Notice we intentionally made our test fee,
but it says my statement
after all the assertion.
So it is my statement.
This is my statement.
It means my entire code got executed
right now here, if you see it says
Click to see difference, click here.
The first one is Human
Resource Management System,
but phone human management system
guys.
Second thing, welcome admin expected.
But what we got
we got welcome coming to me.
Yes, yes, yes. Correct. Correct.
We use this and didn't
unless the checkpoint verification
and validation check is a strict
we will use this one
then the expected was false
but found true. Why?
Because I was expecting this message,
this welcome attribute.
It should not be displayed,
but actually it was displayed.
That's why condition was false.
So my assertion got to clear
three assertions.
I put all three things, but still my code
word executed and I got consolidated
report because of this solve for dot
assert all method
right days
so far
in this session,
do you guys have any question?
I hope you are understanding
the things slowly gradually
we're increasing rate
we are increasing over other topics.
We are increasing over
the advanced features of testing.
All right.
Shall we proceed further now
or you guys are still writing the code
up to 15 minutes.
Maybe. All right.
And please
write this right after 15 minutes.
There definitely is definitely
show.
Go ahead, just click
or there is a link, right?
It says, I don't totally understand on it,
but just one more topic, please.
One more topic and then break.
Would that be okay?
I know, I know.
Recharge is needed.
I'll give you a special access
from my side for sure
whenever I come to you, as
I'll give you that.
Great.
You didn't put that code here.
Give me if there is no option. Right.
You'll see.
You'll find these differences
in blue and be great in.
The console itself,
you'll find that difference
great.
It's a deal being done.
You can have my words
even on a blank paper
along with my signature. Correct.
That's what index four saying.
That's what I'm saying.
It's in the console.
If there is no facility to see, click
the difference.
Right, You will, you will find it.
Then it said the same happened with bird
you the same happened.
Just saw me as well. Right.
So you you will find this information
in your console itself.
You don't need to click or to see the
maybe the different but just something to
I'm not sure but he is
that's what I'm saying.
Mike might be there
different convergence of data idea
but at least we are able
to get the information.
Everyone is able to get
the same information right.
You are able to kill
and see the differences.
Doesn't matter whether it is in console
or your extending your console
well clicking on the link.
Got it.
So this is the one I'm talking about
quite. Now.
Let's
proceed further towards the next topic
right after soft session.
Let me let me ask 11.
here before proceed further.
Let me ask one point to get advice.
Tell me
let's see.
Yeah, definitely.
We are a family,
Mike.
So your one best guess for example,
your village log.
In your village log, it is depending
on another test guess rate.
For example,
you have to enter username and password
you have to introduce and or for example,
let me give you one very basic example.
You want to verify the dashboard, right?
So to verify that dashboard
in this human resource or each application
you need log in or not
of this the unit log in.
Correct.
Without log in, can someone verify this?
Our dashboard page?
No, it means we can see that my dashboard
verification page test case
is highly depending on my log in.
Correct.
Or it is completely depending
on my log in gaskets.
Right.
So now what testing do you see is here
is the indices.
Students I know your requirements.
If you have any requirement like this,
when you have two test cases
and your one best guess
is rely on any other test.
Guess what I do is I will execute
the dependent test gets later,
but first I will execute the test.
Guess you are depending
on which test this.
It means your dependent test
case will execute later.
But the test
guess you're relying on will execute
first work test and you
getting my point.
I'll give you one example here.
Let me right
on let me this
writing depends on active group.
Right.
I have written two methods I'm going
to write to maturity and public void.
Let's say mine
log in method.
So I'm going to write
This is my
log in my
the another one
I'm going to write that exist
public void
verify
dashboard page.
This is my dashboard page
before you know default
not not on any default here
to see what I'm going to do
my this particular verified dashboard page
method is depending on my log
in or not pay me.
Is this correct?
Now, let me do one thing
here.
I'm going to write.
Depends on methods
it is asking depends on methods.
The moment
it asks the difference on method.
What I will write, I will write here.
No, what I will do,
I will write.
Log in now.
Now, when I try to execute this particular
method, what it will do,
it will first execute the previous method
that is the log in method very,
very light and then it will execute.
Depends on method.
Correct? Correct.
Right. Yes.
So when I'm writing here, log in.
This log in is nothing
but the name of my method
or the method where I am,
which I am relying on.
Right.
So my verify days
work pages relying on log in method.
So I wrote depends on methods
which method log in method fine
and I simply execute this particular one.
Now let me write one more thing.
I'm writing a static test public void
verify log out.
I am writing this out
and then this is my out
page.
Find my log in now my verified log pages.
Also, depending on what method,
which method it is, depending on it
is depending on
a verified dashboard page right now.
See what happens now.
See what happened.
See, I'm going to execute very fine.
I'll go
there.
What I'm thinking, what happens? I'm
depending on method public one
depends on attribute
fine log in method
which is associated with this
are not included.
Maybe some a spelling mistake or what.
I'm not getting it now.
This should work.
Yeah, this should work.
That's what I'm saying.
Or even I'm not getting this.
This is the method name
I copied and pasted here.
Right?
This kind of thinking is fine.
Difference on method is also fine,
but the point is also point.
This one is perfect on this one.
One Line 18. What happened online dating
my very excited of
this one.
You are seeing great
in this case right?
This one you're talking about.
Got it.
Got it worked fine.
Let me run this very fine.
I'll go. Okay. Right.
Let's check there
yet. This should work without that also.
But I'm just trying to check why
it is not working.
I don't think it will.
I don't see it will work. Right?
It says test password again.
It is giving me this option.
I'm not sure.
Why is it working in your working one
the same code?
Right. Because they should work.
I'm not sure why it is not working. Fine.
Let me show you this also from here,
because what happens basically
not that is fine.
That is fine when we use this,
when we have multiple operations
to pass, for example, here
I'm using this part and this part.
And then with comma, I'm going to use
verified dashboard.
It means on all methods. It is depending
if I'm writing this one like this,
then got to liberate this.
I need if I'm writing just a single one,
then I don't need to leave this. This
now see?
Right, exactly.
Exactly. Now,
if you'll see here it is working fine.
Right? My this method verified. Fine.
Now go to method is depending on log in
and verified dashboard.
So I don't need to execute all these
three methods or this entire class.
What I need to do is basically
I need to simply call this particular
method and it will execute my remaining
two method as well.
Right.
So if you see here what I executed,
I executed this defined logos method,
but then it executed first login,
then it executed my dashboard.
Know if you'll see here
I just run if I logo
see the same method.
Right.
It is working correctly. Fine.
Yeah, kind of.
But here what you're seeing my complete
my this verify log out
method is depending on the print
on verified dashboard.
That one is depending on my login.
So when I execute my verify
it now go to method first it should log,
it should perform and execute my login.
Then it should execute
my verified dashboard
and then it should execute my verified
No go to method.
Write more test.
And this is here when I'm writing.
This depends on methods.
Execute in verify logo.
So this verified now go to
method will be executed in the last days.
Verify no go to
method is relying on some else method
and those some else's methods will execute
first in my first and you clear now
right.
Is it clear?
It is working fine when I execute
some on verified logo portion.
Can you see this?
This is not inheritance because we are not
inheriting the property right.
We are just saying
that we are relying on that method.
So just go ahead and execute
that method First.
Inheritance means inheriting the property
right of the class.
Yeah. And then I know that.
So now, guys,
we are done with all the attributes.
Write something very interesting.
We are going to learn after the break.
I know you guys need to break it all.
So guys, how much time you need?
It's 9293 almost year.
How much time you.
Fine.
All right, so I'm putting it here.
Break for 20 minutes, three days.
You can have a break for 20 minutes.
Now I'm going to
write.
So now, so far
we have these two different packages,
three
package, one package two
while good deal.
Seriously, if you look at this package,
these two packages
having different classes, getting
in this two different classes,
if I want to execute
this particular class,
I'm not talking about priority enable
disable
all these things that we are doing
inside the class, inside the class.
But still, if I want to execute any class,
what I have to do,
I have to go in that class
and then I have to execute
the segregation level.
BE every should tell is only the level
we are writing precondition
post condition inside the class.
We are writing before test
after test inside the class
we are writing multiple test
which is also inside the class.
But still, if I want to execute something,
I have to execute my entire class first
or not. Again,
right click and execute to my class.
This is what we are doing.
Correct.
Now, if
I want to execute all these three classes
depends on attribute stock decision
one associate to.
If I want to execute
all these three classes, what I should do,
I should click on depends on attribute.
First I will execute it.
Forget about those configurations
which we have inside the class.
I'm not talking about those right now.
If I want to execute soft assertion one,
what I will do, I will right
click here and I will execute similarly
for self decision two as well.
I have to right click and execute
whether it is method or it is all the test
or it is a simple class,
then what is the point of using test?
And earlier we had committed it.
Now we will not execute anything from one
class, right?
We can execute all these classes
from one place.
What is that place?
That's what we need to understand now.
Okay, I need one point.
I need one execution point.
Make me open my sketch
point.
What I need here.
I need one execution point.
Right
Now, when I see the execution point,
what it means,
it simply means
I want to execute all of my classes,
all of my test from one place
so that I can execute
all of this things
in a single click, correct.
That's what I need to do.
So I looking forward
to get that particular part.
Okay, Now let me go
on this execution point
by here.
I need
one point where I can
I can execute
all of my
classes,
methods, everything I can do
from one execution point.
That's what I'm looking for, Right?
So to do this point,
see the classes, methods, etc., right.
I can execute all my classes.
I'm not writing class all the classes.
It means A, B, C from multiple packages.
I have
depend on group maybe.
No SRI no no. Depend on group.
All the methods also available again
depends on group
is what I can segregate
all those methods depending on group.
Right.
But again, when it comes to classes,
I have my classes.
I don't want to do it.
I want to execute all of my classes,
which is aiming
all of these methods and other stuff
right from one point that is execution
point 94, that For that
we need one fight which file we need.
Let me right here.
We need
test and jee dart exam will fight.
Let me go ahead and open my notes first
sessions we are done part of sessions.
Talk also fight
after the session.
This is the test
case. Right? I will give you as our task
now depends on done.
This is the part
I want to execute.
All of my classes,
all of my methods, all the functions
from one particular fight.
We need this test and DART
will file first
and then we'll go into detail.
Right.
The first thing is
how we can get this fight in our project.
So let me open up project.
This is our project.
It goes
now. So get this fight guys are.
You listening to me?
Everyone?
Alright?
Please pay your complete attention
for the next 5 minutes.
This 5 minutes are very crucial.
How we can create this test
in a single fight.
All right, See,
Click on file,
project structure, Click on Fight.
I'm on.
Click on file.
Project structure.
Right.
I'll do one thing.
What is not.
Thank you, Jose.
Do one thing.
Simply write people
who are not able to find from there
just to go and click on this search icon.
Right.
Let me just keep it down for now.
Click here on Search Icon.
I'm giving you the shortcut from there.
Also, I will give you that option right
here, just right.
Plug in what you need to write
this plug ins
start
I'm giving you click on search option.
Go here and write plug ins
is getting it
What I'm doing.
Simply click on plug ins.
It will open your plug in here.
Right it open your plug in.
Shortcut.
Another way to do this is click on file.
Click on by going to settings,
going to plug ins,
you'll see again you are coming on
the same screen, right click on file,
go into settings, and inside the settings
you will find this plug in.
That is correct.
Now go on to the market place,
go into the market marketplace and right
create
the moment you read, create
it will, give you create this symbol
because it is already
installed in my machine.
It is saying it is installed for you.
It will give you it will give you a green
icon like this full install.
Simply you need to install and click.
Okay,
great.
Simply you need to click install
and simply click okay.
Make sure when you install
it should give you this option.
Disable for all project and install
because it is already enabled.
Right? So you have to enable it.
It should be enabled.
You got it.
What you need to do Click on file
going to settings.
Inside settings.
You'll find this plug in here, right?
Create this and you will right the moment
snake span because of chain is correct.
That's fine. That's fine.
One of three
on this planet,
one of the three things is Chinese, right?
So that is one of the three things
this guy is
doing
the mic, which I'm using Chinese
the speaker I'm using Chinese, the mouse.
I am using Chinese.
Yeah, except you didn't find what got
what was there
disable option again up
how intimately you are getting this
this settings option
this option you are not
you're not able to see then you will
you must be to see that option
it just as installed right.
So installed is fine.
If it is installed it is fine.
It means you have installed it right?
Correct. Correct. Installed.
Yes. Are you sure?
See here, have to click
next four times and click on file.
Click on settings.
Go into the plugins
after going into the plug ins
just right here, create test and examine.
Okay.
If it is not installed, select the
checkbox, go there and you will install it
or it will give you the option
Green tab for installation right
to install it.
Everyone done.
That is fine.
It says installed so it is.
Can you go into the install tab?
Can you go into the inside your device?
Now you're showing me on marketplace
rates.
Can you go into to the installed tab
in the installer right there.
You will get this option.
See I'm showing you here file
settings.
This tab
you are right now on this tab marketplace.
Right.
You should go here on the install tab.
There you will see all of the installed
plugin available.
Right.
And then you will be able to select
one of them.
Now getting option
folders.
Do you
want me to close in, open everything
all right, Jose?
So now all good with the installation part
everyone now
are getting all
about other students
getting Jose Garrett
just one showed him nobody's up.
If you're not getting the settings
button here, no issues.
The another way is
see, just click on this search icon here.
You must be getting this icon.
Click here and right plug ins,
press enter and you will be on the street.
Once you go on there, just be there.
You will go to text Marketplace
and install.
When you click on installed,
you will see this artist
and do not accessible
getting it, but do
okay by
already
got it done now
fine shows that I think it's done.
Imam techniques minutes Imam are you ready
then let's proceed further guys that
right click on your project that we want
right click
after right click
go below you will see this option
create this Then you got submitted.
How many of you guys
can see this option now?
Create custom one,
click on it.
It is asking this hi process.
It is I click okay, click on it
click okay.
Then.
All right. All right. Click here.
Go below.
The last option is
the existing Duratex image.
Now, after doing this,
what is the next thing
you guys have to do?
Right. Click it, refresh your project.
It says reload from this point.
The moment you reload it from this,
you'll see
one magic test
and you detect similar failures. It.
Then you see
open this file
is right click project
and then you get this option
reload from desc, right.
Just click on reload from this
and then you will be able to see this test
and do detect symbols
by here on the below site.
But it everyone then
thank you It is.
Let's go ahead, guys.
Now in this file people who are Mac users
right first toward windows user
just type control I l
rate control
i l c it is for automatic
can you see control or and for mac users
command option L
for mac users option come on and
and then it will be permitted
in this option
then everyone
you need to reload your project
note as I am.
It is different for
if this testing do not simplify it.
You'll see here this is just do not.
Yes, I'm writing here. I'm writing this.
Come on
in the check I am putting this
control plus
I plus.
And this is for windows.
Yes, that's right.
Yes, they will read it. Don't worry.
They will see.
Now what I would say
similarity from the quote.
Don't worry about it. First,
let's take everyone on this page.
There is all the this.
But what is the issue?
Did you install the plugin? Sure, sure.
Right click on the project.
Go onto the bottom side.
You will get this option
create test in the exhibit.
Are you getting this option?
Yes. Corexit.
Corexit. Why?
It is not showing for this
reloaded the project, not getting the test
and do not exhibit.
There must be some issue then
with your installation part
you need to check on the installation part
because remaining all of you guys
got a great idea.
But it now your issues also resolve
this post your query in the tech support
rate.
I think more some is there
and he must be able to help with there
work on say I did all the steps
but I don't see it simplified
okay for me
as I also got a great knowledge
also got it and now it's about ignored
also.
So just stop
or make this correct.
Fine.
You just need to check
in the same support.
Right?
Then you can get this quick.
Now let me give you
just double set here.
One funny part.
What is that See,
everyone is using in the industry
this testing great,
very famous tool, widely accepted
unknown tool, right.
Still
if you'll see they have haven't added you
can you see one bug
this filling of create is not correct
this right and I've been
seeing this from last two two
and a half years.
Last two and a half years
I've been seeing this.
They're not they're
not ready to accept their this is the bug
static.
They are not accepting this bug.
They keep sending as the new build,
but still they are not making it fixed.
They're not fixing it.
Well, one of my colleagues,
the same thing emailed to them.
They never replied back.
He took that initiative
and even if they reply,
they will reply in Chinese,
which we won't be able to understand.
Right?
So there is no point
of explanation of that.
All right, let's get active.
Like getting
game, shall we?
Proceed for that.
Everyone got this by now.
Everyone is having this file.
Wait, let's do it
first.
Let me to do this to a shorter part
by now, you'll see.
My one class I'm taking
there is depends on attribute.
Right.
Let me open it.
This is my class.
It depends on.
I think you
all let me take any another class
of I'm taking my session class.
This class Lucy talk assertion one year
I'm going to write.
No, you don't need to do anything.
They right now just look at this.
Just look at this here. Right?
You don't need to write anything, okay?
I'm doing it for you.
I'm just trying to explain.
Couple of points. Yes, right.
So just don't do anything.
You will understand everything.
You will get this code in your repository.
Don't. Guys, don't do anything.
Yeah, No, no, I know.
What is the meaning of this?
I will reply in Japanese.
No, see,
I have written one more test
inside this right
in soft assertion class.
Now I'm going here and I'm writing
my thought solution.
One is taking
which method I want.
So let's see.
I am going to write my first method
that is
another method.
And the second method is
soft assertion validation.
Now look at this structure days.
Look at this structure.
We are having tests which are opening
and closing, opening and closing.
Let me to my website,
my application, right click
going to the inspect.
This is the code
you see here right in this record.
It starts with this head, then body,
and then they put every single tag
which we are opening here.
If you go below side, you'll see we are
closing with this statement slash body.
We started with head and body
extremely will it,
but we don't have slash yet.
Why we use Slash to close this bag. Right.
This is my demon code that
now go
into my test and do not assemble fight
You'll see when I'm writing this.
So opening this.
I am closing it inside this I have test,
I am closing this, inside this.
I have classes.
I am closing this. Inside this.
I have class.
I'm closing this inside this.
I have methods.
I am closing it.
Fine. What it says.
What does it mean?
It simply means
you don't have to do anything.
No priority, No, no.
Enable, disable nothing.
You don't have to do anything
in your classes.
Every single customization,
every single customization
you can perform from test
and do not exhibit fight.
For example,
you want to execute just one class,
which class soft associate
class claim you can execute from test
and do not accessible.
Now you say don't want to execute
soft assertion validation method.
I want to execute
just another method inside one class.
I have all methods to test cases.
I want to execute one.
I don't want to execute another one.
To do that, you have one flexibility,
one feature in your class itself.
Which feature is there
enable is equal to true.
Enable is equal to false.
What I say
we don't have to do anything in our class.
Whatever the things,
whatever the customization we need to do,
we need to do that
customization in our test
to do fight
so it can be included, exclude methods.
It says, Yes,
you can do that. How we can do that?
Let me show you.
You just put in name one
and then exclude another one.
Now It will execute only one method
for this class.
Right?
Let me run my test and do not see.
I have run my test
and do not take symbol file exist estimate
because my another method
has this method message.
Estimate how many tests it has executed
just one
by just the one because I include one
and I exclude one here.
I don't have any dependency.
I have nothing to do with my class.
I implemented myself. The session class.
I'm not going to use that class
for customization.
I am using my big bonus.
This thing I'm using.
This is the engine of your test engine.
Remember? Right.
You can do in number of customization.
Trump You
getting my point?
Everyone
so far?
Is it clear?
Is it difficult to understand? Yes.
You don't need to write anything here.
You don't need to write anything.
See, let's do it.
You want to execute all the methods
of your software solution class, right?
Definitely.
Let's say you have this class, the
the dart syntax.
Dart Class two.
This is your foxy dart
syntax dart class to
inside this package
you have solved a solution.
One This is after solution
one your class name.
That's why I put class
name is equal to this
right?
That's what I'm saying, Mark. Right.
That's what I am saying.
We need to write it.
We need to write the name of the class.
Fine.
We need to shorten it.
We need to reduce it.
We need to customize it
according to our requirements.
We can do that, right?
We can delete all of that, guys.
We can delete all of the class name
and whatever the class name
I want to keep,
I can keep only those class name.
That's what I'm saying.
Okay,
earlier on, if you remember,
I had the same I had the same
kind of structure right of this
to do not simplified what I did.
I deleted all those class
names and I put this one
self isolation one
right this one from here.
So definitely what you need to do
basically is let's say
you must be having class name like this.
See this tab class name right.
You must be having these days
this and this.
Right.
Like this you will be having all of this
class name like this, right?
Correct.
Everyone.
So what you do
just keep one class name for now.
Class two class guys. See?
Make sure this takes
what must be working after classes.
There will be class.
So class is start and class closing take.
Right after that, all the class is
starting, class closing text
In this last class
just remove them form Now
just keep one class because I'm
taking the example of one class.
Right. Okay. So that Mark Elizabeth
it now everyone is on same page,
I believe.
Right with me.
Right. I again, I'm repeating again.
I'm repeating only not Elizabeth Marx,
but everyone, please
focus on the explanation.
I will commit this code in the repository
you will get.
They demand every single line of code
will be available in the depository.
Don't worry about it. Okay?
Just focus on the concept.
If you learn the concept,
you can play with this fight.
I'm teaching you
how to play with this configuration.
Right? This is configuration file.
We need to learn
how we can configure the things.
Let's proceed for this.
One more thing, guys. Let's see.
In this particular class session, one
class, I want to execute my board methods.
I want to execute all of my methods
and methods.
Then I don't need
to parse this method. You
simply I will write to my class.
And that's it.
That's it.
The moment I write my class name.
Here it is more than okay.
I don't need to do anything in that case.
I don't need to do anything in that case,
because it will,
by default, execute all of my methods
of this particular class.
So now if I execute my test
and do not take symbol file,
tell me how many tests it will execute
to test this.
It will execute. Right?
Because I'm not excluding any method.
I'm not including any methods by default
it is giving me right C
one and one to select
one field one plus why it is failed
because we were using softer solution
and there we had some fail associates.
Right? Intentional.
But you'll see the numbers two
if you go below
you will see totally test run this time.
Correct
either correctness
right now let's proceed further.
Whatever the things we committed
now we are going to know,
don't every single thing First thing
I was telling you
know of,
we have to test this
right in the assertion C one is this test
another method and one is
this test
to solve the solution validation.
So so when I'm trying to execute
both this right, I'm simply my class name.
I, I'm not mentioning to include this
method or to exclude this method.
I'm not doing anything like that. It
all right now,
whatever the things we are doing here,
we are doing
only on one class, right?
It's still the combination
of multiple classes.
We thought we should see them in similar
file as, but you're talking about methods.
So methods we we can see, right?
We can see the methods.
If we need to include some methods,
we need to exclude some methods.
I just give you an example
guys doing I give you that example
where we have included
some method excluded some method.
Do you want me to repeat that part
once again, guys?
once again?
So including exclude part of methods?
Sure.
Why not
see inside this class?
Inside this class. Right.
I'm going to write my method.
So here you'll see.
These are my methods.
I'm writing here.
Methods I'm going to write.
Let's say I want to
execute both these methods.
These are the two methods.
So if we want to customize our classes
based on our test,
then we have the option
include including got.
So inside my class.
You need to understand
one thing here before understanding this,
you need to understand
one thing like this for you.
Remember in one project.
In one project, right?
You have
multiple packages, right?
This in one package.
In one package we have multiple classes,
correct.
In one class,
we have multiple methods.
Is it correct or not?
They said
so now.
Now, while understanding this part
does the implementation we will be having,
in our case candidate X symbol file
how you will be having complete
thought
and you can consider it as a project.
Inside this you are having test.
Just forget about testing.
So I will explain this later.
Inside this you will be having package
or multiple inside
this you will be having classes inside
this, you will be having methods.
Correct.
So one class can in multiple metrics,
one package can in multiple classes,
one based can in multiple packages,
one sort can have multiple test.
Is it clear now
if you come here, you'll see
inside classes there is a class
that you can use inside of.
So there is a test.
Let me show you
this complete hierarchy. Here
it is
inside.
So that is our test.
Inside test.
There are multiple classes
inside the classes.
There are class inside.
The class, they're automatic, correct?
They are meaning they are linked.
These methods belong to this class, right?
Right. Based.
So I'm dealing with just one class
right now.
Obviously,
so many things are coming forward.
Currently, we are discussing how to play
with one class in multiple methods
available inside that class.
That's what we are learning.
So if I want to include all the methods
which I'm having inside one class
for execution
by default, identical mentioned
because if I'm just mentioning the class
name, it will execute all of my methods.
If I need to include some of the methods
that need to include,
exclude some of the methods, then
I have to use this pragmatics inside this.
Let's say
I want to include another method.
So this is include.
I to exclude this method
so I can right exclude this method.
Simple correct
categories.
So now this time.
This time
it will execute my sort of session
one class and then it will execute
to my another method
and it will not execute my soft assertion
validation method.
Now clear to everyone.
Great.
So should I do this right?
Let's say
I want to execute my one complete class.
Right?
But I'm thinking one thing here
I am thinking you're most welcome.
I'm thinking one thing
up. You're using windows
or you're using this Mac machine.
Oxana
If you're using windows, then control Z.
If you're after deleting Windows,
after deleting or control
Z, simple controls the control Z,
you will get that.
Fine.
Now I can see one thing.
I want to execute multiple classes.
I don't want to think of just one class.
Okay, so let's try that.
Also, what I'm going to do is right,
I'm going to execute another class.
So let me take one more class.
I'm going to create one more class.
This class would be my
first class, right?
Simple name.
I'm giving my best class yet
in my package, the beach package.
And talking about right
now, see Dawson text Art Class two.
Right.
This is my package.
So I'm going write, enter
a dist annotation.
Then my normal method.
I'm going to write
this method here.
Fine.
This is my method.
And then again
I'm going to write another method
as it is
public void,
another test method.
This is my another test.
Correct.
This is my class.
Now I want to execute my soft assertion.
One class and my test class.
Guys, these two classes
I want to execute together.
Omnia.
We didn't have any option
to execute two classes together.
Now what test and acceptances?
Go ahead,
write this name
here, Change the class name.
So what is the class name?
It says test class.
For this fixed class you need to write
correct. And
now? Now C
by default, by default.
Here if you open. I have no method here.
If I open this, I have to test here
to test and to test how many tests
in total
correctly,
how many testing total for test,
How many classes in total
two classes.
Correct.
Let me go ahead and Nancy
and test in your text.
Well, I will right click here
and I'm just see,
there's no
I'm not changing anything in my
this class is in sort of section
one and this class. Right.
I'm not doing anything
inside of my classes.
How many test cases executed
today's test fail the one positively.
The total test.
How much?
Run for it?
Is it correct?
I hope you are understanding
what I'm doing here.
Now let's do another customization.
I said inside of my class.
I'm going to write metrics.
Fine.
This is the method thing
I'm going to write.
So I'm going to write
include
when a name is equals to
inside myself.
The solution.
My method name is
another method, correct?
So I'm seeing
in my two classes I have four methods.
In my two classes
I have how many methods for method.
It means total for test.
I don't want to execute all four.
I to execute just two one
from test
class, one from the solution, one class.
Right.
In my two classes I have four out of this.
Four I want to exclude two,
I want to include two.
So for exclusion,
I don't need to mention for inclusion.
I need to mention it means the ones
who are not in inclusion by default
they are in exclusion.
Correct.
Now, if I,
if I execute this particular test
and you don't take someone by now,
see what happens, fine.
Can you see that just to test executed.
Correct.
This is the
we can do.
All right.
When do you have to create a new symbol?
Fine. Up for the customization order.
For each customization,
you don't need to basically write
as long as you are
done with one file. Right?
It should be okay.
In my opinion.
Correct.
Now let's proceed further.
Let's try to learn
so many new things in this set.
In this test entered our next middle class
is still we are not done this one class.
All right?
We have to do so many things here
right now after this.
After this.
The most important part, right?
The one you asked right now.
Yeah, right. 2 hours will be gone.
Don't worry about 2 hours will be gone,
believe me
again.
Let's try to do the same activity, guys.
Let's try to do the same activities,
which I do it
right.
Click on your project.
Do it with me if you wish to.
Otherwise, just look at how you create
standard or take symbol,
click okay.
Right click on your project.
Click on Create Distance.
You click okay
and then again, reload your project from
now, again, right control point.
And can you see my previous
my previous part was gone.
It was gone.
It's not here anymore. Right?
New configuration.
I got my point.
That is, did you get what I did here?
It created a new test and do not simplify
what happened.
So got to correct the new test
and you take similar file over
then the previous one by
because the name is seen,
the name you see right now what
we have to do in in this case, basically
point blank,
this is my previous file, correct.
If I want to create a new file,
I have to make sure that this symbol
should be the unique name.
So before doing that, what I'm going to do
is I'm going to rename this
standard or symbol file.
So I'm saying, here is
this in one dot, right?
I'm going to do a factory test.
And you are correct.
I just rename it.
Now let's do one thing.
I'm going to create another test
and do not file Trump Yet, despite.
Okay, right click the note from this
find.
If you see this,
then do not accept any new file over here.
This is my new test
and you detect something
correct.
Just go to the issue of ordered.
So now we'll be having to test
and you will find here, correct?
Correct.
Exactly.
Let me do one more thing.
Let me bring in this file.
Also defective rename and I'm writing this
to you to protect similar to this one.
And this time I'm going to create
not from my project
not from my project,
but from my package, right click
create test.
And you're not assembly click.
Okay, reload.
From this,
you'll see that third test and you're not
this time.
If you'll see this time.
If you see it comes only with the classes
which are available in this package.
Only there is no other class from package
one, the class one package.
All the classes are from only class
two package.
Why is it so?
Because this time I have created my test
and do not take well from package
new thing observed or not
correct.
My package name is start class two.
Yes and earlier I was creating the test
engendered excel file from my project.
Right. So. Right. Exactly.
So this time let's say I have 1000 classes
in my one package
and 1000 classes in second package.
If I needed my test
and do not take from project,
I will be having this two classes
inside my one test and do not examine.
Fine.
Then it will be very difficult for me
to identify
those 1000
here, 1000 there and still do what can do.
I can simply go in my project.
I will right click on my project
and create new test in your taxable file.
So in that case, I would be aiming
only those 1000 classes
which are available inside my package.
Correct.
Understanding my point
is they shouldn't go in boring now.
Or is it
okay?
Okay.
Mykes as it is going boarding now.
All right.
Because list number of jokes that are to
the decision because their topic is very
their topic is it?
You know what I would say import.
That's why.
Fine.
Let's proceed for the next for further.
I'm seeing one more problem.
Great.
Getting correct.
So now see, one more thing.
Let's say
in my up for method level for class level
and then of multiple classes
inside one to standard or text.
Well these the things
we are done with correct
you know how to include it
exclude metrics right
you know how to include in exclude classes
also right
correct or not based on
super.
No. I also one thing
that in my one
package I'm working on 17 project.
So in my one package, in my single
package, I'm having a lot of classes
5.600, 700 classes.
I want to execute all of them.
What do you expect?
Should I write
all those 500, 600 classmates
or should it eight include this class?
Exclude class one and to discuss
not simple.
I want to execute all of those.
All of those classes right inside
one package.
Let's say I have
how many classes? 500. 600.
I want to execute all of them.
What is the best way to do it?
Let me show you this.
Correct.
Classes deleted.
I don't want any class.
I'm going to write packages
inside the packages which package
you need, which package you need.
So I said my package will see a dot
syntax Dark Class two.
This is my package. Correct.
You send not only this package,
I need one more package.
I said, okay, fine. Big package.
So you will see my package would be C dot
syntax. Dot
block one point
right now, whatever
the classes, whatever the classes
I have inside these two packages,
it will execute all of those classes
inside one class.
If I have multiple methods, it
will execute all of those metrics correct.
So now this is the whole scope of this
thing inside one package of 500 classes.
No, what is just the one
line will execute all 500 classes
or 2000 methods
you have inside those 500 classes.
These two lines of code
will execute your two packages.
That is having 1000 classes,
having 3000 methods inside them.
Every single thing will be executed
just by including the package name here.
Clear.
Let me show it right.
Let me try to run
just one package from see, this time
I'm going to execute this package,
this test and do not single file.
I'm going to execute
method based execution vaccine class phase
execution.
Vaccine package is execution.
Now we see
the good one. Mike
Right, guys.
See now here, if I go
if I go and I see, I test switch.
Totally test.
How much?
See, let me close it first.
Let me show you the other. You'll see.
Let me close this also
depends on attribute depends on attribute
soft assertion
one soft assertion one soft assertion
to softer session to best class
first class
all four classes from package to eight
executed inside these four classes
How many test it?
What executed c do I have yet
right and then for what I have yet
to add it
and how many ideas
right total eight
then.
All right did this executed just one
that is verified logo.
Right.
It is equal to two in one three
after three.
It executed just three
and then it executed this
to how many total eight test cases.
It got executed. The details are here.
Valid log in.
It executed right.
Another method in soft assertion
validation
it executed and log in verified
based voted executing.
You'll see all of this method name.
Also whatever the things I mentioned,
he had it executed here you'll see.
Right.
Total test run eight Bostic years two.
This is your consolidated report
you got from here of the one package.
Now tell me one thing.
If I want to execute all of the classes
I have throughout my project.
What should I do?
All the classes I have inside my project
what should I do in that case?
Simple.
Just to mention all the package name.
No, not project simple.
Just write all the package name.
Correct.
You guys are having
very good impression of this 20.
You think that's ten?
He can do anything.
Okay. Getting my point
this here instead of classical,
you can write class one
and then it will execute
all of the classes from package one.
Right?
If you write for both the package syntax
or class and start, where did you clear
the symbol for package?
Just right click on the package.
Let's
right
click on the package and create, test
and do not accessible from the package
books. Enter.
You said not really for what?
Not understood
for the entire project.
You mean?
Yes. Black Correct? Yes.
It is a best practice to change it.
We will.
I will show you that also.
Don't worry about it.
I will show you that
we do that for sure.
For the project.
No, just one simplified.
It includes all the packages
name in there.
So we generally execute all right,
so this is the least we can do, right?
But yes, there are some more configuration
which we can make here
in order to make a life easier.
Okay.
So those configurations
we are going to make now.
Okay. So far,
is it clear to everyone?
So for whatever the things we did, getting
let's go back to the slide
first.
What is the second effort
extended or similar?
It is file there.
Describe configuration of first
and usually using this change of file
we can test available in one or more class
by right.
This didn't do not take civil file
use to pass that and we test for the test
methods that I will look into this
after some time.
This Didn't do not examine file provides
different options
to include packages, classes methods.
In our case,
we are doing all of this things
like it allows us to
configure my people test in a single test
to switch and run them in multi-threaded.
And this is what?
Because parallel testing might be played,
we will see that.
Remember one thing
when we were learning this
before the method after method, I skip
the intentionally to part.
Which part I will
see here is test class based annotations
before class, after class, before method
after method test.
These are class based annotation, right?
If you go here before this week,
before after.
See these are SML based annotations.
Can you see
the difference test
and do not SML based annotations?
Why? I'm saying these are just
some of the best annotations.
Let me show you
right.
One class.
Okay, so I'm going to write here
classes.
This would be my class,
so I'm going to write here.
I just didn't do it last night.
I'm going to use one class, Correct.
This is my class.
Let me open this class.
How many metrics
I have inside of this class based?
Tell me
three methods
that I'm going to write here.
And then I'm going to write then
now, before class
executes, before the execution of class,
after class executes, after the execution,
before method after method, done
right before every test, after every test,
there is
another one called the rate
before
test.
Now see, I'm writing at the rate
before test, right after this.
I have written
this piece of code. Correct.
Now let's go back to our
test and do not take point
here.
When you see this test to take guys
video, see the test today
inside the class.
What I would say to the class,
outside the class
inside one test,
can I have multiple classes?
Can I have two classes
I can have right
when I write this
before test, read after test,
how many times
it will execute when I have two classes.
All right.
If it executes two times,
then what is the difference
in between before class and before test?
Because class will also execute two times
y Because before class
always executes
before execution of the class.
Correct.
Getting my point based these two classes
is a part of single test.
Can you see?
So whatever the condition
you're putting inside before test
it will execute just for one time.
Doesn't matter how many classes you have
after test will
execute just one time
liquidated liquid printing.
First, I'm going to run them
state.
Then I've written that test class, not
for the classmate.
So I have to write here.
This is mine.
In package one.
It is fine
for me.
The one thing.
Yeah, that's fine. That's what I'm doing.
That's what I'm doing.
Don't.
No, I think everything is good.
You got it.
So now if I go on my test and similar,
this would be my test class right now.
If I execute.
See, because we have so many classes,
so even I'm getting confused
where we are writing the code.
That's funny, right?
Can you see it executed? I am before test.
It means this code executed.
Before that I am before test executing.
Correct.
And then I am before class.
Then I am before method.
Then this is another matter.
Latest in the class. Fine.
Then after the method.
Then before my third.
After my third.
Before my third method and after method.
In the end it says estimated right.
I am after class. Why?
I'm after class.
Guys, this is for after class, right?
And then another class execute it
for estimated right?
In the end you'll get this option
which is in the last call time after test.
The last statement is after test.
It means what
your two classes executed together
all methods executed all the classes
executed.
A statements executed before class,
before method before
test, before method
after class, after method extract test.
Everything executed.
But before test executes.
Just before the test
and after test execute.
In the end of the test player,
you'll see this is the last district.
Meantime, after test
and this is the
first statement I am before this
in between this you'll see
these are two classes
executed inside these two classes.
All of this method is executed.
Is it correct?
Now there is a big difference
in between before tested,
before method,
before the method executes, before
every test.
Can you see you can't relate two things
together right before method executes.
Let's say you have 100 test cases.
If you put before test,
then it will execute hundred times.
But if you write before test,
it will execute just one time
and then after hundred executions
it will execute after test.
But before the method executes
hundred time, it after method
to execute from today.
This is the difference.
Getting my point.
Great.
Right so far clear everything everyone
three
okay,
let's proceed to order.
So far so good. Correct.
Everyone.
Why do we have one before
test in one class, another before test
in another class?
We need to verify right that if.
Okay, so this is the it will not work.
Right?
Because test could be only one grade.
It should be.
If you have multiple test.
If you have multiple test,
then you will be having before tested
after test examples that we will discuss
but before tested after test.
If it is just one test, then two values
for one test will not work.
Okay, Got it.
Let's go ahead.
Today's
the next one.
The next one, which I want to show
you here is
is still one day remaining.
One thing is still remaining
before sweating after sleep.
Let's go ahead and implement that.
Also now.
Now I'm going to go ahead and write
again inside my first class.
I'm going to write here.
All right.
Now, I've done this the first week
after switch in, say the one class, Right.
Tell me in this execution,
if I execute again,
my test will write my test.
And you taught me how many.
So you can see here this one.
So how many times my suit executes
one time
it will execute before test on our biggest
before.
Correct.
Now, the idiocy, the scope.
The scope is getting larger.
We discussed with before my method
the scope was just for one test.
Before class, the scope was multiple, test
before test scope was multiple,
class before.
So it is scope of multiple test. Right?
So the scope is getting larger.
Let me execute it
first, then I will show you
the overall idea
is it will work.
It will work.
No issues are done.
I will show you that also subject
right now.
I'm going to show you this
right after that.
What we see now the first week is
I am before this week
and I am before test.
You won't find this a statement
throughout your class and in the last
you will see here
I am after test and I'm off this week
and that is correct or not.
But now if you change
the order of the class, fine position.
Let's see.
Let's do this
and then try to execute.
Does it make any difference?
No difference.
This test class will execute later.
This class will execute first.
Simple, because it is following the
order, correct? Correct.
The scope is getting expanded.
No, you'll see.
Softer section executed for this class
executed second but state before.
So it executed before. Test executed.
Then executed.
Then all of your code
and in the and also after test
and after with executed correct
fine so far
so whatever you want
but I need to learn something new again
if need a one more break and this
you guys need break
of this did that
why confused
I mean, is it difficult to understand
what I'm showing right now?
Okay static
is working fast break
or next topic.
Okay.
So maybe we will see that.
We will see. Next topic.
The same what you're asking.
All right.
We share more. So let's take a break then.
Okay, guys,
10 minutes.
Enough.
All big.
No. Okay, guys, let's take a break.
All right, Just in due to
this one, just double
click on it.
Yes, double click
on an extended or accessible file
and then you'll be able to open next
and you take somebody.
Okay.
No break is not started here.
The guys because they have questions.
So I'm just trying to resolve
their queries.
Correct Word.
You got it.
How did you create noticed in G class
two of you just need to rename it right?
First you have to rename it. That's it.
This just a neurotic symbol.
You have to right
click here, refactor and rename.
And once you do that, create a new test
and you accept and
then you will be able to create
this test indeed to the next level.
File 1.6 Simplified B have renamed them.
That's why they are the new one.
Great. All right, guys. Now break starts
cardigans week.
So before the break, we went to this part.
We went to this bar for test
and you will buy it right then.
We have seen
all the different combinations right now
towards getting more flexibility,
towards getting more flexibility
from this portion.
We have to learn another topic
here. Right.
And what the topic is
we are going to study it now. See,
let's see.
Let me share my screen with you This
you joined an organization, right?
So what is the ideal duration
of constraint If you are working
in district Agile or supported by Agile,
what is the ideal of spring?
No, the ideal duration of the spring
is always two weeks.
Remember, these are always two weeks.
They are.
Now let's say you have already joined one
organization, right?
Which is already stable and they have
the process and every single thing
you have started working right And again
and in the spring, the one next spring,
the one you work on think this gives us
this is the overall your project duration.
Then in spring to
spring your work done it is to get this
in the spring three.
Let's say you are working
on some critical user studies.
Are you logged on
just to fight this disease
and it is trained for
you logged on.
Lesson 11 This gets this.
I'm just giving you random numbers
right on and on.
Eight, 513, 13, 11 2424 compatible
you worked on 34 test cases in your
for is correct
that you have done 34
test cases
in your four different settings.
Now you entered into Sprint five
and you are planning to take
some more courses to execute.
But if you're entering into this doesn't
mean whatever the test
because as you have written in the last
for the spring, you will not execute them.
You have to execute them or not.
This is strengths.
Just to get this,
you have to execute all these 34 right
along with the new test cases
you will be writing in this big five
you have to correct.
You have to execute the remaining test.
This of all the four sprints,
you have to execute
for the spring, 5% is fine.
You are working later in 51.
This thing is sprint 51.
Should I consider that
almost 300 discourses?
You have executed 300 because as you have
written in, you want to sprint in
just 40 sprint
when you have, let's say 34 test cases.
So in 50 sprint you can have 300 test
because is also possible.
Now here maintaining this three
and because this would be difficult of not
can in this three and take this
because this makes it
you have 29
test cases belong to smoke testing
and 301 test because this belongs to your
integration test unless it
complete 330 300 complete test cases
but be a integration out of this
29 belong to smoke.
Is it possible or not possible?
But when you have 300 test cases,
when you have three and it says
don't think it would be very difficult
for you to execute
only a small switch from there.
Isn't it difficult
only in that you 29 test get this
What do you have to do
from our existing setup?
You have to include those test
cases, those 29
and then you have to exclude
remaining 300.
But to include this, remain at this 29
smoke test because this in your framework,
in your code, in your testing,
it is also a
bit test, correct?
Because
it is a big test.
So this
then just says you don't have to mention
not do don't mention this include
or exclude the test
because this institute you can segregate
you can separate all of your test cases
according to your requirements
in multiple groups.
What we can do is we can separate
all of our test cases
in multiple groups, right?
So when I in multiple groups
let me go inside of my any class,
like let's say this is my first class,
I'm going inside now.
See how many kids to get this.
I have you
retest to get this correct.
Now let me remove this before
switching off this week.
I don't need before test after the first
week of this week, otherwise unnecessary.
I would be having so much more before
class after class. Also,
I'm ending before my third day
after method
and three test simple one correct?
Sure.
So I have written this code right in
say new class
just before my third after my third
and three test
before my third.
After my third entry test, I'm going to
define them based on the groupings.
How can we do this?
Groupings Me Show you here.
I'm writing.
Let's see, this is my fourth test, right?
So this is my first test.
This belongs to
group.
Which group it belongs to.
Let's say it is a part of my smoke.
And also it is a part fine.
Let's say
it is a part of my smoke right now.
This one groups.
It is also a part of my smoke.
This one again, groups.
It is a part of my integration.
For example, my one best
guess they connect.
Now I will vote in this one
in soft assumption.
Right. Another class.
And here I would say this one.
I'm writing groups
and it is a part
of my
small fine.
Let me open this one right now.
That is class.
I will go inside of my fist
and do not take symbol, fight it.
And I said, All right, just class.
I have, for example, right now,
I want to execute my test cases.
I want my test
because it's based on groups.
Okay?
Now, it is not restricted in
limited to just one class.
I can write here inside one test
I can write with, say to my test.
Right.
So inside of my test,
what I can write, see if I can write
group
an inside the group I have to write, run
getting this
it says that I'm so what I have to run
it is asking for include
so I'm going to write here
include name.
Let's say I want to execute
only my smoke test cases.
So now if you see when I write this group
inside this class
or let me take another class yet
so my next class
would be my
soft associate
class in my these two classes,
whatever their test gives us,
I have written if those test because
this block, this particular group only
then those test because this will execute.
Right.
So now let me execute
just one class first.
It will give us one error.
Let me show you running.
No, no methods executed in the test class.
This one let me open it.
Why? Oh, okay.
Okay. Got it. Got it, Got it.
I have written the things in grouping
right.
So this is my groupings. One point.
Let me go here and change it to groupings.
Fine.
Now let me execute this part.
I'm going to execute my groupings class.
It got executed. Right?
This is another method. Interesting.
And this is my first method. Correct.
So things now you'll see here
I am going inside this.
I'm going inside this.
Tell me how many test I have
three and how many I've executed.
Test and executed how much
just to Why is it so?
Because my test is this test method
and another method
this to execute
it based on my small group.
Right.
Based on my small group.
This to execute this correct.
But let me open my a soft assertion
to class soft associate to
soft position.
So can you see a soft position right
here?
I'm going to define my groups is equal to
let's it is small
if you do two regression
one is multiple execute two again right
No it will execute then one
because it taking from here.
See it is taking only the small one,
not the regression one.
Correct.
This segregation is done from
this ten do not exit.
So how many test cases
you have the smoked egg
It will execute
only this one getting my point
right.
So now this time
I'm going to take another class.
My soft assumption to
this is minus after session two
and here I have one my third log in.
Right.
I'm going write another method which I'm
writing yet this is what we call,
let's see,
invalid log book, invalid log in.
And this part I'm going to write as my
fixes integration
that I
So one set is smoke.
Once this integration.
What happened here
right now?
Yep I did it
now in testing do not act symbol
I'm using this after session to class
right
one test because belong to smoke one test
because belong to integration.
Correct.
Let me
it is giving me one error.
It is thing null pointer exception
on start assertion to java line number 31.
Here it is
giving me one error driver target title.
It means the moment I enter here,
the moment I enter into this method right
on this line when I'm using this driver,
it is giving me the error.
Can you see why it is giving me the error?
Any idea?
Because we are not opening the browser
before my third.
Not in the smoke that
these are preconditions?
Are those conditions available,
but they are not a part of my group.
My group is depending on precondition
and post correct.
So when I say my group is depending
on precondition and condition,
I have to come up with the setup
when it comes to grouping that
my precondition and condition will always
execute,
will always execute
irrespective of any group.
If I am making it for integration, fine.
It should work.
If I'm making it for smoke, fine.
So to do that, to do that,
what I have to do,
I have to write it
always run is equals to
after my third.
Also I have to write
always is equals to two.
Now if I go in my test and do not exceed
will file and if I try to run
working fine
or not.
So with grouping this is that issue.
If you are not voting, always run is equal
to true in your precondition
as well as your post condition.
It will not work right?
So your precondition in post condition
must be always run is equal to two,
but it is voted on.
Not everyone.
Now let's see.
I think should was asking right?
What? Is there a difference in this test?
Correct?
Correct.
The Sure Is it you also me
who was that was asking the question.
Okay.
I think so.
Me she is not here, but fine.
Let me explain. You see guys
here, I'm saying this is my
support.
So suit my indexing text HRT,
this is my suit.
And here I am saying
this is my smoke test.
I can do one more thing.
I can simply copy
and I can write another test.
This is my
integration test
inside one so I can have my separate test.
Let's say
you have a couple of test cases in smoke.
This gives this integration some test
because this belongs to both categories.
Is more integration in this solve
the solution to if you see I have
this gives this integration
as well as I have
discussed this in the smoke to correct
that it don't always tell me
let me show you
here one belong to the creation.
One belong to smoke.
Right, right, right, exactly.
So now you have to test.
One is for the creation, one is for smoke.
Nobody is.
Go ahead and run this test
and do not estimate by this time.
If you run this test and you detect
single file, you will be able to execute
not only your smoke
but also your integration.
Getting my point.
Just one click, just one click
you need to do and then you will be able
to execute not only your smoke
but also integration for clear.
See, that's what is executing
no integration test to start
the second smoke
I changed already date I change already.
I show you that
you see this is my integration right?
And this is my.
Oh, okay.
Okay.
Got it.
Fine.
This is my
now, now again, let me execute.
Yes, it is
my mistake.
Now you see, your precondition
is working for smoke right now.
Those conditions will also work for you.
Smoke right now, right
then your precondition is working for
regression. No.
Any opposed condition
is working for your Scorpion King.
Scorpion.
Your post works for the condition.
Also see if I open this.
If I close this, See, this is my suit.
So in H&M is my complete sleep.
Here is smoke test
here. Regression test.
Correct?
Yeah, I'm
all right. It was a smoke. I forgot
some zero
Scorpion King.
No disabled and smoke.
These four names.
I remember one more.
It was Molina, I think.
Okay, Reptile kind of
fight.
Got it.
So that is if you see here,
this is my suit.
Inside one suit I can have multiple test,
direct integration
test a smoke test inside one.
So so this is the difference.
One suit you get in multiple test,
in one test, you can in multiple packages
in one package,
do multiple classes in one class.
You have multiple methods, correct,
which you can include and exclude
according to your requirement here.
Now, if you want, If you want,
you just need one single file.
So fine.
You can pick the name,
you can rename it to smoke, not symbol.
If I write a smaller text symbol,
the another one you need to just execute
if you want to execute,
just regression test
because this you can rename the file
to litigation vertex symbol fight.
Correct. So there.
So it would be very easy for you
to configure your test cases
and execute your test cases
according to your requirements.
Got it.
Got it or not?
Let's pass it for the
fine.
That's the new symbol part.
We are done
with internal reading to the class three.
Fine.
So to top
it test parameterization into stingy.
Right? Always run.
We are done test cases grouping
we are done. Yes.
This is the part how to specify groups
include exclude groups client
test parameterization.
Right.
We will see that part
before this.
Before this build this point late
knows us.
This point is
we are almost done with this laser scheme.
Yes, yes, yes.
Very nice things remaining.
Now, there is one thing
in the starting point.
When we started,
I told you the biggest downside
of selenium is they do not have
any reporting structure, any effect.
If you're executing thousand test
because there is nothing that can express
that can show that can prove
that you have executed 1000 test cases.
We were looking for report.
This is basic explanation,
but I don't want this report.
This is not my report. Right.
This is not my report at all.
To take this string, to pass
this one failure information is fine.
Yesterday we were talking about you
not taking the console output.
So this is the console
only This is not the report I need report.
Okay, let's go ahead.
Let's see how we can get the report.
All right.
Ready, guys?
One More thing.
One more new concept.
That is the question which I have time.
We are almost done with this. Like, So
which question you are seeing? Should you?
I didn't get your question.
So do you find this something?
Oh, okay. All right. Let's go ahead.
So let's click on
Run edit
configuration, Click on Run and edit
configuration.
Let me know once you are able to see this,
the screen must
find this.
Is there an option?
Click on
our currently control.
Click on edit configurations.
Everyone is on this screen.
Everyone now
great
click on listeners.
You'll see this must be blank.
Nothing to show.
Click on
guys.
Please update your status.
Everyone, please.
Whoever is working on this
great. Now,
is everyone on this list? Correct?
Everyone is here.
You all can see there's nothing to show in
this plus sign, right Click on this.
Plus fine
and type here, email able.
Reporter You get this to email.
Reporter one email multiple.
Do you have to select the first one
email reporter Selected first one
selected everyone email able Reporter
Click.
Okay.
All right.
Applying here just to find both things up.
So guys, remember
if I am creating a new class
and if I am copying a code
from another class,
it is just because
I want to save your time.
If I keep writing the code again
and again, the same piece of code,
it will be a problem for you
always on the right.
Why I'm copying the code
because want to save your time
and the code which I'm writing here.
This is not rocket science.
If you already have this code
in your classes. Yes.
Yes. Correct.
So the code is already available, right?
I'm just copying this code.
And whatever the changes I'm doing,
I'm also showing that
these are the minor changes
I'm doing in the code.
If you want me to write every single code
from scratch, I can do that also.
But again, it will be a burden for you.
Yesterday
I having the problem right there.
Yesterday I was having a complaint. What?
Complain that I'm spending too much time
on doing the same thing.
Why not on this thing
now when I'm copying the
from one place to another class, right.
That code is nothing
which I'm writing new.
This is a previous code.
Anything which I'm writing new and,
rewriting it from scratch.
So please try to understand
this is for your goodness, right?
Not for me.
If you want me to write the code
from scratch, I can write anything.
Sure, sure, sure, sure.
So, guys, here, click on Run,
click on edit Configurations,
click on Listener's
Right
click on Plus sign
Search for email Reporter.
Click on this email label.
Reporter Click.
Okay here.
Also click okay.
No, it doesn't matter. It doesn't matter.
You can do that and it will be applicable
for the entire project.
Don't worry about it.
Okay.
All right.
So simply click.
Okay.
Right
now, let me go in my this part, right?
I'm going to create another test
and your text will
do you want me to create another one?
Or we can use the existing one too.
What you can say is a
new one.
So right click
again, go back to create a standard
or text symbol.
Reload from there. This
very new file,
we can repurpose those. Right?
But if I repurpose those once again,
people will complain, right?
That You are using the same one and your
copying the code from here and there.
I'm not copying the code, actually.
I'm writing every single new code
right here.
Fine.
So now I'm simply just giving it
to new name.
Let's just find
my first name is just Okay.
And instead of having so many classes
and so many methods,
I'm going to remove all of them
from here.
I'm going to take just one class normal.
Last year.
Let's see.
Soft attrition, one class.
I'm going to take that, guys,
Is this okay?
Let me open myself
to social class from here.
This is my soft position.
Last night.
I'm not using any group as of now,
so just remove
this grouping part from this class.
One method and two methods
in my testing.
Do not simplify.
What I want to do is simply alternate
the grouping also.
Otherwise again, people will get.
I looked at groups here.
Nobody at told
little bit.
I'm taking the smoke right?
And if I go inside of my
this class I'm going to right here.
This one should belong to my one groups.
The group name means a smoke
and this one also belongs to my group
group name system operator.
Obviously it will execute both this.
Just get this correct
in my soft assertion.
One this and did not extend well part.
So this time if I execute this time
if I execute,
you will see one thing.
Fine.
So now now I see one thing here.
Just I'm creating here
and I'm going to reload my project
and it why?
Let me show you that part.
I'm not getting this.
If we go ahead again, run it
configurations.
Just a moment.
That's why it was not working.
Reload this project from here.
It does give me a more case
to click here.
I did configuration part when I go
this should be mine
inside of see part. Correct.
Okay, fine.
Now if I apply and okay. Right,
let me execute
this time because my output directly
part was empty
so it was not generating the report
at any place.
Now, this time, if I run, sure city sure
mistake you.
So now, if I executed here,
you'll see inside
my SIRC
there is one file generated automatic.
Can you see this file is email report dot
and it got generated automatically correct
can you see this is this is the reporting
structure we were talking about.
So now the next thing
the next thing which we need to do is
we need to look into this proper
report in the browser.
Since this is the HTML report,
we can simply open it
into the browser
and how we can open this report.
Right click here.
I'm going to open browser
and the moment you click on Chrome
you will see this
colorful report available on the composer.
And you see this report Everyone. Yep.
Correct.
Right.
So what are we doing here?
Basically, no, there is no is.
You don't need to add this for each
single file.
See any list?
No to any accessible file. Right
within that. Any list.
No to any accessible file.
This is the list
we have added on the project level.
Let me do it once again
to see what we have to do is first
we have to click on Run
after Run.
We have to go into edit
configuration part.
When we go in edit configuration
here in the listeners,
we have to select this option, right?
We have to select this option
and then we have to write for email.
If multiple of.
Yeah, like that's
what I'm repeating once again.
Click on Run.
After running you
will get edit configuration part
the moment you click on edit
configuration, you are coming on this
particular page, click on listener Stat.
Once you go inside the listener step,
you will get this plus option.
Click on this option and search for email.
Reporter On this email reporter
you will get two options.
Email a reporter and email reporter
to What you need to do
is you need to select the first one
that is email a reporter
simply selected, Click, apply, click.
Okay.
Once you're done with this,
go into your next email file.
You don't need to add any dependency,
you don't need to add any other thing.
What you need to do is simply just right.
Click it and execute your test.
Do not simplify.
So I'm executing my test
in simple configuration file
when I have this a small group,
Whatever the test cases I have written,
which is having this textbook
and there I'm going to execute my class.
The moment I execute my class,
you'll see it updates.
My report.
So this is the report
we were talking about.
I did it.
Okay.
Yeah, that's fine. See,
you have to select first time, right?
What one will find, why it is so?
Because it is asking for the execution
part, Right?
So the execution part is available.
Let me show you where it is. Asking Demo.
Maybe you're going here
and when you click on this listener part
right before one listener part,
there are files.
These are the files you're talking about
in Excel groups.
It gives us an edit. Fine.
So in the Excel group,
we don't find anything yet.
If you'll see if I go in this,
let me just open it.
Come on.
Fine.
Works for a specific axiom.
Okay.
All right.
You have to reload.
Your project
is still if you're not still
if you are not getting file
right is still
if you're not getting this file.
Remember one thing going to run
edit configurations right here.
Check this part the output directly.
Can you see this output is
inside this output directly.
Just select
the part that you want to store.
So let's see.
I've selected this RC.
I have selected this is RC here.
So simply click okay
and then it will be generated.
The output report will be generated inside
the folder you're providing.
So I have provided
it's image generated under is clear.
Yeah.
If your yours is empty,
you have to provide this output directly.
First thing.
Okay.
Before list,
not before the list of just above the list
you will find this output
directly party it
right on this box.
You have to provide the part
where you want this report.
So let's see.
I have provided this part
for my project inside SIRC.
So that is.
See, I'm getting this report here
in billable reports.
In this case, I'm
getting this image label report
correct.
Now click okay and then execute your test
and you take some.
Yeah, that's fine.
You must be getting one best output folder
that's mine.
Just select its RC and click.
Okay.
And even if it is not SIRC,
any other folder,
if you want to take user drivers
right inside, it's obvious if you want to
take drivers can select driver. Also
select any
other folder.
All right.
So now everyone got
a you guys able to see this report now?
Great great great
today is today
notes will please ask
should you please ask what is the issue
where you're getting stuck
we are here to resolve any issues
don't worry about it gives us
El-Al.
Please ask where you're getting the issue
then, which is fine.
And it would step.
You're getting this issue
fine.
Let me go ahead one more time, you guys.
Right. Okay.
You're you're good.
All right.
Let me go ahead once again, guys.
See, let's start from scratch.
Click on Run.
Now, everyone please follow.
Please pay attention.
Click on Run
of all
which code you're talking about.
The solution one point
This is my software solution.
One I just added a group name,
nothing else.
All right, fine.
So, guys, let's follow me, please.
Everyone click on Run
then everyone
click on
Edit Configuration.
All the others.
Olena, Virgil shoul everyone, please.
Everyone, please
could you please post What is the error
in a peaceful post-acute?
All right,
so now everyone is on this screen, right?
Just click on this network post,
click on business.
Now click on this Plus sign this icon.
So that's ideal
project in search of a need.
So it should be a search by need,
not project here
you have to write email table.
The moment you write email label,
you will see this email label.
Reporter Here
are you getting this email level reported
here?
Right? You enter this thing,
click apply and okay, now you see here
this output directly.
Can you see if we want output directly
here?
If it is empty,
you have to provide the path
of this output
directly where you want this report.
So you have to provide the part.
Have you provided the part by clicking on
this plus sign from this folder I can
already click on here.
It will give you this,
it will give you this option.
So just select this is RC
selected is RC and click.
Okay.
Simple of
can you see this folder?
I can
click on this folder.
Please click here
and you will see things like this
and you'll see this
your project name and everything.
This is your project name.
This must be your project name, Correct.
It is giving you the option
for the folder.
So from, from the downloads. Right.
So instead downloads, just select the
but instead of the downloads,
can you see the downloads option
on the top right?
Instead of download.
Now select
your project name video is a stored.
All right, no worries.
Let's do one thing right.
Let's create inside, download another
folder, Create another folder download.
It's a new folder, right?
And then try to provide the port
and when you execute
you will find this report in the why.
I want you to put inside your project
so that you can see the report
inside your project.
Excel.
All right.
That is how many of you are done
with this part.
Listen. Part.
And you're bored with this.
Fine.
Just really,
I don't want to have make anymore
such reports for every assignment.
Yes, for every Excel.
You can create this report. It's
not an issue. It's not an issue.
Don't worry about it.
All done.
I also. Anybody in support?
Yes. Was must be there.
What is the issue?
The net. Can you please post your
Can you please post your problem? Get
we can refactor we can do better
you posted here.
Let me check which one
are all in.
I didn't see
cannabis posted here Inside life question
so they or I can check there.
Also it says
Ma'am,
your providing the class name
but package name is missing.
You are simply writing
software solution to our Java.
We are not writing any class
name like this.
See here
that we just detected
among
If you'll see my test in
do not take similar file.
I'm writing class like this.
Great. Nor java.
So what you have to do?
Your package name is class zero too,
so it should be class
zero to solve the solution to
and not our Java
Java.
You only know That's what I'm saying.
Can you see?
That's all you need to write your part.
If you want, I can type your path here.
No, I'm not holding the class.
I'm just resolving all of your queries.
Go to place, check the comments
on Sundays. They're already free.
Please check the comments of your query
there and.
The support.
You will find the answer there.
Why your writing on the syntax?
Because it is already just class zero to
because the
class zero to write.
Okay.
All right, guys.
So this is the image label report.
This is the image level
against the ability for trait.
This is your SDM report. We can see here.
Now let's go back to our slides
the next thing after
this is parameterization, right?
Since it is a time taking activity
and we cannot complete this parameter part
in just 15 or 20 minutes,
I will keep it for our next class.
Would they be okay?
Because already
you guys have learned so many things today
and I see the confusion in between right?
Yeah,
because I can see the clear confusion.
You guys have got so many things.
This looks almost
we have done in two classes
and I don't want to create more confusion.
I want to give you time. Right.
So that you guys can practice. Yes. Yes.
It was intense, correct.
But it is.
Tell me one thing
before before we wrap up this session,
before we do anything, are you any
is anyone who is still having the problem
with understanding the concept?
Forget about writing the code.
I'm going to commit this code and I'm
going to comment this code right now here.
So the code will be in your repository,
right?
That's true.
Yes. That is code is concerned.
I remember whatever the code I am writing,
I'm going to commit this code
in the repository right.
You will get entire piece of code, every
single class, every single line of code.
You will get this.
That's why I always say right whenever it
to practice, you can refer to this code.
But before that you need to understand
what are the code we are writing.
So let me come
and push
because it is the issue with the Mac.
That's why. Fine.
So I have committed the coordinates,
right?
Code is there.
I have already uploaded the files.
This just in.
Just like in your canvas.
Everything is there.
You have the whole weekend,
right?
Please post your query in the syntax
upload.
Right.
We will be there to support you.
Don't worry about it.
Just posted right after the classic
possible will will give you the support.
There.
Nor every single code is available. Right.
Like I said,
I gave you the installation details also
right as assistant every one of you
for the installation part.
So your environment is ready, right?
You just need to take the code,
all the code of the repository,
the updated code, and the same code
will work on your machine
as we.
Yeah, the link is here
just 3 minutes ago.
We have committed this code.
I just frustrated by.
All right, guys.
Yes it does connect correctly.
It's working fine.
Mike. I shared link in a check.
If you'll see that, please confirm
here in the check.
Only if you didn't get it.
Let me just mistake in the announcement.
Also, I gave it already in the course
announcement.
Great.
All right, guys, is there anyone
who has any other question,
any query, any confusion?
Please ask.
Sure, Mike.
Definitely.
Again, I'm repeating, guys,
if code is an issue
you think too much of code then wouldn't
available in the repository, right?
Just try to take the concepts
which we have known the topics
you will find every single class
for existing topic.
All will be available inside the class.
Go ahead and check the updated
or take the pull of this repository.
You will be having all the code with you.
Okay, everyone.
All right, guys, then I think
I'm done from my say for today.
See us next week
by the time.
Please practice. Please practice.
Okay.
It is very important.
If you practice, you will get perfection.