All right, guys.
Last number one, NBA.
And I've already started recording it.
You see, it's already started.
Okay.
I hope everyone can hear me clearly
once you're nice, because today
the only thing you have to do is
listen to them speak.
Just listen to me what I'm saying.
See what I'm doing here on the screen.
Right?
You don't have to touch anything.
Anything, Billy.
Right. And that.
So you will be able to understand
every single thing.
What I'm going to teach
just fine.
First, understand, let's start from a
the time
simple language,
full form is application
programing
interface.
What is it?
Is a master expert, by the way. It
application programing interface API.
This is the full form,
just simply for right
now. Let me explain to you what API is
my medium.
I don't even know the meaning of one word
from this for fine
application programing interface.
You guys must have seen.
Uh. Okay,
now you guys must have seen
this many people names, I would say
hundreds of times.
Google things,
which I'm going to explain, you know.
But you didn't observe them
the way I want you to observe from now
what works.
So now, from today onwards,
after that glass, whenever
you look at those things,
your perceptions will completely changed.
It will be changed
because of the explanation
you're going to have from today.
All right.
So in this post,
Glass will see the significance of it,
rate the use of it,
how it has changed, significant how
it has brought significant change
on dinner table for all of us.
How big connects
so many things, how it provides
so many benefits in our lives
right from now,
and how we generally use them
in this industry.
Without this,
I don't think that anyone from us is
surviving day in this digital world.
Let's start them one by one right?
First, let's consider one example
a very simple example.
What is this based?
This is a restaurant
called a Message in my husband.
All right.
So restaurants, this is my message
for Katrina because what it was doing.
So let's play
right now.
Now, let's see in this in this restaurant.
In this restaurant right.
Maryam threw a party movement.
That's what they meant, a Katrina.
They all came to the party.
Now, let me give you
the internal arrangement of this.
This is their table, right.
Which is available here in my their right.
And these are the chairs available
like so here,
see my safety
right it Katrina is sitting
on Maryam Izadi certainly her mother also.
Right.
Or what was passing
by saw Maryam Coleman here also joining
so what this sitting in the group
but now now
this is the very basic example
I'm giving you a very basic exam
not on this day, but on this table.
You for people.
Absolutely right.
If you need something to eat,
listen carefully.
This if you need something to eat, trade,
there is a kitchen available
right where ship is making so many things.
So Chef Sylvain is available.
Right ship is cooking everything
right now.
If you need something
from me, for example,
produce, you're asking them,
What do you do?
Right.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry if I misspelled this, but.
Okay.
If you need this on me,
we're saying we come together
to give whatever the things you need.
Will you be able to communicate
directly with me?
That's good. You can have
Jimmy Castro's friend get request.
I, Jimmy, No,
you cannot communicate with me directly.
Right?
You communicate here.
You communicate here with a person.
We call him maybe a waiter
or a server or some of the things. Right?
So let's say
your server guy is available yet
his name assignments
like my best friend assignments.
He's a bit in my company
because he is my best friend.
There's what I do with my best friend
most of the times.
Like So now.
Now what do you usually do?
Simonds and Mr.
Simonds will ask you, ma'am,
what you need it.
Miriam's is I need this burrito.
Assignments will come to me.
Assignments will ask me first,
Do we have burritos straight?
If I say yes, we do.
Yes, we do have.
Right.
Then it says will get fine.
She ask for one burrito, right?
She asks for one burrito. Right.
Make it
right, make it once.
But it is really not.
Who will you going to make this?
I am a chef, right? This is my that.
I'm going to make it like.
So if I'm going to make it
after cooking your burrito,
after making you connect
directly, come and give it to you.
Do not look right.
Like who?
Who is going to who is going to delivery
this Mr. Simas.
So you will send this burrito wire, Mr.
Simas and Mr.
Simon is going to deliver it on your team,
Correct?
Is this correct
enemy?
How many times
how many times you did this in your
multiple times?
Thousands of times. Millions of times.
Alex is exceptional.
These are just one very nice,
great.
Maybe you're saying one way everything
might be fine.
So now, now see why.
Why you cannot communicate with chefs
Because of so many reasons.
Let me tell you, some of
the first reason might be
because you guys know
English extremely well.
Right?
And that guys, chefs or Italian
explained it extremely well, Benny.
But you guys don't know how to speak
Italian.
He doesn't know how to speak English.
Now, people from two different languages
cannot communicate with each other,
cannot communicate with each other.
Right?
So if if you cannot communicate
with each other what you need,
you need someone in intermediate grade.
You need intermediate who can establish
a connection in between you and chef.
So who can take your order?
Go there in the order
bank and delivery on your table.
You need someone like this. Correct?
You need someone considered.
We will translate Zima.
That one was
This can also be an example. Great.
We need someone in between.
Correct.
So who can help us in
communicating with the chef what it is.
It would be this
second reason.
Right now we're talking for
small restaurant, great small restaurant.
We're not involved right now,
but if you go to any first grade,
maybe you are at the eighth floor on ninth
or 10th floor of the you
that you're ordering from. Right.
But the restaurant is not available
in the same to the restaurant, maybe
in the ground floor or maybe in the top
of a beautiful it could be possibly
right place.
So what chef
and you guys are not at the same place
when you both are not in the same place.
It's impossible
to connect with each other.
Right? You're not going to call anyone
to the ship
and the name of the page you have.
I did this, but you have this.
You don't have the money.
Even got it and is not.
You know that
he doesn't have that much of time
that he will going to accept your call
waiting making something in the restaurant
at the same time you cannot do this
right this he cannot do this.
So again
you need someone who can communicate
in between you and the chef.
Speak now.
Now, when we talk about this part,
when we talked about this
part, this situation, here,
we have three things.
First, medium
thinking.
So that is a chef.
Third,
silence is a wait, right?
It is, but she is a customer.
So customer, waiter and shame.
When we talk about blind
server architecture, remember one thing.
Remember one thing.
The one the one who makes a request.
The one the one who gives
the order is like
the one who provides,
who provides the food.
Who makes the food is server
and the one
the one who is transporting this order.
Taking the dishes back to you
on your table is your
If is your
Nona's good API is timer's
server is so that
remember the chef chef cannot be a waiter
and Victor cannot be a she. Read
the is understood this
first example
what I explained about restaurant
three
Now here
when we talk about client server
architecture, right.
Remember if you understand this term,
what is Glen server architecture right.
And you implement the things the way
I'm trying to explain you entire
a bar is a piece of cake.
Entire A bar is a piece of cake.
The only thing you should understand
is what I'm explaining.
You truly
connect connecting people
right after connecting people disappears,
right?
We don't need that kind of a
Gardner.
Right.
Is this butterscotch?
If we discuss after we send it
right?
So now,
now, here it you see in client
server
architecture, right when you're customer.
But in this particular example
as a customer, you are a client.
As a chef is chef and Ms.
is a server.
Right?
And this waiter, Mr.
Simonds, he is an API is an API.
So the order you give
listen one more point again,
the order you give in this situation,
we call this order as
a request
request.
So assignments beg your request, right?
It API take your request to home
server
and then server answers to your request
Server answers to your request.
So the answer settlement is giving you.
So the answer server is giving you.
We call it
response.
We call it a response. Understood.
The one you say is request.
The one you receive is response.
So the one client is sending request.
EPA is taking your request to data server
server is providing something to API
that is response.
So API is again
taking back this response to that line.
So blind server connected
via API client is sending request APIs,
taking the request, taking it to
someone
instead of what is returning the response.
Again, it is taking this response
and delivering it back to the customer or
playing server architecture using API
in normal length windows to
the ones we're doing.
So far so good or not
nice,
but do you want me to go slow
or the point
after a long time
and then the device?
Right now
let me give you the example of API
how API box is you could see
and then you will be blown away
by thinking that, Oh,
I'm seeing API every day
and I wasn't aware of it.
Seeing
first this example clearly,
so I'm not going to use it anymore.
It will deliver
liquid logic.
Tell me some of the banks,
some of the famous banks of use
the name of those banks
which you guys are using, Bank of America
cheese
for Wells Fargo,
Hong Kong and Shanghai
Banking Corporation.
You'd be fine.
Enough, enough, enough, enough.
I don't want bank account in any of them.
And that's Scream five is more than
B and C, D, C, u, ABC, x, y, z.
When you do three every bank
Lloyd user got
25 banks is c d d Bank of America
is Wells Fargo, HSBC right
now tell me how many of you guys
are using this credit debit cards,
specifically debit card to withdraw
the money from the ATMs and everything
almost.
All right.
And don't take the responsibility
for every one
about yourself.
I just delivered an audit.
Someone said I don't use
by using it on my behalf,
but majority,
you use this card rate, fine.
Have you ever observe then
if you have a card
of Bank of America
radio Bank account in Bank of America.
But if you go to a be a machine
automatic bid machine,
everyone knows Indian Railways.
The machines we generally use it will do
the amount they do to check the status.
Even this idiom belongs to Chase Bank.
This APM is for kids bank right
race If you go there.
If you go there,
if you go there in this bank
here, a machine is available
and you insert your card
which is available in Bank of America,
but your account is available
in Bank of America.
But you are you forget about
how many dollars yet charging
and why they're chatting and not willing
to talk about the job is not right.
We are going to talk about the school
right.
Money comes first. Everything.
I'm explaining something.
No one is going to focus on that.
Everyone's thinking
I have to pay the money.
We don't have to pay the charge.
See here, here
in this ADB,
a card that you have,
this card is Bank of America card.
Great.
But the ATM you're using this is belong
to the 18 belongs to your she bank.
But still the moment you inside your card
it shows your date on one.
It shows your little notation
right
now Now just consider the same situation.
Just consider the same situation.
All bank can integrate.
It's like this it money is trying to exist
in another form
and as opens up hopefully is
but it shows at another point.
Miracle Epsilon
three.
Is it possible?
No, no, no, no, not it's north.
See, Marina is already
logged in in her form,
and that is loaded in her phone.
So if you logged in with your account,
you can not
it can not show any of that account.
Right.
It can not show any of that account.
But but here in this A.T.M.,
a guy from Bank of America
from d d bank chains
bends for just b c from any bank,
from any bank rate.
You have a debit card or debit card.
You want to withdraw some money,
you go in any of the atrium right there.
You use your card and it will allow you to
withdraw your money.
It will allow you to withdraw your money.
Right.
This is the functionality everyone knows.
That's how things work in. Let
everyone
Now let me give you how
this things work in banking.
See, that's
fine.
So now, now see what happens.
This database.
This database is available.
They will find their trade.
What example? Bank of America.
Read all the all the information related
to the customers accounts and everything.
Bank of America put all this information
here in its database
right now.
Don't you think that is
data is very, very important
for the bank?
It is very important.
Can they share their data
with any other bank,
For example,
this is their database or Chase Bank.
This is their data for us.
No, they cannot share any data
with any other bank.
Correct.
Any other data with the credit.
History is not the financial data, Right.
It's your record
just to give you more loan or something.
Right.
So see,
Bank of America has its own database,
which is purely Securency, right?
Chase Bank has its own database, which is
purely secured, and at the same time
the bank has its own redundancies
or just purely secured seats.
Correct?
So we have multiple database for
multiple banks.
The point
multiple database for multiple banks.
Then how is it possible
that when they try to insert my bank card
right in any other way as these bank AGM,
it is able to rate
this particular bank
is able to fetch my data?
How is it possible when bank is not going
to allow the access to their databases,
to any of their main, then how does a be a
machine is getting my data.
That is the only question.
See how it looks.
Remember all these banks,
whatever the private banks are available,
public banks are available, government
banks are available.
They all are connected to federal bank
better Bank is basically
a government government bank.
Even centralized bank, federal bank.
It owns this federal bank owns
all the banks.
Right?
So all banks, for example,
it is Bank of America,
Chase Bank, any bank, any other bank.
All these banks are connected
to federal banks or not. The
all these are connected to
connect.
So now here, here, here,
every bank is connected.
This one, this one, maybe some World Bank.
Right.
And then this A-Team, this A.T.M.
machine, the Indian machine we talk about.
Right.
This data machine from Let's see,
she has been trained.
It is connected
to this centralized server.
Okay?
It is connected
to this centralized server.
So now what is happening at
the moment, right?
See how it works?
All these banks are connected to Central
bank, right?
The moment you insert your card, you get
the moment to insert your card.
It sends a message, a signal
to just bank that, Hey, I got one card
having the number one, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight, nine.
Do we have any detail
for this particular card?
So just banks is.
No, we don't have any user with this data.
It transfers that request to us
and delays the database.
So now here in this centralized database.
Right.
Because their data was not able to phone
inches bank.
Right.
What is being does it send your request
to federal bank database
here in central bank
see Bank of America is available.
Chase Bank is available right.
Citibank is available,
Wells Fargo is available.
Other banks are also available.
So now it quickly
check with everyone who you have.
You have it is. Yes.
Bank of America says yes, I do have
I do have this database available with me.
Find it sense
that the risk to Bank of America, someone.
But now when it sends
that it goes to Bank of America.
Central Bank of America says yes,
it is a customer, a gentleman customer
having everything in the account
allow him to use his account.
So the moment it sends this message,
this is what we call response.
The response comes back to the central
bank.
It transfers back to the bank.
Just bank shows the same thing unexpected.
And that's
how you generally take your money
from the
industrial
underscored
everyone.
Now let's talk about $3
to spark
your favorite.
Everyone's favorite, $3.
Why? Why they charged this three bucks?
What is the reason behind it?
Why did you have to this three bucks?
Basically because they can.
Right.
So remember, remember case
if you use the same bank
18 various account exist.
You don't have to charge anything.
If you
use someone else's a DRM,
then you have to charge.
You have to be right
that in case
why is it
see if your account is inches bank
and you put you inside your card
in the ATM that Adam is also
in the juice bank, it simply sends
you requested it's simplest answer
request here just makes is yes,
we do have this.
We do have this. Okay.
So are they interacting
with this federal bank services?
Are they interacting?
He is no right.
So there it provides
a detail directly to you.
Just make sense.
All right. We have this data.
We are not going to connect.
We are not going to leverage your services
for this particular call.
That's fine.
We are going to allow this user
to take anything from his account.
Right?
Right. But
when it comes to this centralized
database of central bank, this works.
This would be issues
to this linking of connections,
everything to maintain this,
to keep them updated.
Right.
And live and working and up all the time.
24 seven. Right.
It means it requires a lot of maintenance
rate case,
but it requires a lot of maintenance
so they can not charge with anyone
about this maintenance.
So what they do is if you are using
the services that only you have to charge,
if you don't use the services,
you don't have to charge.
And that's that's
why if you use any of that, Adam,
if you use any of that idiom,
then only you have to pay this price.
Otherwise you don't have to pay this price
got replaced.
How We
generally get the money from the Indian.
So now, now here,
the one who is sending the request,
who is taking the response,
communicating with all the banks
that were with federal Bank, everything.
Right?
Maybe other database of Bank of America
is available in New York
and maybe the database of Chase Bank
is available in Washington, DC
and maybe this federal bank
centralized is robbery is available.
Maybe it's the Chicago, Illinois. Right.
And the guy is trying to get this money
from to California.
Right.
So one is in Pacific, one is in Eastern
Time, one is in Central Bank.
All over the U.S.
things are distributed everywhere.
But then who is going to connect
all these things together?
Who is sending this request?
Who is picking the response?
Everything. Who is doing
behind
FBI connect all this?
This comes together
to make of one ecosystem,
to make one ecosystem.
All right.
Now, tell me since how long
you have been using this services,
Indian services, long thing
since how many years
when you have been using this?
18, maybe five, six, seven, eight,
nine years, 18 years.
Right. It might be possible.
1983.
Like similar.
You are older than this planning.
Excellent.
All right.
So, see, we have been using this database
in so long,
but we never knew that we're using API.
We are utilizing API visit
industrial, this example,
every one.
So for any confusion in describing
what API means,
how we works.
Right.
So the first example, the first example
which I gave you
was a completely non-technical example.
I took probably a length
and then the next example
which I give you, it is a little bit
technical, little bit technical.
Right now the title exemple,
which I'm going to give you
is more technical in More Easy,
which we use every now and then.
We use every now and then.
Right?
So let's go ahead and take that exam.
Zima Something came for you
in the chat. Oh,
by the way, there is liquidity.
One thing we have an option
where you can text first with your
in case in case if you need
we have that option.
Just it
it's for me.
Thank you so much matter.
So now see I'm going to open right
one particular
application.
Let the journey begin.
Skyscanner don't go.
Not in the right.
What is this?
Days Skyscanner
great website, the book tickets, the link
basically.
So for example, if you want to book hotel
for your upcoming vacation
in Santorini Island, Greece,
you can go here, put your best in
if you want to book a tickets.
If your visit to India, come and meet.
I'm available right.
So you book tickets from here.
If you want to hire something
in any other country
where you're traveling,
great for vacation,
you can simply
you can simply hire those car services.
Also from you know nice.
Makes them bank for sure.
No, just give me a heads up in advance
before two weeks
and to be able to make some
Katrina
Internet.
Is it
when is going
to be committed?
So you need
how would I handle
why they're trying to ruinously
I already have 21 trainings in pipeline.
How can I make such a decision?
My plans can wait.
No, someone else will take this.
Basically
it conflict
work is a priority.
It simply does reality.
As long as you're working
people just think
as long as you're delivering
according to their requirements
of their requirement,
they reach on you, talk to you.
That is you.
They give you money,
they give you everything,
they give you your their time is.
But the moment you stop doing all of this
things and you focus on the person,
they would forget.
They would forget for sure, Right?
The one rule that applies to
this one is the rule of exchange.
You give you knowledge,
you give your time,
and then they give you respect.
It is nothing great.
Giving selflessly to the community
doesn't exist anymore.
It's simply to it.
No, I'm talking about in general,
everywhere you go,
whether it is a business
or it is any of that thing, everywhere
you go, right, it happens, right?
So it's it's better to
accept what it is and how we have.
So that that's
why you have to be very nice, right?
You have to have more
knowledge like an export.
So when you open your mouth,
you build people who you are busy.
Good.
So make sure
whenever you just enter into the room,
you just light up being dead
or with your presence.
That kind of knowledge,
that kind of confidence must not educate.
You should get it actually right.
So that's where I'm focusing on is right.
The one you're talking about
is not a big deal.
If I decide in the morning,
in the afternoon, you didn't get a news
credit, that sort of big deal.
This is something we can do
at any point of time.
Everyone is doing this.
But what I am doing,
everyone cannot do it right.
So do the provision
that everyone can not do.
And then automatically
you will get more respect,
more valued.
Fine.
That that's what I'm betting you learn.
More commission engineers are available
in the market right?
But once you start betting,
they prevent in such a way
prepared yourself in such a weak
field knowledge in such a way
that you can tell this right when making
I wanted to your recruiter like this.
Okay go ahead find all the people
find the screen
all other candidates in the US.
If you find someone like me
hired him otherwise come in
like this kind of attitude you should get.
And believe me, the moment you get it,
this type of attitude and the way
you give your interview with this
attitude, they will not going anywhere.
They will come to you.
They will hire you or sure,
because everyone needs exception.
And that is the industry.
They know her.
What is like that?
Try this.
Try this in books.
But you don't have to do this first.
Explain that
explaining your knowledge in everything.
Otherwise you say, Hey,
you will never find someone like me.
And he said, All right,
what is an Indian web driver?
And you said Then he said, Yes,
I will never find a person like you
to do it.
Okay?
Because you're completing something else
and you're delivering something else,
sufficient or not, but
correct.
Now, let's come to the point again
when you guys got some of the best wing,
but it's not a base work.
Some news I wasn't aware
that is going to get engaged.
Congratulations to the brother.
Why you one
why So now
what I'm going to do here is
I am going to book a ticket.
I'm going to book a ticket from
New York to Mumbai.
Right. From New York to Melbourne.
I'm going to book
now see what happens
all 141,000 160,000.
Amazing.
Happy 705.
It's Indian Guernsey.
It will be
all over, Mother.
It's expensive.
Genocide, kind of.
Oh, it is.
You can consider
almost 2000,
almost 2000 books.
Right.
So now, now you see what is happening
when I start to Skyscanner that hey,
Skyscanner
go great go here.
And once you go to this particular place,
find me, find a particular one,
Find me a particular flight
from Mumbai, New York to Mumbai.
Great.
New York, Dubai, cutting.
So what it does, what it did,
basically it gave me multiple options.
See, Skyscanner
says, okay, we have got the
we have United Airlines,
we have British Airways,
we have Etihad, we have India.
I'm just taking this plane
now. No, Nicole,
I will send your ticket.
I will send it.
Fine.
So now, see, Skyscanner
gave you five different rate.
Skyscanner gave you five different
airline details for your search.
Now, for us, it is very easy.
They tell me one thing, Ari,
connecting directly with Qatar Airlines,
United Airlines, British Airways,
the dehydrated
out of interacting with them. No.
But can we see their flight schedule
from Mumbai to from New York to Mumbai?
We can see that
right now.
Just consider here in one place,
take one destination.
You're getting all these options right
with just one request.
How difficult would it be
if we had to interact with Amy
with every other airlines?
We have to go to their website.
We have to invest their data,
we have to get the information,
and then we have to compare the prices
manually.
We have to check.
Okay, despite this point of time
and having this much of money.
So I should go with this
or when all this thing
now is doing by one particular part, go
Skyscanner.
So Skyscanner is taking care
of all those things,
correct.
But in reality, Skyscanner
is not an airline,
which is Skyscanner is not an airline.
Then how is it possible that
Skyscanner is giving you the details
of all these elements?
Right.
So now let's understand this hierarchy,
how things work in the banking sea.
You are sitting on your computer,
you make a request, right?
You search for here
new your book movie.
That request went to Skyscanner.
The request went to Skyscanner.
Right now again, databases
very important data is very important.
Correct.
So here Qatar Airways has its own database
data is its own database.
If Etihad has its own database,
British Airways is exported, Right.
Skyscanner sends this request
to databases, to all their databases.
These databases are available
at different places.
Different places. Right.
This this Qatar Airways is
they these Etihad cities and British this.
All right.
We cannot share our database with you.
We cannot share our information with you.
The only thing you need,
the only thing you need,
you will be able to take that.
How When I search for New York,
the Mumbai isn't giving me any option
for release to London. No,
but do you think that is a disaster?
Etihad Airways do not.
And this British Airways
has only flights from New York
to one with just one flight.
No, they are having hundreds of flights,
thousands of flights all over the world.
Right.
But it is giving us segregated options.
Three third options, the options we need.
It means do advantages.
First, we are getting very sorted, things
we don't have to be bothered about.
Okay,
which one is from New York to Mumbai?
We don't have to worry about it,
but It's very simple.
Second thing,
these airlines are very reliable buy
because now they are shedding
just one piece of information,
just one chunk of information
or the complete information
from their database.
Right.
They are having the details of thousands
of flights, but at the same time,
they are not providing
all thousands of flights.
They're providing you
just one flight detail
that you are expecting them
to provide cutting.
So now Skyscanner
how they are protecting their database.
Cadbury de pigeons in British Airways
at this point of time,
they simply provide access via API.
They said we have made what
is Skyscanner.
If you need to read the information about
the flights, use this particular API.
In this API, just the parameters unique.
For example, Mumbai
to New York or for example
New York, London by example,
the New Delhi, whatever the flight
you need,
just provide those parameters in your API
and then we will give you the information
about that particular location
and how many flights we have,
what is the seed status
we have and every single thing
about this particular park, right?
So it means sharing the small chunk
of information
from the database can have fun,
can be done by an API.
That's what Skyscanner is doing.
So now, now your flights trade,
your flight tickets
may be available, right?
If someone else press some constraints
here, then you book it via Skyscanner.
It charges convenience fee.
If you observe it, rules
it, charge convenience fee,
Skyscanner every other website.
Right.
If you go here, for example,
people try to book this ticket
all year.
Why did you look in the last adult show
you right
with this price they will add some charge
they will add some charge, what we call it
convenience fee rate.
Convenience fee.
So how how this part is this Skyscanner
is making money via this particular one.
It basically provides
you all this guidance.
Right.
And when you're making that request
at the time of checkout,
at the time of making a payment from here,
right from here,
it will charge some amount, for example,
of $10 or $15 or $20.
Maybe the digital will be all right.
So now now just imagine
airlines are getting their own money.
Right. And what do you think?
How many people use this Skyscanner
or this type of websites day?
How many people use
them throughout the world?
Too many.
Let's consider one.
We have almost homeless
people on the planet,
almost 700 millions, right?
Almost 7 billion people.
We just consider .07 percent.
It is 1 million that 1 million users
are making the request.
Right.
And they are made making their bookings
by Skyscanner everyday.
No, Skyscanner is not doing anything.
It doesn't have any database.
It holds the information.
It fetches the information from several
places and gives you that information.
Right.
So 1 million requests, if they charge just
ten bucks for every request and we see
how they're making a big
next business,
that's the business API has, right.
And that's
why nowadays you'll see is my dream.
Make my dream easy.
Go and Skyscanner and so many other
so many other
players are available in the market and
they are providing a lot of facilities.
Expedia right.
And this one we call it
which one?
My area book this part hotels
or textbook Booking.com.
Right.
So so many so many websites are available
in the market.
They generally provide
this type of vassiliadis.
Right.
So they connect with the Airbnb right
Airbnb connect.
So these these websites basically connect
with hotels, connect
with of greens, connect
with card renters, connects with airlines.
Right.
So now at one place
you can book your hotel, so you can book
your cars, you can books your trains and
you get booking flights and everything.
So it's not only about the facilities
that they provide,
it's about the money
also that they are making.
Because if a customer comes to their
website, customer comes to their website,
their rate, this customer can booked
every single thing.
So now this customer doesn't
have to go to any other people
just when using one paid
customer can leverage every single thing,
every single industry.
Now if you're making a flight tickets
flying, right, they charge $10
each site, $20 for your roundtrip profit
and giving you a nominal charge.
It could be more because you're making
a booking for $2,000.
Definitely.
They charge 25, $30 minimum,
then hotel booking again, convenience
card rentals,
an inconvenient fee from one particular
customer.
They can make 30 to $40
just to understand.
Now it happens 365 days, 24 seven
every single.
Their job is to make sure that their data
is coming directly and people are able
to book their tickets, whatever
they want to book, then it will double.
The only thing is management.
They are just managing their servers,
they are just managing their websites.
They are providing you the facilities.
We go there,
we provide our data, we provide that
email and phone number,
name and every single thing.
And they use this data
for marketing as well.
That's why
sometimes you get messages from nowhere.
They are very happy with intensity
level with your loved ones.
They complete pursuit of use this quote
on their website and user.
I got 50%.
You already provided your data
to the website, right?
That's why
they are giving you this for the marketing
purpose advertisement kind of stuff.
So if they have reply flights
available, right, there is no
there are no people in the plane
and they're giving you 50% discount rate.
Even if people booking that,
it will to make money.
They're making money now from this. Right.
So there's some eBay books
connecting with
multiple databases of multiple airlines,
making the relevant
information, providing it to your system,
to the request.
You have made.
It gives you the response
in return of that.
And then you start to your book,
their tickets, their tickets, books.
By making a payment,
it connects you to Internet
banking or via card to bank server.
From there you get confirmation.
So that is also eBay.com booking
their tickets, getting them permission,
and it is also API call booking a hotel,
get the details of the hotel.
There is also API.
And so every various API
that connects multiple systems
together, industrial
so far
so good rate.
This is just
this is just almost half of the class.
Tell me any confusion about API
now you can you see how API is
are working in your lives.
Is it something regarding you something
you know it was already there.
It was already there.
We just we just have to
look at the look at the things within
like so no,
no whatever the things. Yes.
Getting whatever the things we learned
so far is first
line,
second set of
code API,
The one was client.
What he does is sense that request
blind is the one who's saying stuff
request
and server is the one who just wants to
that request.
Server is the one who responds
to their request API.
Big care of transmitting
this request in response
from blind server from server to play
in this case.
In this case this New York
we played this and you you are a client.
You are sending this request and you get
the response straight from Skyscanner.
These are the claims, right?
This is Skyscanner
is the API who is going to working this
process, transmitting the
information from here in this
industrial this everyone,
should we proceed further
now let's talk about
flying
server
architecture.
Mind you,
if I go to slides, you'll see
it's escapes.
This is very bad thing.
I never look at those clients.
Fine claims server architecture.
The first thing, the first thing
we are going to go with, You see,
now, without looking at this picture,
you can penetrate
what is sort of
what in what is going right.
It gives you one example.
There is a server that connects
with multiple text on it
connects with your laptop,
it connects with the Internet,
it connects with the printer
and with so many things, connect
in technical terms I'm talking about.
But the example which we see,
it is more clear by looking at that.
Now, if you understand,
if you look at this particular one,
after understanding those examples
now, you'll be able to tell
what is the server for the server who
responds to the request.
Now, who is going to make the request
blind?
So which are the client?
You see, four clients are available here.
If you want to print
something by a server,
you are connected to bring
that you are connected to a domain, right?
You just send a command it, okay,
Bring this page and bring that.
It will give you the page.
Connect.
So this is basically a physical server
rate of 11 point.
Now, this is something
we need to understand
client server architecture,
blind server architecture,
one by one will go
and look all the categories of blind
set of picture.
Okay.
Already case.
So here, here, when we talk about claims
server architecture, we have to make
sure that we understand one
layers.
What are the layers specifically?
See, we have three layers.
The first is
we have presentation
layer, we have application layer
and we have detail.
Listen to this point carefully, guys,
how many layers we have in
any application
with a kind of yes, three layers.
We have not understand every single layer
and every single layer.
How many of you guys user index
each item by far
majority of US rate
use this particular part.
The majority of us use
this particular part rate.
The one you see on your screen,
the one you see on your screen,
we call it UI,
right?
User interface, front end
so that we can communicate to the system,
the one which we see here,
the one which we see here
on to our screen, because in this UI
or we call this front end right,
this is your presentation is
because rendering something,
then it presents something.
So we call it presentation layer
Discord,
it presents something
we call it because initially,
but then you want
when I right here user name
and when I read your password,
I click on log in button.
It takes me to dashboard reach, right?
It makes me for
who said this,
who said this to a chat and application
that, hey,
if someone enters admin
as a username and password,
you want to chat and clicks on logging
button,
you have to open only dashboard page
not even page, not an employee bit.
Who said this
developer said the purpose
of this, this
and this was develop the application.
Right.
So basically, basically this is the logic.
This is the logic.
Somewhere someone has written this logic,
correct?
Some of this
someone has written this project.
So remember, this is not your data guys.
Their data is coming from database.
That is another thing, right?
This is the logic that I'm talking about.
If someone inverts username and password
and that is correct, and when someone
clicks on logging, you should not
get that particular customer
an error
message, but instead
you should provide this dashboard screen.
Right?
So it comes, it comes from application
logic, where application near
where business logic has been written
that business logic is
all right,
where business started restricting
this is the application. This
kind of
so now are two things we understood.
First is using
it has nothing to do with the logic.
It is just a UI look and feel.
What we are seeing there.
User name well, which I do in blue.
Kind of amazing
when it comes to both username people.
Extremely nice password, nice.
Not logging button green.
No business logic.
See it's built
this presentation layer application.
This is if someone enters username
and password correctly and clicks on
logging button,
then you should open only facebook page
if someone enters username and password
incorrect and clicks on login button,
then instead of opening dashboard page
this time
you should provide an error message
and error message
and this should be the error message
you should provide.
Connect.
So now this is the logic.
This is the logic.
Fine logic is available
when in application
like the third layer is their data.
And thirdly is their data.
Yet what does it mean to see
business logic sees if someone enters
correct username and password
and click on in,
you should provide dashboard page
on dashboard page,
you should provide all the details
of the employees in every single.
This is logic system, but they mean
does logic have any data?
No, no.
Logic is kind of instructor logic.
Just instruct the things
logic sees everything, right?
Business logic.
Since everything that he application do
this, do this, do this fine.
Should this data,
this data and district are fine,
but the data is not with application.
Their data is not in the business.
Logic data is in data is in data layer
x5 why we call it database
or simple language.
We colleague.
So like
server
rate database or server
or industrial
and this world everyone
now in more simple language,
in more simple language,
this presentation is your frontend
this data and it is your bank
and this application layer is
your middleware.
It is rooted in frontend, backend
middleware,
presentation layer application layer
data. Yes.
And this code against the meaning of three
layers, presentation, net application
layer and intelligence.
When we connect
with these three layers together,
when we connect these three layers
together,
we get one and
then you enter something,
you provide some inputs,
you get some output
details coming on UI so you can see it
easily.
Middleware is providing the logic that,
hey, if someone enters this party
should provide this data databases.
I have one information based on the logic.
Just come to me.
I will give you all the information there.
So things we're going to be making for
any of the application behind the scenes,
these things that are going
on, these three layers, all honestly
great.
And on
the printing, on the presentation screen,
we always get the output,
which is nothing but the outcome
of this particular part
and the structure
fine, let's cross it further.
There.
So now here, let's start with claims
server architecture.
In the first architecture I'm thinking is
the architecture
which when we are taking guys
and we like the architecture, not what is
this won't be an architecture goes,
Have you ever heard about this one?
Do you know
Dominic's
in a hundred kilometers
enough.
When you have presentation live
your application layer
and your data
layer, your presentation layer,
your application layer
and your data layer, all that.
Three layers are available at one place
or in one machine
in one place.
We live in one place or
in one machine.
In a single machine.
Getting my point what I'm explaining you
when your presentation there
application layer data layer
on that the layers are available
in one place.
Your presentation
that is nothing but your blind
rate from where you make request.
Your This server is nothing
but your data layer, right?
That gives the response
correct application.
It is nothing.
The logic is written on
a transport circuit
according to the logical request you make.
Great guess.
So when when your presentation live
your application in your data layer
on the three
layers are available in a single machine.
In one system,
we call it one beer architecture.
The best example of one architecture is
a calculator.
How calculated?
The best example Let me show you.
And you see, I want to calculate the
everyone's
what I see in front of me.
This is my presentation, the mark, the
this is not presentation.
If I type here, do
less.
Frank
and I click on equals to sign.
So it gives me estimate
who said this to calculate other
hey calculator
if soil type do
and then plus sign and then five
and then if you put equals two
you have to add these two things together.
Logic.
So very logic is available.
Extreme logic is available.
The logic is available in application
this cutting.
So mind my application,
it is also available at the same place
or not.
My application
here is also available at the same place
and the is correct
so two plus flight is equal to seven.
Now. See
now see
this data is available,
two plus five is equal to seven.
So it holds the information.
It holds the information.
If I write here something, let's add three
plus five
is equals to it says end right this time,
which says eight.
If I click here, you see three
plus five is equals to two
plus five is equal to seven.
The previous operation,
which I did, the previous operation,
which I did, is also available here.
The current operation, which I did just
now that is also available here.
Now tell me to operate this calculator.
Listen to this point carefully.
Just to operate this calculator,
do I need to connect
with the internet? No.
Even if I don't have the Internet,
even if I don't have
any of that connection is still
if I open my laptop
and if I want to use my calculator,
I can simply come here.
I can simply open it, perform.
Some explains the operation,
and I can get the output at the same time.
I can see whatever
the operations I performed in.
The data is also available here,
even though if it is for a temporary basis
but still data is available here or not.
Right.
So it means my data
near is also existing in the same system.
My application.
It is also existing in the same system.
My presentation
there is also existing in the same system.
Right?
So according to the definition of claims
that our architecture model
type would be an architecture,
when of presentation layer
your application layer your data layer,
all these three layer exist in one system,
we call it one
the architecture
and the example is calculator
and a story
week.
Everyone in the street or not, students.
Is there anyone who has any question
in this part in sort of architecture,
some now, now in this UI part,
why our presentation layer
when you put three plus five is equals to
what are you doing?
Make a request,
you are making a request with three
plus five
and when you got this eight,
what is this eight?
This eight is the response.
This eight is the response. Who does this?
Who transports this data?
API API transport is simply three
plus five.
So API gives you a simple
because these things happen very fast
in a milliseconds you get all of this
information, you getting good.
The negatives will never understand the
response rate, how quickly things work.
But yes, this is what we need.
We need quick resolution,
we need quick solution
and that's how we get quick solution.
Is this clear to everyone?
Nice.
The moment customers are
new, what it are simply time
frame.
Fine.
Let's take a break guys.
Then.
All right,
so now, now before the break
for clean set of architecture,
we are done with the first time.
We are done with the fourth type call
with the first one,
call one the architecture.
Right.
And here in this one, be an architecture,
have seen one exemplar,
which is calculator.
So the question is, do we have
other examples
Also for one, did architecture.
So the answer is yes, we do have
what are those example?
Let me give.
So basically, basically
when we talk about the examples of client
one bit
architecture, one year architecture,
whatever the stand alone application
we had
is doing a loan application.
We also call them desktop application,
such as
Ms. Bank
loan bed
calculator
and so many apps.
These all are a standalone application
or in simple language,
we call them desktop application, right?
So all the desktop application
and stone estate and on application,
these applications are the best
examples of one
be an architecture understood
both Perfect.
Now let's talk about the second type
called
second type called
two different architecture,
what we call today's
to date architecture, right?
So here in this two architectural house,
the arrangement again, we will play
with the three Layers application
presentation indeed and earlier.
So here we write
application.
First I should write presentation
and presentation layer.
Second, we have this application layer
and the third we have is
data.
Correct
increase.
When your presentation layer
in simple language, we call it UI, right?
When you presentation
layer is available is available
on client end
and your application in detail.
This two layer application and data layer
when this two layer
is available on on server
and so and right
so on the line and you will have
your presentation layer on server
and you have your application in detail
here.
Understood.
Now let me give you the example
then maybe it will be more understanding
that we will.
The best example is have you ever been
to McDonald's many or Domino's?
How many of you in there.
Yes, Katrina. Great. With three. Yes.
It seems you go there every now
and then and delivered with plus nine.
Nice. Right?
So you guys go there eight.
Everyone was really simple
When you go to there once a week
I could see everyday my prime right.
And then it said junk food.
But still I couldn't
find any best example in there.
So I'm taking this one.
So now, now if you go there
and you stand on to the counter
where a guy or a girl is available
right on that cash counter.
Right.
Or the billing counter, you see one
machine is available
there.
One machine is available there. Right.
What is that machine
self-checkout?
No, not so.
Checkout
machine. The machine in the machine
there is a monitor available.
When you see when you said that, Hey,
I need one burger
or I need one piece that one,
they generally do.
They put some details in that system,
then put some details in their system.
Right.
And then whenever they provide
the details, their system provides you the
getting their system
provides, you the bill.
So now now tell me, for example,
if a guy or
a girl is living in New York, right,
it orders pizza.
There's order visiting Domino's.
And that guy who's living in California,
he knows orders is up in Domino's.
Will there be a same price
or different results, Same pizza
in New York and California?
It's a different place. Why?
No, not Texas
under fucking more Texas guys.
I'm talking about Texas.
I'm talking about the pizza base price.
The base price of this pizza, for example.
It is available at $10.
I'm just taking one example.
So it is available in dollars in here
and here.
Heroes.
Then you put some Texas,
you put some other factors,
you put some service charges.
These are different thing.
But when the base prices are the same
rate,
they always seem the base price.
Now this Texas and everything
depends on the
which the state is imposing how much Texas
so there is generally a takes part
I'm talking about the base price.
The base price is steam by
because the system of Domino's.
The system of Domino's creates
rate for the entire U.S.
rate rate.
It clears for entire U.S.
So now you find all the items,
the items available here, the same items
will be available here. Also
rate whether it is a lower gig
or it is a discrete
or best result, it is a pizza or whatever,
whatever size, great slides or anything
you'll find here.
Also the same thing you find here.
Also, they know what system does.
You provide some detail straight away.
You provide details.
For example,
one pizza gives you the price of $10.
Here.
The price is coming from here
from your server,
which is a database, correct?
This place is coming from there.
It does seem to
it, doesn't it?
It could have been done.
Okay.
Your order will be there
and they could give you this piece
right directly without asking your name
and everything. But
but what they generally do
is they ask you for your first
maybe rate your email,
your phone number, right.
All the things they ask, and then
they ask for this.
Do they really need all these things?
Do do we really need all these things
to make a bill?
To generate a bill?
No, but still.
But still.
They're taking this
this is the business. How?
Because they think that you didn't see it.
The intel, you didn't see it on your bill.
Right.
And they gives you this fine
Now, on this particular bill,
even if you don't have your name,
there will be having invoice number,
it will be having transaction IED.
If you made any online payment. Right.
It will be having order details,
the price of orders
and everything right
then where this information goods.
There's no question
you'll never find your email
ID or something great on your bill.
So what they generally do is
they are making their database,
they're increasing their database in here,
and they are just keep adding.
They are just keep adding
your data into the database.
So they would be having more data
because they that is a new good
information zation
right in today's generation.
So now people are spending
millions of dollars just to buy some data.
Correct.
So if the buy some data, they
can use this data for so many purposes.
For so many purposes, correct.
That's why that's why when you provide
your email in phone number.
Right.
Certainly on your birthday
or on your anniversary or on any day,
any nation holiday,
you get messages from Domino's.
They use it for marketing purposes.
The message to take would be,
we have this offer right in house.
You just come in,
there's often order online.
You get this offer getting.
So they use it for marketing purposes.
They just do mass meeting.
They just do bulk SMS to all the people.
And even if it converts by 1% or 2%
or 5% rate, it makes millions to them.
That's why
they generally get in this information.
And then wait, getting this information,
it costs nothing to them
because you're already their customer
is already here at their doorstep.
Customers.
Their customer is ordering something and
they are just collecting your information.
It is stored in their database
free of cost.
On one hand,
they are saving millions of dollars
on the hand
they are making millions of dollars.
Right.
Win win situation for Domino's
and for all the other franchisees.
Right.
So in this case, in this case,
this presentation
earlier, when we talk about this
presentation, they are right.
It is available there.
So now this guy who is standing
there is a blind right
who is providing your details of orders.
Right now.
The data goes to database via
some middleware.
Business logic is written over here.
So presently only available here
data available here, presentation
the application layer available
here, presentation layer available here.
Data layer available here right.
This part one.
This part one
can include in due arrangement.
That's why we call it to
the architecture.
Is it clear to everyone, any question
in this book what I just explained,
any question in this part?
No question of it.
One more example for to the architecture
and then we'll proceed further to it
because they're the same.
They are going to be here
because there are two levels.
The first is presentation in one place
and the second is
application and Italian it
another place is right.
So two layers.
Let's way
one more example.
Have you ever been to Barbican
or any of the restaurant
where they generally provide.
Right.
So when I brought to you.
And in that embed
they ask you to give them feedback.
It happens a lot nowadays.
People don't provide those, you know,
checks or bins or something like this.
So basically they give you one simple iPod
or I think their application opens.
You just need to select some radio
buttons, checkboxes and then you need
to make a visit
there.
So we provide feedback.
So in this case, then
you might have seen it page somewhere,
some Applebee's hazard
rate, some Applebee's having some good
we use have
great
the airport great
great the way airport also you see this
nice of them
fine so
now when you provide this detail right
think about this application.
Tell me can you access this application
for providing feedback in your phone. No.
Right.
Because this presentation
there is available in one place
in their own network.
Whenever you embed your data
in asked to your date of birth,
your marriage, anniversary date,
something like this,
it ask you to immolated.
It asked your name also
and then it gives you some evidence.
Homelessness are based reason was
the food was the ones their discipline
and every single thing rate
and then you provide
your rating on the label in whatever it is
and then you see So what happens
the moment you enter all these
onto the presentation layer, Right.
It goes to their database, right.
So according to the logic
which is available in application there,
according to the logic which is available
in this application, right.
This logic is what the logic information
goes and seals in their database.
And then the same logic applies
for marketing purposes, right?
So then you good messages, you get e
you get constant.
One more example of duty
architecture completion.
Is that clear? No
suitable.
Now let's talk about another one called
3D architecture
called 3D Architecture.
Great, simple.
In one year architecture,
we had presentation layer, application
layer, the Italian in one place
and do their architecture.
Weird presentation needed one place
application that indeed area
another place in 3D architecture.
We will be having presentation
layer it one place
application
layer one place data layer two.
And why is this so
and what are the examples of it?
This is what we need to demonstrate.
This is what we need to understand, right?
For example, here I go
and I open here
I open Amazon right?
They see Amazon here.
Okay, Now see
if I had ideas black shirt
and I search for black shirt.
Just a moment.
All right.
So now, now, here
you see right when go to this application.
Right.
And I search for the black shirt.
What is happening?
I did it on my presentation layer.
Correct. I'm representing layer.
Now, if I go
and this is Amazon, by the way,
I'm using great.
This is Amazon, by the way.
I'm using see,
I click on this particular one.
I opened it.
Now you see who is selling this?
Is this Amazon?
We're sending this?
No, it's cloud added, right?
Some X-Y-Z company. Right.
So let me
explain. Is the company is selling
now see the business.
You are here on your screen.
You searched for you search for work,
black shirt, Amazon,
Amazon is having your exportable
rate, Amazon
having your support,
and their business logic is redundant.
Okay.
If you search for black shirt here.
Right.
If you search here for black shirt
then what would happen?
You search for black shirt.
So now this Amazon is connected
with so many people.
It's connected with so many,
you know, merchants
who are selling their products via Amazon.
So it states that exist
and it captures their data
from all the people who have black
shirts available and provides it here.
Correct.
So now now this letter,
the logic is written and this data layer
where their data is available
can not be in the same place.
It cannot be the same place.
And the reason is very simple.
White cannot read the same place
because here, here this place is available
somewhere else and this data is available
somewhere as correct
correct guys,
because their data is coming
from multiple sources.
We have one Amazon so that in a group.
Great. Right.
So now you'll see.
Now you'll see this presentation it
another place application did it
another place data layer in another place
right data near it another place.
When we have this type of arrangement
we call it read the architecture.
Now this three year architecture examples
are Facebook,
Instagram, Amazon,
Skyscanner
is my trip.
Airbnb
and so many others and so many others are
guys truly therapeutic generators to
bring three data architecture in this.
Would everyone let's
let's go a step further
something very interesting.
If we expand
if we expand this 3D architecture,
it becomes it becomes
distributed architecture or we call it
and the Iraqi just what we call it,
the Iraqi
nature distributed architecture
or Indian architecture.
Now what is the meaning of this
entire architecture?
What is the meaning of this
distributed architecture?
Tell me one thing
Microsoft.
Microsoft is having a database, correct?
Let's consider this presentation layer,
this business layer,
application layer and this data layer.
Now tell me how much data Microsoft has?
A lot.
We don't even know how much data has rate.
Microsoft has in one server.
In one server, can Microsoft
put all their data store all their data
just in one server? No.
What would happen if it was all in one
sort of a server
is not capable to handle in a
just a moment.
No, no, no.
You not lost me.
Don't worry.
You don't lose me. I'm here to Silver.
It is just a bit
of history going on dates by
going to connect us.
Fine, fine.
So now you see presentation
layer, application layer data net rate.
Recently you might have heard the news.
Maybe.
I'm not sure
whether you guys heard about it or not.
Recently,
Google decided to change its data center
in India from Hadramout to Bangalore.
Wait, everybody is a place in India.
We call it cyber. Huh?
Now the new cyber
city of India is Bangalore because of
climatic conditions, right?
They decided to change their data center
from Hadramout to Bangalore.
Because Bangalore is more favorable.
Bangalore has more favorable
climatic conditions for the database.
Now the same problem rate
was heavy
with Microsoft as well in the US,
and they were spending billions of dollars
just to cool down their servers
because the amount of data
was so high, right?
The amount of data was so high
and they were not able to manage
those servers because they were,
you know, spending millions of dollars
just to cool them down so that engineers
subpoenaed data.
A guy from India. Right.
They're ingenious.
And the leader of those engineering
team has decided
and they came up with the strategy.
You know, what is that strategy?
They decided not to spend millions
and billions of dollars just to cool down
those servers and, you know, putting them
into cold room or something like this.
Instead, they found a location in the U.S.
They found a location in the U.S.
They're out one year, nine months,
nine months.
That's the climate is freezing.
The climate is very cold.
So they found that location in U.S.
Right now, what they do, generally,
they're they're
they're in good place and they hired.
Yeah, me I will tell you the name of it.
The zip code for
so now what they do generally what they do
generally is
they hired the complete lack of what
at the end the bond over there.
Let me show you this.
If you can.
You see this, everyone
think so.
What they did generally,
they hired this, you know
river the complete bond for 100 years
from the government.
They took it on lease basically.
Now already the climate is very cheap.
The climate is freezing
very cold at the place.
And if you talk about water,
it is just freezing rain.
This water temperature is very low.
So it cools down
your server automatically.
So what they do, what they did generally,
they created this type of,
you know, this capsule straight
and they placed their servers
inside this capsules and they put these
capsules down into the water.
You see they're putting down
all their capsules.
This here, this one, right.
They're having their server
like this their database.
So now my
if you're thinking I'm storing my flight
in Microsoft Cloud, but it is voting,
it is storing here in this particular
your flight is available in this river.
Can you see like this
That's how they seemed
millions of dollars
they saved millions of dollars.
You see
their data is available underwater.
So now next time next time,
if their database increased,
what they will do create one more capsule,
put it under the water.
Simply, they don't have to spend millions
and billions of dollars.
Right.
So now, because they're deep,
AI's available here doesn't mean
that the application logic
will also be available here.
Application
logic can be available at another place.
I need an example also,
but so now first let's sort out
this particular part data layer.
Work.
And as you guys this everyone understood
database part.
Let's come to our point.
So tell me one
system can have multiple database, right?
Multiple servers
relies coming from multiple sources.
Correct.
Similarly similarly
if we talk about application,
so tell me how many countries
we have on this planet,
how many countries we have known globally.
I'm taking your blood in the
knowledge hundred, 301 9200
2066206.
Earlier, it was 36 countries
really
to about Europe
to zero four was earlier.
I think the numbers was 204
and essentially two countries in Greece.
Right.
So it's two zero, I think.
So to zero six,
according to my knowledge, 207006.
These are the number.
So now now see, in every country
this book is available on
the Amazon is available in every country.
Yes, Amazon is available everywhere.
But tell me one thing.
If I open Amazon, right,
and if I go here, right.
You see these languages available?
These languages available, right.
Hindi, Tamil, Telugu
and Malayalam trade bundle up in Marathi.
These are some of our regional languages,
right?
These languages are available
only for Indian users.
But if someone tries
to access the same application
the same Amazon in U.S.,
will they be able to get
all these language options?
No. Right.
How is it possible that one application
in had multi functionalities
for different languages?
Remember one thing to operate
with in any country,
every application has to follow
the regulations
of the beginning nation Correct.
And then these regulations is different
for different countries.
Correct.
So this time the application
logic comes into the picture
where we have made
people application. Yes.
When we have multiple logics available.
Right.
So for example, in India
you have to provide this use,
you have to provide this China, provide
these European countries,
some native Sweden, provide this,
you provide this, Brazil,
provide this, Mexico, provide this right
lot of business logic.
So it was lot of business logic.
Now, wherever you are,
this is a presentation.
We're blank.
Whenever you are,
you let's log in from Brazil.
It connects you here, take your database.
What I'm connecting from India, connects
me here, District office and so on.
Right.
So you'll see application layer
there check by and B what is AP
IP? Yes, it's IP config going to IP
country.
Great.
So now now you see this presentation,
it is connected multiple application layer
and this multiple applications
layers are connected
with multiple data layers.
So when we have this multiple data layers,
multiple applications near a presentation
layers, right.
That are distributed to multiple places
and from those multiple places,
we are making one system,
this type of system
we call distributed architecture
and IT architecture or extended three tier
architecture, any question.
So for this
so far, so good.
Everyone
models, let's proceed further.
Now the question is fine.
Whatever the things
we are seeing here on UI,
it means on presentation
that thing is coming
from Italian, correct, from server.
So everything is from place to server,
data is coming from here and showing here.
Then why do we need this API?
What is the need
to test API?
The point then what do we need?
Why do we need to test APIs?
Very genuine question.
Right, Very genuine questions.
Fine.
Let me tell you this.
See why API testing.
So basically, basically
when we talk about three things
UI, we call it,
we call it front end development, right
at the same time someone works on
database, we call it back in development.
At the same time someone is calling.
If someone is working on middleware
also, right, That is also a development.
Now tell me
which language people
generally use to develop something,
but you develop with which language.
English language.
No. Yes.
They use either HDMI,
CSF, JavaScript
and Angular this language to use.
Right
for banking,
which language people generally use
for banking.
Java,
python, Ruby for shell JavaScript
swimming like known as well
estimators for printing. No.
And then you see assistance for printing
gasket extensions for banking.
There is no cases on HTML.
It's a hard core programing language
like Java C++.
By then it will be full shell.
These are the languages.
All right.
Similarly for middleware,
also some language.
Great. I don't know which language.
We also they use some language
for developing
three layers.
They are going to develop.
Three beams are going to work on this.
All these three teams are working on
different programing languages.
So you are let's
see if it is available in CCIS
or in Angular backend is available in Java
and is available in 18.
Now see to make this application working
to enable this
application first, what we have to do,
we have to connect these three layers
together to make it a single application.
So make it a final product.
We have to connect all these three things
together or not, and
we have to do it.
We have to connect all these three things
together.
Now I guess he is. No, ma'am.
You should believe it.
Without connecting,
there is nothing which is going to work.
Great.
So we have to connect.
We have to establish this connection.
All right.
If you don't connect
your database to your machine,
if you don't connect your database
to your application,
then what would happen in that case?
What would happen in that case, you would
not get anything on your application,
right?
If you don't connect your business logic,
no connection,
nothing is going to come
from the database.
Correct.
And no communication.
Fine. So no, no.
Remember one thing,
these are the limitations of application
that the applications which are developed
in different programing languages
cannot communicate to each other directly.
It is as simple as that.
If you know how to speak English
and if someone knows how to speak Italian
right, you cannot communicate
directly with that person.
Mean unless you know this language. Right?
Or you find some intermediate.
He doesn't know how to speak English.
You don't know how to speak Italian.
There is no communication at all. Right.
So you need someone
who can translate your message
and you can translate his message for you.
Right.
You need someone similarly here
also to check
whether these applications connected
develop in a different programing.
Languages are working correctly or not
and are able to communicate
with each other or.
Not we have to use one intermediate thing
and that intermediate
will pass on the information
will transmit the information from layer
to another layer to another layer,
because this part is API, right?
This part is API.
Understood, right?
More clear example is Skyscanner.
Maybe Skyscanner used an angular, Angular
and some other
and then it connects with data airlines.
So maybe data is using, let's say, Java,
how these two applications
are connecting together,
how these applications are communicating
with each other when they're developing
different programing languages, using APIs
using it, right?
So now why API distinct is important.
See here, firstly, to make systems
developed in different languages
to communicate.
Second thing for security reasons
also, right,
Because no one wants
to share their database with anyone.
I give you the example of data
and I give you the examples of Etihad.
I give you the example of Qatar Airways.
They don't want to share their database
with you.
Instead, they
but they are ready to give you
the only piece of information
which you need based on your query.
Correct.
So now if you have an API, then
you have this facility, but you can share
just one piece of information
and not the complete information.
You just share one piece of information.
And that would be more than enough.
That would be more than enough, Correct?
Is this correct based?
So security also maintains this
posting.
It enables us to communicate
among the people applications
developed in different
programing languages right now.
See now see what is happening.
What is happening here?
My Do we need to use this particular part?
For example, let's say
now going to book the ticket from New York
to Mumbai, from New York to open it,
she would indicate,
and she got one DNA number after booking.
And the Vienna number is one, two, three
at the same time.
At the same time, someone booked a ticket
from Kiev, Ukraine, right.
To, let's say,
someone critical from Ukraine to
the U.S., like New York.
She also got the same
be another one, two, three.
How is that possible that for two different bookings people got simply enough
people got simple enough.
How is it possible
is there any issue with their database?
No databases,
just giving you the information okay,
this is your data
is that initial with the presentation
there
no presentation
that is just showing you the things.
Is that initial with the logic?
No, there is no issue the logic either
because logic says
if you book a ticket,
we will provide you be in a database.
This all right,
this is the business ticket
and provided there, what is the problem?
There is a glitch.
There is a glitch in a buy
rate,
different database for different person.
No such one database for all people.
Glitch in the API.
How glitch in the API?
It's very simple, but
when we talk about a glitch in the API,
always remember one thing, right?
That API is not able to get
the exact updated data
from their database.
It simply goes there right.
If there is a glitch in the API,
it simply goes here.
Great.
Fix their data
but their data is not get updated.
So the previous data only issues on
to the application.
According to the logic,
we will show you data.
So trade according to the database,
we will send you their data.
It is also right
according to the presentation,
it says we will show you the data.
It will show you the data,
but your logic is correct.
Presentation
there is correctly data player is correct.
Who is the culprit?
Culprit is your API,
which is not upgrading the data.
So that's why two people can get saved
for different bookings.
That's why we need to test API
to make sure
that data transmission of data
transfer of data is going smoothly or not
industrial.
This part
on this
is the booking reference.
No, it doesn't update the data.
It makes the data updated data.
IPS translating one programing language
of a server to another.
No, no, no.
I never said
this API is not going to translate
or convert or translate
any programing language, right?
It provides that chunk of chunk of right.
It provides a chunk of information
in machine
readable
form, right in machine readable form.
And then it converts
this chunk of information
that is no translator translator
I just gave you.
I just gave you the example of that.
Yes, it is it is a at basically
it getting information here in this book.
Normally it has to be in the.
Yes. When normally it has to be unique
and generally it is unique.
But if your API is, then definitely
it gives you this kind of situation, but
it generates do the same reference number
for two different bookings
already.
So for
any question, why do we need to test
API domain
then the security to enable the system
so that they can communicate
with each other right.
With each other?
It connect now.
Now let's talk about
let's talk about the last portion
of explanation we will use.
Postman only.
Yes, sir.
We will use Postman only contact.
So now the last point of this class.
Then I'm going to explain.
See here,
let me open our application right.
This is our application, right?
Tell me
when we perform any type
of operation in this application,
what are the things we do generally
in any application?
What are the things we do?
Clicking
search
request.
Just click
first log in by credentials.
Okay.
See, browse, request log in served.
Okay, let me ask.
It's talk about some
high level of information.
Typing something,
log in something clicking
something, browsing something.
These are very low level information rate,
very a ground level information.
I'm talking about high level information,
the scope of this thing,
the scope of this to to best any software.
Right.
What are the operations we need
to think about adequately this
either
we read the information
from start of
our database,
either retrieve some information
from the database.
For example, let's see,
I click on employee list
and it throws me out
every time it happens to me.
Whenever I try to log
into this application includes me
or we send it to database.
Fine.
So first first high level of information,
I'm telling you.
So when I'm checking the
who creates wanted times, this
right So
now now you see right now you see here
we include so now you see here
all this data is coming from this
and media is
their data is coming from their database.
But now when you are actually searching
for an employee here,
for example, this one,
if you are searching for an employee here
using this particular I.D..
Right.
What would happen in that case?
It gives you the data.
It gives you the data
for this particular employee.
Correct.
For this particular employee,
it gives you that data.
So you will be able to see that database,
right?
Correct.
No, it could be multiple ways.
You want to search one employee.
You can search one employee.
You want to search all the employees
you can search all the employees.
You want to see the leave calendar.
You can see the need in calendar.
You want to see whatever
the things you can see everything here
by our database.
So you are leaving the information
from the database and verifying it.
It means getting the information,
verifying the information.
All the things cover in just one part,
this part retrieving the information,
correct.
Guys, please.
Correct.
A lot.
Second thing, you are
adding some information
in there, database or server.
You add some information
in there, database of server.
For example, click on an employee.
Go here.
Right. Gave
one saved
employee generated
and began a scan of
Who is this bug?
Well right.
So we created
we created an employee, right?
The moment we created an employee,
what what does it mean?
It simply means we have added some pieces
of information in the database,
then added some of information
in the database
more than we did this right.
Similarly, if we are applying for leave,
if we are going to assign some data
to someone, some information to someone,
we are simply adding
some pieces of information
in the existing database.
So it means creating a data
or adding a new record in the database
or start over and then verify it.
That is the second option.
That is the second operation.
The third operation,
the third operation Create.
The third operation
we do is delete something.
We delete the information
from the database, from the database,
or someone tried to delete
this information from their database.
What sort of innovative right
is this correct.
Right.
Whatever the data is available there,
I just deleted three employees.
So what I did, I deleted some information
from the database.
I deleted
some information from the database.
Right.
And then then the last operation,
the last operation we perform is,
we just update some information.
We just obtained some information
in database,
in database or settlement activity place.
So basically, on a high level,
if we talk about the operations
we perform, so we perform one operations,
we perform
simply creating a record in the database,
retrieving the record from the database,
updating the record in the database,
deleting the record from the database.
These operations
we call create operations,
which we generally perform in in U.S.
history
in the United States, using
which tool Selenium
VM menu connect.
Yes, correct.
But it is operating.
There is is this period.
This is one level.
Let's talk about another element
I have seen recently.
You guys have completed your sequel part
my sequence, right.
The database part.
What is the joint?
What is intercalated,
why we grew by.
See, no one is going to take
that.
I just wanted to check
whether you guys are still awake or not.
What was the last one?
Group by
group By order
by there is are the keywords distinct?
Right.
These are things you generally use
while making your select quality.
I don't know the database, you guys.
No database.
I don't know.
We're looking for collection of data.
Okay, fine.
Let's come here.
Now, see, in database
you use my equal, which
if I'm not wrong,
my second will be trained right.
Some query like this, the leg
stuff from
employee data we have.
Employee I.D.
is equal to this data.
And then you selected there is an option.
You run it
and you get the data for this in
something like this.
This is you select
what is equal query there.
So you rate
now see what are the things you perform
here.
Also,
you are retrieving the information
from the database,
getting
you can object to the information
also here or not.
And me,
you can delete a record also here or not.
Tell me
and you can add
or create a record from here or not
because
for things
to retrieve, update, delete and error
or create records,
these four things
trade
create operations.
Again,
you are performing grade operations again.
You are performing
using your database, right?
So now if we talk about the UI
part credit operations,
if we talk about banking part
that is database credit operation.
So there is a middleware
where we are going to test API.
So what we are going to API,
what we are going to test in API is
we are going to perform same operations.
Then my board, the aims are showing me
create operations right
then It is very simple that I'm going
to describe the operation in API.
Also, it has nothing to do with DreamBox
testing.
Alex is white box, black box, gray box.
It has nothing to do with this.
Okay, so we hear great operations.
Either we create the data
or we retrieve the data or we update the
data, or we believe the data
rate.
Right, guys?
Yep. Yep.
So these are before things.
These are the four things
we are going to perform, right?
The entire API is doing
is all about thread operations.
That's it.
That is the FBI is all about
that is nothing else in the API.
There's the whole explain mission of API
in real life, practical, laid back
niggly architecture wise
how things work,
what the operations we perform.
By any question so far in this book,
was it clear, was it understanding
and interesting as well?
And is it right?
I'm telling you, I'm telling you just
just spent some time with this.
Now tell me, after three out of Bece
now, how many of you guys
is still not aware of you?
Yeah, well,
what grade I gave you the business idea.
Also, is there anyone who still understand
what is API in how API
see Zima? No.
Silva. Elena.
Anna,
where were you guys?
Where are you now? Fine.
And then I came to the picture.
Yeah. Yeah. That one is missing, correct?
Correct. And.
All right, guys.
In tomorrow's class, right, Right.
You can take.
Right.
Nothing is
excellent, Silva.
You're learning.
I see. Right.
So tomorrow's class,
we will see how we are going
to make all of these things,
how we are going to make that request.
What is the request?
Actually, What are the things?
What does DNS help?
We generally provide a lot of things,
lot of things on the right.
And also, meanwhile,
I will share one video right
from that video you can see
how we can download the post to it.
So guys, please download the postman.
Right? I would share the video.
It's really easy process.
Even if you write, just download
Postman right.
You will get it.
It is an extension
also available with Chrome
so you get the postman from there.
Also, I don't think that you need video,
but yes, still I will give you the video
so that it will help you
and stay with message in practice no more.
But if you if give up this early
based on just one day view
play,
do you really think that your thought
this cannot
many people will see like okay
you can't do this explain
things are very difficult find
because things are difficult
that's fine here
otherwise it would be done
by someone else.
Right. I think I will definitely share
that with you.
Don't worry about it.
I will definitely share the video.
It also I'm going to update the slides
for today's class.
Okay.
So you go there.
Yeah. At the same rate.
So you go there
and you can use them as that happens.
Point great.
So here right now, because we are not
using this part intelligently, right?
I'm not going to push any because that is
the only thing we have is just our slides.
So I will put the slides
and the ones to start writing of the post.
We read on question
everything that you will be have,
you'll be having every single thing
in your postman except
on this.
Bob I think I'm done for my sake
for today's class.
If you guys have any question
you may ask or else we can do.