Hey, guys, Can everyone see me?
Can everyone hear me?
Okay.
Okay,
good.
All right, guys, let's get started.
I hope everyone is doing great
and everyone can see me
and everyone can hear me fine.
All right.
Let's see.
We have a good amount of people.
So how is everybody doing, guys,
What's going on?
I hope
everyone was having fun with the
with the homework.
I'm good. Thank you.
Tired.
Okay.
We're.
We're halfway done. Right, guys?
So when do you guys start?
You know, starting June.
July. Okay.
Yeah, Almost halfway, right?
Almost halfway.
Done.
There's three more months left, so
let's push it.
Guys.
Don't get tired.
I know a lot of people will get
a little bit
overwhelmed
towards the end,
but don't give up, guys, because that's
going to be a lot of information. So
no social life with syntax?
Well, yeah, I'm in six months, guys.
Okay, so only six month of commitment.
And after that you find a job and then
your social life will get back to you.
Okay, So just keep trying.
Let's not give up.
Okay, guys, we're almost there.
And the window windows.
Okay.
Only with Firefox works.
I think you're talking Andre.
You're talking about the last tab, right?
When you open the last tab,
is it where the issue is?
Okay. Yeah.
So if you open the last tab, it's.
It's how it is configured.
So I want to I wanted to to see
if you can handle this kind of
issues.
So that's why I gave it to you
that, that homework.
So let's go ahead here.
If you if you open up this
there is an h html in here
but it's a bit different
than than the other windows.
But if you open up this window,
you can see there's an actual
what's
called there's an actual view around here.
Okay.
So if you see in here, there's
no you around.
So it's just an h HTML document in here
over the homework.
I think you guys are going
to be going over over that tomorrow.
If I'm not mistaken.
Okay.
So this the this one,
this works in Firefox.
I'm not sure why,
but I'm assuming this is how the
how the tab is configured itself.
But developers.
Okay. And also,
whenever you're dealing with with Windows,
you won't be handling this kind of windows
unless you're opening a document.
Okay.
And if you open a document, a new tab
during the automation,
you should be doing that manually.
Describe the difference.
So you could take a look at the
what's
called we could take a look at the URL.
So there is an actual euro here
which navigates to this page.
Okay.
But here it's it's nothing in here.
Okay,
So it's there's nothing in here.
So that means
this is not a link or anything.
Okay.
So it doesn't
you don't I don't think you even need
an Internet to open this.
Okay, So this is how it is.
So this is just an H HTML file.
This is this is an email file as well,
but it's connected to a link.
Okay.
Any suggestion to your question?
Oh, let me see.
Where is your question? File
the main page title.
Okay.
Is there anyone else having issues
with title sites?
I mean, not
including the last tab guys.
Okay, so there are people who completed
the homework, not including the last tab.
Guys.
You should be able to get the text
and the title.
Okay. So please take a look at this.
I think people share the homeworks
and the syntax.
Students okay,
So please take a look
at that and communicate with each other.
Okay, guys.
But as I said, guys, the last the last one
here, the last tab.
If this is not working in Chrome,
you don't have to worry about it.
Okay?
I knew it's not going to be working
anyways.
Any other questions, guys?
Okay, so seems like no other questions.
So let's do a quick recap, guys.
What we've done so far yesterday.
What did we cover yesterday, guys,
we know handles, right?
So what we did is we will learn
how to manipulate the windows, right?
Switch to them
and then perform some actions.
Right. So
so we use
we said we use two different methods,
which is we get window
handle and get window handles.
Right.
So before we dive in there,
what is the window handle
itself, guys?
It's a unique idea.
Okay, For what?
Unique idea for what guys?
Unique idea.
Which holds the address of the tab. Right.
So how many how many characters
are in there?
It's approximately 40. Right? Almost 40.
Like alphanumeric
character idea.
Right.
Okay, good.
So where do we store the
if I get if I get all the window
handles, guys,
where do we store
in a set?
Right.
So what do we know about sets, guys?
Why do we stored in this set?
Because you want to keep unique,
unique elements
only inside that container, right?
There is no duplicates in there.
But there is one more thing in set, guys.
So what's the order in the hash set?
You guys, It's random, right?
But yesterday when we when we were trying
to do four different, when we were trying
to manipulate for different windows,
how do we know
which one is what
if it's jumping on on the random
order? How do we know that
by the handle name.
Okay,
okay.
We use iterator. Okay.
But what if it doesn't
get stored in in insertion order?
Guys, how come that it's.
It's going from the first
to the second from the second and third,
and then from the third to the fourth?
Any guesses on that?
Because of alphanumeric IDs? Not really.
What do we have inside the set interface?
Guys?
What is
what classes do we have under the set
interface?
Okay,
so hash set linked, hash
set and a tree set.
Right.
Which one supports
the insertion order guys
linked hash set.
Right.
So let's go ahead here.
So whenever you store all the window
handles inside the set, guys,
it automatically converted to linked
hash set.
Okay.
So just in case
you get these kind of questions
in the interview.
So if you get this kind of question
saying that, hey, it's a set,
it doesn't support any insertion order
or it's random,
so you can just tell them, Hey, whenever
I store all the window
handles inside the set, it automatically
returns me a linked hash set.
Okay. By default. Exactly.
All right, cool.
What else did we cover, guys?
Synchronization. Right.
So what are we trying to
synchronize in here?
Guys,
when we run, when we execute our code,
when we execute our selenium code,
when we're performing
something on the website,
what are we trying to synchronize
the speed,
the speed of what
components?
What are those components,
what it would trying to level.
Okay.
Web page and what
exactly.
So the speed of our code
and the page load right.
Because our our code doesn't wait
for something to appear on the web page.
Right.
So when you start your execution,
no matter
what's going to happen,
it's going to run until the end.
Or if it fails, it's
going to just terminate everything.
But it's not going to wait for your page
load,
for your elements to load
until you specify.
So, okay,
so we are synchronizing the execution
of our script and the page load.
Okay.
And what kind of wait
did we go over last class
implicit way?
Right. Okay.
So what do we know about implicit.
Wait, guys.
Okay,
It's usually set to 20 seconds, right?
It's a global wait, right?
What else
is the web driver to wait for?
Send amount of time.
Okay,
So what is it going to look for, guys?
So you set your implicit wait, right?
How many times can we set it exactly?
It's only written once.
Right.
So what is he going to get?
What is it going to look for? Guys?
So we set an implicit rate
right?
This program runs faster.
Okay.
No, but what is he going to wait for?
For 20 seconds, guys?
So I said my implicit way for 20 seconds.
What is it for exactly?
It's for finding the elements, right?
The elements where we're looking for.
Exactly.
So whenever we set it for 20 seconds,
we try to find something, right?
It our implicit way comes there.
Okay?
So if it finds that element in 5 seconds,
the rest of the time is getting ignored
and we're moving on to the next action
or to the next line of the code.
Okay.
All right, good.
Any questions, guys?
Yep. If it didn't find that element in 20
seconds, then we're getting exception.
Right?
So we're getting
in no such element exception.
Okay, guys,
any questions?
All right,
So today, what we're going to be doing,
we will be covering explicitly
where we'll be covering Sloane weight
and we will be covering
how to handle the web tables.
Okay. So
all right, So let's start
with the implicit weight here.
Implicit weight, right.
And we set that it will be
applied for
finite element methods, right?
Because we're trying to find something.
It's it's going to be waiting
for some elements to locate.
Right? Yep.
We just started now.
We're already in class eight,
and I think we already we all only have
like I think 11 processes
and in me mistake.
Okay so for more
with today's class. Okay
All right so explicit weight
or in other words, it's
called web driver weight.
Okay.
What do we know about explicit
weight, guys?
Anyone did research on this?
It's smarter
than its implicit weight. Okay.
In what way?
So it waits for a certain amount of time
and certain condition, Right.
So basically, for explicit weight,
you explicitly set a weight that needs
to wait for a certain amount of time
and a certain condition.
Okay.
And it can be applied
only for a specified element.
Absolutely right.
That's very good.
Okay.
So let's put it in here.
Web driver weight
is used to tell the web driver to wait
for a certain
condition.
Okay.
Before
throwing
a specified
conditions exception
for throwing an exception.
Exception for a specified condition.
Okay.
So we set that we are
explicitly right.
We're explicitly
said a wait for certain condition
and for a certain amount of time.
Okay.
So explicit weight, guys.
It works with expected conditions, class.
And as we set and waits until
the sun conditions are met
or the given time is achieved.
Okay.
So if the given time is achieved already
and the expectations
or the conditions are not met,
then you will be getting an exception.
Okay.
Most of the time you will be
getting element, not visible exception.
Okay.
So explicit
weight works with
the conditions class.
Okay.
And waits
until certain
conditions are met
or the given time is achieved.
Okay.
So any questions in here, guys?
No questions.
All right.
So let me go ahead and create
another package.
And here
and I will create a new
Java class.
So. Okay,
So let me see
this.
Okay.
So what we are going to be doing,
we will be navigating here
and what we're going to do,
we will click on the get new user.
Okay.
So when I click on this,
you see it's loading
and there is someone popping up in here
with a first name and the last name.
Okay, So let me sent the
link to you.
Okay.
So what we're going to
do, we're going to wait for those elements
in here and we're going to verify
that those elements are present in here.
Okay.
Any questions, guys?
I'm assuming there's no questions,
right, guys?
Okay, good.
All right.
So let's continue in here. Okay.
So let's go
have a
copy this here.
And let me actually update
the overall.
All right.
So we're navigating there.
So what is our next step, guys, in here?
What I need to do
explicitly right away
so we navigate it here, guys,
what do we need to do first?
We need to find the element, right,
that we're going to need to click on
first, right?
So let's inspect this page
and click on this.
All right.
So there is an ID for this, right?
So let's use
this ID, I'm going to copy this.
Go back and create a web element in here.
That user button
driver's find element
by ID.
Is this here
right.
And what we need to do,
we need to simply click on this at that.
So now what I want to do,
I want to get this first name in here
and then print it out in my console.
Okay, So how do we want to do this?
We need to put the implicit word
before performing the action.
Yes, it will work.
It's going to work the same because we're
just trying to find this element in here.
Right.
But I'm going to explain the difference
between implicit and explicit word
right after this.
What's called example. Okay.
So here we won't be using
we won't be using an implicit
wait for now.
And then I'll go over the differences
between implicit and explicit
and then it's going to be more
clear for you.
Okay.
All right.
So I clicked on this
get new user button in here.
So what happened with
I want to get this first name
and then print out inside my console.
Okay. So let's actually first
identify this
element and create an X path for this.
Okay.
So what I'm going to do here
is, okay, okay.
So let's go ahead and see where it is.
Okay?
So it's inside the okay, that's fine.
So what if I want to use this P only guys,
what was that P standing for? Guys
paragraph.
Right. Okay, good.
So what I want to do guys,
there is an idea in here
we can probably use this, but I want to
use this P and create an X path for this.
How do we want to come up
with an X path for us? So
okay, so following siblings.
Okay, what else?
Why do we want to use the following
sibling guys in here?
We could just use text. Right?
This is a simple text right?
Guys?
So what I'm going
to do and do double slash
P, right?
And then there's a text in here
is equal to
first name
or right.
What happened
is in a unique enough case, right? Yep.
So it is unique.
So if I click on the get user again, guess
what happened?
It changes the user every time, right?
So what can we use in here
in order to keep our x
path dynamic? Guys
we can use contains
and what's the part that we taken in
our X path
guys only that first name, right?
Absolutely right.
So what I will do in here,
I'll go ahead and do contains
open the parentheses,
close it here
and what I can do I can remove this.
What's wrong in here, guys?
Why is this not detecting it
using contains using the first name.
Why is this
not working?
Exactly. There's no equal sign.
We need to put a comma in here.
Right. So. Okay.
So now
we use contain. So
I'm getting a new user here.
It's still one of one, right?
Because we don't really care
what name actually popping up.
We care about this element
which we identified by using contents.
Okay, So this is the beauty
of keeping the x dynamic
or identifying your elements as dynamic
because you get the constant part of it
and you don't really care
what the dynamic part
because you can still identify it
with one single X path.
Okay.
All right.
So let me copy this. Right.
But this element doesn't pop up right
away.
Right?
So what we can do, let's actually before
we wait for that element, what I want to
do, I want to identify this element
and I want to print that text.
Okay.
So let's the web element.
First name, right, is equal to driver
find element by
export.
Right?
And then what I want to do, I want to just
print out the text.
Right.
So if I run this, this is going to fail
because it's waiting
for one or 2 seconds
to in order to pop up that element.
Right.
So what I'm going to do here,
I will set a weight,
but I will set a weight specifically
for this element, which is first name.
Okay.
So what I'm going to do in order for us
to use an explicitly what we need to do,
we need to create an object of the web
driver weight.
Okay, So what I will do here,
I'll create an object.
What type of weight?
Weight is equal to new
web driver weight?
Okay,
so I'm going to close this statement.
So it's throwing out some errors.
It's not compiling because it's X,
It's right now, it's waiting for us
to pass some arguments in there.
Okay.
So it's it's waiting for us to pass
two different arguments in here.
So one of them is going to be
that object of our web driver.
So we need to let this guy know in here
saying that, say selenium,
that we using a web driver
and this is our object.
In this case,
the object that we're using is driver.
Okay.
And then the second thing that we need
to pass in here, the waiting time.
Okay, So the waiting time is going
to be in seconds right away.
Okay. So I would set it for 20 seconds
and you can see that
it's time out in 20 seconds.
Okay. E,
this gets
okay, guys, I
need you to be more active, okay?
Because I don't really know
what is going on.
If you guys are typing.
So let's stop typing.
Okay?
Okay, cool.
All right,
So we created an object of the web driver.
Wait here.
We saying that, hey, this is a driver
that I'm running everything with,
and this is the amount of weight
that I will be waiting for.
So now we created a weight,
but we don't know
what is the condition
that we need to wait for.
Okay, So right now
I'm going to use this weight object
that I created and do wait until.
Okay, so I'm
waiting until all some conditions. Right.
And as I said before, weight.
What type of weight is using
the expected conditions?
Class?
Okay, so inside the parentheses,
what I need to do, I need to pass
the expected conditions that we want to
wait for.
Okay. So what I will do,
I will pass here.
As you can see, expected
conditions, class.
And when I press that in here,
you can see there's
different
different different conditions in here.
So visibility of element alert is present.
There's title right
elements selection, state
element
to be clickable, element to be selected.
So there's a lot of different
different methods that we want to use.
There's different conditions
that we need to use. Okay.
So in this case,
what are we trying to wait for guys?
So I'm trying to wait for that element.
But what is the actual condition
that I'm waiting for?
Guess
to be found or what else, guys?
So if we if we are.
Exactly.
We're talking about the visibility, right?
So we want that element to be visible
on the page first.
Right? So what we can do here,
so we can use
visibility of element locator.
Okay.
So I'm going to choose this method. Okay.
So now inside this parentheses,
I need to specify the locator that I am
finding this element.
Okay.
So you can do by or we can do by X path
as we already did in here.
Okay, so I'm going to copy this X path
we already found in here
and I will place it in here.
Okay? Is that clear, guys?
Any questions in here?
So it's okay. That's fine.
All right, so here again,
guys, on line 21,
I am creating an object of web drive.
Await. Okay.
Telling that, hey, this is my driver,
that I'm running everything
and I'm setting the weight for 20 seconds.
Okay?
And then what I'm doing here, I'm waiting
until I meet the expected conditions.
Okay?
Once these conditions
are met, I will go ahead
to the next line and perform my action.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys?
All right, so now let me run this
with work until.
Yes, we will be using expected conditions.
Yes, I'm running this.
So let's see.
Okay.
Waiting for this.
And then you can see in here,
it's printed out.
First name is Hector.
Okay.
So headed here.
This guy is printed out
inside our console.
Right.
So now, guys, the difference
between implicit and explicit.
Okay, so when you set an implicit weight,
it's only working
with find element, right?
So whenever your
your element is not found, it's
going to throw you an exception.
Right.
And here as well, you can use the implicit
way it's going to wait for 20 seconds
until it finds that element
and print out the text in here as well.
But the difference between implicit
and explicit weight is
in the conditions.
Okay, So in implicit, what you're
only waiting for the element to be found.
Okay.
But in the explicit way you're
setting different conditions,
you waiting for different conditions
specifically for that, for this
or that element.
Okay.
So sometimes
when you set an implicit weight
and you don't set the explicit weight
so you can find an element,
but it might not be visible.
Okay.
Or you can find an element, but
it might not be enabled to click on it.
Okay, So implicit weight
will only help you to find the element.
It's not going to tell you, okay,
I found the element, but it's enabled
or disabled.
Okay, so this is the difference
between implicit and explicit weight.
Okay.
Any questions on this this? Yes.
With explicit weight
you use and a specific element, right.
A specific element to perform action
or to wait for certain conditions.
Okay.
Not very clear.
What's the confusion?
If you have any questions, guys,
type it in.
Seems like you guys are so passive today.
I don't know what's going on.
It's either you guys are tired
or you don't understand anything
or you understood everything.
All right, It's all okay.
All right, let me see.
I had another task.
And here.
It's all right.
So let me see.
Okay, guys, here's the task for you.
Okay?
Give 5 minutes to complete this task.
Okay, So I want you to navigate
here, wants to click start.
Okay.
So it's going to load in here,
and I want you to verify
that this text is appeared in here.
Okay.
Explicit word.
You can be more specific
on what exactly. Yes.
So you are more specific.
You are explicitly setting a condition.
All right.
Is the task clear, guys,
I'm going to copy this length for you.
I'm going to send it to me.
Okay.
There you go. So you have it in
live chats.
Okay.
5 minutes to complete that task
and we'll do it
together.
And no one else done except exceptional.
Then I think this is the only one done now
you've probably copied
and pasted in right?
Yeah.
It's done.
Good.
It hasn't.
It's not 5 minutes.
Yes. Yes.
We've done
all. All right, that's good.
Okay, guys.
So let's do it together now.
Okay, So let me actually grab this
here.
And I think we need to take this.
Okay, So I have the URL.
What is my next step, guys?
Okay.
Help me out to finish this task, guys.
So I'm navigating to this URL.
What am I doing next?
Okay, we need to locate the button, right?
So we need to locate this start button.
All right, so let's inspect and see here
what we have.
Okay, I have an idea.
Okay, so let's use a CSS selector.
Let's use a CSF selector
with the shortcut.
What was the shortcut for idea
in CSS selector guys?
Hashtag or a pound key. Right. Okay. Good.
Nice. Okay.
Okay. That was probably
autocomplete.
Right.
Okay.
All right, guys.
So double slash, right with CSV selectors,
and then I have a tag.
What's my tag, guys?
Button. Okay, button.
And then
the pound key in here.
I'm copying and pasting the idea here.
Why is it why it didn't work?
What's going on?
No, double slash. Exactly. There we go.
So in CSV,
we don't start with double slash, right?
Okay, so we found this.
Let's go back to our script and start
storing this inside the variable.
All right, well, element start button
is equal to driver dot find element
by csv selector and let's face it in here
and then start button that click.
Okay. All right.
So we know there is some some time
that we need to wait for, right?
So let me click on this.
It's loading.
All right.
A couple seconds in here
and what it does, and then we can see this
text.
So let's
identify this text as well.
So let me
leave this
identify this again.
Okay.
So what can we identify this by, guys?
How do we identify these elements?
I mean, this element
by text.
Okay.
Do you want
is it possible to identify by latex?
Good.
Yes. Now, there is no length, right?
There's no. And a tag, guys.
So that's why we won't be able
to identify this by link text.
Please pay attention.
Right.
So there is a different tag in here.
Okay, So what we can do,
we can use the text, right?
We can use the contains
because our tax is too long in here.
Right.
And there's one more thing
that I want to show you.
So let's identify this by.
Our tag is age four.
What does this age stand for, guys?
Head right okay
so I'm going to be using contains in
here contains the text right
And our text is
welcome.
Right. Okay.
All right, guys.
So there's one more thing
that I want to show you.
So most of the time on the on the Web
pages, guys, on the Web
page is what happens
whenever you see this H1, H2, H3,
They may get changed
during the development of the application.
Okay.
So headers
I usually get changed to like if
if this header is edge for right now,
it might get changed to age
three or age five.
It's up to the development team.
Okay,
so most of the time they get changed.
so you don't want to use this edge for H2
or header tab in general.
Okay.
So what you can do instead,
you can put a wild card in here
which identifies
any tags inside the edge, HTML.
Okay.
What you can do, you can simply put an
asterisk in here
and you can see that it is a wild card
it identifies any
what's called any tag name.
It can be replaced with any tag.
Okay. Is that clear, guys?
This star or asterisk is a wild card.
Okay, so let's use this.
So what I'm going to do,
I'm going to copy this
and I'm going to go back here.
No, not for CSS selectors, guys.
It's only applicable to Xbox.
I'll put it in the note.
Okay,
so let's identify this element first.
Okay.
So where element
welcome is equal to driver
find element
by x pass and let's start in here
and then what we're going to do
just in driver
click.
Okay, so let's go to our notes and
X Path is a
wild card which
can identify
any tag name
and we can just put this example in here.
Okay.
By I.D.
the correct to use the ID.
So let's check.
You can use the ID,
but if you get the text,
it might not return to the text.
Okay. So
you got the text.
Okay, then that's fine.
Then. It's fine.
Okay.
So let's go back
to the text.
Okay, guys.
So now what we need to do,
we found that element.
We're trying to get that text,
but before we do that,
what we need to do,
we need to wait, right?
We need to wait because it takes some
some seconds to load that element.
Okay.
So what I'm going to do here, I will be
creating a web type of weight
object right?
Grab. Wait, wait is equal to a new
web drive weight.
And now here what we need to do,
we need to specify what our Web driver is
and how many seconds we want to wait for.
Right.
So the first one is driver object in here
and we want to wait for 20 seconds.
Okay.
So now in here, what we can do,
we can wait
until our expected conditions are met,
Right?
Expected conditions
for visibility of the element located.
Right.
So and then
located or locating this by X path.
And we'll store this in here.
Right. Okay.
If you didn't get the text,
send us the code.
Let's see what what did you have?
Is it the CSeries or Express?
What did we identify our
this element guys with.
What's the locator?
We're waiting for this text. Right?
We're not waiting for the button to appear
or to be visible.
Right.
So that's why
we need to put an X passing here.
All right, So let's run this
and see what's going to happen
or be clicked.
There we go.
So it printed the text
and it quit the browser.
Any questions, guys?
Okay.
So, Masood, you said you created
a web type of wait, but you didn't
you didn't set the expected conditions
like I have on line 22.
You only have this web drive.
Wait.
Okay,
So set a condition after this
and then you will get the text.
All right.
So no question, it seems
everything is good, right?
So let's see.
So that's about it for explicit
waits, guys.
So I'll give you some homework later on
and you will be
doing a lot of weight in there.
Okay.
But let me actually
that's
okay.
A lot of waiting. Yes.
Okay.
So now let's go
over the fluent weight, guys.
Okay. So
slow and
wait, guys, what do we know about Sloane?
Anyone did a research on Sloane
Wade's guys
is romantic.
Yes, it's.
It's slightly waiting.
Right.
You didn't.
Okay, that's fine.
All right, guys.
So the fluid weight, right?
So the fluid weight is considered
as a global weight
as well as the implicit weight.
Okay.
So but it's used a little bit differently.
So Sloane Way
is used to tell the web driver
for certain condition
as well as its frequency.
Okay.
Before throwing any exceptions.
So I'll explain to you
what kind of frequencies we have
and we'll see what that means.
Okay.
So let's put in here.
Let's actually put it
is global weight as well.
And it is used to tell
Web driver to
wait for
certain
condition
as well as
its frequency
before
following and accepting.
Okay.
All right.
So let's go ahead
and see how it actually looks like.
Okay.
So I'm going to create a new class here
and say fluent
Demo.
All right.
So for the main method in here,
so the fluid weight before we get into it.
Okay, so the fluent weight is a little bit
outdated, guys.
Okay, So the fluid weight is not
that used in a real world right now.
Okay.
So in my project and the previous project
that I've worked on,
we don't really have the font weights
in our framework.
Okay.
So fluid weight is has a little bit
of different syntax and usual weights.
Okay.
So implicit weight and you just set it
once inside your execution and that's it.
And then explicit weights. What you do is
you explicitly
waiting for some elements to appear
or to be visible
to be this display to enable or disable
it doesn't really matter.
Right?
So here what happens is
we're looking for some frequencies
you can do,
you can set some timeouts,
you can set some polling time,
and you can ignore some exceptions
with fluent weights.
Okay, So this is how it looks like
we won't be doing any tasks with it
because
it's not really used in the real world.
Okay, So what I'm going to do here,
I'm going to create
an object of the web driver, okay?
Travel driver is equal to new prime
driver.
Okay, So and then I'll start
creating my float weight.
Okay.
So this is how this looks like.
Okay, wait in here.
So this is a web driver weight as well.
And I'm creating a new object in here.
Okay. New
flowing weight.
Okay, So inside the fluent weight,
we should be
mentioning the work driver in here.
Okay.
And now what we can do,
we can start performing our actions.
We can start
there's no set property
because we won't be running anything.
Okay?
I just want you to see
how the fluent weight looks like.
Okay?
And what kind of actions
you can perform with this.
Okay.
First of all, you can do with
with the float weights.
Okay, before we get into that,
you need to set the driver in here.
Okay.
So now what you can do,
you can set a timeout.
Okay.
So usually when you set an implicit
weight, how many how many
seconds you get a timeout
with 20 seconds.
Right.
So what you can do in here,
you can set your own
timeout.
Okay.
And you need to specify your time
units as well.
Okay. You can say duration
that of seconds.
Okay.
And you can do 20 seconds in here.
So now this is how you set your timeout.
Okay.
And then what you can do after that,
you can set the calling time.
Okay.
Calling time in here, calling
every let's say you pull every 5 seconds.
Okay.
Again, duration.
Duration of seconds, five. Okay.
So does anyone know what polling
means in here, guys?
Kind of looping.
Yeah, that's that's a very good idea.
So calling every 5 seconds
means that whenever you start
finding your elements.
Okay, so let's go back to this example.
So not this one to the implicit weights.
Okay. So when you set an implicit rate
and you
set it for 20 seconds
and you try to find that element, okay,
So your web driver will start looking
for that element every 0.5 seconds.
Okay.
So every half second
it will go ahead and start looking again.
Okay.
But here, when you set your polling
for 5 seconds,
your web driver will skip that 00.
5 seconds and it will start looking
for your elements
after each 5 seconds.
Is that clear, guys?
So this is what polling means in here.
So you basically look for your element
every 5 seconds.
Okay.
And here
and then what you can also do with
I'll repeat, polling.
Okay.
So let me finish this one in here.
And what you can also do,
you can also ignore some exceptions.
Okay.
Which is no, let's say
we have no such element exception.
Okay.
The class.
Then you can close your statement.
Okay.
Calling guys. So
in general, when you
set an implicit way,
it waits for 20 seconds.
So it will be looking for the element
you trying to find each half seconds.
Okay, So it will be looking.
So it looks for the element it did find
and it's looking again in 0.5 seconds.
Okay.
So but if you set your fluent weight
and you set your polling to 5 seconds,
it will start looking for your elements
every 5 seconds.
Not 0.5, but 5 seconds.
Okay.
Is that clear?
Does it mean it's slower?
It is a little bit slower because if it
if your element is available inside
2 seconds, then it will have to wait in
for 5 seconds for the next iteration.
Okay.
Any questions, guys,
when you will use this?
This is used
most of the time in frameworks.
Okay, So slow and wait is, as I said, it's
a global weight, right?
So fluid weight will be written
only once is implicit.
Wait. Okay.
So you can write it once in your execution
and it will behave
as how you set your timeouts,
how you set if falling or what.
Whenever you ignore something,
this is going to be your fluent way.
Okay, so you don't have to specify
this multiple times
in multiple places.
It can be the same value in here
if you want to do it.
Five and this is five.
But that doesn't
that won't make sense, right?
So why would you wait?
Why would you time out in 5 seconds and
you pull every 5 seconds?
That wouldn't make sense.
So it's better not to set it this way
Logically, it wouldn't be correct.
Right? Yes.
We're not interacting
with any web elements here
as we don't interact
with implicit weights.
Right.
You set it
so it's going to run in the background.
Okay.
But in explicit way,
what you do, you interact with the
with the specific elements
that you want to set
conditions for.
That's why we set that implicit
and fluent weights are global weights
because you just set only once
and it'll perform
for the whole execution.
Okay.
Any other questions, guys?
You can do an example.
Yeah, just use this the same.
Whereas a phone
we just use the same way in here that
this use this in any of these examples.
Okay.
And it should work us.
All right.
Yeah.
So let's take a break.
815 right.
And then,
and then we'll continue with the
with the web tables. Okay.
So let's get 16 minutes break
and then we'll continue
the second half.
Okay?
I'll see you guys at 830
here.
All right, guys.
Okay.
Gave you three more minutes.
Give you three more minutes.
Let's see.
I hope everyone is back, guys.
Exactly.
There you go.
Okay So let's continue.
Okay.
So I see some people asking for
for an example for fluent weight.
Okay.
So what we're going to do
is I just pinged Moazzam
so that he can go over the review.
Okay. If he can find any
any examples of fluent weight
is going to show you and then you're going
to get more clarity on that.
Okay, guys, because we have to right now
we have to move on to the
to handling the web tables.
Okay.
All right.
But as I said before, guys, fluid weight
do not really
dive deep into this topic
because you won't be really using
any fluid weight at work.
As I said, it's a little bit outdated.
It's it's rarely used now.
Okay.
All right.
So let's see
the notes.
Okay.
So now, guys, let's go over the work
tables.
Okay.
So let's see if I have your table.
There we go.
Okay, before we dive into the web tables,
okay,
what are the web tables on the Web page?
There's
anyone doing research on the web
tables? Yes.
Let's see
a little bit just now.
Okay, That's fine.
Next week's topic.
No, it's probably
if you look at the slides, they are.
No, it should be this week's topic
now, Class eight, guys.
Okay.
So anything which has rows and columns.
Okay, there can be static and dynamic.
Very good.
Okay, so web tables,
first of all, are what, on the web
page, guys,
what are we always looking for on the web
page?
Okay. It is a web element, right?
So web tables are
on the Web page, which is constructed
by having rows and columns.
Okay.
And as Mark
noticed,
that it can be static and dynamic.
Right.
So and we will go over
both of those today.
Okay. So web tables
are our elements
on the Web page,
right.
Which are constructed
by having
rows and columns.
Okay.
And types of web
tables.
First of all, it can be static web tables.
The second one is dynamic
Web tables.
Right. Okay.
So obviously static table guys,
what can it be?
Rows and columns are fixed, right?
So dynamic would not be fixed
dynamic will be the information
inside the web table will be changing some
some rows will be deleting or more rows
will be adding inside that table.
Okay.
So let's go ahead
and take a look how the web table is.
Can inside our HTML.
Okay, So let me do this.
Okay.
So this is our table, right?
So let me put this bigger in here.
Okay.
So if you look in here,
what kind of tag we have
for tables, guys?
Pretty straightforward, right?
It's a taped table tag.
So now
our table is consist is consisted
of two different parts.
Okay.
So this is the first part,
which is a table head.
And then the second part
is the table body.
Okay, so and this kind of tables,
they don't appear always okay.
Sometimes developers include the header
of the table inside the body as well.
Okay.
In this case, what we have
we have a table, we have a head in here
and we have t body separately.
Okay. Is that clear, guys?
Any questions on that?
Okay, good.
All right,
so now let's open up our header.
Okay, So let's expand this.
So what do we have in here? This.
So I have a header, and then I have a t r.
Okay.
What does it stand for?
Anyone knows their role, right?
So t r stands for table of row.
Okay.
And then t h goes in here.
Table headings.
Exactly. Or you can do
it. If it's under the
t hat, it's going to be t t h
because it should be the heading
of that column.
Right. Okay.
So now let's
go ahead and take a look at the body.
Okay.
So if you look at the body,
what do I have in here,
guys, again, Right.
We have multiple, multiple roles.
So if I open the rows up and expand these,
what are we having in here?
T What is the T stand for, guys?
The table data.
Right? Exactly.
There we go.
So basically you guys are
tables are consist
consisted of table header, right?
Which has one row and it has the headings.
Right?
And then what we have in here
we have a table body,
we have a table rows again
and we have the table data.
Okay, so let's go ahead in here
and say with tables
consist of
different sections
or we can say different parts, right?
So okay, first of all, what we start with
is we start with table, right?
And we close the table.
Okay, so what do we have inside the table,
guys?
We have the header and the body, right?
So let's start with a T hat, right?
So we have t hat in here
and what we can do
t hat is.
All right, so let's take this here
and let's take this year.
Okay?
What Else do we have inside the t hat?
What does it come next?
Rose Right.
So and then what we're going to have t
are in here
and then
t are
and inside the rows.
What are we going to have
if it's our header?
Guys,
we're going to have TDs in here.
We're inside the header
guys, we're inside the header,
we're inside the rows of the header.
Let's take a look in here, guys.
What are we having in here? Guys,
What is the tag?
The tag is the headings.
Write the headings in here.
Okay. All right.
So what we can do in here. So
h All right.
And then close the not to see H
And what we can also say
this is our column data or a heading.
Okay.
The now, okay, so this is what we have
inside the header, right?
So after the header, what we have
is our t body, right?
So do we have inside the T body guys
we have again
the rows inside the T body
and then inside the rows.
Guys, what we're going to have,
we have the x data, right?
So here
what we can do is
put table there.
Okay, so this is how web tables
are structured inside our h html.
Okay.
And as I said before, guys,
if you don't see the header
inside the table
sometimes nothing to worry about.
It's just a part of the body. Okay?
So sometimes it comes with a t hat,
sometimes
it's in the header is inside the T body.
So this is how everything is designed
quite develop.
Okay, so here we don't
we can't really do anything in here.
Okay?
We just have to
find our elements accordingly.
Okay. So
this one,
this is the closing statement, right?
So you open the t r
you close the t, right.
So if you look in here, so you open the
the tag and you close the tag.
Right.
That's you put that slash.
Okay.
So if you see here, you open your row
and you close zero in here.
Okay, so that's the closing of your tag.
Okay.
So now let's go back here.
Any questions on the structure of the web
tables,
guys?
Player so far.
Okay, good.
Okay.
So now what
we going to do in this example?
Guys, We're going to go ahead and start
navigate this Web page.
Okay. Well, well,
well.
Identify this table.
What we're going to do
is we're going to see how many rows
we have inside our table.
Okay. And then
what we're going to do,
we're going to get all the text
from the rows.
We're going to print it out
inside our console.
Okay. Is it clear, guys?
Any questions before we get started?
Okay.
Seems like not right.
Okay, So let me create
a new
class in here and length
study
of table.
Also. Okay.
This will change
my view of all your.
Okay, so we're navigating
to that website, right?
So now what I need to do,
I need to locate this
table.
Okay. Okay.
Let me send you the length.
There we go. Okay, guys.
So now what I am going to do,
I am going to locate this element
step by step.
Okay?
So what I need in here,
I need to print out
all the raw information.
Okay, so what I'm going to do.
So most of the time, guys, whenever you're
interacting with the tables,
okay, what you want to do,
you want to get access to the rows.
And if you want to do that,
then most of the time
you will be using an expat.
Okay, so what I will do here
are start locating my rows.
Okay, so
in here
I'll do a double slash, right?
I have my table.
And what am I identifying
my table by guys in here?
What do we have that we can identify it by
the ID, Right.
So I have an I.D.
in here is equal to
task table.
Right. So one of one. Right.
So what I want to do,
I want to capture all the rows right now.
Okay, So what I need to do, guys in here.
So if I want to capture all their rows,
how would do this?
There we go. So
after the table, I want to go to my body.
Right?
So what I can do is put a slash in here
and do t bottom right.
So now let's expand our body in here.
So what I need here,
I need access to all the rows.
Right?
I'm going to put another slash
and I'll do t r.
So how many roles do we have now
or how many elements did we locate?
Right now
we located seven elements, right?
So if we have more than one element,
how do we handle this kind of situations?
Inside my script, guys, where do we store
these?
We find the elements and then we set them.
We we store them inside the list. Right?
Okay, so let me copy this.
Get back to our script now.
So now what I'm doing here, Driver
Dot, find elements right
by experts
pasted in here.
Right.
And then assign it to the list of
web elements.
Right and stuff elements in here.
What I can do is
throw data right from the table
and import from this facility.
All right. Is this clear? Is the line 18?
Clear, guys.
Okay.
How to find it in X path?
So you start from the very top, right?
So you have the table.
You start your X path
with, the table tag,
and then you see it has an idea, right?
So you can identify that table by ID
and now what you want to do,
you want to move forward
until you get the access to the table.
Rose Okay. Why?
Why use ID instead of class?
Why are we using ID instead of class guys?
Okay, Classified as space.
That's fine.
Is there any other reason why we using ID
guys?
It's faster. What else?
It is unique, right?
It is always unique.
Unless you have some numeric values
in there.
Okay, ID is more reliable.
Okay,
so that's why we're using ID in here.
So now what I want to do.
I don't want any headers in here.
I only want the actual information.
Right.
So what I want to do
I want to go to my body
and then I want to go to the table rows,
step by step, right.
Okay. So let's get back to our script now.
So if I want to see if I want to print out
how many rows
I have in my console, what would I do?
Guys, if you
size.
Right.
Okay, so let's print it out real quick
in here.
Real data that size.
Okay, So let's run this.
Let's run
this and see what we're going to have.
Well,
we're going to have inside the console
right?
Okay. Well navigated here.
Let's get back.
Okay. Seven rows, right?
We located seven elements.
We have
we have printed seven rows in here.
So everything is good.
So that means we have those elements.
Everything is good.
So now, guys, I want to get all the
all the data and print it one by one.
Right?
So since we are interacting
with different, different elements
at the same time, what do we need to do?
We can either loop right or what?
What else can we use, guys?
We can use an iterator right?
Okay, there we go.
So let's try to use iterator
and we'll use loop later as well.
Okay?
So what I'm going to do here,
I have an iterator of what guys
what am I to writing through in here? The
web elements.
Right?
So I'm iterating through the web elements
and this row data
is going to give me that iterator.
Right. Okay.
So now instead of using the
for loop in here,
what we're going to have,
we will be using the while, right?
So while
there is something on my next step, right.
Only then what we're going to do,
we won't be going
inside this
inside that while.
Okay,
so now what do I need to do next, guys?
What I want to do at the very
and I want to print out all the
all the information
inside my console.
Yes, that's a good one.
Yeah. So.
But let's do it step by step.
Okay.
So what is my next step if I do if I
if I take one
step forward, what am I getting in
return, guys?
So let's do
that next. Right?
What am I getting in return here?
Am I getting a string, guys?
What am I to writing through?
Am I to writing through strings?
No. Right.
I'm iterating through the web elements.
So web element
row is equal to my next step, right?
So in order for me to get the string now,
what am I doing?
I need to get the text of that row. Right?
So string
row text is equal to
that text in here, right?
And then what I need to
I need to print this out.
Okay, So let's run this
and see what
we're going to have in our console.
Okay. I would go and navigated here.
So as you can see here, we printed
all the data from the
from this table.
Pretty cool, right, guys?
So what we did,
we just identified all the rows, right?
We started iterating through them, right?
We got the text in here
and we simply printed it out.
Okay.
Any questions, guys?
Feel good? Okay, cool.
So now what I want to do.
So now what I want to do, guys,
I want to print the headers as well.
Okay?
Each heading that we have in here,
I want to print them as well.
How would I do this?
So we printed all the rows.
Now what?
What do I need to do in here
to print all the headings?
Okay, that's a very good idea.
Yes. So let's let's go ahead and start
looking for the headings.
Right
So we need to locate the headings first.
Right.
So where are my headings
located in this table.
So this part of my expense
should be fine, right?
Because I'm still interacting
with the same table.
Right.
What's going to come after this?
Guys?
So what I want to do,
I want to get the headers.
Where am I going next in here?
Okay, I need to go to the T head.
Right.
And what else is that? It?
I want to go to the rows
and I want to go to the heading
themselves.
Right.
So the heading would be our column. Right.
So this is the first column
you can see
here.
One, two, three, four. Right.
So we basically moving
through the columns, right?
So with located four different in here,
what are we going to do with these.
Let me copy this exact
storing them in a set
or store them in a list right.
Okay.
So list of
web element, right.
So columns data in here
is equal to driver
dot find elements, right
by express,
place it in here.
All right.
So now what I want to do,
I want to know how many columns
I have.
We need the size, right?
So print out
columns, data size.
So since we already used the iterator
in the previous example,
what I want to do,
I want to use a for loop in here.
Okay, so
create a for loop.
Right.
I am iterating
through all the columns, data.
Right.
So what,
what is this container contains of
web elements?
Right. So
web elements in here,
what I can do column data,
right.
And then what do I need to do here guys,
in order for me to print it inside
my console?
It's a writer.
Okay, We already have a loop, right?
What is my next
step, guys?
We get the text
and we simply printed it out.
Right?
So string
alum text is equal to
column data.
Get text
and then print out
column text in here.
Okay.
All right.
So let's run this, guys, and see
if we are able
to print out the column data
as well.
Okay. Here.
All right.
So after this
print line, right.
We can see that we have four,
four columns now.
These are the text of those columns.
Pretty cool, right, guys?
So we can manipulate
we can get the text from the rows,
We can get the text from the headers
and we can print them inside our console.
Right.
Any questions, guys?
Confused a little bit with this one.
Okay, let's go back in here.
All right.
So what we need to do is we
we need to look for the header, right?
So where is our header located?
It's inside the table.
Right.
So if you go inside the table,
you need to go inside the t hat.
Right.
So if I the t hat,
what do I have inside my head, guys,
I have one row in here, right?
So if I expand the row then you can see
I have four different data
which is the heading data, right.
Or which is the column data.
Okay.
So inside one row, I have four different
column data.
So this is how we should go
by the hierarchy.
So you, you identified the table,
you go to the header,
you go to its row and you go to its data.
Okay?
So you have to move one by one.
Yes, you are getting them right.
So if you look, you identify
we identified four different
elements.
Okay, Yeah,
almost like an absolute, but you don't
really start from the very top, right?
So you start from the table and
this is how the furthest that you can go.
Okay, so after the T or TD,
there's nothing else in the
inside
the table.
Okay.
Any questions, guys?
All right, so
let's get back here.
Okay.
So now what we're going to do, we will be
interacting with the dynamic table.
Okay?
So we set that dynamic
table is what the dynamic table is,
where inside the table
there might be some changes, some
new raw insertions,
or it may be something deleted in there.
Right.
So those are the dynamic
web tables, right?
All right.
Too much info today, as I said.
Right, guys?
Yesterday,
It's going to be intense a little bit.
So bear with me, guys. Okay.
A little bit left.
Okay.
We'll
finish the dynamic tables
and then you guys should be good to go.
Okay.
All right.
So let me actually log in
here.
Okay. So now, guys,
what are you seeing in here?
What do we have in here right after we log
in, Guys, we have a table, right?
We have a table is the list of the orders.
Right?
So how do we know if it's dynamic
or static?
Table guys?
Okay, so we have the delete selected
button, right?
Or you can see that there are checkboxes
in here that you can select.
Right.
And since this is the list of all orders,
so that means
if you receive any more order,
this table is going to get updated.
Or if you if you're done with the order
or if it's a wrong order,
you can go ahead and delete that order.
Right.
So the username and password
is right on the on the website.
That's under the password.
Okay.
So what we're going to do is
we will be interacting
with this table today and
to interact.
So then it's a dynamic.
Yes, a link for
you should have the link
I think already guys.
Right.
So because we worked on this website,
a lot of times.
All right, so let's get started with
with the log in.
So let's go back in here
and let me open up
a new Java class
and link
dynamic table.
And this
this one, let's keep that
this.
All right.
So the first thing, what do we
what do we want to do, guys in here
find the element, right?
Find the log in and
password.
So let me inspect this.
Go ahead and see.
Okay.
There is an idea, guys.
So let me get this ID
and create
a web element
username equal to
five or fun element
by the
then username
sentence.
All right.
And our username is
that's the
right.
Yeah.
I mean it's it's not good to use
but you can use a different one.
That's fine.
You can use you can do you can
you can do an X path and do contains
so that you don't
have to use this numeric values in here.
Right. But usually it's not.
But since this is a test website,
it doesn't really it's not going
to change anything in here.
Okay.
All right.
So elements.
So now let's figure out the password.
Okay. So it has an idea as well.
So I'm going to copy this
idea.
Right. And
I will send these in here again,
this is my password, which is
password test.
Right.
And now what I need to do,
I just need to go ahead and click on log
in right now.
There is an idea again in here.
So I'm the copy that.
What elements
find elements like that I d again
here.
So in this case what we're going to do
will be simply clicking this right.
Okay. So let's go back in here.
Let's log in.
Okay, guys.
So is everyone clear what I did?
From line 16 to 21 guys.
Okay, good.
So now let's get back to our page. Right.
So what we to do in here again, guys,
we want to
we want to interact with the table,
but this time,
what I want to do, I want to go ahead
after I print
all the text inside my console,
what I want to do,
I want to click on this order book,
which has a bulb feather name in here.
Is that clear?
You guys?
Any questions?
Okay, so where do we start, guys?
So if the task is clear, where do I start?
In here. I logged in.
Everything is good. I see the table.
What's my next step?
I need to find the rows.
Right.
So I need to interact
with the rows. Right.
So Let's see in here.
This is our table. Right.
So do we have a table header in?
Here goes.
No. Right.
If you look inside the HTML,
there's no section or part which is t hat.
Right.
So as I said before, guys,
not all the tables will be inside
with not all the tables will consist of t
hat and t body.
Right.
So in this case, the whole table,
the whole rows,
they are stored inside the T body.
Okay, so I open the selector box in here
and I will start to identify
this table for table.
Right.
So what do we have in here?
So we have ID, so let's use this IP
in here. I d
place it here.
Okay, so we identified our table.
This is good.
Okay, so where do I go next, guys?
T bottom. Right?
So I'm going to go to t body and, then
I will go to t r.
All right.
So now we captured all the roles in here.
Okay, so we got nine in here,
So we captured nine different elements,
Right?
Okay,
so let's go back in here.
So what do I do with those nine elements?
Guys,
let me.
Okay, this
what we're going to do,
we will be storing them
inside the list right
list of with
elements in here, say rows
C drive or
find elements
by X Factor in here.
Is this right?
And let's import the list.
Okay.
So now what I want to do,
I want to get all the text,
print it out inside my console.
But this time what I want to do,
I want to use the regular loop guys.
Okay,
so we stored everything in the loop.
So I'm starting my for loop in here.
So where do I start from Guessing here.
So I have an integer I write is equal
to what?
From zero.
Okay. From zero.
And then I is less than what
the size.
Right?
So we have rows that size
and then we will be incrementing by one.
Okay. All right. So this is our for loop.
What do I need to do next, guys?
How do I print everything out?
There we go.
So we get the string.
So text right
is equal to
rows that get I here, right?
Because we lose.
We're using the regular for loop.
So we need to go with the indexes in here
and then get text.
And then what we need to do in here,
we can simply print out a row text.
Right. Okay.
So let me run this
and see what we're going to have.
Okay.
There we go.
All right. So what do we see in here?
So it printed all the rows in here,
but what did it
include inside our console guys?
So other than all the all the
what's called the data and all the orders,
what else do we have inside my console?
The title of each column. Right.
So the headers. What if I don't want them?
How do I, how do I get rid of those guys
if condition?
Why do we need an F condition?
What do I put in this condition?
We can simply start from one.
Right? Exactly.
There we go. So
because everything is under t body.
So instead of starting from zero
element of the mess,
we can start from the first one and let's
we run this
and see if we can get rid of
so right. Okay
here. There we go.
So we only have the information about the
what do you call about the
orders. Right.
So now, guys, what I want to do in here,
I want to go ahead and click
on this particular checkbox.
How would I do this?
Any thoughts
contains.
Okay,
Boolean method.
Okay.
What do I have inside the if condition?
Okay, so if condition,
what am I having inside the?
If okay, so let's say I have okay.
Is okay
a row tax right
contains let's say
we're looking for a bulb feather right?
Okay then what am I clicking on?
CheckBox. Okay. Where's my check box guys,
did I identify the checkbox in here?
No. Right,
not yet.
There we go. We haven't decided yet.
So now let's go back in here and find.
Okay,
so how do I want to locate the checkbox?
The do I just locate this one does
or how do we want to keep this?
Okay, so we have ID name
so we can just locate one checkbox in here
and go ahead and click.
This does
How do we want to approach this?
Guys?
Any thoughts?
I can locate them all.
Okay.
Okay, guys.
So here what we want to do,
we want to locate all the checkboxes.
Why am I locating all the checkboxes?
Why am I not just coming here
and clicking on this one
in case the data changes in the future?
Right, Exactly.
So we said this is a dynamic web table.
So tomorrow it can be the bulb
feather can be the last in here of orders
or the first one.
We don't know that. Right.
So if we just locate this checkbox,
it won't click on that.
Right. Okay.
So now what I will do, I will get
all the checkboxes are available for me.
Okay, So I am inside the rows right now.
Right?
So where is my checkboxes located?
It's inside each row, but it's inside
only one thing.
Guys.
What is it?
Input. It's inside the column. Right.
So it's only inside the first column
that we have inside our table.
Right?
So so far, by this X path, guys,
what we did is
we only identified the rows, right?
So what I need to do now,
I need to go ahead and identify
only the
okay, so how am I going to do this?
So let's take a look.
What do I have inside my rows, guys?
What is inside my rows?
Guys, the table data. Right.
Which one of these table
consists of a checkbox? Does
TDI want input?
The first one, right?
Only the first data of
of each row has the checkbox.
Right.
So what we can simply do in here,
we can put td1.
Okay. And it will
that particular cell.
Okay.
And you can see we identified
only eight of them.
So let's go ahead here you can see that
we identified all the checkboxes in here.
Okay.
Any questions on guys?
Why not?
Okay, so you want to do a text box?
Sather Right.
So what if what you're
here, your condition changes?
What is it going to click on?
It won't work, right?
So if your condition changes in here,
then you're going to have to manipulate
with your
with your checkbox as well. Okay?
So that makes it to a different two
different places to change it.
Okay, so what you want to do, if anything
changes, if your condition changes,
so you want to make changes in your script
as less as possible.
Okay.
So here
we identified eight different checkboxes.
So I'm going to copy this.
And what I will do in here?
So if I, if we identified a checkboxes,
what are we doing
with those
two? Right.
Before we iterate,
we need to store them right?
We need to store them in a list
of web elements
right here.
We can say the checkboxes
is equal to the driver
that find elements
by x path
and paste my x path in here.
Okay guys.
So now what
do I need to do in order to click
on that checkbox?
If let's not check
if it's selected or not yet.
Okay, So let's just click on that
how do we do
that?
I am using a specific name.
I'm using specific name in here, right?
So if I change this to a different name,
you're path is not going to work
right?
So your X path indicates
your Xbox indicates box further in there.
What if I change the name in here?
Then I'm going to have to change your
your X path as well.
The one you set before.
Okay. All right.
How do I click on the checkbox guys
in here?
So I just do checkboxes dot click.
Okay.
If not, how do we do this?
And then click okay.
Okay, guys, we have a list of web elements
I need to get one
finding by index.
How do I get an element from that?
From the list guys.
Come on, guys, you can do this.
Get I. There we go. Why?
Why do we need another loop in here, guys?
No. Right.
Because we are already
iterating through those
through those rows.
Right. So we don't need another loop.
So We simply can do in here.
We get one element
from that, from the list.
And what we can do, we can click on this
right?
And then what do we need to do
after we click?
We need to break the loop, right?
So we need to stop it.
Okay, So let's run this so that you can
visually see what is going on.
Okay?
Okay.
There we go.
What happened, guys?
What did we click on right now?
Everyone got the Samuel Clements, right?
What is going on in here?
Why did it click on the next one, guys?
All right, go.
Okay, let's.
Okay, This is the code.
Why did it click on the next one
and not on the bop feather?
There we go.
So we started from the one, right?
And here
I'm starting from the first element
in here,
from the second one right in here,
because our elements from there,
from the list
is starting from the index of
right.
We starting from the one
we're getting an AI in here.
So we starting
from the second value of the checkboxes.
Okay. Is that clear, guys?
Why it clicked on the next one?
So in order to level them up,
what are we doing in here?
Is it plus one or minus one?
Is it plus
because it clicked on the next one, guys.
So we need to get one back, right?
So what we're going to do,
we need to do minus one in here.
Okay, So
let's get this rerun again
and see if we going to
click on the
right one.
And then there we go.
So now we have box feather in here.
We clicked on that checkbox
and now everything is working fine.
All right.
Any questions
on this?
Let me close this.
Okay. Yours gives the same result, right?
Okay, good.
So now change the condition in here.
Change the condition in here
to this Susan MacLaren
and run your code.
But do not change your X path, okay?
What's going to happen?
See, that's what I was telling you, Andre.
Okay, so because you changing
your condition in here,
but your expert has the name as well.
So that's why that's why it's
going to be changed
in two different places.
If you go with your.
Okay, first
place.
No, no, no.
It clicked on Samuel Clements
because we starting from one in here.
Okay.
So if you start from one in here,
that means you starting
from the second checkbox in here
so that that's why you going one forward.
Okay.
So order for us to go in a level
with that for loop,
we need to get one checkbox back.
Okay.
Any other questions guys?
Okay. So
okay, I'll break the code.
Okay. One second, guys. Okay.
So I have a question in here.
What if I want to click on Mark
Smith, Bob Sather and Claire Jefferson?
Guys, what would I change in my code
or how would I do this?
Let's go back in here.
So if Bob is lost, that's fine.
Put or okay,
So what if I take a look at the table guys
using and take a look at the table?
Do we need any or and inside our
if condition
it will only click one.
Okay we don't need the break
because we're clicking on different ones.
That's a good point.
Okay. That I agree with.
Okay, so let's go ahead and delete this.
Right. Okay.
What about how how would I do?
How would I click these three
without putting an end
or statements?
II minus two?
Not really.
Okay, guys,
let's take a look at the table.
Let's pay attention to the table rows,
guys.
Just two more clicks.
Not really.
No. I want to keep it as it is right now.
I don't want to add more clicks
by product.
Absolutely. Right. There we go.
You can see in here, family album,
family Album, Sam,
the album in here, right?
So the product they have is the same.
So what you need to change in here is only
this part.
Okay, so let's run this
and see
if this is going
to click on three of those
and we go 1 to 3.
Right?
That's why, guys,
I told you to pay attention on the table.
Okay. What do have on the rows, guys?
What what is the common
containing text that we have
that we don't have to write a lot of code.
Okay.
If there was no
same product, then you would go with
with different things
you can do, you can put or
inside your F condition
or you could do another if condition.
So it's all up to you.
Okay.
In this particular situation,
the only thing that you want to change
is the containing text, because they have
they all have the same exact
product.
Okay.
Any questions, guys?
Any questions on how to handle
static and dynamic
web tables?
And let's see,
people are typing to the code.
Okay, yours click to checkboxes.
Send us the screenshot.
We want to see the code.
Okay.
Okay. Any questions, guys?
Any questions on the weights?
Any questions on?
The the web tables?
Yeah. We just need some practice. Right.
So see?
Yeah, yeah.
The for the floor loop,
we started from zero.
Okay, so you need to start your
for loop from one.
Okay.
There are only two checkboxes.
There should be three
right from the album.
And let's see.
Okay, it's yours.
Checked only one.
I think you have a break inside the loop.
Okay, so you need to remove that break.
Okay, Let me see.
I should put on three.
And you're not getting any errors.
Whoever is getting only two checkboxes,
is there any error?
You guys getting?
Okay,
let's
not sure why it's not clicking.
It should meet one, but it's probably.
Let's see now.
I should
match or.
Right. And
if you have the same exact code in here
it should be present on.
So you guys
are you worse?
Okay, so take a look at
what is the difference between yours.
Your and demo of these code.
Okay.
Okay, guys, any other questions?
Yes, I'll push the code, guys. Okay.
Any questions on on anything
we have covered guys.
Intense, but not too much.
You want more?
I can bring more guys if you want.
Have not today.
Okay.
Only fluent ways.
Not clear, guys. Okay.
Don't focus too much on the one. Great.
Okay.
I'll ask Moazzam if you can.
If you can bring up an example. Okay.
I hope you can.
And he will show you the example for the
what's called for the flown way.
Okay.
And let me see actually what I have.
So the
we want to have
some more topics today.
Unfortunately.
Unfortunately, we're out of time.
Okay. So.
All right.
So let me get this.
Yeah.
Opposed to homework in here.
All right. So
let's see what it was.
Okay, guys.
All right, so here is the thing.
So here's what I want you to do in here.
Okay?
So they
go to this website, right?
Click on the checkbox and click on Remove.
Okay, Click on the checkbox,
click on remove.
So you want to do you want to make sure
that this text is
is appeared in here.
Okay.
And then
what you want to do,
you want to enable this text box.
Okay, You want to enable it
and verify that this text box is enabled.
Type something in here
and verified this text
and click on this some disable as well.
Okay, Click,
disable and verify
that the text box is disabled.
Is that clear? Guys,
any questions.
Okay, good.
Don't pay attention to this one
because it's not functioning properly.
Okay.
Just do the steps and verify
the text in here.
Verify the buttons,
not the button, the text box, if you like.
And let me post this
of course, announcements
I posted
and of course announcements, guys.
Okay, one more thing.
Okay, guys, I have a question.
What Is the topic that you're in with Java
guys.
Okay. In the maps,
you know, what's the next topic, guys
Is it exception handling
or file hand?
Okay, okay.
Okay. File reading. Okay, good.
After that,
you're going to have exception handling.
Okay.
So what I want you to do now, guys,
what I want you to do.
So we have eight packages in here, right?
We have eight packages.
What I want you to do,
I want you create another package.
Okay?
Create another package
and name it as utilities.
Okay?
Or you can name it as utils.
Okay,
So create that package name utils
and what you need to do,
create a java class.
So let me put it here, create a package
and name it as
utils. Okay.
Or utils.
It doesn't really matter.
Created class.
Okay.
And name it
as common methods.
Okay guys. So what want you to do?
I want you to build two functions,
which is common function.
When I call that function,
it opens my browser
and when I call the second
it will close my browser.
Is that clear?
Guys,
create
functions.
I mean methods.
Write methods to open
and close the browsers.
Okay, guys, is that clear?
So what I want you to do,
just create a method.
Okay, so Create two methods.
Which one?
The first one opens up the
what's called
the browser and navigates to the euro.
Okay, so the URL I can
I need to pass
the URL inside the signature.
Okay guys.
So I hope you guys already know
how to create methods,
how to do the parameters
and how to do the return types.
Right? There we go.
So open launching the browser
and navigating to the euro
closing
is going to be just quitting the browser.
Okay, So whenever I, I call those methods,
I want those to open
and I want us to close the browsers.
Is that
clear, guys?
Andre Yes, that's what I want exactly.
Or you can come up with different idea.
That's fine with me.
Okay, so let's see how good you are in job
analysis.
Okay, so this is basic, basic
things that you going to be actually
creating methods inside your framework,
okay.
Because you're going to have as a separate
class, which has all the common methods
to click to send keys
to choose anything from the dropdown,
to choose any checkbox
or any radial button.
Okay, guys.
So you will have a lot of different common
methods.
Okay.
So I want you to start with these two
methods inside your Common methods class.
Okay.
All right. Any questions, guys?
Is there anyone who is confused
about the second homework?
I hope not. I think
you're confused. Why?
You just need to.
You just need to build two methods.
Right?
So what are you confused about?
Okay, so if you're a little bit confused
with how to build those,
please communicate with the teammates
and come up with some solutions on that.
Okay, guys.
All right.
Any other questions
is no questions.
Then we can wrap it up for today.
I know it's a lot of information,
so let me check.
What do we have for the next class?
Not really sure what we have.
Let me check guys in quick.
Okay. Yes.
So next class, guys,
we will be handling calendars.
Okay.
So please take a look at that.
How to handle calendar Miscellaneous.
Okay.
Okay, guys.
All right. Please complete the homework.
Please review all that we've done so far.
Okay.
And I will see you next week, guys. Okay.
Stay safe.
Have a good one.
Yes, I'll share the slides, guys.
Okay.
Have a great night, everyone.
Take care and I'll see you next week.
All right. Bye, everybody.