You're
Republican, but
let me start the record.
Fine days.
So now
we'll start right with we could begin
with the glass for
glass or first woman that it
then?
Why do we need a donor glass
to mostly talk about this right now?
Why do we need run glass case?
What is one of us
who configure
the execution
flow of OD just gives us current
to configure
the execution of our test cases.
We need to look glass
right now in this room of glass.
We have a lot of options.
Remember, these are under glass.
Witness starts with the right amount.
But let me open.
So the red table with when I'm
taking this part, we are taking from it
in cucumber we are running into with
G unique.
Right? So a direct line
between the taking.
It simply means the move
from TV to the channel you want to watch.
Cutting them is right.
So now we are seeing that we are going
to run not to kill, but with Johnny.
So run with Johnny.
And in the return with Art,
we are taking this a direct action,
but options to configure are so of glass.
So now here
here in are enough glass right
we need Adelaide run with option
and option from
from g unit
and then to do other options we need
we need to provide
we need more options to provide
configurations to provide configurations
quite
bindings now
indicating more options
to provide configuration options.
What are these options?
See first is features, plate
first is features
in features we provide What
part of my
part of my feature finds current.
Wherever I stored
all of my feature device,
I provide the part of those feature files
in my feature step
boasting steak. Anything.
Right now here we can pass either one
feature fight or we can pass the bottom
the entire folder where all of my picture
files are available.
Right,
Right.
Point after features after features.
The next thing we have is blue.
What we had next thing is blue, right?
Why do we need blue?
Always
package.
Now remember, it's not about package.
Blue means basically
whatever the feature flights
you want to execute for back each of you.
We had steps implemented but not so the
no glass always ask for this thing.
If we have this the steps implemented
in available, we need to provide that.
But so part of a particular location
where I have all of my steps,
it could be in one class,
it could be in multiple classes, right?
So if I have, for example, to simplify
the go to easily understanding,
to maintain the code,
we have separate steps class
for every single page, right?
That's why
we put all of those things in one package.
So instead of providing the part
of multiple classes, I'm
going to provide the part of the package
where all of my steps are available
in different classes.
So glue is basically what
of the steps
step definitions
for each of rights
ladies, Is this going to
one of the most important options
which we studied yesterday in our donor
class was a dry and
lost dry
enemy.
Guys, why do we need dryer?
No, your fabric is pretty common.
All right.
So basically,
we saw right before using the dryer
and what we were doing,
we were actually writing the steps
and we were executing the feature
by unnecessarily.
It was taking time
to execute the previous code
and then it was giving me
the steps for implementation, right?
The snippet it was giving me.
So that time unnecessarily
I was wasting my time
or the limited execution right now
to get rid of this problem.
We came up with one option
or try it in our don't. Plus
by default
it is state to false by default.
To disable false false means
you can continue
with the indication from the class range.
That is not in fact
because of this particular option.
The moment you make it to
the moment you send a greater
is equals to true,
then it stops your actual execution.
The first thing it does,
it stops your actual execution.
After stopping
your actual execution,
what is the next thing it does?
It quickly checks it quickly checks
all the steps
that you have mentioned in your feature.
It checks all the steps
right after taking steps, it will see
which steps are implemented,
which is steps are not implemented.
If there are a couple of steps
which are not implemented,
it will give you all the snippet,
all the code to implement
those steps in system definitions.
But so it's not only scanning
all the steps, but also providing the goal
for missing the steps.
Both things it one day.
So the first thing we are saving
the time of the deliberate execution
because we are not doing it
stops your actual execution.
Second thing
it is checking not in one picture frame,
but in all the feature file.
It single by all the feature, by its
legacy of 100 feature by another method.
It will check in all the region
points right?
It will give you the steps
which are not implemented.
You can simply go ahead,
copy those two steps and put it into
the particular plan perspective
plus the steps
like right in
both cases and goes towards and
then the next is monochrome.
What does it mean? Monochrome?
Great now because we
are having good segregated output,
but if we don't output in the console by
running digital
but in this
ink is if there is any information or
unreadable character exist in the console.
Right.
Executing make it in this case,
then what it does when you write
monochrome is the equals to draw.
Then it removes all those things.
It removes all the irrelevant
information, it removes
all the unreadable character, right?
When it removes all the unreadable content
in the limited information, it
gives you prop, but it cleans the output
only with the relevant information.
That's what we are taking already.
So monochrome does equal is
it was removed is not working with this.
But yes, if you are having that kind
of information, if someone is living right
in their console indefinitely,
you will see the effect of it.
Then we use x rayed
this particular part X,
we will go ahead and we will see
more things in this factory duty.
So that name
I will explaining in plug ins, right?
Yeah. Text.
I will explain.
You indeed get three more plug ins
right now.
Right now, yeah. In plug ins.
Right, right.
We need plug in a lot of plug
ins available.
It is you use always which one
monochrome.
Ah yes ideally
you should it's optional but we can use
All right so now in
plug ins read
it it's not only for report generation
plus we have so many things
which we can do via plug ins.
As of now,
we are creating just one report rate.
When we proceed further,
I will give you more scenarios
what other things we can do
using this plug ins.
All right.
So right now just one plugin we are
waiting there to be editable keyboard.
What is that keyword
in plug ins to be added one word, right?
That is the word
to be added
or read this word, we add it here.
And after that
we provided the instructions.
What kind of instruction?
For example, HDMI, What does it mean?
I need a multiple colon target.
It means inside my target folder.
What slash estimate?
What does it mean in my target folder?
I need one report product.
Each team is are not eligible for work
report related to the converter I need in
my using this plug ins
which is available in middle class
and just put
and then this is deprecated.
Right.
But like I said,
it is simply an alternative
to the Triton since we already have drain
and that supports deprecated.
So we don't use a strict rate
as a whisper crew here.
At the rate what it does,
it takes all the steps and it is against
what they were.
These steps undefined
and it gives you the initial conditions
frame.
This was the render class
we have seen yesterday, correct?
So Triton,
if it is inserted to brew
it starts right.
So KG provides
the instance
snipped
in monochrome,
which is
invalid,
means that pretty soon
and the
simple language
as of now
we will shed some more light on it.
Plug ins.
Very good morning division plugins for
before generation and under purchase.
Fine guys.
So this is all about class now than me.
What if I copy?
One is the definition
in to establish classes.
What would happen in that case?
And we do this
domain problem.
Okay, fine.
We will get Adelaide duplicate exception.
No, no big boundary.
I'm talking about one instance
in two different classes.
The nicer two different classes implements
big ones.
It is not normal with the like for example
use only we get to do it
John And this application,
if I implemented this steps in two
different classes, then what would happen?
Your symbol get confused.
Right?
I have to take this steps from there.
So remember we should be having unique
steps implementation for unique instances,
which would be clear enough feature.
Correct.
So it has to be a single
list, not multiple places.
Correct. But
the second thing does order maintenance
where we are implementing
in which we are implementing steps.
No, it doesn't matter.
What matters is linking used in our mark
when that I am able to link read
my steps, declaration
with my steps definition or not.
If it is the point, if it is implemented,
then we can see the linking.
Everything is fine and the stored
point.
After that we learn one more important
keyword.
Go make chrome.
What does it mean when I speak?
Guys, why do we need big joke
commonality?
Common steps, right?
For reuse the common step that,
for example in one feature
remember my words in one feature.
Fine.
If I had multiple scenarios
endorsed in end use,
I see the starting flow is being.
The starting flow is the mark.
My words in their name.
I see the reference in the step
builder name.
I see the difference in the step
build next.
And if we see all the
for the two step straight,
all the prior two steps are similar.
They are common, so we can use those steps
as the terms of big ground.
Instead of writing those steps again
and again and again.
In all the scenarios, we can keep
those steps only at one place, right?
And that one place is nothing
but my big current.
So common is that certain place
different systems with the person names.
Now make sure your background
is applicable,
but only one feature by
only one be generally
understood.
This could add an incident,
but it wouldn't cut.
Fine.
So this is all about my big jump.
Let me put this thing
steps
with the use
of single
or single
file.
The bigger
we use big group days.
No, the so far we have done this things
confirming it
can not apply to feature,
but it is a feature by leaps.
It doesn't apply
for all the feature piece.
You mean to sit there trained.
So using the build
we already created big ground.
Great big ground.
Great for a brief feature.
While big ground is different.
We did it last in the last class.
See this bigger.
This particular this class,
this big ground is for particular
with this particular feature.
So one big ground for one feature
or linked.
Alright.
Yep. Yes.
Sorry.
Find. Now
let's increase the scope.
Let's increase the scope.
We are not going to restrict
on imagination and we should build one
feature or deal one class.
We observed one bigger.
There is something common in one region,
some other thing
common in some of the feature by some
other thing, common in some other feature.
But there is one thing
that is one thing or two things
which are common across the entire feature
finds
across the entire project.
It means precondition in both condition
for all the feature files is same
given you that is,
get to a gentleman's application
first to super
user close the browser blast is
going to employ such feature
a given user comment
to step you close the browser common step
go at employ even use a common step.
You close the browser of common
description.
Can everyone see?
We can see it. Great.
So now when we have something
which is common across
all the features face,
we don't need to write
even in each of this part,
we don't
even need to write this in feature.
We have a separate place
to call precondition in most condition,
and that thing will work again
and again and again.
Put every single feature by business block
We go hooks into timber,
what we call them hooks
like what
we call them hooks, why we use hooks.
We use hooks to provide
precondition
pause conditions.
Again, I am repeating yes,
it is correct Hooks
We use hooks to provide preconditions
in most conditions and you can
now see that is a precondition
for every feature file we connect.
We colleague.
If we have a precondition in every feature
by we call it
background.
Similarly, if we have a precondition
and most conditions
to augment project, to automate
all the feature points, we call it
oops, right
now tell me what all are the annotations.
You know, the state,
what all of the annotations
you want to be invested
before, method
after method, before test after test,
before class
after class, before sort of this
right.
These are the annotations. You know,
sometimes it becomes very difficult,
sometimes it becomes very confusing,
right?
Sometimes it becomes to remember
all of them and to decide
which one to use,
which will not be correct.
Correct. It happens.
So now now what?
To compasses.
You don't have to be worried
of all this things.
We have just two hooks called before
and after.
Simply put your preconditions in before
put your post conditions
in after the next eight door hooks
we have in the entire computer.
That's it. All right.
So many hooks.
We have guys here.
We have just two hooks.
So good number of hooks are block of code
that run before or after each scenario.
Now, remember,
when we use our hooks before and after,
it works as a before method flat rate,
correct? Correct.
So before method means running
before everything, then
after method means running
after everything, then correct.
That's what we were using
guys remember before method
after method in this dingy.
Right.
Similarly, when we are going to implement
this a done it before and it after
in December in terms of who it is
considered as a matter of the method,
it means it months before the scenario
and after it vicinity
destroyed.
So far.
Second thing
second mark this works, modify works.
What I'm saying
we always have to define hooks
under the back page
where my steps are available.
If we put this point, we should provide
hooks under the package
where my
steps are
in separate class.
Yeah, we will.
We will create,
we will clear nobody, nobody.
Right.
So now what I'm saying this
we have to provide our hooks
under the separate package rate
where all of my steps are available
because hooks are related to steps load
with your actual feature.
Right.
Your feature points
are also going to be jump
steps are also related
to step definitions, correct?
Correct.
And then if you
you're not have any step definition,
does it make sense
to have all the feature weights?
Does it make sense?
Will it work?
It will not work. Great.
So first we have to write
hollow steps in feature weight.
Then we have to write all this step
definitions, right?
We have to make sure that these
the step definitions
are the step of feature points
that are integrated.
When these two beams are linked together,
we have to
wait hooks in that steps package.
So what would happen this time?
My hooks linked with my steps
which are available
in the different classes
and it executes before
of this menu in terms of precondition
in most condition.
So how many hooks we have?
We have just two hooks before
and after, before and after that
saying no method, no test, no class, no.
Is this point clear
point.
Now, remember one thing
when we use before
let let me let me give you one scenario.
Here is my board.
Let me ask you one thing. That to me,
this is my feature by
in my feature file,
I'm having a big growth
rate and I am having my Cincinnati
getting my scenario, says van user
clicks, or it's been
user interface
and I'm also having my hooks
hooks big time scenario feature by
and I'm having my camera. Plus
when I execute my remote last.
Tell me what will execute first
Hooks will execute first, then
item hooks.
Big will execute yes feature by correct.
So in feature find
what is what will execute second bingo
and third scenario
content.
First hooks will execute,
then background will execute.
Instantly you will execute
and then again hooks will execute
again.
Hooks will executed or not. Any
first, second, third, fourth.
Isn't it the correct order?
No, no.
You should not get you should believe
because I explaining right
and it's like a loop
not it's not like a loop,
it is just a singular single line.
See hooks execute before condition,
then big known, then scenario,
then hooks execute after condition.
Simple like this that I've been on call.
Got to fight.
All right, guys. So two hooks only simple.
We have before
and we have after that expect.
All right. That's it.
Is this a graphical representation
is clear to everyone
or not about the hooks?
This is clear. Super.
Let's proceed for that.
I am going to implement
this hooks part in my project.
First. I'll right
what I'm going to do.
I'm going to put all of these things
in my hooks part.
So like I said, that I need these hooks
based, that I need hooks
instance.
So let's open the steps.
Let's open this open here.
I'm going to write
new class code
hooks
and insert hooks.
First ritual.
We have two external common methods. One
fine guys.
Now then me,
we were talking about do keywords
in the hooks, only two hooks we have.
The first one is the
before.
Can you see
it is coming from remember Java?
Remember
we have before with a larger unit as well.
And we had before with
I could convert our java so big this again
what I ordered do Commodore Java don't use
your Einstein bleed use
I ordered to convert our Java
byte big the second one from
right
now in this before hook.
I'm going to write my precondition.
Everyone knows how to write precondition
goes public
void lets it start.
This would be the name of my precondition
and this is the method
I called for My common methods
and right guys.
Open browser launch application
is the matter to be implemented.
Not a common method
is that anyone who has any question
related to this particular part.
We had been doing it multiple times.
Now there is no question
there should not be any question about it.
Great
preconditions then
precondition, then
let's talk about forced condition again.
I don't get Googlebot or Java.
I or not could convert
or Java public void.
Find the end simple
clause browser.
We are calling this method again from our
particular finding great common mistakes
before after done right then we
let us come to our log in feature.
Then let's come to a log in feature,
see what I'm going to do.
I'm going to commit
to this particular step.
I don't need
I don't need this a step here and here.
I don't need this a step also.
So let me remove this a step also from
now see
my scenario is getting shorter, right?
It's getting reduced.
Earlier we had five plus steps.
Now we have how many days? Ten.
Now we have how many steps to be
in the username password.
Click on log in button
Just three.
Right.
Let's try to execute it.
Okay. Let's try to execute.
Let's see.
I'm going to say log dog feature.
Okay.
It says smoke scenarios.
I have to execute both the scenarios.
So I'm going to put smoke here and smoke
here. Fine.
Both scenarios of smoke I have,
is there anyone
who is not getting what I am doing?
Is that anyone who has any question
can be checks? Yes.
Why don't these are the hooks.
Please check it Is
is there anyone who has any question
with this part
log in feature
by Yes.
I need you that moment.
So here now can you show the log
in feature economics open?
So now if you'll see here,
instead of using double slash to command
something, this is not your Java.
This is a feature file.
So here we have
we use this hash rate hash to commit.
Did you overnight
when I didn't smoke next in that
or what rate what
what over eight nine.
Number 13. Okay
no I provided multiple takes.
Okay let me simply by today's okay
don't get confused.
It's simple.
Remember grouping I told you
the user takes how to use their tag.
Now let me keep it.
Just one is of no fun.
Let's go here in class
and I'm going to run
working fine without my without my step
from grader to sticking the code
for launching the browser and everything.
It's taking the code from my hooks
now, right?
It's taking the code
so simple, launching the browser
or browsing the browser
we need to connect Whoops using
no that we don't need to connect.
We don't need to connect.
That's the beauty of the.
But you just mentioned the hooks
and because you provide it already, glue
it does deps.
Your hooks is already
under your steps, right?
Your hooks are already under the steps,
so it will get automatically identified
by gate.
So now you see this is the hooks back
here.
Now see what I'm going to do.
Do we need this a step.
We don't need it.
Remove it from here.
Do we need this user.
Close the browser nor remove it.
Do we need this step?
No. Removed simple
going to employ feature.
We need it.
No. Then removing booted the last step
not do it now.
See how simple it is great
how simple it is.
Can you see
very small scenarios right?
It makes an easy cutting.
So now let me show you another
very good point.
See what I'm going to do in my log
in feature?
You'll be blown up.
It lets in so they give us keyboard
to simplify the code.
Which keyboard
like hooks?
Yes, correct.
Got to simplify.
They like the background scenario
and everything got it.
Now see you said I'm having a lot of
than a lot of then not a lot of pain.
I don't want all of distance
I don't want this.
When then and keyboard.
I know what my scenario is working
how these things are working.
I know the both gain is always
my precondition
because now you see precondition is going.
Where is your precondition in your hooks
videos? Where is a most condition?
It is also hooks.
So this is just your actual actions,
right?
And the expected results
that you're getting in using sanity kind
categories.
Another important thing,
another important thing, before
I beat you in this particular topic,
you see hooks are applicable.
Well, Blade
hooks are applicable to all the violence
you see in Breakdown Down.
We have different systems in logging.
You should be able to remove this,
nor am I going to do it.
Please don't do it
even if it is available there.
We are not going to call it. Right?
If we are not calling it, it will be dead.
It's like those useless clothes
in your wardrobe
that you're having, but you're not going
to be at the point on time,
just like that.
Just so just keep give them, give them.
Because
it will look good when the time comes.
They will remember. The code
implies that you should see
is everyone.
But with this nice.
So now let me put this in the notes.
People often get confused in between hooks
versus.
Big crown.
So when we talk about background,
it is applicable
is applicable
1 to 1 feature file.
And when we talk about hooks,
it is
applicable to
the feature.
It means we can have multiple becomes
one way people classes,
but we cannot have multiple hooks.
For many people in classes.
There will only be just one hook
for the entire project,
one before one of the next big
point
will be just things to consider.
This one is also spelling mistake.
You guys are very clever, you know.
It is my stick, my
Olga still made amends too.
We didn't start with the actual paperwork
once.
We'll be having the complete part
of print, but it'll be blown away
by looking at the functionality
on another class.
Shows you.
This is the class view. Yes.
Cutting that gold is applicable.
No one features like
you are correct, but
yes. Yes. Yes.
Correct. Correct.
Your scenarios will be like this
only just the one step. Yes.
Yes is correct actually.
And this is correct.
That was about will tell you this that
we started from six, nine, seven, nine.
Those scenarios are
they will end up by just one later
synthetic everything will be in just one.
We will learn this trick.
So next time, when you take a data job
and when you go into the company,
you'll be having an out of in the computer
and just one of
it will be doing this.
So fine.
Let me come to this particular page.
The blind, which I wanted to explain
is this When keyword and keyword,
then keyword
given keyword, this keywords
are for our understanding, right?
This is what our understanding what use
user lot of when your dog did not open.
I do want this point no issues
but implicit all this keyword
with simple start.
Yes I missed it.
It depends.
It depends on the scenarios of scenarios
there definitely we have to use multiple
separate of scenario is just one minor
and if we see that begin
to cover everything in one line,
we will read like that.
Now you see, guys,
it's not going to impact on
any of the big impairments
in areas like this right.
It would be confusing anonymously
since we are learning right now.
That's why you think it is confusing
when it comes to proportionate rate.
They always you start at keywords,
even if by right this start street.
So keywords can be replaced
with a straight yes.
Correct.
But still you'll see if I right click
click on go to go under declaration.
It still does taking me to the same speed.
Can you see
it is
still taking me to the same state correct.
It's it's not going to impact
anything on my baby killer implementation
implementation is not happening now
Nordstrom
let's see whether it is running
with this strict sign or not.
The log in feature
I change in log in feature only extra
words for beginners.
Correct me with
working
fine.
Yep. Yep.
Right
now you'll see here and you see a star.
Star star again.
You'll see here stars does not rate
in using your console.
Always these things change
based on your implementation.
It changes
indirect scenario in a star.
No, no, no, no, no. No limit.
They could go better,
but not with the respect of conversion.
Okay.
Play with the element that is the way
it will not allow you to execute. It
is a shortcut to add
short
is trick is just a one click me.
But you need more shortcut learning
how to say this.
I don't know what kind of shortcut
you need to add
this trick.
What?
This is available in your keyboard
trade in your keyboard as well.
You just click.
It will work.
We can column selected by encoding or non
normal.
It would work.
Are there certain things that want
if you are very much professionals?
Right.
And if you guys are working day and night
with the scenarios, you think that
these works are taking my much time
and I don't want
this thing where I do mistake.
So Did you add this particular part
in your books?
Sure.
Did you call this clause?
But I was on my 13 year after folks
driver not wait we have just over
not good bit
like we should
see this is we have private
or what can you see
now if it's not closing
can you check whether you still have I
then I close the browser.
If you have that step that
if you have those systems deleted,
delete those steps. How can you read?
How can you start to make a trade
in good improvement?
There's one by one if it is already closed
and that is no point to call it again.
So it will be difficult read.
So just remove those two steps
from all of us to that use.
So this is in case if you want to do again
in case if you want really
if you don't want to do
no issues with your keywords,
find don't get
right.
It's optional.
Completely optional.
And of course this everyone.
But yeah.
You mean we will use keywords?
I was just giving you what needed.
That's the whole intention.
That is nothing else. Yes.
Yes. It is clear for any user.
Tell me any user reads this thing
or any user reads
this particular thing and what can easily
Imodium for sure, why not? But
is that anyone who is falling behind
long silence?
What happened?
Clear.
Done Good Read Good Nice.
So so far.
So far.
Class this mode Guys,
I hope you are not taking
a lot of pressure of burden of the class.
Right? Everything is going smooth.
I just want to make sure
please employ such.
Okay. That you
am very much
habitual to take decision
by looking into this camera.
So again, I'm talking to you right
by looking to the camera.
But I always forget that
I have this camera be
this problem is
anyone would be playing something
by your yourself, correct?
Yes, ma'am. Yes.
Can you open an employee? Fine.
Yes, sure.
They will be
it. Right.
But definitely you will be able to see
this is the big
one of the analogy.
This is the big
one of your entire learning.
If you know how to explain the preview.
Anyway, your clicks in the preview
are totally fake.
The V rate, if you can explain the way
I'm going to beat you,
if you explain your framework in that way,
you can have my words
that you will be able to
mark my words to record this station.
Right and draw it on my face.
If you don't get a job, just explain
the way I'm going to teach that.
Excellent.
All right.
Shall we present for this?
We're going to not
great.
So now.
Now, I was talking yesterday
about one particular
topic right?
You remember the topic we lived in between
two people working on spring, one
in spring, then spring three,
then spring four, and then spring five.
Right.
In this particular spring here, five
scenarios here you have ten scenarios.
Here you have these scenarios again in
your twenties was
So by the end of the spring
you'll be having five.
By the end of second of spring
you would be having four be
end of third, 30 and a fourth.
You'll be having these
scenarios in your bucket
now. Now
you want to check rate how many scenarios
you had executed in your spring, two
in your spring table
at the same time
you want to execute or best guesses
for smoke suite and on the very next day
you want to execute your test cases
in your regulations.
We did some
cutting
categories,
three tables of execution you have.
Is it possible that your scenario belongs
to a string?
Do belongs
to spoken, belongs to regulation is but
in all the three categories
you'll one see that you can do a not
Yes it can be a bar right
It can be a part of your for example.
But if I talk about
a logging functionality
could be implemented
in your second script, Right.
So that particular scenario for logging,
it should be a part of your smoke
because it is a key
functionality of the application.
It should be a part of the ignition order
just to get this.
And because you implemented it
in the spring, do
it should be a part of your second
sprint release in animals or not anymore.
So it means you're one
scenario can be with multiple categories
can be it made people point made fine
this is my log insanity.
This is my log.
The menu you see, it belongs to smoke.
It belongs to the creation.
It belongs to my is
correct.
Correct.
Is this correct?
Now, now, EMC,
if I go if I go in my this particular
Patrick DB, this particular part in my
if I go in my remote class, I have a bag
right here, you see smoke back.
I want to run my multiple scenarios.
So I'm c either right
and under those scenarios
belong to small category or run
those scenarios belong to
the ignition,
either
smoke a degree or ignition Category four.
Now I'm taking just one feature
by because if I take
all the picture paints everything right.
So this to save your name,
I'm picking one particular feature. So
let me go here and
let me change this particular
one to category shape.
Now, tell me how many scenarios
I have, what ignition
and how in this videos
I have four smoke one.
Now let's go into that another class
right here exclude.
But there are no class.
I am using all the keyword
what I'm using this
I'm using or keywords or means either
execute those scenarios having smoke
discussed or execute scenarios.
Having that ignition in this case.
So now in this particular feature,
total three. No.
So not totally actually today, two
because Yes, because
we have two scenarios of how we're going
to execute three scenarios.
This one is common
for smoke integration both
and this one is a specific pot
ignition industrial.
Or let me do one thing, let me do one
thing liquid delete the significant thing.
Now tell me how many scenarios
it will execute from here
if I write smoke or ignition,
this will execute because smoke is here
and this will execute
because regulation is is great.
So when I use this or keyword,
it means it will execute
either those scenarios having smoke
or those scenarios having your
regulation understood
industrial base.
Let's execute this looks executed across.
Now see it to go the scenarios in as well.
I'm coming to that point
also I just explain.
Great.
I just explained the point
guys do to explain
what are there different disciplines
we have in their Nagra.
I will it's once again significantly
like nasal radio
check this particular diagram
when I was explaining,
did you take this data?
Okay,
so now here, you see,
I already expected this print to smoke
and the creation rate.
So now let's see.
We executed
based on either smoke or regression.
Now I need to execute only those scenarios
that is that was developed
only in a spring
do it belongs to smoke a degree.
What the conditions I need was 20
should it should belong
to spring to second condition
it should belong to smoke industrial in
that is what I have to do.
I have to open my remote last
and I have to use this keyword as end
as and
here I'm going to do it.
So that's what I'm doing. City
sending fake.
Maybe you ask the question only for
So this is your logical end
and that was your logical order.
But no, no, that's fine.
That's fine.
So now you'll see here
when I use and keyword, what does it mean?
It simply means it will execute.
Only those scenarios think both prototype.
Even if you have just one
dead, it's not going to execute
because we need smoke
it as well as we need sprint.
Do it correct.
Now let me go into this and you tell me
if I have here smoke big,
would it execute the second one?
Yes, I will it execute the second one? No.
How many is it will execute in this case?
Just one. Just one scenario.
Let's go here and let's execute
this one.
See, just one scenario would good.
What are the standards to
categorize those scenarios
for smoke or two scenarios for smoke?
Who decides this?
So you decide this.
See just one test exposed.
Now, let me tell you how many of you
remember a couple of days back
I gave you the definition
of smoke integration.
Everyone knows the functionality
by looking right.
Looking at these three class
is going to amaze
the same liquidity once again scenarios
which defines the key
functionality of the application.
If you want to test only those scenarios,
we call it smoke testing, right?
All the scenarios, all the scenarios
when we check after every deployment,
after every fixed,
after every week of delivery to retrieve
it, four weeks depending on the decision
of the management based.
When you decide
and when you run all of your test cases
to check the health
check of your application.
We call it integration. Understood. Now
I see.
Great, great.
Even if you say 99.9%,
I will repeat the point.
I look like not even 99.
I need to inform you because I'm giving my
the incredibly will execute only gives
this with two takes
what with at least one day yesterday.
Got it.
Get it now. Here, here.
You see this and this
and or you can use it for multiple days.
And integration, right.
If you want to add another one then.
And onwards exist three also and so on.
Right.
Similarly you can use this for auto
also great or this
or this or this simply like this.
And so a lot of combinations
you can use understood
in the mix them knows that ideally it's
I was invisible to use the combination
right
anyway in the framework will see
and it will not be running on one last
maybe be having separate execution
point for that
and then will simply
then migrate all of this or just one click
and it will change the execution
of all the scenarios
that also we are going to do looking
now. Now you'll see
how many of you guys remember
we used multiple test
and do not exactly like
everyone knows it, right?
Everyone understood.
That point is to remember
very similarly.
Can we have multiple classes?
We can have. Great.
So let me do one thing.
Let me rename this class and
smoke
smoke trade
and let's create
another class called
duration.
No, no, I will coming.
I will commit everything.
So I'm going to be
from here.
I will copy this particular part
and put it in the integration,
will put it in the regression
and instead of smoke
I will put only the regression.
Now see, everything is changed.
All the smoke related
scenario will execute from here.
All the regression
related scenario will execute from here.
Right? We just need to
provide the part of this part.
Now we got two execution points right
based,
is this correct?
In another class,
the British smoke or regression
did it in log in feature on facility.
We don't smoke in seconds in a
in that case it will execute on
it will be executed in one
unit that we just did it
if we have smoke or regression
and in scenario
we have clustered smoke and second
regression, then both will execute
because is smoke, it will be found in
both point and regression
will be found in the second one.
Can you open regression?
Make sure everything is
same with the smoke.
I just changed this take from smoke index.
Everything else is same.
It is just start a leak of your smoke. One
to describe more trade.
Instead of writing a smoke in regression
you can write the smoke Grammar
integration.
Okay, you can read negative
so far.
So what everyone
Nice months now
Now let's come to this.
An employee feature
here here
you'll see like we are seeing user
clicks on it in button and user
in first name and last name.
Can you see this user in name and nasty
guys?
Can you see
let me go inside this particular
step.
This is what we are doing.
Are we doing correct
and we will to
remember I told you one thing that posting
the hardcore data is not good.
How many of you guys remember
data agreement testing?
I am restricting my scenario
to just one particular employee
data driven best seller.
Remember data provider.
We implemented their data provider
in testing so that our scenario can run
May eight straight
in the name and last name from site.
All right.
Any of those additions would.
I will definitely want
any of those additions.
Good for now.
Thank you so
so now
all are providing this hardcore data.
Someone asked
before that we can make this method.
Yes, yes, yes we will.
We Will do it without Benami transaction.
That is no data driven.
Without data driven,
there is no experience of the framework
without
there is no standard of the playbook.
There is no job.
If there is no job
that is more like that thing.
Certainly
we will make them better mid-priced
now for better grades,
they should be already discussed
right from the data
from their data provider.
But it was very big and we have a small
amount of data then it is good, right?
We already discussed this part.
One more thing Data provider belongs to
data, provider belongs to
this engine
can be used to deploy that here.
No, because we are working
we are dealing with younger.
So do we have anything particular?
So the answer is yes.
We do have one thing with the governance,
but we are going to implement.
No, no, Sebastian,
there is a part of later
discussion post will start from one part.
Okay, First will start from one part.
So step by step. No, that's fine, sir.
That's fine.
I'm glad that still
you have a knowledge of great Nancy Grace.
We will follow the step first.
What we will do initially is
first thing,
we are passing hardcoded data.
Correct.
First thing we will do is we will pass
this data from one byte
second thing.
So they will pass this data
in terms of in terms of grace
and in Windows.
Then we will pass this data
from data driven pass
and then we will pass this data
from external source.
All of this is discussed
today, one by one, already
passing their data
through multiple means fine.
And we windows data driven testing,
external and source.
Obviously excellent source
also belongs to everyone. Just
talk about report.
Yes, ma'am.
Report is also marked one by one.
One by one. Hold your horses.
We still have three more classes
for more classes after this one.
Right?
If I beat everything into this class,
what would I be?
Jump. That would be classes.
A lot of things are on the way.
So just a week for you.
So now first
we will pass this data from file.
Okay, Let's take one scenario
where we can pause the data from like,
let me come here.
Great
and let me go into my log in feature
frame.
Anyway, guys, do we have any place
where we have paused this username
and password?
Let me go into my log.
In the steps will be line eight zero
redlining when you know I'm seeing
where we have provided
all of my username and password.
Do we have any place
certain
configured properties?
We already have this
and we have this function as well.
How many of you guys
remember this function?
Read properties, configuring properties.
How many of you know this function?
This one gain property value configurator.
Everyone knows it.
Fine.
So let's go in the log in two steps.
Instead of passing this hardcoded data,
instead of passing this hard,
would it do not pass from here? Go
configurator, don't
gain property value by username
and we do this
and we do do this as friends.
Similarly, instead of passing
this hardcoded data, we can write
configurator door get property
when you and pass the password.
Now. Now this data is coming from where
this is coming from mine.
And remember one more thing.
You're doing this
for a username and password,
not for the second step,
which is this username and password.
Okay, so both things are different.
All right.
So just I'm passing this data from here.
Configured property supply.
First, let's check
whether this scenario is working or not.
Just bring it to synergy.
So let me go and change this
back to print.
Let me run this.
So I'm going to replace my hardcoded
data with my file connect.
See, it's
taking their data and then user ID
and username username password.
Good for me. Trade. And it passed.
So now let's come back to this
particular point earlier.
Earlier
we were passing the hardcoded data.
Okay, Now we are passing the data
from one particular.
This was the first material intention
behind.
Right?
So now we achieved this milestone
the most.
We are passing the username and password
from one particular property space.
We did same thing in our destiny portion.
Well,
is there anyone who has any question
related to this particular implementation?
What we did so far
one string squeak.
Should you get a positive?
Please answer my question.
Is that any question?
This is the code you see.
This is the code.
We have this great initial
log in the steps that you see
the VB called browser.
We are simply calling
username and password text.
Now see, everything is everything, right?
There is no hard.
Could it be a mistake?
Can you see it is no hardcoded data.
Everything is connected to
is. I can see
a lot of people are still typing the code.
That's why they're not to blame.
Let me come with
the big guys can take the good
so please check and your username
your passing just once
the one side quote not this level
quotes on the other side in the username.
That's why it is giving you the error
you undoable.
But you know what happens
sometimes if I do this straight?
Well they will not see anything here
right.
But they will not write.
They will stop writing the quote
I had this experience in back
when I was teaching grade and there never
was not that which obviously
I was telling them that, hey,
don't try to communicate the good,
but they do that.
It doesn't matter for them.
They do to tell them, right? Whatever.
You just keep telling them.
They will keep doing the things
what they want to do.
So at the time, I stop pushing the code
before the completion of the class.
But then I found some to some their age.
They didn't even have the code
in between them,
plus the duty when it does anything,
even though things were easy.
But just because they were not able
to write, they were not able to type.
They need to understand.
So from the beginning
they started this strategy
to commit to the repository
before every break rate or in between.
Obviously that is the fact that I'm
committing
the most number of times in the batch. 11,
eight times, ten times, 11 times.
I'm committing the code
because what is happening
then I'm explaining something important.
I'm not talking about every single one.
Majority of the students are busy,
Blade are busy with.
The writing of code they are writing.
They're busy with their code writing.
They're not giving any focus
on what I'm explaining.
And after some time
they come up with the questions.
I need to understand you. Please repeat.
That's what happening.
Got it. Correct and index.
What I always see
this code is for your reference.
You should always have the code
under the glass plate in your machine
so that if you get stuck at some place,
take my code late, take your code with me,
and then if you find any problem,
it would be easy for you to identify rate
that again.
Incorrect.
So even if you copy paste it,
you're not going to know.
Right.
But doing the same thing
If you're not taking my code
from the repository after the class, then
obviously you will make mistakes, right?
And you will keep making the mistakes.
You should be having one reference
point up to the class.
Great. Great.
Great, great, great, great.
That's what you know,
I found the intermediate to be
so that everyone can be on the same beach.
I know a couple of
you guys found me slow in teaching,
but again, I mean, it is the way it is.
The need of the hour is of now.
Everyone needs this kind of teachings
and that's why I'm doing this.
Earlier in the study,
I was bust in second class
and then I got a lot of messages.
It Hey, can you please slow?
Can you please go slow?
We are not taking
they're not skipping school.
No, it's not.
It's good.
It's not good.
And you got me confused.
It's good. It's tangible. What was that?
Got it.
Miriam?
Yes? It's the break. Well, with you.
Amazing. See,
during the show.
Great. We would.
We were talking about those important
points, the strategy
and everything,
and she was quite good the time.
And then suddenly when in just one minute
she said, I'm going to break it.
All right, guys,
let's take a break. Right?
Let's take a break for 20 minutes.
And after 20 minutes,
once again, place, great place.
Let's take a break for 20 minutes.
So now
looking at this,
we're looking at this picture file park.
We are done.
Thanks for is passing
the data from candidate properties
something right basic properties, but
we are done with this part.
Now let's talk about this barometer spark
how things done
how can do the things in better meters
to campuses.
I have my own inbuilt functionality
which you can use to perform data driven
testing in terms of barometers.
When I say data driven this right,
it simply means it
simply means that you can pass
multiple sets of data
in one scenario and that scenario
will execute a number of times
depending on the number of datasets
you're passing.
That is what we call data.
Is this going to
is this correct or not?
Based on data driven testing,
the definition of a test?
My first, what we will see
in terms of parameterization testing,
what how we generally do it,
we pass parameters in method
in terms of arguments.
We handle those arguments straight in a
actually script and we fill the data data.
That's what we do there.
So what we do not always
we do this
fine.
So instilling,
you know, sort of into gomber,
we have one key word going
synthetic.
We use this given to render
scenarios correct.
Could there be right
just a simple scenario
and we are passing the data
from some exquisite config file.
Then we are doing this point
all in old tradition.
We don't need it.
Another keyword we have in the Google
is scenario
outline
what we have.
The next is
this one is over one,
this one is updated, one.
All right.
So we need this in any outline to deliver.
Understood
industrial base.
Now see where we can find this
scenario later on.
If I go if I go, let's see in my
an employee feature,
if I'm going to write another scenario
here,
can you see it's a scenario scenario
outlining template.
If you see three scenarios,
scenario outline and templates
now see the difference
now see the difference here
generates in any you outline trade
when I see this scenario apply here,
see what I'm going to do first,
if I'm going to write scenario outline,
it is giving me the add of liquidated
scenario paid employee.
Let me copy this complete portion
just for a moment.
Copy.
This complete version is still
it is giving me the enter
y see when I go yet
it says example is section is missing.
For example section is missing.
What does it mean?
Example section liquidity.
After completing that after
completing the scenario, when you are done
with the scenario writing,
you have to write examples here.
Now see scenario outline and it is gone.
But what does it mean
when I read examples here?
What does it mean when I read examples?
And let me be
here, I will write See,
with this symbol I will read
both me
and again symbol and write it.
See me delete
again.
Symbol and write last name and close
by the same thing right here.
I'm going to write the best
best 1 to 3
grade middle name, Image's
last name, maybe best 4.6.
Again,
this ABC
middle name means last name
first X, Y and z.
Then again best 97.
When I missed
then best 3 to 1.
And you see this.
Can you see what I'm doing here
now? Now what happens?
My this scenario
this scenario will execute three times
because my first name we didn't name
last name how many did I have to wait?
3.3 things right now.
The point is how are we going to link
our exam buds to our scenario line?
How can we link
are examples to our scenario
outline understood.
How can we do this?
So let's see how we can do this.
Here we are going to write user interface
to me.
Right?
So now see instead of using this post,
copy this
it here first.
Now do this.
The quotes.
When you provide double codes
like this here
again, the way that works and here
you provide again
the key that you're passing below sake
and then you will put this key
with the last name.
This one.
Now you see the connection just to orange.
Nice guys.
Can you see
this cannot changes to orange one.
It means somehow it found this key here
correct?
Correct.
But we do not have any step definition
for this particular step
because this is the new step.
Remember, minus purple.
Congratulations.
Now color changes, right?
Collecting this. See?
First name, middle name, last name.
You passed these things right?
When you pass this three keys,
make sure these keys match with the keys
you're passing.
In your example statement.
Right.
They should pass in your examples
deeper understood this Borges
every
time it will begin in first vibration.
If we take this data in sync.
In addition, it will take this data.
In addition
it will make this data understood.
Make me right here called new take.
I'm waiting.
Could be the
best.
Is there anyone Who has any question
with this explanation
what I just explained.
Let me show you examples table
also here.
When you provide first name,
middle name
and last name, these three things
when you provide here, right?
And you pass via
later examples, people
first name, middle name, last name B b b
an e to be to be able to be three.
The m three the find
these is their data
that you are posting from your examples.
People
how things work
when you execute your scenario
right it fourth time
it will identify and it will get
these are the keys we are passing them
with the last name from here.
From here.
Right.
And then we are passing
these two in first orientation.
If we take this data, same thing.
Anyone will run for this data,
same scenario will run for this data.
So tell me my one scenario will learn
how many times
my one scenario will run.
How many times three times,
depending on the state,
depending on the state
or number of this dataset.
I'm waiting here
getting current categories.
Let's create this step.
Let's create this step for this one.
Now tell me if I want to create this step.
What is the best approach
to create this to
driver point?
So they're just going to the small part.
State Let me change the state to DDT.
Correct.
And let me check this
because I'm focusing on just one feature.
Fine. So I'm voting for this aid employee.
The feature
added employee don't feature right this
guy's right.
What I'm doing
right
now, Brian, is equal to to
one more thing is right
and is equal to put
good.
Let's proceed for that
which I
It gave me the step straight.
Can you see it
says that is Dem user does 2123
EMIs best 456
guys can you see it is not picking first
name, middle name
and last name or tier undefined exception.
It means it is already started
reading the data.
But here now see what is the difference?
It is speaking.
The string is string string
with double chords
you passed staking three strings.
Can you simply
the difference in
would be normal step
and the difference in between scenario.
We have to take out the hard data
from steps.
No, we have already order heart
rate from the step.
We are creating the new steps.
We have to do it now. See,
this should be the part of your employee
steps or not.
10 minutes.
They should be the part of good
employee steps right now.
See, earlier
we were adding data like this.
Right now we won't use this.
We will use this particular
see I have written it over here.
Now see how things work.
Tell me the first key is which one?
When looking into this scenario,
what is the scenario
when looking into the scenario?
First key is first name.
So let's take this key.
Let's take this key and go here.
Go here and you forced to me
second key
break would be your No, no.
Only means they can get your middle name
right.
So just take the middle name key
find good people you're here
put is in the third key is your
last correct
Is this correct case
is built still
these keys are agreed
by because we didn't use
we didn't use this keys right
anywhere find so for false name and
for forced them in last name.
We already have this data.
Guys.
Can you see we already have this element
supposed to stimulate.
So let me copy.
Let me copy this post.
The last thing you any question
why I'm calling this
any question, I'm
changing the keys to force it to see it
because it is matching with the argument
firstly.
So first name, what is the problem?
I am fine and I'm changing this last to me
and see here also to this last name.
Now tell me this.
Do I need to pass this data hardcoded?
No, no, I don't need to.
Instead I can pass my first name barometer
yet I can pass my
3000 in parameter right now.
See, both are black color changed,
but middle name is still great
because we have to take the locator
of this middle name also, right?
We have to take the locator of middle name
also.
Fine.
So let's go ahead and take this locator.
My my code work without.
Right.
This is steps.
How? Just two questions.
Why and how?
Yeah, that's fine.
That's fine.
Let me find this locator first.
It will find this.
Look at the first you age.
But I am going to treat
one missing one string.
So did you check that your implementation
part is correct in your feature point?
Is this the part that you did
correctly like this?
If it is like this,
only a good one, please check their
very similar to test engineer this.
Right. Right.
It was where it not yet.
We are doing this
in spec for them.
Really.
If I go here it is giving me would they.
This might be how many words variable.
No. Which but I that it was corresponding
file.
Okay.
All right. Tell me what is up.
This is my arguing number.
You know how parameters to make works,
right?
This argument which I'm passing right.
I'm passing in my method. Right.
It will consider as the first argument
that I'm passing from my feature point.
From my feature. Right. Right.
So the first one is going to be handled
by a first argument.
Second value will my second one
and third value will be handled
by the third one will break.
All right. Well,
then there's a part of Java
right now.
Let me write this one for element
of be.
This is to appear
and they should be slightly better than me
and this fourth
we didn't see
this one was not that I would
so what is this going to create
so far
but the second row, when you went to
the third, Benham would
circle the second web element, right?
The second element, I am passing the key.
So here it is dealing with this key.
See, in same because I'm passing the key.
Right.
So now here is key based
and from there it is argument.
This numbers matters from feature
vital steps in methods.
Right.
But inside the steps where we are calling
it depends on the key.
Key should be matched.
So it doesn't matter
that if I'm going to take this middle
name in the first place, it will work
because it is matching with this key.
And this is coming from my feature right
so far.
Is there anyone who has any question
with this portion?
No question.
Everyone good.
Now let's come here for an employee.
One say Sure, sure
is we no one's going to want to
see this one.
And I see smoke.
Sure.
There you go.
This is the smoke.
I was reading all those questions
that I'm getting in slack from students
or just taking to those questions
where they impact accordingly.
Am I missing another part but
must exist those resources configure them.
Are you not using system
to propagate property
multiple
then everyone?
But this fixed She will help note
something is fine.
Shall we proceed further?
Let's execute.
Oops.
It's not going to work.
Great.
But you'll see here
what I wanted to show you Quick
is one, two, three, four, five, six.
Best ABC, Ms..
Best x, y, z,
Best 9x7 and Ms.
Just three, two, one.
And employee number one.
Number two, number three.
But it employs too many.
Are these details
we were looking forward to.
Now let's actually execute them now.
Let's actually execute them.
Make it influence
going through the scenario
and see it is clicking on
the were employed successfully.
Fine let's go here and execute
run run run fine so you already run it
create a
link to it until yours is done.
Great. Yes.
Yes sir.
Thank you so much, sir.
See D do it all together.
Do it all together.
Aiming to make it work all together.
Everyone should have it
ready.
Now does this for the sake of degradation
right.
See the second iteration.
But the second one, then tighter.
Got it, guys.
Correct.
Did you observe one thing?
My browser is not closed,
even though I provided hooks.
Hooks should execute the network
opportunity,
but every time my browser launches
everything right, my browser launches
every time it is closed.
Sorry, my right, it's closed everything.
It means what?
Operating my employee
every time it is closed.
Even when I am working
with just one scenario,
even if
I'm working with just one scenario,
every time it open the browser,
it close the browser, open
the browser, closed the browser
time, opened it and closed. Why?
Because now the moment
I provided the negative
when distinguish consider asked
three scenarios are not ones.
So now you see below to test paused
How many?
How many test cases are passed?
Let's see the report also here.
Let me show you this report
from Target window
open in browser
going to Chrome. See?
And you see it says employee straight
for EST one, two, 3456 past ABC M is x,
y, z pass nine x.
The name is just 3 to 1.
First all these three.
Now you can simply take it
as the screenshot and send it to anyone
like this on the correct correct
already understood
in this report.
Clear
easy work
is there to give or take screenshots.
Oh no, no.
We will give you the screenshot
also with the reports.
Just because we didn't provide stuff.
Right or not, we already changed the next
so far.
So what everyone want in
of blame portion here everyone.
All right.
Let's go back to personnel you
right now time to learn something new.
Something new.
Let's say
obviously the hardcoded name
is not appreciable appreciably.
We already discussed
we cannot pass hardcoded data
and now we do not have hardcoded.
Fine.
Then what else we can do?
What else we can do? Simple.
Either we can pass data like this
in terms of so that it will work.
Getting
correct so that it executes
across multiple sets of data.
Or else we can do one thing
if we have just one stick of data
in that time.
If I don't want to pass by our hardcoded
data, then what we can do. See,
I will take simple scenario
which is ending one
log using good feature
right now.
See, again, I'm going to provide the
parameterized data but in different form.
So this time
if you see I provided scenario
and not scenario understood.
That is I provided scenario
not seen any new.
You see everyone
it means
it means if I'm providing scenario
and not scenario.
Okay.
Do any to provide exemptions do but
no, we don't need to provide any example
simple rate this time
I'm going to provide simple bar.
Now see what I'm going to do
here.
Okay.
Let me copy this complete scenario.
I cannot find.
So I am going to write user interface.
I added data
such as, for example, let's see
Sebastian
Vos to name just to make it unique.
Then the name would be
pristine.
We didn't name
and then would take
you get the last name
and you see what I'm doing
directly.
If I have the data, If I have the data
with the help of the well
codes,
I can directly aid what I can do directly.
So let me write it again here with
simple conversion rate, I'm
ready to convert it
just to just to make it unique.
Guys, if we have just one employee to add
or if we are dealing with this scenario
where we have to bias just one data.
So instead of passing from a new fight
or instead of passing this data hardcoded,
we can simply pass this data
directly from our feature
so we don't need to be bothered
about having other points in this group.
So far, the spark
questions is no.
Christin now understood
what I just expected.
Months now see, this time
I need to do just one thing.
Change time to become better
over and provide this right and as equals
to why I'm making it this one.
Making this one to
the right.
I don't want to waste time.
I want to generate system.
See again, because this data
can you see
again
we got this data right
so just take in the formula
springs from here
is taking the form of the strings
go in the method heart rate, go into the
an employee instance and add this step
and add this.
No, see,
I am going to pass this data as is
first need
this data as
Melanie and this data is
us now tell me
how I'm going to fetch this data
from my feature by Simple.
The first data we are passing,
it will be considered
as the first name
because the order makers from there.
But when I'm taking this data from here,
can I simply pass it?
Can I simply password here like this best?
Can I do this?
Students
and simply I can change this keys.
I can take this case from here to match.
Right.
So these are the arguments I'm handling
this data with the name and possible.
Any questions far in this part?
What tag we use?
Oh, yeah.
Indirectly.
Right.
Because we are passing the data
from to Uber, so we use it directly. But
you can rate and no issues
anything you can use personal.
You use see
with scenario.
Let me open this in any which scenario
I was showing it
employs steps
only this is the employees break
so it was opened earlier also
this feature by looking why not me.
What is the issue here?
Is there any other one with question
like this?
Any other one
with this question?
Why are we using this?
I told you was it belongs to you.
It completely depends on you.
Whatever big you want to use,
you can use that thing just to make it
easy, just to make it, just to memorize it
using this particular data.
So really easy to understand.
Correct.
To use the Michael for title. Right.
But again, know
all the vegetables, all the fruits,
anything you can use which are not
simple good timber scenario.
Another intelligent kind of
additional equipment keeps all
the goomba
scenario.
You already
let me copy this one
and paste it in my small part
and let's do it straight equals to false.
Shall we run it now?
Because we already implemented the state.
I will give you time based on quality.
After this.
I been given my complete work.
Let's extra
it added their data
and big employee correct.
Is this correct?
The students.
But if we don't run with Vegas
specification, those two methods
is to be recognized
because they are overloaded.
Those two methods wish to winners
of your preconditions and post condition.
You. We.
But then if you don't use tag
that will execute
all the scenario, right?
It will execute all those in the result
to make them you
to make the attribute correct
and this to there.
See, let me show you what you are
trying to say.
I got it. See if I click on this method.
Likely I told you to check the link
writing go to declaration.
It is coming to this particular run rate.
Can you see?
Can you see
it is coming to this particular work?
But if you go here and you click
here, right
click and go to
it is taking you to this one,
right?
So internally
it is linked because of example, stable
income leads, the example stable rate
so far.
So what everyone
in equal
but is by shows that you go
there in this article
is this hard coding as well.
So this is not hard coding.
This is not hard coding.
Hard coding means you master data in your
this particular part
trade in your method in the matter
passing them.
This is not hard for me.
You can change this data you put there.
That's what I saying.
So when you parse their data
from your scenario of you continued
at any point of time in this scenario.
So that linking of passing the arguments
is not going to change in this case.
Right.
It may specifically explain
you have to use this case,
but you have just one set of data.
All right.
You have when
you have just one set of data,
then you have to use this approach.
Otherwise you can use another approach.
What is that approach?
I already told you examples table right?
Guess.
Are these two things
clear to everyone? Nice
to proceed further with the third
rate.
Let's proceed further with the third one.
So here, if you see
file part is done
using example unstable scenario
outline is done
right now
we are going to talk about employee data.
Okay.
We are going to talk about employee data
busting from some external source.
Right?
So when I see the data,
which we are going to pass
from some external source,
we are going to use that data.
All right.
All right. Now what we will do,
we will keep our scenario in one place.
It will keep us any one place.
Can we do a negative testing of an admin
log in with example?
It will. Yes, sir, we will.
We will do that.
Hopefully we will implement that.
But also,
if you want, let's do that first.
If you want, let's do that first.
It would be very easy.
See what we are going to do
when implementing this logic, right?
See how easy it is to perform, to
raise rate to is to pass it first initial.
Then we will see how to pass the data
from extremely by going to log in feature,
going to log in feature, create
another scenario here
we trained Samad
you mercenary
you actually your vicinity apply right
so negative
next point
so I'm
entering here for username password.
So when a user
enters great interest
I'm bringing different
username
and password
activity.
The be verify the
added
user interface,
different username and password
activated by the error for
for all the all the combinations.
And here I'm going to write my examples
table.
I will boss username is the key
to password is the key
error message is the previous right.
Now let's check.
Let's check for this scenario
first go here on the application form
and let me loaded first from
look first.
If I write see the combinations
all the genius.
Let's create your menu knowledge
first.
If I write a valid username
embedded when it is an invalid password,
something invalid password
and I click on log in that
it is invalid credentials.
Can you see
it says invalid credentials?
Fine.
If I boss invalid username and
password, it says click on log in again.
It says invalid credentials.
Two guesses for requesting
invalid username, but it password.
Well, it is an invalid password. Correct.
Lucas's what would be the code biggest
medina man?
What would be the 30th
MP Great.
So I will pass worst enemy and leave empty
Both Incorrect
it is password cannot be empty message
in the fourth one
keep it empty and plus something here
and then click
it says username can not be empty.
Got it.
So it means for combinations
we can think of
is of now for combinations trade
and then error is changing.
So how many errors we are getting those?
The first one is invalid credentials.
Secondly, those are invalid credentials.
Third is password can not be empty
and for this username cannot be empty.
So all in one we had three error messages
invalid credentials
in both the cases that in three
error messages we are getting
20. So let's go ahead here.
Let's talk about one by one first
valid user and
invalid password x, y and z.
So what would be the error message?
Error message would be invalid
credentials, correct?
One day, please follow me.
Is this correct?
Nice.
The second one is I'm seeing
Cristiano
and the password is correct. One
again, I would it invalid
mentions rate
three days
and then the third one I'm begging is
leave this pool empty
user name empty and put the password
so it should see user name
and not B
can not be empty
username cannot be correct.
And then the fourth one I would see
take their data username,
leave the password blank and right.
So I should see
four again.
Not be empty.
Are these correct combinations or not? I
am saying
log in test just for waiting one day
for long.
Log in all empty combination.
All right. So again,
I think it's not going to change.
It will take you to the same place
because it will check first
for username,
so it will give you the same error.
That's why I'm working
when I'm using this log in big rate.
Or you can write log in validation
also whatever those in your
because you can keep.
I don't have any issue and providing
just a log point let me go into the smoke
and here I will provide
this particular scenario name is logging
missing and
balancing and
invalid
credentials.
Anyway, it will going to give you invalid
We have to provide
invalid credentials, but
even if you provide end,
it's not letting us log in.
Next my standard
within a fraction of a moment.
All right,
so now let's go here in the smoke part.
And here let's make it true again.
Let's make it to again my to make it to
my to make it was prevents
yeah good list can and do this to find
the running
for that one
common
logging feature.
Yes yes yes yes sir
It employee nature kind of
it came with resistance
so let me take it from here.
Let me go into my log in.
This is my log in the steps that you
implement.
Now see now see what I'm doing.
I'm passing here my next see username.
This would be my password.
This would be my error message.
Correct.
And the code for this log in username
and password I need to provide here.
So let's provide this
for username and password.
First I'm going to take from it.
Loading it should I must.
I'll get it would be this username
as the username value.
This would be my password.
LBJ should have passed
his username like this
when it was username like this.
No, this time I will pass username
value for my examples table.
Right.
And this boss word of a new
also from my exemptions table.
And then the third thing I need
is the error message.
So I need to identify
the look of this particular error
message link.
Next right click.
I'm taking this particular error message,
but it says spend message.
I can you see why I'm not taking text guys
That is why I'm not taking the text.
What is the reason?
Because it is.
Yes, because a text change
sometimes password, an empty,
sometimes username empty,
sometimes an invalid.
Credentials.
Wait, so we are just taking this look.
At the rate it might, it will change
and I'm going to write it when and then my
message is equals
to try to find it in by.
No, I.
And this would be the IED cutting
kind. No.
Now tell me one thing.
If I'm going to verify this message,
to verify the added message
in the same state, in the same state.
So just observe closely
where I'm going to click,
when I'm going to click on log.
But I have to click on my log.
It went down inside my business demo.
Leo Not
inside.
This is here to click on log
in within this after the username
and password.
Correct.
Because see, we do not have any other step
which we are calling after this
in single step only.
We are providing username,
we are providing password, we are
clicking on log into button in a minute
verifying the error message also.
Now remember that point I told you
we will learn how to write in edu in
just one
in just one in password
stored in the Visser
password or gives is the correct one
like this.
You will see.
Oh he is not in the know
we have to provide log in button for this.
You click on log in button.
This is the functionality, right?
Yes. Yes. Correct.
I got it.
But I'm in an undersea
if I provide it to me.
Right.
If I provide admin, if I click anywhere,
for example, like this.
See, I'm clicking outside of this
and I'm being built here.
Right
here.
So it's taking, digging, digging, digging.
Nice.
If I click here, for example,
if I do anything
you will deleted
and if I click on here, then it's changed.
But if my username
and then if I invalid password,
let's see something else once.
Now this time it's speaking,
you'll get by.
So next time would be stating credentials.
Fine.
So simple digging clicking on logging
button.
Right.
And then it should work.
Now guys, see here
another important point,
another important point.
We are going to find the message
let me completely
and coming to that point, I said
another important point I'm explaining
is I'm building unless I finish.
Please don't raise any question with me.
Please let me complete.
And then if you think
I missed something, then
another important point is
so far we didn't verify anything.
We didn't provide any verification
and validation check point,
right?
We didn't violate what we are writing.
It is verified.
It is verified. It is verified. Why?
Because the assertions be used
in distended electrical,
your testimony assertions.
Remember the assertions
we used those assertions
relating to your best energy
that we used earlier.
So the assertions
which we are going to use,
these solutions are related
to your G-Unit assertions,
which so we are going to use case
your following.
So force be posting.
See, what I'm going to do
is I'm going to read a string
added
or let me read it an x,
then I should read it expecting
it should be
address
message.
Don't get text.
Whatever the biggest
I am building on this particular locator.
Right.
I will store it in this adequate.
I will store it in
this part. Is this correct?
Is this correct?
Why? Why I'm not picking
is displayed method
because if the locator is displayed
it's not going to verify my error
message messages changing everything.
So even if I used is displayed, it's not
going to add any value value to my work.
Right, guys, that is getting my point.
Really good.
So now, now here
we have to use a solution.
So see, I'm going to write here, assert
when I write assert.
Can you see it does give me assert from
all are not unique
can you see are Jordan
G United is giving me the assert now
you need that list of all errors
in and use correct
so guys from this time we are going to
use the assertions which are coming from
g unique and not from best in g grade.
Since we are working on Google
with the unique part.
So please provide a search dot
all those
all those assertions that we had earlier.
We are using assert assert
to string fine.
We can take any one, anyone, any strings.
Now see how this assertion work this time.
I'm telling you
assert equals which I'm going to take
to assert because
is string message playing
with string mostly in string?
No, no, no.
Let's take anything.
Let's take anything. Assert equals.
So first, first I have to provide message
in case. In case.
If strings don't match,
then it will provide values.
It will give me the assertion error,
which with the message
so values do not match comma.
Then I have to provide the expected
one which is coming from my.
This one is coming from where
we provided the actual one.
This error is coming from my C
feature by this
and it is coming from my feature file
and here I'm going to provide the actual
one which is coming from my building
base.
Can you see in one simple assertion line
I provided straight, the value is coming
from one particular part.
It is going in one part
and it is comparing these two is together.
So now in case
if my assertion means it gives me
these added values do not match,
otherwise it will compare the value.
And if it is asked
then it will not give me any and therefore
it will not give me
any extremely positive message that you
understood
this part.
Understood or not.
So now,
thinking by rotational loop coming out, we
very simple rate.
This is very similar not
shall we execute this one now
which is going to test
against for different parts
initial log in please.
Sure that this is the log in.
But we must do this.
We must turn it and we will need line 49.
Sure will.
Pleased
with.
So these are just the arguments
that we handle now.
You'll see
these are just your keys
that you're passing
from your features right.
Uh, when I said this and that,
if I write this error, actually,
then it will ignore all the errors
when I said this,
this is just an assertion
that we are providing data.
So providing the assumptions doesn't
mean we ignore it,
will compare all the errors,
all the error messages,
and whenever it is going to give you
the added rate, wherever it doesn't match,
it will give you this message and.
Whenever it matches,
it will simply pass your assertion.
So it is just a simple assertion.
We are not writing anything to ignore
something
understood.
Shall
we proceed further and execute this call?
Nice, Ahmed. Excellent.
Excellent.
So that's what I was expecting.
Nice.
Let me make it false. And now let me, me
see. It
is going to execute four times
four scenarios.
First,
second,
third, fourth.
All four passed.
Can you see
that is going to suit
everything is biased.
That's why there is no message
from the associate part.
Every single thing is just fine.
Let's reload this project from there. Disk
open.
This could compare each team report
this time.
Can you see
these are the scenarios Be executed.
Write
any names of anything.
Actually should Thank you. Right.
Because this was the part
I was supposed to trade.
Now we are in the same flow, right?
We are in the same flow.
So it's called effect trade. Sorry.
One more time to log in two steps point.
One more time to log in is on.
Right.
Which is my log in the steps that you go.
This is the log in two steps.
There's just a you
lined up this task
earlier and I was supposed to
this as opposed to perform this later.
But now I will complete all this in that
he was related to example, stable enough
and then only which one to the next task.
Thanks for raising remembering me
when we have a break. Yes.
After completing this particular task,
which I'm going to take next,
you guys can take a break
for five or 10 minutes.
I'll take
what is here.
So you are writing a third at equals.
Please remove
this edit just write assert equals
an employee feature.
Next an employee feature show that you go.
This is the employee feature.
Why do you need an employee?
Each of you are dealing right
now with log in feature you
non-negotiable.
It is not.
It is not my writing, right?
These are not my my head here.
No, the other one. Sorry.
All right.
It's a log in feature.
Every one of you guys, every one of you.
Do you want my brothers and sisters
in particular, logging steps, please.
No issues, Jimmie. No issues. Vital.
So sorry.
You're asking.
It's good because you are trying.
This is the log instance instance.
I hope you guys are understanding
what I'm teaching grade
and it's not too complicated for you
going to manually correct
names.
I mean, we went over that,
but what if user study done
instead of the log in button
on in line number
53 of the people, how do you account
for the situation
line number four digit for default or read
more diffuse it hits the written
written means
they will not navigate dot backward
there's what can we
never not navigate navigated back
just to return in general
no written means sir
I mean in terms of command which command
in regards to ever not bigger
bank or keys don't in there
or just keys back to the bar
for entering the password.
Click on user name
which which one you mean
on keyword.
On keyword return means physical need.
Right.
So it simply removes the thing, Right.
Which you already have in the field.
Yeah. I got the question.
I got the difference on keyboard.
If we place in a big space
that is that again key.
So big removes the keyword.
Right. Whatever
he and it's simple but it's not.
It has nothing to do with this
alphabetic negation builder
name to their data one more time
assert equals did we use this is J unique.
This is unique.
Sebastian.
This is the G unit all urgent or generic
you'll see here import or do not do.
Can you see?
So we use this the word assert
like Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Give me 20 minutes.
And then after that I will give you the
is give me something.
I just want to show you something.
That's what
is this
line based?
It is assert equals.
So is why we use assert equals
when we have to
compare groups strings together,
do values together.
Right.
If we are going to compare
two venues together, we call it assert
equals equalization means
comparing two things to get at rate.
But when we talk about a safeguard
assert true,
it simply means
we are taking the Boolean condition.
That condition example is in
this particular element is displayed.
Right?
So if I see this element is displayed
is displayed.
So what does it mean?
It simply means if it is available, it
returns true, otherwise it returns false.
And a student
everyone understood this.
What kind of assertions we used.
Right.
So now tell me what you guys need a break
or should we continue?
We should continue.
All right. So let's continue.
Right, for one more topic.
And then after we give you the break.
Okay,
I made some type of
noser credentials.
So please, babe, Capital
II of invalid credentials
at least see what I'm typing here.
See, it is I would give an invalid
would give me the like.
Can you see
I wanted this to run rerun it already.
Maria, we're running
it useful.
All right.
I will come into the repository, ma'am,
and then you'll be happy.
Okay.
Yellow Valuable of the property index.
All right.
No, no.
Raise the
Then we use examples table here.
We added, we added rate.
We added here all the keys in one state.
We added all the keys in one nested.
Can you see it?
Everyone
break.
When we added this scenario.
Here you see we added all the keys
in one state only.
But this should not be the case
wouldn't be used
when we are dealing with indirect
examples, they will instantly apply
so we can add these points.
We can add these points in multiple lines.
How big we should.
It says a domain user
is successfully logged in. Correct.
So instead of writing
admin user, this time
I'm going to write it.
This time I'm going to write like this
admin user is successfully logged in
and this line many user readers
username and password right
when user interface username and password.
Cool. It's
great. Let me provide here
like this.
And now.
Now here I'm going to write for scenario
outline.
I'm writing here.
Examples Table and examples
given I'm going to provide write the name.
So let me copy and paste to your
username password. Right.
So that we provided the connectivity
for this document each and every 1 to 3.
And then here
I will going to provide this data.
Me What would be the name of the element
simply
understood?
What does it mean when I'm dealing
with scenario outline and example stable?
I can boss whatever the keys
I'm mentioning in, the example stable.
I can pass
all those ds in multiple steps as well.
So even if I have 15 or 20 years
which I need to pass,
introducing this depth
with one example table
we can use why I'm explaining this point
because I got one
is Stephen Hawkins in the last batch
last to last batch actually
write in batch nine and he asked, Hey,
you are passing multiple keys in one
particular step, for one example, step one
Do I need to write multiple examples
the boss data in multiple instances?
And then I got
this idea that how students can think
out of the blue, right?
That's why I'm explaining this point here.
This is the point I wanted to expand.
So now see here in the lines
in lines I am passing different keys.
Right?
But the same examples table
I'm using to perform this particular part
understood.
Industrial days
or red days.
So now, now what I'm going to do is I'm
going to verify, I'm going to redefine.
It means a successfully logging or not.
I will put one more solution in in
one line and passing username and password
so it's okay to need the start
instead of when and then yes, yes,
it is completely fine because
as long as you are compatible, it is good.
It is completely acceptable.
No that point.
So now now here
I'm going to use this as bridge to deck
because this is the date
I know which I'm having in unique.
Let me take it here from this dry
and make it
look why I need to create two steps.
Right case.
We need to create two steps on log.
Let's run it.
Let's run it
now. See how many steps I got, guys?
How many steps I got you
two steps.
Fine.
Now, see, we have to divide on keys.
Going to log into steps.
This time we have to divide entities out
first.
First, we will provide here
username value and here are
password value.
In here we are going to provide are
and mean well understood
and this provides
similarly similarly similarly here.
I'm not going to provide anything right?
I will simply write one thing
the locator of that particular one.
Right?
You can provide this associating was part
the thing.
If we keep simple.
Oh, I'm going to take the locator
of this particular one call it mean
point three.
If we take this one
and I'm going to take this particular
look at the point.
So this should be the look,
baby will come.
So I'm going to take this
look at I will trade with the neighboring
element, push forward message
the sequence to try to find the element.
My ID
and I put this and I'm writing
one assertion called assert
not assert
assert true
what to bash
good message don't is displaying
bad case.
You can use this particular one
if you want to use
If You don't want to use you don't use
great when you provide this outlet.
But everyone knows now, right?
Everyone knows how to write this assert
don't assert equals.
I'm using the different one
so that we know how to make different kind
of assertion.
So this time I'm using a third thought.
So too.
Is this okay to everyone everyone?
Is this okay to everyone or not?
Quick guys, come on by.
You guys are getting lethargic.
It is just a matter of hold
five more minutes
and then you guys will be on break.
Really enjoy this for 5 minutes.
Guys, please.
Everyone ready?
Let's go.
Here, log in, feature check and a slogan.
Nice.
Going to smoke.
Make your right and from draw go false.
After making it false.
Let's run this time.
Well,
no such element exception for
button log in.
Why? Let me check.
Let me check
log in button.
We worked already, right?
We vote already
for logging with the state.
We vote already for logging in now
after I get written,
it worked.
Here, let me go into the feature.
All there is. There's a problem there.
A problem
We calling this log important here
and we are calling this logging button
one more time in our steps.
Now see what is the issue.
See when I go in my steps right here.
Also, I'm calling logging with the
race. Can you see
here also I'm calling this logging button
in username password.
And here also I'm
calling this logging button.
You see here also,
I'm calling this logging button.
There's the problem.
That is the problem.
So this case in this case,
what I have to do basically
is I have to simply remove this code
from here.
I have to simply remove this code.
It now,
if you see, my code will definitely work.
So let me go here
and let me execute my actual scenario.
Let me this one right
now, one of good.
No, it's working fine.
Is it working fine now?
Promise you'll see
so far.
But credit goes to you
that you raise this point
so that we ended up with this.
All the scenarios with all these scenarios
and you see
all of the scenarios.
Brady's
ISIS username Normani log in.
Wait minute log in and every single thing
right, right.
Based, can you please
show log in two steps for us?
Sure.
There you go.
This is the log in two steps.
Would you briefly repeat
what was the last error?
Certain is what happened
was in the in this depo.
And so here in this particular method,
I was in the username,
I was entering
password and I was clicking on log
in, would read all the three things
we were doing
because we were copying the code
from this particular area.
That's what we were doing.
And again, in my log in feature
I was calling the clicks on log in.
And so what happened
after clicking on log, it wouldn't
actually, which was happened in this step.
Right.
My console was on before beach, but then
I provided this user clicks on log in.
Right?
So when I provided
this particular information,
it was unable to find
it did find this mark understood
and destroyed base.
Then we are listing different options.
Do we need a different project folder?
Or we can use some other classes?
No site for different websites
radio to create a separate project.
That's way
one application, one project there.
So we followed the standards.
You can not be having
multiple applications, one
because every website
is having a different functionality
and when we say different functionality,
it simply means different code,
different locators and everything.
So we can make a new package. No. One. No.
Then you have to config,
like I said, for framework, right?
Everything should be unique.
Delete completely depending one project.
So if I'm making one project
I observe the application was the nature
of the application and then only
I implement the logic in my framework
according to that particular application.
That's how things work.
If you do one framework
which is actually implemented based on one
application, you put it in the spec
and one it's not going to work.
Understood.
Everyone,
can you upgrade the code on GitHub?
Yeah, I'm going to do it.
Let me just to complete the explanation
then.
Only I can do it right.
So let me edit, let me edit me commit
this code in the repository
before we go on break it all this point
so that it would be easy for you,
as always, to understand this part.
Let me do it and let me push the code.
Also the repository.
So now the code is available
in the repository, right?
You guys are living all this code. Okay,
You guys are reading all this, everything.
You guys have not understood everyone.
Everyone understood.
Great.
Now, after this, we are going to learn
two very important topics.
So I said already I've committed
to my code in the repository.
Great.
I cannot open my good these understand
multiple times on every single.
Please
use the reference point from repository
one. Right.
Because those instead of waiting
I see better messages also in my slide
the data that having problem.
If I open one thing again and again
find this so far.
Any questions?
Anyone?
Is there anyone who has any questions
or Firebase
everyone good.
Understood.
Then let's take a break.
Which we are going to start
is blasting the data from one another.
We all read from one another.
So far what we see
all the combinations
hard order data,
then replace it with some external file
such as config properties by
right
associated bust.
But I
hardcoded data then we pass from file
that is considered proper despite
after they deposit their data
from our examples.
Grade from example stable grade.
When I'm a transition,
we have seen both the scenarios
in one line
they mean multiple lines passing.
They keep correct.
Is this correct? But
now we are going to talk about
the fourth one.
The fourth one, and the fourth one is
Sebastian
the Go.
We are going to talk about
what we are going to talk about now.
You were in grade four, but
yes, I still remember.
So now we are going to talk about data
table one right?
Why? I explained intentionally
this particular point.
Which point?
This one,
when you see we can pass
table that data from examples.
Table in multiple lines.
Right. In multiple lines.
So this example tables
is applicable to my entire scenario.
Understood.
I misspoke.
It is applicable to my entire scenario.
However, when we talk about data table,
it is applicable to mine
just one particular step.
Is this understood now?
What I just said
is applicable to my one particular step.
I'll read
Fine.
So now see how things works,
what the scenarios, what the scenarios.
We will see
one by one for their data table.
Right.
Let's dig
the really forced scenario for detected.
But again,
the intention is to add multiple employees
three or data doing this to getting
so data driven testing
using one hardcoded data,
then considered properties
by then some data from passing
the parameters of something,
for example, stable now using data
stored
or understood.
Now using data table just to move
already.
Nice.
So now we are going to use
this particular portion called detectible.
From our feature,
we now see how detectable what
what happening is here.
I placed my link right.
So when I read something right here
on Sticky, I'm reading the messages.
So when reading those messages,
I'm on sync.
And now when I'm writing the code,
I'm looking here.
The camera is available
here, Slack is available here.
That's way.
If you talk about another camera,
then that camera is a database, right?
So I'm not looking there.
I'm looking here and.
All right.
No, no, that's fine. There's one.
The setup is very
weird.
I would say
diversified, right?
One thing available in this place.
Then my light is this place.
And then my system here,
my, like, here, and then the camera there
and then like this.
So very distributed system
findings.
So this time, this time
I'm going to add a scenario, see?
So now
what I'm going to is
in this point, in this point
we have the simulate nice
in this point, we have the same data.
Right.
Let's copy this.
It's copy this for our scenario.
Right. And pasted here.
We are not going to use our blame
only scenario we are going to use.
All right.
And here I'm writing code data table.
Now just see the beauty
of how to compare works.
I'm going to write here.
I'm going to write right
in all these things I'm going to write.
And then when
the head
employs and
redefine
the editor.
Now tell me, guys here,
see in this scenario, also
build employment complex unemployment in
this scenario also build an employment
in this scenario.
Also build an employment
and everything is the same
or not
everything is going to make sense. Yes.
Jimmy Cutting does
it make sense to keep writing those things
again and again repeating those things?
No, we can do it in
one particular tag called Big Round
and then we keep this part
now simply removing from this system,
remove it from this particular scenario,
remove it from this scenario
and then remove it from here.
So now in this one step, I'm
going to add user
and they will verify they use it as well.
Okay.
Alright guys.
Now let's see what I'm going to do.
I'm going to write here it is, first name,
then the
middle name, then
lastly, edit
Let me use the same data.
Let me use the same data
guys.
Now see what is the difference
in between normal examples table
and this particular table?
What is the difference?
You see?
Oh, Glenn, look, fine.
I'm talking about the difference.
No, see that your client
that is also white.
It is a normal you will get get
not identical bit.
It's kind of the same.
First Evelyn's case,
we are not using example statement because
like anything,
we are not posting these keys here.
And based on these case,
we're passing values here.
We are not crossing any keys here.
Right.
And you see,
it means there is no linking of my step
to my data,
even though my data table is applicable
only for one estate.
And that step I have already added here
right step I already did here,
but still I'm not calling any of the bet.
And we do these variables
in my particular step
right?
Right. Yes.
So now see the magic magic of teaching
about how to convert books.
It knows it very but very intelligent.
Learn how things work.
You I go in my look,
I'm going to write for my third
employee feature.
The bag would be
data table and let's make it right.
It is equal to
let's see in an employee
which I do have this take yesterday with.
I have this take
executed.
So when I actually execute
can you see this time it is giving me
something else
that is
this time
the implementation of the step
is something else.
Can everyone see
first?
First let me copy and then I read that you
first let me copy and then I bring that
you hear
how things work in this particular scene.
It says, Right, Everyone is opening here.
What I'm thinking it's
not everyone is agreeing.
They see it is right code here.
Then does the phrase above
into concrete actions
for automatic transformation.
Change your detective.
But it means the one
we provided in our feature find.
It says change data table to one of one
topic means from multiple things.
You can change it into one of either list
grade or list of list
or list of man
or only man or map with list.
Right?
And this with an element or key
or a new grade must be string integer
float, double bind, short long
big integer or big basically.
All right.
What does it mean?
It means either we can back as a list
or we can big as a map,
or we can take whatever I want to do.
Point now.
Now, let me show you something
really important.
Another see,
I'm going to tell you
at this particular point here,
when I'm passing the data in detected
when I'm passing
like this first name, if you understand
this point, then further and further
an explanation would be very easy.
Middle name, last name.
You want
to run the element
in to
improve the need to be 3 p.m.
3 p.m.
three.
Can you see these three points? C
This is what first names
these.
This is your key.
This is also your key
and it is also European, Correct?
Is this correct? Grace
What is this?
This is your value.
This is also your body.
This is also your
industry.
What I'm explaining in.
So now when it returns first name.
So there you will get one key
and you will get one value
when you want
when you get renamed,
it will give you one key and one value.
When you will get last name,
it will give you one key and one
value correct.
And in case 111213.
Similarly, in the next line
also it will give you one key, right?
And then one value and then second value.
And then the third And
the third line also will give you a key.
And when you key and value key
and when you rate,
what does it mean?
Give a new key value
given new every single
every single rule,
every single rule is returning.
One man
keys values means one map.
No gear map one
keys values between
another map from here, keys and values
between another.
Remember from here.
So now, how many maps
this particular portion is returning and
how many messages returning?
This particular table?
Three maps, three, four premiums.
Good.
It is returning with three particular
maps.
Now is recommended,
and I'm going to get just
three maps every day.
So it can be in number of maps,
it can be in number of maps,
read it can, and then maps, 20 maps,
30 minutes, whatever.
I don't know how many maps.
So it means what? One, two, three.
When it comes to count,
it is simply a missed from
it is simply a list of map or not
multiple maps.
If I want these maps together, I need to
keep all of these maps in the list.
Have to keep
all of these maps in the list.
And then what I have to do, I have to keep
every single map in the list
because every row is returning one
map based on date and venue.
So when based on keep and renew,
every single row is returning the map
for every note and getting multiple maps
every row and getting unique
maps, multiple haussmann's, multiple maps,
I want to keep all of these
things together.
It means I need a list of maps
and a
list of maps.
Now see now see the beauty of the Google,
what it sees here
when you come in the Gutenberg part here,
when you come,
it says automated transformation, infinite
automated
transformation, you just need to call one
is bibs from the to jumble
and it will automatically transform
your maps and to list
it will take your entire data
in terms of maps.
It will convert any time to list and
you will find no need to read any code.
Now let me show you.
First, we will hide this data table.
Instead of writing this,
we will simply imported.
Right?
So just read like this table and import
class
from EU not to convert
or but imported from.
I'll start to convert
dot data table please imported
imported uses this data table here
today.
This is the object of the data table.
Which object of the data?
Their data will be used here.
The object trade of this particular
one correct?
Correct.
Goes.
Not the next thing.
The next thing. Let's do it. This part
here, I'm going to write a clean code.
I need a word
first.
I'm going to write my data.
They may not exist as list as map.
How how need as maps on this list based on
as maps read.
So let's take it as maps first.
Now, when we're taking this as maps
after this,
we are going to take
all these maps in the list.
It means list of maps.
It means list of maps, meaning no
place.
It is returning all the maps,
but we are not making the list. Why?
First, collect the map added in the list.
At one day we are going to use one day,
not not complete data.
So we need to store all the data
which we are getting from the map.
Once we are getting all the data coming
from the maps will keep it in the list
according to adequate amount.
We can use some expensive data.
ABC 2.1.
rejected depending on the request. Right.
So now I'm going to write here.
See, I'm going to write your list of
list 12th map,
which I need not only because
what is the nature of my username
and password or the enforcement
element lost, then what is the nature
screen?
So my key is my key is string in
my response was correct.
Is this correct?
My DS is spring and my values also spring.
I'm simply providing
the name called employee
Employee names.
And as to the meaning of this line,
now what I am doing,
I'm taking all the data in terms of maps
and then via calling this particular line
and wording good
all the maps and then adding all maps
one by one to the list.
And as
we will like this complete could also mean
we will read the data from Excel,
we will read it will get it.
It's in our book.
It will do it right now. Is this okay
Lives Project folder.
Now I'm going to I create the values
one by one from the list.
Read from this list of maps
admins employs list.
I'm going to get the data one by one.
How delegates to read the data one by one.
What we generally use
for each loop read advanced follow
So from map.
From map which I'm having on screen
along the screen
here, I'm going to provide my
employee.
When my employee names
which expression
it is asking me to remove.
Oops.
And it is called
Yes, I removed it
already.
Map import
human.
This one it is from delegate is the image.
It is from Java.
You would be simply writing.
I was trying to name on like
soda.
Dennis
can you please read java you delegate map.
Can someone please put this in this
like this particular input
so that they can take it
map and
list read We can take this bottle from w
these grapes are from W
we can take it fine.
So far Everyone good? No.
Now their data. No other data.
I'm getting every aberration made
from the map I will read.
Was true
administrator done supposed to map?
Correct.
So from that, whatever the value,
then I'm going to store those values first
before using them.
So I'm writing the screen
name value
yet I'm going to store the value from here
from my in
range, from my and not released
to receive the data from any map
which give me use which method we use
if I want the value
or if I want the key we use.
Which method in maps
the way we use don't add
that any less to add something great.
Be used or put method
to add something in the map for use.
Don't get the method we use target method.
Great.
So now let's turn here.
Here the value which we are going to date.
We are going to pass this keys.
Now tell me which keys I'm talking about
here, which we are talking about here.
The key which
I have provided here, this key
first name with Limited.
Lastly, I write this keys.
So now,
now I'm going to end the keys here.
First name
and then similarly
we are going to get it for
the name and this one,
we are going to get it for last
name, right?
If we look at value
and this one I'm going to critically
last understood
and this one
I now know what I'm going to do
is simply I'm to add rate.
I'm going to send this data
in my actual bar.
So this is my first name, last and middle
name and last and write
in distribution, correct?
Is this correct?
Okay, fine.
So when I'm doing it right,
when I'm doing it,
let me first ask you something, guys.
First, ask if something
I wrote
this particular point inside the
my for each loop
inside of map for each layer last for
what is the reason behind this?
Because you want them to really find a mr.
detectable
to me
yes vibrating multiple employs
the that each value.
We need to do it.
We need to look for
No tell me one thing I say to your user.
Adam was deeply embroidered right
and verified the added force
to let me menu this part and then
I will take you to the further part.
Looking
I'm seeing this is right last name
I think is almost.
I know.
Fine.
We got this doing that now see,
I don't notice you.
You're going to correct that. Correct.
Now you see is how things work.
I wrote my first name,
I wrote my middle name,
I wrote my last two rate based.
These three things I have correct.
For example, this is the value.
Do you want me to be three?
Do you want to improve proof
3d133d3 straight days
when it returns here,
When it returns here, the first believe
it will give me this key
and this values, right?
So here the values become B1 first rate
which I will be passing to this part.
Then D from middle name
which I will be passing here
and from here value would be d13
which I would be passing here.
Correct.
Then in the next iteration because still
the fourth
loop is going on, the for loop is going on
in the second addition, it will return.
Do you do do do do do do spend
which would be passing here
in the third articulation
because still my loop is going on.
It returns this keys and now this venue So
80 1d3d3
Undisputable is how things work.
This is the key.
This is the value line
which I'm going to be one by one
by one, one by five.
So far
anyone has any question in this part,
is there anyone who has any question
in this particular part
strings.
No question.
Now, let's look at this scenario.
If I want to verify,
I need to click on also or not any any
I need to
consider that also correct?
Correct.
I need to click on separate and also fine.
So now let me go inside my
that is my third of steps.
There you go.
After this, I need to consider what time
do we have any functionality possible?
Yes. This is the place it
clicking on same button.
Is there audit?
Is there non non.
And then what is the next thing?
Screenshot really?
We need to verify first more.
We're not looking
what's been screenshot as of now.
It means we need to put assertions rate
assertions.
So assertions in homework is of no for you
it isn't old.
What I'm quoting here is it will work.
I will keep you.
I will tell you this assertion also.
No, no one important thing
needs one important thing. See?
Let me do it manually.
First,
remember when we talk about
table examples,
what is the main difference?
Remember in examples, double
hooks worked before every scenario.
Another arbitrary
and it updating all the employees.
My hooks were closing the browser
and it.
But now when we work with detected
with my works just one day
it means it means if I go on be
if I click on an employee,
if I go click on an employee part
from here,
and when I add some of the employee, let's
add this one, this data in listed
now when I click on see,
see when I click on See Wonder,
I will be on this page only.
I will be on this page only
Understood, Understood.
It means my hooks are not going to work.
So when my hooks are not going work
in the code itself,
I have to come on to that screen again.
All right.
So my big down works just one thing.
My bitcoin also works for just one day
we are going
to click on an employee current.
So now see my hooks work.
How many times, how many days?
One day my big go to works,
how many things
one day trade so hooks
background What work did one day point
after editing the employ?
I am on this screen mostly after looking
at this screen, where should I link to it?
And then that employee
I have to click on this employee.
But then again.
Right.
And then I have to
have the details correct.
So now just imagine when you are using
example stable, when you are using
examples, stable vicinity of line,
there you were unnecessarily logging in.
Everything okay.
Clicking on promotion, click on it.
Employee option,
then adding the employee, then step button
then verify their the user that ended
or not and close the browser.
Then again opening the browser, then again
entering username password.
Then again click on promotion and employ.
Isn't it a waste of time?
Even in the scenario itself?
We can see if I have to add employees,
then why do repeat all the steps again
and again?
I can read just one step
that will repeat again and again
and all the employees open the browser
when they closed the browser.
One thing that's excluded and implement
this after
clicking on save button
what verification rate?
Let me intentionally put
some training or sleep because I know it
is going to take some time.
You're operating in the data.
Fine.
Let's throw this exception.
And now after this,
we have to click on an employee.
So where we have the
this imperative based and
we have right employee have been able
this is the one we have an employee
would not find its copy this piece of this
underscore what I'm doing
create not sleep
3003 seconds
so that you know
applications loaded properties
guys this to come back again on
employee is green screen
because pools and big girl
who spend big on looks just
one thing looks ten big trolls works
just one thing is
this kind
is this correct Gates What I'm doing here
because we are dealing with digital.
Yes, we are dealing with it.
People break.
We have any question with this code,
this piece of code,
what we've written over here,
there's clear to one.
So now
now if you go in your employee board
and you'll see how many scripts
you have written in your agents
in any
how many steps, just one.
Right.
And just think this situation now
where you have your background trained,
which is common to all us
and then using this feature,
you have your hooks which is taking
of your precondition and post condition.
So all you need to do
is you just need to put your piece of your
your piece of code in just one particular
step.
And step will work for you.
Right.
All right. This
shall we execute this one
line 67.
Can you expand?
Please do not detectible 967
This part you mean
I see
this is the object of your data table.
Greater detail,
how you call your deductible,
which we have mentioned in your feature.
Right.
So you need to call your deductible
that you agree to an individual point
in your method actually.
So with using this particular with keyword
from the part you are actually calling.
So you see we are using this
deductible object and taking this as maps.
So whatever the values be
have defined over there in, that region.
Right.
It will take those values in terms of keys
and police statements map
and then we're adding all these maps.
See, this is not map.
This is map segments, multiple maps.
We are digging right in these maps
and adding the list as a multiple maps.
Right.
So taking the list of maps,
that's what we are creating here.
We got a list of maps here.
We are putting it in advance for loop
one by one zero is returning me
one map giesen when this we are reading
all the values based on the key.
So we pass the key.
We are getting the value.
This value we're passing
not actuals in any read
or write.
Nice.
Could we also use implicit
with individual rigorously? Yes.
So Sebastian, we can use.
I have a very good option for that.
I think they do their duty
and they do their part.
But let's let me execute this part now.
All right.
So let me go ahead and execute
this now.
Let's see how many games
Web browser executed
saved, viewed for 5 seconds.
Click on an employee
at second data
done,
wait for 5 seconds, click on an employee
and their data
frequency
employee only exists
because it already
existing the employee decline.
And then again, click on paid
rate.
It's passed
because there is nobody positions.
That's my response. All right.
So now see, based on number of data
which I have provided
in my region
by Right, it executed my best case.
Is this clear to everyone
using the digit even like this
based
everyone needs nice
it's you.
Let's
see the another usability with already.
Let's see another usability remote
we can use for this yellow
movie can use that, but instead of this
I would give you another good option.
So now.
Now let's see the another way.
Let's let's do the under this scenario
here.
See let me go into their dashboard which
this is the beach agent really open rate
might open this page
can you see as an admin taking element
beam leave time recruitment performance
dashboard and added options
rate So far we are coming on this page.
So far we are coming on this page.
We are not,
but we are not actually a very fine rate.
What are the options
we are getting on this particular page?
Right?
So we never know
whether it is getting all these or not,
so we have to verify it or not.
It is to keep functionality
or not to these options,
but it is.
Is this the key functionality or not?
Yes, it is the key functionality. Right.
So I've got to log in first.
I have to modify it all these options.
I can get all these options I can get.
This is
this is a good form of detecting with
the simulator
team will be able to use here also
when this time when we are actually going
to use this data table
in this data will be
will not use key and value.
We will simply use values.
What we will use simply
we will use only values.
No key value
because there is no value available.
Right.
So we were allegedly
used as windows are will be leave time
to recruitment in everything.
How we will implement this.
Let's have a look of it.
So the new feature
which I'm going to create now is my is my
dashboard door feature
is my dashboard or feature.
See page
functionality.
And here I'm going to write some elements
that they're going be
it would be simple thing
I'm going to go is dashboard
just to give make it easy dashboard
reading for the baseboard
really fine dashboard or text
based verified dashboard.
Perhaps
so, but any questions?
What I'm doing
the meaning is tips.
I think the meaning of steps
I think would be seem great
where we have this particular one
user interface
where it is any password to user playing.
So log in with the trade
in. We take this particular run
successfully locally.
It would take this three steps from here
if we put it in my
name.
Can I use the three steps
a lot to me, right.
1 million times we use these steps.
If someone says we can't use
correctly, you
next time then
then ready by
all the
all the dashboard steps
then verify all their dashboard. This
All right.
Alright guys.
Now see, by using the data table
how we get good data
table is applicable for how many steps
data table is applicable
for how many steps?
Just one step.
So when my detectable is applicable
only for one step.
So here for this last step,
I'm going to write my data
table point
No issues deliberated one by one.
What I have here in my data, in my
application and the motion
I have the option.
I have an option.
I have
group
option based.
Take this building
as I'm writing here, performance option.
And then the next one is dashboard
option and the next one is
an entry option.
Is this correct?
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight, eight.
Live time.
The group main performance dashboard that
we did, I took myself
at a greenish board performance
to make time
leave be me for.
All right, so now, now let me go here
and let me change it
just to keep like this.
Only every time I need to change,
I will change only year
one point dashboard and make it plan.
And as it was to do,
like don't why I'm making a do
and why change Degas dashboard
if you No no.
Check the recordings.
So again again for the data
they will here for their data table.
Great for the data.
Well I'm going to copy this
particular skip from here
and I will create another two steps here.
Guide
Where is my gun for steps?
So I'm going to extend my
common methods,
right? And then put it here.
This particular park,
I put my common method here.
Now see
what I'm going to do again,
Trade the data table first.
Which one was to reach one?
This is my data driven.
I'm going to be imported
Fine. From make it.
You'll learn guys.
Now see, very interesting point for me.
One how can we use
how we can use this particular detective?
Well, here it's what I'm going to explain.
You see
this time?
Do we need a maps
where I use produced?
I need to place from a be one
where I used words
just three or four active in the group.
Then are this
How many of you base having nature there?
How many days you have
really important things we are discussing?
If someone missed and asked me
after those nationwide
include do it, then you will see my gun
is scared to say something.
If mistake you will kill.
No, no, no, no, no.
I don't know.
That is of no, no.
But it is for us right
now. See, this time we don't need maps.
So first clear.
We need simple list break.
Yes, yes. Time.
There you go.
So one sometimes it is good, right?
I you know, I'm
getting with your being with you.
I'm enjoying with you
at the same time of meetings with some.
It's good to be honest.
So everyone everyone
you know, can attend the class properly.
You can
all the players here.
All right.
With you.
Having said this, I will tell you one very
rare scenario of my school life
after this part
to play the mobility,
I would tell you a story.
What happened to me,
What happened with me, actually,
what my teacher did
very bad.
So now we need this data table,
this time as a maps.
No, we need this, this time.
This simple list.
Correct.
We need it at least as a list.
We need it to calculate.
So I'm going to write simple
when I'm writing a list.
So my list is having reached a sprint by
and providing the name the code that's
this line.
Clear
this line Dear everyone.
What I wrote
Simple and list major industry.
I provide the name of the list as best
So from the deductible
I am taking one as a list
and converting it and putting it here.
There's the expenditure now. Really good.
Then I got the code snippet
from my consultant for step five initial
point I'm going to write here now.
See, I'm going to write.
First thing is, then I'm going to write.
Fine.
So first I need dashboard.
That's
what I need this dashboard deps,
I need a new dashboards
so that I can compare
the values of dashboard
red with the values
that I got from my feature.
Right.
So now tell me
if I need this dashboard tabs from here.
From here, what I can use, what I can use.
But see, let me show you.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
I can take element
or I can take elements, element
or elements and me
it means from this particular class,
if we take it from here
and we days how I'm taking the rate
the class is equals
to menu slash you and
now you see here
in this UML right
in this unit I'm having all these a light
a light and I options or slash
and I see one, two, three, four, 5678.
All these options I'm getting on
based
let me take this
including this from here
and I'm going to put it here.
Tell me how to write X but what elements
is this correct
here?
What frenetic
web element
or web elements
or list of web element? Yes.
I should meet
y should take like this or not.
Tell me,
is this correct expression?
So now from this step,
reading from this particular example,
what I'm going to do is see, first
I'm going to write for my actual EPS.
I'm going to write under the list here
list,
which is having all the values
as is framed.
And I'm writing this as actually EPS
is it was the new edit list.
If someone has any question, what is that
list, What is length, the list,
Any question, Right.
I told you to revise Java.
It is a part of collection.
Go ahead and read it is
didn't have any question
you let Neil I will not answer
in advance for loop in advanced for loop.
We are going to compare the values
which we are getting from our actual thing
and from one dashboard tips.
I read mistakes but techniques.
So one value me about.
From there we are passing one value
in my feature point
and one value
we are getting from our from our script.
So to get the value from a script,
I'm going to write this particular part
called The Element, and I'm going to
for my on my dashboard next.
Great, because I need every single element
one by one.
So enforce tribulation.
It will return one element
in synchronization, it will return second
element organization,
it will return third element and so on.
Right.
And every time, every name
when I taking this, what I'm seeing in
list, just take these values
and add what I should add here.
And the element
and the
element text and after this, right.
Once you add all this things,
simply print here, simply print.
What should I paint here?
The first thing I would bring here
is my X.
In the second thing here
I want to print is my actually next.
Now see this, this then this dense.
I'm thinking what I should rename.
We do expect that it would be very easy
for you to understand expected depth.
I'm making the right.
So these are expected dips
which are coming from my
which is coming from my case, coming from
each of my
couple
that is coming from my feature frame rate.
I know this is a list for this list
expected coming from feature find
and this one is coming
from coming from application
or coming from simply
automation script Economist.
Right now when it is
coming from there,
I kept everything in the list
one by one,
all the steps I'm taking so it one time
from the elements
it is returning one element.
That element I'm taking and I'm
storing
that based on that particular element.
Three days
I'm ending the text of that element I'm
printing here and this what I'm doing
one by one, what I'm doing
fine after this, after this.
See after this what I see.
This is the end of my voyage loop.
This is the end of my polish
loop in one spot.
So I'm outside the loop.
I'm doing one of this things here.
I'm going to provide a solution
for a solution which is ocean.
I have to use case
which is of certain equals.
I can use trade
or let me tell you, that totally
solved software solution
in cucumber.
And I got one. Yes.
As with no, no, let me tell you,
we will use only to you need a solution
but the code way of using the C
I can write.
I start dark, I start
to you must be thinking when we're going
to compare two things, how it can be true.
I'm telling you, I'm writing here expected
depth, not
equals
true pets
in I write this
I'm comparing to lisp together actually
expecting steps toward equals a tips
If this particular
if this particular expression is correct,
this assertion will returns true
otherwise it will return
false guys
guys understood.
So just for information,
I'm going to write here
all values, all
are equal.
A lot is is is
my best guess is parsed
generate this
write this case
Yes I can write this You want really to be
nice as you wish X Excellent
excellent great.
Okay let's executed first.
They should put steps right there first.
Let's do it we check in this part?
Fish brightness equals two thoughts.
Let's try to run this code now.
I'm going to run it.
Now you see here that
I printed this first,
which is coming from might be fine.
And the second one is coming from my from
my application just to show you
these two values are equal
on what you see here.
That's what my assertion is doing.
It is comparing these two values.
And when we consider what this doing, is
that equal?
It is giving with this message.
So all the combinations,
but in rotational examples
scenario claim
normal scenarios, detectable,
detectable with keys, detectable
with without keys usage.
Okay, use a background that every scenario
with every feature without region user
and or cases in their tags,
every single thing is that question
that you guys have in this part.
Meanwhile with the with this code,
it is not equal.
Then it will give us the associated
yes following output would not print
because that image will stop on that line.
So it will not go on
to the end of the migrate.
So in that time we will not that message
already.
So this is all I'm done from side
for today.
Now, now I'm going to give you time.
Right.
Because I committed the code
in the repository.
You guys can take this code
first and I'm still here.