Hey, guys, Can you guys.
Can you guys hear me?
Or Buck Hunter's?
Let's see who is here.
Whoo hoo hoo!
Here, Here.
Who is here and who's not here?
All right, let's see.
Good evening, class.
It's good to see you again.
We see each other.
We're together today and tomorrow.
And then that's it.
Let's see who else is here.
Let's to see him.
Nikolai. Ivan.
Allan. Lou Lubo.
Marvin Chavez. Zeman. This year.
I'm Rod.
See your guide to Angelica.
The million
this year
to Mina PRC.
Michal Hanoch, Aisha Fairfax.
Alicia. Ramy
Mariam.
Mustafa
Sorbonne.
This year Amar Nihal
broke So long to mine and decided
to show the class as a very good,
very good
tool.
Allan
Legacy Method
two Millennia
for hard.
So guys, it looks like
it looks like we're ready right
August here.
Now leave this here.
No, Bill is here.
Christine is here
for holidays.
Is here as well.
All right, guys,
it's good to see you again,
or at least good to read your messages.
Am I going to vacation that well?
No, I wish.
I wish I was going to vacation.
Would go to the.
How are you guys? How's Java treating you?
This is your what is this your first week?
Right.
I think you're your fifth
week.
It's fourth week on syntax.
Really?
This can be the fourth week
because this is
the third week of teaching.
How can it be the fourth week
we were starting to love
Java.
Okay,
cool, cool, cool.
Don't you know, don't.
Don't be discouraged. You can't do,
you know, a
a problem.
Don't be discouraged.
And for some of you that understand
the material, congratulations.
But if you really want to
if you if you really want to confirm
with yourself that you understand
that or not try to help your classmates
who are struggling
and try to teach them the material,
you know, it's going to be a good way
for you to retain the information
that that you're you know,
is are solving this stuff.
The dream team.
The dream dream team.
Ah, Ladies and gentlemen,
gentlemen, ladies, good
people of the North,
the South, the west and the east.
Today marks
class four,
Class four.
We go.
Absolutely. Have you done research, Alex?
Have you Google there?
Have you watched YouTube videos?
Has anyone here done
any Google research, YouTube
videos on anything that we've learned?
Absolutely anything.
Right.
Good, good, good, good,
good.
You doing research? That's very good.
Go. All right, so let's start off with
let's go over.
Well, let's talk about
and I know you guys
have had a long week and stuff,
but let's talk about what we talk about.
Last US class, we basically discussed
the types of testing.
Right.
How many types are there?
Right. Two types.
Right?
Only two types. Okay.
And what are they guys?
What are they
on? Automation,
Functional and
and nonfunctional, right.
Well,
we also talked about other
and I'm going to read Tendra.
I'm glad you said that because I'm
going to clarify some things today. So
so we have functional, nonfunctional and
undeclared.
These two categories are what can anyone
just start
saying different types of testing.
We have ad hoc right at home,
we have small, we have
what else have fibroid.
Very good by the way.
White box, right.
Some sort of black box.
Seems that regression right.
Regression. Sure.
Let's throw in retesting And there's one
system. Yes.
Very good. Yeah.
We the hacker is here.
API performance.
Yes. Okay, good.
We didn't say anything about regressed.
Very good. I show from Florida.
She's new class guys.
I show Florida days in class. Right.
And integration.
Oh, man, that PRC.
Unbelievable. Unbelievable.
What do we call people like priority guys?
You guys remember we call people like PRC.
What do we call
people like parents?
Does anyone remember bag of money?
Exactly.
Ad hoc.
We said that ad Hoc is also known
as exploratory testing.
Right.
Cool. And so forth.
All right. So
white box versus
black box testing.
What do we say?
Those are the testers.
That's that's a good way to think about it
if it helps you.
White box is done by developers white box.
You need to know the code.
You need to know
the internal structure. Right?
And only the people that develop
the application
are the ones that internally know
the system right?
It only makes sense. Right, guys?
What about black box?
Very good.
Black box doesn't
black box is functional, right?
Exactly. Mean. That's right.
It's functional.
It is functional testing. Right.
Okay. Very good. Okay.
Can someone can
we talk more about the difference between
small
testing?
Smoke is quick, Lightweight.
Very good. Smoke is quick.
Yes, that is true. Yes.
Like lightweight light testing. Right.
But it's it's testing
the most important functionalities. Right.
Okay.
Yes, exactly.
But good done by testers.
The most important thing since the test.
What about regression then?
Once that regression is testing
of two coaches of this or improvement?
Mohammad That is very well said.
Yes, exactly.
Angelica Very good.
Sorbonne Very good.
Second priority test.
That's a very good way to put it.
So one, that's awesome.
Regression is one of the most
or is more of the overall stability
and functionality.
Okay. So
can you give me
an example of a smoke test case?
And they give me an example
of a regression test case.
Smokers log in
When you're not testing the log in button,
what are you testing
The log in functionality?
Right.
You want to make sure
that the users can log in,
but that's essentially
what you're testing, right?
Exactly. I should. From Fairfax
Spelling regression.
That's right.
But very, very, very good.
Okay. Very, very good.
Let's see, what else do we talk about?
We talked about the different types
of testing.
What is ad hoc testing of exploratory
testing, random testing,
Very good.
Without documenting.
Okay, testing, Improvised stuff, informal,
not documented.
Okay.
What is, by the way, testing?
What is 508 testing?
Yes. No, that's that's true.
Extra testing, disability do.
What do you mean disabilities is.
How are you going to answer that
interview question of they ask you what is
what is five eight tests?
You're going to say disability, right?
So it's exactly right.
And this is a different type of person
that you want,
you know, you won't really be doing.
This is a different type of testing,
obviously requires different tools.
I in my project,
I do all of these by the way.
I do at Ad Hoc.
You know, obviously everyone does it.
I do small, I do fibroids, I do
white box, I do
I do black box
regression.
You know, obviously we retest
performance testing as well.
You wait.
You sure I'll hire all of you? Absolutely.
Requirement tools and websites for people.
Exactly. Very good Sorbonne.
That is true. Yeah
they're very good is testing them.
Make sure you know you don't.
It's just that
I'm actually an architect,
so I know like the internal structures
of some applications
and I actually have to run
some unit tests myself.
But you guys won't have to do it.
Yeah, So?
So, but this is, you know, I'm doing
you based on experience.
You don't really
have you don't have to know this right.
And most projects
yes ad hoc testing but everyone does it
You all do a lot of smoke.
You do a lot of regression. Okay.
That's the type of black box
testing right?
You'll do system testing both your testing
as part of system testing.
Remember, we talked about that last time.
You will do API testing.
You will learn that in class.
I actually teach all the API classes here,
but I think you guys
will have another instructor this time
you as well as to assist with that.
But I want to clarify some things
than I would like
for everyone to to pay attention.
So okay,
everyone looking at my page
and actually
I want to talk about this test case.
You guys remember this test case?
We we wrote like Sorbonne wrote it.
We just went and fixed it and everything.
Okay. So this right here it
is testing
to verify that a user can log in
with valid credentials
right from the home page.
When we do this test case, we're actually
physically we're actually, you know,
interacting with the functionalities
of the application, right.
Where we're navigating to Netflix icon,
we're clicking on a button, we're entering
text and text boxes, we're
clicking on buttons, and that's it, right?
So this right here, guys, this right here
is an example of a functional test case.
Okay, Does that make sense?
Functional test is
this is an example of functional test case
because at some point
here we are testing the functionality
of this application, right?
We're clicking buttons,
we're entering text and text boxes.
Right?
And that's those are the functionalities
that we want to look for
it that we want to test.
This is a type of functional test case.
Now, someone said there are two types of
testing, which is manual and automation.
So let me clarify that.
So this is a test case, right?
You either manually write,
execute this test case,
meaning you open the browser,
you type in Netflix dot com, you're moving
with your mouse and everything, right?
You're entering you're
actually typing data with your keyboard or
or you automate this functional test case.
Does that make sense guys over
you guys understand
where I'm going with this, right?
Or you automate this functional test case?
Do you guys remember when I showed you
a demo of like one of the forms
for one of my projects? Right?
And I told you
I could either manually execute that
and which is a functional test case.
Do you guys remember
how it was like entering
data, clicking buttons and all that stuff?
Right? That's all functional testing.
So I had the option to manually
fill out the form and submit it
or I can automate that functional test
case.
Okay. Does
that make sense to everyone, by the way?
Right.
Is that clear to everyone?
So when you say manual and automation
with the type of testing that we're doing,
we're basically talking
about functional testing, right?
You either execute
those functional test cases manually
or you can automate them right at the end.
It's still functional testing.
Does that make sense?
Does that does that make sense to
Alex Gray Box testing.
We can talk about that later.
You know, you can kind of it's
kind of self-explanatory, right?
If white is white and black is black,
then there's great.
What do you think that means? Right?
It means that you do both,
but it's mixed.
At the end class,
we will know how to write and run the same
right, and run the same
like you did the other day.
The one. Exactly. Yes.
You will be able to do that.
But I want everyone to understand that
when we do, you in testing,
what do you mean by UI?
We do UI testing.
UI testing means
we're just testing the user interface
and we're actually going to the website
right?
These are
you guys are going to be automating
a lot of functional test cases
throughout the class.
Does that make sense to everyone?
But I want you guys to,
to like really understand
that you are automating functional test
cases.
Okay.
Or you can manually execute
those functional test cases.
Now, there are different types
of automation that we can do right?
We're not just going to automate
functional test cases in this class.
Later in class,
you guys will learn about API testing,
you guys will learn about SQL testing,
you guys will learn how to manually do
that, and you guys will also learn
how to automate those test cases as well.
However, those test cases because
they're considered nonfunctional, right?
That means you are automating
nonfunctional test cases.
Okay, So but that will make more sense
towards the end.
Okay.
But for right now,
I just want you to focus that, you know,
this is a functional test case
and stuff, right?
So I'll show you. Right.
I'm going to go to expedia.com, right?
So to
expedia.com, I'll come here and let's say
I'm searching something, right?
I have a test case to look up a trip
somewhere.
So I'm already clicking right.
I'm clicking on this, on this off.
So I have to click on flights as a user.
I expect this flights, right?
This flight's link or button to work.
Right.
If I if I have cars here
and I click on it, I expect it to work.
You know, if I click on flights,
I fly to work in this textbox here
leaving from if I click on it as a user,
I expect for something to happen, right?
And I can enter,
you know, whatever,
I can answer this right?
And if I click on this,
I expect for something to happen, right?
So maybe the test case can be
to, you know,
as a user, as an Expedia public user,
I should be able to look up
a roundtrip flight,
leaving from Washington to
to Vegas.
Right.
To Las Vegas, right.
And search right.
And I should be able to see results.
Okay.
So and this is going to I'm going to
kind of throw something at you right now.
Okay.
And so this is Expedia,
and we're using a website, right?
And I'm entering information
and I'm searching information.
Okay.
When I search this information,
I get a lot of different options, right?
I get a lot of different options
from different airlines.
But let me ask you this.
Where do you think
this information is coming from?
What do you think
this information is coming from
databases, from those airlines?
Exactly.
Very good databases from those airlines.
So the thing is that now
in order to test that, the data
that is being retrieved
from those databases are correct.
That is a different type of testing
that we're going to have to do,
which is back in testing.
Okay.
Because this is frontend testing right
front to front end testing is everything.
The user can see the public website read
everything we are doing here, this UI
testing, right, the clicking by clicking
this, you know, clicking the checkbox.
All of this is front end, right?
We can see it.
But then there's also backend
testing and back in testing is basically
nonfunctional testing API testing,
equal testing, where we're going to test,
we're going to verify data
from the databases differently.
Okay. Does that make sense
that you will learn later in class?
Okay.
And don't don't stress about it right now,
but I want you to understand what we mean
by functional testing.
You're actually testing the
functionalities of the application, right?
So entering data, clicking
buttons, dropdowns, checkboxes,
radio buttons and so forth.
Okay.
So is that clear with everyone? Right.
So and this is why I asked you this.
Remember when we talked about I asked you
what is what does automation mean?
And some of you guys automatically started
saying, Oh, Joel, so let him do cover.
No, I basically asked, just what does
automation mean in general, right?
It means to automate a process
for something to be done quickly,
you know, to be more efficient.
We gave different life
examples right, Like emails.
Right.
And, you know,
and different like, for example,
you're out of the office,
someone can send you an email
and an email gets sent back right away
saying, Hi, I'm out of the office
until this, this, this.
Right, exactly.
So so always think about that
when you hear the word automation.
Cool.
All right.
So we've clarified that.
And we also talked about smart regression.
You will learn about API lit later.
We talked about environments, right?
I hope you do.
So tomorrow, guys.
Tomorrow after class. Okay.
We're going to have
a big you guys know what code is.
Have you guys done? That's over.
So tomorrow we're going to have
a big cohort quiz at the end.
All right, guys.
It's going to be exciting, right?
It's going to be really, really good.
Guys, the winner of this whole game
is going to get a real prize.
A real, real prize.
All right.
Like it's it's going to be good, right?
You should attend tomorrow because
because you'll have a good idea
as to where you are.
Okay, cool, Because that makes sense.
So tomorrow
and the winner gets a real, real prize.
I won't say what the prizes,
but it's not a sticker.
It's not a sticker. Right.
It's going to be a good one.
So, Sebastian,
you got to do a lot more than 1 to 4 for
for a job.
Okay, cool.
I see.
Cool, cool, cool.
So all of these keywords, guys,
I just want to say everything
we've learned, all these keywords,
performance, integration,
if you were to understand it,
that's good for you.
But as the course goes on,
you're going to understand it even more.
And at the end, recap all of this.
Everything is going
to make a lot of sense. But
so if you're right now
doubting yourself, saying,
you know what, I don't understand this.
It doesn't make sense.
It's going to make sense
as of course, goes on.
Okay, cool.
All right.
There's a reason
why our success rate is very high,
but you guys know that our success rate
for students getting jobs is very,
very, very high
compared to other schools in the area
compared to other schools in the area.
I would be lying to you
if I told you that 100% of our students
get jobs on porches.
There are students
that have some issues like
they just quit,
have went through or they don't, you know.
No, it's much higher than 70%.
Much higher than 70%.
So. All right, guys, Today
we're going to discuss a new topic, right?
It's going to be a very good
and we're going to discuss what is 050000.
So where you guys able to log in?
Everyone should have been able to log in.
You guys were given.
Oh, and I just want to say something.
You know, guys, it's like 83 of you
guys, right?
So, you know, when I ask you a question
or when I say, hey, you know,
do you guys understand and stuff
or you guys ask a question, guys, right?
I get a lot of message.
Like my my Slack channel is just going up,
right, with all your messages
and I may miss a message or two.
Okay.
I may.
I don't have the ability to reach
super, super, super fast, unfortunately.
I'm sorry to break it to you. Right.
So if I miss a question, just let me know.
Right. Let me know.
I ask it again,
and and and we'll see from there.
Okay, cool. Just ask again.
Make sure to to pay attention.
I don't miss.
I don't mean to miss your questions.
Right. Just ask again.
Okay.
Cool. Yes.
Everything was in course.
Announcements.
So everyone is there.
Anybody that does not have
the JIRA information,
anyone?
Okay.
You don't have your JIRA information.
We asked you guys to log in last week
as a member.
Nope. You didn't get an email.
We specif.
We specifically told you
that we're not sending an email. Right.
Thank you very much.
So, so guys trying to stay on top of this.
Okay, Try to stay on top of this stuff.
Okay.
So how many people have not logged
in two zero.
How many people have you have
in the instructions?
All right.
There you.
Okay,
Cool.
Now, for those of you,
open up your browser and let's go on zero.
Go. Let's go to zero
and let's go to zero.
And you'll see this.
I have different credentials,
so log in with your credentials,
please.
Oh, to
log in When you log in, let me know once
you guys are done.
All right.
We good?
Are we there or are we there?
You are right?
Is anyone not in and is there anyone from
support helping us today?
Is there anyone from support?
Support? Are you there today?
We have anybody
support someone.
So what Cause broad Stop man.
Dude, he just made my name.
He just made my name
because somebody are you.
So that is up.
So guys, if you have problems, you know,
reach out to
to a positive support channel.
All right.
So if you log in,
you should see something like this.
You should see something like this.
Who doesn't see something?
And if you log, then you're logged in
to see something different.
And if you see something different,
then take a screenshot
and kindly share it
so I can see where you are.
Regardless,
we'll end up in the same place.
Okay, that's fine.
That's complete. Okay, Miriam,
That's fine.
That's okay.
That's screenshots.
Good, but that screenshot is fine.
Okay, very good.
So do me a favor, guys.
For those of you that see that screenshot,
can you click on or
can you click on Explore Current?
The current projects
And then
and then let me know what you guys
would you guys see
you're in awesome.
I'm a good job.
Yeah, very good.
Perfect. Wonderful.
You guys are there, but
there's not much going on here.
It's just logging in and making sure just,
you know, if you don't see what I see,
that you should see what everyone else is
seeing. Right.
And if you see a different screenshot
like the ones that are above,
click on, explore current projects,
go cool.
All right.
Now is everyone on board with this?
Yeah, that's fine.
No more management.
That's cool. Is everyone on board?
I don't like to leave anyone behind.
I don't like to be in you.
And you guys are,
you know, please don't be shy and say,
hey, like I'm stuck or I'm behind.
Say something, please,
so that we can help you.
Geralt's like, yeah, might
just are cool.
All right, all right.
Nice, nice, nice. Right.
So let's talk about what year is first?
Why not to me now?
What do you see?
You know, just reach out to support
and will
help you out.
Okay, So anyway, here's
the thing.
All right?
So all I did to see this, right?
If you guys see these menus here, right.
Just I just clicked on our boards
and I went and I went to the bottom
and I click view all boards.
Okay, click view all boards.
And then it took me to this page,
but you guys see that.
So I went to boards, I went to the bottom
and I clicked on view
all boards and I'm here.
Okay, cool.
All right, now what I'm going to do
is let's talk about what year it is first.
So everyone hands off your laptop
and let's talk about what
what is Jericho working?
So you think it's just going to start
making a lot of sense?
So JIRA is a project
management tool
and this is a project management tool.
So JIRA is not the only tool that, you
know, that is out there that's popular.
There's different ones.
There's really
there's IBM tools like HP, LMC, Alarm.
A lot of what you will know about
JIRA is actually
the most popular.
So guys, JIRA is a project management
tool, right?
If you saw, we'd access
basically a website, right?
This is a website that's JIRA
and we logged in with credentials.
Right?
But this software, this application
is where we can manage the project.
We mean everything, right?
And when we meet everything,
we're talking about
documents, which is what?
Which are what documents?
Which are
what an agile environment, right.
Which are what guys do you guys remember
artifacts, Right.
We can have our backlogs.
Here are user stories, our tasks, our test
cases, everything, everything,
everything we can have here in JIRA.
This is how we can manage the project.
This is where you can see your progress
on day to day basis with your team.
Okay?
This is the tool that and it's just
think of it like a ticketing software.
It's a very, very easy ticketing software.
A lot of companies use JIRA
for a lot of different, different project.
They use it differently.
We're going to use it in the way that
that, you know, we use it for testing.
Okay, So this is
this is zero and don't do anything yet.
Just follow it.
I'm like, don't touch your laptop.
Just watch me.
Okay? We created a project.
Please don't click on anything.
Just please watch the screen. Okay.
Before you start seeing what I do,
I mess with the camera repeater.
Just watch the screen right?
So we have our mess. Batch 11.
I want to click on this project
here. Okay.
So now this is
this is how the activity board looks like.
Okay.
And all right, now it's like what this
you know,
I don't understand anything of this.
On the left hand side, if you look at
my screen, there's different options.
Okay. Different options.
We have a backlog.
We have active sprints, we have releases,
we have reports, issues, more.
Morecambe. Okay, cool.
And I don't want you to do anything,
but I'm going to click on the backlog.
Okay?
So the backlog,
this is how the backlog looks like.
Okay.
And let me let me repeat myself again.
Please do anything.
Okay?
Because with JIRA, now that you logged in
with your credentials, I can see
absolutely everything.
What everyone does if Tomana comes here
and moves this up here like this,
I will be able to see that she moved that
ticket like, you know, somewhere.
Okay, So please don't do anything
you're not supposed to do, or you're going
to ruin the flow of the class.
Okay, that makes sense to everyone.
Can we can we follow instructions?
Right.
Okay, cool. Right.
So this right here is the backlog.
Okay, I just went here.
I clicked on
and you're watching my screen, right?
And here I have what we call issues. Care
issues are also known
as tickets issues a.k.a tickets.
Right. But we have to describe
what type of issue,
what type of ticket goes in JIRA.
And this is the way that JIRA works
everything in JIRA.
Okay, is an issue.
A test case is an issue.
A user story is an issue.
A task is an issue.
Everything that you create is an issue,
and that's just what they called it.
Does that make sense?
Is this just what they call it? It's just,
you know what it is?
It's their thing.
Okay? It's it's gross thing.
Don't ask me why they call it
that. It's their thing, you know?
So it's called an issue now
and other project management tools.
They don't.
That's funny.
Mohammed In other project management
tools, they don't call these issues.
They may call them tickets,
They may call them something else.
I don't really recall right.
But that's why you see here
like four issues.
But in reality,
what we see here is like for tickets,
I want you guys to think of it like that
because it's going to be easier.
So we see one, two, three, four, right?
And these are movable.
You can move this.
Oh, and by the way,
this is the backlog read.
And we said that a backlog is an artifact,
which is a document.
But is this in the form of like a word
documents?
Is this an a form of word document
or Excel
or PowerPoint slide or anything like that?
No. Right.
This is just here. This is in JIRA.
This is considered a document.
This is considered,
you know, a document here.
And with projects,
this is always, you know,
like highly maintained and everything.
So there's four tickets here. Right.
And another thing I want to say is
I want you guys to look at this right.
So when I clicked on this, okay, right now
you see this right?
When you click on any of these,
you're going to see a preview
that's going to open up here.
Okay. You're going to see a preview here.
Okay. The the tidbit issue i.d.
is h.r. Mass b11 hyphen four.
Right. Okay.
What is the issue
id for this one for a search employee.
What is the what is the issue id
or the ticket id for search
an employee. h.R.
Must be level three. Exactly.
Very good.
Right now, when i click on this,
okay, i see a of that ticket.
You see how it opens on the right
side, right?
I can see a preview of this ticket here.
Right?
I can tell that, you know,
it says invalid user login.
There's an acceptance criteria here.
Okay,
so this is because this is a user story.
Okay.
Do you guys understand that
this right here is is a user story, right?
And you will learn the signs
and how user stories look like.
Okay, so this is a user story.
We have an acceptance criteria.
Okay, we have some comments here,
but this is just a preview of the ticket.
So what we can do is when we click on it,
we see the preview.
But you have to right
click it and open the link in a new tab.
Okay?
And when you do that,
you see the full ticket.
Does that make sense?
Did you guys just see what I did there?
So let me go back. Right?
So if you click on any ticket right
here, you're going to see a preview of
it, right?
If you want to see the full ticket,
just right click,
Open link and new tab,
not open link in New window.
Open link and new tab.
Okay, so when you do that, I get to see
like the full ticket here the way it is.
Right?
So this is a user story.
How do I know this is a user story?
How do you know this?
A user story?
Because it says story, right?
Mean you guys are so smart.
This is really you know Exactly.
This is a this is a story.
It says it's a story.
It's labeled story. Right.
That's what it is. Okay.
So very, very good.
Right.
So let's get familiar with the tool
and then we see the acceptance criteria.
Right?
You remember
I told you acceptance criteria
will be written in user stories.
Does that make sense now?
Like, is that the is it is it clear?
Now, remember when I told you
when we started learning this,
I said, your boys are going to write
the acceptance criteria
as in the user stories.
Okay. Right. So this is what I meant.
This is a user story
and this is the acceptance criteria here.
Okay.
Is the report of the VA
the reporter Can the reporter in
JIRA is the person that created the ticket
Okay.
So when you create test cases
and you guys will create your tasks here,
you're going to see that the reporter
is going to say your name.
Okay. That's a very good question.
So the reporter means
the person that created the ticket,
the assigned me is the person
that this ticket is assigned to.
Right now, it's unassigned.
I haven't assigned the tickets to anybody.
Okay. I'm cool.
And the comments are here, right.
And you can see all the activity
and you can see the history of everything.
I can see everything a cell did here.
I can see when she deleted something,
When she changed something,
when she moved something.
I can see that she
she changed the ranking of the tickets.
You can see everything.
And with every single project management
tool, like in your organization, whichever
one you're going to work
with, historical data
that is saved
can never be fully believe it.
Okay,
Does that make sense, guys?
So when you use JIRA or whatever project
management tool you're going to use,
make sure that that you're professional
with your comments.
Okay?
Make sure that you're
you know, you're going to
make sure you use don't
be careless with it.
And stuff. Okay?
So just be professional
with your comments, with your labeling
everything, and I'll show you
how to do that kind of cool.
All right.
So Far you guys are doing good.
You guys are following instructions.
Last batch.
When I told them not to do anything,
they started moving tickets around.
They started moving things.
They disrupted the flow of the class.
Everything like that on campus.
All right, so we have a backlog go.
And on the left side, we have
another option that's got active sprints.
If I click on it, we see a board.
Okay?
And there's three columns
to do in progress and done right.
Obviously, right here,
you don't see any tickets yet
because we haven't started the sprint.
This is just an empty board right
now. Okay.
Once we start the sprint,
you're going to see that
you're going to see the information here.
And there's other stuff
that we'll talk about later.
But don't worry about this other options
right now.
We need that.
So okay, so why do we use this tool?
You're going to you're going to see why
to keep our day to day
progress, to report our progress.
Like, for example, we talked about
your daily startup meetings, right?
You guys know what those are every single
morning and agile environment.
You basically say what you did yesterday,
what you're going to do today.
And if you had any blockers.
So when you're saying
when you're saying that you basically
give an update on your work.
Right.
But we just don't talk and say it,
we have to show it somewhere.
Okay.
So JIRA is going to be
where everyone will be able
to see your progress of whatever it is
you're doing.
Okay.
Right here
we have four user stories right here.
Okay. They are in the backlog.
All right.
So lentils,
let's we're going to basically,
you know, practice
everything from scratch.
So don't do anything just yet.
I promise you will be able
to play with JIRA and every way possible.
Okay.
But here what we're going to do
is let's pretend we're in a team, okay?
I'm the business analyst.
You guys are developers and testers.
Okay, So what we're going to do
so then that's true.
So what we're going to do is the sprint
hasn't started yet.
Let's have a
a sprint planning session. Right.
But you guys ready?
You guys want to have a sprint
planning session?
This is how it's going to work.
You're going to have a meeting
you're going to meet and the the B
and the Bay or Scrum Master
is going to pull up the backlog game.
And you guys are on the call.
We're on the call. Right.
And what we're going to do
is we're going to say
we're going to create a sprint, okay?
We're going to create a sprint.
Now, this is not something
you're going to do.
This is only done once
again, the PR or the Scrum
Master will do it in your project.
So they'll create the sprint again.
And it looks like
we're going into Sprint to
okay, we're going into Sprint two
and then that's fine.
Sprint one.
I have to find out why I didn't
start in Sprint one, but there it is.
Right? So check this out.
This now's the backlog.
And now this right here is
what we're going to call the sprint
backlog.
Right?
So right here
you only see one, two, three, four.
You see four tickets, right.
For user stories.
But in a real project,
your backlog will be much larger
because you're going to have a list
of like a lot of tickets,
a lot of requirements,
a lot of user stories. Okay.
And now we're going to start Sprint, too.
So this is a sprint planning session
where or ceremony where I'm going to say,
okay, invalid user log in.
We have this test, we're going to open it.
I'm going to open a new tab.
Let's see on the a scrum, as I want to
say, okay, this is the acceptance
criteria.
Okay, Farhad, you're the developer.
How long is this going to take you? Right.
And then you give your estimate,
we're going to say
this is what the client wants us to work
this sprint, right?
They want us to complete this
in the sprint so far.
But can you give
like an estimate to how long
this would take you?
Right.
And our sprints are going to be two weeks
long, right?
That's fine.
But I think you guys already learned
about user story points, right?
Like assigning that level of effort,
the time that it's
going to take you to complete this, Right.
No, we're not talking about burn down
chart right now.
Right.
So we're talking about user story
points, right?
And in every single project,
every every project assigns
user story points differently.
Okay?
That is a topic that we can
we can assign to we can talk about later.
Okay. So I'm opening this ticket.
I opened it.
This is what we have to work on, right?
Let's just assume
that these are the tickets
that the client wants us
to work on this sprint.
So for how long will it take you right.
He can say two days, right?
He can say 8 hours.
6 hours. Right. Whatever it is. Okay.
Right.
He's saying 6 hours. Right.
So what I'm going to do
is I'm going to edit this ticket.
Give me one second.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to add
this just to for reference to help us,
I'm going to click on
Let's See labels Best Solution Story.
Okay, I'm going to click on edits.
Right When I click on edit,
I'm able to edit the ticket.
Okay, I'm going to comment something here.
I'm going to say low level of effort,
right, guys?
Right. Level of effort.
Right.
Amount of effort
to complete the story.
He's saying 6 hours, right?
So 6 hours. Cool.
And want to update this ticket.
And let's see, it should be displayed
here. Okay. Right here. Right.
I added this right here. So
Catalina, right.
It looks like Catalina is doing something
right and Catalina,
you're supposed to be seeing my screen
and not doing exact like, just everyone's
observing what I'm doing right now.
You're not doing,
you know, hands off keyboard, basically.
Right?
So, you know, so
if you could, you know, that's fine.
Just please don't disrupt the flow of
the class. Right.
So so here it is. Right?
So I enter a level of effort, 6 hours.
But what we can also do is we can add it
to the description right here.
And again, don't do this.
I'm just going to do it.
I'm going to say L-O-V-E, All right?
Actually, I'm going to put it
under the acceptance criteria.
I'm going to put it right here.
I'm going to say hello.
6 hours, right?
6 hours.
Okay. There you go.
It's in the description. Okay.
So I went ahead.
I had it as a comment, but I'm going to
add it to the description instead.
Right.
So far,
what is going to work on this? Right.
So now what I'm going to do
is I'm going to click on this.
And Farhad, what is your job?
What is your email?
But then you guys use the email ideas.
What is
what what is what is the email?
Sakata Is it
this one
that you are looking at?
You have to. Okay, I'm going to send it
here. Okay. Right. Look.
So I'm selecting for hot and there you go.
I assigned it. Right?
So the business analysts or the Scrum
master in this case it was a cell.
Okay.
And we assigned to take ticket
to Farhad, the developer.
Right.
In this case, we're seeing
that Farhad was a developer. Right.
So now if I go back to the previous tab,
right, this ticket,
if I go ahead and refresh it,
this ticket has not has not been updated.
So we have a sprint
one over here. That's fine.
So we're going to skip Sprint two and
we're actually going to use Sprint one.
So what we're going to do is
you see
how his little avatar here as well.
There's no picture displays because we
assign him the ticket, so it'll show that.
Now what I'm going to do
is I'm going to grab this ticket
and I'm going to move it to Sprint one.
Okay, Now
we have a ticket in our sprint backlog.
And yes, it's not in the form of word
document, it's not in an Excel sheet.
Literally,
this right here is the Sprint backlog.
What is the Sprint backlog?
It's a document of the tickets
or the tasks that we're going to work
on the current sprint.
Right.
What is the backlog in general?
It's a list of task of user stories,
right.
That we need to complete for the project
at some point.
Right.
So all we're doing and watch these guys,
all we're doing is we're getting items
from the backlog and we're moving them
to the sprint backlog.
Does that make sense?
So the backlog will in most cases
be pretty long.
They'll be huge.
Like right now we have
for which you will see a lot of tickets.
Right.
And every single sprint,
we cannot complete every single ticket.
We have to choose based on priority
with the client chooses to move
whichever tickets we want to work,
they want us to work on in that sprint.
Okay, Does that make sense?
In this case,
I just move that ticket to Sprint one.
Can I just move it to Sprint one?
So now let's go to the second one, okay?
And please everyone,
just keep your hands off your laptop.
I promise you guys will touch you
as much as you can, but just wait and pay
attention, please,
so I can cause this other ticket.
Right? I don't need it.
So I want to see the full ticket.
What am I going to do?
What am I going to do if I want to see the
full ticket for him as be 11?
What?
What are you going to do?
Right click
and you're going to open link in new tab.
Right? Exactly.
So now we have this other user story.
Go. What is the problem
with this user story?
What is the problem here?
Come on, guys pointed out,
I'll give you a hint.
It's in the description.
What is it? Missing something.
Give you a hint.
We're missing two words.
Very good.
We're missing the acceptance
criteria. Right.
So we're going to go in here
and say acceptance
and material.
Right?
And I'm going to go ahead and say that.
All right.
So next person in line,
We're still in the meeting.
Okay.
Add an employee. Right.
And we read the acceptance criteria.
Okay, cool.
So I'm going to say,
who's the next developer?
Joseph. Joseph. Gabriel.
Joseph Gabriel.
You're the developer, right?
Joseph, can you please
give us an estimate for this
for this ticket?
Right. Can you please give us an estimate
Please write on the salary.
And now let's wait to see what Joseph
says.
God, Joseph says 5 hours.
All right, So 5 hours to complete.
Joseph, what is your email I.D.?
What? What is it?
Or the idea you used to log in?
Okay. Get real, Joe.
Yeah, there you go.
So now we've signed it to him, right?
So now I'm
going to go back to the backlog.
And what I'm going to do is I can refresh
the page because it hasn't been updated.
So refresh it.
And now you see his avatar here. Okay.
So I'm going to grab this.
And what am I going to do next?
You're still in the backlog.
What am I going to do next?
Guys?
I'm going to move this to the Sprint
backlog, which Sprint Sprint Tour.
Sprint one,
Sprint one.
Exactly. Because we're only working Sprint
one right now.
Right, Exactly. All right.
Very good.
So we have two items on our sprint
backlog.
Right.
So let me go back to the backlog here.
Okay.
So to open this ticket, add a new
to view the full ticket, right click, open
link in the tab.
All right.
Who's the next developer,
let's say Roque Solano.
All right. Roque Solano, Right.
Rogue Solana.
This is the acceptance criteria.
This is what it is. Looks Roque.
So I'm sorry. What is name?
Looks.
Elena Roque Solana What is
what is the level of effort?
How many?
How much time do you estimate to complete
complete this, to develop this future?
Right.
So let's wait to see what Roxanna says.
So Rosalina says 7 hours are 7 hours.
So we go and we give 7 hours.
We say, okay, Roxana, can you please
leave?
You're funny, man.
All right.
So, Roxanna, can you please
tell me your your email address
or your ID so I can assign this ticket?
Right.
Roll over.
There you go.
So there it is. Right? Sign it to her.
Okay.
Now I'm going to go back to the backlog.
I'm going to refresh this and I'm going to
now we see this in the backlog.
What Do we do next?
What do we do next?
Oh, let's stop right there. Hold on.
Marvin asked a very good question.
He said, How much time is too much
and how much time is too little?
Okay, So
when we start projects, right,
you kind of read it.
And so here's what happens.
So when a project starts, scratch
in theory, you don't know how long
something is going to take you, right?
Imagine
the project is just starting from scratch.
A lot of things need to happen, right?
A lot of you know, you don't know
how long something is going to take you.
So the hours or the estimates
are usually little longer.
Right?
And it's like this for the first couple.
For the first few sprints,
you start to realize how long something
is going to take you.
Right.
And then you finally get the hang of it.
Okay.
So once you once the project has been
established, you need to work on a story.
Okay?
For example, we do our test automation.
Well, let's focus on what we're doing.
We need to give an estimate of how long
something is going to take to test, right?
We need to take into consideration
a few things.
We need to make the time
to write the test case.
We need to take the time
to automate the test case
and with automation comes a lot of stuff.
You have to do a lot of your selenium
and stuff and you'll learn that later.
But we have to take into account
that time, right, Writing the test case,
automating it and so forth.
We don't just give the time
that it's going to take for us
to actually test this
because more needs to go into this.
We need to create a test case.
We need to,
you know, automate this and so forth.
So at some point
you will know how much time to get.
For example, let's say this friend,
you gave 6 hours, right, to test.
But you realize, right,
that it's going to take you much longer.
This is why we have daily
standard meetings,
because just because
we're giving this estimate right now
doesn't mean that, like that
said, it's locked in and that's for sure.
Right.
A lot of the
times developers can't finish their work
on time.
Testing can't be done in the same sprint.
So what happens
is they actually move these items
to the next sprint time.
Does that make sense? Right.
So let's say developers working on this
and you can't finish this right?
It needs more time.
He didn't know
he was going to need more time
then it's going to be moved over
to the next sprint.
Okay. Exactly.
There are times, though, where
and we always have to keep the client
updated with this.
Right.
And so and a lot of times
it doesn't look good. Right.
So let's say Roman said, okay,
this is going to take me 6 hours
or this is going to take me like a week
and a half or whatever,
but he still can't finish it.
And then we go to the client and say, Hey,
I'm sorry we won't be able to finish this
this sprint.
It needs to carry on to the next sprint.
Right?
And the client's going to be like, what?
I thought you guys were going to be able
to finish this, right?
But now you can't.
And then they're like,
okay, fine, move to the next sprint.
But what happens is next, Sprint,
the same thing happens again.
What happens next?
Sprint Roman gives an estimate
and he can't deliver, right?
So then we have to go
to the client and say, Hey,
you know,
we can't we're not going to be able
to finish our our, our task this sprint.
Right?
So they're not going to fire you.
But then it starts to get annoying
for the client. Right.
And it certainly won't look good for us.
It won't look good for us.
It is not clear.
So when you give time estimates, Right.
And you will eventually learn
how to give time, estimate and so forth,
you always want to give yourself more
than enough time to complete your task.
For example, if you know 100% sure
that you can finish something in one hour,
just give yourself another hour.
Do 2 hours, right?
If you're for sure that you can finish
something in 6 hours, like 100%
sure you can finish in 6 hours.
Give yourself another couple hours
instead of six.
Say eight. Right.
Give yourself
some extra, extra time. Cool.
All right.
So I'm going to move this back to this.
I'm going to move this to the Sprint one.
Okay.
Now we have this last one,
certain employee who wants to be
a developer for this.
And by the way,
this is our sprint planning session.
Again,
this is their spring planning session.
Cool.
All right.
So there's an employee here.
We're going to have to delete this.
This is from last.
So did we say Sheriff?
Sheriff?
Sheriff is developer.
Sheriff, give an estimate, please.
Like how long, as a developer,
what this takes to develop.
Good.
You say 9 hours. Okay.
9 hours.
It is right there.
It is 9 hours. Now,
I want to show you guys something, right.
So we give 9 hours.
Sheriff, what is your user ID?
What is your Sharia
position?
Of course.
Okay, cool.
So I'm going to take this issue right now.
Now, I forgot one step. Right?
I forgot.
And I'm sorry, I forgot,
but let's go back to the first.
Take it. Right.
So I'm going to grab this ticket.
I'm going to move it to the sprint. Okay.
We have a sprint backlog.
It looks nice.
Okay.
And I'm going to refresh this,
but I forgot one thing and I'm sorry.
Let's go back to the first one.
Let's say a valid user log
in, the one with Farhad.
Right.
So here's the thing, right?
Farhad gave his employees, right.
And in this sprint,
this Sprint grooming session
sprint backlog,
we sprint planning.
This is just development hours, right?
So we can say
developments
LLC and then we need testing, right?
So let's say we have the testers.
Silva Silva you're the tester,
you're the Silva.
You know, it's going to take
four hot 6 hours to complete this.
How long will it take you to test this
use user story?
So is is Silva there?
Yeah, she's there.
She says 5 hours.
5 hours. Right.
So now we've also measured that.
So in total.
In total,
how long is it going to take the team
to complete this user story?
11 hours.
Exactly. Right.
Very, very good. Right.
So let's go back
and let's update the other tickets.
So we have our developers already gave the
the estimate.
Let's go to this one.
Get Gabriel gave leave for 5 hours.
And Eris, you're secure for this, right?
So hours,
how long is it going to take you to
to test is three
pieces, 4 hours.
4 hours. Right. That's what he's saying.
So now, how long is it
going to take us to complete?
Exactly.
9 hours. Right?
Very good.
As did you guys are doing really good
for your first sprint planning session.
Very, very good.
I told you I would hire all of you
if I could immediately, right away.
Skip interview that thing. Right.
So here
we have development and then we have
Roxana gave 7 hours for development.
Okay? And now we need a cure for this.
The cure for this will be
to monitor you, if you like.
Do you feel like working tomorrow?
Tomorrow? Give us an estimate, please.
Give us an A.
How long is it going to take you to test
this user story?
She's is 3 hours old. Yikes.
That's a little concerning, right?
Why is that little concerning? Does
That's a little concerning, right.
Rog is going to step in and say tomorrow,
wait a minute,
what is it going to take me 7 hours?
Oh, you're going to test it in 3 hours,
right.
And tomorrow going to say, yeah, probably.
And she's probably right.
So let's leave it at 3 hours. Okay.
So how long is it going to take us
to complete this ticket?
The team?
10 hours, Right.
Okay. Very, very good.
All right. Let's come back here.
This refresh it, and then we're going
to open this link in a new tab and then.
All right?
Sure.
Sure. Of cancer.
We gave the privacy,
so we need to.
That's going to
lead.
All right. So
let's say.
Oh, sorry, did you
who is red tendrils something?
Are we just giving ours by assuming
we're making our best assumptions
to how long it's going to take us.
Yes, that's Andrew.
Very good.
But we need to be careful
with this estimate.
Okay.
So, no, you want to be the cure for this.
So no.
How long is it going to take you to test
as user story,
how long it's going to take you?
24 hours.
Right now, this is also concerning, right?
Because now Sharif is going to step
in and say, wait a minute,
what are you going to do?
Right. But then maybe,
maybe what?
Who give that?
No, Maybe all the smart is probably
saying, okay, it's going to take 9 hours
to develop this, but
I know that I have to create a test cases.
I know that
I have to write an automation script
and that's going to take me some time.
This pregnancy.
I've never tested this feature before,
so I think this is how long it's
going to take me, right?
So we'll say, okay, fine.
Right. That's
probably what he thought about.
Okay, that's fine. Cool. Right.
So let's go back because that.
All right, cool.
Are we there, guys? Are we there?
Are we listening? Right.
So now there's nothing
on our backlog right now,
but in
your project, there
will be a lot of items on your backlog.
And every single time more
items are being added.
So now for Sprint one, are you guys ready,
guys to start the sprint?
Are you ready or are you ready? Right.
Another question. Do we always use ours?
No, I show from Fairfax,
we use a user points.
Right.
And but guys, I want to say it
varies from project to project.
We either use user story points
or in some projects you use ours.
Your projects will have.
It's very traditional
to calculate by user story points,
but your projects will have
their own thing, they'll have their own,
you know, their own little,
little thing going on to go,
and they'll obviously tell you
how it's working, you know, not not,
not just going to expect it to jump in
and be like,
oh, you don't know how to do this.
No, don't tell you.
They'll show you. You know, it's fine.
So are you guys ready?
We just had our spring planning session.
It was ours.
The same as points.
No It's not. It changes
because the sprint is to be long,
so we make our testing based on that.
Yes, You have to write.
Oh, and by the way,
there's four tickets here, right?
And we gave like very little hours. Right.
But any real project,
there will be a lot more tickets.
There will be a lot tickets.
Who is going to be like a lot more?
And you're obviously going to be testing
more than one ticket.
Okay.
Like, obviously, there's than 7 hours
in a sprint, so they'll give you more.
Don't wait. You will be busy.
So. All right, Ready?
We're going to start the sprint.
Okay, hold on.
If I don't click start Sprint and if I go
to active sprints, there is nothing here.
This is the Sprint board.
Okay, This is the Sprint board.
There's nothing here.
So I need to actually start the sprint.
I'm a quick start sprint. Okay.
And I get to make some configurations
here.
I want to say two weeks start date.
It's going to start on October 20th,
which is tomorrow at 12:12 a.m.
I'm actually going to move this to today.
Okay.
So it will start and we'll go to,
you know, November 2nd.
Okay.
So that's two weeks, guys.
So I'm going to start
from one and bam, let's jump.
So now, look,
you still if you click on backlog,
you will still see the items here.
Okay.
And then at sprints.
Now, what do we see now?
We see the tickets on the board,
we see the issues on the board,
we see the stories on the board. Right?
We had X is a successful
sprint planning session.
Guys, give yourselves around.
Plus, that was very good.
How did you guys like it?
That was good, right?
That was good.
We met up, we read the acceptance
criteria, we gave Eloise,
we gave development hours,
We gave testing hours.
Right.
This is how it will work in the project.
This is exactly how it's going to work
right.
They're very, very good. Right.
So that.
How do you guys feel?
It feels good, right? That's it was hard.
It was pretty easy, right?
There's nothing hard about this.
Right?
So how long is our sprint
if you're paying attention?
How long is our sprint?
Two weeks.
Exactly They vary, but others
do it with some systems and
others a sprint planning session.
You take guys?
That is a very good question.
The question was
how does a sprint planning session usually
take a sprint planning session?
The meeting, the ceremony we just had?
It depends.
Sometimes they take like an hour,
sometimes it could take 2 hours.
Sometimes I've been some quick ones
that take like 30 minutes.
You know, it all depends.
So it varies from but sometimes they like
to just limited to one hour.
It all depends on your project. Go, Go.
All right, cool.
So anyway, this is the board,
so not everyone log in and everyone go.
Listen to this. Listen to this.
Click on a project
okay, click on projects.
And if you don't see them as batch 11.
Okay, First of all,
let me know if you see this.
And if you see this, click on it.
If you don't see this, let me know. Yeah.
Okay.
If you don't see this, okay, then do this.
Do what I'm going to do.
Okay, look, when you click on projects
first, click on projects.
Are you then give a thumbs up.
If you did that, like Skip
give there's like a thumbs up emoji there.
Some thumbs up.
Okay. So,
all right,
then go to the bottom where it says view
all projects.
You guys should all have
that option, right?
So click on the all projects
and when you click on your projects,
you're going to see like a list
of projects here.
Yes. And by the way, no,
we don't take pictures anymore.
Right. You are an i.t.
Professional, right?
We take screenshots, right?
If you don't know how to do it,
what do you do.
You don't know how to do what you do.
You wouldn't know what to do, right?
You know what to do. So.
So do you guys see this for those of you
that you guys see this, right?
You guys should see something.
That is right.
Go, go, go.
Right.
So now we have to look for our project.
These are a lot of projects
from different guys.
Don't click on them.
Please do not click on
any of these other projects.
Then please don't do that.
So scroll down until you see our mess.
Batch 11. That's your project.
So click on this HMS Batch 11.
Okay, HMS Batch 11.
Okay.
Once you click on it right,
you will see the Sprint board.
Okay, Do not move the tickets again.
I will be able to see
just like we were able to see Catalina's,
you know, actions on the board.
I'll be able to see what you're doing.
Okay, cool.
So. Right.
So are we here?
Are we on the sprint board?
Are we on the springboard?
Very good. Very good.
All right, so now what we're going to do
and I want you to see this.
Right? Hands off.
Hands off, gyro!
Hands off gyro!
Okay, Just fantastic. Right?
These tickets.
Watch. And please,
just watch. Watch me. Right.
Don't do what I'm going to do again.
Don't do what I'm going to do because
you're going to ruin a lot of things.
I want
to see if anyone's when we be already.
Okay, good balance.
Moving stuff.
You guys are doing much better
than the last batch. Last batch?
We had some kids in class.
I had to tell them, like,
you kind of have to look up some stuff.
So here's the thing, right?
So these tickets. Right.
These tickets right.
They can be moved.
Okay.
Now, let me tell you something.
In projects, this is a big deal.
If you're going to grab a ticket from the
to do column two in progress,
this means that
now this ticket is in progress.
Okay? It means that has been developed.
It means that is currently being worked
on. Right.
Whenever it's complete.
Where do you think
this is going to be moved to
tomorrow?
You are like, you know what
we call people like you tomorrow.
What do we call
people like tomorrow, guys?
What do we call people like tomorrow?
Years, right?
A bag of money.
That's exactly
kind of the best we can lose, right?
A bag of money right now.
Look at this. Right?
As soon as they move this is done,
there's a line that kind of goes over the
the link here.
You guys see,
this is like scratched means.
It's like done, right?
So anyway, I'm just trying to tell you
that we can move these tickets
in according to our progress.
So in our daily stand up meetings. Right.
We'll move the tickets. Right.
Let's say we have two tickets on hold
and two more.
You get the progress,
right? You're going to say
Emily is
going to be like, Yeah,
I'm still working on MSB.
11 04i wrote some test for this.
I'm still working on it.
I hope to finish
by the end of the day, right?
And then there you go.
Right. So like, okay, cool.
Next person to money
says, you know what, Last week I was
I mean, yesterday
I was out of the office,
but today I'm going to start working on it
and that kind of thing.
Okay, then Marianne from Maryland
come says.
Yep, I'm working on that.
I should be done next couple
hours, I'll pick up on another task.
You know, Mikkel comes in and says,
I don't have anything assigned to me.
Can I pick up a ticket? Okay.
You know, and so forth. Right.
And that is what it is.
Okay, cool.
Yes or yes, you I understand
the school.
All right.
So cool, cool, cool.
All right. So
let's continue doing this.
So don't move any tickets, okay?
Don't move any tickets.
Yes, it can.
But we shouldn't do that. It's really bad.
Practice is bad practice.
Cool.
But this page for developers or testers.
No, this is the board for the whole team.
That is a good question.
Okay.
This is the board for the whole team.
Okay. The whole team.
The BAS,
the product managers, the program owners,
the product I'll be able to see
as a client if they're on the call.
This is everyone, developers, right?
Everyone gets on that call and discusses
what's on the board.
Right.
And it everyone is on the same thing. Come
at the pens PRC That's a good question.
Who can move it?
Actually, anyone can move it, right?
Anyone can move these tickets,
but you shouldn't move them
because you will change the process
so you shouldn't move them
unless you are trying
to indicate the progress by.
Let's go. Cool. So.
All right, now, everyone,
before we go on break,
I want to discuss something else
because this is what we're going to do.
I am actually
to move these tickets to in progress,
all of them,
because we're working on them. But
again, now let's say they're developed.
Okay, Let's say they're developed.
Bam, They're developed.
Let me move them.
Let's say they're developed.
Okay, So now all of you guys will test
every single ticket here.
And this is what you guys are to do.
First of all, I want you guys
to click on a ticket, see a preview.
I want you guys to right
click and open link and you tap it.
Not right now. I'm just showing you right.
And then I want you to read the acceptance
criteria.
Okay? And
and I want you to test this.
After you test it,
I want you to write a test case
and you're going to write a cucumber
scenario, okay?
And the way that you're going to do that
is this once you open the ticket, right?
You're like, okay, I'm testing it. Okay?
I know what I need to do now.
I need to write a cucumber
in there for it.
So what you're going to do
is you're going to create
you're going to click create, okay?
And you're going to see that issued,
typed, right?
Because we said that
everything jeera is an issue.
So when we click on this right,
you have three options.
You have the option to either
create a story to create a bug
or to create an epic. Right.
We'll talk more about that later
in this case, we want to leave it at task.
Okay. Task is already selected. Go.
And what you're going to do
is it's actually 820
to tell you what we'll do all of this
after break.
It's 822 because I know
that somebody doesn't want break.
Let's come back at eight 840.
That's a good break.
That's a very good break.
That's a generous break.
That's too much of a break.
Don't move the tickets on the board.
All right.
So go and enjoy it.
This is going to be very easy going.
Enjoy your,
you know, your break or whatever. And
anyone who has questions, as usual
here,
if anyone has problems,
anyone struggling to catch up,
this is your time to catch up.
Yep. 840
Gerald, quick
review on what?
Gerald What do you mean quick review?
And you'll get it.
No worries.
We're going to upload all every,
all the slides.
Okay,
I'll make sure we do that.
Yeah,
sure, sure, sure.
But that's
what they were saying.
I missed it so
a quick review of all I see
it will be tender.
What do you want? A quick review of
You were
working on log in when you started.
What do you mean you were working
on log in or you missed the first part or
you look confused.
You want me to start
from the beginning of JIRA?
Yeah.
I'll give a quick review
once we come back,
but please follow along
because it is a lot of information.
How many takers
can be assigned to one tester?
And it depends on project to project.
I mean, I said it depends, depends on
how big the tickets are.
Depends.
I've had up to like 20 or
30 tickets assigned to me at once.
Well,
sometimes as low as two,
maybe one.
All right, guys, we are back.
You guys see my screen right now?
Everything or
how about now?
Yes, you see it? Okay, cool.
All right. So.
All right, we're back.
Let's talk someone else
real quick for a quick review of JIRA.
Okay. So
let's talk about what JIRA, we basically
discussed a lot about with you.
But high level, high level,
short overview.
What is JIRA?
But what is JIRA?
It's a project management tool. Right.
And what can we essentially do
with this tool?
What can we essentially do with this tool?
Manage a project, right?
Create a user story, tasks, bugs.
You know, so far it's right. Everything.
We keep track of our work,
what we're working
on, you know, give updates,
you know, and so forth.
You got
who sees gyro, you the whole team does.
It's for everyone.
This is where everything is.
Okay. These are the user stories.
Do you guys remember when we started class
and I said, Hey, if an acceptance
criteria needs to be updated, ask
the business analyst to update the ticket.
You guys remember,
this is exactly what I mean.
So if you read this
and an acceptance criteria is unclear,
you would say, Hey, can you clarify this?
Okay, boom, it's been clarified
and you're going to say, okay,
can you update the ticket?
So it reflects that.
So they'll come here
and they'll update the ticket.
Does that make sense?
This is where they do everything. Cool.
All right.
So we manage our tools here.
We had a a sample of a
sprint planning ceremony, right?
We had that sample of Sprint
planning ceremony.
We did.
And that's how they would go.
Right.
What do we do in the sprint
planning ceremony?
What do we do?
We created the sprint.
We had a meeting, but what do we do?
We assign we assigned level of efforts.
Right? Exactly.
Scott said. Assigned to developers.
Right, exactly.
Very good. Right.
And if you remember,
we were on the backlog, right?
And we had the items in the backlog.
Right.
And we moved them to the sprint that we're
currently in, which is Sprint one.
And you can see here that it's active.
Cool.
All right, cool.
All right.
So now let's say that the tickets are the
they have been developed,
okay, have been developed
and they're here.
They're in progress.
However, we can move it to Don
because testing hasn't been completed yet.
So what we're going to do is this
this is going to be your test and everyone
pay attention to this,
but don't do anything yet on the board.
Please pay very close attention
so that you don't have to ask
a million questions.
You're
going to open this ticket in a new tab.
And when you're here you're
going to read the acceptance criteria.
Okay, guys, what are you going to do?
And you're going to
I want you guys to test it first.
I want you guys to go into the syntax
mass application
and test this yourself first.
Go without writing a test case
first. Cool.
Then after that and after you know what
to do and everything like that,
then what you're going to do
is you're going to create a task.
You're going to create a task.
And this is what I want you guys to do.
So let's say that
I am testing this ticket, okay?
Let's say I am testing this ticket.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to
copy the name of this ticket.
When it copy the name of this ticket,
you can copy it somewhere, you know,
whatever I'm going to click create.
And the summary is that name.
I'm going to put the name here.
But first I want you guys to type A,
a user log in and at the end, type
your name.
Okay?
Type your name.
Okay.
This is the naming convention
that we're going to follow with the task
that we're going to create. Okay.
Now listen to this. Right?
I'm going to scroll down and I'm going to
assign it to myself.
This case, I'm a cell, so I'm going
to send it to myself, assign it to you.
Assign it to you
right here in the assigning field.
That's going to be you.
Okay. And here's the thing, right?
I want you to look at this.
I want you to
click on Sprint and select
the active sprint.
Right.
And we are in
H are a mess and pay very close attention
to which spread you select
out of all of these.
We are an h r m as b 11.
That's 11 for your for your batch
sprint one and you see at the sprint
you're not going to click sprint two,
you're not going to click Sprint three,
you're not going to click on a batch
ten project,
you're not going to click on anything
else.
You're going to go to HMS B 11 and click
Sprint one read
as you're active a sprint, Don't
do anything yet, okay?
Don't do anything yet.
So when I do that,
I get a message on the bottom
that says Sprint scope
will be affected by this action.
Okay, so I am
creating a new ticket,
okay, I'm creating a new issue.
What is this issue?
This is a task.
Okay. This is a task, right?
And I'm set because I'm assigning it
to this sprint, which is already active,
and I'm adding more work to the
to the sprint
I'm getting this message right,
saying that the sprint scope
will be affected by this action.
Again, essentially when we add a ticket
on the board or a issue on the board,
that means that there's more work to do,
meaning more time, Right?
That's exactly what it means.
So that's what we're getting the message.
But honestly, we're just going to use this
to write a test case and stuff.
We've technically already
assigned our employees.
We're testing stock and our test case
creation is part of that employee, right?
So here what we're going to do
is you're going to click this,
and here
is I want
you guys to be very close to this one.
Okay.
So first of all, let me cancel this.
Okay. And let's start again.
I want to see
if you guys were paying attention.
So what am I going to do first?
What am I going to do
not create?
What am I going to do before create?
Copy the name of what?
Copy the name of what
I want.
Copy the name of the ticket
Title of the user story ticket.
Right this right here.
So I'm going to copy this. Okay.
And then what am I going to do?
Create. Yes.
And then what am I going to do here?
I'm going to place it
in the summary. Right?
And then what am I going to do?
What am I going to do with the name?
Tell me, where am I going to write this?
Very, very good. Yes, that's right.
I said from Fairfax things
Q a hyphen about user log in
right hyphen and your name.
So I can visually see better
because you guys are going to create
a lot of tickets.
I want to be able to easily see who it is.
Okay, so Diego, right?
You're going to write your name.
Okay, What's next, guys?
What am I going to do next?
You're going to scroll down
in the same to myself, right?
In this case, we're going to send it
to cell because I'm a cell right now.
Okay.
Okay cool.
All right.
And then what else am I going to do?
Pick the correct spread?
Yes. So I'm going to click on this
and what Sprint are in.
Which one are you going to click on?
Sprint one.
But which one match 11. Sprint one.
This one.
Right. HMS B 11. Right.
So I'm going to click this. Okay. Right.
Very, very nice.
Fantastic. Beautifully done.
There is one more important
step that we need to do.
Okay?
And this is going to be the step
that I actually want to remember the most.
Okay.
So first of all, there's this option here
that says linked issues
a.k.a linked tickets.
Right?
And we're going to say that this task
that we're creating, right, this task
that we're creating, make sure this is
set to tests with an S right.
This task tests.
What issue
H are
a mess B11 for do you guys see this right
here?
This ticket is going to test
h arm b elapses.
I wanted to have an h r
and that's actually not bromfield.
Sorry, h r that's u C and it comes here.
So I'm going to select this one
right here.
Okay?
That's what I'm going to do.
Okay. Now
again, we're going to make sure
that this is in test.
If you click on it,
there are other options relates to blocks,
clones, errors like that.
Now we want to select test
because this task tests
HMS B alone for now.
What happens
if we don't do this part? Right?
And I'll tell you what happens.
So what I'm doing right now,
the linking that I'm doing right now,
the linking that
doing right now
is creating or establishing a relationship
between this ticket, this task
and the user story.
Okay.
If I don't link it,
there will be no relationship at all.
And I'm going to show you
how that works, Right.
So I'm going to link it
No one to anything.
Once I do this, I'm going to create it.
Right? Okay. And it's creating red.
And if I scroll down
and actually if I refresh the page,
right, you see, I, I,
if I says this ticket is below for
if I scroll down it says it's tested
by the ticket we just created.
So not as the terminology
that we selected.
We said tests, right.
And we selected this
and now it kind of changed on its own.
Is it tested by
so this is saying, hey, HMS B 11
four is tested by this ticket, right?
So we're able to open this ticket
and this is the ticket that we created.
There's obviously nothing there.
We didn't add any steps subscript.
That's that's what we did.
Now, if I didn't do the linking guys,
we wouldn't be able to see this here.
Look, it would look like this,
but I'm going to delete it.
I'm going to delete this link. Right?
It will look like this.
Even though we created a task to test
that user story.
Right.
There is there will be nothing.
There will be no relationship, nothing.
So what happens is this.
Whenever you're trying to tell your team
that you're done testing, right,
the betas or whatever,
when it's time to see, like
maybe they found a bug in production
and they're going to ask you,
Hey, Anna, did you test this right?
And you going to say, Yeah, I tested this,
This is user story HMS Beloved for
they're going to come
and open the ticket, right?
They're going to come
open HMS B 11 four right.
And they're going to see
wait a minute, you said you tested this,
but there is no test case linked to this,
right?
There's no test case linked to this.
When there's not a test case
linked to this, that's automatically
going to give the impression
that you didn't test it correctly.
Okay. Yes.
There is no proof of being tested
that maybe you just said, yeah, whatever,
and you just move the ticket and you said
it was done without really testing it.
Right. It's going to give that assumption.
It is part of documentation,
a very good thought.
My yes, you're right.
Does that make sense to everyone?
Okay. Does that make sense to everyone?
Yeah.
So we need to create that
relationship now.
Do you guys
remember how I assign the sprint?
You guys remember how
I assigned the sprint?
Yeah. So because I assigned.
That ticket, that task to the sprint,
look where it shows now.
It shows in the sprint
in the sprint board because I assigned it
to Sprint one, you guys remember.
So now it's here.
So here's another pointer.
If you don't select a sprint,
this ticket is going to go to the backlog.
Okay,
So a lot of you guys are going to say,
Hey, I don't see my ticket on the board.
It's not there.
I created it.
Well, you probably didn't link it, right?
You probably didn't
link it to the correct spread
where you maybe didn't
link it to a sprint at all.
Therefore, it's probably in the backlog.
Right.
Secondly, you know, you need to make sure
that to link that ticket.
Right.
So I'm going to open this ticket again,
HMS before 11 before it.
So if you forget to add link
when you create it, that's okay.
There's another way to do it.
If I open the ticket
and I'll click on more
when I click on more, see,
we have options.
As you see, there's an option
that's called link.
Okay, So I'm going to click on this, Okay?
And I'm going to
and this already says this issue tests.
No, this issue now is tested by
and we already created the ticket.
Right?
So what is the name of the task?
HMS B11 five. Right.
So what I'm going to do here
is i'm going to come here.
I'm going to say h.r. Must be 11 five.
It's already in there.
Okay.
It must be 11.
This will be h.r. Mess
h.r. Mess.
Whoa.
H or mass.
B 11 five.
Okay. They up.
So now i am going to link it.
Okay.
And it's linked right here.
Okay, cool.
Does that make sense?
Does that make sense to everyone?
Right? So the wording change.
Take a moment to read how the wording is.
Right?
You can do it right right off the bat
if you followed instructions.
Right. But I also showed you
how to come back and link on it.
You forgot to link it.
Okay, so let's recap what we did.
We created a task.
Read what I did was I created
I opened a ticket, a ticket
that went into, let's say, HMS B 11.
Can I open this ticket in a new tab?
And then I read the acceptance criteria.
I'm going to go and manually do
the testing on my cell first go.
Then I'm going to come to create
wait before clicking create.
What do I
before clicking, Create what I do.
Copy.
Copy What?
Copy the title.
So I'm going to copy this
and I'm going to come here and then
I'm going to paste it.
Okay? Yup. Exactly.
So there's a Q8 hyphen, right?
Name your name So there's a gaggle, right?
And then what am I going to do?
Assign it to myself.
Okay, what else am I going to do?
Link it, link to issue.
So I'm going to say, do I say tested by
is this a correct terminology?
We're going to change the tests. Exactly.
We're going to change it to tests.
And then what do I enter here?
What do I need to
The ticket must be level one.
Very good.
Very, very good.
No, not for one.
Because this ticket right here is one.
You guys see this HMS B 11 one.
Exactly.
So I'm going to look this up at this one.
This one, HMS B 11 one.
Right?
There you go.
So now I've established that relationship
with this task, Right.
And this user story.
So then the sprint what Sprint,
am I going to select?
Y why would you say to know
you're going to select HMS
Sprint one, HMS B 11, Sprint one, right?
Because we're going to work on two
disparate work on it right now.
Now what happens
if I forget to like a sprint?
What happens?
Where will you find it
if you forget to?
Yes, it's going to be in the backlog
Very, very, very, very good.
Okay. Very, very good.
And then once you do this, you're going
to. Great.
Now, I forgot to say something.
Well, actually didn't forget.
This is going to be the last
ultimatum step.
These are going to be
your cucumber scenarios or test cases.
Okay.
So what you're going to do is you're going
to write your scenario here using given
when that came, you're going to write
your test cases there.
Yes, I saw Fairfax. You're like on Fireman
on Fire.
I show unbelievable.
Unbelievable. Okay.
So do you guys see that you're going
to write your cucumber scenarios here
that's writing this here
bag of money, right.
So does that make sense?
Right.
You're going to write your test case here.
Once it's done, guys, click create.
When you guys created,
I will be able to see your test case.
I'll be able
to give you a feedback on the goal.
Okay,
Ready, set, go, go, go, go.
You guys know what to do? Let's go.
You're going to test every single ticket.
Okay, But actually, hold on. First of all.
First of all,
everyone only work on h.r matters.
Hold on, hold
on, hold on, hold on, work on
hms b 11 to okay, hms b 11 to go.
This is a class activity.
I wanted to work on HRA mass b11 to
do not work on any other ticket
until I tell you to do so again.
So because of that, I'm going to move
the tickets back here so you get confused.
We're working on HMS level two.
Okay, so go ahead, open that in a new tab.
Create the task as we discussed
and go for it.
Okay? And go for it.
Let's go, guys.
Let's go.
Right.
Okay.
Let's see.
Someone already created something, right?
We have Aleksander created very one.
He follows the naming conventions.
Going to see what he did here.
Okay.
He didn't read the cucumber steps,
so he already didn't
follow the instructions
to actually test the scenario.
Okay,
so he didn't write the cucumber stuff.
So this is already not good. And.
But he did the linking.
Very good.
So that's well done.
But you still need to test guys.
You need to do the testing first, guys.
You need to do the testing first
and then write your cucumber scenario.
Okay.
So write your scenario there.
Let's see. Ellen.
Ellen already did this.
Let's see what's Ellen doing now?
Alan, you need to write the scenario.
Like, you actually need to read the test
cases, guys, not just given when and then.
So he linked it properly. Very good.
Okay, write the scenario, guys.
Write the cucumber scenario.
Marvin did it.
I'm pretty sure the same thing, Right?
Write the scenario.
He linked it properly. Very good.
Okay, but go and write the cucumbers
in here.
Actually write the scenario
net affect quizzes.
Ahmed.
Okay, so he like to write, but you need to
go and write the cucumber scenario.
Okay, All in. Time out.
Time out. Too much.
I'm out to my everyone.
Time up, time up,
someone hold on, hold on.
So when they created ticket,
they made a mistake.
Okay, hold on, guys. Time out.
Stop creating tickets.
They made a mistake.
Marvin and Othman. A mistake.
Okay.
What mistake do you think that is?
Just look at the screen.
What mistake do you think they made here?
I'm going to close this.
Okay?
It is not a task.
They created a user story.
They were not supposed
to create a user story.
So go back and change it to a test.
Where is the cucumber scenario?
You actually need to write it
yourself in the description area.
Gerald Okay, so look,
if you open my ticket, for example, right,
it was below, but you did the linking,
but in the description here
you write your, you write your scenario
given, you know, just fill in the blanks
and so forth.
All right. Just go with it.
Okay.
But, but you need to actually write
real cucumber scenario.
Okay.
So first of all, you need to test it,
and I'm going to review your work.
Okay.
So let's see
Marvin,
go back there and change it to a task.
Lots.
Who's lost a lot?
I didn't write the cucumber scenarios.
They did the linking very well.
Okay Lotto Who's letter?
Whose letter
who's not?
Someone
that you need to go
and write the cucumbers?
No, but the linking was very good.
Okay, You need to write the scenario.
Okay.
We have
I can see that Alan Right. So
admin user log in.
Zima.
So Zima didn't
follow the naming convention.
What is she forgetting here?
Look at the screen.
What is she can what is
what is she forgetting here
in the naming convention?
The hyphen. Exactly.
After logging right there.
Very good.
So please pick that amazing.
Emma, you also didn't write the cucumbers.
You just wrote the keywords.
You need to write the actual test case,
guys.
You need to write the actual test case.
Lewis.
Lewis,
You need to write the actual test case.
The linking was good.
So in the description
you need to write the actual test case.
Okay, Jimmy, same thing with you.
You did the linking.
You need to write the actual test case for
the you like write the actual test case.
Okay, let's see. So Jimmy is there.
So guys,
a lot of you guys are creating this
for writing the test
because you need to write the test cases.
Arwa, you did the same mistake.
Go change it to a task instead of a story.
Okay.
Someone created it without name,
so I can't even say anything about that.
Emily Asia and
Malaysia in the in the lead
you in Malaysia
and Malaysia did the linking.
Well, she did a very good job as a task
but she didn't write
the cucumber scenario.
She needs to write the cucumber scenario.
She's only writing working keywords.
You need to
you need to write the cucumber scenario.
Okay. Dominic,
Dominic, Dominic.
One thing you didn't do, Dominic,
which is a big red flag, you didn't link
your take your task to the user story,
okay?
You need to link
the tasks to the user story.
Yeah.
Yes, it is a task. It's not.
I use the story as a test. Okay.
And you also need to write your cucumbers
now as guys come out.
Come on, please come up.
Hold on, guys. Come on, guys.
You guys
actually have to write the cucumbers?
No, not just given
when they write the test case
for that user story, go write it.
Okay, So, Ekaterina, same thing.
You it. Well then everything. Well,
you linked it, but you need
to write the cucumber scenario.
Ahmad Shah.
Michelle
Sorry if I didn't say write the delinking.
Well, you get everything back,
but you didn't write cucumber scenario,
now did you write the cucumber scenario?
Did you write the cucumber scenario?
The use read the Q was given one that
you need to write.
The cucumber scenario came
Lenny didn't follow the instructions
on the naming convention.
So and she also needs the changes
to the tasso.
Lenny, please fix that.
Nikolai
You also didn't follow instructions.
You selected a story instead of a task,
but you wrote the scenario
and I applaud you for that.
Very, very good.
So, Nikolai, please go back and change the
user story to a task.
Okay.
Good job.
Nikolai
Sorbonne.
Once a month.
So, what are you there? Are you in class?
So, what are you in class?
The Sorbonne here is.
So why are you there?
So month
to month you're writing a scenario
for a Netflix test case.
The acceptance criteria
for this is for syntax.
h.R. Ms..
You actually need to write
the real scenario
to test that user story.
Okay, so change it.
Right.
Fatma, are you there?
Instructor
Guys, look at this. Look at this test.
Look at look at this.
Look at this in there.
Read the scenarios, read this.
NARRATOR
Look at this.
You can see this is.
I already showed the linking.
You see the follow through, right?
I told you I should have.
I'll show you right
now. Right, I'll show you. But you got to.
You got to stay on your toes.
This is going to keep you on your toes.
Okay, So here's the thing.
Look, Fatma, this is good.
The linking is good.
But please write your cucumber scenario
to reflect the acceptance criteria
that you're testing.
Okay? Okay. Don't worry.
I sure will help you.
I'll help you out. Okay.
I'm just going in order here,
so I'll get to your show.
Alexei,
you didn't
write the cucumber scenario, Alexei.
You didn't even do the linking.
Right?
So your test case is like
you have no relationship
between this task and and that.
So, Alexei, please fix that.
Has seen
you didn't write a proper.
Okay, now it's timer time.
Our real quick time.
A timeout timeout timeout timeouts
tenant timer come out.
Okay turn up okay
Right.
So look at the screen
I seem is breaking some very important
rules with this cucumber scenario.
What is the number one
rule that we see here?
What is the number one thing?
The first letter of each
key word has to be capitalized.
Right?
So he needs to change the lowercase
G to uppercase G.
Same thing with W and A and and these.
Secondly, there is no linking.
So look, I'm a
keep it 100 with you guys, Right.
I will keep on I'll keep it 100 with you
if you're not leaking
that's just show me that you didn't
attention to it and follow through.
Now some of you guys may be having issues.
That's fine. I will help you.
But a lot of you guys, I keep saying
the same thing over and over again.
I keep saying write the cucumber scenario
to reflect the acceptance
criteria that you had to test, but
you guys aren't doing that only somewhat.
The only person that paid attention
was Nikolai, Right.
And he's he's following through.
So please, please fix that. Okay, Fix it.
Fix it, Fix it.
All right, let's see.
Lewis.
Lewis linked it
to Yes, Lewis.
That's right, Lewis.
Right on, man.
Very good job, Lewis.
Amazing.
You know, we call people like you, Lewis
Where we call people like Lewis
Bag of money.
That's right.
Got a bag of money is right.
Okay, let's see.
So I'm going to go down the list again
to review anyone who's working on that.
Okay, Hold on, hold on, hold
on, hold on, hold The hold on, guys.
Hold on.
Okay, You guys are all you guys are
breaking the rules big time here, right?
You guys are doing things
that you guys weren't to do.
Why are you guys moving the tickets
to the column
that anyone say, Move the tickets.
Don't call them Merriam.
Anyone told you to move into the done
column?
Whoever
this is, admin user log in must be 18.
I can.
I know who did this, but
you obviously didn't follow directions.
Hanukkah, Hanukkah is not you.
You didn't follow instructions, right?
So how to go back and write cucumbers
notes?
Open the ticket.
Your task.
And in the description box right in there.
I'll show you. Okay, look, everyone pass.
Everyone passed. Pass, pass by surprise.
Plus, as possible.
Look at my screen, please.
Look at my screen.
Okay, Licorice screen.
Okay. First of all, hold on.
Cool.
Move the ticket back to the in progress.
You see, now we have a task
CC moved into in progress.
No one told you to move the ticket
to in progress.
Right.
And where's the user story
that we're working on?
You see what happens
when you guys start moving stuff.
So now I have to go back and look for it.
Which one was was it user admin login.
This one to log.
Which one was it
1 to 2.
We for.
Okay.
Abdul
guys, what happened to our ticket?
Someone messed around, didn't
follow instructions and that's that's
what happened right.
You get lost.
A lot of you guys
aren't following instructions,
which is why everything's been started.
A backlog.
Shareef is one of those students, Right.
So what happened to all that?
No one, no one touch anything anymore.
Because some of you guys
obviously messed all of this up.
All right.
And in your workplace,
are you going to mess up
like this?
Are you
are you going to mess up like this?
Right. Are you going to. No, you're not.
You guys are moving tickets
when you guys weren't told to do
so, you guys are changing
the name of the tickets
when you guys weren't told to do so.
And now it's all a big mess, right?
So like, you know, follow instructions.
No, I can't find that ticket.
Someone changed the status of it.
And guys, stop creating tickets.
Let me figure this out.
What cause can you log into JIRA board?
Now we look for this ticket
because I can't find it.
I can't.
I can't find it.
Can't find it.
Policy.
Okay, hold on. No one do anything.
Please don't stop, stop,
Stop doing what you're doing.
I need to fix this.
I to fix this.
Oh, I think it was one
shoe.
Was it to hold on?
Was it to see?
Well, on.
Oh, Oh.
What?
Cause I found it.
So cc cc you went and changed this for us.
You actually opened the user story
and you it who sees it?
Who is BRC or h.R.
Yes. Who is this?
We need to find out who this is.
Okay I need to find out who who it is.
Who is cc?
Guys, who is this?
Who is cc like, you know,
we change it back to story.
Got it deleted the steps as well
okay, I'm going to just change this here
7 hours
and 37 hours itself this criteria set
this criteria will done
at the bottom guys hold on,
hold on, guys, hold on, hold on, hold on.
Don't do anything.
Please don't do anything on the way to go.
Let them just fix this.
I met this again.
Thanks to the history that I can see.
Someone obviously named CC,
not follow instructions.
Right.
And guys, please ask questions
instead of, you know,
messing things up. Right.
So assign this back.
Let me see. Hold on, guys.
Don't do anything yet. One, two, three.
Well done.
We Have.
Where's the other one?
Hey, get one of those.
Please don't do anything.
Want to
hold on?
Look at this.
Hold on.
Okay, so we have to have one to
talk.
We as
someone moved it to Sprint two
for some reason.
I don't know what you
made.
Okay.
And we'll just back.
Go back to that two sprints
bitch on this one.
All right, guys, can
everyone can everyone just.
Just stop what you're doing, please?
Which is not what you're doing.
It is very clear that some of you guys
don't know how to follow instructions.
Right.
And some of you guys like, just like,
You know what I mean?
Like, if you're going to do this at work,
you're going to get fired.
Probably, right?
You should not do this, especially
with the project management tool.
I already told you from beginning, right?
I said, Everything you're doing,
JIRA is recorded.
I tell you guys what to do
and not to do something.
And so where you guys still went in there
and started moving tickets around.
So What, you guys move things to another
sprint, right?
So like,
I mean, that's how you are that that's a
you are right but don't you know
don't don't ruin the rest of of the course
you know do this for your classmates
who are paying attention to everything.
All right so HMS B 11 two, we found it.
We're good.
We're back on we're back on track.
Okay. So continue what you're doing.
Please do not change any of the user
stories.
Okay? I'm pleased on issue.
I don't see HMS before.
Why do you need to see HMS before HMS
B 11 before?
It's right here.
But we're not working on that.
We're only working on HMS B11 two.
Right, guys, we are only working on h.r.
Mass. B 11 two and nothing else. Right?
So you shouldn't
even be worried about hms B 11 for that.
We're only working about HMS B 11
two and I need to see
if you guys how to remove move a ticket
from the backlog.
You go to the backlog. Right?
And if you see the ticket here, you have
to click hold and drag it like this.
You will click, hold
and drag it to Sprint one.
Okay, cool.
I hope you found that right.
So let me see.
So HMS B11 two,
that's what we're working on.
My read your comment, Momma,
how's your kid doing?
How's your brother's
son's name?
Who How is
this done?
Doing good.
Let's see.
That's good. That's good.
That's good. That's a really good.
That's a really nice name.
So. All right,
Thank goodness somebody took a screenshot.
Thanks. Armored carrier one.
Just actually pay attention.
I can,
but I don't know about the rest, so.
All right. So
the signee is is
you assign it to yourself, right, Dennis?
You assign it to yourself.
Yes. Okay.
So I'm going to go down and let me look
let me credit.
So first of all, Shareef didn't
follow the instructions at all,
so I'm going to skip it.
I'm going to go to the next one.
Alexander So let's see what Alexander did.
He linked it.
Well done.
When the admin attempts
to log in with proper credentials
are Alexander, delete the word attempts.
You'll see when the admin
in with valid credentials.
Yeah, but everything else is good.
This is good.
This is good. Alexander.
What you can do is you can help me
help your classmates.
Come.
So, Allan, let's see. Allan.
Allan links it.
Well, he runs the cucumber scenarios.
There's inconsistency in your scenario,
Allan.
You have a period in the last statement,
but you don't have a period
in the other ones.
So you decide what this I would do
when the admin
to log in with proper credentials.
So I'll work on that.
Allan Okay, I'll fix it, fix executive,
fix it, fix it.
It's good.
Marvin.
Marvin So Marvin either is Marvin here?
Marvin
Marvin there.
Marvin changed the like.
You got to change the key words when
and then it's given one then.
Okay, make it make sense.
Far as that everything was was good. So.
So work on it.
That's good.
Okay.
Ahmet, are you there?
Is Ahmed there?
Okay, hold on.
I might try.
Some of you guys ask Alexa. You mean
how to fix what exactly?
Alexa?
What do you mean, how to fix what? No,
but I think Alexa ask.
Alexa, what do you make Change it?
Like, What do you mean, make changes?
Alexa, can you tell me the your ticket ID?
Can you tell me your ticket
ID so I can look it up?
No way I can help you.
Oh, it's right here. Right.
Okay. There you go. Alexa.
I found it right here.
Okay, everyone, pay attention.
I'm going to work on Alexa's ticket.
And a lot of you guys
are having this issue, so pay attention.
So, HMS B 1128, I'm going to open it.
This is his ticket.
He followed instructions.
The name is good and he didn't link it.
Right. And I think that's
what you're asking, Right.
How do you link it again, Alexa? Right.
Is that your question?
Okay, so you need to read the cucumber
scenario, by the way.
But here's how we link it, Right, guys?
Everyone pay attention.
If you forgot to link it the first time,
if you forgot to link it the first time,
what you do is you open your ticket,
which I did on one Alexei's ticket.
Okay?
And the next thing you're going to do
is you're going to click on more.
Okay, what do you think?
I'm going to click here, Link.
Right. I'm going to go to Link
right there.
Very good.
And then is this tickets tested by
or does this test
test another ticket?
It tests?
No, it's not tested by it
tests another ticket.
Right.
So I'm going to change this to tests.
And what is the ticket number
that he's going to test here?
He needs a ticket number. I don't have it.
What is it, guys? Do you guys now
for this one, add me use long.
It must be two. Right?
So age are a must be two right there
and you click on it.
For some reason I have to type it in
and then I have to press enter
and then it works.
Okay, so I must be 11 two.
Right? And Alexei, did you see that?
That's all you have to do.
I'm not going to do it for you.
I want you to do it. Did you.
Did you hear that, Alexei?
I want you to do it.
Okay?
It's very simple,
but I'm going to cancel it.
I'm going to go back.
All right, let's see.
Sharif still hasn't fixed his ticket.
Sharif.
Sharif, is this your ticket?
Show it right here.
What do you think the problem is
with The problem is Sharif
right?
The naming convention?
At the same time, you also didn't link
the user story that you had
the test you didn't link and you didn't
establish that relationship.
Right.
We we talked about that.
Okay, guys, hold on.
I need to say something to someone right
now, okay?
I need to make an announcement
to the class.
Can everyone stop? What You're doing.
Can everyone just stop what you're doing?
We're going to go back to this,
like, in 2 minutes.
Okay?
We're going to go back to this,
like, in 2 minutes.
Okay.
All right.
Just just listen to what I have to say.
I get it.
So a lot of this
material is new to you, okay?
A lot of this material is new to you.
That's fine.
I get it. It's
the first time you're doing this.
You may need instructions
to, you know, to be repeated again.
That's fine.
I'm here to help.
Right.
For those of you that can do this, right,
this is probably 65 to 70%.
The job showing your progress,
knowing how to work with JIRA,
knowing how to how to show your progress,
how to you know, what ticket to touch,
what take is not to touch.
You know,
if you're able to do this one,
you followed
instructions, you were able to learn it
and now you're able to use it.
And this is a very, very, very big thing
that you guys will use in your projects.
Okay.
Does that make sense to everyone?
Does that make sense?
Yeah.
And at the same time, right.
For those of you look
for those of you,
if we're everyone in this class
and I see this all the time, right,
for everyone in this class,
if you are falling behind
or if you have questions on something,
then you have to ask the questions.
Don't be shy,
okay?
Don't be shy to ask questions.
You are the ones that are paying
for the class, right?
So get your money's worth, right?
Ask the questions right.
Put the work in and ask the questions.
Right.
We're not here to deny
someone and like ignore some one or not.
I'm trying my best to address
everyone's questions is just I see this
like channel
just move up and everything like that.
Okay. Does that make sense? Everyone?
So ask questions because if you don't
get out of this comfort zone
that you're in right now,
if you don't stop to ask questions
and no question is stupid, there's
no such thing as a stupid question.
Okay?
And the thing is that
if you have a question,
there's a very high chance that a lot of
your classmates have the same questions.
Okay, So get out of that comfort zone,
because for the rest of the class
guys, it's going to get very intense.
Okay? It's going to be while.
Right.
It's going to be, you know, in this,
you know, what happens
is in syntax, students, look, I'm lucky
that I'm give it a hundred with you.
A few things happens.
Either students gain a lot of weight gain
or they lose a lot of weight, okay?
Or they start to smoke cigarets or
something like that,
because that's how intense it gets, right?
So make it easy on yourself.
Ask the questions, reach out to support.
We're here for that. Right?
But there's a difference.
There's a difference
when you don't ask the questions,
when you don't ask for clarification,
when you don't stop and say,
Hey, I don't understand this.
Can you please help me?
Guys,
you are responsible for your own progress
and for falling behind and stuff
like that.
Does that make sense or one
is that clear to everyone?
Right. This class is going to get hard.
It's going to get complicated.
But everyone who does, who puts the work
in, who puts the time and effort
in, ends up being successful.
This isn't a get rich quick scheme, guys.
That's what everyone thinks.
And The beginning of the class, right?
Like what?
How is that?
You go somewhere for six months and you
come out making this much money, you know?
Right.
You got to work for it, right?
And this is exactly what we have to do.
Okay.
But it all starts from here.
From the it all starts from here.
Are you able to follow instructions?
Are you able to pay attention?
Are you able to listen?
You able to ask for help?
Are you able to help others? Okay.
These are things that you have to kind of
think to yourself
as you move on in the course.
Does that make okay?
And all of you guys, I applaud
everyone here for being here and changing
your life.
A lot of you guys are here
making a big difference in your life.
Some of you may never had a job
that pays the patient this much.
Some of us
are just looking to change fields.
So whatever the case may be, right,
some of you guys are in here
to to, to to better, better your families.
We have students like Eric
who is not listening to what I'm saying.
I was sharing a screenshot right.
So we're here to either for our families,
for ourselves,
to to make our families proud,
to make our name for ourselves.
Something like that. Right Right.
So does that is that clear to everyone?
It all starts from you.
You have to ask questions.
You cannot leave a class saying,
I didn't understand.
This instructor, he's
not good at teaching, right?
If I recall really?
Well, every single instructor here at
Syntax is really good at what they teach.
Every single one of them.
Okay, If it wasn't it, I promise
you, Samir would not let them teach.
I promise you that. 100% guaranteed. Okay.
And I'm being very, very honest
and same thing like, you know what I mean?
So you need to ask the questions.
You are responsible for your own progress.
You have to ask the questions. Guys,
we are here.
And I repeat that
you kind of have to do this for yourself.
Okay. Does that make sense to everyone?
It's kind of like that phrase, right?
Do you want to be happy?
Everyone's responsible for their own
happiness up to a certain extent, right?
The rest is up to God itself, Right?
So are we good with that?
Does everyone understand that? Right?
Does everyone understand
that?
I'm just because, you know,
I mean, like, you guys can do it.
We have had Uber drivers,
but I've never opened the laptop before
and they're like out there successful,
you know, killing it and stuff.
You know what I mean?
We have you know,
we do, you know, Home Alone
or home moms that do this
and they become successful.
They become the backbones
of their families.
They have
we have different success stories.
We have people
who don't really need a income.
They just want to switch careers
and they still do it.
And that's fine.
I'm all for kids. There you go.
So there's going to be,
you know, a bag of money soon.
And then her kids
are going to be bags of money, right? So.
Well, because maybe at some point
they'll see how nice it is and so forth.
Right.
And this goes to everyone out there
and everyone who has kids
and families married or whatever
your case may be.
You guys need to, you know, There you go.
All right.
I okay.
I hope that's not you know,
I don't want to smoke cigarets and stuff.
Okay, cool.
All right.
Are we clear?
Can we move on?
And again, to those of
you asked the questions.
Okay, ask the questions. Go.
All right, let's move
on. Let's proceed. Right.
So Lisa says, Can you help me?
What's wrong?
All right, so to address a leaflet.
A leaflet, what do you
I think are trying to link?
But where is your
where is your
where's your your your ticket?
What's your ticket number.
Let's a lease.
A lease on the lease the lease.
The lease.
I don't see your number here
but I don't,
I don't understand
what would your what quit.
Okay. First I try to link OMG
okay.
If are you okay if I move on
to the next question because I find
okay so.
Oh it's probably already linked, right?
It's not what you're saying.
It it's probably really linked.
Is that what you're trying to say?
Okay. There you go. Yeah, that happens.
If you already linked it,
you won't be able to really get.
Okay.
Farhad says that was in the question
now says and how and how what I don't know
with notes that I'm going in order.
You guys just bear with me. You
all right?
Okay.
For those of you that have said good job,
look into the other tickets
and help me help your classmates.
Alright? We're all the team here at See?
Okay.
Objective now is going to help
is going to be some kind of question. No.
If you're not typing anything
and I on to the next question.
Okay.
Mom of three of you there's no question.
How do we see the issue of management?
What do you mean?
How do you see the issue? Like me?
Are you there?
Like what?
What do you mean?
Like, what's the question?
How do you see it?
Well, it's right here. Right?
So what is the ticket?
What is what?
Where is your ticket? You.
Do you know it or no?
Yeah, that's fine.
But you can do whatever you want.
So let me ask.
It is did you create it or.
No, you created.
Okay.
Method that you assign it to this Brant,
did you follow the naming convention
that we're supposed to follow?
You didn't follow that.
You didn't follow the naming convention,
which is why it was difficult to.
Are you a me no start?
Because now you or no.
Okay. So you didn't follow the naming
convention, right?
The domain convention
was to distinguish the tickets.
You know, first
you blocked
something here.
Why is to say that someone changes again?
You probably didn't
assign it to the sprint.
So it's right here. I found it. This is.
This is your ticket.
If this is your ticket. Right.
So What is it? It.
What was your question?
I thought
I had to see instructions or issue.
I don't understand the question.
You're saying like what instructions?
Here is the issue.
Here's the issue. We found it.
So what is the question of what?
What is that?
I see that you added an incorrect link,
so I'm going to you know,
you can delete it, you can delete the
links, how to see the acceptance criteria.
The acceptance criteria is on the ticket
that you need to test.
So you're testing
them as be to right so as we to
is right here,
this is a term as B to and someone who's
sorry survivor on Your honor
why are you moving tickets and secondly,
someone changed this again
I'm going to see who it is
and I'm going to call you out
to let's see
and someone needed to acceptance criteria
she's since it's
Come on guys
there
I hope that I don't have to do this again.
All right. So
let's see.
People are creating their own
spreads. Who?
Who's my hand?
My hand.
Nikolic.
They. You.
How did you create your own spread
when you were supposed to
know?
Create a difference? Spread.
Come on, let's.
All right, so I'm going to change this
so have Verona move back to a progress
and see
she is
can choose back to a story.
So that's been updated.
All right.
So let's continue on.
Okay. Let's continue.
I'm going to go back here to Gerald
Gerald Hicks.
You may want to capitalize
on your last name,
Gerald.
So the gods, you should have copied
and pasted the name instead, Gerald,
because I see that you have lowercase
terminology here.
Okay. And
giving user
what page went and log in is disabled.
So we need to write a better cucumber
scenario.
And Gerald, you actually did not link
the user story.
Okay, so you need to do that.
Hanoch you linked it,
you have no description.
77 you have no cucumber scenario.
This is not good.
Okay, I'm
is that who is who is asking for 77 but
someone else.
If you created a story, change it please.
It's not a story, okay? It's not a story.
What is it?
It's a task.
Mustafa 75 Link link. Did.
So this is okay. Mustafa 75.
But here's the thing.
Your step one enters
valid credentials, right?
And you can say and logs in right
then the user.
So you're forgetting a step right now
you just entering valid credentials.
They have to do something else
after after log in.
So need to edit that step.
74 Roman remain.
You didn't assign it to yourself,
you linked it well
when admin logs in with no content.
Okay, good.
This is good.
Roman. You understand?
You understood the assignment
so Maher.
Maher, this is okay.
You don't need to have the URL.
You can just say
given users on the syntax.
HMS on page right?
That's fine.
Okay.
Now we'll.
No, no, no
nos links it.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
Very good.
Not bad. I'll Take it now.
Good job.
67 all Olga
on page one user.
Okay, good logs in the linking is correct.
Olga Not bad.
Not bad at all.
Eric I will get to you. Okay,
I'll get you.
Please be patient. I'm going down.
I see. It's fine. I see your mess. Don't
worry about it. Just.
Just wait, okay? Try your best.
That's fine.
Okay.
So let's see all that good guys.
Let's help
some of our classmates out, please.
Okay, Let's help
some of our classmates up.
All right?
Let's help some of our classmates out.
65, Roman
Romano, 65.
He links it.
Well, given the websites,
what user enters value and password,
we're forgetting to click on login.
We don't need the URL,
so you may want to rewrite that scenario.
Roman 65.
The Lincoln is good, Charlie.
Now let's see.
Cutting the links at Well,
she didn't write this cucumber scenario.
Catalina, you need to fix that
63 Aisha or I see.
I Aisha.
I don't know which one
it is for our fun facts, but given a user.
Yes. Is there a reason
why we have a period in the last statement
but we don't have a period
in the other statements?
So that's inconsistency, right?
So we need to fix that.
71 Michael
Billington Well, yes, right. Good
Yes, very good.
Where's Michael?
Michael 71 This is pretty good.
So Michael here
spoke on the goal of Michael.
Okay, good stuff,
Michael, Dennis, Dennis, Dennis.
Dennis
follows naming convention.
Well, hold on, Catalina.
I just noticed your naming is off.
It's incorrect.
You're using invalid user luggage.
That's not the correct user story
that we're testing.
Okay, Catalina.
Yes, you are the assignment, right?
Fatma, You're going to
be your assigning to yourself
the assign or is
it just you can just assign to yourself?
Assign it to yourself.
That's fine.
Dennis You didn't write.
You didn't write the cucumber scenario.
Well, you linked it. You everything else.
Well, but you didn't write the cucumber
scenario.
Please, I shall.
Fairfax links it.
Okay. So I shall Fairfax.
When you enter valid
credentials, we're missing
one step and clicks the login by it.
Or you can just say when the user log
or when they I'm in logs
in with the credentials, the linking
everything is good.
Honeyed
giving the user the ability to log in
when two days, 6 hours.
No very bad cucumber scenario,
but you can fix it.
You also didn't link it.
That's fine.
Q admin user Silva
you Silva Silva Silva you linked it well.
You want to change the wording.
Silva You don't to use the word attempts.
Okay.
So when user logs in with
now the credentials, okay.
Sebastian.
Sebastian Yes, the linking as well.
Why do you have the acceptance
criteria here?
Why did you copy and paste
the acceptance criteria in the ticket?
No, you were just supposed to put
you're just supposed to enter.
I know this is not a good to cover.
You say,
given the users on the syntax. h.R.
Resume appears when the user does this
and this happens, right?
So rewrite your scenario.
Sebastian to no, it didn't link it.
I don't see a link to me now.
I don't see a link.
I don't know why we're talking about
facebook when the acceptance criteria has
there was syntax mess on page
or the syntax is application to me.
So you definitely to change that pre
RC, you would need to change your story
to a task.
Okay. You did link it well
and your scenario is very well written.
So priority over there. Good job.
You need to change this to a task.
Okay. Joseph G.
Gabriel. Joe.
Oh, given the user log in to,
we may need to change that.
Cucumbers narrow wording a little bit.
It doesn't really make sense.
And Joseph, I don't see a link to the
to the user story so we need to fix that
Guido
you know you there
you linked in well given user
should be one user
log in below you don't need the URL. Okay
and is username and password
and clicks on log
and by
you may want to change this.
This is not
yeah you have you have a lot of different
things here so for example
your Guido you there.
Yeah. Are you
are you there you here.
Okay so Eugenia is there a reason
why and is all capitalized
but is a given isn't also your test data.
It can go somewhere else.
Not in the middle of the scenario.
Yeah. So let's.
Let's fix that.
Okay, Let's fix that.
This is fine.
Lewis.
Lewis was good. Angelica
links.
It right follows the naming convention.
Yes. Angelica if you're there, not bad.
Not bad at all. Joseph.
Richard Riker.
Joseph.
Rico.
So you link to.
Well given. Okay.
When the admin clicks
the log in fill with credentials.
Okay, I'll take it.
We could be better, but it's good.
The build the build links it.
Okay. Not bad in the bill.
It's fine.
Very good in the bill.
Are you there? Good, good, good.
Miriam, I'm going in order, guys. 44.
I'm 44 right now.
It must be two, given the website, so.
Okay.
Miriam, are you there?
So you're saying given the website link.
But what does that mean?
It was a given.
The user is on this page, right?
We're talking about the user, right?
When the user enters and you did it right
with the next step, we you have a comma
at the end for some reason
and then you have a period
at the last statement for some reason.
So we need consistency right.
Lugo links it Well giving user is giving.
User is what the URL
we need to reward that
when user enters username
and password and clicks, log in.
Okay, good.
But you need to fix the first up
loop.
All you need to fix is this.
Simon Simon links. Well
giving user with valid credentials
that first step doesn't make sense.
Could you? That doesn't make sense
when admin
when admin user logs in.
Okay, you need to fix that. Simon.
Simon.
The linking is good
you to fix your scenario.
Mohamed
Mohammed I don't see linking.
You need to fix it.
Okay.
I see what you did with the scenario.
It's okay,
but you need to fix the linking.
Okay. And I'm 139
so. And links it.
And are you there?
Anna?
Who's Anna?
Anna Not bad.
Not bad at all. Not better.
Then were you with Maria?
Who's free? The Pomona
oh two Minority link is good.
Okay. Period.
Period, period, period.
So she decided to add the periods.
Okay, but it's okay.
That's fine. This is good.
I'll take your Solana.
Given user has valid credentials
guys it needs to be given.
User is on the homepage
giving user is on syntax
as you know
when log in HMS then logged in.
We need to reward this Roxana
you linked it well
Antony, you're saying
when entering the correct
valid credentials, but then something else
needs to happen, right?
You forgot.
If you can write a step like this,
Anthony, you need to specify that.
You need to click on the login button.
Right.
But everything else looks good.
The linking looks good.
Okay, Anthony, I hope you heard that
survey
survey.
The linking is good
given user is on login page
one user is along a page
and then just how it is needed.
It's a password obviously. So. Hey.
So hey, I have a question for you.
This is actually it's fine.
That's good.
The linking is good.
Up to linking is good.
When the admin logs into the site
and the admin logs in with.
Now how how does that make sense?
How can the admin log into site
and then
how can they log in with potentially
when they're already logged in.
So we need to we need to reward that.
We need to reward that and okay,
the linking is good.
I'm in 31 nya 31 given
admin user log in page. Okay
then it should be log then
nya if you're there.
The linking was good.
1630 the linking is good.
Given user two HMS we could definitely
write a better cucumber scenario
and admin insert with DC.
I don't know what that means.
That would help test case review. Alana.
Okay, you're linking is good
given the admin user navigates the syntax
with the admin logs.
Okay. Not that alone. Are you there?
There's a lot of there
were no,
not that. I'll take it along. Okay.
Eight out of ten.
I'll take it. I'll take it. Right.
The linking is good for HMS 28.
Given HMS Admin is on.
Okay, log in patient analyzer.
Okay. Alexei
Alexa quizzes you.
Alexis Tableau.
What is this?
Pretty good job.
Alexei No, not bad at all. Then.
Fatma Let's see.
Fatma there.
Fatma
Okay,
give the user one user
logging in with look.
Fatma.
Fatma Is there a reason why you have
periods at the ends of these statements?
Not a period here.
You can either get rid of all of them
or add it to all of them to be consistent.
Right?
The linking is good,
so fix that Sorbonne 25
The linking is there good? Yes.
And then the user admin is logged in
and directed to the okay, I'll take it.
Sorbonne.
Nikolai. Let's see.
Nikolai. Nikolai.
Nikolai.
Linking is good with these that aren't so.
Tell you what
you guys there?
Okay, so listen, for those of you
that are still waiting for my feedback,
please wait on the call.
For those of you
who I said you guys are good.
The homework assignment for
this is too, and I'll say
it, but it's going to be working on
another task,
another user story,
and doing the same thing again.
I need you guys to write the cucumbers.
Mario for that other story.
I'll tell you which one it is.
Maybe it's one, maybe it's four.
I will. I will.
We will see. Okay, cool.
Guys, tomorrow when you come class, it's
just going to be just pure zero, okay?
Just 0000.
And if I called your name earlier and I
said, Good to go, then you good to go.
If I did that, please wait.
Okay? Yes.
If I said you're okay, then you got to go.
Okay, cool.
Okay.
If not, good will be tomorrow. Okay.
But at the end.
Tomorrow? Yeah, I'll yours.
So, Nikolai.
Nikolai, you're good to go as well.
A Lenny.
Lenny. No,
no, but Lenny need to linkage you
to read the cucumber scenario for that
where we can practice.
You can practice with the new task.
That's fine.
When I'm in logs entering with valid
credential clicks and log in.
Okay.
Ahmadiyya of March.
But, Marshall, this is good.
I'll take it. You're good to go? Yes.
Our posting the work in the course
announcements.
Ekaterina
Okay.
Ekaterina This is good. You're good to go.
Dominic You linked it.
Dominic You're Dominic Need to.
We need to specify here
after entering with valid
credentials that the user needs
to click on login, right?
So then the homepage can display
but everything else is good.
You fix that, you're good to go.
In Malaysia, the linking is good.
We're missing a malaysia.
We're missing the step
to click on the log in button.
Okay?
Because that's the only way
they'll be able to see this in text
page.
Whoever is doing this,
it looks like Hanoch Hanoch.
You didn't name the naming convention,
you didn't write the scenario.
Okay. All right.
Is there anyone else who's waiting on me?
Marina Alexis, you said,
can you guys give me your ticket ID?
So 48.
Let's look at 41st.
Okay.
48, 4848
The link is good given that,
I mean, actually when the admin
logs in with proper credentials
and we'll be logged in.
So. 48 Marina, is there a reason
why we have a period here
and that in the other statements
you could either get rid of them
or do all of them right?
So, you know, the sign
this one was 48, right?
48 way.
Where are we going to order
that? 48.
Christine, are you there?
45. You said 45, Christine,
but 45.
Yeah. 45.
Okay.
Christine So the link is good.
When the admin users on the login page,
the HMS application, but
where are they logging in?
You're not saying that
like when they enter or what log in,
they're not just going to be on the
they're not just going to be able
to be logged in
just by being on the login page.
We need to change this scenario.
Okay, So next ID 83, Alexis
Alexis 83.
Danny is that they think Danny.
So we need to make this not all uppercase,
but we need to specify here, Alexis,
that you're logging in right here.
You're only specifying that you're,
that you're entering the credentials. Okay
So you need to
you need to change this so that it says,
you know, and clicks on login
by and or something like that. Okay
So. 83 and then you say you got to go,
oh, as you're not, okay.
Given
the users notices that
when the user enters valid credentials
same thing as your that she's just
you need to specify guys
you need to specify when they got it
so they're entering valid credentials.
Right.
But just by doing that they're not log
then they have to click
on a log of one right.
So you either create two steps for that
or you just say when the user logs in,
just fit it into one step, right?
So that's fine.
Let's See, Farhad says he was 17.
Okay,
we're 17
and 17.
Farhad says the linking is good.
Okay. Nope.
Same thing.
Four had the same feedback applies to you.
You're not clicking on that login button.
Okay,
Arwa,
so we're missing the step
to click on the login button.
Okay.
For I mean, of Arwa.
Sorry.
Okay.
Okay. In Malaysia.
I'll address that right now.
All right.
So let's let's not this out.
Who else is next?
Let's let's do Ladies first.
And you ladies, lovely
ladies, let's let's get there.
Probably let's let 11.
Ladies first.
64. Okay, let's do it.
Let's do 11.
First day
11 first
All children.
That's
of course, I'm going to say 11.
Where's your typical 11?
11, 11, 11, 11, 11. Ladies first.
Got to date. Ladies first.
All so that we can
just the last two.
I don't see 11.
Where's 11?
Where's 11, 11, 11, 11.
The love that
there is lot to. Okay,
the linking is good.
Yes, good. I'll take it.
That's fine.
But there was no point
of putting the court the colons, the
the colon here the
you didn't have to do that.
Okay.
After 11 was what after 11 was
Catalina 64.
Okay. 64.
Guilty.
64. Catalina.
Yes. No.
Wrong user story.
Catalina The scenario is good.
The scenario is good.
Catalina you linked the wrong story, okay?
You linked
or you linked the wrong user story.
Okay, I'll get there to me. No,
just give me a second. Okay.
So link the correct
the correct user story is this one.
Catalina one. Okay. Charm as we two.
Okay.
After Catalina,
it was a ladies, ladies. 23.
Right. Leonie 23
three.
Let's look it up. Okay.
23 That a Leonie given the admin,
when I log in with the admin,
then the admin will be logged in.
Okay, that's fine.
Melanie. Good job.
You link the log, you linked it.
Okay. Thanks.
Let any of the night or day
after Leonie was.
We're looking. Ladies first. First guys.
Any more ladies in line 45.
I've got to really look at 4545
given when the HMAS is on a login page.
So for Christine,
I really already get feedback on this.
Okay.
So you're saying given
the user has valid credentials, okay,
when the admin users on the login page,
so when they're there, then
the admin user should be able to log in.
I don't think that's how it works
when they're on the login page.
Then what did they have to do to log
in right?
It's not. It's not up there.
Let's see
all you want me to update it? Refresh it.
Okay. See
45. No, it's the same thing.
I still see the same thing.
So we have fixed that scenario.
Okay, Ladies, ladies,
Are we good with ladies?
Is there are there any other ladies
in the call waiting before I continue?
The gentleman.
We good?
Okay, So, Mina,
what is your question to me now?
What is the question to Mina?
I'm not seeing the batch 11 to link to it.
You haven't created a task yet.
I did.
So what is your ticket number?
Oh, well, cause I have you there.
I'm good, and I'll take care of the rest.
It's good seeing you again, right?
Being with us again.
So, Mina, words to Mina.
What is your ticket ID number 47.
Okay, so 47
minutes here.
Okay, So to Mina, giving a user
when the user logs
in, then the user should be logged in.
Okay, we can get rid of the period
so you need to link.
Okay, so it's right here.
This is your ticket. Okay. To me.
Not so.
In order to link it right,
you need to click more
and you need to click on link.
When you click on link,
just change this to tests, okay?
And then enter the ticket number
that you're testing.
Right. So this is a ticket for HMS.
What is, what is the idea for the ticket?
B2 Right.
I think HMS B on B 11 and I think it's two
and someone changed it again.
So hold on.
So one of the two done for some reason
and I can find one.
So I'll open this tab when it chooses to.
A story
Okay, do this
and then we're going to come here
and then that's how you link it.
Okay, To me now I just show
you I'm not going to do it for you.
I just show you how to do it.
Okay, so you do it.
So again, open your ticket.
Click on more, click on link.
Right.
Not tested by because this ticket
is going to test ticket.
So you say this ticket tests
and then you look up the other thing
it's must be 11 and two
and it's the first one.
So go ahead and link it.
Okay, You can do that.
And then you should be good to go.
Okay.
So next 15 Jimmi.
Gentlemen, gentlemen, gentlemen.
Let's go with the gentleman. 15.
I'm gonna start with
15. Right, I'll start with 15
and start with 15.
Okay.
The linking is there.
Yes, yes.
Yep. That's good. Gemma.
You're good to go.
Goodnight.
Well, let's see who else.
Lewis,
You were already good in the first place.
So why are you still asking for
what you already got?
What is the difference
between Somali images?
Says when the admin logs in
with proper credentials. Yes.
And this when the user logs in with proper
with the provider
username and password.
Emily. Emilia, what's your ticket again?
Was your ticket number so I can look at it
again.
19 is a good 19. Good.
Let's look at 19.
So it says given the users and the syntax
when the user logs in the provider.
Yeah, this is good.
This is good. Then
I say it was bad. No, this is good.
This is good.
Yeah.
When the user
I thought I read something else
when the user logs in with the provider
username, but that's good.
That that makes sense.
So you're good to go. Emilia.
Sorry if I said something else that.
But this is good. So.
No, no, it's fine.
I think I may have read someone else's
ticket by accident or something like that.
Okay, so let's see.
So Jimmy was good.
Okay, so
turn off that
the link is good.
Okay, So, Ahmed,
is there a reason why you have a period
at the end of the last statement?
Just delete that and you're good to go.
Okay, so that's so that said, 70.
Marzio has been saying 70.
Even when I said
ladies only so I can't find 70 here.
It's not here.
So the fact that I cannot find 70 in
the Sprint backlog
tells me that they are in the sprint
tells me that you didn't
link it to the sprint.
Okay.
The notes.
This is for 71, right?
Who said NASIR so?
I can't again find your ticket.
12. Okay, let's find 12
K 12.
No, the Y you don't attempt to log in
with all the credentials.
You just log in with your credentials.
This is a
this is more like a negative test, Z.
Everything else is correct.
We just got to fix this, right?
So when the admin you just
when the admin right.
I'll change here for you when the admin
right.
Does change the wording logs
in with the credentials.
There you go. Bam.
You're good to go.
So let's see who next.
85. 85.
I don't see 85 here.
It's not linked to the sprint board,
so if I can't find it, it's not that
easy to make this report.
Right.
I don't see 85.
Okay.
Don't see 85
then. Could see 88.
Is there a tendra.
So the link is there.
When the user logs in with algorithms,
then the user should be logging in.
Okay, that's good.
Good stuff.
But then do a good job.
Have a good night.
Let's see.
35. Anthony.
Anthony.
So here, Anthony, this is good.
Very good.
That's great. Yup.
I already told you what the car was going
to be posted in the course announcement.
78 for Amar.
I'm not Amar.
I don't see it on the springboard,
but we see it in Lincoln.
Well, 58 for Sebastian.
Let's see.
The link is good.
Given the admin has valid
credentials and clicks, log in.
So this is a weirdly written scenario,
Sebastian, because we want to say,
given
the users on this, when the user logs
in with valid credentials,
then the syntax home is displayed.
Okay, so we can reward this
cool 41
and 41 Sherif,
I'm going to refresh this again,
but you're asking me to check yours
and I believe I already told you
at the beginning of the class that
you needed to work on yours.
Look, you still didn't
change the naming convention.
You linked the properly,
you linked it incorrectly.
You didn't write the cucumber.
So what exactly do you want me to look at?
14. Okay.
I didn't know we had Lewis in class 14.
The link is good.
So, Lewis,
if you see this case right here,
the linking is good, right
But you're saying give given.
I mean, users on the HMS won't page
as good
when the user logs in with no credentials.
Okay. This is very good. Yep.
I was reading something else
so that's good.
Okay.
That's very very good.
13 that I would check. 13
the mirror.
13 The link is good
giving users on this one.
User logs with this and this.
Okay. Nice.
Very good. 13 is good.
The mirrors good was
a you
click hold and drag it to the sprint 14.
Someone said 40.
Okay, so we're set.
We have the link
given user has valid credentials
and is on URL and types of username
and password click so again.
Okay, this is fine. It makes sense.
So you've got to go.
40 is good.
81 Is there anyone else guys? 81
The link is good.
You don't need to have the acceptance
criteria here
when the user never gives sufficient.
When the user logs,
when the user logs into log in section.
Remember this is the displaced look,
this is okay.
You don't need to accept this criteria.
Okay.
Well, it checked the backlog.
We didn't link it. Well,
yeah.
So who's not?
Who's next?
Yours is displayed, but it's not good.
Look, Hanoch.
Oh, you created another one.
Well, you linked it.
Well now, but you didn't write
the cucumber scenario.
That's the whole point.
You need to read the scenario.
Okay, so who else is.
Who else do I need to review?