All right, guys,
let's get started.
What's going on, guys?
How's it going?
How's everybody doing?
Good.
Everyone is doing good.
Nice.
Okay.
I'm doing good.
Thank you, guys.
Hopefully you guys completed the homework
and created some functions.
Right with to open and close the browsers.
The common methods that we talked about
last class.
Okay, good.
How is everyone feeling, guys?
Is everyone tired?
What's going on, guys?
Everyone is good.
Ready to learn? Okay, that's good.
Okay, so we're almost there, right, guys?
So there are probably three or four,
four classes left for us in selenium.
Little bit overwhelmed. Okay, that's fine.
So that's.
That's what happens, right?
Yeah, we have
we have probably four more classes.
Okay.
I mean, three, three selenium classes
and one more.
I'm going to go over the page
object model design.
And that's how you guys are going to start
with your framework.
Okay.
And then you're going
to start with this and G
and then you will start with Cucumber.
Okay, So three more classes to go.
Okay, Couple more topics to cover.
So hopefully you guys in a good mood.
It happens that
you guys are going to get overwhelmed.
Okay. It's okay.
Just a little more push, right?
And we're going to be finished
by the end of the year.
Okay.
Any questions before we get started, guys?
Not really, no.
I mean, in testing
G testing G is a different tool, right?
So test and G, what you're going to do
is you're going to integrate it with Java.
And so so you're still going to be using
Java and Selenium at the same time.
And you will add test and G on top.
Okay.
So Test G has its own features
that you're going to be using
along with Selenium and Java.
Okay.
So remember guys, when you started,
you started with one tool, which is Java,
and then you added selenium,
you're adding test and G now
and then you're going to be adding
cucumber, you're going to be adding Maven,
and then you will
be learning sequel
API testing and everything.
Okay.
So it's basically
a lot of different combinations of tools.
Okay.
This, Angie is a framework, right?
It's a library as well. Okay.
So it's a library like, like selenium.
It has its own, not the methods
because testing G
is consisted of annotations.
Okay,
I won't probably teach any other subject.
Okay. So selenium.
I used to teach cucumber as well,
but not this time.
It's going to be different,
different combinations. Okay.
So that's how you, you, you form
your your framework.
Okay.
It's not just Java and Selenium
and you go test everything.
You're going to be having different
different tools, integrate them between
between each other,
and then you're going to form
a complete framework.
All right.
Any other questions
before we get started, guys?
Face some technical questions. Right.
Okay.
So let's go over our sets
and compare it to selenium.
It's a completely different tool.
Okay? It's a completely different tool.
It's based on annotations.
So in testing G, you're not going to have
main methods, guys.
Okay.
It has a different execution point,
but that's going to be
the major difference
between selenium and test engineer.
Okay.
So right
now, in order for us to run anything
in any classes, what we have is
we have our main method, right?
So which is our execution point.
So in testing, you won't have it.
It has a different execution point.
Okay.
All right.
So let's start. Right.
Okay.
So let's do a quick recap what we've done
last class, guys, and what we covered.
Last class.
What did we cover?
Last class, guys.
Let's see.
Okay. Weights and web tables, Right.
Okay, So what did we
what do we know about weights, guys?
Weights in selenium?
What kind of weights do we have?
Okay, three types of weights,
implicit, explicit and alone weight.
Right.
All right.
So what do we know about explicit?
What is an explicit weight, guys?
Waiting for a condition.
Okay.
Or condition to be true.
So explicit weight is
used to tell a web driver to wait
for a certain amount of time
and for a certain amount of condition.
Right.
So what is the class that we use
our explicit
weight with
expected conditions.
Class. Right. Okay.
So you set a separate
and independent condition
for some elements
that you want to be visible.
You want to be clickable
or you want to be enabled.
So you are just waiting
for a certain condition.
Right. What about fluid weights, guys?
What do we know about fluent weight?
Fluid weight is a global weight.
Okay, good.
What else?
Time frequency.
Okay, so it's used to tell the web driver
for a certain condition
as well as the frequency
of the ongoing execution. Right.
So it's not used so often. Yes.
Yes, it is not used so often.
That is correct.
Okay. So what
what kind of methods does it have, guys?
What is it that we can use
or what is it that we can
implement when we are trying to use
fluent way?
What it did last class.
Right, guys?
Okay. Polling.
That's very good.
So you can you can set
polling duration, Right.
How many seconds you want each iteration
of following to be okay.
What else?
Okay.
So you can ignore some exceptions.
Right.
And you can also set some timeout time.
For you
can see before throwing an exception.
Exactly.
So basically,
you're trying to manage some of the
implementation in the execution.
Right. Okay.
All right.
So now let's talk about
let's talk about the Web table.
Okay.
So what did we say about the web tables,
guys?
How many types of web tables do we have?
What is a web table on the Web page?
There are elements, right?
And we got two types. Okay.
So it's a static and dynamic.
Okay.
So what's the difference between
static and dynamic web
tables, guys?
It consists of rows and columns.
That's very good.
Okay.
Static is fixed. Okay.
So nothing is changing in the static web
table, right?
What about dynamic?
Dynamic.
We have the data changing, right?
So, like,
we've done an example last class, guys,
that that
show that you can click on something,
you can delete some rolls
or you can add more rows, right?
So those web tables,
they are considered as dynamic web tables.
Right?
Okay, good.
So let's see.
Okay.
Here. Let's see what we have.
All right.
Okay, guys.
So today we are going to do we're going
to be covering a different
a different table,
a different approach to the table.
Okay.
And and we will be covering
calendars at the second half of the class.
Okay.
So if you look at this table,
guys in here,
what do we see?
So we got what?
Let's go back in here.
So we got five in here, five rows in here.
And then if I click next,
there is another five rows.
If I click next, there is another three.
Anyone knows what this is.
Call one, two, three.
Anyone knows what this is called in ten
pages.
It's not as almost.
Yes sheets.
Not really
X elements.
Okay.
So Pages is really close
to what it's called.
Okay.
So what does this navigation
bar code, guys?
Anyone knows
Oksana?
Absolutely right.
It is called pagination. Okay.
So in tech, guys,
whenever you hear something
about pagination
that is either called inside the tables
or some of the
some of the pictures are changing greatly.
So if you click next, it
you stay on the same page, guys.
But you are trying to move
to a different different data
or to a different element.
Okay. So this is called pagination.
Okay.
So you were staying on the same page.
We have a table
that only thing that is changing
in here is our table data.
Okay.
Sounds like a bad word.
Okay. Yeah, well,
that's actually if it is
if it sounds like a bad word,
it's easier to remember, guys.
Okay, so don't forget this.
Okay.
All right, so this is called pagination.
So today
we will be working with the tables
which have pagina
and we will be having in a dynamic
script in order to go back and forth
until we have our conditions
or we have the data that we need to find.
Okay.
Is that clear?
Guys, any questions?
Okay.
Expected to call them pagination. Yes.
So basically, pagination
is more professional way to call it.
Let's put it this way.
Okay.
So if you say pagination at work
now, they'll all know.
If you say a page, they'll they'll think
it's a complete web page.
Okay.
So pagination
would be a professional approach
to this.
All right, so let's do this.
Right?
So let's go back
to our intelligence.
Let me put it here.
Tables
divided
into several
pages.
Then navigation, bar
is called
pagination.
Okay. All right.
So what I'm going to do,
I'm going to create a new package
in here,
and I will be creating a new class.
Okay.
So what I will say with tables, with
pagina is
this.
All right, so let me go back
here and copy this
pasted in here.
And what I will do,
I'm going to change the U around here,
and I'll send the URL to
you guys in a second.
There you go.
All right.
So now let's get started. Okay.
So what I want to do in here,
so when I navigate to this page, right,
I land in here.
So what I want to do, guys,
I want to go to this second page.
Okay.
I want to go to the second page
and get this row
and print this out inside my console.
Okay. Is that clear, guys?
Any questions?
Okay, good.
All right.
Okay.
So once I navigate to this page,
what is my next step?
And here goes
with finding the elements.
Right. Okay, so let's locate the element.
Let me go ahead and inspect this.
So let's go back in here
and let's expand this a little bit.
And so I have a table, right?
So let's identify this by the class
name in here.
All right.
So copy this
in this up.
We'll see.
What is the shortcut?
I'm not sure.
I think it's f 12 guys,
if I'm not mistaken, to click on F12,
it should bring up the down.
Okay.
If the page is too slow, that's
because we are all using the same page.
And this is for
and the server is not that powerful.
Okay.
So we're
all using the same server right now.
So that's why it may get a little delayed.
Okay.
So that's why
if it's if it's delayed for you guys
so that it doesn't
get delayed on my side just
just follow me right now
how I'm going to implement everything
and then you can type.
Okay.
All right.
So what I'm going to do,
I'm going to create a next path for this.
Okay?
So double slash, right?
We have a table in here,
and then we're trying to identify this
by class, right?
So I paste the class in here.
So it's one of one.
Everything is good.
So our table is unique, right?
So what?
What I need to do next, guys, in here,
let's take a look
at the structure of the table in here.
So where do I have to go
next, guys, in order
for me to capture the rows?
T hat
do I have to go to the T hard right guys?
Because
I have t hat antibody,
but the thing that I need
is only the rows, right?
Is it t body or t hat guys?
Okay, so let's navigate to the t body.
Right.
So if we go to the t body and expand
this, we're going to see
all the rows in here, right?
So what I will do slash t body in here
and slash t r right.
How many, how many roles did
I just find guys.
13. Right.
How many are displayed
for me right now, Guys?
Five.
Right.
So if you look at the structure
of the table in here, guys.
So if you look at the style,
it says display the table row.
Right.
And if you look after the fifth row
display is none.
Okay.
So if I move to the next page in here
and go to the second page of the table
and here
you can see that 1 to 5 is getting
this is getting displayed none.
And here it is displaying the table row.
Okay.
I hope you guys see this changes in here.
So if I go back, we're getting displayed
in a different set of rows.
And if I if
I change the pagination in here,
you can see that
the display of the rows is changing.
Okay, so let's go ahead and get this.
Okay, So get back in here
and try to try to find these elements.
We're going to have to
store these elements.
Guys, inside the array list.
Right.
So list of what guys,
what am I going to have
a container of
list of web elements.
Right. Okay.
So let's create
a list of web elements in here.
So lists of web elements.
So we say table rows, right.
Is equal to let's import this guy
here and let's see for the list
as well from Java utility class.
Right.
And now what we can do driver dot
find elements right
by X path and let's paste this path into
okay.
So line 18, what it does, it gives us 13
rows of that table, right. So
how do I have to
print all of them out? Guys
I to right through them.
Right. Okay.
Or we can simply,
instead of using the iterator,
what we could do,
we can simply use the for the right.
Okay, so how do I,
how do I go ahead and start iterating
and printing everything?
Guys?
So let's print out everything first.
How do I do this?
So if I want to print all the rows
right now, what am I going to do?
What is my next step in here
without the iterator?
Or so that's
that's the regular loop that works.
Okay,
so we have the advanced loop as well.
Okay. So for
so we're iterating through each
and every element, right?
Table row and then we're iterating
through the table rows.
Right. Okay, so what do I do next?
So I have my loop.
I start going through the arrows in here.
So what I do next?
Okay, so we
need to get the text
and then simply print out.
Right?
So let's have a
let's say so text is equal to
table row,
get text.
Right.
And what I want to do, I want to print
the row text.
Right. Okay.
So now let's go ahead and run this
and see what we're going to have.
Okay.
So we're running in here.
Okay, guys, what happened?
Only five was were printed, right?
Only five rows were printed.
Why? Guys?
Because they are visible, right?
Because we then go to the second
and third pages inside the table.
Right.
So they only display in rows.
We have our from 1 to 5
and then you can see
there is this much break in here.
So that means they are empty, Right?
So as you can see in here,
there's no display whatsoever.
So our selenium is not going to see that
until we go to that specific page.
Okay, guys, is that clear?
Okay, good.
So now what I want to do, guys,
I want to click on the next
and get this row eight
and only print this one.
Okay.
But the thing is,
I don't want to have like
we know we're printing row eight,
but what if this guy is moving to row ten?
Okay, so I want to keep our code
as dynamic as possible.
Okay.
So that we can print every time this guy,
no matter
what page this guy is.
Okay,
Is that clear?
Guys, any questions on this?
Okay, good.
All right, so let's go ahead
and start doing this.
So the first thing that I want to do
is what goes in here.
So we know
there's one row we want to print, right?
So but how do we get to the other pages,
guys?
How do we keep everything dynamic in here?
Find the elements.
Okay, So what element do
we need to find in here?
Pagination.
Okay,
so we need to find which one, one, two
or three guys. Two.
What if tomorrow is on the third page?
If needed element is not present,
move to the next page.
That's a very good
that's a very good idea.
We need them all. Okay, guys.
So how do we how do we go through
one page
to a to another page without going
without going through 1 to 3?
What if tomorrow we have five pages?
So right now,
if I store one, two, three, tomorrow
I will need to store four or five.
Right. So I am changing my script, right.
So right now,
what is not going to be changing
in this pagination guys
next button and the previous button.
Right.
So the navigation arrows.
Absolutely right.
Okay.
So we don't care
how many pages we have in here.
We know that we can navigate through them
one by one.
Right.
So what I'm going to do in here,
I am going to locate this next button.
Okay?
And I think we can we can find this
by by the class name in here.
So let's create an X path for this.
Okay? So let's do
a tag.
We have them here at class
is equal to this guy.
Okay?
One of one.
And we can use this X path, right?
Is everyone clear
what I'm doing in here, guys?
Am I going too fast?
Okay, cool.
So what I'm going to do,
I'm going to copy this X path.
I'm going to go back to our script.
So now what I will do, I will create a web
element purple in here.
Okay?
And I'll say next button, right
is equal to driver
signed element
by X pass
and I will paste that x.
Thank you.
Okay, so now guys,
when do I need to click on the next button
in here
inside the loop?
Okay, so I'm trying when the row is empty.
Okay, So I'm trying to find this guy.
So if we don't keep clicking until sound.
Right? So that's a very good
idea.
Okay, so we need to keep clicking
until we find this
specific element, Right?
So how are we going to do this?
Okay, so
it is a little bit of a tricky logic
in here.
Okay, guys, So we know that here, guys,
we have we're getting the text
with printing out the text, right?
What if I want to print only that row?
Guys, how am I going to do this?
Okay, so we need an F condition, right?
So, okay,
so if right, we have a row text in here,
we're we need contains.
And then what was the guy's name?
Okay, whatever it is. Right.
So our key J only then what
I am going to do, I am going to go ahead
and print this value right.
Okay, so I'm looping. Looping.
If I see this, I'm going
to print this guy. Okay,
So now, guys,
what I will do, I need to know
when to click on the next button.
Okay?
So in order to do that, I'm
going to implement
a little bit of a different logic.
Okay.
So what
I am going to do in here before my fault,
I will create a boolean value of a flag.
Okay, so I'll say Boolean flag
is equal to true.
Okay,
so now what I will do before my for loop,
I'm going to I'm going to create
a wire loop in here.
Okay.
So I'll say why loop?
While we have a flag in here.
Okay.
What I'm going to do, I'm going to start
moving.
Okay, Bear with me, guys.
I'll explain the logic one by one.
Okay, so now what I did and here
I created a bull, a Boolean flag,
which is true, right?
And when my flag is true,
I am going to start my iteration.
Okay.
Okay. I'll.
I'll come to your question. Why?
Why not just while true. Okay.
So you will see the difference yourself.
Okay.
Let me finish this and I'll explain it.
While the flag is true, okay,
what I'm going to do, I'm going to start
going through each
and every row inside the table, okay?
But then if I go inside the fourth.
Okay, and I don't find anything,
what do I need to do?
Guys, if I don't find this guy,
Guys, click on the next button.
Right?
So what I will do after the
four, look what I will do.
I will click
on the next button.
But guys,
when I find this guy,
what do I need to do?
Guys, we need to break it.
Very good. Right.
So break in here.
Right. So what did we do right now?
What did I break right now?
In here, guys, we broke the fourth loop.
Now what I need to do,
I need to break my wire loop.
How do I break my wild loop?
Guys,
my flag needs to be false, right?
Right After I find that row that I need.
What I need to do,
I need to set this flag as false.
Right.
And I think this answers to your question,
Jamal, then, that we cannot
just go ahead and put true in here
because we won't be able to set this
as false.
Okay.
So that's why I need here
as separate variables
so that I can manipulate the
values inside that wildly.
Is that
clear, guys?
Okay, so now, guys, I'm
going through the logic again.
Okay?
So I have a wild loop.
If the flag is true, right?
I'm going inside the table rows.
So I'm.
I'm looping.
If I don't find it what I do,
I click next.
My flag is still true, guys, right?
So if flag is still true,
I am going to the wild loop again.
Okay,
so now that I clicked on the next button,
on what page am I
to write?
So on the second page
I am iterating through the
through the rows again, right?
I get the text
and if I see that this guy is available,
I immediately set my flag as false.
I print out that row text and I break
my for loop.
Is that clear? Guys?
Any questions on this?
Yes, we click next.
I'm coming to that point a little later.
Okay. Why does flag
and course
in here
I'm not really sure
why it has the what's called
it has the underscore, but it's fine.
Guess it's not a big deal
where I got the name.
It's right here, right on the eighth,
eighth row.
Okay. So what I'm going to do,
let me run this.
Okay, guys, if I run this right now, on
what page On the table pagination,
are we going to end up
the flag is going to be
your your kind of condition.
Okay.
So most of the time, whenever
you need to set some kind of condition
as a Boolean value
like we've done in here,
you want to name it as flag.
Okay.
Because usually flag means red flag
or white flag.
So that's how
it's used in tech as well.
Okay.
So if you have some Boolean values
that you want to set it to, true or false,
okay.
Usually with these Boolean values
are going to be
named as slot.
Okay. All right.
So let me run this.
There we go.
So we end up
we end up on third page, right?
But if we look in the console guys,
we got what we want it,
right? Why?
Why did we end up on the last page
and not the second?
Because the loop is going to end
after we click this, right?
So When I'm here, when
my condition is met, the flag is false.
We print the value, we break the loop,
but we still inside the Y loop, right?
So we need to click on this.
So how do I avoid to click this
and stay on the second page? Guys
in for loop?
So if I put it in for loop guys,
what's going to happen?
If I put it inside the for loop?
What's going to happen in here guys?
It's not going to work, right?
Because it's going to click
on the next button after each row.
Okay?
So after each iteration,
it will need to click
the next button
so that if condition
is really good guys, but
we don't have to break in there, right?
So in what condition am I clicking on
the next button? Does
when out of for loop?
Okay.
But sometimes when I'm out of for loop,
I don't want to click
right
like we have at the last iteration.
So I'm out of for loop,
but I don't want to click on next button.
So how do I avoid this?
Any suggestions guys?
Any thoughts?
Okay. Seems like not.
That's fine. So
the only
time that I want to click on
the next button
is the same time
when I get inside the y loop.
Guys, right?
Whenever my while,
whenever my flag is true.
Only then what I'm going to do,
I'm going to click on next button.
Okay?
So what I will do, I will
simply do is flag in here.
Go ahead
and click on this.
Right.
Because on my second iteration,
when I find this,
my flag is already what guys,
my flag is already false.
So if I go out of the loop,
what is my flag right now?
My flag is false
and this guy is stating that it is true.
Okay.
So that's why
what we want to do, we want to go ahead
and well, in order
for you to break the while, the right
you need to set the condition as false.
Okay.
So in y loop,
you can't use the word right.
Okay.
So y loop is based on the conditions.
Okay, guys.
So that's why inside the Y loop in here,
what we have
in here is the
we have a condition, right?
And inside the iterator guys, remember,
each dot has next.
What is it?
It's a it's a boolean value, right?
If if, if that has next is true,
only then you're stepping inside that one.
Okay, So if I run this right now,
what's going to happen, guys in here?
Am I going to still
end up on the
on the third page
or the second one?
Okay.
So it seems like everybody
ran already, right?
So let's run this
and see what's
going to happen.
There you go.
We stopped in here and we're printed out
the row that we need it
right?
You can break
y loop with the break.
Okay, Try it. Try it.
But I've never seen anyone
break into y loop with break.
Okay.
You can probably do it,
but I don't think so.
Guys.
Oh, you guys did it.
Okay, good.
Okay, If it works.
Nice.
Good.
All right, guys, any questions on this?
Our questions.
Is everything clear, guys?
Okay. Nice.
All right, so let's go ahead
and do another exam sample in here,
okay?
Okay.
All right, So
let's take this here.
All right?
So what I'm going to do is create
a new class.
This.
Okay, guys. So the next example.
Okay, so what we're going
to do, we will be having
an example on this application.
Okay, So let's see.
Right.
So, man, what was the password?
Okay, I hope you guys all know the
this application right
already.
Okay, So
this thing, when we log
in, I think we're going to be landing
here.
Okay, so what?
We just log in, guys,
we will be logging in
to this specific
of what's called to this specific page.
Right.
So what we need to do
I'm going to go to the PIM.
Okay.
I'm going to go to Pim.
I'll go to
let me see to add employee.
Okay, So what
I'm going to do,
I'm going to add some employee in here
and when I say it's going to navigate me
to the employee list in here.
So you see here we have a huge table.
Okay, So
it's a alphabetic.
It's going to say it's going to get saved
in alphabetical order.
Okay.
So what I want to do when I save that
employee, after I save it,
what I want to do, I want to find this
employee inside this table.
Okay, click
on the checkbox and delete that employee.
Okay?
Is that clear, guys?
Any questions?
Okay, so whenever we add
an employee, whenever we add an employee,
you can see that
it might be in a different page as well.
Okay.
So you click on this, it's
going to be the second page and we have
72 pages.
Okay?
So all we need to do, we need to find that
employee through the seven from 72 pages
and then start
and then delete that employee.
Okay.
So what I would suggest for this example,
just follow me, okay?
Because when I start adding
an employee, guys,
it will add an employee for you as well.
Okay?
If you run it at the same time
as I am doing it.
So this website is going
to get really slow.
Okay. So
if it gets really slow, our
test is going to fail, so you won't see
what is actually going on.
And there might be a lot of different
duplicates as well.
Exactly.
So for right now, just follow me
how I'm going to implement everything
and then you can do it yourself.
Okay? All right.
So let's get back in here.
Copy this.
Let's change the URL
incident here.
So now what I need to do is
let's look out.
So what I need to do is
I need to go ahead and start
locating these elements right.
So I'm going to inspect this
in here.
Go ahead.
My username right here.
I have the ID for the text username.
So what I'm going to do then copy this ID
and go ahead and start my script.
Right. So element
username is equal to driver
find element
by ID.
This is my ID value and what I need to do
I need to click
right.
So before
before I go to the password
guys, what I want to do,
I want to during my execution, I want to
I don't want to use any threat
that sleeps or anything.
Right.
Oh. Username seventies.
Sorry. Yes.
Two keys and it's going to be my right.
Okay.
So what I want to do,
I don't want to use any threat
but sleep if there are any interactions.
Right.
What do I have to use in here
in order to wait for some elements?
What Kind of wait.
Implicit. Right.
So let's set that implicit rate once.
Right.
And hopefully that's going to run.
That's
going to run throughout our execution.
Right.
Okay.
So how do we where do I need to set that?
Guys, after after
navigating?
Right.
So driver
that manage for managing timeouts in here.
Right
implicitly wait
so what do we need to specify in here guys
inside the parentheses
guys the duration right.
So we want to wait for 20 seconds in here
and then
we actually need to say
that we want to wait 4 seconds, right?
So we don't want to wait for days
or hours.
20 seconds should be fine for us. Right?
Okay.
So now let's continue
let's go back to our page and let's
locate our password in here.
So it has an I.D. as well.
Let's go back
Web elements.
Password is equal to five four.
Second element by the
basis in here,
and then password
sent keys
in. I think it was
this was the password.
My mistake. Yep.
There you go.
All right.
And then I entered the username
and password.
So now what I need to do,
I just need to click on the log in button.
Right.
So this button has an idea as well.
So that's very good. So copy this
here and other web elements
equal to driver, but
find the elements
again by D
and paste this here
and what we need to deal with.
Log in button is just simply click
right.
So is everybody clear guys
what I'm doing until line 25.
Any questions in there?
Okay, cool.
So let's log in again
and there go.
So we're logged in and here.
So what I need to do,
I need to click on this Pim first
and then click on there and improve.
Right.
So what I'm to do the locate
this in here,
How can we identify this element?
Guys?
What is it that we can use in here?
Okay, what else?
Instead of link text,
there is an idea, right?
So it is the most safe one.
So what we can do, we can use an ID here.
So let's get back
web element.
I think
I am button
for my element by ID
and would paste that I.D.
And what we do is
we're simply going to click
right. Okay.
So after we click this, after we click,
what we're going to have is
we will have this
ADD employee button in here, right?
So I am going to locate this.
This one has an ID as well.
So what I'm going to do is copy
this idea in here.
Okay? And
I will create another web element in here.
Okay.
So add employee button
driver side element,
I.D., though, and
an employee that clicked.
Okay, so let's go to add employee in here.
So now what we need to do,
we need to actually
create or ADD and new employee, right.
So in order to do this,
I need to locate a couple
of different elements in here,
which are the first name.
Last name. Right.
And then what I need to do,
I need to save this employee.
Okay, so first name in here.
What do we have?
Okay, so we have an idea. Cool.
So let's
go back.
Where Element
first name
Driver.
Got my element
by I.D.
again.
Then first name
send keys.
So let's see.
We need to come up
with the name guys in here.
So I'm just going to put anything in here
and let's see
how that's going to work out.
Okay, so first name.
So let's identify the last name here.
And we have an idea of last name.
The first element.
Last name is if this is driver,
find element by E,
Right.
I'm good. Okay.
That's a good one.
Last name the keys,
whatever the last name is.
Right.
Okay.
All right.
So once I enter
past them and last name.
Right, what I need to do is
I need to click on Save.
Let's see what we got for saving here.
We've got an idea as well.
So let's copy this
and implement it here.
Save button driver
to find element like this ID
and then save
click.
Okay.
So let's say in here
we are entering something
and clicking on Save.
So what happens is it gets in here.
Okay, the next thing I want to do,
I want to see the whole table, right?
In order for me to see the whole table,
I need to click on employee list in here.
Okay,
So let's go ahead and inspect this.
Okay. So
it has this idea as well.
So let's use this idea as well.
Okay.
Now let's get back
where elements
in most button equal to
driver dot find elements by idea.
And this is our idea,
right?
Okay.
And then what we want to do, we want to
simply click okay.
Is this clear, guys?
Any questions on
what I am doing right now?
So let's click on employee list in here
and we're going to see
the whole table, right?
Okay.
So what do I need to do right now, guys?
So before moving forward,
before doing anything, guys,
So what I need to do,
my job is to find that employee, right?
So this employee is right here.
So what we want to do,
we want to store this
whatever we going to be entering
is going to be stored on max pages.
We'll try to store it on the next pages
so that we can go to the next page.
Okay.
So right now, what is my next step, guys?
What do I need to do in here?
Locate the table.
Right.
Okay, so let's do this.
So we have this table, right?
It has the ID.
So what I need to do,
I need to go through the rows.
Right. So let's find this table.
And here, table.
Right. I.D.
equal to
resolve.
Table.
Right.
So where do I need to go, guys?
So I located the table.
This is my table. One of one.
And what I need to do in here.
Let's collapse this.
So I need to go to the body
right? So
slash
the body and then the rows.
Right.
Okay, So I identified the rows in here.
So now what
I need to do to copy this x path,
go back in here
and store it inside the list
Web elements. It's
all right.
And I'll say table was equal to
five elements
of X plus.
This is my x five and what I'm going to do
for this class.
Okay,
So now, guys, I have a question for you.
So once I am here, we added the employee,
Everything is good, right?
So I'm on this page.
I located the
all of the all the rows of this table
and I start iterating to my rows.
Right.
What is the criteria that
I am going to
delete That employee that I just added?
What am I looking for in here?
How do I differentiate my employee
that I just added
by ID?
Okay, good.
So not name
because names can be duplicated.
Right?
Job can be duplicated.
Last names can be duplicated.
But IDs are always unique.
Right? Very good.
But where am I getting this idea?
So I save this and the ID is generated
automatically.
Guys, where am I going to get this?
I don't know.
The IDs that
for the employee that I just created,
where am I going
to get it?
Any thoughts
for employee list?
Okay, let's see.
I think okay.
Are you talking about this?
Okay, that's a good point.
We can get it from here. Okay.
Is there any other place that we can get
this ID from?
That's a very good observation,
actually. Yes.
We have an employee ID in here.
The last employee in the list.
Not really.
Right, guys,
The employees are sorted by first.
A last name.
Okay.
It's given to us. Where?
Yeah, we can get it from the row, guys,
but we don't know it yet.
Now we don't need a scanner in here right.
Okay,
so one thing that we can get it from here.
That's a good point.
Is there any other way that we need?
We can get it.
Okay, guys, I need to get the ID,
but I need to get the ID,
but not from here.
There's no creation log.
Most recent person added, Not the headache
guys, pay attention, guys.
It's a small detail.
It's a small detail that you can find it.
Guys, let's
see. So
from an employee.
Where?
From an employee, it had an I.D., right?
So if I go on an employee
when I'm adding that employee,
there we go.
It's already given to us, right?
So you don't have to go to the next
and perform some actions.
You can perform the same action
right on the same page.
Now, you said you can get it
from the employee list, right?
Not not employee list,
but from last year you create it. Right.
And you said you can get it from here.
Yeah.
When you added it
right after you added you,
you come to this page.
But then he agreed.
You agreed when I said this point.
Okay, that's fine.
Okay.
We could get it from here, guys.
All right, good.
All right.
So we can get it from here
when we are entering the first name.
And lastly. Okay, but here, guys,
I go here.
What am I getting in here, guys?
Am I getting the text from this?
From this text box?
What am I getting?
I need to get the value.
How am I going to get the value in here?
Guys?
Is there a method
that gets the value in here?
Let's go to the to our script.
Do we have to get attribute value
method ghosts?
What is the actual method
that we use to get
to get the values
from the HTML to get that attribute right?
So when I
when I just enter the first name
and last name in here,
what I need to do,
I need to get that attribute.
But before we do this,
I need to locate this.
Right?
So let's see.
It has the idea.
Okay, so
where element
the employee I the
do field is equal to driver
find element
by the
so now what we can do
so actual employee ID is equal to a driver
not drive driver.
The employee ID field that that attribute
which is the value
attribute was okay right.
Okay is that clear guys.
So we trying to add an employee in here
we passed the first time a last name
and what we do we getting the value
that is already given to us in here.
Is that clear, Guys, Any questions?
Okay.
All good.
Okay, so it's 820.
Guys,
Let's have a break, a 15 minute break,
and then we'll come back and continue
with this example.
Okay?
All right.
I'll see you guys.
That 835.
All right, guys, let's get back. Yeah.
And with this, tell us.
All right, All right.
Let's see how many people have backed us
so that we can
continue.
Okay, cool. So we stopped
where we got
the value for the employee ID, right?
And what we did was we located
the table rows from the web page.
Right. So let's go back
to the employee list.
Okay?
All right. Yes.
So what we want to do in here
is, again, to
to go through each and every row.
And what we need to do, we need to find
our employee first, check it.
Right. And delete that employee.
Okay. All right.
So what is my next step in here?
So let's go in here
and see what's going to happen.
So what is my next step, guys?
What am I doing next?
So I identify the all the rows.
What am I doing now?
Set the flag.
Okay, so before we set the flag,
let's loop through the rows.
Okay, so what I will do in here,
I have a for loop.
Right.
Let's use the regular loop this time.
So integer is equal to zero
and I is less than
table rows that size.
Right.
And we're incrementing one by one.
Okay, so we have this.
So now what I need to do in here goes.
So we start iterating through the rows.
What is next?
Store each element to the to the variable.
Okay. And then do what?
And then get the text right.
Okay.
So let's just do string
row texts, right?
Is equal to
table rows that
get text.
Seems like get
text is not available for us.
What's going on in here guys?
We need to get each element first right?
So that I
and only then get that to the text.
Okay.
So I got the text now
what do I need to do next?
Guys?
What am I looking for right now?
Okay.
If condition so inside my if condition,
what am I looking
what kind of condition am I having in here
if our row text right
contains what
contains the employee
ID that we stored on line 38.
Right.
So copy this case this in here.
And then if, if our condition is mapped.
What are we doing, guys,
before we remove anything.
Right. What do we need to do?
We need to find that checkbox.
Right.
Okay, so we have this x pass, right?
So we have this x path.
So how we find that checkbox in here
guys?
So I have all the rows, right?
What do I need to do
in order to find my checkbox in here
by index?
Okay,
so but first of all,
where do I need to go from here?
Okay, I have all the rows guys.
Where is my checkbox in here?
Where is
this located?
Inside the column.
Okay, which column are we talking about?
The very first column.
Right. So
in order for me to get the columns,
what I need to do,
I need to go ahead
and get one
right.
Okay, So here.
So if I go down, you can see that
we're going
through each and every
checkbox in here okay here.
But now, guys, so
here before guys, we used to have
before in the previous examples
that we've done,
we used to have a advanced for them.
Okay, so in advance for loop,
we're moving through the rows
automatically right in here.
Since we have a regular for loop,
how am I supposed to move
through the rows in here?
Guys?
Any guesses in here?
So let's open up the previous example
in here.
Okay.
How do I need to move
through my rows in here?
Guys,
let's get back in here.
Okay, so here.
Okay, so we use the regular loop,
but we started inside the lease, right?
So can I do this?
Can I click on the checkbox
without creating a list of web elements?
Guys, can I just create one web element
and handle this.
Any thoughts on this?
Guys, let's go back in here.
So we we
found all the checkboxes in here, right?
How do I find only one checkbox?
How do I find on the first checkbox
in here?
Any thoughts?
No. Okay.
How do I move through the rows?
Guys in here.
Can someone help me do that?
No, no, no. Just.
Just here, guys.
How do I locate just one checkbox?
I just want to know.
I just want to
locate one checkbox
that's in here in my express.
What do I need to change
in order to locate only one checkbox?
Right now I have 50.
Okay.
Index of what?
I already have an index of one in here.
I have an index of one in here,
but seems like
I still get 50
value.
Anything else in this x path guys?
Right on this x path.
What do I need to change
to get only one checkbox
nested in index?
Not really.
Okay guys, that's fine.
Okay.
So here
I have an index of the column right.
So I have an index of the column which
navigates from the top to the bottom.
Right.
So what if I identify
one of the checkboxes
on my first row guys,
This is what's going to identify
my one checkbox.
Okay, so this is one element in here
so we don't have to get
a lot of different elements and store them
in the list of what element.
Okay, so I'm going to copy this
when I copied this and what I am going
to do, I'm going to create
another web element and say,
driver, find element
by express and paste it in here.
Okay?
But this is going to locate
only first rows checkbox,
right?
So if that's
the case, how do I keep this dynamic
so that I can keep locating different rows
checkbox guys,
What do I need to change in here?
Guys, if I want to.
If I want to locate the second rows
checkbox,
what do I need to change in this X path
index?
Of what index of t or T.
R does
t r right.
So because we need to change the row
in here if I do this
so you can see that that our rows
are being dynamic, right?
So if I go back to my script in here.
So we need to keep this dynamic, right?
So what we can do is
we are iterating through the rows, right?
So we're starting from zero.
And my iteration variable
is that I in here, right?
So this eye keeps changing
every time, right?
So what we can do in here
is we can simply use concatenation,
right.
And put it in here.
Okay.
So every time
we change our
our row,
this I in our X path will as well.
Right.
I'm coming to that point. Okay.
So let's start from here.
If we have any errors
and then we'll move on.
Okay.
So now we identified our checkbox
in here, right?
So what I need to do if my condition is
is met, everything is good.
What I need to do,
I need to simply click on that.
Right.
So I click on that.
What do I need to do next?
So I chose this, right?
I chose this.
What is my next step, guys? Delete. Right?
This is the delete button
we need to work with.
So here we have an ID
right?
Let's go back in here.
What I need to do is let's create
this web element.
Delete button is equal to driver
find element by ID.
This is my and what I am going to do,
I will simply click okay.
All right.
So I chose the employee in here.
Let's click on this.
All right.
So when I click on Delete,
we have something like this.
How do I handle this situation now?
First of all, what is this?
It's an alert. Okay.
What kind of alert?
Guys, it's a pop up. Okay.
What kind of pop up is this?
Confirmation. Okay.
Is it a JavaScript alert?
Is it a Windows based alert
or is it a Web based alert?
Which one?
Okay, So if it's a Web based alert,
how can we handle web
based alerts?
SWAT click
by simply in suspecting this.
Right. Because we talked about it, guys.
It's it's the JavaScript alert
that we need to switch to.
This is a web based alert
so we can simply go ahead
and inspect these
and we can simply perform.
Click actions or close actions.
Right. Any actions we have through.
Celine Right.
We don't have to switch to it
because it is considered as a web element.
Okay, So what I will do in here,
I will copy
the ID, okay, Go back in
here, create another web element.
Okay.
And let's put it confirm delete
driver, find element
ID, There we go.
And simply
to click on this.
Right. Okay.
So when our condition is met,
we click, we click on delete, right?
And we click on checkbox,
we click on delete confirming everything.
So after we confirmed everything,
what do we need to
do, guys?
We need to break them.
All right.
Okay,
so we have to break the for loop in here.
So now if our employee is
not on the first page, guys,
what do we need to do
in this case?
We need to click on the next right.
So let's create a web element in here.
Okay?
So let's go ahead and
inspect this.
All right?
So if it's not here,
we need to click next.
What do we need to
what can we use in here?
What kind of locator
link text.
Right. Simple.
So we can use link text in here.
The copy
web element, next button driver
find element
by link text
and we can simply paste this link text.
Thank you.
Okay,
so in order for to click on the link text,
we need another loop, right?
Which will, which will be controlled
by the boolean value of the flag.
Right.
So I'm going to create a boolean value
and say flag is equal to true,
right.
And then what I need to do,
I need to create a while
right?
Not sure
I can see here
by idea.
Okay, so you want to use your employee ID
and then
and then find that checkbox, right?
So let's see here.
Okay. So you want to do this, right?
So is this the same employee
ID that we have right now
for that checkbox? This
it has a at the end, right?
So what's going to happen is your X
path is not going to work.
Okay. So that's first.
Even though your employee ID was the same
as here in your I.D.
value, what if it's on the fifth page?
So you're navigating here.
You're looking for that element.
It doesn't exist.
What are you going to get?
So the element that you're looking for,
it doesn't exist on the web page.
So you getting what you're getting
an exception, right?
Because
until you navigate to that page yourself,
then you will not be able to pick that up.
Okay. Is that clear?
Does.
Okay, good.
All right.
So let's go ahead and. Copy
everything
from here and pasted inside this one.
Okay. So we broke the loop.
So we are in a while right now.
So once our condition is mapped in here,
what do we need to do?
We need to set our flag to false.
Right? So flag
is equal to false in here.
So and then after each loop iteration,
what we need to do, let's see,
we need to click on the next button,
right?
Is this clear, guys?
Any questions before I run this?
Okay, we're coming to that point.
Okay.
Let's run this first
and see if this is going to work.
Please do not run, guys.
Okay?
Please do not run at the same time
as I am doing okay,
because there might be some duplicates
for employee IDs.
Okay. If we run it at the same time.
Okay, so let's run
this and see what we're going to get.
Okay?
Okay.
Clicking on this one.
Okay, so you messed
click on the next button once.
So we are on the page two in here.
Okay, We're on the page too.
So it didn't click any more.
What happened, guys?
So we are getting a stale
element except, right?
Anyone knows what this exception is?
Any thoughts, Any guesses on this
same element?
Exception codes.
They stayed for some period of time.
Okay.
You cannot access the elements. Okay.
So sometimes, guys,
when you run your code, you will face
this stale element exception.
And this exception is one of the worst
exceptions
for a automation engineer,
because for thing,
if you get this stale element exception,
there is no 100% solution for this.
Okay?
So when you get this
exception, you will need to do
a set
of actions in order to get rid of this.
Okay.
First of all, what you need to do
is you need to refresh your page.
Okay?
So that's one thing that you can do
in order to resolve the issue.
Second, you need to go ahead
and check your locators.
Okay.
So where is this failing?
Why is this failing?
So it says
on line 51.
So seems like
when we moved to the second page,
what happened is it didn't get the text.
Look, it says that table rolls
element is stale right now
so it's pretty old and it's it
can't really identify it identified before
but now it's not there.
Okay. Why is this happening?
So most of the time this happens
when your page is getting refreshed
automatically.
Okay. So if I go in here
and click
on the next button in here,
okay, look at the page, guys.
What happened?
The whole page just got refreshed
in the previous that's in here.
If I click on next, nothing is changing,
but the table data is changing. Right?
But in this example,
if you look at this, if I click on next,
you will see that
we're moving to the third page in here.
But the whole page is getting
is getting refreshed, right?
So every time
the page is getting refreshed,
we need to locate our table
all over again.
Okay, So let's get back in here.
So whenever we click
the next right, what happens?
We need to locate.
We need to find this element again, Right?
So When are we going to do this?
We're doing this right inside our. Why
is that clear, guys?
Any questions on this now?
Questions?
Okay, good.
All right,
so what else do we need to change in here?
So we need to identify
the table rows again
after we move to the second page.
If there Is there any other thing
that we need to change in here?
Guys?
Okay, guys, I need you to be more active
in here, Right?
Because I'm just going to assume
that you guys
are understanding everything
and I'll just continue
with whatever material I have,
and we can finish in 15 minutes.
Okay.
So here, guys,
if I need to locate the table
after each iteration.
What do I need?
Is there any other thing
that I need to change inside my wild loop?
Guys,
what if my page is getting refreshed?
Right?
What am I going to lose in here?
So I initiate.
I initialize
this here, this web element in here.
So everything is good.
What else seems to be off in here?
Guys Guys?
All right. No idea. Good.
Okay, so what?
I am going to do, I'm going to copy
this and paste this in here, okay?
Because this is one of the elements
that will change during our execution
during each iteration
when we click on the next button.
Okay, so now what I am going to do.
So let's see in here.
So we already added this guy in here,
so I need to change the name here.
Okay, So
let's see,
let's
go to the second
page and see what you have
here.
Okay, that's fine.
Let's add anything with
the and see how
this is going to work.
Whatever.
I don't even know if this name exists.
Okay, so let's run this and see
what we're going to have
to go saving
before you list.
You can see
we're moving to the next page in here
right? So
now first page.
And here.
And it's going to keep moving
until it finds that employee, right?
I think we're going to be here
for a while.
I hope
this is going to find that quickly,
but probably not.
So let's see.
I don't even know how many pages we had in
here.
Okay, we're on page 20.
Okay.
Oh, seven.
Eight pages. Okay.
That's not bad.
And let's see what it's going to find.
It. I'm pretty sure it will, but
we don't know where it is. So
show time.
Exactly.
Okay. I'm going to wait until 50
and then terminate this.
Okay, guys, let's
see if it comes up until 60.
What happens
if it doesn't get saved inside this
employee's table?
Guys, what are we going to do
that?
Okay, so running off access to two.
Okay, guys, what's going to happen
is that employee that we added
is not going to get saved
inside this table.
Oh, okay.
There you go. It found it, right?
It found it, it deleted it.
Right.
Then you can't find it. Oh, wow.
Okay.
So you need to create a defect
in that case, right?
All right, guys, any questions?
All right, No questions.
Good.
Okay, so now what I want to show you is
let me create
a new class in here.
So now what we will be doing in here,
we will be handling some calendars.
Okay.
All right.
So let me go in here, see?
Okay.
All right.
I guess
why not?
I plus one.
Yeah, it might have deleted the wrong one.
Exactly
Okay, so you need to make it a plus one.
Right? And that that's.
And then it should delete the right
employee.
Okay.
All right.
So now, guys, what we're going to do,
we will be handling calendars.
Okay, so calendars is the
another web element on the web page.
Okay.
And we will be handling it
a little bit differently.
Okay.
So there's a lot of different calendars.
I mean, I'm
pretty sure you've seen these calendars
when you're booking flights, right?
Or you trying to
put some dates somewhere.
Right.
So most of the time you will see
these calendars when you are dealing
or booking a flight and going somewhere.
Right.
So these
these calendars are handled
a little bit different
than the usual Web elements.
Okay.
And we're going to look into the
into these calendars
what they have inside them.
Okay.
Any questions, guys?
Now, Questions?
Okay, good.
So I have a calendar over here.
So let's take a look
what we have inside this calendar.
Okay.
So when I click on this guy in here,
right, so we can see that
there is a calendar popping up right.
First of all,
if you start working with calendars,
like if you're booking any flight, right.
So what are you going to
what are you going to
look at first, guys,
before you choose the date guys
that year?
Okay.
What else?
The year and a month, right.
So here we have a year and a month.
In what format, guys?
What is this?
It's a dropdown, right?
Exactly.
So in some dropdown,
in some calendars you will see months
and a year as dropdown.
In some calendars
you will see it a little bit different.
Okay guys.
So let's take a look at the
at the dates now.
So if you want to
start looking in
or start interacting with the dates,
what do we have in here guys?
We have a simple table in here, right?
A table with a T hat and, the T body.
So in calendars, guys, most of the time
when you're interacting with calendars,
the dates will be stored
inside the T body.
And the days, days of the week
will be stored inside the T hat.
Is that clear, guys?
Any questions on that?
Okay, so now what we're going to do,
we will be interacting
with the same application.
So what I want to do is
let's go back in here, let's copy
the log in.
Okay.
So this is our steps to log in
in here, right?
So what I want to do,
so when I navigate here, what I want to
do, I want to click on leave
and then click on the leave list.
And then what I want to do,
I want to interact with this calendar.
Okay. Is that clear, guys?
Any questions?
All right, good.
Okay, so now let's get back in here.
Okay, so we're logged in.
So what I want to do,
I want to click on this leave button.
Right?
So Let's identify this
and what we can do in here.
Can we use a linked text for this?
Guys?
Is it possible
it has it D
Okay, now about
can we use live text in here
to work as well?
Okay, good.
All right.
So let's use the idea in here.
Go back
Web elements, leave button
driver, find elements by ID
and what we can do need to simply
click this right.
Okay.
So when we click on that, let's go.
So let's see if I click on leave.
Okay?
We don't have to click on the live
list in here.
We don't have to click on this. Right?
Okay.
So we should be in here.
So now in order for me to
to start
to start interacting
with the calendars in here,
first of all, what need to do?
I need to locate that element. Okay.
So what I'm going to do in here
is to click on this
and if we have anything in here so
or what we can do,
I think if we click on this text box,
this is going to open up this calendar
so we can do that.
Okay,
So what I'm going to do, I'm going to copy
this ID in here, okay?
And go back
Web elements
from calendar
is equal to driver.
Find elements
I D Right.
And to open that up, what we going to do,
we will clicking this right.
Okay.
Any questions until this point guys?
So I'm going to be clicking on that text
box and that's going to open
this calendar.
So before I choose any dates, Right.
What do I need to do in here?
What is the elements
that I need to interact with a
month and a year?
Right.
So let's start interacting with a month.
Okay, So this is my element, guys.
How can I interact with this?
Can we, can we use select?
Plus in this case, guys, now
because of dropdown.
Okay, so we can't use to select class
with this dropdown this,
is that correct?
We do not have to select.
Okay.
Do we not have selected here guys,
what are we looking for in here before
before we interact with dropdowns guys,
what do we need to look at?
Okay,
so you guess we can use select?
Okay. What?
Why can we use select in this case?
Okay.
Seems like we all forgot
what's going on with dropdowns guys.
So we need to look for the tag. Right?
In order for us to use the select class,
we need to look at the tag
that has an HTML.
Right? So we have a select tag in here.
So that means we we can use select
to class in here, right? So
let's identify this by class name in here.
Okay.
So web element
months dropdown is equal to the driver
find element
by class name,
right?
And then so I identified this element.
What is my next step guys?
So what we need to do, we need to create
an object of the select class, right?
So select act
select and here is equal to new
select and inside our
constructor, what we need to do,
we need to pass this right.
Okay, so now when do we want to go?
What month, guys?
When do we want to go on vacation?
Right now.
Okay, so right now is what?
Right now is October.
Okay, So let's go in October. Right?
So how do I how do I select here?
October, guys, how many ways
can we select any option from the dropdown
by visible text,
by value and by index.
Right.
So let's select by visible text
and so month dropdown
that not the month dropdown right select
in here
say select select by visible text.
So if we want to go on October,
do I just put here October
guys,
we just need to put the visible text
that we inside our dropdown.
Right.
So in this case it's a different text,
it's just an abbreviation in here.
So this is how we're going
to, we're going to put it in here.
So we can put select months
here.
Okay, So now guys
in here, I need to choose the year
okay, do we need to choose the year?
And here goes,
Oh, we're going this year, so
we don't really need to change anything.
Right? So now let's go ahead and
start working on that date.
Right.
What date do we want to go
in here
today?
On fifth.
Oh, yeah. Birthdays today. Good. Okay.
I think I'm given the toughest class
on your birthday.
Okay.
All right, let's go on.
I'm 21st.
Okay, so what we want to do,
we want to go on Sunday, 21st of October.
Okay, so now,
if this whole thing is inside the table,
guys,
how do we want to interact with the dates?
Any thoughts?
Okay, list. Right.
And what do we need to do
first, guys, before start, interact
before we start everything
inside the list, find the tables.
Right.
So let's find
the table in.
Okay, so this is our table
so we can identify this class name, right?
So let me copy this class name here.
Table
class is equal to
this.
Okay, so I identified this.
So now what?
Where do we need to go, guys
from here
to the tea body.
Tea body.
I said head. No I said in header.
All the days of the week are stored.
Okay.
So we don't really care
What day is it going to be.
We care about the dates.
Okay, so the dates will be stored
inside the tea body.
Okay, so we identified the body.
So now I need to go to my rows.
Okay.
So would that be sufficient guys
in order for me to identify where
what date I need to pick in here.
So let's actually expand this.
So we have five rows in here
and also have the TDs in here.
Anything else
that I need to specify in here?
Do I need to go over each row or do
I need to go through the each date?
Guys in here, we need to go to each date.
Right.
So we need to move one step forward.
So if you look now, I have 35
elements in here
found like four of them is probably
they are empty, right?
So here what I am doing, I'm going through
each and every date, right?
So what I'm going to do in a copy
this express.
Okay.
And what I will do are stored
in a list of web elements.
Okay.
So from dates is equal
to whatever the
elements, I
expect, right?
And let's
import this.
So now what is my next step in here, guys?
We need a four right.
So for loop in here,
so we have some dates, All right.
And we'll be iterating
through the web
elements.
All right.
So once we start our ideation,
what's going to happen to us?
What do we need to do?
So, yeah, so that's a good question.
So you can send any text in here as well
because it's just a text box, right?
But sometimes sometimes
you won't be able to do that.
Okay.
You will have to interact
with an actual calendar in here.
Okay.
But that's a good point.
Yes, you can do that.
Okay.
All right.
So we start iterating.
So now what we need
do we need to set a condition? Right.
So it's
in here.
My date.
Right.
That text
equals 21st, right?
Then what I'm going to do,
I'm going to simply click here.
So after I click, what I need to do, guys,
I need to break right?
All right.
So let's run
this and see if this is going to work.
Okay?
I think everyone is running their code,
guys, so let's not do that
because you can see it's it's very slow.
Okay.
There we go.
So it's
from the dropdown with selected October,
but it's not selecting 21.
Why guys,
I have all parentheses right in here.
The default was 21.
Now default is set, right?
Default is five.
There we go. We need quotation. Exactly.
Because whenever I get the
text, what happens is we need
we get the string right.
So now
and every time we interact with the text,
it's going to be string.
So we have to compare this
with the string, right?
So let me close these.
Okay, So now let's run that again
where it's a bit
slow, guys.
There we go.
So you can see that we will have here
October 21st.
Okay.
Any questions, guys, on this?
Any questions on how to handle calendars,
how to handle pagination
questions until you forget.
Okay, good.
All right.
Let's go to the notes.
So calendars, guys, calendars,
they are
also now
as they focus.
That's
all right, guys.
You guys seem really passive today.
It's either everything is really clear
and easy or you guys are tired.
Today.
Okay, So there's a lot of information.
Not easy, correct?
Yes. Okay.
So here, you guys.
Why this is not easy.
Selenium itself is really easy, right?
Selenium is very easy
until you start
implementing the actual Java.
Right.
So if you struggle in Java,
guys will struggle with a lot of stuff.
Okay.
So what
I would suggest to focus more on Java,
because the logic is going to be built
by the job, okay?
Anything you do, anything,
even in your framework.
Okay.
So whenever you start building
your framework,
whenever you start combining
all the different different tools
you need to be really,
really good at Java.
Okay? So,
so if you are really
behind on Java guys, I'd suggest
to study more on Java
because selenium itself is really easy,
Test is really easy,
cucumber is, is really easy.
It's simple.
English, okay, But if you don't know Java,
that's going to be a big problem
even in the interview.
And if you find a job, it's
going to be problem at work as well.
Okay.
Calendar handling.
Yes. So yes.
So basically, as I said,
guys, it's a combination, right?
So you need to know when to click,
when to iterate
and when to break the loop
or when to add another.
Okay.
So you have to build that logic in
with combination Java and selenium.
Okay.
And if you are really good in Java,
that's easy to build everything
because the most logic that we're building
is consist of Java language,
these storing everything
inside the lease list and
iterating through everything
and setting the conditions,
everything there.
It's coming from Java, right?
So we need to be really careful
in building the logic.
Okay.
All right, guys, any other questions?
Yeah. You have to practice every
day, right, guys?
It will.
It will get in a
habit, but it's a little it's
a little challenging right now
because every day
we're starting something new.
And I know it's hard to catch up
sometimes.
I was in your shoes before and I
and I know how it works.
So every time we finish the class, try
to try to look at what we've done,
try to go through the logic
and write the actual code yourself,
do not copy and paste lies.
You will have time to copy and paste
after year when you confident.
Okay.
It's hard to believe. It's
hard to believe.
I was in your shoes, guys.
Is it what you say?
No, I was guys.
Okay.
Trust me, I was struggling as well. So
I wasn't the perfect student either.
Okay, guys.
So everything comes with practice.
So the more you practice, the better
you get in coding.
Okay.
Any other questions, guys?
Okay. Seems like no questions
since we have 20 more minutes,
guys,
I can answer some questions
over the pagination.
Sure.
What is this? What is that?
You didn't understand in the pagination
guys?
Sure.
Do you want to.
You want me to go through the first
example or the second one one?
Okay,
So here, guys, what we're doing is
simple in here.
What we're doing, we are storing
all the rows inside the list, right?
So and we're identifying
the next one element.
After that, what we're doing is
we are having a Boolean value in here
so that we can
so that we can have a wildly okay.
So while loop is going to
it is going to help us
to click on the next button.
Okay.
So what's going on in
here is for loop is fine.
We're iterating through the
through the rows and we're looking
for this condition, right?
So if this condition is not met,
we're going out of the loop
and we need to click the next
right.
So when we clicked on the next button,
we need to start our iteration again,
right?
So that's why we need this loop in order
to get back to our for loop.
Okay, So in the second iteration,
when we get back in here,
we find this guy and our,
our conditions are met.
So once this condition is met,
what we need to do,
we need to set this flag as false.
Okay?
And then we need to print this out,
print the roll out,
and then what we need to
we need to break everything.
Okay.
So basically
a loop is going to help us to reiterate
over the rows
and to check on the condition
and is to see if we need to click
on the next button as into
any other questions
I can answer.
Any work related questions as well.
Guys, if you want to ask
since we have 20 more minutes.
If not, then we can wrap up the class.
Guess.
Okay. Homework. That's a very good.
That's a very good point. Yes.
Homework, guys.
Okay. So.
Okay, so this is the homework.
Okay.
So what I want you to do, log in to this
application right, click on leads,
click on live list.
So come to this page.
Okay.
So interact
with two different in here.
Choose a date.
Okay.
From and to okay,
but do not just enter any text in here.
Interact with an actual calendars in here.
Okay.
So with the tables, with a dropdowns
and here so that you have more practice.
Okay.
So when you're done with this,
what I want you to do,
I want you to click on cancel
and reject the checkboxes.
Okay. So only on these two.
Okay. So
and then what I want you to do, I want you
uncheck the pending approval checkbox.
Once you do that,
you need to select
it support from this dropdown
and then you to click
search and quit the browser.
Okay.
Is that clear? Guys?
Any questions on the homework?
Okay, good.
All right.
So if there's no questions, guys
giving you back 16 minutes of your time.
Seems like everyone is overwhelmed.
Guys,
you need a little bit of break right?
Am I still working as a tester?
No, guys, I'm doing both. Actually.
I'm a backend developer and a tester
at same
time.
Was it difficult for me at the start
when I just found
when I just found a job?
Yes, it is a little bit difficult because
you don't really know what's happening
inside, the meetings, right?
And there are a lot of new tools
that you need to learn
and you need to pick up really quickly.
Okay, So you're going to be you.
They will give you time.
Okay.
When you start working, it's not that
they will give you some test cases.
Okay, You need to automate this now.
You will go through the boarding process,
through the everything.
You will go through training
and everything.
Okay.
But the one thing
that is going to be a little bit
challenging is the meetings, right?
Because
you don't know what how the meetings go
and you don't know how they actually do
the process.
Okay. So that's going to be
a little challenging.
Other than that, it should all be fine.
Okay.
Learning new tools is going to be fine
because you're going to get training
and you will be Googling yourself,
okay.
Yes, they will be looking at you
as experienced.
TESTER Absolutely right.
So and first first two weeks,
three weeks, guys, no one is going to
no one is going to
what's called ask you to do this
or that that you don't know.
Okay.
Even in the meetings, guys,
they won't ask you lot of questions.
Okay.
So you're just going to sit
in the meetings in the first two
or three weeks because you don't know
the application, you don't know the tools.
So you're just going to be observing
everything, everyone, what
what they're doing, how they talk,
what they talk about in what meetings.
Okay, So don't be that
stressed, what you're going to be doing
when, you when you just start working.
Okay? So it's okay.
My training was since
my project is government,
I had more time
because I needed to get the clearance.
Okay.
So without the clearance,
I didn't have any access.
So my my training was a little bit longer.
I think it was three, four weeks.
But after the second week,
I already started coding.
Okay,
They'll start giving you.
They'll start giving you small tasks.
Okay, guys.
So they will not give
you really big stories to complete
because you don't really know.
They don't really you don't really know
the application, right?
Without the clearance. Yes.
So if you find a full time job,
they'll hire you first
and then you can apply for clearance.
But sometimes most of the time,
if they don't let you start
without the clearance is when you get
is when you get the job as a contractor.
Okay.
But you will get through it
at the end of the course.
Okay, guys.
Well, it depends.
It also depends on the company.
How they want to work it out.
Tomorrow's topic is calendars and
we will be interacting with more calendars
tomorrow,
taking screenshots and actions plus.
Okay I'm
I'm from batch for
you guys are what batch ten.
Oh well I know it's
not the last class for selenium right.
We have next week as well.
What is clearance usually included.
Do they check your job history.
Yes they do.
They will check everything and
you will go through this process.
Okay.
Don't don't be really scared
about the clearance jobs, okay?
Because you will pass that
and unless you are a criminal
or anything
or a convicted felon in the previous life.
Okay.
So if you don't have any of these,
you will be you should be fine
on passing defense.
If they give me my first salary.
What do you mean
for salary?
Oh, okay. Okay.
Yeah, that's the contract.
Every didn't need to sign right?
All right, guys, any other questions?
Okay, if no questions, guys,
do not get to to stress.
Okay? Everything is good.
You will get overwhelmed. That is fine.
Take a break, guys.
Start over.
Okay, so everything is going to be okay.
So let's push it a little bit more.
There is a little less.
Okay, guys.
So we're almost done with selenium.
There's a couple more tools
that you're going to learn and that's it.
You're going to be on the market.
Okay,
So everything is going to be good for us.
Okay.
All right.
I'll I'll post the slides for tomorrow.
Okay.
All right, guys.
Thanks, everybody.
Have a good night
and I'll see you tomorrow,
okay?
By everyone.