Yeah.
Let's continue with our selenium classes.
Okay.
I think we have enough people
to get started right now.
Okay. How is everybody doing, guys?
I hope everyone is doing good.
Everyone is having fun with Selenium,
and I hope everyone
completed their homework
and everything is working.
Okay, good.
Am I going to share the solution
for the homework
nowadays?
I think you guys usually go over those
on review classes right?
And yeah, there you go.
If you check the syntax syntax students
channel.
Right.
I think everyone is sending their
solutions in there so you can compare
yours to their.
All right.
Okay, guys,
any questions from the homework?
I hope today
we're going to be more active and active
right.
Oh, how are you going to know?
How are you going to know
if that's the right one?
Okay, guys.
So in coding, there's
no one way of solving something, right?
There's always different
different ways of solving something
or coming up with something
or getting something done.
Right.
So I think
whichever solution, if you see some guys
made something different,
it doesn't mean yours is wrong.
Okay.
As long as your solution is working
and there solution is working,
that means you guys both did a good job.
It's working and that's what it matters.
You don't think that you're doing
something wrong or you not doing something
right.
Okay,
so in coding, guys, there's always, always
there's you can do it
different, different ways.
Okay.
And we saw it
even last class that you can do.
You can manipulate your list
with iterator, with four loops,
with the regular, with advanced for loops.
Right.
So it all it's all up to you on what
what approach you want to take.
Okay.
So whenever you come up with a solution,
don't think it is the wrong one.
Okay.
As long as your code works,
as long as your script
is running, fine, That's what matters.
Okay.
All right.
Any other questions, guys?
Yes. It makes a lot easier on
you guys right now.
And even if you find a job, right?
Even when you start working,
you I mean, everyone
has their own approach to solutions.
Everyone have.
Everyone has their approach
to debug something
or find out the solutions
or find out some mistakes or anything.
Right.
So it's not that
there is one way of doing something.
Okay.
So don't be too much worried about.
So that's why we're trying to teach you
some different, different ways
so that if this is does
if this doesn't work, use this one.
If this one doesn't work, use that one.
And you should be coming out with
different, different approaches yourself.
Okay.
All right.
Any other questions?
It's no questions.
Then let's get started with
with doing a recap from yesterday.
Okay.
So what did we cover yesterday, guys?
Dropdowns.
Right. Okay.
What do we know about dropdowns? Guys
with covered
dropdowns, checkboxes, radio buttons.
Right.
So let's start off.
Let's start with checkboxes and radio
buttons, guys.
So how do we handle radio buttons
and checkboxes?
Either by clicking or
using the select
plus for checkboxes and radio
buttons? Guys
only for dropdowns.
Right.
Okay, so let's talk about checkboxes
and radio buttons first.
Okay. So.
So in the for checkboxes
and radio buttons, what you can do,
you can sort them in the list
and look through them. Right.
And then given the condition, you perform
some action.
Right?
Or if you have one checkbox
or you have one
radio button, then what you can do is
you could just click on it, right?
Okay. So that was it. It's there's not big
a lot of stuff
with checkboxes and radio buttons
you can use for loops.
You can use either.
It's all up to you
how you want to handle it.
Right. So what about dropdowns?
So we said dropdowns can be handled
by either clicking
or using the select class.
Right.
So when do we know that we can use select
class guys
if we have the select tag?
Right.
So what we need to do,
we need to make sure that the dropdown
we are trying to interact with
it has a select tag.
Only then what we can do is
we can go ahead and use select class.
Okay. How many types of
of dropdowns do we know guys about?
Two types. Okay.
Which ones?
Okay,
so we have single select dropdowns
and we have multiple select dropdowns.
Right.
So what can we do with multiple select
dropdowns,
which we cannot do with single select?
Am I reading?
Is the video?
Okay, guys.
Okay.
Okay, good.
All right.
Okay, guys.
So what we can do with multiple select
dropdowns that we can not do
with single select guys.
Okay, Select multiple items.
That's first. Okay.
What else
is multiple?
Yes, is multiple is a verification.
It's it gives us the boolean.
If our job down is
multiple, select or no.
Right.
So that's just a checkpoint for us.
What else, guys?
So let me go in here.
Let's see.
So if I do this and I did this one or
manually,
I don't think you can do this in here.
You can only select manually.
Okay. Okay.
So in multiples, select.
Right In multiple select,
what we can do is
we can disallow some options from the ones
we selected.
Okay.
So if you want to select something
from your selection,
what you need to make sure
obviously your multiple,
you need to have a multiple
select dropdown, right?
And only then what you could do.
You can go ahead and select some values.
Okay.
How many ways can we select a
and option from the dropdown?
Three ways. Okay.
Which are
OC by index, by visible text
and by the value.
Right. Okay.
And what I'd say by the value.
Guys, what are we trying to look for?
What value I would trying to get
the attribute value right.
So we're trying to look for the attribute
which is value.
And we taking that value, right?
There's a lot of values in there.
Okay.
All right, good.
Any questions?
I hope no one no one is having issues.
Were the chrome drivers. I saw some.
I saw someone mentioned about the updated
update of the Chrome browser.
So if you get it updated guys,
or it gets updated automatically.
Please go ahead and download the right
Chrome driver for the Chrome browser.
Okay.
So if you have a version 93,
you need a Chrome driver of version 93.
Okay.
All right.
I hope no one is having that problem and
the selenium is running.
Running fine right now.
Okay, good.
All right.
So today, guys,
what we're going to be doing,
we will be going over the alerts
and we will be going over the frames.
Okay.
So I hope you guys did some research
over the frames and alerts
and let me create
a new file in here.
Okay, So I am plus six.
Okay.
So anyone did research on alerts, guys?
Let me see.
What is alerts, guys,
What do we know about alerts?
Okay, so a small message red
box that gives info for the user.
It's a pop up message
or it's a pop up window.
Right.
Okay.
A pop ups,
we can use switch commands. Okay.
That's good.
All right.
So basically, if I go
here and I click on the button, right.
And you can see something pops up, right?
Right on the page. Right.
So this is a pop up,
or you can call it an alert.
Okay.
So it's basically a pop up
and it takes a complete
focus of our main page
that we're working on.
Okay.
And we won't be able to proceed
until it is handled.
Okay.
So if I go ahead and click on
anything on the Web page,
you can see that
I'm not going to be able to do this.
Okay.
So unless I go ahead and click okay
and only then, like
I'm going to be able to go ahead
and continue my work on that Web page.
Okay.
So there are different types of alerts.
But before we go into that,
let me just put it in here.
Alert is a
pop up message, right?
Alert
takes
complete
off of our main page
that we are
working on. Okay.
And we cannot
proceed until
it is handled.
Okay. All right.
Three types of alerts. Okay.
What are those guys?
Simple alert.
Prompt, alert and confirmation. Alert.
Okay, so that's actually the subtype.
Okay, so we have an upper level of types
of alerts.
The three that you just mentioned,
simple, prompt and confirmation.
These are the subtypes. Okay.
But there are three types
of alerts.
Okay.
Does anyone know what these are?
Okay, so web based alerts
is the same thing as browser alerts.
So they're both the same.
And there is a JavaScript alerts.
And then there's one
which is called Windows based alerts.
Okay.
So there's three types of alerts.
And I'm going to go over those one by one.
Okay.
So first we will go over the Web
based alerts.
Okay.
Web based
alerts are also cold as h HTML alerts.
Okay.
So these alerts,
we can simply identify them as elements.
We can simply inspect them
and perform our actions.
Okay. And if I go
to the Facebook page.
Okay.
And I click on Create New Account.
What do we see, guys?
We see some pop up.
All right. On the page.
And you can see that
the main page is getting disabled.
Okay.
So what you need to do is either
you want to handle all the fields in here,
or you can close this, right in order
to get back to your main page.
Okay.
So the good thing in here is
you can simply go ahead
and inspect this in here
and you can interact
with everything on this pop up. Okay.
That's why it is called web pages
or HTML alerts,
because we can perform our actions
from this selenium
like clicks, sending keys
or performing any other actions.
Okay. Is that clear?
Guys, any questions on this?
Okay.
So we can simply
post facts and perform
needed actions.
Okay.
So now, guys, the second one is
the JavaScript alerts.
That was for alerts,
which is also called
browser alerts.
Okay.
So here what we need to do in here,
we need to handle this
a little bit differently.
Okay.
We're going to be using some some
different methods which are switched to.
Okay.
So since
let's go back
and click on one of these.
So since it is taking the complete
focus from our main page,
what we need to do,
we need to switch our selenium focus
to this alert.
And only then we can perform
some actions on it,
and then we can get
a focus of our main page back.
Okay. Is that clear, guys?
And I will be going into details
and we will be writing all the scripts
so that we can get more
and more information on that.
Okay. So we can handle
these alerts by using
switch to method.
Okay.
And what we cannot do in this case,
we cannot inspect a JavaScript alert.
Okay.
So if I click on this,
this thing is not expectable.
Okay.
And if you look at the previous example
that I showed you,
you can simply inspect that pop up
because it's a Web based alert.
Right.
So you can expect that
you can perform actions as needed.
Okay.
Any questions on this, guys?
And you can see it is outside the browser.
Exactly.
All right.
So let's get back in here.
Right.
So third, third alert in here
is going to be our Windows based alerts.
Okay.
So this alert we cannot handle
with selenium.
Okay.
Because whenever you have a Windows
based alert,
if it is completely different window
from your from your browser. Okay.
And that's why we cannot automate
with selenium.
Okay.
And we set it in our first class
that what kind of application we can only
automate with selenium guys.
We can only automate
web applications
by using selenium web driver.
Okay.
So in here
we having a Windows based pop up.
So we need to use some different tools
so that we can get into that
and we can handle those alerts.
And let me see the easiest one that
let me see if we have it
here.
And let's see.
Okay.
So this is this is the one, guys.
So whenever you try to upload any document
in anywhere, right.
So in in any webpage or
you're trying to to upload a picture.
Right.
So when you click on Choose a document
or choose a picture,
then you will see that
this kind of pop up will come up, right?
So that you can go ahead
and choose your picture
or you can choose your document
that you are uploading.
Right.
So as you can see in here,
it is completely different window from the
from the browser.
Okay.
So these kind of pop ups,
they are called as Windows based alerts.
Okay. Is that clear, guys?
Any questions?
Okay, good.
So we cannot handle
with selenium.
All right.
So now we know how to handle the Web based
alerts, right?
Because you can simply inspect
and you can perform any needed action.
We can't really
handle Windows based alerts
unless we using some different tools.
And I'll go over those tools as well.
But mainly we will be handling
JavaScript alerts.
Okay. And
now let's go over the types
of JavaScript alerts.
Okay.
So we said that there are three
types, right?
And as I said, guys,
they those three types
that you guys mentioned,
there are subtypes.
Okay.
So main types of the alerts
are these three
and the three that we mentioned before
as simple confirmation
and the prompt alerts,
they are the subtypes of alerts
which are types of the JavaScript alerts.
Okay.
So let me start from here.
Has a killer engineer.
Do we need to learn those tools to be able
to interact with Windows based alerts?
I wouldn't say so
because you can,
but it's it's a whole lot different tool.
Okay.
So if you want to.
So there's two things, right?
So if you are trying to interact
with the Windows based alerts.
Okay.
So either you go ahead
and learning a new tool
or what you can do,
you can just pass that thing manually.
Okay.
If you cannot automated with silly.
Okay. So there's two options.
And these two options are
they depend on how you guys discuss
with your team.
Okay.
But if you learn to interact with Windows
based alerts
or anything Windows based,
that is up to you. You can do that.
That's additional information.
But as far as I know
and as far as I've seen
in my projects, I have
I have done I have interacted with Windows
based alerts only once.
Okay.
And I have used a different library
from that.
That library comes from Java.
I'll go through it in a little bit.
Okay. Okay.
So the first type of JavaScript
alert is a simple alert.
Okay, Simple alert.
What it does is it pops up.
It gives us some message.
And there's only one button
that we can actually click on.
It's a okay button.
Okay, So if I go back in here
and click on alert.
So you can see there is a information
in here, some information.
And what you can only do is
you can click okay in here
and you get back to focus
to the main page.
Okay.
So what we're going to be doing in here,
we will be simply clicking.
Okay. Okay.
So the second one would
be confirmation of alerts.
Okay.
Confirmation alerts.
So this confirmation alert
will have two different buttons.
Okay. One of them is cancel.
The other one is. Okay.
Okay.
So and there is a message,
of course, in there.
So these kind of alerts, they are mostly
coming up in in like government projects.
Okay.
When you go there, when you just land
on the government project,
that's going to be a pop up, big pop up
saying that you accepted or not accepted.
There are some terms and all that stuff
about some fraudulent stuff, Right.
So if you don't accept it,
then you're going to get redirected
to a different side.
If you accept it, then you can continue.
Okay.
I'm pretty sure you guys have seen
this kind of stuff already.
So confirmation of alert is okay
or cancel.
All right.
So let's go back in here.
Either cancel
or click.
Okay. All right.
And the third one is the prompt alert.
Okay.
So what you can do for prompt alert.
And here you're going
to need to enter some message.
Okay.
So you enter the message
and you click okay, or
you don't enter anything
and you click cancel.
Okay.
So most of the time
you will be entering some text
and then click, okay.
All right.
So any questions so far, guys?
Any confusion
on that?
So now let's go over
the methods of
how to handle alerts in here,
and then we will dive
into the implementation itself.
Okay.
So to handle
JavaScript alerts,
we only have four different methods.
Okay.
So first one,
if you want to go ahead and click on
and click on.
Okay. Okay.
There's a method which is called accept.
And then
if you want to click on Cancel,
as we've seen in confirmation
and prompt alerts, what you can do is
you can go ahead and do dismiss.
Okay.
And then
if you go if you want to go ahead
and if we click on this,
there is a message, Right?
So if you want to go ahead
and get that text
and print it out or verify it or
put some conditions in there,
what you can do
is simply get text in here.
And the last one is for the prompt alerts.
If you want to enter something
in that, if you want to enter any message
or if you want to enter your name,
if you want to enter any text in there,
what you can simply do
is simply send keys.
Okay.
So these are the four methods
that we will be using.
Okay.
Any questions before
we dive into the actual implementation?
Guys, for the new program,
the pop up message,
three buttons,
even have three.
When you close any program.
What all is.
If it's asking if you want to save
or don't save or cancel.
Is that what you're talking about?
No, no, no.
Those are those are
if you are working on the web page
and you see those, then
then you
I mean, I've never seen that before.
If you're working on the webpage,
first of all.
Okay.
If you working on the web page
and it's asking you to save or not,
that's going to be your Web based alert.
Okay.
But if you're working, like,
let's say on Excel or on PDF
or on word,
and you try to save something in there.
Okay.
That way it's completely different
because your application
is not even a web application.
Okay.
So that's going to cause that's going to
be considered as the Windows based alert.
Okay.
But if if you have
like online
Excel or online work, you will have a
you will have a Windows
and not Windows based
and you will have a Web
based alert in there.
It's going to ask you to save or cancel
or whatever it is.
It will be a web based alert,
which you can handle
by simply inspecting and performing
any actions you want to perform.
Okay.
What is the switch to method?
We're coming to that point.
Okay, guys,
I'm just going to create a class
and then we will go one by one
and the prompt alert.
One more time, guys.
The prompt alert will have a textbook.
Okay, So that you guys can enter
some text in there and then click okay.
Or if you don't want to click anything,
you could just click on Cancel.
Okay.
All right,
So let's get back.
So I'm going to create a new package
and I will create a new class in here
and alerts
main method.
Right?
So go ahead and
get these from your
this.
I'm going to change the URL guys,
and I'm going to send it to you
quick right now.
There you go.
So you can use that.
Okay, guys.
So what I want to do in here,
I want to navigate to this website first.
Okay.
What I'm going to be doing,
I want to click on this alert
and then what I want to do,
I want to handle this alert on top.
Okay.
First of all,
what do I need to do in here, guys?
So I, I navigate it to this page.
What is my next step, guys,
we need to find that element.
Right?
Okay, so I'm going to inspect this page.
Okay, So there we go.
Alert in here.
So this is my alert button,
and it has an ID in here which I can use.
Okay, So I'm going to copy that.
I'd go back in here
and I will have a web element.
Simple alert button
is equal to drive or dot
find element
by ID,
and I'm going to paste that value in here.
Okay, so now what?
I need to perform in here.
What I need to do.
I need to just click on it.
Right. Okay.
So when I click on that button,
what I will see
is this guy over here, right?
And we can't really inspect this.
We cannot do anything
unless we use something
installed inside the Selenium library.
Okay, So in order for us
to handle JavaScript alerts
with selenium,
we will be using alert interface.
Okay. So
before I do that,
I need to switch my focus to that alert.
Okay.
So when when our selenium starts
the execution,
okay, when we just land on that
on this web page,
I'm going to click on this
and our selenium is going to boost
the focus.
Okay.
So we won't be able
to control any of the elements
unless we until we handle this pop up.
Okay.
So I need to switch my selenium focus
to that alert and how I'm going to do
this is pretty easy.
So going to be doing driver that switch to
and then I'm switching to alert.
Okay.
Is that clear guys?
That this is how we switch our focus
to alert.
Okay.
So whenever we switch
our focus to alert what we get in return
is the object or a variable
of an alert interface.
Okay, so what I can do in here,
I can do alerts.
Simple alert
is equal to driver.
Switch to an alert.
Okay.
And import the class from selenium guys.
So here I have a variable
which switches to that specific alert.
Okay.
And we don't really have to specify
which alert we want to switch to
because you handle the alerts
only one by one.
And whenever you have one alert.
You can't go really anywhere
without handling it.
Okay.
And there is no way of specifying
which alert you want to handle
because you will be handling each
and every alert one by one, one at a time.
Okay. Is that clear, guys?
Any questions?
All right.
So seems like no questions. Right.
So on line 18, what we did was switched
our selenium focus to an alert.
So now what I need to do,
I need to click okay in there.
Right.
Because it's a it's a simple alert.
There's nothing you can do in here.
So in order for us to click, okay,
what we going to be doing,
we will be using an accept method, okay,
which will be coming from alert interface.
So what I will do in here?
Simple alert dot accept.
Okay.
And let me actually give it a pause
in here so that we can see visual Li.
What is going on on the page?
Okay.
Any questions before I run this?
Guys?
Okay, so let me run this and see
what's going to happen.
There we go.
There's alert and then the alert is gone.
Because what we did is
we handled that alert.
We clicked on. Okay.
And you can see here the message
that it says you have clicked on.
Okay, button in alert window.
Okay.
Any questions, guys?
I hope you guys had the same output
in here.
Whoever is running their code
and here
for handling
simple alerts
and here
switching, switching
office
alert, you didn't get this message
in here.
Maybe you did something wrong.
Check. Check your intelligence.
Maybe there is an exception or anything
popping up
in your console.
Now, if you clicked on,
okay,
you should be receiving this message.
Okay.
Give it some time.
So give it some pause time
because it's probably too fast.
Line 1617.
We're clicking on this alert button, guys.
Okay.
On this one.
And once this is appear
on line 18, where switching our focus
to that alert in here
and online 20, we're clicking.
Okay, so offering your rings.
Okay that's good.
All right, guys, any issues?
Is anything going on
that you guys are confused
with? And
go back to the code here, Right here.
It's got a pop up in the bottom.
What kind of pop up
did you get in the bottom?
Send us the screenshot
so that we can see that.
All right. So
okay, guys.
So no questions for simple alerts.
And now let's go ahead and
deal with a different alert,
which is our confirmation of alerts.
Okay.
So once I dealt with the simple
alert in here, what is my next step, guys?
So I have this.
We clicked.
Oh, you just have a net.
Okay, that's fine.
That's fine.
Okay.
All right.
So whenever we click or whenever
we handle the
the pop up by using selenium
guys,
it will we switch to an alert first, guys.
But whenever we handle it, the selenium
will automatically switch
back to the main page.
Okay?
So we don't have to do it manually.
Okay.
So whenever we handle them alert,
we're already on the main page.
We can perform any actions, but
we can perform any actions on the buttons,
on the text boxes or anything in here.
Okay.
So we don't have to go back and switch
our focus to the main page manually.
Okay, so now what I need to do,
I need to find this
confirm element and then click on it.
Right. So here, there is an idea.
All right,
so I'm going to copy this ID value.
I'm going to go back to our code
and I will start to find that element.
Right.
So let's say for
alert button
is equal to driver
element
I.D. again
and then
with simply click on that button.
Right?
So after we click on it, guys,
what do we need to do?
So, okay, guys,
do you have to do this switch process?
Always if you have one multiple,
multiple pop ups in one execution,
you don't.
Okay.
But in this case,
I will be doing different, different
switch to methods
so that you guys can understand
what is going on.
Okay, so since we already
have this in here, we can we use this?
Okay, but
I'm not going to be doing this right now
so that you guys get in a use
of switching to alerts.
Okay. Is that clear?
Guys,
any questions on this?
So whenever you have an alert,
what you want to do, you want to switch?
Okay.
All right. Yes.
So that you can do accept exactly.
Or dismiss. Yes.
So in this case, what I'm going to do
and here I'll have alerts
confirm alert is equal to driver
dot switch to
alert. Right.
So we switch to confirmation
alert right now.
So now what I want to do in here, guys,
I don't want to click on Accept.
I want to click on Cancel.
But before I click cancel,
I want to get this information
from the from the pop up.
Okay.
So what
I am going to do in here, simple, right?
What I am going to do in here,
I need to call my variable,
right
confirm, alert and simply get that text.
Okay.
And what? This is going to return
me, guys.
What am I getting in return?
I'm getting a simple strength
value, right?
So I can say alert text in here is equal
to information alerts that get text.
So once I get the text,
let's print that text out in here.
And now after I print it out,
what I want to do,
I want to click on Cancel
and how I'm going to do this.
I'm going to just click on Confirm
alert that
this Miss.
Why do we need to text?
Why do we need to get the text?
You mean
it's just I'm showing you how to do it.
Okay.
I'm showing you the methods
that I mentioned before in here.
Okay, so right now
we covered accept, dismiss, get text,
and in the next one,
we will be covering the sent teams.
Okay.
All right, guys.
So before before we handle an alert,
what I want to do after I click
on confirm alert
button,
I want to have a clause of our execution
so that we can visually see
what is going on.
Okay, so I'm running this right now.
So let's see what we're going to have.
Okay.
This is first alert.
This is the second alert.
Okay.
Well, there's something going on in here.
Let's go see what's happening.
See in here.
There's nothing happening in here.
Okay.
See, they didn't even print it out.
Oh, yours is working.
Okay.
Oh, good.
Okay, so that means there's
something going on with mine.
Okay,
So after I click this.
Okay, so I'm waiting for 2 seconds.
Okay, so let's. Let's try again.
Okay, guys, let's see.
There's probably something wrong
with this website.
Let's run
this and see what's going to happen.
Yeah,
this website is a little weird, guys.
And there is there's one thing
that is not at all in here.
Oh, there we go.
Okay, now it's working.
Okay, So now it works.
And we can see that
you press cancel on confirm window.
Okay, so there's probably
something wrong with the website I'm
not sure what is going on, but this
sometimes this website acting up really
in a weird way.
Yeah.
The website the website needed in that
you have some inappropriate ads
that's that's
actually based on your search.
Michael Okay, so
sorry.
Sorry.
Michael That
okay, I think Michael left
that computer, okay.
That computer is strictly for Java.
Okay. Okay.
I see.
All right, I
Fergus, any questions on how to handle
the confirmation alert,
how to get the text and how to
click on cancel?
Guys?
Yeah, you look for Michael Doubter.
Okay.
All right,
so now let's go ahead and take a look
at the scene, okay?
Andre, you have.
Okay, Please, guys, take a look at the
what's called
Take a look at the error
that Andre is getting right now.
So if you look into it, it says
element click intersected, guys.
Okay.
So let me explain that what that means.
I hope you guys already know, but I'm
going to get some more clarity on that.
Okay.
So does anybody know what that means?
Actually, before we go on
element click Intercepted,
guys.
Almost taken like football, almost.
Elizabeth That's a very,
very good choice actually.
So sometimes, guys, when we run right now,
when I run
my browser is not maximized.
Sometimes your
your page
and your elements may get onto each other.
And whenever you're selenium
clicks on one of them,
they it may click on a different element
because they are intercepting each other.
Okay.
So whenever you have
this kind of exception, what you want to
do, you want to maximize your window
so that it is full screen
and you can see all the elements
separate from each other.
Okay.
So that that would be one of the things
that I would suggest to do.
Okay.
All right.
So now let's go ahead and
do a prompt in here. Right.
Enter some tax click. Okay.
So hello, how are you today?
We're doing that.
Okay. It works. Okay. Nice.
All right.
So now what
do I have to do in this case, guys?
So we will handle the simple alert.
We handled the confirm our alert.
So now it's time for us
to handle the prompt alert.
Right.
So locate the prompt element in here.
All right, We have this prompt. I'd.
So I'm going to copy that value.
Go back,
create a variable
prompt alert button
is equal to try for dot
element and I'm finding this by ID.
You place that idea here.
So now
alert click.
So after we click, let's give
it ten more seconds
right?
Yes, I'm using it a lot
because that's the reliable one.
Okay.
And you guys,
I know you guys already know how
to use different locators.
Okay.
So we're given a pause in here so that
we can see visually what is going on.
So now what I need to do next, guys.
So I clicked on the prompt alert button.
What is my next step?
Send keys.
Where
we need to switch first.
Right? Exactly.
So what I need to do, I need to do driver
that switch to an alert in here.
And what I can do is here.
Prompt alert is equal to
switch to alert.
Right.
So now what I want to do,
I want to enter some text
and then what I want to do,
I want to click.
Okay.
All right.
So here prompt, alert
dot simply sent keys.
What do we want to send in here, guys?
Any suggestions?
Let's see.
Hello, world.
Not that naughty Michael.
Nice.
Okay, that's a good.
Okay. Asghar is king.
Okay. Asghar is king. Okay.
There you go.
All right, let's do this.
And then what I want to do,
I want to simply accept this.
Oh, he doesn't want to fight me.
Did you guys ask?
Want to dance? Battle instead? Okay.
Challenge accepted.
Okay.
All right, guys, let's draw on this
and see what's going to happen.
What accepts
what it does.
Okay, So let it finish right now.
Okay, guys.
So this website, I told you
guys, it's acting a little weird, right?
So when we clicked on Prompt,
you didn't really see how it answered it.
Okay.
But you can see that we clicked on.
And it's displaying our
what's called our text.
Right? Exactly.
So that should be our output
because we are entering this output.
Okay.
So okay guys, so accept
we'll go ahead and click on.
Okay on the pop up.
Okay. This is what it does.
Okay.
So you can't just use the click or any
or submit in this case from selenium
that we've done so far.
You have to do accept
or if you want to click on cancel
or you have to click,
you have to go with dismiss.
Okay, Any questions, guys
and alerts
click okay is accept.
Okay, click.
Cancel is dismiss.
Let's
actually put this in the notes. Okay.
So you could do click.
Okay. Is
or let's put it in here
click okay
dismiss it will click
transfer.
All right.
Any questions, guys?
Anything that you guys are confused with?
Okay seems like no questions.
So now use
use another website
if applicable.
Yes, I'll give you
I'll give you a homework. Okay, guys.
So you can work on on a different website
with with alerts.
Okay.
That that one is is is good
we use switch method.
Yes. So you don't every time since
since we have this
or since we have one switch.
That is enough.
Okay so here I am
just differentiating the variable names.
Okay guys.
So that's why I'm using
so that you guys can practice
because this is the first time
we're doing this.
So that's why
I'm switching to an alert every time.
Okay,
So, okay, so explain to switch again.
Sure. So why are we switching in here?
Okay, so whenever we click on this button,
there is an alert popping up, right?
So and right now
I am clicking on different different
buttons
in here, and it's not working. Why?
Because my focus is taken by this alert.
Okay, So I have to handle this alert first
in order
for me to continue on this web page.
Okay.
So I need to click on. Okay in here.
But in selenium, in order for you
to switch your focus, you will have
to have this method of switch too,
and you have to switch to alert.
Once you've done
that, you need to perform an action.
It's either accept or you can dismiss
according, right.
So once you've done
that, you can go ahead and continue
any actions
that you need to perform on that webpage.
Okay.
All right.
Any other questions, guys?
Okay.
If no questions,
I have a question for you.
So If you see guys in here,
I got the text and I sent keys.
What is the difference between this
and the
ones that we used to do before guys?
So we used to send keys
on username password, we used to click,
we used to get text from any
like from last time we did
was the values from the dropdown.
Right So what is the difference between
this get text
and the one we've done yesterday?
And what is the difference between
this keys which we used to do before?
Guys,
this is almost yes.
So this is this sent keys
and this get text
is coming from an alert interface guys.
Okay because you cannot use the get text
or send keys from the previous examples
because those are coming
from the web driver.
Okay.
And those are given
only to interact with the web elements.
Okay.
But this is a JavaScript alert.
This is not a web element.
Okay, guys.
So that's why we need different
methods from
an alert alert interface
so that we can use
those get text
or whenever need to send keys.
We use it from there.
Okay. Any questions?
Is that clear, guys?
Okay, good.
So let me see.
So eight, ten right now.
Okay, so let's take a 15 minute
break, guys, okay?
And then we'll come back.
We'll go over some more
alert stuff
sent. Keys is not working for you.
You don't see the text itself, right?
Yeah, that's the website problem.
Okay, So that's the issue from there.
From the web page itself,
other types of commands or
there are four types of commands
for alerts, right?
Accept, dismiss, send keys and get text
and we will be learning
more, more of commands.
We will be
interacting with multiple windows.
Okay.
And with some different
what's called elements.
And we will be performing different
actions actually on the web elements.
Okay, I'll push the code
at the end of the class, guys.
Okay.
So we import
you won't be able to import it
automatically.
I mean, you can, but
when when you don't have this.
Okay, So this is not going to compile.
So when you hover over in here, guys,
it's going to say add exception
to method signature.
Okay? So you click on that.
It's going to throw that exception
right away in here
and it's going to compile it right?
Fine.
Any other questions,
guys?
You have every every class you start
with, you need to
when you write your script
and something doesn't compile,
you will have to import
those libraries.
All right, guys.
Okay, let's see. Eight, 12.
So let's come back at 830.
Okay.
So time for you to.
Type everything and get some break.
Okay?
All right.
I'll see you 30 guys.
All right, guys, let's get back.
All right, guys.
Let's see how many people we got.
Okay.
All right, so let's see.
Okay, guys.
So we have covered the JavaScript
alerts, right?
We know about simple.
We know about confirmation alert,
and we know about prompt alerts.
Right?
So there's one more alert
that I want to show you
which you won't be really facing
in regular basis.
It's really up to the project, right?
Well, whatever you're working on and the
configurations and all the requirements
depending on that.
Right.
So sometimes when you just navigate
to the website that you want to perform
some actions, you will get an alert,
which is called an authenticate alert.
Okay.
So let me actually show you what it is
now. Okay.
Let's see
here.
Oh, okay.
So I think I've already signed in in here.
So what's
this here?
Okay.
See, guys, when I just try to
navigate to this web page,
what it's asking
me, it's asking me
for my username and password.
Okay? We didn't click on anything.
We didn't do anything.
What we did,
we just navigated to this website.
Okay?
And for us,
in order to handle this of alerts,
we won't be really using
the alert interface.
Okay, so we just need to pass the username
and password in here,
but we're going to be doing it
a little bit differently.
Okay.
We won't be using any cent keys
or we won't be switching
our focus to the alerts.
Okay, So let me open a new class in here
and say
authentication alert
here and
we need to change our law.
Okay.
And I'm going to send you the URL here.
My chats.
Okay, So now we have our you.
While we don't, we're simply navigating
to that web page and it's right away
asking us for the username and password,
what it's asking us for those credentials
in a alert, in the alerts,
what's called safe.
Right.
So what we're doing in here, we're
not going to be using any alert interface.
We're not going to be switching
to that alert.
But we are going to manipulate is our
is our your zero.
Okay.
So after the steps, after the slashes,
but before the actual web
page, you are in here,
what we're going to do?
We will be passing the username
and password.
Okay, so this is how we're going to do it.
So let
this here.
So what you need to do in here
before this website name starts, right?
The URL starts
what you can do, you can pass
the username,
you can put a column in here
and you pass the password.
And then after you did that,
what you can do, you can put an ad sign
and then the rest of your zero.
Okay, So in this website, the username
and password is admin and admin.
Okay,
so what I am going to do in here guys,
I will start putting my username in here,
which is admin,
and then I'll put a call in and here
I'll put my password as admin as well.
And I will put the at sign.
Okay.
And the rest of the URL stays the same.
So I'm going to run this here
and let's see
what happens.
Okay?
Now getting we're not going to be able
to see that pop up as well in here
because everything we are entering
is inside the URL.
So that's going to get
what's called
it's going to get logged in really fast.
But what we are going to be seeing in here
that we have
proper credentials in here,
is that clear, guys?
So sometimes guys, sometimes
you might get a question
or a question in the interview
that, hey, let's say you have a pop up,
but it's an authentication pop up.
How would you handle those?
Okay, you could just say them, Hey, okay,
we have a username and password.
What we're going to do with it just simply
pass them inside the euro
and just navigate to that
or what's called navigate to that URL
and that's it.
Okay.
Any questions?
Can I put it in the notes?
Sure.
To handle authentication alerts
when the to pass
username and
password in the store.
Okay.
Okay. So
let's actually get
this is an example.
There you go.
Okay.
Any other questions, guys,
before we move forward,
how would you to handle the alerts?
How would you handle the authentication
alerts?
Yeah.
When you run it with selenium,
when you run it with your automation
script, you want see
how it's going to input the credentials.
But when you do it manually,
you will see the actual alert in there.
Okay.
You want to you want to
you want the interviewer to do that.
Okay, try that.
All right, guys, if there's no questions.
Okay.
Let's jump on to the next topic that
we need to cover today, which is crimes.
Okay.
So did anyone do any research on frames?
Guys, what do we know about?
Frames?
What are the frames on the web page
and how do we handle those frames?
Guess.
See, frames
divide our screen,
our web page into multiple.
Okay,
what else?
Let me see, what else do we know?
Guys are frames and I have friends.
Okay?
They have their own methods.
Okay, What else?
Okay, we need to switch.
Okay?
We need to switch to methods. So.
Okay, guys, so frames on the web page
are the separate windows.
Okay, so
frames are separate
and independent windows on our web page
and they allow developers to present
multiple views on one page.
Okay.
So let me show you
if I had it here
and models, they should be
here.
It's not safe and there should be frames
one way here.
Let's see. Okay.
This is great.
Okay.
There we go.
Okay, guys. So if you look
on this page, okay,
so I have one page in here,
and I have two more something on in here.
Right? So.
But we can do this.
Okay? Now, I don't need to adjust it
now. Okay?
So and you can see I can independently
go through this page, right.
Go through this separate screen.
And here is well,
I can go through this as well.
So these are
these are different and separate views
that developers build
so that we can
so that they can have multiple different
views and pages on one single page.
Okay.
So and in order to handle these,
we actually need to switch on those.
Right?
And we have a couple of different methods
to handle these frames
and we will be going over those
in a minute.
Okay.
So let me go back in here.
So frames, so frame
frame is in
separate
independent window
in our web page
and frames.
I'll defer to
represent multiple
SKUs on
one page.
Okay.
So as we can see here, we have one
big main page and can have here.
There is one separate page
and there is the second separate page
that we have in here, right?
So Web page.
Another Web page. Yes,
we can say that. Yes.
But this this view is a smaller view.
Right.
So this is not going to be a main view
because main view
is going to be the one
we just navigated to.
Okay.
So it's basically a nested
separate window.
Okay.
Any other questions, guys?
See, when you have navigation, no doubt
those are different.
Those are different.
The ones you talking about that
are you talking about these kind of menus,
the navigation that you can
navigate to different from there?
If you're just talking about
the navigation panel that has like pages
and everything that you can navigate
to a different page from there.
That's Now this is
this is a little bit different case.
Okay, This is a computer.
Those are just links, right?
So you click on those, it's free to read,
redirecting you to a different page.
Okay.
But here
you have a completely different view
on the same web that we just navigate.
Okay.
As frames accessible within our web
page. Yes.
These these web page, these frames,
they are interactive all
like Web elements.
And I'll show you how to interact
with them in a second.
Okay.
So let me go back in here.
So there three ways to interact
with frames.
Okay.
So three ways to
interact with
frames in here.
Look of them.
The first one is by index
by index,
the second one is going to be by name
or idea, and then the third one
is going to be by
web elements.
Okay, so three ways to interact
with the frames.
Okay. All right.
So as I said, guys, so frames are given
us four to have different views
on the same web page.
Right.
And as we can see in here, as we can see
in here,
that it is completely different view.
It is completely a different Web site. So
if we want to interact with the
with the elements inside the frame,
then what we need to do,
we need to switch to that frame first.
Otherwise you won't be able to interact
with any of the elements inside the frame.
Okay,
sure.
There you go.
Yeah, I frame and frame there.
Both say, okay.
All right, so let's go ahead and
start looking into the frames okay,
so what I can do in here.
So as you can see on this web page,
you see this frame
and there is a text box in here, right?
So how do we know that it's an eye frame?
Guys,
what you can do
is whenever you inspect the page
and you open the selector box and here
what you can do,
you can put the double slash
and you can do.
And I frame.
Okay, so in this page you can see that
we have 13 frames on this single page.
Okay?
So those eye friends,
it's going to have its own view.
It's going to have its own
they're going to have their own elements.
They're going to have their own buttons
and everything.
Okay.
Because it's separate
view from the main page.
Okay.
So what we are going to do in here,
we will be interacting with the one
with the first one in here
and will be entering
some text inside this
text box. Okay.
So let's go ahead and
a class.
That button right corner.
Which one
you talking about?
This.
Send me the screenshot
so that I can see what it is.
Okay, so let's create a class in here
and say handling
frames.
Oh, now that one, this is,
this is actually the how
this is from CSIS.
And as you guys remember
I told you guys, CC
is configured and it's
what's called
it is manipulated by developers, right?
They add margins, they add padding,
they add orders to the what to elements.
Right.
So if you can see
if you see this button in here,
it has a basic authentication
or what's called text,
but it also has that black font,
a black what's called
border in here as well.
Okay.
So everything that is you see in here,
it is configured and manipulated
by developers through this CE.
SS Okay.
All right.
So let's have this here
we okay, guys, question for you.
Can we have two main methods
in the same class guys
so that we can execute
two different tests?
Now, why not?
What would be the reason that we want?
We can have this
open and
have only one execution.
Why not?
Is Well, you
the word is main, okay.
But it's just a is just a method.
Right guys
the in
another okay
with overwrite each other
you can overload it. Okay.
Now I'm saying that
can we have this same exact main method
in the same class guys?
Why not?
You guys know how to create
regular methods, right?
So this is a method as well
of just one public method.
So one class allows only one public
method.
Okay, guys, this is one of the interview
questions actually.
Why can I not have
two main methods in the same class?
What do you want? Execute.
Why is it not going to execute? Guys,
what kind of error am I getting?
Okay, we're getting closer.
It's going to give
an error. What kind of error
is the same parameter?
Okay, guys,
anything else
and method?
Yeah, I know Google said that. Yes.
Okay, guys, you can have that.
You cannot have
two same methods in the same class. Why?
Because it's not going to compile.
Right?
So if I have the same
your real variable guys,
the same string, is it going to work?
No. Right.
Is the same
variable different
what's called different values,
But it's not to work
because it's not going to compile. Right?
It's already been defined. There you go.
So methods and main
method is the same thing.
If I have another main
method inside my class.
What's going to happen
is it's not going to compile guys.
Okay, so your Java is going to get
really confused which one to execute.
Okay.
It will not get compiled, guys.
That's the answer you should be
giving whenever you have an interview
with this kind of question.
Okay, So are you saying
that you can overload it or you can
you you won't be able to override it?
That is correct.
But the reason we can't really have this
two times in one class
is that it's not going to compile.
Right.
Okay.
Yes, that is overloading.
But I'm asking if I asked
if you have exactly same right.
So you will get a compile time error.
Okay.
So we will be okay.
Let's continue
with dealing with friends now.
Okay.
So navigating to that website
and try to we will be trying to
access this textbox and we will be
entering some text.
So what I'm going to do first in here,
what I'm going to do, I will be
finding this text box element in here.
Okay?
And I have this text box
which has an idea of name.
Okay? And I'm going to copy this ID
and I will go back to my script
and I will identify it here.
Okay.
Web element,
text box.
Okay is equal to driver the find element
by d, which is name here.
And then what do we want to pass
in that text box?
Guys?
What is the text that we want
to send in here?
Any suggestions?
Okay.
Again, again,
Michael.
Okay. Give the people what they want.
Okay?
Okay. Sounds good.
Okay, let's do this.
Let's do this.
Michael is let's do probably
something, right?
Okay, Let's do this.
We're not sure
yet. Okay, so let's do this.
All right, So let
me run
this and see what's going to happen.
Okay? So
running this.
Okay, we're here.
So now as we can see,
there's something going on
in our console.
Okay, so let's take a look at
what is going on in here.
Okay?
And here
I am getting and no such element
exception.
Okay.
Why am I getting that?
Because I can't find that element.
But if you look in here, I have
this ID as a name
and ID is the most reliable attribute
right?
When you get no such element exception,
that means that it's not even on the web
page, right?
You can't even find this kind of element.
Okay.
So when you are
getting these kind of exception guys,
you need to check on your locator
and you need to check
if you have a frame inside your web page.
Okay? Why?
Because it's that element that you're
looking for inside the Web page.
Your selenium will not seed at all
unless you switch to that frame.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys?
Your selenium will not see that element
inside the frame until you switch to it.
Okay.
So that's why
we know that there is a nice frame in here
and you can see that this is the IV frame
and our element is inside it.
Okay,
So what you need to do in order for you,
for your selenium to see this element,
what you need to do,
you need to switch to this IV frame
first. So
here what I'm going to do
in here before I find this okay,
before I find this, what I need to do,
I need to switch to that frame
and then find that element
and then perform actions.
Okay.
So pretty similar
to what we've done with alerts.
I am going to do that switch,
but this time I'm switching to a frame.
And if you look in the in the frame
method,
there's three different frames in here.
Okay, so
what kind of what's called
what kind of methods
are these guys?
So I have three exactly same methods,
but I have different parameters in here.
What kind methods are these?
They are overloaded methods, right?
Exactly.
Because they have different signature.
One of them except integer one of them,
except strength.
And one of them.
Except the web element.
Okay,
so this time I'm going to be using the one
which accepts the eight integer
and we will be going through the
indexes.
Okay.
So this is the first,
as you can see in here,
this is the first frame that I found
and this is the first frame that I need.
Okay.
So what I am going to do
if we're talking about the coding
index is guys,
where do we start from?
We start from zero, right?
So here what I'm going to do,
I'm going to put a zero in here.
We switch to the frame
which has an index of zero,
and then we start to find the element
and then we paste some element
or we input some text in there.
Okay, So let me run this
and see what
we're going to have.
There we go.
So what happened?
We have a text in here right now.
So what we did
is, was switched to that frame
and then we found that text books and we
entered the text that we wanted to enter.
Okay, Am I saying,
oh, you mean I frame inside the I frame
Exactly. Yes.
That can
be the that can be the probability.
Yes, you can have that sometimes. Okay.
So it all depends on how your developers
build your web page.
Okay.
Frame section.
Yeah.
Okay, guys.
So here what we did,
we switched to a frame.
We found the element, and what we did,
we input some text.
Okay.
Any questions on this, guys?
Okay, let's see.
Okay, so you guys are entering htp s okay,
so just do a step.
Okay, guys.
So how did we know it's the zero index?
Because if you in here I wrote the iframe
and if I go to the next I frames,
they are different or they are hidden.
Okay So and if you look at the first one,
this is what we need.
Okay?
So if this is what we need, that means
if we go back to the scripting,
our indexing is starting from zero.
Okay, So the first iframe on the web
page is going to have index of zero.
So this is how we determine
if it's index zero.
Okay.
Once we are in the frame,
we need to exit, I'm coming to that point.
Okay.
So I look at the one of 13 meaning.
Yes, correct.
That is correct.
Okay.
So there guys, when we switched
inside the frame, right into the frame
and we performed some actions.
So here, guys,
this is a little bit different.
Then we handled the alerts. Okay.
In here, what we need to do,
we need to switch back our focus
to the main page so that we can continue
working on different elements.
Okay, so in iframes, it's
not going to switch automatically because
because we don't know that
Sylvania will know if we have finished our
our actions inside the iFrame.
Okay, So we need to tell our selenium
that, hey, okay, I switched to the frame,
I switched to the frame,
I performed my actions.
Now I'm going back to the main page.
Okay.
And how we're going to do
this is pretty easy as well.
So after we perform
all the actions inside the frame,
what I will do,
all the driver that's switched to
that default content.
Okay,
so we're switching to a default content,
which means we're switching
back to the main page.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys?
Okay, good.
Yes, it will move to the main page
regardless of how you are.
If are inside the two frames
or it doesn't really matter.
Three five.
If you are switching the default content,
that means you're switching your focus
completely back to the main page.
Okay, Back to the main page, correct?
Yes. Any other questions,
guys?
It seems not so.
Let's continue here.
So let's actually do this.
So when we were dealing with alerts, okay,
so we had this button,
so let's actually click on it
before we switch to the default content.
Okay, So let me run this
and see what
exceptions or what errors
we're going to get
running this.
Okay, We have a text.
And now if you look here,
we're getting an exception again,
and it's the same exception that we got
before before we switched to the frame.
Right?
So we're getting no such element
because we're trying to locate
this simple alert button,
which is this one.
Okay, so why are we getting that
exception, guys?
Why can't we just click on this alert?
Because we are inside the frame.
So in order to do so,
we need to get back to the main page
and get our focus back to the main page.
Right. Okay.
So how are we going to do this?
We be just switching
to the default content, right?
So let's run this again, see
if this is going to work.
Yeah.
Now we switched back
or we clicked on alert button
and you see that we have this alert pop up
coming out for us.
Okay.
Any questions, guys?
From France to alerts?
Yes. So ifs okay.
So here's
what you're
going to have to have in order to do so.
So when you switch inside the frame
and you click on the button,
which gets you that alert,
only then you can switch
directly to alert.
Okay, So let's say I have this
iframe and I have a button in here.
If I click on that button
and it gives me that pop up,
only then you can switch to that alert.
But here we have to switch back
and then click to that button.
Okay.
All right.
Any other questions, guys, there?
Okay, guys, give me one second.
I'll be right back.
Okay?
Okay.
I'm going to scream out like that.
Okay? Not yet.
Not yet. Okay.
We got what is this, six class?
We've got five more classes.
Probably After that, we'll see.
Okay, guys.
All right, let's continue.
Okay.
How to move?
Okay, so if you have a frame
inside, the frame
and you moved to
so you have a parent frame
and then you have a child's frame, right?
So if you are inside the child's frame
and what you have to do, you have to move,
you have to switch to the parent first
and then you have to go to the child.
And if you want to move back,
what you want to do,
you can do the exact same thing in here.
Okay, So let's say the parent child
has an index of zero and you'd
child frame.
It has it has a index of one.
Okay.
So you move from zero, you move to
zero first, then you move to one.
And then if you want to go back,
you just switch to zero.
Okay?
Is that clear? Guys?
Any questions?
So it all depends on how it's structured.
Okay. So let's say
if you have a zero and you
have five different frames inside it,
then you can jump from 0 to 5.
Or if you have a grandparent,
parent, child, grandchild,
then you won't be able to switch it
right away.
Okay, So you have to switch one by.
So it all depends on hierarchy
of the frames.
No, we won't be
we won't be dealing with nested frames.
And I don't think
even when you start working guys,
you won't be dealing with nested frames.
Okay?
The maximum amount of frames
that the maximum amount
nested frames you will see is one
you were going to have one frame
and you might have another frame inside
that frame.
That's it. Guys.
You want have like five different frames
inside each other.
Okay,
So that doesn't really make sense to build
actually.
All right. Okay, guys.
So now let's continue.
So this was one of the ways
of how to handle the frame, right?
So let's go ahead and do the second way
of handling the frame and switching
to a frame by name or IP.
Okay.
So let me go back
here and let's take a look
in here, guys.
So this is my frame, right?
So this is my frame.
What kind of attributes
do I have right now for this?
I frame
you have
we have name, right?
And we also have the source,
right So we used the indexing.
So now what I can do in here,
I can use the name value to identify
this frame, because
in here,
the second way of handling the frame
we set, we, we switch it by name or I.D.
Okay.
So if you look inside of frame right now
or if you look into the other frames
and you see name or I.D.,
you can grab those values
and you can switch to that.
I frame by those values.
Okay.
So right now what I am going to do here,
I'm going to copy this name value.
Okay? Go back.
And what I will do, I will switch
back to the same eye frame.
But this time
I'm going to be using the other method
which accepts the string value
for the name or item.
Okay, so what?
I will do a paste that in here.
Okay.
And then what I'm going to do and here I'm
going to copy this web element, right?
Because we already that
and we identified that element.
And then what I will do, I will simply
send something else in here.
So let's just put syntax.
It's not like there's not like this
syntax.
That's okay.
So now, guys, what we do in here,
we switch to the frame by index.
Well, identify that text box, we
send some text in there,
we switch back
and we don't need this, right?
Because if we click on it,
our focus is going to be gone
and we switch back to default.
Now we're switching back to that frame
but in a different way.
And then we are inputting
some different text in here as well.
Okay, So run this and see
what's going to happen.
Name and ID?
Yes, they're both reliable when it comes
frames.
Okay, What happened, guys?
So right now
we enter two different texts in here,
so we should probably delete
the first one.
Right? So we already had that text.
We switched back to the main page
and we switched back to the frame
and we just continued adding more text.
Right? So it added both
text right now.
So before we
add any text, after the first one,
what we want to do,
we want to clear it first.
Right?
Okay, so clear it first and now
let me run this and see
if we just have second
text right?
There we go.
So we had the first one
switching back and forth inside the frame.
And then what we do
is we clear the first text that we entered
and now we only have the second text.
Okay, Any questions, guys?
Any questions?
How to handle the frames
and how to switch by index or by name.
All right, you guys
okay?
No questions. Good.
So let me see.
Okay, so now what I want to do,
I want to switch to that exact
frame by the Web element.
Okay?
So that means whenever I want to switch
to a frame and I use this method,
what do I need to pass
inside the parameter It's guys.
So whenever I'm switching to a frame.
Okay, so in this case,
if I'm switching by web element.
What do I have to pass in here
at two big values in here?
Anything else, guys?
Name of the frame.
We just press that in here right?
The tag. Okay.
The web element.
Right, guys?
So whenever we identify and I frame
right, whenever we identify the frame,
first of all,
I frame is what I frame
is a web element as well.
Right?
So it has these attributes in here.
It has an IV frame tag.
So what we can do, we can identify this
as all other elements, right?
You can write a next path, you can write
a CSR, you can find it by name.
Okay?
So whenever you do that,
what are you getting in return?
You getting a web element variable, right?
As we've done in textbooks.
This is a web element, right?
So you can you can find that frame
exactly
the same way how we did it for textbooks,
because I have frames our web
elements on the web page as well.
Okay.
So what I will do,
I want to write a next for syllabus.
Okay.
So we know that this is the frame
that I'm looking for right now.
So what I am going to do
is I'm going to start writing my stuff.
How would I start my relative X
path in here?
Guys?
Double slash. Okay, double slash.
I frame right,
I have frame and then square brackets
I want to use the source attribute is it
possible guys.
Okay, so we can do that. Right?
Source
is equal to
we have this slash demo dot page send out.
All right. There we go.
So it's one of one
that means that I iframe is unique
and what I am going to do, I copy this
and I will store this inside the web
element.
Right.
And say that this is a frame.
Frame element is equal to driver,
but find element by X path, right?
So we have an X path in here.
So now
what I need to do,
I need to simply switch to that frame.
Right. So here driver,
switch to the frame.
So this time it's going to be a web
element.
Okay, so what we need to pass in here
a web element object.
Okay, So here
what I'm simply going to pass is
frame element that we just identified.
And now what I'm going to do
is clear this and I will
enter some different
text things here. Okay.
So let's run this and see
if we have the last text.
And there we go.
Yep, I did.
I think I did clear the previous text,
but what is going on?
So there is something going on.
It says no such element exception.
So it can't find our X5.
Why guys,
what is the issue in here?
We need to switch back to the default
and then switch back to the frame.
Right. Exactly.
So after we entered these right,
what we need to do,
we need to switch back
to the default content
and then it's going to
I'm going to be able to
I identify this element,
switch back to that frame,
clear the text, and then enter our
new text right. So
we're in
a move line.
Yeah, it will.
If you don't switch the default content
and you remove line 31,
is that what you meant?
Yes, it will work.
You will just identify this element,
I mean this frame, right.
But you're not performing any actions
and then what you are doing,
you are just
what's called you
clearing that textbox again and you are
entering a new text into.
All right, guys,
any questions on how to handle alerts,
how to handle the frames
online?
31 Yes, I use the frame element variable
that I created online.
30 Okay,
so this is how I identified that frame,
because the frame is the web
element as well,
right?
Let me find that.
Let me find the X path again.
Okay, So the X path, we go
double slash
and we start with the eye frame.
Okay?
And start with the eye frame.
So now square brackets, right?
I want to use the source
attribute in here.
So add
as our C is equal to single quotes
and do
slash demo that HTML.
Okay,
you take this value,
you just put it in here
and it should work.
Yes. Switching back
and forth inside the frames,
it requires a little more attention. Okay.
So let me actually put it in here. Okay.
So in alerts, guys, how do we switch?
So how do we switch to an alert
and how do we switch back guys?
So in alerts, so we manually
switch to the to an alert
and automatically switch
back to the main page right?
So switch
manually
to alert and
automatically back.
Right?
And in frames guys
in frames, we switch it manually, right?
We switch to an to a frame manually
and we switch back to the main page
manually as well.
Right?
So manually to frame
and switch
manually
back to the
main page.
Okay.
All right.
Amber of selenium. Okay,
good.
Selenium is easy, guys. Okay.
So this is an easy subject that I
that I chose.
Okay.
Java is really,
really difficult to explain.
Okay.
So let me put one more interview question
for you guys.
Okay.
So sometimes in the interview,
you get to ask how you handle the alerts.
Okay, So this is an interview question.
How do you handle
alerts in selenium?
Guys?
Any guesses?
How do we handle alerts in selenium?
How would you answered this question?
I'm your interviewer
I'm asking you this question.
How would you
how do you handle alerts in selenium?
Switch to OC?
What else?
By using alert interface.
So if you say that that is enough.
OC So when you when your interviewer
is a technical person
and they're asking you how do you handle
alerts in selenium, you can just tell them
I'm handling alerts
by using alert interface, okay?
And you can actually ask them if they want
more information or if they want
if they want to know on methods
that I can use, Then
if they say yes, then you can go ahead
and start telling them why
we're going to be switching to that alert
and then we can accept,
accept, dismiss, get text or send keys.
Okay.
You deserve a shot now. Yeah.
There you go.
Okay, so with handle
alerts
by using alerts interface.
So if we go back here, where is alerts?
So let me actually open this up.
So if I open up this alert guys
alert interface so you can only see
there is four different methods in here
and that set, there's
nothing else in here.
Okay, So just open
the declaration for alert interface
and you can see that there's this maze.
There is, except there's get text
and there is send
methods in here
and there's no other methods whatsoever.
And okay.
Any questions, guys?
No questions.
Okay. So let me see
what I
have here.
Okay, guys.
Seems like that's what I have for today.
And let's get let's get your homework.
Okay. So
get you some tasks
in here.
Okay, guys.
So there's two tasks for you to complete.
Okay, So what I want you to do here,
let me copy this.
I think we already have this, right?
So there we go.
So navigate to this URL.
Navigate to this URL.
So what I want you to do, guys,
I want you to verify
this header is displayed.
Okay.
Was it that one?
Let's see.
I think they changed it, but it's fine.
So what I want you to do guys,
I want you to
verify that this logo is displayed.
Only this one.
Okay?
There's two different law,
two same logos in here.
So what I want you to do guys.
I want you to verify
the one on the left that is displayed.
Okay?
And then what I want you to do,
I want you to verify said to enable
the enroll today
button in here is enabled.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys?
Any questions on that task?
Okay, good.
So now the second
one is let me open this up
here.
Okay.
So now, guys, what I want you to do,
I want you to click on this,
handle this alert.
Okay?
Click on this one and handle this alert.
And then you click on this one.
Enter
some text in here and you click, okay.
Okay.
So click on each button
and handle the alert accordingly.
Okay?
Is that clear, guys?
Any questions on the homework?
Let me send it and the course
announcements, the last one.
So navigate to this website.
I want you to click each button in here
and handle the alert accordingly.
Okay, So click the first one,
handle this alert, click
the second one, handle this one as well,
and then click the third
one handle one as well.
Okay.
All right.
Any other questions, guys?
If everything is good and clear,
guys, I already posted in the course
announcements.
Okay, guys, the GitHub, your roles.
Let me see
one second
section
on this.
There go
this is the URL where
you could just pull the code and clone
everything.
Okay.
All right, guys.
No questions.
All good. So please practice.
Guys, please finish the homework
and please practice the java.
So next class, guys,
we will be dealing with windows.
With different windows
with different tabs.
Okay, guys.
So we will be manipulating
with different tabs and multiple windows.
And we also be covering
we also be covering the weights.
Okay, So there are different weights
other than this thread that's sleep.
So we will be covering
those weights as well.
Okay.
All right, guys.
No questions. Good.
So please
practice and I will see you next week.
Okay, guys,
have a good night, everyone, and stay safe
by everybody.