It's not going to work.
But the purpose of good
is to make your life easier, right?
So I would recommend
that it's very important
that you get a very deep inside
of how special it truly works.
Okay.
So let's begin out today's session.
And let me just give you a scenario.
So here is our scenario.
We are working in a company
and what happens
is that
one day we get an email from our Lee.
He says that, okay,
you need to build a car.
That's it.
Build a car.
This is the plan?
No, nothing like that.
Okay, so in while discussing it,
we won't be focusing
on any kind of framework or any stuff
you'll be just focusing on.
So don't worry about that.
It's only going to get.
Okay, so now I want to build a car.
What I would do simply go to my encourage,
first of all.
Now, that's not a problem.
Start building it right away.
So let's open up
a new project,
a new job project.
Get that?
Yes. You guys should follow.
Open up a new project window.
Just name it.
It's fashion or whatever you want to.
Okay.
Let me know once you are done
with the creation of the project.
Okay,
so now let's create a new class over here.
Let's animate car basics.
So I have up last name car business.
So what are the few basic
things that I can have
in this part of the class?
My car is going to have a color, right?
It's going to have
engine.
It will have doors
number.
So let's have color in gender and numbers.
These are the four things that I have in
here.
Let's go to our main
and let's say the basic structure.
So this point.
Do you guys think that I should
now make a comment of my good.
But what about the rest of you?
Do you guys think that
I should make a comment
public?
So all the time, it's very important
to build this sense
of knowing that
when you should commit people,
you should not make unnecessary comments,
because that's going to create a lot of I
this guy, which is not desired.
You should not have massive comments
like the comments which serve no purpose.
It's very important to develop this sense
in you guys
and I'm going to help you build that.
Okay.
So right now
what I see is that I need to build a car
and I have some basic structure available.
I have one class in which
there is like basics of the car
which are going to be there.
And I have a mean
the next of the stuff that I will be
building is going to change. Like
I can give it any number,
any color and stuff like that,
which I have not decided yet.
So I'm sure about one thing
that these two things,
the main and the car business,
they are going to stay here.
So what do you guys think now?
Should I make a commit
of this particular code
at this point?
Okay.
I'm going to repeat again.
I think I should
I should make a comment. Why?
Okay.
So we are to develop a car, right?
We are to develop a car.
And we know that our car is going to have
color and gender number.
Right.
These are some of the constants
that are going to be there.
We know this
and we know
that we will be creating
an object of the last car.
We are sure about this.
This stuff.
I'm sure that
this stuff is going to be here in my code.
The rest of the things that I will be
writing down, like car color,
assigning it the color,
assigning it
the number, assigning it in the number.
I have not decided it yet.
And it can change over to die
in my decision.
Like I may see that, okay,
the car is going to be red
because in the requirements,
if I show you guys,
I was not given
any particular requirement.
Right. It was just build the car.
It did not tell me that.
What kind of cars you should build.
So I have developed a basic structure.
It's good practice to commit
my basic structure so that at least it
remains sealed.
And if anyone wants to see my progress,
you can see that.
Okay.
I have started
working on the basic structure
and the rest of the stuff
is still going to be in the pipeline.
Now, does it make sense?
Okay.
So should I be making a comment right now?
Okay, So in order to make a comment,
I simply open up my
explorer.
I go to this particular location
where my files are,
and I'll simply say,
get back here.
Okay, guys,
to know what I want to do is
I want to ignore the dot idea file.
And I also want to ignore the out file
that is going to be there.
So what we will do.
Okay, the command is touch dot,
get ignore.
Okay,
it created a dot.
Get ignored file.
I'll open up this file
and I'll enter in here
slash dot idea and slash out.
The alcohol out file is not yet here,
but it will be here in the future.
I know that.
And I don't want it to be tracked.
So I just added the both names in here.
Now, to save this file,
let me know when you guys have done this.
Ignore file and enter these two
files.
Okay, so
I'll say get in it to initialize
my repository, have it initialized,
and then I'd say get status
update.
So it's only going to create an SRT email
and dot it ignore.
I'm good enough with that.
That said, get add dot
and get commit dashcam. Now
I'm not going to name my commits
random like we used to do before.
I'm going to try to name them
as much descriptive as they can be.
So what do you guys that just that
I should name this part of the comment.
It should be descriptive enough
so that if anyone reads it, it knows that
what is in there?
No, you'll be done.
That's not something
that we are going to name it.
No more Hammer
Bar one.
No, it's not
a gain of defining
part.
Last the basics of body
we ignored in text
these two files dot idea and out of it.
So I'm going to name it.
The basic structure of our is ready
Yeah without any features.
So the more description
we can add, the more good
it is.
Okay.
There you go.
And now let me see if I do with.
It shows me
the basic structure of it is ready
without any features
and my head is pointing towards it.
Are we all good
till this one?
No, I don't.
I don't know why we do it. The message.
I think that it's if it's not a done.
Okay, great.
So let me just a bit my simulation
over here.
What we did is
we have key files
that ignore SIRC.
Good.
Ignore there.
And we have as far see
what's
going on. We are.
Just wait a moment. I'll go back.
So we didn't get at Dot in which
we placed
all the files in the staging area
and we made up comments
this.
Okay, so there you go. Here is a terminal.
You want to have a look at it?
What do I do if I get decode
this?
You need to write type in Q
It will get you up.
Rescue and press enter.
Okay. Guys are good.
All of us.
Okay, great.
Now let's start
building that car.
So let's say the car color is red.
Oh, and its engine is
that same. And
we also have the number of doors.
Let's make them to for now
and let's have the number.
Okay.
So these are the features
that are assigned to this particular car.
And then I said, okay, let's have a look.
How does it look?
So system dot out-of-print album
card, dog color
or display, whatever there is.
So let's assume that after writing down
this whole cord,
I pressed the play button
and it shows me my car,
which I just developed.
I can see it visually.
I'm giving you guys one minute
to reach this point
and then you'll be proceeding together
here.
You about that
and I'll give you all good.
So when I press this button,
let's assume that we are able
to see the car that we just need.
And it's a beautiful red
car, two doors and,
you know, it's pretty awesome.
But I got one eye contact.
Okay?
I don't want this red car.
Maybe the blue car is going to look better
like, no, I'm
not decisive enough right now.
So I want to make some changes in here.
But I don't want to lose this goal,
which I have already written.
So what do you guys suggest?
What should I do?
I don't want to lose this good.
And I want to make some changes in.
Okay, so
you guys are saying that committed right?
Okay.
The problem that the commit is going to be
that this particular car
is going to be during the coming history
and it's going to be a redundant commit.
If I plan on changing the car
and making a new one, it's
going to be redundant.
Coming.
So I cannot make a commitment because
I have I'm not finalized with my decision.
So that's the building of the Senate
that whenever we make a commit,
we should be final,
we should be final with our decision
that, okay,
this is what we actually want to happen.
Use always understand
what you need to change and know.
Yes, exactly. My
right that
that was obvious right of you.
So what we can do and get a very
beautiful feature we can use thing.
What is that. Let me give you a look.
So what we did,
we made some changes in our SRT, right?
I'm representing
those changes of the vehicle.
We made those changes.
And then what we want to do
is we want to redo them.
So what are we going to do?
We are going to run
the command, get stashed.
These do not run it right now.
We are going to run.
The command gives Dash
along with a message.
And what it is going to do
is it's going to pick up
our changes
and it is going to place them
inside of the station area.
And along with that, it's
going to revert the condition
of the working
that the same as the one in the wrap.
So it's going to pick up this horsepower
from the repo and it's going to place it
over here and it's going to just,
you know, the media.
So this is what's going to happen is
this one is a little clear to all of you.
Okay, one more time, I'll great.
No problem.
Okay.
Okay, guys, let's have a look at that.
I want what I did is,
was I made some changes
and the ICRC right.
I made some changes in here.
Do you guys agree with that?
And those changes? I can see that I added
the features of the car.
These are the changes that I need.
But I'm not sure that
whether I want to have this car or not,
maybe I want a blue car
or maybe I want to be in car.
I don't know about that right now.
So now I can make changes
and not lose the previous changes.
What I can do is I can use get staff.
It's going to pick up the changes
and it's going to place it in a stash
inside the target folder.
Along with that, what will happen
with the working type?
The working party is going to be reverted
to the speed
of the last commit in the rapport.
So it's going to pick up the source file
from the wrap group
and it's going to replace it in here
like this. Yes.
Why is if you don't need that,
I know we may need that in the future.
Maybe in future.
I don't like the blue car and
I want the right kind of game back then.
What?
I don't want to lose that cool.
Okay,
so is the workflow clear to all of you?
Because this is the only thing
regarding the stuff.
And if you have to eat about this,
we are good with session.
That's it.
This is how staffing works
and newbie.
Thank you.
You've got the answer
yes now.
Okay, so I'm going to do it.
I'll just move it back
and we will do this again
along with the time out.
Okay, guys.
So this is the current condition
of my working directory, right?
The SRT, you can
read means that I have made some changes.
What are those changes?
These are the candidates.
So let's open up the terminal.
Okay.
If I want to stack them, I want to bring
those changes in the starting area.
Which command should I use?
Get dash, dash and
now name it.
Red car.
Okay.
Run this command only on your terminal
and let me know
once you are done with that.
Okay.
When I ran this command, what happened?
Okay, so this is going to move
to the stacking area
and what is going to happen to our working
directory?
It's going to pick up the SRT file
from the latest commit
and it's going to bring it back
to the working directory.
So now let's open up our intelligent
and see that
whether this is the scenario or not.
Okay, so was this our first time in
the latest test?
Was this the latest coming?
So this is how it actually works.
So yes, that's
the upgrade that that literally happened,
that's there.
No way it's going to be there.
We'll discuss that knowing, okay,
now let's start this.
Let's start building our
jealously guard, basically.
Yes, sure. I'm going to share it
because we know
you can have it in the chat.
Okay.
So let's start building our next car.
And that would be the blue car corridor.
Color is equal to, let's say, blue.
This time,
dot number is equal
to let's enter the engine.
Engine is equal to
odd doors.
Let's make it a model car this time
because, you know,
I just wanted to see that.
How does a two car, a two door car
look and how does a full door car look?
I wanted to do a comparison
before I send the car to my team.
So I'm just, you know, making changes now
and car dot what's left?
Engine color, door number, number.
Let's go with the number
38 and let's
find this car.
Okay.
Now, what I did, I had the belly button
and it showed me,
let's say, the blue car in front of me,
which has more doors, this particular
engine and blue color and the number 80.
And I visualized this also.
And I said, okay, looks pretty good,
but how about if I build
another car, which is green in color,
but I don't want to lose this one?
Also, I don't want to lose this blue car.
Also, maybe at the end I'll make
a decision that let's keep the blue car
and send it to the team that,
hey, this is the car that I built.
So what I can do, I can start this.
All right.
Okay.
Let's have a look first at the floor.
So these are the
changes now we made. Okay,
This blue changes
of the blue car.
Let's open up our terminal
and let's run the command jets.
Dash, dash and blue car.
Let's press enter.
So it's going to
pick up the blue car,
not picking it up,
and it's going to put it in this dash.
And what is going to happen to the working
directory?
How many guys what is going to happen
to this particular file?
It will bring back this file
to the same state
as in the latest coming latest coming.
So deliveries come because this particular
file, it's going to bring it back
and it's going to replace.
So let me open up my terminal
and there you.
Okay.
Now let's start building our next car,
which is going to be color.
So car door
color is equal to, let's say, green.
And my dot number is equal to
let's say
car door engine
is equal to
this one
on those links to please.
So this car has three doors
you'll be allowed to that.
Okay.
After making of this car,
I'm going to again
hit the play button
and I'll let you have a look at it.
Okay.
So the green car also looks good, but
I like the blue one.
Now, what should I do?
Okay,
so first let's make the changes.
So this is the state of our working date
night.
We have that we got in here
right now.
We have a green guard in here.
I want this blue car back.
I don't like this green car.
Yes, I tell you.
All right, so what we are going to do,
we are going to start this one
and bring the blue one back.
This is what we are going to do.
So I'll open up my terminal, get dash
dashcam, green car.
Okay.
I have one question over here
for all of you.
Why don't I just delete the green car?
We might want it later. Yes. Perfect.
Good. Yes.
I'm not decisive enough.
My decision to change randomly,
you know, depends upon my luck.
It's been staff dash and green car.
Okay.
When I ran this command, it was picked up
and brought to this dash
for the standard two green.
Okay.
And what will happen
to my working directory?
What's going to happen in here?
Yes, it will bring the file.
But the problem to this,
it will bring the file back
from the apple.
Okay.
So very good.
Now, what I want to do,
I want to bring this blue car here
in my
working directory.
I want to do this operation.
But before I actually do this,
I want to have a look at all
the items that I have in my stack.
How do we do that?
We have a matter for that. It's that
list.
Now. So I'm going to run this demand.
It's dash list.
So what do we see?
Red car, blue car,
green car.
And along with that
we see the numbers 210.
So basically it's like just a cylinder
in which we are placing the colors
and it's piling them
on one upon the other.
Okay.
Now I want to bring back
which number of index
do I want to bring back?
Yes, I'm sorry,
most indexing the blue one.
So what's the index of the blue one?
Let's have a look.
That's the one.
So I'll run the command,
get dash, apply one.
And what will happen?
It's going to
bring this particular dash into our work.
Exactly.
And it's also going to remain in there
in the stash.
It's not going to get deleted
from over there.
That is important.
Okay.
It's going to be in here also.
Okay. So now let's do this.
Yes, Dash,
apply one
very.
Okay.
So let me know what you guys
all have done to this point.
Any questions that we have asked me
and then we'll proceed
to show your terminology. Yes, sure.
There's my terminal.
Jimmy, that dash
that and red car.
Jimmy, you need to share the terminal
screenshot and share even the support.
There's going to be someone
who is going to help you out.
No, you're out.
There are no changes yet in the wrap.
Whatever is done is actually I tell you
what is happening behind the scenes.
I hear you on the visualization.
It's not exactly what happens,
but very close approximation to
what is actually happening conceptually,
the message should be defined unique.
When we start.
Obviously, you will have to make sure that
you make those messages unique enough.
You can also,
I guess, have the same messages.
It's not going to be a problem.
I keep getting green
and that maybe
because Silva you are making the mistake
on the next thing.
Yes, it did.
You guys can see whether the changes
are being reflected
right? Yes.
Silva, the problem obviously,
your problem is that when you ran
the command with static line,
you did not mention anything.
It it just went empty.
So it automatically
applied the green card.
And now you are trying
to apply out of this that.
It won't work like this.
Why assure you you understand that?
As we pointed out,
you have made some mistakes.
That's dash and green car.
Yeah.
When you sent it Silva to index change.
Right
then let's do change.
So you need to now
make sure that you are entering the right
index.
Okay, guys.
So let's proceed forward. I give you.
I think it's set up now.
Let's proceed forward.
Okay.
So after having this blue car, I had been
again chain might see certain that never.
I want direct contact look perfectly fine.
And next when you add another
staff and
this is going to decrease
increase of the like if it was two
it will become three.
Okay so I want the red card.
So what do you guys suggest I should do?
The first one is you.
Okay, so I'll have to again start the blue
and then get the red one.
So this is how it works, right?
No, I cannot do the bits stuff
at this point.
Let me show you this.
I tried to stress applied mustache
without that, this previous one,
it's going to give me an error.
Let me come
get stuff.
Let's not do this.
Let's. Let's have a loop.
Okay.
It has green card, blue car and red car.
Nice. Are you with me on this?
I really need your attention over here
because this is an important concept.
Okay, so I'll give you the brief again.
What I don't want to do right now is
I want the red car
in my working directly.
So what are we going to do?
First of all, we are going to do
is that we are not going
to start these changes
and use this command good stack of life.
So what do you think I should do?
Get stash apply
and what should be the number
index too?
It should be do because the red car
I want to recognize it should be do.
Okay.
So now before I run this,
I'm going to show you what will happen.
This is going to pick this one.
It's going to bring it in here.
And when it's going to say, okay,
I'm bringing in red car. But
when I took the red car, only
this new car was not here.
Instead,
it was at this table like empty.
It was actually
on the apple.
It was at this stage,
but now it has some other.
Cool. So what should I do?
I'm not going to allow you to do this.
So this is very intelligent.
It will say not. Oh no,
let's see.
Okay, so what do we see on here?
It says Your local changes
to the following files
will be overridden by the merge list.
Commit your changes
or stash them before you apply them.
So there is time that, hey,
I will not allow you to do this
either
commit the previous changes or stack them.
There's no other option.
So what do you suggest? What should we do?
We should ask them or commit them.
Sets them
because I don't want to commit it.
Right.
So simply I would say get that back and
you are to
assignment.
I'll I'll explain that.
Okay.
So we that's the blue car and
what will happen does this is interesting
that's going to pick up this new car
going to place
it in here.
Yes. Nicole.
And it will return the working directory
back to the state of the last commit.
Yes, ma'am.
Even though they are duplicate,
it is not going to take care for that.
It will say that. Okay, that's fine.
I'm going to create new stuff
that the same thing is going to happen.
Even if you do blue car. Yes.
And with no difference
because we are not decisive enough.
That's
why we are doing this to the process.
Okay, guys,
let me know when you're done on this one.
So then I will proceed.
Okay.
Now, if I open up my intelligent,
I would take this back to
where it was.
So I want the red car
here.
So but that I'll do
this dash
less because I don't remember this index.
It was So what is the index now?
Red car is on three sides.
It gets that applied three.
So there you go.
The red car is here in front of.
Okay, Now,
I haven't made up my mind and I say, okay,
this is the car that looks perfect
out of all the other cars.
And this one, I'm
going to send it in the commit
so that it's finalized.
No, Simon, we cannot do it.
We have to smash it.
That's how stacking works.
So you made a mistake, right?
That's why
that's why you are getting the green more
coming, guys.
So I have made up my mind and I say that
I want this garden out
to be in the apple in the coming.
So what should I do?
Simply get at not
and then get come it
so let's make this come
get at dot
get comment dash
am and the message should be
the red car is ready for the trial
okay guys
so let me know
once you are done till this point.
And then we have a very interesting
I have
Angelica at the moment.
Your display could just have seemed
better.
Almost like if they are smaller,
they look exactly So
let us go ask them.
And they have not.
And good come.
It doesn't.
It's just testing stores the snapshot.
Okay, guys, I need your attention now.
I want you guys to read it for me.
Stashing
stores, the snapshot of your current file
changes in a separate container
and. Reverse the condition
of your working daily
to the
last comment.
Okay, so this is what we with witness
right now,
all of us.
Okay, great.
Get stuff
dashcam
message.
Just dash the changes
that you have made
and the next command that we have is
get attached to this.
The to view the changes,
to view the statues
and get
that applied
index
to apply
a certain steps.
Okay.
So this is an important lesson
that you like to discuss already.
If you have a statute applied
and you want to
apply any previous steps,
what do you do?
So I want you guys
to answer this question. No,
you must stash it first and then
apply the previous steps.
Number two,
you can commit it or
and then apply the steps.
Okay, We have such a scenario.
Then we
can choose from the following
depending upon the scenario is number one.
Either we must dash it first
and then apply the previous dash.
We have discussed this.
Now you write,
we have discussed the scenario number one,
but we have not discussed
the scenario number two right now.
We will be discussing that now,
the group one adding those dash.
Yes, 13. Right. We'll keep on doing that.
Okay, guys, to this one,
everything that we have discussed,
is it clear to all of you, okay,
now we are diving into this scenario
number two.
I really want you guys to
draw out your hats
because this is something which,
if you understood,
it's going to make your life very,
very easy, as in for doing it.
Okay, so let's discuss
now. I
have made the command of the right car.
Right?
I've done that.
What is now, at this point
in time, my boss just called me
and he said, Hey, I don't like this car.
Send me the green one.
Then what?
Well, my, you, we are an employer.
Okay, so that do the work.
Okay, so
I should sing that then.
In your stance,
Muhammad is saying start the game.
And one last thing you started
and get the car that he likes.
Okay, So tell me procedurally,
what is the first step that I should do?
We will do it on the simulation.
What should be my first step?
Let's come out of that run
at the first time.
Okay.
You guys are saying stuff this
so I get all these dashes.
Okay, so you guys are saying,
okay, do one more thing.
Start the red car.
Okay, So first,
let's go ahead with those people
who say starts the red car.
Okay.
Let's see that the first test,
the red car, it's going to pick it up.
It's going to place it in the
stacking area
and it's going to reverted back to the
red Will come in.
Right.
So it's not going to happen.
Let me show you that I do get stuff
that am
red car
that says no local changes to say
there you go it's not going to happen.
It's not going station.
Is that clear to all of you?
This concept.
Okay, so this
this is something we cannot do.
So what ordinary options.
Okay must apply saying apply
the new one directly.
Don't worry, man.
Just apply anymore whatever you want.
Okay, so are you going to do.
Let's discuss this scenario.
Let it go here
of not.
I get this.
Okay.
So I set things desolate
and have empty all the options.
No, I said that's not possible.
Okay, so the only option that we have,
let's discuss that.
The only option that we have is
to apply the staff directive.
We have no other option.
Okay, So let's have a look.
What will happen
if we apply the staff directly.
Okay, guys,
we are going to have a look at that.
But before we actually move
to the terminal and do that, first,
let's realize it conceptually.
So when I'm going to do stack, apply
this green one,
it's going to bring pick up
this green car.
Then to bring it in here
at this point is going to say, okay, now
I have
a conflict.
We need to understand that.
Why is this conflict upgraded?
No, it's allowed,
but there will be a conflict.
And this is important.
All the conflicts,
you guys will be facing a lot of conflicts
and we'll be working on it.
And you should understand that.
Why the conflict occurs.
So I'm going to take you
now into the understanding
of when does a conflict actually occurs.
Okay.
So let's first discuss that,
how a conflict occurs.
So let me
create the files of
all of you guys.
Are you with me?
Everyone, please
leave everything you are doing
and just be absolute
concentration over here.
This is so
this was the code that was there in my
first Come in.
Remember, this is the code that we had
in our first time
that we made some changes
and we added a car,
let's say we added the red car
after that.
What we did with that direct car right,
we started.
So what is going to happen?
It's going to make the changes
and it's going to start them.
So it created another file
with the red car
and reverted
the condition of this
particular file to the one
which is the last coming
this this understood to everyone
that this is what happened.
We saw that for you. Right.
Okay.
Now what what is one thing that we know
about it,
that it is very,
very vigilant about history.
Right.
So when get made the changes
that did it, remember
that what your file looked like it.
Remember that it had no lines
present on eight, nine, ten, 11.
And it knew that whenever you reapply
I just entered these line on the line
number eight, nine, ten, 11.
But remember that, okay, now what we did,
we made the green car
and we let's say green car,
some CC center here
before we made green.
And the number here like this.
Oh, we made the green car in this file
and then we started again.
So actually we brought these changes
and it created
another file.
Just remember that
when you start this particular stash
online, number eight, nine, ten, 11,
there was nothing.
And whenever you will restart it,
it will simply put these lines
on the respective line numbers.
Is that understood?
Okay, Now what we did,
we applied this particular
the red one
like this
and we made a comment of it.
This is what we did right.
We made the comment of this car.
Now we are trying
to bring back our green car.
So when we will do the force applied
like this and the diagram
that we were discussing,
this is going to say, hey,
when you created this stuff
online, number eight, nine, ten, 11, 12,
there was nothing.
But now there is something.
I'm confused
what to do, where to let these lines
logical, right?
It makes sense.
So that's why a conflict
is going to arise.
There is a conflict
between dual codes that we have.
Do you guys all understand that
why a conflict is occurring? Yes.
You have be done.
So that's the leader I got you for zero.
Okay.
I'm at the same that bleed the red car
in full and just simply statute again.
What do you guys think with it?
Would it work
if I believe that going forward statute
we are
going to try that, but not right now?
Exactly. We will not do it.
If it's a complex code, obviously,
we are not going to do it.
Yeah, we can delete the code.
But the problem is
that we already have that in the comment.
So give is not going to
maybe allow us to statute apply to static.
We see that there are changes
that we need to commit mustache.
Remember,
this is what's going to happen.
Okay. So now we are having a conflict.
Let's try to see that how it happens.
Get statute list.
Okay.
If I want to apply the green car,
what index am I going to use? Now?
Let's see. We cannot do that.
So get that applied.
One time.
But no one knows
that these line members are conflicting.
Decide which one do you want to keep
and look how intelligent it is.
This line was the input.
What good right
system talk out of the pendulum car.
What color this one thing.
So it said that okay,
this is the same for good
So you do not need to change this one.
Only the conflicts just changed them.
Okay,
we can read the message updated screen.
This one is the one that we had
in the comment and staff changes.
This is the one code
that we are applying from the start.
Now it's our decision.
Which code do you do we want to keep?
So what do you guys suggest?
Which code should I keep?
The green one.
So I am going to delete the previous one
and I'm going to keep
the green code.
So my green dot is there.
And if I show you on the simulation
that what will happen,
we must them to both of them.
And now
we created a new code.
Okay, now
get is going to ask us to commit
that I'll make these changes immediately.
This is not going to allow us
to do anything else to say that
okay, now permitted.
So what you can do is get add dog,
get commit
dash and here is your car.
Now, don't ask me to make sense
and we can literally put emojis in there.
Wow, that's awesome.
I so it's going to go in there
and then it's going to go
and I you comment. Yes.
Yes. That it
your guitar
says that
you do not get the conflict message.
What message did you get?
You'll be done. No message at all.
It allowed you to clarify that
that's not possible.
You must have skipped some steps.
Can you show me your eye
so you mean to say that it literally
allowed you and it like
showed me a and like,
how is that possible? Even
That's impossible.
Oh, okay.
So you'll be top.
That is because of the problem.
No, not the problem actually.
But that is
because when you were writing on the code,
your line numbers were not the exact same.
Okay?
That is because your line numbers
were not most probably
not same.
Yeah, that's why
so good actually works
on the line numbers.
Okay, so
get the member of the line number.
It remembers that.
Okay, let's have a look at the file.
If the members that online number seven
online the way this card dark color
is equal to read this
remember this
so when you are going to have another card
or color
on the same line member, it's
going to give you a slip.
Mostafa I don't get that.
What is the code?
Okay. Decode Is that okay?
Rescue It will help you exit
guys.
So what's the status?
What's the status?
You guys with me?
All of you.
I hope you like
this.
Does is like starting or literally
very easy, right?
It's fun.
Okay, Suppose you have done many changes
and you lost
track of color was in the radical.
How can you find out
lack of color?
I mean, what do you mean
by track of color?
You forgot the car color
that was in the report.
Okay, so that means asking that
you made many changes and you do not know,
right now
that what is there in your apple.
So how can you do that?
Guys, if we want to review that,
what's in the report?
And we have done a lot of changes.
No, no, not less.
Okay. So maybe the same.
Let me give you the question
that might be the same,
maybe the same that we have made
many changes in our file
and we forgot that
What was the code in our last commit?
How can we have a
look at the code in an coming
good color code?
In the last name,
we can elect the word it from there.
Apple right?
By using get stuff.
Okay.
I think you guys did not get the question.
Let me repeat the question.
So nobody is saying that
this was our file, this one.
Right.
And we started working on it.
We learned a lot.
We made some a lot of changes
and we forgot that, okay,
what are exclusivity looked like?
And we want looked at how it looked like,
how it came
do that.
You guys get the question now
get this bastard stage.
Let's go.
The difference.
And one other method that I told you guys.
What does that
If you want to remove
all the candies, what we can do.
Okay, so let's do this.
I mean, love you guys.
I need your attention for this, okay?
Because I got
you guys are not good enough.
Okay, let's do this again.
I'm going to repeat what can be last.
Okay, So here is the question.
Is everything in the Apple staging area
and the working directory, synchronize
now. One day I woke up,
I started making a lot of changes
in this file.
After that, I said, Oh,
I forgot what my file looked like.
I want to have a look at that.
I'll simply start this file
and this file is going to be recovered
from the report.
Simple as that.
I've a good.
Okay, great.
Yeah, I get that. I get that.
That's why I said that you guys need
to pay attention to my question.
Okay, So, um,
so we put in the stack
and take the coupon get.
Yeah, you can do that.
How? Yes.
I tried to of itself, guys,
I guess let's take a break.
Right.
It's 824 and Google is like,
I guess asking for break too.
Let's go for a break right now.
Let's refresh our mind and then we can
begin from way.
No, let's
take a break right now.
Minutes. This is 25.
Let's meet at
35, 48, 45 and see you guys at 830.
And then we'll begin.
Go and refresh ourself.
Have a cup of water, coffee, tea,
whatever relaxes you, and then we can
begin.
From this point,
I know, don't have to do it.
Don't do that.
Alex, you need to attend the session.
And my man obviously
you cannot do that either.
Yes, you can. Go ahead.
The first thing to notice
is that hammer, you have five
but most of the as the solution
and you just make your friend mix it
and you want to know
that what's what was in there
like you guys,
I need a break
for some special purpose that's
in my class at 840. So
let's have a look at a logs quickly.
So we have one, two, three.
Come with me.
Okay, so now what we are going to do,
we are going to discuss some use cases
that you might face while you are work
regarding stash and how you can use them.
And then moving on to some other examples
of stashing and that will be it.
Okay, so let's
imagine that you are working on a project
and let's say
let me open up my notes.
You are working on a project
and you immediately
need to make some changes.
And the
board that, okay, so this is area
that you are working on a project
and you immediately
need to make some changes in the code
and send it to GitHub. But
you have some
on final list or the word non, maybe
you're working on a project
and immediately
you need to make some changes in the code
and send it to backup.
But you have some non finalized changes
that you do not want to send.
So what will you do?
This is a use case where you can use DAS.
You will start with changes and that which
you do not want to make a commitment.
Get ignore for hard come on and
why don't you use give ignore
to ignore the class?
No you want
look look good ignore is going to
completely ignore that file
folder whatever is there
and it's going to be very hectic
that you go again to that file
and ignore it and ignore it.
Okay,
so let's say let's take this example.
Let's say that
this is the final comment that we made
and the goal is again, vanished.
Okay, There we go.
So this is the scenario right now.
Okay.
That's the scenario.
What happened now
that I started working on another feature,
I said that, okay,
the car is done and I can
I can do
is I can simply create a new class and
have lives.
I can start
working on headlights on the car.
So I created a new file. This new class
name headlights.
I was following me.
Okay, so we are discussing a scenario
and we are beginning with create
creating a new class headlights.
And you said that.
Okay, let's start working on that.
So I said spring power.
Spring
color and string.
What else do we have?
Signs maybe.
Okay, while I was working on this class,
my teammate immediately
called me and he said, Hey,
just quickly, do some changes in your main
could change the number to selling six
and send me the code.
Do I want to send him to headlights?
No, because this is not something
finalized.
I'm still working on it. Right.
I don't want to send him this.
And what I want to do is
I just want to make this change
and send him the call.
So what will I do?
Guide me status.
Okay, so I do. Good start.
I'll make the change then
after that, I'll make a commit.
Right.
Okay.
So these are the stuff that I'll follow.
I'll mention that
I would stash my changes.
Number two, I will make the changes
and the call that my read
I will committed
and send those changes
in the GitHub.
Now before I went up like the staff
again,
are these four steps still to everyone?
Any questions?
This is the procedure that we will be
following right.
Okay.
Now let's open up our simulation
and let's start working on that too.
I would create a file over here
that's name it
lights
and it is going to be inside BSR.
See, I wish I can.
Okay, so this is inside. That's awesome.
Just know that.
Let me change the color to it.
Okay.
So what I need to do, I need to stash it.
Then I can make changes over here
and then I can send the code.
Okay, So Mohammad is asking that, should
I start have like only my question to
you guys is in get
can we make us specific stuff?
What do you think?
Can you make a class specific stuff
or something specific spec note
We cannot do that.
If we stash, we stack all the key
and just because I'm working on it, please
return to the last comment.
That's a rule.
That's how works.
Okay, so let's do it and do this.
Get stash
diagram, analyze.
What is this a thing?
No local changes to see why that's.
No, it's not about running the code.
So here is a small thing
that I want to let you guys
know.
Get stash
in order
to work on untracked files
need to be stashed
using get stash
stash. You
okay, so
I'll tell you why
it is this little one,
this one, this statement.
This is how it will work.
Okay, For those of you
who's who gets working
and you guys know, get status,
and if it's on track of track
and I'm sure
that you are tracking it.
There you go.
And the quote, you added it already.
You are tracking it.
That's what
written.
Right.
But we did that
when you made our first dash.
Yeah, but
get status.
That's right. Right now.
Because this is a new class that we added.
We are not tracking it yet.
Okay.
So if it does you asked you
you added it, right?
So it means you are tracking it. It.
But those of you who added it,
I'm really sorry.
It will not work for you.
This is just something
that I wanted to show you guys.
This is additional information
that if you want to stash
and untracked file you need to use
get stats that you them are not for you.
I'll come to that
I think that you just have
another kind of problem.
Okay so if I want to stash my file,
what will I do?
Get stash that you
okay so now I'd stash we've got See that
now it's not here.
No, Jimmy,
they are saying they're exactly the same.
They're not different.
No return, right?
You only use that when you are stashing
and untracked file.
Okay.
Works.
Give me that, Mary.
Because of the version of good
that you are, you have.
Okay, you be time coming to that.
Okay,
so now listen
get to you.
What is the purpose of using this stuff?
You it is going to stash our unpacked
files.
If we are not tracking any file,
then it cannot be stash
by simply using get stash.
That's our
get stash that is used to stash
those files, which we are tracking.
Is that clear to all of you?
You'll be that
does that answer your question.
Okay.
Now coming to subconscious question
what will be the name?
Okay, so now
I don't know.
But the good stash that you.
I was unable to find how to put a message,
to be very honest with you.
So if I assure you, it will automatically,
automatically mimic.
So this saying yes,
that it created a stash of this one,
I am going to show you
that in the simulation.
Okay.
So now when we did get stash that you
this particular have came inside the stash
and what happened to our working
that was a pre
what happened to our representative.
It came back to the last time it
for a fact.
Now let's quickly make the changes
let me change the number to edit seven.
These are the changes that my
you know in time
we set to make out of the door floor
and change the ending
to this and all the stuff
Nicole I'll tell you that don't worry.
Okay guys we have made these changes
and now
let me highlight
those changes with color yellow.
Now we want to send this
changes to the repo.
What should I do?
Simply get that dot
and then make another comment right
right.
That's it.
You want to send these changes, right?
You want to send these changes to our Lee.
So why we should be stashing
okay so get and dot get
comment that him
there are the changes
that you asked me to make
please make up your mind
and please
do not make these kinds of comments
that you are actually pushing
in Europe as a people.
Now, I'm done with the changes
that you asked me and I want to, you know,
start working on the feature
that I was working, which is headlines.
So if I want to start
working on that feature,
what will I do?
I'll see it in the list and then get stats
list.
Okay, which is the one that I want.
Okay, the index is zero right?
So I simply do get that applied. Zero
does that
the one.
Okay. I have one question over here.
When I do this, will I have any conflict
of the third thing yet?
So maybe.
But those different classes
for heart is also thing yet.
So those of you who are saying yes,
what's the reason that you think
there will be further conflict, Alex,
that we'll look at?
What's the reason for the passing?
Do you guys see?
I mean, okay, so we made changes.
So what
get is going
to try to apply this attachment
policy, apply
It will try to apply it.
Will it be in conflict
with any other line of code?
Alex The question was there when I tried
to apply the statute, will there
be any conflict?
No, because.
Right. No. What I'm trying to apply this.
It is not in conflict
with any line of code.
It was all the code that we have,
it was a new class
and each test that complete whole class.
Right.
So there will be no conflict.
Let me show you this.
This dash apply zeal.
There you
start on.
You must have skipped something.
I cannot help you like this
without looking at the terminal.
Send it to the support.
Maybe
class
someone is going to have you help you.
Yes. Now it's a lot of feedback.
Okay, guys, so is this is this concept
you do all of you that way?
Are we not having a positive right
now? Yes.
You will do that.
Okay. So two questions
which I have to answer.
The first one is
what's the function of that hue?
So in order to crack the in order
to stack the files,
which we are not cracking,
we cannot stack them by simply
get stash for that and use good stats.
That hue
nozzle is that we are now
this that you
that you stash untracked files
the files which are we are not tracking.
Okay so what are untracked files
files that are not
in the staging area
not crack
by date
appears and red.
Is this clear to everyone
that what are on files?
Yes. And the working directory?
They are in the working directory. So.
And when I talk about crack
files,
what are they?
Right.
If you want to go back and unpack, file
with command,
we have one that
if you want to crack.
And on that unpack file,
which command do we have for that
stash?
If you want to stash for hot.
Not at up.
Listen to the question again.
And which would be
if you want to stash and untracked file
and okay, let's get stash.
Yes but
and if you want to start a track file.
Okay now now is is this due to everyone
problem?
Great.
Perfect.
You'd give it to all of you
That where we can actually use
our session?
This is one of the scenario.
And the other is you will see
as we proceed in the course
and you guys be making use of it a lot.
When you will be working on your code,
you will see that you will immediately
whatever you want to say,
that you are working on a project
and you are like, okay,
I don't want school right now.
Maybe I need to come back to it later.
You would just use that.
You know,
the purpose you use gift will get to you.
It's just like that.
If if you guys have, you know,
$5 in your hand and you are in the dark,
so you just lit the fire doors.
If you need to turn on the own,
you'll just live it.
So if the fire torches there,
whenever there is
that use gives you a little. Yes.
You get to use this a lot.
Okay.
So now we will be learning to get dash
other commands.
So there are other commands which are
serving the same purpose,
but you should know it
if you are in future, you may need them.
Let's quickly them.
They are in simple.
So what If you want to delete a certain
stash, find?
Let's say
I want to leave the stash number for
this stash
drop for this. You.
I don't know what to do that
or some
other command that we have to
apply to stash
and then do need to automatically
close
nor general.
How can you do that? You just need to.
The stash is just gone so know we get it.
Okay.
If you want to fly to stash and delete it
automatically,
how can you do that?
That's good.
Stash list
and the
command for that is good
stash.
But index number, that's a good stash.
Bob Zero is going to apply that and we
so if I do get that list right now
we do not see you see why do you see that?
Okay this is already up a bit.
Okay. Could not give me an error.
Okay.
Well, at this time
I think we cannot apply a particular stack
because it's going to give us an error.
So let's not do that or let's do
another test.
Let's try to drop the third one
for pre
and then do this
task list.
No, it dogs us going to.
Okay.
Well the purpose is that it does work so
right now good stash pop
index it's going to apply and needed
right now you are unable to do that
because we have some conflicts going on
and let's not deal with them.
Okay? Okay.
So the questions
while index you have w IP on master,
let's dash through list we
okay because I did not pleased message
while stashing this
so it automatically placed message
to remember.
Okay so this is an auto generated message.
If you do not put in the message,
it will just put it by itself.
Okay.
But some there must be saved
after we drop into these interrupt
to accomplish something.
That's actually the purpose.
Okay. Okay.
So how like we're saying that after
we have dropped a stash,
it must be saved somewhere as
What's the purpose?
Okay,
so in order to answer that
slashing is your temporary saving area.
If you want to save it, even after
you drop it, you have the grapple
and the stacking area.
Whatever goes once.
If you drop it, it's deleted. It's
nowhere.
There's no way you can recover it.
It's a very temporary story's.
Got it. So
okay, guys,
So I be good with the stashing stuff.
Should I move forward? Oh,
okay.
Okay, great.
So a lot of
stuff over here.
Let's close that
and let me see
if we can do another example
that I may have. So,
no, I guess that's it for session.
Oh, you guys, let's close our project
and let's do one thing.
Where is our terminal
or I close my terminal also.
Let's open the terminal, regains
that log.
Yeah, okay. It's.
It is there.
Let's just go to our GitHub
and we do that.
Okay, let's send it to GitHub.
So I'll open up my GitHub account
and I'll quickly
create a new repository
just like we did yesterday.
And I want to ask you guys, will
I need to create a new wrapper for this
or can I use a previous wrapper?
I don't have to create a new one, right?
So I create a new apple. Limit
that car, create
a positive free.
Okay, so what's the first step?
What I want to
send my code to the GitHub.
What's the very first step
would be
to make sure that I'm in the right right
location.
Yes, I am.
I'm in the right position.
What's next?
What should be our next step?
Okay.
Me, I already have this apple bagel.
I have this wrapper
already right?
So I do not need to initialize it.
I need to initialize the connection
between the remote wrapper
that I created with my local.
That was before.
That gives me more add origin.
Let's name it.
The url is here.
Is that right?
What's the next command?
Dead branch, Dash and main.
And then what should I do
that push that new origin Me
Okay,
so everything
that I have is sent to my apple.
I can show you that over here.
Oh, it's there.
The number of commits were four.
They are there.
Okay, take your time.
Take 2 minutes till 915.
Push up, goes to your apple
and let me know.
And then we'll move forward.
Oh, well, you can do that. But
it's it's important
that you remember the command.
So make it a habit to type it.
Okay?
Yeah.
You dive in,
but you told them it's a copy.
Well, we have someone files know
which files are on track.
Yes, I showed that minutes ago
because of the comments.
Okay, so we have them on fact files.
Okay, let's do one.
Okay, let's come back now.
Get add dot.
Good. Come and dash and
latest
final comment
get push
So make sure that if you haven't
put files add them to
and just make a push with the command
latest file come it.
Well that's because your dog did
ignore file
must not have the correct info
or as now
we all have the same called right.
Okay.
So after the class
you do not have to put in the space.
I suggest you have the dot and the slash.
Make sure that there is no space.
And apart from that,
make sure that you are saving.
Okay, guys, I'm done. To this point.
All of us.
I'm pretty sure that's good luck.
Different colors.
Dennis.
I'm not sure about what you are asking.
And GitHub. Yes,
we can do that. I'll I'll teach you
this.
Not focus on that right now.
Okay, guys.
So let's now refresh
our GitHub.
There are five number of commands.
Fine. Good enough.
Now for those of you
who do not have this good
on the GitHub right now, is there anyone
who doesn't have this code on GitHub?
Let me know
because I need to then
see what I can do for you.
But they all of you are not.
Okay, great.
So, so
yeah, that's fine. Jim.
No worries
and I'll come to that.
Don't worry.
I can click on my commands.
I can show you. I'll show you that.
Just great.
Okay, right now we have another topic.
Don't worry, guys.
I'll teach you everything about GitHub.
The next two classes all on GitHub.
Okay,
so now the first step that we have is
to clone the problem.
But before we do that,
we are going to go into a scenario.
Let's assume that right now
I'm a person is work
who is supposed to work on a project.
I just joined into a company
and they are working on cars
and they build awesome cars
and along with me
another person doing it
that is a clone of me.
So this is me, number one,
and that is the mean number two.
I'm sorry, he's not available right now.
Maybe I've been in office some time, but
you guys do get the idea right?
So two people just joining the company
and the both are supposed
to work on the same project
and which is building the cars.
So let's go ahead and join in.
And I said, okay,
hey, my team, can you please share the
GitHub grapple on which I want to work on?
I'm supposed to work.
You'll say, why not?
Here is fueling will give me this
link.
I'll say, okay, I've got really
I'll go to my desktop,
I'll see this is the location
where I want to place my project
car company
project.
I'll open this up.
I'll open the get back here.
So should I download the code
or should I cloning it?
Okay, why should I want it?
Why not download?
Because I want to have all this history.
That's why.
So I'd say get clone
and then I'll give the
address.
So. Okay, so it's done
of you guys.
Now what I want to do is
I want to go to the logs
and I want to view their previous commit.
How can do that?
Why is this error here?
I'm going to catch it
some someone must catch it.
I'm pretty sure that you will
know how it documents and like that.
I'm sure you guys
will be able to catch it.
What's the matter?
Very good.
And I'm not in the right. Cool.
And I did that on purpose
because I know that a lot of you
will be making this mistake like this one.
Trust me, you guys will do this mistake.
So let's make sure
that you are in the right folder.
Okay?
No, I was just making sure that I let
you know that.
What's the error
at the city
gate car
And now get locked.
Okay,
so here are all the permits that we have.
The final commit
American goes.
I don't like this new entry of the
With that now you have no clue.
Okay guys.
So at this point
I want you to tell me one thing.
I see that hard hat is on the me.
What does this show me
and what does this
origin slash mean?
That's
okay.
So this particular one Origin slash
mean is actually showing us that two
which come commit our GitHub
repo and a local repo
are synchronized
so f origins
last man is the building over here.
It means that this commit is not present
in B remote grapple
now or slash me that had asked me
are at the same location.
It means that they both are synchronized
in fact in fact let me add something here
I just like mean and origin had
these two are
most probably should be the one
we should be synchronized attachment slash
we can be synchronized because it may be
pointing towards some other commit in the
the previous commit indirectly
we can do that.
We can have it move downwards.
Okay.
How much what do you ask?
How did I do what?
How did you fix on the wrong folder?
I simply did D and then I moved into that
folder of which I actually wanted to move.
And that's how I fix it. Yes.
You guys are following. Yes.
At all that. I hope
for you guys.
So this
one, any questions that can be have
have you all good?
Okay.
I will meet all of you.
So now we only have 25 minutes left
and I really want to explain to you
how it works.
Yes, I'm doing that.
I want to explain you
how good get pool and good
fetch works and better.
For that.
I need one small saver from all of you.
And that is going to be to just stop doing
everything that you are
and just focus here.
I don't want you to follow me on whatever
the concept is important.
Doing that
cool stuff is just running one come that
code and that's it.
So I believe that all of you can run
that you will be able to,
but if you understand the concept,
then that is going to be
the core purpose of everything.
Okay, It might get a little bit
tricky because I will be pretending
to be two users.
That's why I really don't want anyone
to be doing anything.
I promise that it will be really easy
to pay attention.
Okay, so I am the user one
who just joining the company
and I've flown the project
on. So
now here is a pool of me.
User two
He also want to work on the project.
What will he do?
So he was also floated, right?
So I went to create a folder I limit car.
So let's limit.
That's why we call
Capital One to open it.
I'm going to open up the pit bash
and I'm going to say good color on
the same
record, and then
I'm going to the pool under Stevie log.
It shows me all the permits
that are there.
Okay,
So now I'm so this one, any confidence
that you guys may have
remember that this one is user one
and this one is user two.
Okay, this is our app on GitHub.
I'm going to be having the
we have five
committees.
One, two, three, four, five.
Okay.
So five permits are here.
So I cloned this represent pre
as we use a one
and I cloned this proposal
three have been use it two
on separate system
let's just as you point out
so the exact same wrapper
will be built right
and similarly for my this user
search. Okay
now is this concept to all of you
that GitHub on GitHub, I had the Google
two users joined the company
and they both known them
on this separate computer system.
They both
have the access to this particular apple.
Otherwise
they will not be able to work on this.
They are invited to collaborate on that.
Is this also due to all of you?
I cannot work on this network.
I'm not invited. I was invited.
How do we do that?
I'll let you know. But not right now.
Let's assume that I was invited.
Okay,
so now let's do one.
So let's pretend to be user one right now.
I opened up this gift card project
and I said that.
Okay, I'm going to the board now.
Let's create
a new file.
Let's name it
my features or let's say
my features user one
Now that I'm in here,
the I'm adding some features.
So what we did, we just simply created
a file inside the project.
I named it
my features user want and added
some text deliver.
Is that well one
simple, right?
Nothing complicated.
Just we have new files.
That's it. Now
this file being cracked right
now. No,
Let's see.
This is an important feature,
and I want to,
you know, just push it to get up.
So what should I do?
It? Add dot click, comment,
dash cam user
features added by the user one or.
Okay, so right now where is this coming
in the local wrap?
Right.
So let's go ahead and do this.
Let's create a new commit
and let's color it with
let's do it.
All right.
So that's like I make that user one mean
okay, deleting that user one was working,
user two was sitting idle.
No, he was working on his own code.
Right.
So what he will be doing,
let's in parallel
pretend to be two
and let's make some changes.
So he was also a very good,
good programmer, so whatever.
And he created a new
file and he named it user to
creatures.
See, I added some features
in there please.
How to log.
Okay, this is being tracked right now
for user to know.
He also needs to add.
So now we use it to
get at dot
that commit dash and
use it to put
features
at the purpose of it.
So now let's do this
in the simulation. Also
and it can be difficult.
So this one.
Okay, now
User one and use it
two were working in parallel
and we are adding in could
everyone should have this back
intersect our classes.
Okay do I'm just set.
What do you mean by I'm set? I started.
I said that the location of the package,
the code is not important at all.
What's important is the concept.
It's not important about the file
is what I would add.
The kind of file.
It's just not at all important.
Okay, How commits are working,
how we are one, we are interested in that.
We are not interested in coding.
Okay, so now do you guys think
that they will be able
to push at the same time? Let's
be realistic
about it.
Well,
someone was push first and the other user
is going to push out the
maybe it's
two second, second or something like that.
Yeah, well, that makes sense, right?
Okay.
So user, do you want to
when user want to use it to.
Okay, so you the one, So user one
let's open, it's terminal,
let's check this connection
it said connected
branch just main
it's already main depth
path.
Okay so user one has
successfully
first deployed the command over here.
It will perform that
over. Now
let's do this for user to
get push.
What's that?
We need to understand this.
First of all, let's read
this error Trust me, this error.
All of you will be giving a lot.
You will be getting this error a lot.
And I don't want to see anyone pushing,
you know, posting this error in support
channel because.
I told you the solution.
It will really make me happy
if you are able to resolve on your own.
Okay. So
this is
the first left with the error
to say that reject it.
The main fact first
failed to push some reference to this.
Like Apple objects were rejected
because the remote contains work
that you do not have locally.
Is that true?
But that remote has some work
which we do not have locally.
Is that true?
Okay, so those of you who are saying no,
it's saying that the mode has some work
which you do not have looking,
so does this work
is it there locally here and use a to know
so it just telling us that
this is usually caused
by another repository
pushing to the same wrap.
Wow. It's
telling me that this is usually caused
because another
repository is pushing them.
You may want
to first integrate the more changes
using get to default working again.
Okay,
so getting is telling us the solution
to our problem also.
So if this error this
but by you guys in future
so you'll be able to solve it
for the world
you are saying no or yes
Alex I'm when to come to that doing
okay so now let's
first understand that what's happening
so when we tried to push here
get it confused
it says that hey if you try
want me to push this code above this,
then you are not going to have
the same history as that on the GitHub.
So remember we talked about this,
that takes history, racism, right?
It is very serious about history.
It does not feel any.
No. Relax in that like that.
You should you must follow the history. So
do you
guys understand this, why it needs to be?
It's giving us power at this point.
Just know
that it won't happen due to the cooling.
It's happening because of the commit.
Okay, let's understand this again.
But not good.
We have not discussed this yet.
Okay, guys, I'm.
I'm going over to this again.
So user one posted scored.
He was able to point
now user to is pushing at school so
what should happen
ideally speaking this code should go
in there and Leo in here is that correct?
Ideally
this is what we are expecting right.
This is what we expect to happen.
Okay, let's suppose this happened.
Let's suppose this for now.
Tell you this, the history, this apple
and this particular apple are the same
because
after the fifth commit,
it has been coming back over here
after the fifth commit
it has an orange coming.
So that's
why it's going to give us an error.
Okay so what we'll do
will open up the time to say, okay,
there is something that's updated,
so let's step,
which is the thing which is updated.
So in order to check
what's the update, only get fast.
So get factual to tell us
whether there is an update.
Yes. Or No.
Right now,
if this command gives us no answer,
it means that there is no update.
But right now it's giving us some answer.
And it's telling me that particular
main origin slash
mean has been updated.
Okay.
So before we go, let's
simply run the command
with log.
Let us commit the user to future added.
Okay, remember that
you guys.
I checked using fact there was an update.
What should I do?
So get for.
Okay.
So let's understand that
now what is happen
will it in their
no doubt if that's not how I would proceed
now build it here
and he's saying that okay
I want put it above this particular commit
but you already have a commit to a new
what should I do?
Make sense.
It wants to put it
above this particular commit,
but it already has a commit doing it.
So what?
Okay, so
those of you who are saying that
you this is an absolute
very good solution,
very good use of staff, if you have not
committed this change.
But once the committed made,
can you guys make a staff
know?
So a good practice and a very good tip
for you, for all of you
before making a comment, use get facts
to make sure
there are no updates
unless there are any updates.
Stature could
pull the report
better.
Make the comment
to explain what Alex.
What do you want to make that make the
what do you want me
to explain?
Sure.
What are you guys waking up with now?
We start
I'm going to add
so that we cannot that Alex,
because you have already made
the commitment.
Once you have made
the commit, it's not possible to start
because remember, stacking does
what it brings
the working directly
back to the condition of the report.
But what how would do that if they're at
one of the work that we are saying
that okay, after you pull that
but you have to apply the stats one
what is that request or you are just
stacking your call will keep it
for you of stacking
your goal will keep it for you.
Formatting this free writing set.
I should know
that's that's not the purpose.
Special purpose.
Whatever we discuss the same like that.
I'll give you an example on that
and then it will get more clear.
For now, I want every one of you to be
sent to the point where I am right now.
What we said is that this code
is here, right?
And according to the history,
when we are pulling it,
it wants to go in there.
What are you guys think?
Will it be able to go in there?
No, because there is already a comment
that has been made.
And remember,
we talked about that it does not allow us
to make changes in the history.
So we put it in here.
That will be making a change
in the history
right.
So get has a solution for that.
It says that,
okay, bring this also.
Now tell me, which code
do you want to keep out of this board
and make a comment.
So it is bringing us this code
and it just saying that choose
which code do you want to be
and make a comment
right now.
Are there going to be any conflicts
between these two code?
Okay.
So where is the conflict going to be?
The both users created this separate file.
Remember,
they created their own separate files.
So do you guys think
there will be any conflict?
But they do not have the same name, right?
If they have the same name,
then obviously there can.
So here's what's going to happen.
It will say that
most them together
and make a comment, merge them together
and make a comment.
So right now quite open up my comment
and I show you what does it show me.
They show me
merge branch mean off this particular
project and
enter a commit message
to explain why this merger is necessary,
especially if merge is an update upstream
into what topic branch
you will learn about.
What is an update stream
and what's a topic branch.
So it's asking us to place up commit
name.
It's automatically making a comment.
So let's name it.
Well,
in order to do that we have to press I
this is the merge comment
and that is the
problem.
W q object.
So what happened
after you jump to feature added
it merge the branch at this point.
Let me show you in the diagram
it created the new comment about this
and it colored it.
Yeah.
So at this point
what happened is the merging
we are doing, we are going to be
discussing merging a lot.
So even if it sounds a little bit
confusing, don't worry about this.
Tell me, is this
a little bit to all of you
that what's happening?
We have a whole that's fine.
We have a whole
one class
dedicated to merge and merge conflict.
You will the idea to worry about this.
I only want to make sure
that you guys do understand that
that's what why it cannot come in here.
Okay.
And you guys do understand that?
Why it cannot go over here.
Do you guys understand this?
Okay, that's perfect.
That's. That's great.
We will discuss merge and how to resolve
this in our class on Saturday.
This concept is important for today.
If you got it, that's perfect.
This is the rules.
You should know
that you can not push it right away.
This is the goal. Yes.
Tomorrow's review.
Okay,
So just forget everything I told you guys
about the merger and stuff
that that a little bit complicated.
I know that you guys do not need
to remember it.
Just understand that you cannot do this.
Okay? Do I have the thumbs up for this?
This concept is clear, right?
You can do this now for this reason.
Okay, So now.
Yes, I do have. Okay.
Okay, guys.
So let's do one thing.
How about we put you to one example?
Yes, I do understand that
it's a little bit complicated concept.
And we have
who will file our class for that.
Okay.
Yes, we're not discussing that.
So, guys,
I just need 5 minutes, then you have plan.
I need 5 minutes of your time.
Yes, the minimum count. Okay.
So how about if instead of
using this approach,
I do need the users to represent
and use that same technique
to show you how we can proceed with that?
Is that fine
today?
Show you guys how to use stacking to work
this problem,
this mess problem?
How come you are doing this session?
Let's understand that
know for how this is going to be
this last session.
You guys already know
it's going to be simple.
So let's imagine, like on this repository,
that's simple, right?
Let's delete this repo.
So user two is going to
up sorry.
Oops.
In fact, I can not do this.
I just remember
because I have already pushed
the pool is right.
Even if I'd known this,
it would bring the yellow ones.
Okay like an animal class.
Now that seems good.
Okay, so let's it out
quickly.
Get back here, get one,
and then I'm going to take the address
so other guys can. I.
Don't worry.
Unsafe hands.
Trust me.
Okay, get going. Is here.
So in the simulation,
we control this project.
No matter. Everything is zero.
You will be okay about my doing.
Okay, guys. So retention.
I just need 4 to 5 and then we are good
right now.
User one has this is free
GitHub has this is free and user two has
this is we are good on that.
You have your yes on this.
Perfect. So now let's do one thing
Let's go to
user one
and make some changes.
So let's delete my feature you the one
and I do not.
I deleted it.
Okay.
And I made a comment.
So in actual what will happen?
User one
made another comment and let's color this
red pink.
Okay?
And also let's push
this coming to the GitHub,
send it to your top
and I do this
the history same right, but history
since I will be able to do that.
Okay so this one, I'm all good.
Okay, now let's work for user two.
Meanwhile, use it.
Two was working and he did what?
He opened his RC and he created a new
okay.
He made some changes and use my future use
The one said that
he made some changes
and then what he did
is he opened up his terminal.
Oh did Sorry KDDI
are this status
of this terminal?
And he looked at his status.
He said, okay, I need to practice.
I need to make a comment
of this particular file.
Right.
This is what he wants to do.
But this user,
Wan, is the one who will start get by me
because this is me actually.
So you will say, Hey,
before I make a comment,
let me do one thing that people could do.
Get fetch.
Oh, my God. There's an update
I got.
I did not make a comment.
I'm an intelligent person.
Before I make the commit,
let's update my history
to avoid that kind of mess
which we were discussing
before.
So what? What should he do?
Get cool.
Okay. Before that?
Yes. First what he would say,
I can use it.
Okay.
Let me start The changes that I have
and that I'll do get cool.
So let's say get stats that am
the changes that I need
changes now
get pull the
you pull the code from the GitHub.
The history is same
and now he will make the comment
that add not
the comment
about shadow.
Oh why is that so.
I forgot to reapply the flash. Right.
So good stuff list.
Good stuff applied
zero.
And we have a conflict in features 140
the deleted in upstream
and modified entity that doesn't matter.
That's good status.
That's fine. That's fine.
Don't worry
if this message is not relatable.
Oh, okay.
We have our file right. Good app.
Not good comment that am
the changes and get full.
Please leave these both. Yeah,
there you go.
And if I show you on the simulation
he has just created a new comment
here and then he
pushed it. Oh,
okay.
So guys, listen.
And that little ember class
and I'll give 5 minutes to answer
your queries and questions
that those of you who got an e-mail.
The last thing that I want to see
for this, today's class is
do you guys understand
the concept of fashion?
All of you have a smooth, simple right.
You got to understand what how to clone
clothing is clear.
Do you guys know the purpose of that
command?
Okay.
Do you guys know the purpose of Blue
for fact?
That is all that you need to know.
Okay, that's enough.
This example that I showed you,
I'll be going over
to this again in the next class,
and the next
two classes
will be dedicated to all of this stuff.
So, guys, don't worry,
don't feel anything.
I'm here in the last two classes.
These all concepts
are going to be very clear to all of you.
Don't worry at all.
Okay, great.
It was fun, right,
Wasn't it?
I'm going to answer the question
and just just to list
how I get it.
Now, obvious
to those of you who are, you know, tired,
they believe I'm here for the question
answer session and everyone is welcome.
So now anyone who had any questions,
I still don't understand
after we call the project made our changes
and we need to come in.
Do we need to create new let's
put it for a push to the more
or it's already do.
That's okay.
So you
the thing is asking
a very interesting question
and that is that once
you have another apple,
you need to establish the link
or create the rapport.
I'm not
so sure even Lorne,
this is a question right
now. This was a question
we know the project made us think that
and we need to come at it.
Do we need to create a new local approval
for the remote?
Okay, because I'm going to answer that.
This.
Is that so why don't you go under Apple?
Let's say that you clone
this particular apple,
okay?
This is the apple that you call under
system.
Okay, So there
now, whenever you want to make a commit
do you need to create
a new was this.
No, you do not have to because
it's already there you just make comments
in that.
Okay.
Now with next server,
this is why we need to cool
that you can do it.
I knew about then, but you just.
I'm confused why we need to do it.
We will do it any way.
By other way,
how how else will you do it? So one
the does that we cannot do yoga.
I'll answer that.
What's this? Barbara?
I did not get your question.
Can you start with.
Okay,
so let's do it.
I mean, you can redefine
the question, please.
I'm going to answer you.
You need to write the whole question.
Without start, you cannot get full.
So you you're asking that cannot
without stats, we cannot do
yoga.
I it will be like this that I'll see
you should not do get full
until you have check
that there is something on the remote
that needs to be pulled
and your history is same
you can do get without good stats,
but it will may
or may not give you a conflict.
We have a way of dealing with that too,
but that's a little bit messy.
I will teach you that thing.
Okay.
I will teach you that way too.
I will not need that.
You will be learning. Exactly.
But it's a good practice
that whenever you make a comment
and you're working on some repository,
you just before making the comment
fetch and see if there are any updates.
If you synchronize your
lookups.
Okay.
And someone
now server
you can do go ahead with in
without letting this one more reason
why you need to teach up
any of the questions.
So again, if you can redefine
your question, I love to answer that
because honestly right now
I don't understand what you want asking.
That's okay.
Got it.
Perfect.
Okay, so I have been taking out
anyone else
who needs to have a need to ask a question
by volume.
So when you move the 500
more to the local,
you need to make a new book coming right?
No. Anymore.
Okay,
So let's say that this is the scenario.
One, two, three, four, five, one,
two, three, four, five.
User one post
this particular orange coming in there.
Okay?
And use it to just pull it
so it's going to be there.
We do not have to make a new comment
when we have to make a move
to make that scenario.
I'll discuss it
with you in the next class.
Okay, So don't worry about that.
You do not have to make
a new commitment report.
That is a special kind of scenario that
when that occurs, will
okay, so any other I will
share the
second one that you add I
any second one,
you need to be more elaborate
when you ask a descriptive question.
I need to understand that
what you look like that's
on the correct step set
then Steph then pull that apply
add commit, push.
Yes, ma'am.
These are the three steps,
but you do not have to remember that.
Okay, Just make sure of it.
You should know it conceptually,
because there are a lot with all of this.
The scenarios might change.
You have to understand the concept.
So let's say you had a red box then.
So do you mean to say that this red box
is the hundred one?
Okay.
And then now I wanted to move
to the local regional use,
the one I used to.
Okay. So I think we want to move it to the
third right.
Let's see.
Okay.
So I'll use get pull
and it will simply move it
above here.
I see. Yeah, we can do it.
But the only problem is going to be
when you have this red box over here
and you have one new coming
yellow coming your way here,
then will you be able to do it? No.
Now there will be a problem.
How to resolve that problem?
Why did it occur?
We will discuss that in our next class.
Okay. No.
Anyone else?
Schools.
Thank you.
Done.