That's only one.
Yet I was always there, just, you know,
I was ready for all this.
Diane,
how are you?
Ron Lugo I shop.
I mean, and really,
I wonder if I pronounce your name
correctly.
I hope I do that.
Oh, well, yeah, I got knew
I was just, you know, going to
the traditions of was that announcer
I guess he was recommending
to have drive thrus and stuff.
So I got lots of fried foods, didn't
I. Thought maybe
I also need to improve my memory.
So, you know, waiting.
So let's see.
They would just need to a
Okay, so
first of all, I want you guys to tell me
that you went over to the Revere
that you're the group
of all of you.
I that's great.
I'm really happy with that.
So is the concept of
GitHub is that, you know,
all of you now
the basis that you should architecture.
No nothing about that
because it's really important
as you move forward
if the basics are strong first
and if you are going to be,
it's going to be very easy for all of us.
Okay.
Yeah, I just thought that maybe instead
of having a 3 hours lecture,
but you have to you
came, I guess it was 30, right?
Not 40,
but it sums up a lot of information.
Okay, great.
So let's sleep for just two more minutes,
and then we will begin
with 1.5 to 25 an hour.
Yeah, if you already know, you can simply,
you know,
make it move faster.
So we will begin at 710 and then
we are going to be having, I guess
approximately
four classes will be at today's Tuesday.
We'll be having a mass on Wednesday
and then on Thursday
is going to be our a new Saturday
and Sunday.
And that's it.
From Monday onwards, you guys will be
review will be off get most probably get
I guess you guys are pretty much done
with every every other stuff
so it's going to be get and
on from Monday I guess yeah on Monday
you guys will be having a session
in which I still am.
I will be guiding
you guys towards the project.
We will try to make it Sunday.
If you are able to finish early.
I'll let you guys an update
on this on Saturday.
So the next week is going to be the book
project.
It's really important, really exciting.
I encourage all of you to participate
fully in that.
It's going to help you a lot,
learn and know it's not at all hard
if you are like if you guys
have gone through to come right
and you know how to do the frameworks,
Selenium is good and right not to get.
It's also going to be,
you know, underpinned a bit
so that all you have to do is combine
the concepts you have learned so far
and put them into action
to do the project.
So it's going to be not that hard.
And obviously
we are always there to help you out if you
if you are
having a hard day. Oh,
well, sadly, I hope that it would happen.
That was exciting.
But now we will have to
we will have to just the basic application
that we have, most of it on this index is
our times is going to be different.
You have to test using different
confidence that you have learned.
Okay, so
it's similar to
let's begin our session and the rules
you guys already have.
Spend a lot of time with me.
You all that I always encourage
to question without really you guys
find anything difficult, any concept
that is hard to get, let me know.
I can explain that
and simpler words for you, but
make sure that you guys
are not just sitting lightly.
It's very important that we communicate.
That's a tool which I don't
get is really important.
If you guys understand this, you trust me.
You won't have to ever, ever review
it again.
It's it's a one time effort,
if put correctly,
you guys won't be ever needing
to review it again.
It's not like selenium or any of the stuff
that you guys have to go back
and, you know, remember stuff
this just simple concepts
go through them
once you will ever have to review that.
That's my promise to all of them.
But the condition is
that you have to be very interactive.
Okay, So today's agenda is going to be
to understand the concept.
First of all, of the local
at the remote repository,
we are almost familiar with that.
But people moving that, the next one
as to how to create a local level
one make commits in it.
We already know that this is something new
that we will be learning today
how to perform different operations
using get command on our local level.
Okay.
How to connect your local output
to the remote one.
We already know that,
but we will be revisiting it.
And the next new concept
that we will be learning is how to clone
some other get comparable.
I believe that you guys already know
how to clone.
Right?
We have been doing that
and but we will going back
a little bit understand the concept
that how learning actually works.
And the last thing,
how do we let go from our apple,
which you have already clone.
I believe that you guys have been already
pulling also.
But today we will be learning in depth
that how the poll works
and how it differs
from going and stuff like that.
So nothing very new in today's lecture,
but we will be reviewing a lot and,
you know, understand the concepts.
No, not that
we are not reviewing that.
We are just shooting very basics and
we will be learning a few more concepts.
Last time when I talked to you guys
and I skipped a little bit information
that need to be delivered,
so that is going to be included
pretty
that's fine.
Today is going to be cloning and killing
is going to be our major focus.
Some worry about that.
Okay, let's start from the beginning.
Okay.
So why do we use good?
We all know that whenever we are
working in our on our one on the project,
we need to crack it because in future
there might be a scenario
where we have to revisit
some of the previous version
or we might have to share our code
with some other person who is not located
on the same in the same region
where we are located.
And for that purpose
we need to track our project
and the best option for
that is to use get.
Do we have any other tools
available in the market apart from there
to take our projects?
Yes, of course we do have like SVM bit,
but Bitbucket
and other tools are also available,
but it is the most popular one.
And right now I was just in touch
with one of the students in the market.
They are also using somehow
some of their Bitbucket,
but that is the exact same copy of it.
So you won't be having any problem.
Okay,
so let's
start by tracking our first project,
for which what I'll do
is I'll simply open up my intelligent
and then I will be creating a new project
that's Bitbucket.
Okay, so inside my intelligent,
let's create a new project
from scratch.
File out of the project.
That's our project.
Let's get Project one.
All right.
W Yeah, a Java project.
Just create a project and
start a computer
you should follow.
If it wasn't
awkward,
let me know what you guys are
done creating your project
so that we can proceed.
Okay, great.
So now what do you want to do?
I want to have a track of this project.
And let's say
that you have a code in there that says
I'm about to enter that
just prints out this particular statement.
Nothing. Nothing else. Nothing.
And it is not mean class.
Okay, So the first step is to create
a local repository, right?
So we will obviously have to open up
our location in the system
where our project is residing.
One smart way of doing
this is to right, click on it
and click on Opening Explorer.
How is my project Get Project one?
Okay,
so this is for Windows and Mac users.
You got you guys can simply going
to finder and drag down this back
and open up the X open up
this to the project in the Explorer.
I'm sure that until now
it's going to be not a task for you.
Let me know when you guys open up
your Explorer, all the Mac users
and Windows user and then we can proceed.
So this
is a project one and I have opened it,
opened it up,
yes. Alex
Because I'm going to also
draw this quick one over here real quick.
Let's name it
the project one.
Okay.
Inside this folder I have no idea
as RC and project one dot I am.
I'm just going to draw for now as RC
and dot idea because the I am a file.
You are not interested in it for now.
Let's have it all.
So let's not just ignore sa c
dot email and let's see.
Not idea.
Okay.
So the first decision that we have to make
is that
we are to create our app.
Okay.
I can either go inside
SRT and create a three at this point
where the main code is located,
but can you just tell me that
what will be the disadvantage
of creating repository over
here? I
Exactly.
Very good.
So if
I create a representative at this point,
only the main and other classes
that are inside this folder
which I create or the time will be trapped
by that click relatively.
Any other files that we have over here
and inside this border, SRT,
the column is located.
They won't be trapped by it.
Are we all clear about that?
Okay.
So now we have seen that
when we are working with MAVEN Project
or like in Java,
we will have a lot of classes.
And in Maven also we have some extra Clive
Palmer example and other
configuration files.
We may have them.
So it's a very good practice to all of us.
Create your repositories
inside your immediate project folder.
So if this is my group, get Project one,
I should create my repository
at this particular point
that all the files and folders
are located.
Okay.
So now in order to create the repository,
what I need to do is
I will simply right
click on it and click on Get Bash over
here, right
click on your inside the project folder
and select it back here.
And it's going to open up your comment
for Mac users.
What you can do is
you can simply go to your folder,
you will right
click on it and select Open in terminal
or open terminal over here.
I don't remember the exact words
of that man or that option,
but it's going to be something like that.
Let me know when you guys have opened up
this particular
get bash
grid.
So Demi has shared that.
Look at Mohammad.
So look at the shot screenshot
that the Museu.
Okay,
I'm going to read for one more minute
so that all of we can cope up
because I know that matches,
as some of you might be having a hard time
with getting it
the don't we just created a means class
and that's it.
It's using the IBT terminal.
You can use the terminal ultimate
out of the command that open up
a separate terminal on it
that will be more convenient.
And all of this, we commend
you guys to stay away from the terminal.
I personally don't recommend it.
I personally don't recommend using
the Ivys at all use when you are using it,
because that is something
which is totally separate from any idea.
I know in Windows 11, I know
that's okay.
For Windows you have to click on
get back to.
If you do not see this option,
then what you don't have to do
is you will have to navigate
manually to your folder.
I believe that you know that
the only purpose of showing you this
is that it's a short charter for you guys
that instead of doing all that stuff
with none of your PWT
and then LCD, etc., navigate
to that particular folder,
you can simply follow this talk
that I did not teach you guys
this first,
so that you should also know how to do it.
Okay.
Because most of you might not be able
to find
this option in your coverage
or for those of you who can find it.
Very good.
But if you are unable to find it,
just simply navigate to that folder.
Okay.
Using LR, CDP and the the middle.
That's fine.
If it's not showing up,
just navigate to it.
Okay.
Well, you should know how
to navigate manually also.
Okay guys,
so navigate to your project folder.
If you are unable to find a site
to do it to the terminal using
the command of navigation
that you already know,
one minute for this and then proceeding,
I believe that you guys should know that
because we have
reviewed it a lot of times.
Okay, great.
So now if I do PWT,
it shows me that I'm inside
my get project one
that with a thought
that I immediately came here.
So it saved me a lot of time,
a lot of hassle.
Okay, now what I need to do
if I want to create a repository
at this point which come out of the gate,
we know that.
Does this work?
Get an IT perfect.
So get in.
That is the command path.
Get initialization.
What it did is initialize empty,
gives up a zip free and c users
and then the path is shown
to me very creative my free.
And at the same
time what will happen
is that I would see a folder.
I had them folder inside my project,
which is an audit folder
and this is a folder which is actually
going to be a repository.
Okay, So at this point
I would just quickly draw a simulation for
you guys
also so that we can move together.
Okay.
And then you go, let me create with me.
You there is an effect
on. Okay, so
after running the docket in a command,
we got
you guys able to see these lines
under visible
public group.
But so we will be having a folder
of dot and that docket.
So as soon as you run, come out of this
folder, appear inside this quarter,
I do two things.
Can you guys quickly tell me
what are they?
What is this this or will have team
that I have not?
Yes, this is the staging area.
And what is this?
This is our airport.
The local one is local
because it's residing on our system.
And what is this area?
This one, what do you call it?
This new working directory.
Perfect.
Okay, so now we've got t status in our
working directory staging area and repo.
So that's why we call that
it is a three stage architecture.
Okay.
So at this point, if
anyone who has any questions, let me know.
If not, then we can proceed.
Okay. So now
how? We check hidden files on Mac?
Can someone tell me?
Tell me how to show
hidden files that I can.
Okay, so now what we need to do?
We need to understand one thing.
These dot idea file are output files.
If I run this cooler,
let me run this code quickly.
I see an outfielder.
Right.
Let me throw that one to.
Let me name it out.
Okay, So do that.
Think that whenever we are backing up,
do we need this out of our cooler
in our repository?
Now go.
Come on, Chip Dot and it will appear.
Okay.
Do we need dot idea
folder in a repository?
I know I just ran my code
and it built make presented me
with this one to run your code
and this will build up you book.
So do you think that we need
good project one Doug I am
Alex.
If you don't have a good folder,
then make sure that your files are checked
and you are able to see your files.
If you are unable to see that it's
completely fine.
It's just good and okay.
Have you installed get
okay in order to have that kind of view.
And then over here
you will see hit an item.
Click on that.
Okay.
So we do not need this all folder. Why?
Because just run this code, run this,
good at it out a little bit of you.
We do not need this out folder. Why?
Because this is something that
contains our binaries
and they are generated on runtime.
They are system dependent
and I do not have to share it
with other colleagues or friends
because it serves no purpose.
Right.
They are going to be different for me.
They're going to be different for you.
I don't
need to send this dot idea folder item.
Okay, so what do you guys think?
If I want to ignore these files
and I don't want them
into our opposite facility,
what should I do?
I have and get.
No, not really.
Okay, so here's what I get.
Ignore and get.
We have a special file called dot
get ignore
and it's help us to ignore the files
that we want.
Don't want to crack. Okay.
So let's
see if we want to ignore some files.
Then we have to create
object, ignore, file
and add the names of the files
that we want to ignore.
Simple as that.
How do we do that?
Number one
touch dot.
Get it? No.
So I'm going to open up my terminal
and I'm going to write in the command
touch dot get ignore.
Now press enter.
We created a file dot with ignored.
I said because we want to ignore
a few files we don't want
get to track them.
You can not run your code the one only
intelligent and it's going to be the
okay, do you guys have this file?
Don't get ignore
the We all have it
all perfect.
Christine, you need to run this command
and it will appear.
Okay, now open up this file
using your notepad
and simply write in the name
slash out.
And so I wrote down the name, slash out
and said this dot would ignore path.
I know I'm not much.
Okay, So there you go.
This is my terminal, This is my dog.
Get ignored by
that's dot get ignored.
Yeah. Okay.
Then after that, save this file
and close it.
Okay.
Now tell me if I type in the command
git status.
What do you guys expect to see
on the output of the console
without running this command?
I want you guys to tell him.
Do not want any command before me.
As you. You guys are going to have problem
this file
then is this come out of desktop
get ignore.
Okay so get status.
If we run the command with status
it shows us the status,
the current status of our app. Zippy.
So right now
this will make you guys have a look at it.
If we do not see anything
in the staging area of the repo. No.
So logically what should happen
is that everything that is there inside
working, right?
We should appear in red, but we have a dot
it ignore file over here.
So we are expecting that
our client is not going to be tracked.
Yes. No.
Well, after saying it closed
the get status and that's money.
Okay.
Now I see every file,
but I do not see the output file. Why?
Because we have the mean included
and get ignored.
And now this file get knows
that I don't have to track any changes
that make inside this folder out
is not going to be tracked.
So this is a little trick
that you guys should know.
You will see that whenever you are
exploring some repositories on the GitHub,
you will see that
a lot of them have got it ignored file
and which people are ignoring
the files that are unnecessary.
Okay,
so let me
know when you guys are done to this step.
Any questions I'm here to answer?
Anyone having any problems?
I'm here to answer and then what happens?
So one minute for that.
How to ignore the idea.
Okay, so if you want to ignore
dark idea,
simply open up your bit, ignore quality
and in the next line write down
slash dot idea
and set it.
Now if you do get status,
don't see the dot idea.
Yeah, just simply do that.
Also ignore the dot idea file.
So you just ignore the intelligent.
Yes. All of should do it.
All of you should do it.
Add another dot idea inside your notepad
and ignore that to.
Okay.
So you guys see,
whenever you want to ignore
something, simply create a dot
giving no file, open it up.
Simply put in the file
name and it's going to be ignored.
What if now you want some file
not to be ignored?
Sebastian is asking.
Simply delete its name
and it's going to be proud of being okay.
Sebastian.
I'm going to write the step to also
include the file name and the text
file that you have
read.
Extension Don't get ignored.
See if that file
and just see what your
you can do to ignore it if you want that.
That's not an issue. Denis
Okay guys, so don't get ignored.
If I ask you now to create a don't file,
ignore few folders
when you will
all if you be able to do that.
Okay, great.
So like right now
only two files are appearing in red three
so I'm not giving no file.
I'll get project email at SRT.
These are the files
which are me appearing them red.
This means that you're just saying that
these are the files which are untracked.
Let's let us know that this habit of now
reading
whatever is being shown on the console.
Because trust me, if you guys, I have it.
I have a habit of reading your console.
It's going to be very easy for you to know
what you guys are doing wrong.
So. Right. Not since on Grand Master.
No commits yet.
So have you made any comments?
No. Such is that there are no comments
but showing us
that untracked files are these see files?
Have we started to track any files? No.
So this means that
all these files are on track.
Okay, now what I want to do,
let me first open up this and
let's have
a circle over here which represents
dot it.
Ignore.
So I have my out
and my dot idea
inside this sub.
These two quarters
going to be pressed right.
Okay.
So I want you to tell me
if I only want to crack.
See, like, I only want to initiate
tracking of source and what I need to do.
Which command will I use?
Get add srt regular.
Okay,
whatever I want to track
all the files.
Okay, so for tracking all the files,
we have the command and get at dot.
So as soon as I run this command,
what's going to happen?
It's going to take a snapshot, a copy,
and it's going to place it
in this staging area.
So in my staging area,
SRT is going to be there.
Which other file
am I going to have an investigator here
if I use get that dot, I will have my I.A.
file. But
and I know dot ideas and
it get ignored.
So I want to be having it right now
so it won't be packed.
And this got it ignored.
File that you created is going to be there
inside my staging area.
Let's do this.
Okay.
I'm at the same that you put the files
we don't want to track inside.
Do not get ignored.
But we are tracking the file dog.
No. Yes. Because that don't get ignored.
File only contains the name of the files
that have been ignored.
Okay,
so let me come to the mean vocals file.
So let's say that you are working
on a project and you ignore those files,
but you have this got it
ignored file also available.
So what can happen is that in future,
if someone wants a the file,
you can look into your docket.
Ignore and ask you for that.
Hey, you ignore this file.
But I think I needed.
Can you share this file with me?
So that's the reason
it's good to have a get ignore file.
Upload it on your behalf.
Makes sense.
Exactly.
Okay.
So let's go ahead, guys,
and just run this command.
As you saw in the simulation,
I hope that the same will happen
if you get that dot on the terminal.
Okay.
And if I want to see
whether work correctly or not,
get the status of game.
Now, I see that every file that
that I was seeing
previously appears in green color.
So what does this green color represents?
Files appearing in green
in the presents that
they are in staging area.
Okay.
These farther down the staging area,
just keeping track of them good enough
now if you want to see that,
what are those files
that are inside the staging area?
Let's see.
At any time of time and point,
you just want to immediately check that.
Okay.
I just want to see
which ones are in my staging area.
How can I do that?
I know all of that is going to show me
the files in my
in my working directory.
Christine Log is going to show me
the files are the commits in the recall.
Nas will get status is going show me only
if the fire zone staging area
but not in the wrapper. Okay
so before
we do that, before we learn how to do
this, let's do one.
Let's quickly make comment. Okay.
So in order to make a comment,
what we do is simply use
the command, get comment
dashcam along with the message.
Let's call it first time.
I spent a great deal of time
teaching you guys how to name your commit.
But for now we are going to name them
very simple, just like voice
animate or something.
That's what if I'm going to run
this command it's going to get
is going to take a snapshot of everything
that is there
in my staging area
and it's going to make the first time.
So this is going how my repository
is going to look like you guys agree
and there's going to be a
message
along with this same first comment.
Okay, There you go.
Okay, get commit.
That's our
first comment.
Three files change between insertions.
If joined up, then what it actually did
and it has made some
comment inside the wrappers if we actually
and we are good
until this point let me know
and once you guys have made the commit
and then we'll be proceeding
forward.
It doesn't work.
I never use that.
So I'm going to lock that if it works.
Okay, that's fine.
Okay, great.
So now what we want to do,
let's say at this point,
we want to view the status of the deficit.
So what do you guys expect
that if I run this command, get status,
what will the output
without running this album?
Okay. So we are expecting
to see that our increase mean
there's nothing to be committed.
There's nothing to be in there at.
Okay.
Right.
Okay. Yeah, that's fine. But, you know,
get status.
It shows that on grass master,
nothing to commit what can we is putting
everything is up to date
all the three stages are synchronized
if I make you see that
all the tree state is working directory
staging area
and they're up they are synchronized.
So one of the other thing about getters
and GitHub is synchronization.
It is actually synchronizing
your working directly,
your staging a rapport
and your animal travel.
They all should be same.
You guys do know that you have this backup
for WhatsApp and you don't drive.
It gives you an option to saying that
synchronize your local with the remote.
So it's just like that.
But in the terms of coding
that you are actually
synchronizing your calls and folders.
Okay.
Okay. Mohammed, your issue is because you
most probably reinstalled it
and you have to make these configurations.
I recommend that quickly go to your
support, Karen
and I think you are, of course,
is going to be there
to help you automatically.
You are that okay.
You need to make configurations.
Okay.
So the next step that we are going to
learn is
exactly when
to see
which are the files of folders
there in the staging area.
We have this command get Ellis that files.
So let's open up our terminal
and write down
get out of dash class.
So it is now giving me the files
that are there in my state.
There are three files, right?
And I see them all.
Okay, so this is one of the extra commands
that we we will be learning.
And the point is
that good is a very vast tool.
They are going to be around, you know,
50 commands
that are there that you can run
in your local terminal
to perform different kinds of operations.
Do you guys need to memorize
these commands? No.
The basic one you should know
the very basic one, add command, etc.
But these at one does not have to
remember them whenever you want to
in your real life project.
So whenever you need to do
some operations, you can simply go through
the sheet that I'll share with you
at the end of this session.
The whole session I'll shoot with you
a few teed off get.
You're going to always open up
that ship, look for our particular command
and its purpose and use that in your
terminal whenever you need it.
So now
I'm going to teach you a lot of these
powerful commands and their purpose.
You might find them handy whenever you are
working on your project,
you might need them.
In one of the case
scenarios, I want to be going over
to each individual scenario
because that is going
to take a lot of time.
But whenever you are, you should know
the purpose and the scenarios will appear
as you start working on the project.
Daedalus files will show you the files
that are there
in your staging area of your data.
That's the purpose.
Okay, now let's discuss one scenario.
There was a file.
This file.
Good project one that I am.
I accidentally,
you know, just adding it to staging area.
And now I'm thinking, Oh, my God,
I should not have done that
because I don't want to crack it
right now.
While there might be much more reasons,
number one, it's not ready yet.
There are errors in it and I don't want
to share it with my colleague.
I don't want to crack it right now.
Number two, this is an unnecessary file
which I don't want to crack.
So if that's the scenario.
You and I have already added it
to the staging area.
If I want to remove it,
how can I do that for that purpose?
Again, we have a very good command
available to us.
Let me do that.
To remove any file
from the sitting area,
use the command, get on that guest
file.
It's actually dash.
Dash against.
So let's try to move this project.
One dot.
I am.
And by the way, guys,
let me tell you another shot that
whenever you are writing down filings
after Dash, if you have written
get press simply tab, it's
going to autofill the name for you guys.
Okay.
After writing that
and it shows all the file like VIP press
tab button
and it's going to fill the whole
complaint.
Yeah,
Tab. Oh, I'm really sorry.
But for Mac, I don't know
what's the argument before that
maybe it's
okay we have that in in Matt also.
Okay great great
priority. So
this is the command that we are using
to remove the file from the staging area,
get rid the access cache, and after that,
we have to give the filing.
So the shortcut I'm teaching you is type
the initial like get and press tab.
It's going to autofill the name for you
guys.
Okay, let's press enter.
Okay.
Now it says that that's removed.
We want to see whether it's moved or not.
Which command do we have for that?
Get this file that is.
I want to have a look at the files
inside my staging area.
Right.
So I'll use get ls that files?
Do I see now any file of the name.
Good.
Good project
I am. No. Which was being shown before.
Do I see that? No.
It means that it's
successfully removed from US area
so it can be a folder name to serve on
most of that
you have to give the full back.
If you use SRT, it may work, but
most really you will have to give the full
back.
You can try on both.
I guess that it will work in
both scenarios, but sometimes it doesn't.
If it doesn't, you have to give
the complete back of that file
that was not working for you.
I show you on Mac on my windows.
Mac. I don't know.
That is one back.
If the tab is not working,
just type in the name.
I'm sorry, not a mac expert.
Mac is really hard.
Anyone who had a success with Matt
Mac just, you know.
Okay, it's working for a moment
now. How do I get it back
from simple, right?
What do you think happened?
You got it back.
That status?
Yeah, exactly.
Just you get that again.
I will add it up
probably.
Right.
So let's take a two minute break to digest
all the information that we have learned
until now. Any questions?
Let me know.
Anyone who is lagging
behind is going to have join us.
But we're here now.
I want all of you to be on the same page
with me, okay?
Yeah.
2 minutes till eight.
That's not a big break.
It's just for the rest of the summer
to catch up.
That's it.
Okay, so let's see what you got. And
Alex, madam, you also
need to configure your get.
Okay, So you need to use this command
get config
that's desk mobile user dot email.
And then after that, in inverted commas,
you have to enter
your email ID which you are using on.
Okay.
And apart from that,
get that desk mobile user name
instead of your name
you have to add to your GitHub username.
Okay. Yeah.
Use this command, but you have example dot
com instead of that,
use your github
email account.
Okay. Your email account.
Whatever you have on the GitHub. Yes.
We are dealing with right now
on local episode.
How good for the Mac users.
It's okay if the socket is not working.
I guess you guys can simply chime
in, right?
That's fine.
Let's figure out the socket later on.
Okay. Still everyone has gassed up, right?
So I need use for even for names
or only something.
Alex just imposed in this board
and someone is going to be there to help
you out. Okay.
This is something that you should have
done it already, but not a new machine.
I understand that.
Simply get to the support center.
All right. Nightmare.
You know, that's on a day to look at OC.
Not going.
You have my console using the command here
to just have a blank console.
Okay, So
at any point in time,
if you guys want to have
see the difference of the files
that you have in your
in your app
and of the files that you have
in your staging area,
which command we have for that purpose,
that is a list.
Okay.
So the thing is that letting you
open the song,
let me update this we remove this right
Don I am plug was the
yeah we
didn't move this file.
I would be the person. Just wait a moment.
Let me update the
this picture for you guys so that
everyone is up to do.
Okay. So the
this is updated. Okay.
Now if I use get status,
what do you guys expect to see?
I'll be the person who doing okay.
So if I do good service at this point,
what do you guys expect to see?
We remove the item file. Right.
We should be seeing now
that I'm file
has been deleted.
Let's have a
that says that
changes to become.
I did get how we did this file got I email
from the staging area so this the one
appearing in green
it shows us the status of the
staging area.
So right now do you guys agree
that we have deleted
this particular file from the
from the staging area?
So it's showing us
that the status of the staging area is
that this is has
been deleted and unset file
because it was deleted from over here, but
it's still present in the working that.
So it stated that this book ready to file
is not being tracked.
So that is what we have just joined us.
Is this
clear to everyone whatever is being shown
on the console?
Okay, now we have two options.
What are those two options?
Number one,
make a comment of this particular
staging area, this particular
speed of staging area, I must see in which
we do not have a dot idea
or I am bookmarked.
So it's going to create a comic
and then a lot be done.
I will file
number one.
This is the thing that we can do.
Number two, what we can do is
we can add this file again
and then do we need to come back
at the inside of this file?
What do you guys think?
No, because it will be synchronized again,
right.
Okay.
So is the concept of synchronization
here, Do all of you.
That's how it actually works.
So if that's understood.
Very good.
You guys are doing great. Really great.
Okay, well, how much?
So what I said is that after the meeting,
this file
from the staging area,
we have an unsafe area.
It's a staging area. Right.
This is not synchronized.
Now we have to synchronize
all the three stages.
Number one option is either
we make a comment of this
over here and the apple.
I believe
that this file also from
over here and direction back,
that's going to synchronize it right
this is one of the option.
And the other option is to add this file
name in the staging area.
And we do not have to make even a comment
because everything is at the end
going to be synchronize.
These are the two options that we have.
And I to think of it.
Okay, so let's do one thing.
Let's simply delete this file
from here
and the working.
So I simply did my file dot.
I am on my working day.
I want you guys to do the same. Yes.
Synchronization
means that they all are at the same level.
They have the same files
at that point in time.
Okay, so after deleting this file,
what do you guys expect to see?
If I want to get status come up.
Please
tell me without looking at your console,
without running the command
that your console console.
Okay, so
let's have a look at this
particular picture
and let's try to realize
if I deleted this dot,
I am a file.
I this is what we did, right?
We deleted this dot.
I am file from our working directory
right.
Are you with me?
All of you.
To this point we have deleted this dot
I have to file.
Let me show it to you.
You do not have it now
this thing that working right
can stay here.
Yeah.
They are synchronized
working area and staging area.
Ah, this implies Mohammad and Fahad.
You see that they are synchronized?
Yes, they are synchronized. Right.
Okay.
Is the rapport
synchronized with the staging area?
synchronized with the staging area? No.
So at this point, if I run the goods Davis
command, what do you guys expect to see?
Whatever we are, we we have discussed
that will be the output, Right?
So can you can someone tell me that
what is going to be
there on the console?
Okay, let me give you options.
Let me give you options.
Is there going to be anything in red?
Is there going to be anything in the red?
No, because there is nothing to be had.
Right.
Will there anything in the green
showing the status or any changes
that are there in the
staging area?
Yes, there Will be something in green
because these two
things are not synchronized.
Right.
These two
these two things are not synchronized.
So there will be something in Greek
that can show you get status.
There you go.
Yes, Dennis, I know that.
But, you know, I just want you guys to
follow my instructions to your concepts.
That's the best I can do.
You should listen to my thing
and do not keep me.
That's not a good thing.
Okay, So do you guys see
now that we only see this
particular green signal?
And now what I was talking about,
that the staging area, it was not
synchronized to get started is showing me
that what needs to be synchronized.
Do we get it?
Okay.
Something that appears in green
either deleted are either.
Let's see. Added which
which portion
of the grid that refers to like
which portion,
which part of the architecture is to
the staging area.
It's referring to the staging area
that needs to be synchronized.
And the one that we see in
red are assigned to be
working dynamically.
Right.
This is one one of the ways
to have a look at your messages.
Okay,
so what do you guys think now
if I do get comment that what will happen
that will be sent to the staging area?
Yes. So let's say that
if I use the command, get comment,
second comment,
if I use this particular command,
another comment is going to be made
and there will be no dot in the file.
Is this what's going to happen?
Okay.
A little question over here.
Do you guys think that particular file
is going to be during the first comment
or is it going to be deleted
and the first time it
it will stay? Yes.
Perfect.
That's the purpose of using good
not to lose our history.
Remember, whenever we are dealing with it,
we very conscious about our history.
We do not mess up with the history.
Whatever is there, it's
going to remain there.
Okay, so let's do this.
I'm going to open up my terminal.
No, sorry.
There's no way you can delete it
from the repo.
It's going to be there
in your previous coming,
but it's not going to be
in your latest one.
Okay, So that's fine. That will be there.
Anything is free, but it is not going
to be in there in the present.
So recommendation second comment
I'll be guys, let me know once
you have made the second comment
and then we will be proceeding further.
Okay.
At this point,
do you guys think of working great,
the staging area and the repo,
the all our thing
okay.
For harvesting? No. Why?
Why? If or not, why did you say no
to add?
What?
Look at the simulation.
What do you think is missing
there? Apple has two files staging there.
You has two files
and are working to create.
Also has two files on the same and didn't
know these two files are being ignored.
Right.
So what's the unseen thing?
Time. God, I have this picture.
Oh, of
So get status
is going to show me nothing.
Okay, so now tell me if I want to have
a look at my comments.
What can I use
that lock?
Yes. Right.
So that's the get log.
And let's have a look.
First, commit
the outcome. Okay.
So those of you who are having problem,
that's the reason you need
to have your email address
and username enter
so that it can get of label
your name
and your email ID with your comments.
That's why you were having that problem.
So this is my first time
and this is my second comment
and this is the commit quote that we have.
And they are going to be unique.
Yes, them and I should go ahead.
94 was that there is 94.
Yeah.
We have loop gaps.
So we do that with this one step.
So do we need that I'm
I so we just the that file
I don't have it.
Okay so my last thing happens
that I didn't get that is that it's
still trying to delete the file correct.
Okay. Did you delete it wrong
here and do opposite and local.
What exactly. No.
You must have skipped does that.
That's why that's happening.
Okay, but don't worry.
Even if that's doing, if it's there,
that's fine.
You must have skipped some step.
Just make sure that you get that. Not.
Why do you need to?
I don't think that you need to add
something.
If you have deleted it
and everything is synchronized,
then it should not appear in that.
It did not appear at for me.
So for all of us,
the output should be exactly the same.
If you are following
all the stuff that I'm doing.
That's why I mentioned that never run
a command until and unless I have ran it.
I give you time to run this.
So please just try to be,
you know, hold your horses
before you under command.
But that's fine.
Let's let's move forward. Okay, guys.
So one thing that I want to ask you
to manage later,
I will have to look at it in the break.
Okay?
I'll help you out.
Okay, guys.
So let's focus on this.
I'll have coming out later
on. Let's focus on this.
I want you guys to tell me that.
What is this?
Do we know anything of budget?
No, we don't. Great.
So let's not say that Brad.
So let's not confuse us.
Okay, So her hat is like a pointer.
You guys do know that.
What's a pointer?
Right?
So let's say in your GitHub,
you have different commits
and your head
let me call it call this hat.
How disappointing
do this particular comment
it means that right now
this particular commit is in your working
directory.
Okay.
Does this make sense to all of you?
Okay. So what if I say had
plans to this particular commit?
What if I say this?
What does this mean? Yes.
If the hat is pointing to the first commit
that it means that
in my working type right now
I have my first one.
Okay,
so whichever commit is going to be there
in the version
that we had
is going to be pointing towards that.
Is that understood?
Yes, we have by
default is pointing to the last minute.
Okay. I repeat.
Okay.
So, hey, wherever see this particular hat
that anarchy and then master it means that
we had is pointing do
that particular commit.
So if this particular hat
is pointing to our second commit,
it means that our second commit
is present in the working directory.
Whichever commit does the hat one
two words
that commit is present
in the working directory.
If your this one do second
it means that just second commit
in your working directory.
Okay.
So if if.
Now the question is that
if my hat is pointing to the first commit,
then what record is going to be there
in my
in my working agree.
If this is the scenario
that had this pointing the first coming,
then which code is going
to be there and the that
the first commit is going to be
the networking directory.
Simple enough guys.
This this is nothing complicated, right?
I'm going to write it down.
So for those of you
who still have misconception
can get it get
let me copy that.
That's not bad.
Master
points to the commit
which you out in your wrapper
by default it once did.
The latest coming
okay a medical response to the latest
coming right so our latest one
is the second command commit.
So it's going to be pointing towards that.
I know you'll be done
working that we had this pointing
towards the commit in the working that you
which is in our
in the under apple
which is now working that
okay to that
which you have in your assignment
biological.
I'm ready
sort of with that thanks for the days
of the office I made the amendments
guys I'm really sorry I'm a human being.
I can make mistakes. I'm sorry for that.
I wish I was a roadblock.
No, sorry, I don't.
We stop. Just kidding.
Can you show your terminal?
Yeah, sure. There.
You know it.
There's my terminal.
Okay, guys.
Still this blind.
Everyone, are you with me?
Okay, great.
So let's go to a break right now.
And in the break, I can help out students
who are having any problems,
and then we'll resume our lesson
from over here last weekend, the gains,
that is,
let's not get into that discussion right
now, but hard 20 minutes.
That's going okay.
I can give you 10 minutes if you give me
a five minute lecture by off the class.
Let's go for 1515.
You asked me that.
That's that's a nice example.
Okay.
So eight 3434 and 34
plus five is 3839
And I'll see you guys at 839.
Meanwhile, I'm here
to help you out with the problems.
So anyone who is having
a problem that's quickly
here.
Oh, I see you are bringing them on now.
What the issue should a screenshot
I have problem.
Okay So, Alex,
can you help me have 100 of for me
I hope I'm pronouncing that correctly.
Alex can you help him
because he had the same problem
at the moment.
Here you screenshot.
Let me.
Yes I'm record
after the second commit
and it gets digitized.
Try still read.
No that is no.
Okay then unless you have a screenshot
of your terminal,
also share
the screenshot of this terminal.
Can you just collaborate with Alex?
He's going to help you out.
Is there anyone support Marcos
and are you there?
Okay, so this status.
Okay then the reason being that
get project deal one that I am
I can still see it
in your working directory.
Why does it still do
this? It's appearing in red.
It means that there is something
that is still untracked showing you that
your your project 01.
email is untried
and it's in there and you'll automatically
you have not needed from the version
that they can get you need to from there
and then run the status command.
What's this like what is this last mile
what do you see this project,
the one that I am or why do I see this?
I'm going to go to see.
It is a table for you.
I can see this project to one point.
I am the last file.
Seriously?
Okay, come on up.
One, two, three, four, five, six.
Can you have a look at this six folder?
What's that?
Oh, oh, Oh, I'm not.
Seriously, dude, seriously.
Like I was.
I thought there's some kind of spooky
stuff going on because I can see that
you're saying that you.
You are able to see. It's
not that. Okay, that's fine.
Sorry. Shit.
So that's fine.
Anyone else?
I guess now. So I'll go straight to that.
See you guys at
839. Okay.
So it to the nine break time as a rule,
I hope that all of you are back to.
Okay, so
and then no,
I guess back.
Okay, great.
Great.
Perfect.
So let's do one thing now.
We will be discussing a little bit
more about these demands and then we'll
be proceeding on to the next topic.
But before
that there are two very powerful commands
that are going to come very handy
when you guys are having some problem.
So before you actually use these commands,
I highly recommend that you do
not anything on your own computers.
You just look at what I'm going
to show you, okay,
So do I have your attention, all of you
just need to understand how they work,
okay?
I don't want you to do anything.
You do not have to execute these commands.
Please just watch the instructions.
I hope to you.
Okay, So let's see
before we actually jump into it, Let's.
Yeah, You have to promise for that.
Let's review that.
What we have done when we left,
we centralized everything, right?
Remember, we have synchronize everything,
the rapport, the staging area
and our that.
So at this point if I run get status
what do you guys expect to see the output
symmetry right.
This is what we are expecting
so I'm going to open up my terminal
and I'm going to get status
out of it.
So what's stack
up? What is that? So
just wait. Just wait a moment.
If it blew up, it shouldn't have happened.
I'm ready.
You know, that's that guest.
Yeah.
Okay, that's fine.
I'll Now look at it.
So let's do it.
They have moved up
against status.
Okay?
Nothing. Nothing. Okay, now what do I see?
I see that for me
shows that I have
what if by the following dot Java,
what did you have to do that? No.
Okay, now I'm. I'm going. Okay.
I have not made any changes,
and it seemed that this fight is modified.
I'm very brave. Okay, What should I do?
So what do you guys expect
that I should do?
No, I cannot just ignore
call.
I mean, what I'll be holding up
is the lesson alone.
I think that you get abnormal.
But the problem is that
if I do this, it will mean that
I don't know what changes are there in my.
And I'm trying to add them. Right.
Is that a good thing to do?
No, no.
I do not even want to add us.
RC Okay, so this is the problem
that you guys would be as you proceed
in your group projects wherever you are
working, you will see that
like you cannot make any changes
and this kind of message is appearing.
There might be others.
You could also have this book in that
we have a particular command
in order to view such situations
that what's going wrong
and that critical command is get this.
So get this is the command that shows us.
Remember, you will not be
doing anything. Remember that
get this shows us
that difference in the files,
the staging area
and the working directory.
Okay, guys.
So it's saying that it's modified
using this particular command.
I can see that.
What modifications have been made right,
Because it will show me the changes
that are there in the file
which is in the working.
I see.
And the one which is in the staging area.
And then I can decide
whether need to come back.
Those changes are like my file
to the previous state.
So let's have a look at that.
Okay.
So that's the change.
An empty line.
I have accidentally inserted
an empty line,
which it was taking as a modification
in the file
that not that all of you
on this point.
So I don't need this. Right.
So what I can simply do is I can
try to,
you know,
delete it if I want.
Let's see if this removes it.
Now. Okay.
Yeah. Now that there's nothing to commit.
Now I have I just did that line
and it says that everything is
same.
Okay,
so this is one of the use case. Okay.
Of this particular command.
Look,
there you got it will be using it a lot.
Let's assume that, you know,
there are some changes
that you made in your code
and you need to compare it before it.
You need to compare that filed
with the file in the staging area.
You need to make sure
that those that you are making are there.
So you can you make use of this,
come back similar to this.
Let's do one more thing.
Let's open up our encounter
and and to become and to the other
systems are different languages
I'm back track
let's add
this let me know once you have added it
we simply open up our SRT
and we have added another line
which is I'm back backup. Yes.
You with that.
You were right about it.
Okay. So
all of you have added it right
now. Let's open up our terminal.
I'm going to do it.
First of all.
Tell me if I do get this,
what changes do you guys expect
to see? Yes.
Get this.
That's showing me that
you have added this second line.
This is a nation in the file.
Okay, So now if I do get status,
what will I see?
Get status is going to show me what
a modification in
made on Java. Right?
Right.
There you go.
And now I want to add it to my
staging area.
So what I would like to
get at DOT update
and now I want to make a comment of this
file.
Okay.
So let's wait before we make a comment.
Before we make a comment,
let's wait and let's do one of them.
Let's our pictorial representation.
Okay. So over here,
let me quickly color it red.
And when we did
get at on this particular command,
when we ran it, the screen,
what happened is that it
took the snapshot of the updated SRT
and it placed it in here
reference.
So this is what happened right
after we landed that dot.
It updated the authority,
sent back to the white there.
What that is, is this clear to all of you?
Okay, now, before we make a comment,
before we actually make a comment
in the Wrap, what I want to do is
I want to see the difference
of the five zero in the reticle
and in the staging area for that purpose.
We have a command
get death mask that stays
there. You
so this particular command
with the best staged is going to show me
the difference between the files,
which I'm not seeing in the repo
and in the staging area.
Okay. One more time.
I'm going to I'm going to read that.
So what we did
is that we modified our SRT, right?
And then we use get ADD doc,
it added that file to the staging area.
Now is the word from the command
staging area
at the same sync level after this command,
get that dot
and they have the same sync level.
Yes they are.
Now before
I think my staging area and my rapport
before I see that,
I want to see the difference
between the files that are out there
in the staging area
and the wrapper cannot see the difference.
Yes, for that I have a command
which is get death dash dash stage.
The previous one was get def
only.
The next one is
get death.
That staged
and it's going to show us the difference
in the files
in the staging area and we record.
So there you click
that will show the difference
between the files
and the staging area
and working correctly.
Get that back up stage is going to show
the difference between the file
and the working directory and the staging
represent the staging area.
Let me mention it over here
like this.
This particular difference is shown by
get the
this particular difference in the five
filling by
get the access states.
Okay.
So now is it is it clear to all of you
right.
Okay, great.
So what I want
you guys to do now is
have this difference,
write this down and then
run the commands get add dot
to add
this file in the staging area
and then let us together made a command.
So we are synchronized together
and we all have
the same number of comments.
Let's do that. So
let me know when you got once
you are updated to this point,
made the modification in your code,
just add this file,
add this line.
Once you have added this line,
then what you need to do is then you
need to run the command, get to add dot
to bring it to the staging area.
And after that
you make a comment to the AP.
I'll give all of you time till 854.
Let's make it. Make what?
Make the comment.
No, let's wait.
Let's wait for the rest of the guys. Let's
let them catch up and then
we'll be proceeding to that.
Yeah, let's make it all the way out of it.
Great.
Oh, there we go. 54 three.
Now, simply,
I would have to use the get comment dash
select on it right.
And this is going to actually
bring this over here
and this video is
and the hand is going to want two towards
by default.
The latest coming right
So get commit action
so current.
Okay. And now if I do this log,
I see all my pre commits over there.
Let me know
if you guys are done to this point
and then you will be proceeding together
for the
okay to all have.
We can quickly just do this
and then it will be presumed you got
the third commit is still in working area.
I didn't I did not get you
to my update.
So you are talking about the fact.
Now let me show
you get the lot of you guys.
So my head master is pointing
towards my coat coming.
What does this mean?
Okay, so you need to do this.
You need to WQ or that's just you.
You need to press WQ or Q
or. Right.
Okay.
So if they had this pointing
towards my code commit,
it means that right now in my working day,
this is the present op.
You have to
look.
Look, I said you need to press.
Q how to write down.
Q When press enter or press WQ and enter
after the column.
So I'm writing nice on one of these,
you can choose about it
if that doesn't work and try
window see okay, work program.
Oh, okay, guys.
So let me look at the notes.
The next command
that we have in our plate.
Let's have a look at that.
Oh, well, Alex,
That's right.
Because you are not
following me.
You have done some of the stuff.
That's why it's right.
Yeah,
we have discussed nothing about GitHub.
We will be doing that
and then it will ask that.
Okay, So
one command, which I love,
I'll show it to you guys.
Okay, so let's do that.
One day I was, I was just sitting down
and I accidentally
deleted my ASIC
books that got deleted.
Let's do that in real
order.
That got deleted.
Now what? No,
no, no. Don't do it, guys.
You don't have to do this, okay?
Only just have a look at this.
Not no one is going to follow this.
Oh, even if that's deleted, no problem.
We have that file
in my staging area. Right.
So? So let's try to recover it.
Come over there
and I'll say get talk. SIRC
and there we go.
SIRC.
Is that so?
A simple command I'll just mention Get
restore
file name
to restore a file
from your
staging area.
Okay.
So apart from this, we have other commands
also, which I'll share with you,
but I'll not keep you.
I will just share it with you.
But I believe that
after going to all these commands,
you guys, I have made you capable enough
to understand the meaning.
And I have made you capable enough
to write this.
Those commands on your own,
if that's what I'm expecting, is
my expectation.
Correct With you.
Right. Because they are simple.
You just need to understand the purpose
and run those command and build work.
Right.
So I have told you guys how to fish.
Now fishing is your job, not mine.
You had to fish and eat yourself.
We cannot have.
We still have one. All right.
Yeah, we do have.
I love fishing. Fishing today.
I mean, I also love fishing a lot.
And I would do that, though,
but maybe one day.
What was the last command?
The last amount is this one.
Just restore five.
That restore planet?
Yes. Yes.
We still have one hour left
and we will be doing cloning.
Don't worry about that.
Okay. So
I want you guys to take one minute,
take your breath and let your mind align
because we are going to be jumping on
to the next stop.
And I really want all of you to be here
with everything
that we have done on the local repository
so that we can smoothly work
on the next topic.
Okay.
So before we move on to the next topic,
here's what we are going to do.
I'm going to delete
this avatar that we have done
quickly, but
and I'm going to
create my GitHub
repo man,
going to connect it with my local wrap.
So I want you guys to do it with me.
We are going to do it together.
I believe that you guys watched
the videos.
You have a clear idea of what not to do
and what to do while creating a backup.
How many repo should be connected
to your one remote repo?
I believe that all of you understand
that, right?
Because I'm not going to go through
that, Alex, many, many times.
So let's go hard on GitHub
and let's try to create a rapport.
So I'll be creating a new rapport
on your episode, please,
and I'll click on New Rapport.
So are you guys following me?
Okay, so does that code name is
get that level?
Because you know, you're
just creating a remote wrap on GitHub.
That's it. Okay.
So you also have to go to your GitHub
accounts,
create a repository, make it public,
not private, and we'll discuss that.
Why it has to be public and
then you will not be selecting anything.
You just completely contrary aggressively.
Okay,
so once we have created the repository,
so if I could show you on simulation,
this stuff is going to be there
on the Internet, on GitHub.
Right?
Let's do GitHub.
Let me go have this there.
Now, my local oracle has some stuff,
but my remote report is empty,
so how can I send my stuff
from the local to the remote?
What are the steps?
First of all, establish following
that remote at origin
and the address
to which you want to connect right.
So I'm going to go to my terminal.
I'll say get remote
and origin and the address.
I can simply take it from over here
or come over here or fall over here
anywhere.
And I just need the you
of this personal representative
so I can select it from anywhere.
So there I go.
We have this one
that connected it.
Okay, so now who is asking that?
How about if you want to push two already
existing rapport?
Okay,
so now if you want to do
an existing rapport,
my first question to you is,
does it have any content already
or is it empty?
Is it empty or does it have any content?
It has some content. Okay, guys.
So that question has been raised.
I'm going to just answer it.
So now it is asking me that
what if we have all our apple
with some number of comments right?
One, two, three,
and we want to connect
this particular output to our
already established that one.
Get up and send the data over here.
What do you guys take?
Would we be able to do that?
Okay,
so for those of you who are saying maybe
and who are confused, I'm going to
make it clear for you,
but please pay attention to this concept
because I don't like repeated at the end,
okay.
Because this is something that
I really want you guys to be very about.
Okay, So listen, if we try to do this,
first of all, I'll have to establish
a link, right?
A connection.
Obviously,
I'll have to establish a connection.
Let's say
we have established a connection.
Okay, Now, my question to you guys
is when I will use the command,
get push.
What is it going to try to do?
What will this command do?
Just type in whatever you think.
Okay So.
Okay.
So okay, fine.
Now, here is this concept.
There is this concept,
this call already has some command.
It's already established.
We have not pushed anything.
So tell me first is the history of border
Apple.
Same is this is this history over here,
this rapport? No.
When we tried to push it was
is there going to be a conflict
in the history of border apples? Yes.
So it's not going to allow us to push
it. Let's say
there is already some history
on remote apple that you do not have
on local.
It will say there's already some history
on remote report
that you do not have on the local
and it is right about it right.
He's very smart guys
so what is the solution to this
What do you guys
the solution to
this is to create a new replica.
And there's another solution
which we will not be discussing right now.
I just it up and you will be discussing it
in the future.
And that one is to
mask the history for that purpose.
You will have to first download
this history in your local apple,
and then we be able to push make sense.
Okay, so.
But now, for now,
we will not be discussing that.
We will be just creating a new apple.
So now is what I hear about this
concept. Now
this.
Okay, great.
For now, I hope that you will be
also in the future.
Okay guys,
I think I skipped your questions for you.
If you if you want to ask them
quickly, ask them because
I skipped them.
They are I'm not going up.
So let's see what
what these are.
It is the stupid question is that
when the terminal doesn't have anything,
what to that or not?
That's an important question
to mind about it.
It's not a stupid because that is going
to happen to a lot of you.
When you will be
using the command object log,
it will most probably not allow you
to write anything.
But in order to escape that solution,
what you have to do is
use column WQ
and press enter.
Okay,
I just use column Q that to help you
exit the editing mode of the terminal.
So just make sure that you remember this.
So is that one of the instructors need
I mean, they were adding a bit
in the content in there.
Yes, that that is what they were doing.
They were matching the history
and then they were working.
So whenever so here is
pushing something on GitHub
and I come in
and I try to push in there first,
I always make sure the history is matching
and after that I push it.
So we will be learning
that hard to do in the future classes.
But for now
we will be creating a new GitHub wrapper.
Okay,
so that is I have created a new report
and how to have established on that.
Let me know when you guys have established
something using the command
with remote abrasion.
So the second step is name the branch.
What is this we'll be discussing
in the next coming classes?
But for now
we will be just going along with that.
We have the name my branch,
so get a branch
dash and me.
We will run this command.
Okay, so we need all these two commands.
Well, we need to establish a connection.
After that, we do not ever have to run it
once the connection has been established.
Do you guys know that?
Okay. Vega, Grace.
Alexa.
I'll come to that.
That's okay.
Let me know what you guys have done
from this point.
I'll of you and, then I'll be telling you
something else
similar.
This is what I said. So
once.
Well, it can
at this point I'm going. How?
And well, if you enter the wrong origin,
it's going to change origin, right?
So if you enter the wrong name, it's
going to change the boss name.
Right?
So that's how it can be problematic.
Okay, so I'm going to teach you
something out of this
might come in handy.
What if you want to check the connection
that is established,
you want to have a look at it?
Is it the correct one?
You want to make sure
that you get the one that we.
And there you go. You have the address
to that in the repository.
You make sure you read it syntax applied.
You get that allowed on here.
Is that the correct repository
where I want to put. Yes.
This is the correct neighborhood
which so I'm just making sure
that I have enough
in my up to the right level
of work all the time.
It may happen that we accidentally
are getting the error that this
that you cannot wish to so desperately
go ahead use this command
so make sure you are connected
to the right repository.
Okay.
Know sort of on use make no matter
with the more that we
do check the address through which
your local is kind of
like this.
Okay, come on Fahad, I'm going to that.
Come towards that.
Let me time. Max,
Trust me, I won't leave anything.
Well, yeah, your pass is very fast.
Okay, so
this is something
that you guys should not do.
I'll just.
I'm just mentioning it
For your information.
You do not have to follow me on this,
okay?
You do not have to follow me.
I'm repeating.
Do not follow me.
What if you entered the wrong origin?
You can simply remove that and enter
the right one.
Get remove.
What's the command item or region
of the?
I forgot the command at the moment
Command to remove the origins
victim. What?
The rules. Yeah. Okay. It's more cool.
So the command is
If I am working for origin
now it's obvious
after typing this command,
if I do get the more bash league
it appears empty.
It means that I have successfully deleted
the previous connection
that was established.
Okay.
And I hope that you guys
did not follow me on this.
This is just part of knowledge
that in future you may need me
to remove the connection.
So to remove
the already established
connection.
Okay.
Now, because I remove my
connection, I need to reestablish it.
I just use the command.
Okay.
By the way,
in order
to move to your previous commands,
you guys can simply use
arrow keys will take
you take you to the commands
that you have all these on.
That's also one of which, like this
use arrow keys.
The up and down works to
okay navigate to your previous commands.
Okay Okay.
Of so
I will not be telling you anymore.
I start this from now
because you may probably know it.
Yes, I'm going to do it
all of you guys.
So to this point, are you guys with me?
Is everything up to date on your computers
and tell you proceed.
Okay, Now let me open up the simulation
so I'll use the command.
Get across that hue
origin main.
And what is this command going to do?
Can someone tell me
that's going to see
both their efforts right.
It's going to save them.
It's going to copy all the commits
that are there in the local
and put them in during launch.
So this is what what is going to
so all my comments are going to move
into the more critical
one, too.
So we have to become a site.
So I have moved all the speed permits
into the room.
Okay.
So do you guys agree with me that this is
going to happen when I run the command?
Get that you origin me
Okay,
so let's open up our terminal
and let's do that.
Get push that you
origin
name. Oh,
well, how did you need to enter
your password over here
And how to do that?
Maybe after the class
I'm going to teach you because that's
something that's going to take time.
Okay? If I read that my page right now.
Okay, I've got my comments over here.
How number of comments do I see?
I see three comments right.
Okay, great. Now,
this is pretty thin.
Like we all have done this plenty of times
and we all know how it works.
So that's should be a problem.
I think this is a terminal
public release.
So at this point now,
I'm going to close it
and I'll close this one to yes,
because for tender,
what you did is that you have entered
the correct remote add or is in command.
After that you have get branch
and dash meeting, same line.
You need to enter them separately.
That's a problem.
Deleted that right.
I show you the link to that.
So that's that's why I did not have it
done.
I am the one.
Yeah. It will affect the code.
It will affect the code,
but that's fine.
That file is basically concentration
setting of the intelligent
and it has to be there.
But I just deleted that to show you guys
the operation is that
if you can perform and
using it, you know you do not
actually have to be it okay in real life
of a great
so let's jump to our next topic.
Okay.
So what is it
that that is going to be get clobbered.
Let me open my
notes
this full
now the before I jump into it.
Are you guys done till this point,
all of you, are you with me?
Okay, I now need your attention. Okay?
This is something
that we need to understand.
I need your attention.
We need go.
What is this concept?
And then it's going to be pretty much
easy.
It's very simple.
I still give you
guys a link of prepositions.
First, just
open this up.
Last.
That's
okay.
Now, cloning.
What do you mean by when I say clause?
Something, make a copy.
Right.
And what is going to be the difference
between cloning and downloading the code?
And you guys get someone telling me
that the difference
between the.
Okay, it's the thing.
Okay.
So have you guys ever clone
a requisite riff on guitar?
So how do you get these chords
on a computer? It's
E like you corporate is like
you will put up the code and copy it.
Yes, I call it fusion.
Okay.
I'm really sorry, guys.
I'm really sorry.
I'm serious.
Let let me
let me tell you,
if I click on this, there's
an option, downloads it right?
You click on your code, there's an option,
downloads it, simply click on it,
and it will download your code.
Okay,
let's open it up,
extract that file
and you have it available.
Okay.
So, so what you need to do,
click on the scored downloads
in the zip file
and after that
just extract it and you have all the codes
available.
This is not loading,
this is downloading the code.
Okay, We are downloading the code.
So So
I don't like this separately.
Let's select another level repository.
Yes. Okay. I'll repeat.
Okay, I'll repeat
that.
So I'm repeating this.
Make sure that you guys
first listen and then proceed
whenever you want to download.
One of the food
that is dealing with GitHub,
you can simply click on this code,
this green button.
And under there
there will be the option called downloads.
When you hit this option, it's
going to download the code in your system.
For some of you, it may download
a zip file for either of you.
It may download and unzip file for me
it's downloading a zip file.
So I'll just
see where this has been downloaded
and all the codes are inside that.
Any questions?
Download is simple, right?
Yeah.
There are two.
You can simply click on this
and download zip.
It will download everything.
All of those that are there.
You see
they are going to be on your system
any questions regarding download.
Okay, great.
Right now
let me also mention that I'll get
the download
download the code
that is there on the top,
and that's us.
So let's be clear.
Let's just say that
I want to work on this.
So in basic about 11,
I want to work on this
project
and I also want
all of you to work with me
on this particular project.
So what what should
we all be doing right now?
I also don't have it on my system.
You also don't have it on the system
and we all want to work on.
So what should we do?
Okay, why not?
We just downloads it.
Okay.
No, no, I say you are right.
You are wrong about it.
Now I've selected app.
Yeah, I'm fine with that.
Yeah, I'm just kidding.
You can be wrong about stuff.
I'm not expecting you to be
right all the time.
So do we have as it is in?
No, that's to remember that wasn't true.
Come on.
It wasn't color.
That's not correct.
Repository is really.
All right.
What do you have to work with this?
Okay, Let's say this is a repository
and it got.
It's a mic one commit
to kind of clean random
score. See?
Want to see three and see four.
Okay, guys.
So this is important.
When we do download zip,
it's going to pick up
this particular
see for the latest commit that is zero
and it's going to bring it to us
on the computer.
Okay.
When we do download zip
that brings the latest commit
and it downloads it on the computer,
this is what downloads zip.
Does this
like when you get closed, it actually
downloads the whole recipe for us
with all the previous commits data here
just the difference.
I've to all of you
what's the difference between download
and clone?
Yes, we get the history with the clone.
Okay.
My next question to all of you is
why is that important to clone
when you want to work
in a project together?
Why is it important to close?
Never.
The most important reason
is to have the same history.
We should all have the same history.
Only we will be able to push backwards
right?
Else it won't let us with this group.
Does it make sense
if we don't have the history?
How are we supposed
to, you know, push our records to the
GitHub?
Yes, you're right about okay, so whatever.
We are going to work on a project
we must do for working on it, cloning,
I hope that is now evident to all of you.
Any you guys can ask me?
I'll show you the procedure.
Don't worry about it.
I'll be back.
So let's have a look at the procedure now.
So here's what we are going to do with
all of us are going to clone
this particular episode on our system
and open the pool in our immortality.
So here's what I'm going to do
all on my desktop.
I'll create a folder, I'll name it,
get cloning.
I just named the School of that because
I want to make sure that it stands out.
And I
know that where I am cloning my project.
Okay, so create a folder on the desktop
all you will get cloning or any means
that you want to give it and let me know
and we'll proceed together.
That's after that. What you need to do.
You need to open up this folder
and you'll open up your get back
all your terminals.
At this point.
Now you guys will be using the command
get clone,
and then you give the address
of the repository which you want to clone.
So this is the address I'll copy it
simply busy doing here
that will show me a message
cloning in to setting in but this exact 11
you know my internet is maybe slow
I don't know.
Yeah so it will take some time
and after that it's going to
be done. So
I want it on the desktop.
You can go anywhere you want to.
I created a folder on my desktop
with it cloning
and then I cloned it inside that.
I will put up my password there
and then I'm going to do
let me know once again
all of you have cloned
and then we'll discuss
some things about it.
Okay.
Now I want to open up
this project in integrity.
And also I want to have a look
at the repository that I just clone.
I want to have a look at that.
I want to have a look
at the number of items that are do.
So first of all, I'll do pwt.
It shows me right now I'm in get cloning.
So this is the cloning right now.
If I open this
cloning, there is another folder inside
that.
So basic batch 11,
I want to go into this folder.
How can I do that?
Maybe so.
Even basic back to that right
now, I'm in this particular folder right?
I have navigated this folder.
Okay.
So on my Explorer,
also I have navigated to this folder.
What do I see in here? I see. I've got it.
I see a dot idea, I see driver
notes out screen screenshot,
SIRC and everything else.
I see it over here.
I said, What do you want to do with step?
If you
from get off the
you want me to repeat
after me?
My folder is empty.
Did you know how you must not have code
correctly?
You need to have name.
Okay. Yes. I'll repeat
that.
Mainly because we know that
you have not flown to the right solution.
You have.
You need to see that you go
to the replication.
Okay, guys, I'm going to read.
Please follow me.
So this is my for the right
click closed and over
I opened up my
I will not make a mess and I use
the command get flow on and the address.
I'm going to enter that name.
I'm going to read this right.
I use this command to get cloned
and then I use the address
and it cloned everything, right?
This is what I did.
So this one,
any questions that you may have
noticed?
Okay, great.
Now what I want to do, I want to
in this folder, I all the important files,
which I want to open up.
So I want my terminal to navigate
inside the school there.
Is that a heart?
Just this.
Is that something hard to do?
We get inside the folder, right?
So see me solving here.
Let's examine it.
And I'm inside it. Now
I'm going to
clear my pencils.
Do I need to create a repository
at this point?
I already have it. Right.
Good status.
Nothing to update, get lost.
All the commits.
I see this
new virus.
You pass this, this and this.
Everything is there.
These are the previous commits
that are here.
Okay, So
at this point
I have successfully cloned
the whole recipe.
I want to work on the project.
So what I'll do,
I simply open this project in my activity.
So I would say open up the intelligent.
It's already open file. Open
Now after opening, click on Open,
I'll navigate to the location
where I have cloned my project.
So That location is
for me.
It's my desktop.
On my desktop I see get cloned
and over there I
see selenium based it back
out of click on it and I click on key.
This will open up the project
inside my intelligent.
All the classes are there
and all the screenshots, everything
how it's opened up in the ecology.
Okay, so you need to click on file.
Then you go to open
from over there.
You need navigate to the location where
you downloaded or cloned your project.
For me, it's desktop
and then something in basic Mac 11.
I'll click on that. Simply press.
Okay and select New window and it will
open the whole project for me in the IEEE.
That's how you do.
Yes. There your that is my terminal.
Just the status then with love,
is there nothing else?
Okay, guys, are you able to do this?
All of you?
Have you done it?
Okay, great.
So. So now
the scenario is this that
this is the repository on the Internet
and I just clone it on my own system,
right?
I made a copy of it on my system.
Okay.
So now if I want to work on this project,
what I can simply do is
I can open up this project
and I can simply create a new class.
I'll create a new package, let's name it,
get classes
and add inside this spectacular new class.
I limit
testing, clone.
Okay, so what I did, I simply
created a new package and a new class.
This is something that I believe
that you guys can do quickly.
So just create a new class
and they're just a package in a class
and let me know what steps done.
Yeah, you are beginning in your class.
You have to add them matter.
Okay now let's say system
that out not just
print out
anything.
Okay, that's it.
These are the changes that I made
and I want to make a comment on my report.
Oh, we are focusing on coding right now.
Okay, guys,
we just focus on how we have words.
That's feedback.
So we want to make a comment.
How how are we going to do that?
Get at DOT right
get commit dash
am my get comment.
Certainly
I need some changes in the project.
I made a new comment that says
if I show you in the repository
right
now, there is going to be a new comment
system and blue color
and it's going to say
the message
which our output is.
Okay, so this one,
any questions that we have?
I'm just showing you how to clone.
And after learning how to simply
start working on the
project, that's it.
Nothing else.
I just talked to you guys
how to clone and start working on it.
How did you first clone projects
now? So
we haven't got any clone projects
right now
since it was in terminal
there. I have pushed.
I don't know what.
I haven't pushed anything.
You mean how I closed the project?
You want to know that?
How I closed the project?
Are you talking about that?
Okay, so now.
Well, let's put that question for now
unanswered after the class, okay?
Because we got little time in the class
and that's how we got to that.
So you guys some I'm asking all of you
to this point
and the questions that we have,
what we doing, what we have done
that, you know, so that I can make it
clear for all of you
and then you can proceed for the process.
So now I'm coming to that
because I haven't reversed
you haven't reversed turn down
your question before I traversed below.
Then I guess one.
Okay, guys.
So we just learned how to clone
and then start working on our project.
Simple.
Nothing complicated in that.
Now the real part where the problem
is, okay,
so this is my working directory
and this is my docket folder.
And here my project files are
this is the repository
on GitHub, right?
So this is the remote
repository on GitHub,
which we have closed, right.
This, this and this too.
But I want to do this one.
Okay.
Now does this repository
has this particular commit
the new one that I just created
and you also created?
Does it have this particular commit?
No, it does not have it right.
So what should we do?
So they push it.
Okay, so let's open up our terminal
right now.
I don't want you guys to do anything,
okay?
Only I'll it not you.
Let's
get push.
Okay. The statistics commit.
Now let me see this Is there?
Yeah, there are 30
and then it's updated.
Right.
It says that 4 minutes.
So this one is what I did.
Great.
Now I want you guys to.
To push
this.
Okay? Yeah.
You guys will be having a permission
problem, and you will be tonight.
Not much. Yes.
You won't be able to push in there.
That's how you stop the bad guys
from coming into your apple.
So I'm able to push
because that's my own reference.
I it.
No, it's not about this.
It's not about the space.
It's not about the history. It's
because I want this for Apple
and I
kind of push do it, you guys,
you do not own it.
You just clone it
and you are trying to push it, pushing it,
It it will not allow you to do that
because that will be the scenario
everyone is going to push
in each of the rep.
One is going to be a lot of mess, right?
So how do we deal with this
when we are working on a project
in order to make you guys work
on the same project in GitHub?
I invite you guys to work on my repository
as a collaborator.
Okay, first
I give you the access to my repository,
then I invite you to work
as a collaborator
in which I give you the permission
that you can push.
But before I give you the permission, it's
very important that I do kick
you and make you learn that where
to push and when to push,
because that's
what I'm going to do with this name.
You are going to know.
So that's why I'll give you the access.
But after our second or third class.
But not right now.
Okay, Now, now we are done with this.
But we are done with
we are left with only one concept.
What is that?
Let's discuss this quickly and get well
and get fetch.
Okay.
This.
So get cool and get fetch.
What do they do?
Get fetch is the command
which will tell you
the status of your remote trap.
Is there any update
that needs to be downloaded?
So when I want,
you will run the command, get fetch.
So it's going to tell you whether
there is anything in the remote output
that you should update.
Yes or no. So at this point
I have synchronized it
so my local end more are synchronized,
but I got a local under mode support.
Synchronize.
So I want you, all of you
to run the command,
get fat and tell me what's the output
for? Me Because everything is up to the
use the command
Good fetch and tell me that
what is there that
you guys see?
Yeah.
So over here it shows you
that you need to update your origin.
Mean this particular branch.
You need to this branch.
What is branch outlet.
You know so quickly
I'll make some changes in GitHub.
I don't want you to see that
because it's just like
I'm adding a new commit on the guitar,
not local,
so that we can be on the same page.
Okay,
so now my remote is also not synchronized.
My remote is one commit further,
I did something.
I have made it
with the same scenario as you guys.
So if I do get fetch,
I see that there is something that
needs to be updated right. So
nothing wrong.
You are doing nothing wrong.
You just need to escape this.
You need to press column Q
while when loading a file to your desktop,
you also linked to the live report.
You use the link off
the online network to clone
your project on your desktop.
That's how you do it.
Okay, guys, let's let's get back to this,
all of you.
So get fetch is just going to look at this
and tell us
if there is any
updates on the echo or not.
Okay.
Mohammed,
we are pushing without providing the URL
because then included
the URL was already embedded in there.
We do not need to establish the connection
once we have got it.
The URL to that
proposal is already embedded.
Yes, exactly. If you check
all of here, I want
you to run the command,
give you more destiny.
What do you see?
You will see my oracle connected.
Yes. That's the reason
you are all connected to my laptop.
So if you want to.
Yeah.
If you want to create your order up one,
send it to your own repository.
You can simply move this link, place
your will address and upload it to GitHub.
That will work to
know how you need to rescue
Q, Press Q and let you continue.
Okay guys, to this point, I'm all good.
The rest of you.
All good.
Okay, so get set out.
I was expecting you guys. Good. Fetch.
So what does good fest do?
It Just go to your GitHub,
the repository you upload, it looks at it
and it tells you that hey there is
something that needs to be updated.
That's it.
It just gives you the message.
There is something to be updated.
So you guys also get the same message
right, which I am getting.
It means that there is something in this
particular box that needs to be updated.
So if I want to have that update
on my computer, on my system,
I'll use get pull.
Now it's going to download that.
A lot of this command.
Tell me if you guys see this particular
that's been going on, not
which I created
the command
vehicle.
Okay.
That's it's there.
That's fine.
Mohammad Mohamud you
okay?
We just need to add something
and just press.
You know, this.
Okay, I'll.
I'll have a bit of a break thing. The
very good.
Yeah.
Okay, fine.
Prod is also getting that.
Now let's discuss the outlet.
Yeah, I just need 2 minutes.
I'll feel that,
you guys. I'll just be explaining you.
Why is that happening?
And then we will be
discussing the solution tomorrow.
Okay, Is. That's fine.
We'll discuss the solution tomorrow.
But just.
I'll tell you why this error is there.
All of you.
I want to listen at this.
Those of you who are having the error.
Very good. You guys did the right job.
Those of you who are not having that,
you guys did the wrong job.
Okay.
So let me tell you why.
So right now
you have a permit in your right
with the same file
as the one that is on the GitHub.
The name is
Get Glass testing.
What do you guys have
the same name as mine.
The permit that you had.
Do you have the same one?
You have a different one.
Now, for those of you
having the error, I'm
talking about you that
okay, so you are having the same someone.
Someone is having different. That's fine.
But why the errors?
We need to understand this is important.
Okay, so
I'll have to drive for you like this.
And so that is going to take some time.
Let's to our tests.
It's actually happening
because the history is now conflicting.
The history is actually conflicting.
Just giving you a that's
why it's happening.
So we will discuss this in depth.
And tomorrow you have more
seriously my in this kind of point.
No, that's not a cover of Excel.
Let me just end our session before that.
I just want to make sure thing
to this point
you guys understand everything, right?
And we are only left with
on this particular agenda.
First of all, we have got it right.
Great.
Good.
Tomorrow we will be going to
the start of this cloning.
And, you know, the error
that we're getting
will be discussing that.
And then a very important topic,
which is special.
So I really want you guys, you
go to the videos
are stashing before you got to the next
class I'll share with you
and just
make sure that you understand that
a little bit about it.
I hope that you guys enjoyed
learning that.
It was really fun.
You guys will be having a very good time
in all the classes.
I assure you that
now the class is officially over.
I won't be teaching anything new.
Thanks to all of you, The rest of you
who are having any problems,
any questions are still there.
And I going to help out
so the students who are having problems.
Thank you now.
So I assure everyone.
Okay, Alex,
this matter that you have disclosed,
it will discuss this tomorrow,
how to resolve it.
We'll discuss this tomorrow.
Yes. I'm learning a lot about GitHub.
Don't worry about that.
That's on me.
Okay.
I'm still here.
Anyone who has questions,
mine closed margin.
A whole key.
Yours merging.
Okay, cool.
Yeah, just to just close it.
It's an error.
We need to understand this error first
and then how to resolve it.
So tomorrow? Yeah.
All of you who are having this error,
that's fine.
Just delete it.
Yeah, sure.
I'll show you the time.
Okay.
Now, so I can try my level best that
I share it up.
But I still cannot promise you
because the link is a little bit after
one hour and most of the
I am asleep at that time, so
I'll try to sit down. You
okay, guys?
Anyone who has any question,
let me know else
we can sign.
Finally.
Okay, let's. That's good.