Oh, Dad, I know it's a first
class, though, so it gets a little bit,
you know, confusing.
It's very late. 2 a.m. here.
Istanbul. Oh, wow.
Okay.
ATC, can you give us an idea
what a laptop.
As long as you have a gigabytes of RAM.
It can be Windows
or Mac and 200 GB storage.
Mathias, I think you should be fine
and you should be absolutely fine. Hey,
guys, one thing.
Whenever we have a class,
just one thing, please.
This is everyone's duty.
Now, I know sometimes the instructors
forget this. Do
remind all the instructors who, whenever
they are teaching to start recording.
That's the most important thing right
now. Yep.
It's recording. Perfect.
So we want to make sure
that, you know, when we start
that you guys don't miss anything.
But yeah, it does happen in this zoom.
You have to manually press record,
otherwise it doesn't us.
We want to make sure that, you know,
whenever the class started,
just remind your instructors as I'll be
your instructor for just a few classes
and then other instructors take over
and we'll go through five or six
different instructor in this course.
So there's a bunch of them out here.
But while I'm here and least remind me
as he a few more people
still asking questions.
Okay. No, that's good in Slack. Okay.
So, guys, as you can hear me right now,
let's let's also any questions,
anything you have just strictly
go to the live questions,
not the support or syntax students.
Again, it's a first class, though,
so I completely understand.
It just takes time to get adjusted.
But I just want to make sure
everything is smooth for everyone.
Let's hear
myself.
I mean, I'm here for three or four.
You and
and then we have different instructor,
different module.
Is there a deadline to delete the videos?
You have those access to those videos
till you get your offers jobs basically.
So we we keep you keep it till that time
and then we give you
a month or so afterwards if you need it.
But if you ever needed, let's say
once you're done with the program,
get the jobs and everything, you know,
you requested.
We always get back to you on that.
Okay. So that's that over there.
I think we're ready
to basically get started.
I think I see everyone jumped on.
I don't see everyone. Everyone jumped on.
But it's fine. Totally fine.
I think some people are just
getting adjusted to the online one.
I'm just going to check if there's anyone
and see.
Is there any book or reading material
for class?
Are books too outdated in this sense?
We won't really, really use any books
or anything, but everything you have over
here is going to be the slides, notes
and videos.
They're going to be more helpful.
Yes. When you get into the programing
class sometime instructors
do recommend some books,
so you can definitely
look over those
and we'll definitely give you also
some time
eBooks in the canvas as well too.
But kind of don't really need any books
particularly so.
So you should be good.
Yeah. There you go.
You can use Udemy
as an additional resource.
YouTube,
a bunch of other things out there, Right?
So you have a lot of options
in that sense.
Well, guys,
I'm excited and ready to get started.
One thing before some of you I don't see
pictures of you on your slides.
If you guys can,
please, definitely if you can
add your
pictures,
I think that it's going to be fine.
You'll get it.
You get to see this,
these slides on canvas after class.
We usually don't give them before
because we've seen
some people get distracted on that.
So once the class is done and everything,
you'll see everything on canvas.
You'll see all these slides over there.
Yeah.
All the content, like, you know,
notes, PDFs, everything like that.
You're going to see all of them on
Slack, sorry, on, on canvas.
And that's basically where we have
everything.
Someone says, My voice is gone.
I just want to make sure, okay,
maybe that might be yours from our end.
Usually our connection is very smooth.
By any chance, if the video's not showing
or voice is going on
enough,
do check your connection, by the way.
So just to make sure.
All right, guys, let's just get started.
Let's just get started. Okay.
So we have an agenda, basically,
of what we're going to cover today
for some of
you might be a little bit easy.
It's fine.
If it's not easy, that's totally
fine as well to just stay put with this.
You know, we like to start off
slow, get you into the rhythm,
make you understand what everything is,
and then basically pick it up.
Okay,
How to mute sound in Slack.
And the best way to do it is
go to the notifications in your channel.
Go to notifications and you can
you can control the yeah, the pop,
the sound and everything
can be a little bit like in there
or go to the settings in there.
You can, you can mute that out
so if you don't want it.
Yeah.
Otherwise
all the things you're going to see
the notifications coming and going anyway.
So this is the agenda,
very simple and easy.
I try to go it at a pace where everyone
can understand and if it's easy, relax.
That's totally fine.
You know,
just maybe hear some examples and things.
If it's the first time you're hearing
about some of the examples,
you know, take notes, anything you want to
my my goal is to make it very simple
for you guys and relatable.
So that way, you know, it's easy
to understand the big picture.
So we start off slow or very basic
and we basically pick up
on hearing tomorrow's session.
You will have more terminologies and such.
This is just step.
But for that one thing,
guys do ask questions.
I'm looking exactly at Slack.
So what?
I'm looking at Slack, any question
that comes along, I try to answer them
if I miss anything, not on purpose,
repeat the questions and I'll get to you.
Try to make sure everyone's
questions are answered.
And yeah, that's
basically typically the how the process is
one thing goes is interaction.
In these theoretical classes,
interaction is very much needed.
So when I ask basically starting my class,
which I'm bored of doing any second,
you know, I asked you questions,
I want you to basically type away
your answers in Slack.
That way we all can be interact
and see what everyone thinks,
so it makes the class more fun
and you get to see exactly
if everyone's understanding
or not understanding what's going on.
So let's make it more interactive, right?
So today's agenda is
what is exactly software?
What exactly is software in your device?
No, but let me see what you guys think.
Then we're going to go into something
called software development lifecycle.
And there's something called
what is Waterfall, which is one of the
methodologies that we're going to cover.
So this is what we're going to cover.
Basically in today's session.
Some of you probably researched this
and I saw someone share some links,
which was nice.
That means they went to canvas
and they looked at the calendars.
So good job if you did that. Right.
So maybe you did some research already.
So let me ask you this.
I like to make my class more interactive.
Let's see what you guys think.
So what do you guys think? And type it.
Okay, guys, everyone, I need everyone's
participation here.
What do you think is a software?
What do you guys think of the software?
Give me some examples.
Is going to be all examples of you
guys. Now,
before I go in and explain what software
is, directions
that we can program, Okay.
Applications.
Okay, very
good. See, and now I see more interaction.
Okay, everyone try to type it away,
sees to see what you guys think.
Software is a code that directs
electric segment.
Go in the room shape.
Are you in more technical?
But that's great and
it's your program application
collection of data.
Okay.
It's a program that helps interpret
the commands.
Okay, perfect.
With structured data, Windows or iOS
that spills are definitely
some examples
and instruction for the computer.
So instead of unstructured data programs,
life of program,
someone said, okay, Alexa,
awesome
software as a system hand which okay.
And if program is a software okay
language of machine right.
Okay.
What about like, I don't know.
Let's see Windows is Windows a software is
type of let's say Microsoft Office?
What about Microsoft Office
software?
Some sort of software. Okay. Okay.
Your OS Windows or Mac OS
is that we have okay.
Software.
Okay, good, good looks. Look.
So we on the right, Right, Pat? Yes.
So let's look into a basic example. Right.
A machine readable code or a program
that tells the computer
how to perform tasks, programing code,
you cannot touch it.
Right?
Basically, that's exactly
what software is now, what about, like
Uber, Lyft, X
Excel out of no different type of program?
Zoom?
Are these softwares?
Yeah, they're all softwares, right?
Yes. Uber Live, their apps.
Apps is a form of software, right?
Some of them. Right.
So all of these are softwares.
We cannot touch any of them,
but they do a lot of things for us.
This class itself, is this a hardware
class or is this a software class?
Let's see what everyone thinks.
Well, I'm glad we're on the right path.
Yes, it is mostly well, 99% is software.
It will bring some other details in there.
But yes, it is completely software.
All right.
So we on the right path over here.
All your games, let's say Candy crash,
a lot of know call of duty nowadays.
So many games,
everything is software, hardware.
What are the examples?
Software, right? Yes, yes, yes. So
all for
let me ask you this on a day to day basis.
Let me see.
Let me just see the dependency
of people on software.
Right.
How many apps do you guys on average
use on a daily basis?
Like three or four or five?
Let's see how many apps, 5 to 6, ten, ten,
five, ten, six, eight.
A lot of software is right.
Look to too many 20.
Well, I hope you're not using 20.
That's too much.
15 apps a day.
Wow. Okay.
A lot of infinite
a lot of apps on your phones, right.
A lot of them out there.
And you guys use a lot.
Quite a few of them.
Makes our life easy.
Can be kind of Candy Crush free.
Depends with kids games. Yeah absolutely.
Market apps, stock apps, crypto apps.
So many apps out there
you would inside of a dating software
that's true right
had Tinder and all these apps
that are there absolutely
the world is changing and slack
AB Right here
great great
see look at the world
how much it has evolved right
And we have looked at this,
if you look at it the last 20 years.
Wow, maybe some of you weren't born.
We have some 1890 year old,
but things have changed quite a bit now.
What is the opposite, right?
What is a hardware?
Let's see what you guys think.
How many types of talk,
a type of software?
There's a few of them
which we'll cover actually in a few cases.
Actually.
Let's see, it's touch about PlayStation
five.
Hard drive a machine.
Okay.
Computer Okay, this CPU
let me see
every physical part of the computer.
Good ads are okay.
Keyboard scanner, mouse.
Okay. All right, perfect.
The actual silicon
that can be and runs the software.
Okay, that's great.
Physical pass. Tangible.
Good way to look at it. Yes.
Everything that's tangible processor. Yes.
Actual accessories.
Good, good, good.
You guys are sharp.
All ready? Yeah.
I like some of the apps
that you guys are giving me already.
Okay. Yeah.
Are these physical, like screen monitor,
keyboard system unit speaker?
You can touch it.
All of these think is your phone
or software and hardware.
Is it a combination?
I'd say absolutely, yes.
Both read
PlayStation five.
Someone said write Ops four or something.
That's a combination, right?
It has a software,
it has a hardware as well.
Perfect. Perfect.
At least we know the difference
between two.
Part of it, though, you know what
a software is, what a hardware is, though.
Your printer, your mouse, just your
the camera
that's connected here that we can see that
that has some sort of software there.
But it's hardware as well, too.
We need both in the tech world.
You need both.
You need both in order to build
apps to do things and everything.
You need both part of it.
But software is basically the brain.
Remember this and the hardware,
if it doesn't have some sort of software,
for example, your phone,
if it doesn't have any software, it's
useless.
Right?
Back in the day it wasn't.
We had the large phones and everything,
you know, it worked better.
But nowadays your smartphone is
if it doesn't have any apps, that's
it is garbage basically.
That's the
that's like if you look at that is the
that is the brain
someone said at the beginning I saw
which was nice that's the soul of
the of the computer is basically
it means the stomach
it's the perfect you guys are good
virtual stuff
now older I see do you you
how can I go to select
without know lose dessert
you can minimize or shrink your window
your screen if you can
and you'll see like this or that's
why guys I remember now you might see
separate screen would help a lot though
by the way sorry guys,
if I don't pay attention to your cue,
any questions on Zoom?
That's why I'm looking strictly at slide,
but I'll try to do it for today's class.
But if I missed apologies,
just try to stick to slide.
All right.
We're on the right track. We are.
We are on the right track.
Router.
What about router, modem, keyboards?
They're all part of basic.
They're all hardware. Right.
So we both have hardware and software.
They go hand in hand.
This course will strictly focus more on
what it takes to build software.
What is behind the software?
Who are the people
behind the software that
are created?
Right.
And if you are,
I get to the point in a very good way
to basically explain to you
what's going on.
Yes, developers are there,
but you will see today also
there's a lot of other people involved
in, let's say, creating the next.
I don't know, Uber app or Facebook app
or Instagram, whichever it is.
Right.
It takes it takes more than that.
You know, just one person. Right.
And if you look at in the last 25 years,
has technology
changed a lot significantly?
What would you guys say?
Yes, right.
Quite a bit. Absolutely.
What are the what do you guys think?
One, what could be also one of the biggest
pillar to a lot of change, let's say
crime timing.
What about right now?
Now, technology
is moving at a very fast pace.
We have more and more basically innovation
and things of that.
But what do you guys think
could be a very big key to that?
Anyone think, guess
where is
something that changed significantly
and is creating more?
Yes, there is someone already answer
Internet.
Internet Internet. Yes.
Internet has made a massive difference
in innovation.
The speed of Internet
and all of these things
have made a major difference
when it comes down to
it has created a lot of laziness to AI,
but it has brought a lot of innovation.
It's doing a lot of things
that we were not able to.
If we look at it, guys, what was it, 12
years ago, I think in 2000, eight or 29,
When did when did the iPhone come out
in 2000, nine or 2000 around that time.
Right.
Or came on 2007.
Really should I forgot.
Okay.
Yeah, maybe iPhone came out in 2007, but
the app Store came out in 2009, I believe.
Right
around that time,
2029, the App Store came out,
if I'm correctly.
Now think about it, guys.
Look at all the things I asked you at
the beginning, how many apps people use.
You guys said five, six, seven, nine.
Then I saw some 20.
But if you just think on
just for last 12 years,
look how much has changed.
Billions
and billions of dollars of companies
have been introduced to the world
because of the App Store
or the Google Play Store
because that was the new you know,
if you look at it,
that's why they said Steve Jobs, you know,
they give him a lot of credit
is because if it wasn't for the app stores
you want to have these
these cool new apps and things and such.
You know, a lot of different things
that changed because of the App store
came out.
Look at how much innovation has happened
since they're so quite
a few things have changed
and we're doing this at a very fast pace
Is the
change only in software
so or it's also in hardware?
Absolutely.
And I'm glad that you brought up to
just guys.
Think of your 20 year lesson
as do 25, let's say 30 years ago.
What did you guys use for music?
What did you
if you wanted to listen to music,
what did you have 30 years ago?
Cassettes, Walkman, Raid boomboxes,
tapes, Right.
Some people probably don't even know
what cassettes and Walkman are
if they're know born in the 2000,
you know, CDs.
There you go. Right.
But look at just music.
Just look at how music have changed.
You had boomboxes, those big things.
You have cassette tape, ones
you have to listen to.
You know,
I believe it's still someone using that.
Okay.
But look at how much that has changed.
We had that.
Then came CD player.
CD player was the cool thing.
You know, you you either
downloaded some music on the scene
or you actually had the CDs
and listened to all the music right?
Then you had M.P.
three player and B three players came out,
the small ones, and then iPod came out.
So look at that.
That's the hardware change.
You know, we went from a big device
to a smaller device.
Now I use LimeWire.
Yes, I use LimeWire and Morpheus
for my delivery when I was younger, too.
Yes. Everyone did.
So if you look at it, quite
a bit of change when it comes to software
and hardware.
Hardware
especially has changed quite a bit.
And over time,
as you know, hardware have shrunk
and a lot of
it has shrunken in size as well.
If you if you haven't noticed, you know,
so there's a massive,
massive, massive evolution
when it comes down to technology.
Now, if you look at it,
all of these things right there, all
if you look at it,
why the technology is changing so much.
If we really look at it,
how can I turn off this notifications
like go to the channel,
it's up in the channel.
There will be let me see.
I know some people get annoyed by this.
I actually get annoyed too.
So where you see, let's say live questions
go to Slack in there.
You can change the
you can change your settings there
and that will basically.
But if we look at that,
let's go back to the thing.
There's the topic itself.
You know, all this
evolution of technology is
is always basically changing
or solving a problem.
That's one thing to understand.
It's solving a problem either
something already exists
and it's making it better in the sense of,
you know,
improvement there or completely
solving a problem right there.
Right.
And there are apps and things that
we already had, but they no longer exist
because someone came out there
and they made it completely different.
They did not reinvent the wheel, but
they just add some some some touch to it.
It made it better.
To give you some examples,
back in
2008, let's say, or maybe before 2000,
what did you guys use
as a social media platform?
What was the big social media platform,
let's say late
nineties or early 2000?
MySpace high five. Okay.
Oh, well, yes, I remember that time.
VK Yes, if you're Russia, yes.
Or yeah, get your kid to Yahoo!
Messenger. Right.
Those were your your if you look at those
were your main social media platforms.
Do they exist now or do they
are we using them anymore?
I think VK is still being used, but
a few of them, very few survive right now.
If you look at it.
Yes, One big example would be MySpace. RE
MySpace was really cool.
You when you joined MySpace,
you had your one friend right away, Tom,
you had Tom with you there.
So whether you joined if you didn't have
any friends, you at least have Tom, right?
Good old Tom. Yes.
You had Tom with you
and you know, that's how it started.
But if you look at it,
when things started happening,
when MySpace became very popular,
it became very spammy.
There was a lot of things,
you know, adult content started coming on.
There was becoming
cluttering and everything.
So you see it was becoming
it was just kind of going downhill.
What came after MySpace that took over
Facebook, right?
Facebook came over.
Now let's look at Facebook.
MySpace exists.
What would you say the similarities
between Facebook and MySpace were?
How similar were they?
I mean, they're different
at the same time.
No, but very similar. Right.
If you look and it was very similar
in the sense of the idea was the same.
But what did
what did basically Facebook do?
It was basically.
Yeah, there you go. Luis.
It was an improved version of it.
It took away the clutter, added
it, made it nice and clean,
and it connect you directly
with people of the universities and all,
you know, colleges, universities,
all of that.
It was a very different nice touch to it.
It was a lot cleaner and it targeted
basically at the beginning.
All the university college
kids, basically.
Right.
So if you look at they existed,
it's already existed.
Something already exists.
Before a MySpace, there was Friendster,
I believe Friendster was there.
So, you know, someone came.
They saw that there was a problem there
or there was something like, Hey,
how can I make something improve?
How can I change something?
And there you go.
You have and you end up with
there was something called yearbook
to wow, I didn't know that.
But, you know,
someone came with a better version of it.
And look,
when you improve certain things, look,
you take over, you basically take over.
And we've seen that over the course
of last 20 years
in throughout basically, you know,
in the tech world and outside of tech,
where we've seen a lot of evolution
in technology nowadays.
Yes, man, they're more on Monopoly now.
But but let's look at basically
just said the beginning how things work.
Right?
And this doesn't just apply to Facebook.
You know, let's think of another example.
I want to give you a lot of examples
so you can kind of picture everything.
Think of what was your guys number one
or the first X, what's that?
Internet browser. You guys use?
What did you guys use?
Do you guys remember the early days?
Internet Explorer. Okay.
Explorer.
Firefox. Explorer.
Firefox came a little bit later though,
but someone already said it.
The very first one was not Internet
Explorer.
It wasn't open, right?
It wasn't Chrome.
It was Netscape.
There you go.
Someone say Netscape was one.
Netscape came out
and then I believe afterwards came out.
Was it Internet Explorer
or Firefox? Right.
So we go all the way back, guys.
Netscape was the very first browser.
Now, if you look at Netscape,
you see some of you even know
what Netscape was someone probably born
in 2000, in early 2000.
They have no idea what Netscape is, right,
because you see outdated it out.
And now we have Google Chrome.
Of course we have Firefox still.
But if you look at it right,
it has evolved.
So much.
Things have changed in the last 20 years.
It's ridiculous.
And now it's going at a pace
that's that's it's it's it's
hard to keep up even just,
I don't know, just modern technology.
But I'll give you an example.
How many of you or just any of you
have anyone visited China, by the way?
Let me ask I'm going to
give you a very cool example.
Has anyone been.
Not yet. Okay.
I was a banker and not yet.
Okay.
So few years ago,
I think in 2019 I went to China.
Or was it like would never been to China?
Man, it will blow your mind away.
It is massive and the buildings
and everything just makes you feel like,
Wow, New York is nothing
compared to what you see in China.
Right?
But one crazy thing that I saw in China,
which really blew my mind
away, you know, in China,
people don't use cash.
They don't use cash.
My cousin actually lived in China,
so I went to visit him.
But they don't use cash anywhere.
Do you guys know what they use?
And we're talking about three years ago.
Yeah, barely anyone uses cash over there.
Like, you know,
we don't use the currency credit cards.
Not much as well.
Do they use guys in China
if you're not if you don't know about it,
they use Wechat's.
Yeah,
they use WeChat and basically everything.
Everywhere you go
there's a QR code and everyone scans
there, opens their phone
and literally guys, it can be a
this was before COVID, by the way of way
before COVID.
We'll talk about 2000, 19, 2018.
Guys everywhere over there uses
just their WeChat.
Take out WeChat.
It could be a street vendor, it could be
a fancy mall, it could be anywhere.
And you just go there and swipe your phone
basically, or you just scan the QR code
and you pay. That's how they're going.
So look at this now.
In 2018, 19, way before COVID,
we're talking about and to this day,
of course, is what no one is using.
No one is using cash.
Basically, let's say, you know, now
I think two or three years down the road
now we have Apple Pay.
Some of these things like WeChat
is similar to WhatsApp,
but a lot bigger WeChat.
You can do everything on WeChat.
You can buy things.
You can do so much more there also.
Yeah, Micro, unfortunately,
I hate to say it,
but when you do go to China
and you explore China and you see
some of the things, they're like,
Hey, it kind of takes you like, Wow,
I guess they are something
Alipay is one of theirs, I believe.
I think are them.
But when you go see some of the things
in China, you'll be amazed.
Now think about it, guys.
So we're talking about, you know, 1.3,
1.4 billion people using WeChat
every single day.
Do transactions
literally can be some guy at random guy
on the street selling you popcorn
and he has a QR code, doesn't take cash.
Right.
So, see, the world is really,
really, really changing.
It's growing at a pace
that's hard to keep up.
Probably.
I would say
90% of you didn't even know that that's
what's happening in China, Right?
Because we're so disconnected in one way.
But yet so many things.
You know, if you look at it,
it's changing at a very fast pace.
Now, recently, not too long ago,
I'm sure everyone is familiar
with cryptocurrency and everything else.
I'll be there, I believe
adopted cryptocurrency
or Bitcoin as a currency now, right?
So you see evolution.
We're coming to a very,
very different timings right now.
You know, the funny thing is
things that we would see in
cartoons are becoming reality now.
You know, back in the day there was a
there was a cartoon, I think, growing up.
Have you guys ever heard of The Jetsons,
by any chance?
That's in.
Yeah, exactly.
The flying car type of thing.
Okay.
I guess maybe I'm a little too old. Yeah.
So the Jets and right now
they have a flying car.
I think there was there was I think
few months ago there was Jane. His.
Yeah. My Michael. Yeah.
So yeah.
The flying cars you know they are
I don't know why we need flying cars
but they successfully actually
launched a car
that flew and landed and everything right.
I don't know if we're going to see that
in the next five, ten years.
I don't think there's a need for that.
But who am I to say anything like that
and not to duty big?
I guess we do, though, people.
But, you know, things are coming
at a very different pace or not.
Things are changing, changing, changing.
And if it all comes down to it,
it comes down to, you know,
some people think that there's
a problem in the market, so they come
and come up
with a different version of it to improve.
Soon people will go to Mars.
Yeah, that's very,
very possible and very possible.
Right.
So it's happening quite a bit, guys.
It's it's changing.
And all of these, if you look at it,
they're solving a problem.
Guys are either solving a problem or
they could be for different factors to
just want to make money or whatever it is.
It could be financial reason.
Well, whatever the reasoning is,
all this evolution of software
that you guys are seeing is first of all,
what big causes for that is Internet,
but also because people are not aware,
okay, the demand are changing.
You know, as someone mentioned already,
you know,
you can date people now through
I don't know, through apps right
before used to call people.
Now people have become socially awkward
and you can't even call
everyone just talks to text, you know,
But you know, things are changing.
The world is really changing in
so many ways.
Even changing our behaviors at time,
which I don't know.
It's a different conversation, though,
but still, you know, it's it's technology
can be a it can have a lot of advantages,
but it can also have,
you know, a curse is a curse
in one way as well to we're so addicted.
If you ever want to know about technology,
there's a really cool documentary on
on Netflix.
I believe I forgot what it's called,
something someone will say right now.
I'm sure something about social media
and everything, how much we use it.
So watch it.
Very good.
Someone probably will
put a name out there. It's
Does anyone know Social dilemma.
There you go. Yeah. There
you go. Watch that. Very cool.
Really cool.
Makes you think like, hey, how things are.
But but, you know,
we're seeing a lot of change, guys.
We're seeing a lot of change.
You know, 2018 now, sorry, 28, 29,
the App Store was built, you know, it
introduced a lot of different things.
Do you guys have any idea
how many apps are released per month
and posted on Instagram?
Like 8000?
We're talking about 50,000
plus not not millions, but, you know,
50,000 apps easily at this
point are being released every month.
That's how much things
are coming out there. Right.
So we're seeing a major, major,
major shift right now
in in in in technology
and apps and everything.
But also, just to give you a few examples.
Right, let's let's go
I want to give you a very big picture,
which I'm going to connect towards.
Yeah.
What was, by the way, before Netflix,
what was the main big thing
out there to rent movies?
Blockbuster Raid.
Blockbuster was the Redbox, I believe,
still exist, but Blockbuster was,
you know, the chain that you you
whenever you want to watch movies,
you go there rent, Hollywood
videos, blockbuster, everything.
Look what happened to them.
Do they exist now?
Absolutely not. They're gone.
I think there was only one store left, but
I think they even closed that down, too.
Yeah, they closed that down.
So, you know, unfortunately, you know,
over time, you know, if a company is don't
adapt to the new changes,
they're gone, if you will look at it.
I know.
I hope I'm pronouncing Nokia right.
Someone calls in, someone say Nokia,
I mean Nokia, whatever the brand was.
But look how big they were.
Those were the phone makers, guys.
BlackBerry was the phone maker,
you know, that popped the last
not 20 years,
but let's say in early 2000 and such.
Those were the companies.
But look where they are now.
They don't exist anymore because
they adapt to that change in the time.
Kodak Yeah, a good example.
Kodak.
Kodak was a very big one when it came to,
I believe, or pictures and all that stuff.
SEAMANS There you go, you guys,
you guys understand what's going on?
We're talking about floppy disk.
You guys remember floppy disk?
They were floppy disks
very first time I remember
growing up using computer,
there was something called floppy disks
that that had like what,
one megabyte or two megabytes
or whatever was, three megabytes, barely
any memory.
Now what we have was crazy.
So a lot of things are changing
if we're seeing in this time
too much change is happening
and it's all happening
because of a need to improve.
And we're going at a very fast pace.
Internet has made things happen.
And also one one side effect of it,
you could say, is
because technology is changing so much,
we want more and more efficiency
and we want things at a speed of light,
almost like, you know, you want
food, you do Uber eat, you want to save
some money, go left or right.
Wait. So many things are happening, right?
Dialing phones.
Someone said that? Yeah,
Those are long gone right now. Right?
So so many things are changing
at this point.
It's a crazy thing.
But someone is behind it.
Someone is behind it.
There's a
there's a process behind all of this.
So let me give you another example.
Does anyone know
of one of the biggest companies
that is out there, how they started Uber?
Anyone know how they started?
Look, they changed the transportation
industry completely.
I wish I was
so Uber came out.
If you guys know the story,
you're not some weird guy of the guys
who were behind Uber.
We're kind of kind of rich, actually.
They were very rich.
Travis Kalanick,
one of the ousted SAE, was it the CEO?
I'm not sure, but the founder
no longer part of the company,
even though he was one of the founders.
But, you know,
him and his buddy were at a conference,
I believe, in in Paris, France,
and it was raining outside.
And when a conference ends, you know,
good luck getting a taxi back in the day.
Right.
Or Yellow cab
or any of those type of taxis right now,
of course, in France, something different.
But they had a hard time
catching a cab at that time.
You know, rich guys well, the people,
they will usually take a limousine, Right?
You know, that's how it works for them.
They decided or the idea came like, look,
this is crazy.
I can find a cab,
I can get a limo service.
What if through my phone,
I could basically get an a limousine
service to come out and pick us up while
we're drenching in rain, for example?
Right.
So the idea literally came from that.
No one probably thought about this
before, like, hey,
what if I could press a button?
Something comes.
But the idea literally came out in
two guys just stuck in rain.
And just think about what
if there was a better way of basically
getting from point A
to point B in a limo service.
Uber actually started as a limo service.
Guys.
It did not start off as a as,
you know, Uber X just pick on anyone
basically you want to it started off
as a limo service strictly for executives
people who could afford
basically they start off as a limo service
and then later on they transition
into Uber X and all the different one.
But they came out with the concept.
They made a contract
with basically limousine companies.
And hey, we created this app.
Whenever our customer wants it,
they download this.
Your limo service company
can go and pick these people up.
So that's how it started.
And of course, now look at it.
Uber and Lyft have completely changed
the entire industry of transportation
when we look at it.
Right. Destroyed the taxi market
basically.
Before that you were stuck
somewhere, let's say 1 a.m.
or two.
GM Good, Like you can call it a yellow cab
or red cab,
but if someone should upgrade, if not,
you know, or while you're stuck there
now, doesn't really matter
as long as you have connection.
And hopefully Uber is you works
in the area, you can get it right away. So
then left stole the idea.
Well, I guess maybe I'm not really sure
they stole the idea
but but yes, similar competitors always.
Competition is always good by the way.
So that's how it started.
Now, one thing
one of the greatest thing about them is
Uber is they actually don't own anything.
They don't own the cars.
Then I think they're just connecting
the customers to the demand,
basically right to the app itself.
And you ask you and I can basically drive
the customers around
and basically make money
and they can take a car
and they don't own a product.
They don't own a product.
So it was a very ingenious idea
for a market that was, you know,
no one really thought about.
I don't even think
there was a demand for it,
but they created demand for that
something.
What is another company
that doesn't own a product
and that does serve
similarly, can anyone think of
Alibaba as one of them?
Absolutely.
But Airbnb, Airbnb doesn't own any hotels,
anything.
They destroyed the hospitality industry.
If you look at right,
anyone can rent out basically
any room through their platforms.
And yeah, make money.
And keep in mind they don't own
any products themselves, right?
Airbnb or Uber, they don't own the
LinkedIn.
Well, those are different examples.
Tory Yes, sure.
Care.com, Yes.
Yeah, that could be well,
Booking.com, we're going off a little bit,
but I'm thinking of big examples, right?
So Airbnb or Uber,
they don't own any product,
but at the same time
they are serving the purpose, right?
One is helping the transportation
industry,
the other one is basically helping
the hospitality industry.
Another one example someone said was,
you know, Alibaba, Alibaba
does the same exact thing.
They connecting manufacturers
to customers.
They don't own anything.
Remember this, guys?
Alibaba doesn't own anything.
They're the biggest out there.
You know, when it comes to, you know,
manufacture, connecting all of them.
You know, they're eBay.
That's similar to.
Yeah, but a little bit different example
in that sense.
But if you look at it, guys, there are
massive Amazon is not the same as Alibaba
because Amazon does own warehouses
and they own the products.
Is not the same thing though.
Does anyone know just a random fact
just to see
how much Alibaba Well, on a prime day,
how much do you guys think
Amazon makes on their special prime day
sale that they have
the one or two days they have or Cyber
Monday, whatever it's called?
How much do you think revenue wise,
Amazon makes in two days?
300 million? 500 million.
A lot of millions, Not millions, guys.
We're talking about Amazon.
I think last time I checked in 2020,
they made about $12 billion in two days.
That's what their sales were,
12 billion, 11 or 12 billion.
It probably is more now.
Now, what do you guys think
is four for Alibaba
in one day?
So they have something called 1111.
That's their
that's their big day when it comes to 11
W thing a lot more.
Someone is very close.
They make about $55 billion.
Who won the $55 billion thing?
Right.
And keep in mind, they don't own anything.
They're just connecting.
They're taking a cut.
So if you look at all of this,
if you look at all of this,
these guys saw a problem,
a need created a software.
And look,
you guys can be the next when I hear
if you think of some crazy idea
you have some venture money
you get a public out there.
You can be the next thing.
It's always solving a problem, right?
Think about it.
Before that,
what Alibaba did, it was amazing.
No one no one knew how to connect
with manufacturers.
Right. How to connect.
And basically, let's say
you get the product cheaper, guys.
Everything, baby.
90% of the items see in Walmart
or anywhere
you go comes directly from China.
But that's that connection, right?
And that's why basically they mean
nowadays Shopify,
all these other businesses,
everything's coming out because people
have access to manufacturers,
you know, factories and everything.
I've been to China myself.
I've been to some of the factories,
I've seen how it works the right,
But it's crazy.
You can do all of that from just
from Alibaba.com and let's say like this.
And prior to that,
none of that existed, Right?
Someone came with that problem
and it connected the entire world.
Now we're looking at Alibaba
doing 50 billion plus in one day sale.
That's ridiculous. Right?
But that's how it works, though.
You know, someone comes with an idea,
they improve upon it and they re go boom,
They're AliExpress to the
same order are the Express and they have
two other ones as well to the same.
Jack Ma is the founder,
you could say, or majority stakeholder.
Yeah.
So at the end of the day, if you
look at it, they're all solving a problem.
That's basically all of all everyone's
basically doing right now.
Let's look at some
just some example right here.
Let me show you an example over email.
Think of this one.
Guess
how many works for Amazon Alibaba?
I'm probably sure a lot of them, right?
Look at this example.
Look, there was an email sent on September
seven,
22nd of 2017 to 1 of the owners of
Airbnb, not owner site co-founders.
Brian.
I thought of a way to make a few bucks
turning our place into designers
bed and breakfast,
offering young designers who come into
town to town
a place to crash during the 40
when complete with wireless internet,
a small space
sleeping mat, breakfast each morning,
blah, blah, blah, all of that.
This is just an idea, right,
that these two founders came up with.
Now, this idea came from the fact
that these guys are in Silicon Valley.
And a lot of times whenever there's
a conference in town, Right.
What happens, guys, is all the hotels
get booked out or let's say
big major holiday, let's say a Labor Day
or anything like that.
Good luck finding hotel rooms like,
you know, impossible to find.
And these guys are like, look, these guys,
a lot of the design doers
of some sort of probably UI UX convention
or something like that.
I don't know the inside details,
but you know,
the idea came because they couldn't
find any rooms available.
So they thought of what if we could
rent out our own room for someone?
There's a massive demand out there
and we can give them a place to crash.
You know, they can crash in pairs, bed
and breakfast type of thing.
Basically, the idea came from a problem
because there were not enough
hotel rooms available, Atika, because
there was a convention in the city.
I experienced this one time, two one time,
I think it was
I was in a different city
and it was Labor Day.
I did not book a hotel.
I had a hard time finding hotels.
I had to drive one hour away
just so I can get a hotel room right
somewhere far away.
So the idea came just like this, guys.
Someone found a problem and yet
came up with a solution through an app.
And there you go.
That's how Airbnb really started.
So you guys, tomorrow,
if you have a genius idea
and you know how to work it out,
then you could be the next Zuckerberg
or someone bigger.
Did you hear about the guys in New York?
Was renting out their vans for 100 bucks?
Pretty cool. Didn't know that
is also help to have someone bankroll
you. Yes.
That's where you go for the seed
funding and stuff like that.
Venture capital.
If the idea is good,
you'll get the money usually.
But yeah, if you look at again,
if you go back to all of this stuff,
you know,
it all comes from solving a problem.
So we've seen a lot of a lot of change
in the software industry
because of examples
like the ones I'm sharing with you guys.
And you've guys seen this all across.
You know, in the last 20 years.
You've seen everything is changing
just on a day to day basis.
I think about a year ago or year plus ago,
no one knew about what Tick Tock was.
It wasn't even that popular.
But now if you look at Tick Tock is
destroying Facebook and Instagram, right?
You see, even never thought
that someone could compete, Let's say
Instagram or Facebook
didn't really think it was possible,
but hey,
someone came with a better version.
Actually, you know, they came in.
Look at how it is now.
So, you know, it's it's crazy.
It's crazy how things are changing.
Let's look at some other technologies.
This, guys, 60 years ago,
this is a data processing division.
What is it?
That's a massive hard drive, guys.
You see right there, 60
or maybe this is more like 7080 years ago.
But this is what I IBM hard drive
really look like we're talking about
we're talking about 60 today.
How big is that?
If you had to have four people
just put it on to on a truck or whatever,
they're try to do it, but look at how much
the technology has changed.
And I'm sure that probably cost thousands
and thousands and thousands of dollars,
if not hundreds of thousand.
So one gigabyte capacity, I would say more
like one megabyte capacity of that,
then one gigabyte or not this broad
and this will probably have more like one
megabyte.
We're talking about the supercomputers.
Yeah. Now look at this one, guys.
30 years ago, a hard disk
that was ten megabytes
cost $3,398.
This is maybe, what, maybe 30 years ago?
Yeah, and look at right
next to it, a five to hour.
Goodbye. SanDisk right here.
So just looking at this stuff, you can see
that you're not in the hardware world.
It's changing quite a bit cost wise.
Everything nowadays
you have these SanDisk ones, little small
flash drives
that can have a terabyte on there.
And this thing right here
probably had maybe one megabyte, right.
The size of data could store our
our phones itself stuff right here.
These phones can hold
millions of data, basically.
So if we look at it,
it looks it's is changing quite a bit
when it comes down to all these things
are changing at a very, very fast pace.
If we really look at it and it's because
of, you know, our Internet
and so someone coming up
with that solution
thinking of a problem and coming up
with a solution, ingenious solutions.
And here it is, though,
if we see right here
and see, by the way, give me
let me give you another example.
Just just because we were on here in the
early 2000, how did you guys send money?
You guys remember
or maybe early nineties when you wanted
to send money internationally?
I like this one
because I use this Western Union, right?
Western Union then came out PayPal
and now we have what Venmo, we have
Cash app.
We have so many resume.
Yeah there's a lot of different one right?
PayPal was one of the biggest changer
in the early 2000.
Who does anyone know
who created PayPal by the way,
or who was one of the founders?
Elon Musk was one of the founders,
and then Peter Thiel and a few other guys
came up with PayPal.
Right.
And look how much you changed.
Not Elon has all sort,
you know, been involved in other projects
that are pretty fascinating, too.
One of the project guys,
everyone knows Tesla, for example.
Right.
By the way, he did not start Tesla,
the company itself.
There were other people
who established the car company
when he became a majority holder
into there.
He basically took it to the next level,
but he did not invent the
Tesla, by the way.
He did not come up with the car
at at the very beginning.
So just know this.
But also not just Tesla. Right.
Look how much the before the you know,
keep in mind, guys,
look at this one, this example. Right.
20 years ago,
this technology was still available.
Hydrogen cars were available, everything.
But no one made it successful. Right.
But when someone made a successful right
now, look how much changes are coming in
2000, eight, 2000, nine or 2012,
when Tesla became more popular
electric car, a lot of people,
you know, thought that
it wasn't going to become the new thing.
It wasn't going to take over.
But now every company
is competing with Tesla just so they can
come up with electric versions.
Someone came up with a change,
which a lot of people at first doubted
that change. Right.
And you know what else is happening
right now?
By 2025, I believe, and 2035
in the United States,
all cars have to be electric.
Did you guys know that
they're getting rid of of basically
gasoline cars and in Europe
they're more strict by
I believe if I'm correct, it's 2025
and in the United States, it's 2035.
So you see what's happening.
Someone came up with a change.
Not even government policies are changing.
So many things are changing.
But, you know, it's happening
for the better.
But, you know, if you look at it,
it was only just ten years
ago, it's maybe 2030 in Europe.
Maybe. That's right.
That was 2025, though,
but it's changing quite a bit.
Now, another example, just because
we're talking about Elon in this point,
all the other companies
that he had, that's very,
very famous.
Now, Space X, does anyone know what Space
X does?
Solar what?
I think that's a field project.
They have reusable rockets, right?
Basically they came up with something
called reusable rockets.
Now they filled a lot of times
the guy almost went bankrupt
just trying to make it successful.
But what is
what is the reusable rockets basically do?
So let's say before
you wanted to send a satellite
or something into space, right, Maci?
I think the cost of doing that
would cost anywhere 600 to 800 million.
That's how much you would cost
to send basically space into space, right.
When it came to Tesla,
when it came to SpaceX s
Space X, they made reusable rockets.
They cut the cost down to 30 to 60 million
and basically, you know, changed
the entire game of the space race.
If you look at it, though.
So they cut the cost
and they used the exact same,
you know, rockets again land them.
Of course, they failed.
A lot of times you've
probably seen a lot of videos online
where they failed so many times.
But if you look at it, the
you know, someone came up with that gene
no one believed.
And when the cost if you look at the
before that were in the 600
to 800 millions,
now we're talking about 30 to 60 million.
Now they're winning
even more and more contracts.
Now, there's also,
I believe there's origin by Jeff Bezos.
He has a company, too.
But you see someone coming up
with some change
and that those changes
are really basically making a difference.
And now it's happening
at a very fast pace.
So we're
we're part of this culture right now
where things are going to change fast.
More technology's going to come fast.
But we need to understand
what's behind all of this, though.
But before we get into that, I'm
making my point here.
Let's look at a few other examples.
Look at this one, guys.
This is the craziest thing.
And I think one of the biggest factor to
this is also because of Internet.
This is a little old, outdated slide here.
But I found this very interesting
number of years it took for each product
to gain 50 million user, 68 years
it took for Ally.
That's crazy, right?
Telephone 50 will just go over, skip
some television 22
computer took 14 years.
Cell phone 12 years.
iPod took four years, which is not bad
50 million.
That means 50 million were sold.
And then when you look at Facebook
three years
and we look at Pokemon Go,
which came out in 2016,
I believe it took 19 days
for 15 million people to get access.
And I think of
that is because of this right here, guys,
because of this phone right here.
Great life changer.
But look at the access
we're getting, guys.
46 years for electricity
to reach 50 million and it took Hulk
Mongo 19 days guys 19 days
nowadays
if you are let's say think about this
you can actually reach more
than 50 million.
Now let's see your Cristiano Ronaldo,
right?
He's the the most popular
what is the most popular Instagram figure?
Right.
He has like 300 million followers, right.
When he makes a post, let's say,
for example, millions of people are seeing
exactly what he's selling or whatever
he's talking about.
Right. This is technology, guys.
That's what Instagram did right now
with the crazy followers he has, or Messi
to anyone.
Basically, teenagers crash the world.
You can say that in some way,
but I digress.
Kylie I don't know. Maybe.
But I think it's Ronaldo.
I think he's the number one
when it comes to social media.
But keep in mind, it's
300 million people access to him.
Basically, he can sell the products.
Kylie became a billionaire
from Instagram, right,
because of the reach
the how much their reach is.
So because of Internet
and because of these apps.
This is what's happening ladies.
I think there's a guy name
can be or something
he makes this funny videos like this
like he does right?
He has 100,000,001.
I just keep up with some of this things,
but even I'm forgetting
some of these things.
This Gen Z crazy.
You guys are a little bit too fast.
I feel old compared to you guys
and keeping up with you.
So technology changing. Changing?
Yeah. He never speaks, right?
Yeah. Good.
He never speaks. He has 100 million
from 0 to 0.
I visited a slide just so you can look at.
This is a little older one too.
I couldn't find the latest one.
But in 2017,
let's triple this by the number.
Let's say Amazon
sales were what, in every minute to 58?
I'll probably put it a million
at this point with a tweet said
about one about half a million
every minute.
Skype calls were about 150,
maybe probably 300,000.
Now, who knows?
YouTube views or million views
are watch probably at this point
since it's four year old, This this
this picture is probably I would say
probably five, six or seven at this point.
So as you can see, massive,
massive growth.
Massive growth is happening
in all the sector of tech.
When we look at especially apps
and things like that, you know,
it's it's going crazy.
So many things getting viral
and things like that.
It's it's a make
it makes a huge difference.
People can literally become superstars
overnight if their video becomes binary.
I mean, things are really changing.
No one really thought of these things
ten years ago, but now it's happening.
It's happening.
I mean, what's happening now
with even the cryptocurrency right now
we're talking about,
you know, in the future, probably next
five years.
Sounds like something else. Okay.
I'm not going to say that because anyway,
but let's say in the next five years,
cryptocurrency will become a reality.
I believe so At least some companies,
whether you agree,
whether you don't agree.
But even the way I mentioned your example
of WeChat, people in China use that.
The same thing can become that, right.
So if we look at it, it's
happening at a very, very, very fast pace.
Now to keep up with all of this rate
in order
to keep up with this exponential growth
we're talking about on the software side.
Right. We must have some sort of system.
Yeah, it is all the tech right now.
We're just talking about tech in
of course.
I mean, even in other industry,
it's going to take an eternity
just to talk about it.
But to keep up with all of this,
for example,
we're talking just from the software
point of view,
you see how much growth there is,
how much thing is going on.
We need to have some sort of processes.
You cannot just come up with the next next
Tik Tok app or tip top.
Who knows, whatever the next thing
was going to be just like that.
There must be some sort of standards,
some set of procedures
that we need to follow.
And now we're coming to the point
basically, and that process itself is
when you want to make the next app,
let's say, for example,
it's called software
development lifecycle.
This is what we're coming to now.
Now we're coming to the main
things, right?
So it comes down to something
called the software development lifecycle.
This is the structure
behind any successful app that comes out,
any successful, you know, a next
big tech company that comes out
that created a new official,
not an old offering.
The there must be some sort of software.
Right.
And without this without this structure,
you know, it's not really possible.
It can it is possible. Sorry.
But it will be more difficult. Right.
So what were you going to get into now
is basically what is the world of software
development lifecycle as you guys
are going to be part of this industry?
Now, you guys could be working for
Amazon too tomorrow.
You could work for Netflix,
you can work for any of these communities,
mammoth companies
or maybe a start up tomorrow,
but you will see
who are the people behind it.
It's not just one person
who invents this crazy opportunity.
It involves an entire team.
It involves a process.
Before I get in, before
I go into more of the technicals
and start explaining to you
how this works, I'll give you some example
from a different perspective on it
so you can kind of see a picture.
Now, this is just a high level example.
I'll give you two example.
So let's say you want to build a house.
I give this example every single time and
let's say you are a wealthy couple, okay?
We are a wealthy couple
and you have a lot of money
and you want to first
make a decision, Do we buy a house
or do we build our dream house?
Let's say you husband and wife
had this conversation.
You know what?
Where are you going to build our
dream house because we are filthy rich.
We have 100 million in our account.
Whatever. Right.
Let's say for the example.
Okay, So you've decided
that you're going to build a house
instead of buying a house, right.
What do you think happens then? Right.
You most likely will reach out to who?
How do you let's say, for example,
if you want to build a house,
who do you reach out to?
Most likely,
probably some sort of construction company
who has architects, engineers
and everything.
Contractor, but
someone who can basically builders Right.
Let's say hypothetically,
let's say you talk to the builders, right?
Let's say you have a construction company
that has designers, everything, right?
For example.
So now you have that company,
okay, You have a meeting with them,
you tell them, okay,
my dream house needs to have a pool
and used to have a tennis court.
It needs to have a 20 seed, let's say.
Don't know.
A movie
theater needs to have four garages,
whatever you want, 20
rooms, blah, blah, blah.
All the details you write right?
Basically you would.
We need to explain that to the builders
what you want them to build for you,
right?
Let's say you're the wealthy couple.
Let's say I'm Bill Gates tomorrow.
You know, billions of dollars.
That's exactly what I want.
I want a house with this, this,
this amenities.
Right? So think of your dream house,
whatever you want.
Maybe you want a
I don't know, a racetrack, a house.
I don't know. Whatever you want,
basically. Right.
So you explain that to the let's say,
the construction company or the company
that is going to build your your house,
for example, all the things that you want.
Now, let's say you've done that part.
You know,
you tell them all the house you want,
you want indoor pool, outdoor pool,
whatever you want.
Basically, let's say
you get all the requirements now.
Now what basically the company will do is,
of course, you had the old shoe,
the land, blah, blah, blah,
all the things.
But most likely
they'll show you a blueprint of what
the house will look like.
Right.
You see property, those,
you know, sketches are,
you know, designers will work on it.
So mean things will happen.
They'll come up with basically a blueprint
of what the house really looks like.
We'll go over those details.
Let's say you approve it, right?
By the way, guys,
of course, there's more than that.
There's permits, so many things out there.
But just for the sake of this example,
right, you will,
let's say, get a blueprint.
Once you get a blueprint.
Right.
If let's say everything is approved,
everything is good to go,
what happens then?
They go down to the construction
part, right?
The building.
Basically, builders will come
you all the construction work
and they'll start putting the cement,
the foundation, everything right,
blah, blah, blah.
Let's say it takes six months, right?
So they start building the house Now after
the house is built, let's say,
for example, everything is done.
What do you think usually happens, Right.
Of course is not checked off completely,
but what kind of things will happen?
Let's see.
It's it's built in.
You're looking for you're
trying to finalize things, right?
Probably tests, inspection rate.
You will do an inspection,
inspector will come, you know.
Okay, this is off.
This is you know,
switches are not working, whatever it is.
Right.
They'll basically do the inspections
when the inspection is done.
You know, good to go. Everything is good.
You basically make the last payments,
everything, etc..
And then most likely you'll go.
And if something needs fixing
or it most likely will be fixed.
Right.
And then you basically the wealthy family
will most likely move in.
Is that a typical process?
Do you think that's how it typically works
without the finer details?
Guys,
Do you guys think that's how it looks like
typically? Right.
That's basically the high level
of basically then divorce later.
Hopefully that but yeah, it could happen.
But yeah basically that's your
your typical idea
of how a house could possibly be built.
Right now
the same way, guys, the same exact way.
If you look at it,
softwares are built to
you see there's there's there is
if you look at it,
software is built in the exact same way
just with more different terms
and key terms.
Now, when we apply to this
and I'll give you another example, right.
I used to give this a
I know this probably was okay,
I'll give you another example.
I give his names Apple,
every time I try to relate to real life.
Now I know, for example, Lamborghini
used to call let's say,
a supercar company, right?
Right now Lamborghini has SUV.
Did you guys know that the
the Auris is the most popular SUV in
right now
from the line of Lamborghini Supercars.
Yeah that's the one but they were not
known for, let's say before SUV, right?
They were absolutely not known for that.
So let's say tomorrow Ferrari decides,
hey, you know what,
The Lambo SUVs are selling crazy.
Not Ferraris are not really known for,
you know,
I don't know, trucks or anything like that
or SUV.
Right.
What do you think goes
through their mindset?
Think about this now.
Think of of a company massive company
they have never done
basically, for example,
never built an SUV, a Ferrari SUV.
They probably will do research right?
Yeah. How can we do this better?
They have to see, like if we built
tomorrow, let's say, for example,
they will do the R&D. Yes, absolutely.
If we build tomorrow, the Ferrari
SUV, are people going to be interested?
Let's see this. Let's do a show of hand.
Let's say you are filthy rich.
Okay, Right now, just an example.
Would you buy a Ferrari SUV or not
if it was available in the market?
Okay, so a lot of no's.
Okay, great.
Some yes.
Okay, fine.
Maybe you got it.
Let's let's take this most yes.
How about that?
Let's just say
for the sake of the example, right?
Let's say for the sake of example,
if you all said yes, it's
like all everyone says yes, you know,
Ferrari, as you would be very nice.
You know, Ferrari
is going to think about these things.
Is there demand for what I'm building?
If I'm going to come up with a new SUV,
which we never known for, Right.
We've known for a two door red sporty car
that we've never even tackled.
AC Is there going to be a demand for this?
Okay, fine.
Let's say this.
If there's a demand for it,
then they need to look at,
okay, is it going to be a four door?
Is going to be a two door SUV?
Is it going to have 600 horsepower?
Is it going to have a thousand words rate?
What kind of agent V, ten V8,
whatever it is
they have to go through
all those different specifications.
What the car needs to have. Right.
Once they basically come up
with all the specs and everything.
Okay, we're going to have the SUV
with the, I don't know, four doors.
We're going to have the doors
open this way,
that way, whatever they basically are,
whatever they're thinking, right?
Then they basically go through that.
The phase of it, Right.
If you guys have seen
maybe online videos, you've maybe seen,
you know, they will design it on paper,
but also sometime you've seen that,
you know, they design it on clay.
If you have ever seen that, a lot of times
they make a mock of in, let's say, clay
and they start putting everything
just to kind of get
feel of it right,
how it looks like and everything.
So let's say they do the designing
and everything
from their idea of going to the factory.
Let's say design got approved
factory goes in all the parts,
the assembly line,
everything gets put together.
Everything basically there is
get bought easily and they do it right.
So let's say the car gets assembled
what happens after that.
Usually testing happens, right?
They do the crash testing all the things,
everything if you look at it.
So when they basically do all the testing,
everything is good.
The cars that pass the test,
they end up basically in a in a showroom
somewhere and maybe a Ferrari showroom
or somewhere else. Right.
I'm sure there's more to it,
but just for the sake example,
they end up over there, right?
And then one of you lucky
people will basically buy this one day.
Right?
So if you look at it, similar process.
Yeah. Then push it to the market. Right.
So if you look at guys similar prices,
the way a house is built,
the way a car is built,
everything goes through a cycle.
If you look at it, it's a cycle.
So Now it's connecting down to what in
it looks like.
It's the exact same cycle.
But now we're going to use different names
for it.
We're going to use different,
you know, we're going to call it
in a different way, basically.
Right.
So does it make sense
how a product is built?
Are you guys getting the picture
of what it looks like?
I just want to get it and see.
Does it make sense
how I connected everything,
how technology is changing everything.
Okay, great.
Great, great.
Okay. It makes sense. Perfect. Perfect.
I just want to make sure
you guys get the big picture.
That's why I give you a lot of examples
at the beginning.
See how technology changing
and what's behind that
is. Deployment is one of
the steps
in, as is not really a step though.
But that happens
and I'll explain that later.
Okay, so now what to do?
When are we going to go into this?
You have the big pictures
of how software is basically built, Right?
So now let's break down these steps
planning analysis,
design, implementation, testing,
integration and maintenance.
Now, what we're going to do
is see what happens in each phase in
when we look looking, when you're going
to be working tomorrow in a company,
for example, who are going to be
the people you'll be working with
and what is it like
basically how a software is built, right?
So we're going to go into that
after the end of Mike.
And then what's still your money from?
Some companies will do maintenance,
some companies will not do,
and I'll explain that a little bit later.
Okay.
So first thing,
what happens is whenever a company
wants to build a software, remember
there's there's two type of companies
you need to understand in the tech world,
okay?
Ones that build their own software,
basically, let's say
let's say, for example,
I don't know who can say Facebook
or let's say Google everything.
They build their own softwares, right?
They build their own.
So the company is building own products,
basically.
Right?
And then there are companies
that are basically
another company builds
a software for them.
For example, banks for example, they're in
the operation of running the banks.
They don't make their apps
and things like that.
They usually hire a big company,
Hey, build this software for me, right?
So there's two ways to look at it.
We're going to use an example
in the sense of
of basically the company that hires
another big company and makes offers.
If you guys have heard of Deloitte,
have you guys any one of these big, big,
big shot companies,
consulting firms, Deloitte,
Accenture CGI, I don't know who.
Booz Allen, Massive
consulting firms, right.
They don't have a product of their own,
but these are big companies basically
who builds wind projects
and build something for another company.
So let's say tomorrow, the government.
The government is not in the business of,
let's say, making softwares, right?
So they would need to hire a company
that's going to build something for them.
Right.
Of course, now big even hire
Google, let's say.
But Google has their own projects.
They'll work on their own. Right.
So let's say, for example,
a company wants to build a software
right of or let's say
a bank wants to build a software.
They or they want a software,
they're not going to build it.
Most likely
they're going to hire someone, right?
They're going to basically hire
like Deloitte, Booz Allen or some company
and pay them millions of dollars
Hey, built me this software basically.
But what happens at the beginning,
right at the very beginning,
that this is not where you and I testers
developers involved
but very high up management people.
What they do is something they do
something called a feasibility study.
What they do is to figure
out is there an adequate demand
for my product.
That's a very important thing, guys.
Is it marketable?
Is this going to be let's
see if we build this software,
if they decide to sell it later
on, is it going to be really successful?
Are we going to make any money on this?
Are we going to actually be successful?
This is the very first part
that happens at the very beginning.
The initial planning part
and a feasibility study
happens at the beginning.
Now, why do you guys think is important?
What do you guys think?
Do you guys think is this an important
aspect of when you're building
a software, if there's an adequate
demand marketable or is it not?
Is it a timely story as the
studying
the market is very important, Yes.
Yeah.
You guys know, guys take a wild guess.
What is the average?
What percentage of startups fail
do you guys know?
Let me ask you this question.
New startups.
Yes. Someone did some research.
Good.
90% 998.
Thankfully not.
But 90% of startups fail.
So tomorrow you think you have the genius
idea of a new app?
Let's for example, right?
You think you have the greatest app
and everything.
For example,
you can fill in any of these category.
You have to understand
this one saying this to you
because I used to build apps,
by the way, for living.
I used to put a lot of apps in around
2011, 2012,
a lot of apps in the App Store.
Then I got out of it.
It wasn't profitable.
But to give you an idea, right,
a lot of startups feels
because they think their idea
is the greatest.
First of all, they first.
Everyone thinks the idea is the greatest,
but maybe the market doesn't really think
that way.
Remember that You might think
your idea is awesome and great,
but maybe someone
it might be great for you,
but it might not be great for the majority
of the audience if you look right.
The other thing is not just that,
is it marketable?
Do you even have the budget?
Can you market this?
For example, the idea that you have?
Are people really going to click on
the let's say on your app, for example,
how to compete into that,
not just that the return of investment?
Are we going to make any money on this
probability of achievement and success?
If we look at all of this,
this is very, very important
how you find out.
There's a lot of different processes,
a lot of
do they do surveys,
they do a lot of research,
look at competitors,
so many things, a lot of research,
a lot of companies, if you look at
they do research and develop R&D.
They do this a lot of times
because for for a company
to let's say I'll give you an example,
Google Glass is right.
You guys remember Google Glass out in 2009
or ten or something like that.
We thought it would be a cool concept,
but it failed.
Google came up with the Google glasses.
No one wanted that thing. It
bombed. Right?
Or even I think
Snapchat came out spectacles or something.
They failed to Facebook came up with
what's they.
Facebook came out with a phone.
They came out with the
phone. They didn't have it.
Do not have any app for syntax.
I don't have app for syntax.
So if you look at even big companies,
we're talking about billions
and billions of dollars companies fee.
Yeah, they had a phone actually
Facebook came up with a Facebook phone.
It looked horrible.
It was ugly.
Even evil Windows, Microsoft,
Microsoft came out with the Windows Phone,
if you guys remember.
But it failed. It failed in this category.
If you look at in the very beginning,
maybe their research was telling them
something else, but it didn't happen.
So to understand this, guys, is
this is a very important part
when you're trying to build a product or
let's say a company is hiring something,
they have to do that feasibility study,
they have to do planning a lot of detail.
The same thing.
Like I said, if Ferrari is going to build
an SUV tomorrow, they got to see
is there demand, Can we market, is
can we make money on this
or is it going to succeed?
Also, remember for for last ten years,
maybe now they're profitable.
Uber was never profitable,
by the way, guys.
Uber and Airbnb,
they became profitable afterwards.
Long term vision, right?
Return of investment
right there, long term.
So it takes time.
Guys,
You have to understand it takes time.
And also companies have
to make very tough decision
at the very beginning.
Whatever product they're going to build
is their demand for this is or not.
So that's why we see 90% of failed
because this is the part
that they feel that not enough demand
for this market ability
return on investment and also data
in some time, you know, executing well.
Right.
So we looking at this some keep in mind
someone who is trying to build the app
and they don't do this part, the very
first part of SDLC they're doomed.
They're doing from day one right.
Okay now when this happens, right,
and that planning happen,
let's see company A, hired company
B to build their software.
So let's say company
A, The bank hired Deloitte right now.
Right. Okay.
We're going to take you on this project.
We did the research.
We want this product built for us
or this app built for.
Okay, great. That's awesome.
Now what happens?
Okay, well, let's see what happens
when this comes in life, right?
Okay,
So now I need to basically what happens is
from company, let's see
which, is the client, for example, Right.
Who you building the software
And they have, let's say Deloitte,
the company, they won millions of dollars.
Let's say the project.
They basically hired
to build this project.
Okay.
So there is an individual
that basically works directly
between these two company A, company
B individuals called business analysts.
Now, you are not going
to become a business owners,
but you will be interacting with business.
And these are some of the members
that you're going to be interacting with.
What is their job?
Basically, what their job is, is
talk to the client in this situation.
Client is company
who's paying millions of dollars
to Deloitte to build a software, right?
So from Deloitte side,
an individual called business
analyst is going to go to Company A
and ask them, What do you want?
I want a software that can do
blah, blah, blah.
Like Sarah, the client might say, okay,
how do you want it?
Right?
This is what happens behind the picture.
Now let's say the planning happens
now my team goes there
and try to basically figure out
what's going on.
So I'll give you an example.
I used to work for Hewlett
Packard Enterprise.
Give me an example.
Hewlett Packard have guys heard of HP?
I'm hoping some of you have the computers
of HP and Hewlett Packard Enterprise.
So Hewlett Packard had a consulting side
just like Deloitte,
even though they make laptops,
but they had another sector enterprise
side of it which basically
built application for other companies.
So I used to work Hewlett
Packard Enterprise and one of our project
was to work with United State
Postal Service.
They needed a new application
modernization of office, basically.
So if you guys are local,
they're located in Sterling or Herndon.
That's where I used to work.
I used to work there, and our project
was with the government, right?
So our project was with the government.
Hewlett Packard Enterprise won
millions of dollars of project to build
some software or update a software
for the United States Postal Service.
The software itself was basically
a management
tool for basically all the post office.
If something broke down or something
like that, they can make a ticket
there and vendors can build on it
and fix this
issues at the post office.
Basically that was a software, right?
So to give you an example,
we used to from our end,
basically if you guys are local,
you would know
the headquarter for the United States
Postal Service is in Washington, D.C.
They're in Farragut Square regard,
which when it is,
but they're in Washington, D.C.
So from HP, we had individuals
called business analysts every week
or at the very beginning of the project,
they would travel to
basically the headquarter
and have meetings there.
And in those meetings
they would ask the client client is now
basically the United States
Postal Service,
which has been millions of dollars
to HP to build a software, Right.
Pay millions of dollars basically to them.
And from there and HP side,
we as someone would go a business
and is whose job is to basically
get all the information right
and what I need to show you
this this is what is
their job is to get all the requirements.
The requirements are descriptions
of features,
functionalities of the target system.
This is very important to look at. It
functionalities.
What do they want us to build?
It basically can be is user expectation
from the software product
what the client wants writing it down,
analyze it and document
it is known as requirement gathering.
So this individual, for example,
would go meet the clients
and gather a lot of these requirements.
Okay, By requirements we mean this.
So let's say United States Postal Service
wanted this new application right?
Let me see.
Someone had a great business
and I listen to these requirements
for clients in between chain.
Yep. Absolutely I should. That's correct.
So basically what they do,
their job is okay, you want this software?
Okay. Okay, great.
You want this software to be well.
Do you want a log in functionality? Okay.
Do you want log in function?
Do you want to log in to be with Facebook
or do you want specific with Google?
Whatever it is,
do you want, let's say this software
to be open on Google Chrome only?
Or is it, let's say, for example,
mobile version of it?
They could be asking things like, okay,
how can we create new users?
Okay, do you want users?
Whatever the functionality is, right?
What are the software needs to be built?
Let's give you an easy example. Let's see.
When Facebook was being built, right,
you had a log in first,
then you had a story
come in, then you had a feed page.
All of these are requirements
what Facebook wanted.
So the same thing when basically
when it comes down to the beginning
requirements are all the functionalities,
whatever you want to do.
If you wanted to calculate one plus one is
do you have to tell?
Basically, yeah,
I want this software to do this.
You know, all those functionality,
all the features,
what this software supposed to do.
And that is the job of a business analyst
to write them down.
Exactly.
They make notes of all of this. Okay.
Whatever.
They have their excel documents it take
they speak back and forth
and take all of this information
and they make it in a readable way
so that future team can work on it.
Are we getting the picture
of how it works?
Basically.
Okay.
Business Analyst
You will be working with them
because they gets the requirement.
Remember this,
This is the most important part
and they're one of the most
important people in your team.
They're the one who basically writing down
all the information.
Right.
So let's look at more in detail
what exactly a requirement
requirement done by B, Okay, that's fine.
Talking to client, giving a go.
So basically what they're trying to do is
and use the person
that will be using this application
the most by end user we mean is, look,
when we're talking about HP and post
office, right?
We're talking
to, let's say the business people.
But that's the headquarter, right.
That's the corporate office.
The postman doesn't work
at the corporate office.
They work at all the other location.
But end user would be the person
who's actually using this software
at the post office, Right?
Corporate office
is just giving you details, etc., etc..
Stakeholders.
Are people involved in this project
who have this thing?
Industry analysts, meaning people
from the post office, Right.
They're giving all these feedback,
collecting information from competitor
is everything.
Basically what this does is
what a requirement gathering.
Yes, they will.
They will talk to all the individuals.
So let's say someone from from post
office, right.
In the sense of, okay, how do you want?
Because remember,
if if there's a business person from USPS
giving all the details
and he's never been in a post office.
Right.
He's not the right person
to ask information for someone
who you're building the software. Right?
So there are different members
that will give the feedback.
We want this.
We want this
because someone who
is working on the post office using that
software will have more information.
Remember, this will have more information
and more understanding
what their software needs to be.
So what what a business.
And this they talk to all these
different people and basically get
all the information, whatever they
whatever they want, all of that.
Basically they got it.
I'm going to go over one slide and then
I'm going to give you guys a quick break.
Okay, guys, So
do we understand that a business analyst
will talk to people, business people.
They will talk to people from post office.
Whoever their people are, doesn't matter.
They will talk to them, gather,
pick their brain, you know, brainstorming.
What do you guys want?
How do you want it to be?
Give me all the details.
Because remember this
based on this details,
this software is going to be built.
Whatever detail is not mentioned,
it's not going to be built.
So it's very important for business
analysts
to grab all of this information right.
That's what they do.
Now, sometimes this picture is a harsh
reality of what happens in i.t.
Not to look at this picture.
I recommend gathering it
as is very important.
Why the business owners have to do a job
well, what the customer really wanted.
This is just for example, right?
And this happens a lot by way
how the customer explained it.
A lot of times
the customers
don't know exactly what they want,
so they might have a clear picture,
especially if their business people
who are not tech related,
they definitely don't know
how the customer explained it,
how the engineer is,
meaning how the developers developed it,
how the project leader, meaning
project manager probably understood
what is basically happening,
how the program eroded
and what the customer really needed.
This picture is very important
to understand this happens
a lot in the very beginning, guys.
It happens a lot.
And trust me when I say this, when you
guys start working, you will see this
what the customer wants.
You might think he wants this,
he wants that.
A lot of this, a lot of money gets
wasted on the so much thing happens.
That's why the the best job
is the most important job business.
And this job is very important
because if they can get all the
requirements clear, where are you going
to end the building of this?
We're going to end up building on this
even though the customer
wants something like this.
Right.
So it's very important, though.
Remember this, you will be working
with business families.
They will be your colleagues,
your peer to peer. Right.
You will be working. This is important.
You know what they're doing now.
What is the best way for the business
analysts to do their job?
Actually know what?
Let's take a break before I get into more.
We have a lot more left.
So let's take a quick 15 minute break.
And guys, please do remind me
when we come back in 15 minutes,
850 in 15 minutes or 849, that's fine.
Let's get back.
Do remind me to start recording by the.
All right, guys.
So take a quick 15 minute break.
I'm going to pause the scene
and hopefully get back.
All right.
Yes. Thank you for reminding.
And it started there.
I Saw someone said, let me see
something.
Someone said I was debating
whether to choose instead of be.
If you're very good at writing
and communication is strong,
being is the way to go in that.
So that's what they do.
They're very good at communication
and lots of writing.
That's what business analysts really do.
All right.
Any questions before we continue?
We do have some more to cover, of course,
but any questions,
anything you wanted more examples
or anything as such?
Please do ask right now.
Are you okay?
I am recording. Yes.
Thank you.
No, so far. Okay, Good. Good.
I think
this is
pretty straightforward,
but these are very important concepts
because it gives you the big
pictures of how it works
and you will become part of this.
All right.
So let's continue, guys.
So this picture, as you guys
see, it's very common.
It happens all the time.
Projects get delayed sometimes.
They are.
I'll give you example, Bobby, tomorrow.
They're literally billions of dollars
of projects that have gone to waste
because of bad requirements.
Guys, literally it's it's going to be some
you can have a big problems
if the requirements are not clear
when we start learning automation tools.
Well you start learning coding
first programing on the we can decide
we will start with Java.
Once you learn programing quite a bit,
then you add on the automation to later
step by step.
So you
need coding before you get into that.
So anyway, guys,
back to this picture, very,
very important picture and very clear
that, you know, from outside
you think all projects and everything
companies
operate so efficiently and smooth,
but that's not really the case.
A lot of times this happens.
Developer might think that, okay,
I need to develop this, but
when they really the client want something
else, it really does happen quite often
it's it's okay
it's not a perfect world
as it seem from the outside.
A lot of things happen
when you go to a tech company.
And like I said, business
analyst part is the most important
because they're the one interacting
with a client and it's their job
to pick their brains, get all the ideas,
get all the functionalities
they want because.
Based on that, what's going to happen?
Will this be a PowerPoint?
Yes, All of these will be in canvas.
That's correct.
Okay. One.
Now remember this.
It's not important for you to know
all the details
of a business, and it's because you're
not becoming a business analyst.
But it's good to know how the
process works
because you will be interacting with them.
Now, what is a very good way of
basically for a business analyst strictly
to gather requirements
while they use something called
smart criteria, which basically
means specific, measurable, attainable,
relevant time based,
if they get their,
let's say, requirements in this manner,
you know, they
they have a very good chance
of getting solid requirements in later on
answering all the questions
and needs of what the customer wants.
So let's break down
what exactly is smart criteria.
Let me see.
Okay, So smart criteria, as you look at it
here.
Clear, concise, correct, consistent,
verifiable and modifiable.
But let's going to more
what is it by specific?
It means it needs to be exact.
The the bar needs to ask
very important questions.
Let's say if I go to buy a car,
should I provide details
like car needs to be a four door
SUV backup, camera, etc., etc..
Right.
Authorized user with valid user name
pastor should be able to sign up or log
in right now.
Of course
more the technical one non-technical.
What does that mean? Specific?
Hey, can authorized user only be able to
log in or anyone can log into the system?
Right.
Very important questions
that a business owners needs to ask
when they're building potential software
for for the client.
Right. Measurable.
What does that mean?
If I click this button, the response time
should be less than 2 seconds.
Wait a minute to.
Get specifics how long it needs to react,
what exactly it needs to be.
These are very, very
detailed questions,
but they're important for the software.
What if you build a software
and let's say you click on something
and it's let's say, I don't know, it takes
10 seconds to the job done or whatever.
Right now that's going to be an issue,
don't you think? So
that's going to be a major issue.
Catalina, you did not miss much.
I just went over into smart criteria,
basically, which is a process business
and is used to gather requirement
in the better efficient way.
If they do it this way, attainable.
This is very important.
Realistic should make sense.
If the client wants you to build something
that is the technology is not even out
there, you have to tell the client
that's not possible.
Now, this is very important to understand.
Why I see this, guys, is a lot of times
companies, especially the consulting work,
they really greedy.
Hey, this is the harsh reality.
They've taken projects.
Sometimes they think
they might even be able to build.
But if someone offers, let's say,
Hewlett-Packard
$10 million to build a software,
they're not going to say no
to $10 million. Right.
That happens a lot.
A good example would be, guys, are Obama,
Obamacare, the healthcare.gov
that was launched
in 2011 and 12,
that was a not realistic project, guys.
It was rushed into it.
They spend $1,000,000,000 and
they not even crashed on the first date.
Does anyone know how many people
signed up on the first date?
Anyone have any idea?
Remember that the person that saw
the application
cost was over $1 billion.
200 people signed up.
Less than ten guys.
Less than ten people
signed up on to on the very first day.
And that software costs over
$1,000,000,000, not realistic, right?
It wasn't something
that's supposed to be built
that was yours in my taxpayers money.
What it is,
that's basically where it goes.
So so remember
these things are very important
when the business and this is getting
all of this information
realistic, how much time and money, for
example, building an entire application
for scratch and delivering to find one
month is not realistic.
That is very important.
Realistic meaning, you know, they need
to give proper information to the client.
Look,
this project is going to take five years.
No, don't expect it in one month.
It's just not possible. All in one year.
It takes a lot of time.
You know, first of all,
having the right talent, so many things.
Remember, when you go to
when you get into the tech world,
you're not just coding every day.
You have meetings, guys.
You interact with your business
analysts, you're dealing
you know, you talk to them to understand
what's going on.
You have other meetings,
You have you dealing with clients.
You're not always working 40 hours
coding in front of.
That's no, you have meetings,
have so many other things, right?
So just to understand this, that, look,
they have to get very
realistic requirements
and they have to make sure that,
you know, you know,
whatever they're building is right.
True story.
When we were when I worked
for Hewlett Packard Enterprise,
we got one of the project that we knew
was going to be fail from day one.
But sales Hewlett-Packard was greedy.
They took the project.
The client wanted this project
in one year,
and we knew right away
like, look, that's not possible.
This is going to take three years easily.
After one year,
they fired a lot of people.
And yes, the project continued, went on.
And of course, 10
million become 15 million, 20 million.
So these type of things do happen, guys.
And it's the job of the business
analyst to make sure be transparent
when basically getting these requirements
and when the client is basically,
you know, saying unrealistic
things or technology they want to build.
Not possible.
They have to basically make sure
they let them know, okay, this
now this is the right approach.
There's a mean yeah all business analysts
go according to my criteria probably not
absolutely not okay testable
a car test drive or should I be able
to download the PDF file into a second
meaning it's working is functioning right.
They they have to make sure it is
something that they want is going to be
actually testable in that sense.
So business analyst would use this
basically a smart criteria.
Make sure they get the right requirement.
Very detailed,
measurable, attainable, realistic
and testable if they follow this approach.
Most likely they're going to get very good
requirements and realistic ones
that can be achieved right with the right
deadline, basically.
Now, again,
you're not becoming a business analyst,
but it's important to know what a business
and is does
because you will be interacting
with the business analyst quite a bit.
Okay, now.
Okay,
let's I thought there was a question.
Let me see if there is any question.
Any questions?
No, it doesn't look like
I know person wrote it.
All right.
So when does testing begin?
Well, remember thing
when you start on a project,
remember this.
When you start on a project,
the business analyst is interacting with
the clients, getting all the requirements,
the requirements come back in.
Remember, you're part of this team.
Software development
lifecycle consists of you as a tester,
as a member rate business
analyst brought up all these requirements.
Now you as a tester shouldn't
assume all those requirements are correct
100% or.
They didn't remember this as a test.
Your job is to find loss
in the system,
make sure or break the system.
That's what you have to think.
You have to think in a way you get to be
the most
testers are the most experienced
with the application when it's built
because they try so many different ways
to find issues.
That's when you.
So as a tester, we should never assume
that requirements are correct.
We should never assume
that mistakes can be made.
This is why testing should start
with testing
the requirement against this
my criterion requirement characteristic.
So what it means is that before
you actually do any let's
coding and everything,
any testing you as a tester
should always look
at basically the requirements
and at the same time are kind of second
guessed them.
We basically start testing
from the requirement but not actual
trusting more like, you know, analyzing
the document and looking at angles.
Well, you the
the client said this application
needs to be working on Google Chrome,
but it doesn't say does
it need to be working on, let's say,
I don't know, Internet Explorer or Firefox
and other browsers to see that's something
what a testers can bring up
and start breaking. Because remember this
business and this
client's human being,
they forget things basically.
How many tests are in a project?
It depends.
The small project, 1 to 2 large product,
three or four.
It all depends.
So when we basically
when someone asks you, when does testing
begins, we actually start
testing the requirements.
Because remember those requirements
that the business owners gather,
they have to bring to the team, right?
Developers? TESTER All of them.
Okay. This is what the client wants
in those meetings.
What your job as a tester
is basically to kind of
kind of judge
these requirements and ask questions.
If requirements up is wrong, it that we're
going to build the application wrong.
The end result would be a disaster.
And some satisfied customer.
Remember, that's
what basically when the testers start
basic basically being in work, we involved
from the very beginning in this sense
we're involved as testers.
When the clients are giving
requirements, business and a business ask
to bring them to the team.
We're involved in those meetings
going over the requirements to understand
what because basically
the software needs to be built
and you give you a feedback and analyze
the requirements
at that time, making sure that, hey,
are we missing an angle?
What about this should be doing this?
What about beauty?
Anything that you bring up in, let's see.
It's not in the requirements.
That's what the job of a business
analyst would be like.
Okay, let me confirm with the client
if they want this or not.
Right.
So this is one we as testers
are doing basically non-coding testing.
Basically,
verification is what we're doing.
Does it make sense, guys?
All right. It's perfect.
So now after after the testing is done,
do you mean to double?
I want to say I should have doubted,
but look at it from a different angle.
Maybe they missed some points.
Remember, business owners
might not think of 50 points
way a tester does
because when you become a tester,
you guys,
you do a lot of different things.
You break the system, you try different
ways to find flaws, right?
So you experience impacts
that you will develop over time.
Are we more than what a business analyst
think They might not be thinking of
this think the client
might not be thinking of this
very specific way,
how a software needs to be working,
but you as a tester
later on will know some of those things
and you bring those details
up and question in the sentences like, huh
maybe it can be do to thinking
outside the box.
Absolutely.
You know, giving a different angles,
looking at from different way
of how they can be still flaws.
Absolutely.
You misremember
it is human beings make the application
so their logic can still be there
but they they can be limited.
If we do this where
the testers are like
detectives, that's the best way
to look at it and stuff like that.
All right.
So now let's say, for example,
the planning phases happen.
You know, in that planning phase you saw
what business and is doing everything.
What comes after the planning phase.
Now, we have done all of this.
We've done all the requirement.
What do you think comes afterwards?
Yes, the design phase.
Okay.
Now, this is the important phase of
basically bringing things slowly to life.
Okay.
Now, you as a as a tester,
you're not so much involved
in this phase,
but basically who's involved here now?
Here basically, when we talk about
the design phase, there's a lot of things
that happen to OC architects, developers
and individual called UI UX designers.
You know, they're all involved
in what they're doing in the design phase.
Well, I'll go to the next slide
so you can see they're basically
understanding, okay, all first of all,
we're going to build this software
in, let's say, Java or C++.
They're basically understanding which
programing language are we going to use.
Okay, how many servers do we need?
Architects are going to decide this. Okay,
How many servers?
What does that mean
is, let's say in the future, for example,
this application
get a of volume of people.
Can it hold the volume of people, Right.
All the infrastructure related stuff.
Okay.
Which database are we going to use. Right.
Basically which,
which tools we're going to use.
Okay.
How it's going to be in the future
when the system becomes bigger.
So now this is more technical details.
What the architect
and UI UX individuals,
they are the one basically designing this.
They're trying to understand
how the system will be
from the technical point
and, from the UI buy UI UI point.
What it means is user
interface designer job is to make sure
that the
the application looks nice and clean.
So what they do, they make something
called wireframes, right?
What is wireframes?
Wireframes is basically
how the application is supposed to look.
So it's a design, a mockup of it, right.
How it is going to look when it goes from
one piece to another page,
what the color will be, where the button
is going to be, all the thing.
It's basically
the now the designer is going to do this
UI, UX, this individual
who creates the interface.
Absolutely.
They are called UI UX user interface.
Basically they work and user experience
UI UX.
You might have seen this title somewhere
there.
Their job is to create the look and feel.
Now this is very important.
I'll give you an example which is easier
to use on iPhone or Android
iPods, right?
Very easy to use, for example,
very simple interface.
Great people like it
because it's easy to use.
Now when it becomes difficult, let's say,
for example, are you going to use it?
Most likely not. Right.
If the application is so difficult to use,
you have no idea what each button does
you most like.
You're not going to use that application.
You're going to have a bad experience
with that.
So what?
The job of a designer in the design
for you remember this in the design field,
architect, developer, UI, UX people,
they all have different jobs
within the design.
Architects are basically understanding
how many servers we need, what language
we're going to use, all this thing
with conversation with a developer
and all this, the technical detail
UI UX individual is coming up
with how it's going to look, which color
going to the esthetic,
how it's going to look,
is it going to be smooth to use
when it goes from one piece?
They want to make sure the user experience
is nice and clean.
It's easy to use if the application
is too complicated or is not having.
So they basically mix
all the sketches and everything.
They make the entire look and feel of
what the system is going to look like.
Does it make sense
What happens in the design phase?
Right. Pretty straightforward, right?
Pretty straightforward.
You as a tester, are you involved?
You might attend the meetings,
but you don't have much of input in here
because and keep in mind,
they're different people.
So now we know we met business analysts,
we kind of introduced you to architect
what's really do
they basically are doing the
the infrastructure related stuff
you might not interact with them
remember this you will most likely
not interact with that developer
we introduce UI
UX individual means introduced.
We have introduced for people outside
of being tester right now there remember
part of your team right now.
So those guys are involved in design
phase right?
And they're basically understanding what,
how the system is going
to look and feel at the same time,
how it's going to perform in the future.
Do we have the hardware,
do we have the right software?
All those details happens in
Asia.
There are different softwares
they can use for scalability
to see how much their grids, fake users
and things like that
that can tell how much load volume
it can handle.
So there are different softwares
out there.
They can, of course,
if they know big, the system is going
to be in the how many users going to use.
They get more servers and things.
And that's basically
when they decide from the beginning
they know who they're building for.
And the customer might tell them, let's
see how many users will be using it.
Right? Let's say, for example.
So in this design phase,
this is what happens now.
What do you think happens after the design
phase phase?
There you go. Now we're talking, right?
So we've done the planning phase.
Now we have designed it.
We come up with the blueprints.
Now we're going to go in to the coding
development phase.
Now, are you testers coding here or no?
Yes or no?
Yes. No, no, No. Okay. Or
okay.
Now, here in the development phase, yes.
Remember this.
You are not the one you will be coding.
Yeah, but you're not coding to develop it.
You're not the one in creating it.
Software developer, programing, engineers,
whatever name you want to call it.
Right. They're the one now building it.
They're going to use their language coding
skills to build whatever the UI is made.
Let's say the pictures, graphics,
everything, the UI, UX person meets,
they basically get that
and bring it to life, right?
So they bring all those skeletons.
Now they put them in the best way
to look at it.
You have a skeleton. Okay?
And you're putting the meat on it,
right? The muscles on it.
That's
what the developers is basically doing.
So they now bring it to life,
they creating the database,
They're doing all the stuff right now.
So this is where the developers do this.
They do their coding everything.
They check their code, everything is fine.
They are involved in creating.
So they are going to be
the one really focused on this part of it.
Are you involved here? Not really.
You work with developers, but.
But remember this
you might do similar coding like that.
But remember we look for flaws.
They create the system.
So same programing.
Maybe the developer using Java as well do,
and you as a tester
could be using Java as well.
Same could you could possibly
look at their code and possibly understand
what they've written.
You could absolutely get that.
You can to that point.
But remember, they're building it.
They're adding the UI part of it, pictures
and everything, making it to life.
So their process is going to be
a little bit different.
But this is what happens
in the development phase.
Now, after this, of course, comes
testing phase when something is developed,
then we go into something called phase.
This is where you guys come in now. Okay.
Now, of course, verify
this system works and meet all the bills.
Remember this. This is very important.
Verify that the system works and meets
all the business
requirements defined in the business
requirement Document.
Business requirement
document is what the business analysts
created by getting all those requirements
and documenting it right.
So now what the tester will do is
look at all of those requirements.
The developer developer
created all those requirement,
the functionalities,
and now you have to test all of them.
Are all of those things.
What the customer want.
Is it working or is it not working?
If something is not working,
you find a flaw.
You tell a developer, go ahead and fix it.
That's what we do.
Of course, some activities
which I won't go into right now.
You write test
cases, test plan, automate, log, defeat,
all this which we will cover later.
But you know, I won't go into technical.
The first point
will be QA issue.
You have meetings all the time.
So you go over all of this, what
they're developing, maybe you get to see
what they're working on. Absolutely.
We'll get into that more of the meetings
and everything tomorrow
so you get a better picture of you
get to see their work or not, etc..
Okay. So now remember this.
This is the last part.
Testing is the last part.
Everything has been developed.
You are giving the green light
or or the red light.
Basically, it's all comes down to you
guys.
Allan, you question are blind testers
use it as in tester who goes in
knowing
little to nothing about the product.
There are some
sometimes the client itself,
they might bring some people
to test it out.
Sure.
Who might not have nothing to do with it
sometimes, but usually not.
It depends on the company's product.
Let's say, for example.
I think you mean like in your question.
I think in the gaming industry
they do something called beta testing
gamers before a big game comes out.
They send it out to specific people,
Hey, test it out.
So those type of things happen.
But It depends on the company.
I wouldn't
say it's too much pressure on the testers
and a lot of times remember this.
All this things are
made in a way.
It doesn't have a lot of bugs,
but it might have.
But remember this when you start testing,
you figure out things very easy.
That's Testing reports to their own team.
They have their own management
and everything.
They don't report to developers anything.
They work with them. Remember,
there's a big pieces.
We have business and it's
we have designers,
we have developers and we have testers.
We all work as a team within our testing.
We have our own managers.
We use, don't report to develop
or anything like that.
You don't, you work with them.
Yeah, you find the flaws
and then the developer.
Absolutely. That's basically the way.
Because now after basically
the testing phase is done,
what happens is what we call production.
That means when it goes live, right?
This is the final phase of software
development lifecycle in this stage.
If the software runs
smoothly on the system
without any known flaws,
remember there's any known flaws.
That means there could be flaws, but maybe
we haven't found then it is considered
to be large before the project gets
launched into all previous phases.
Must be company like requirement fulfills
customer need Coding is complete
testing complete.
This is basically mean
that it is ready to go live.
So like for example guys Amazon.com.
Amazon.com is massive website.
Okay.
They're doing testing and development
all the time,
but you and I never get to see Amazon.com
down.
Well, maybe.
Let's see, it's down for a few seconds
because they're making some changes.
Those are things happening.
Deployment is going from yeah,
going to production, basically.
That's my goal. That's what it is.
So This is your software development life.
Second, let's look at this.
We had planning, analysis, design,
implementation, testing and integration,
and then it goes to production.
Sometimes some companies
will have maintenance right afterwards.
They do. It all depends is a 5050.
Some companies will just say okay,
we need one maintenance team now.
The product has lunch to three people.
Maximum will keep.
And that's all usually very temporary.
But the main thing is planning,
analysis, design, implementation,
testing and integration.
This is software development logic.
This is the process,
what it takes to build a software.
Now remember,
there can be some different ways of doing
it, which we're going to cover right now.
But this is the overall picture
of how a software is built.
You interact with business analyst because
business analyst gets the requirement.
Those are the most important thing.
You will be working with them.
Waterfall follows the exact same thing,
which I'll explain a little bit better.
You have designers who makes the whole
look and feel of how it's going to look.
Will you interact with them that much?
Not so much.
Maybe at the beginning
they're more utilizing developers.
You absolutely interact with them
because they're developing it.
When you find the flaws,
you tell them to fix it right?
So this is the entire process. Yes.
Everything has to be completed
before you go out there, right?
Everything one step at a time has to be.
Remember, it's a team effort.
It's a complete team effort.
Every member has to participate,
participate.
Are the steps reversible?
Not really. Think about it this way.
How can you test something
if you haven't got it right,
if you haven't developed it?
So not really.
So there's a tester among the testers
team was a liaison between, you know
you will be working with directly
with all the
all the developers let's say tomorrow
something is assigned to you.
Right. That was developed by some.
Remember you could have four
different members in your team
not one person is going to talk know
someone that developed, let's
say the login page. Okay.
The developer developed this.
I'm going to test this thing.
I will communicate
right away to the developer.
This doesn't work.
I don't need to get permission
from another person.
Hey, go ahead and talk to that. No,
not really.
Developers and test you work hand in hand.
Remember, you could be literally sitting
next to each other,
meaning your cubicle
could be next to them. Right?
So you don't need a special permission
to work usually in your group.
Let's say if it's an office
developer testers,
base business owners are in the same area.
So your communication all the time.
Software development
lifecycle is particularly these people.
If feel like a developer, testers,
project manager, designer, you know
all the specific members, they are the one
who are involved in all of them.
We do not fix them.
We don't fix the problems.
We identify the problems, developer fixes
that.
Remember that our job is strictly
to identify the flaws, nothing else.
We never fix how the developer made
it, fix it.
That's their job.
Our job would be, let's say
you find a flaw, you tell the developer
to fix it.
Developer fixes tells you, okay,
you can check my work.
Okay, let me check it now. Doesn't work.
Still go ahead and fix it back.
That's basically how it works. Guys.
Your job strictly identify the flaws.
Nothing else.
Can developers
and testers sometimes get into.
Yes, that can happen.
They can get in sometimes some arguments
and things like that
because you're telling the developer,
Hey, your work is horrible,
you need to fix this, right?
So it can happen.
But does it happen often? Not really.
Quality control. Absolutely.
You're the last one. Remember this, guys?
Tomorrow Apple comes out with a iPhone.
And if things are not working
and you know there's a big problem, right?
Customers are not going to buy it. Right.
So testing is very important
and it's important
in every single company
is be able to finalize budget deadline
based on client can be
does not finalize budget
anything like that
that will be more on the management side
business.
And remember we have superiors too
there's there's hierarchy in the team
which we'll talk about in a little bit.
What did I miss do
that makes any question by any chance?
I don't know
if I missed.
Please do ask again.
I think we're good for the next step,
next part.
So I just want to make sure.
Does it make sense, guys?
Do you guys understand what software
development lifecycle is now,
how it really works,
who the people are going to be.
You will be working with test developers,
business analyst and all of that.
Pretty straightforward, right?
These are you a member of the tech world.
These are the members behind our Instagram
and YouTube app.
Whatever It is.
They're all the one basically,
if you miss a miss,
if you miss a miss a bug or something,
it happens.
You're not going to get fired for that.
You just have to be careful.
That said, testers test the software.
How about the heart rate? Are we?
If you are the software side,
you don't really need to test.
Yeah, there's some sort of end to end
testing sometime,
but you won't be really doing that.
You stick to your software part.
All right.
Okay.
Now this is software development
lifecycle.
All softwares are created
in this particular manner.
Can they be created without a phase? Sure.
But you see, when do it in a team effort
way in the right way,
you have most likely created a successful
product when you go to this trip.
Now, what we're going to talk about
is another process
that some companies follow.
This is important.
It's the same software development
lifecycle, but on a day to day basis,
some use a different tactic methodology
we call this
and another company might use it
in a different way, basically.
So there are two main methodologies
out there.
I would call them more of the process
that companies uses.
Let's say for example, government
do all government agencies operate fast,
pace or not?
Let's ask it.
Let me ask you this are a small but
very slow rate shoot extremely soon.
I would definitely not call it fast.
Maybe Zema,
maybe they are in Tucson, but not here.
I can tell you that
usually if you look at the government
application or the agency,
very slow pace rate, private sector, fast
boom, boom, boom, they're creating
softwares, they're very fast right now
is because they follow a procedure,
a methodology, basic,
a process of how they create, let's say,
a software or whatever
they're trying to do in a particular way.
So now what we're going to look at look,
look at this from this all of this
consumption initiation design,
because it's the same SDLC,
same exact thing for Agile and Waterfall.
These are the two most popular processes
out there.
Methodology, right?
There are more there.
We see there so many other ones out there,
but we're not going to talk about them.
We're going to talk about specific
two methodologies
that a lot of companies use,
either is waterfall or agile.
A lot of private sector
agile government say
waterfall, a very slow process waterfall.
And you'll see now the difference between
which is which
and what's the difference here?
Is it happening
that they release a software to the market
without testing or is it a must?
Are majority companies
test their
software before they release it.
Hey, you remember this?
You can release a product without testing,
but it can be broken product.
There's always flaws.
Remember,
software is built by human beings.
We make flaws,
maybe bad code or something, right?
So it is a must.
If you want your software to be working
fine.
Yeah. All right.
So the two methodologies are waterfall
and agile.
What we're going to do,
we're going to cover
Waterfall today, tomorrow
we're going to dip big, deep into Agile.
Agile is more on the private sector.
A lot of companies use a private sector
and it has more terminology
which I'll cover. But
let me see if the question
you mentioned earlier about testing
log in Bay, do we also test B like that
for security flaws?
Yes there Allen there's different
type of test things out there.
Remember,
you are more the front end testers.
You will be working on the UI part of it.
Everything there's there are penetration
tests are for example
their job is completely different
they're are
they need to know cybersecurity side
those are guys from the security side.
So there's there are different
type of testers out there
Is is it possible to test the software
by the developer?
Absolutely.
The developers also test what they make.
They always test it out
to make sure it's working.
But the thing is, remember, developer
is focusing on creating their mind.
I think so many ways of breaking it.
That's why you need second ISE
and another team to look at.
Exactly.
That's why they find all these problems
and things like that, you know,
because the developer is more focused
on creating a
can they do the same job
of a test of the technique?
You can, but a lot of times
they're not able to because mixing both
can become a little bit challenging.
I usually like that.
That means they have bad, bad way
of creating software.
They need updated most.
Like you.
Yes. ARENA We're going to go into that.
You can do a lot of stuff in that.
You can make changes in Agile,
not much in waterfall.
So let's break down any
what are the advantages?
There's no I wouldn't say
there's disadvantages of SDLC.
That's just a process
are the advantages and disadvantages
you will see in the implementation
part of it. Right?
We understood how SDLC works,
how people implemented is
either they do it in a waterfall way
or they do an agile way.
Now we're going to see the pros
and cons of both. Why?
Which one works better versus
which one doesn't work?
Which is better for what?
Basic grade.
We're going to understand more of that.
Does it make sense, guys?
Can we move on to just
the last concepts of Waterfall
and explain to you what waterfall is?
Okay.
A lot of the projects, by the way,
when it comes to government guys,
a lot of them are using waterfall
because they're slow, right?
They're very slow.
They like to do it in a specific.
Let me explain this to you exactly
like construction.
A waterfall methodology
is a sequential design process.
Once a step has been completed,
the developers can go back a previous step
unless this crashed the whole project
and start from the beginning.
This is very important.
No room for error.
So project outcome and plan
must be determined before starting it.
What it means this guys in Waterfall
project.
Right?
Let's say a company is falling
waterfall methodology to a software.
It's basically exactly like SDLC, right?
What it means, guys, is
every step needs to be completed, right?
So this means this way.
Let's go back and look at this picture.
So let's say planning and designing happen
requirements have been gathered
everything
and you start working on the design side.
Let's see in the meetings
or designing or implementation.
Coding for developer design
is things that, hey,
by the way,
I think we can design this better.
There should be a requirement for this is,
Hey, a business analyst, can you
check with
the client
if they want, add this feature, etc.
or something like that.
Let's say
a new requirement came more later on.
Let's say the developer or the designer
figure out something.
Right now.
This is a requirement, a functionality
change or something like that.
In Waterfall, you cannot go back,
you cannot a new idea or new function.
Once documentation business analyst did,
all the requirements is completed.
There's no going back now, if you ask me.
It's ridiculous, right?
Maybe something better could have.
Maybe you could have all this with
the design is completely completed.
Everything is approved.
And when the developer comes to coding
and everything and you see that, hey,
this design is ugly.
I don't like it.
This can be done in a better way.
They go back and change it.
In order for to change anything,
the entire project
has to be finished.
No, not alone.
I think you're getting confused.
When we find flaws in waterfall,
we can fix that.
Flaws is different requirements,
very different functionalities.
Remove that functionalities,
maybe adding other things.
Let's say, for example.
Oh well, maybe we can add a logging button
on this speech.
Logging button could be working fine.
Maybe a new idea
or new feature came, right?
You can add that.
But in Waterfall,
if the company is following waterfall
methodology, you cannot do this
when it comes to testing.
If you find bugs in when you are,
for example, doing a waterfall project.
Absolutely. You can report it.
They're going to be fixed.
But that's not fixing
that's not adding new requirements.
Right? It's not.
Cheating is just something
they do not work.
You can absolutely fix that.
There's no such thing as, you know,
testers cannot find bugs in every day.
No, no, absolutely not.
That is one of the biggest disadvantage
of waterfall.
And a lot of companies do this.
If you've seen a lot of this government
project that takes a long time,
a lot of times
is because this is what it is.
Think this, too.
A lot of times government
projects are three or four year long
and when the project is completed
after three or four years
and the customer
finally gets to see that project
either is outdated
or there are things they don't like.
And if they have to start
the entire project,
there's a lot of contractual things,
a lot of different things.
So there are some big, big disadvantage.
But when do you use It's still not bad.
Remember when there is a clear picture of
product should be the one quality, right?
This is very important.
One quality and not speed.
That means when you don't care,
just get it done.
Just make sure it's working fine.
I don't care.
It takes you ten years
and you have clear requirements
when the client wants
in the scope of the problem.
Once the project began.
Well, here it's very, very, very
that you have very clear requirements
that mean the business end is better get
the right requirements from the beginning,
because if you get or miss requirements,
you remember this, you cannot.
Adams Later
on, that's one of the biggest things.
Then the new government
comes in that happens sometimes.
Do they? Absolutely.
Why are they using this methodology?
Great. A great point.
The problem is this.
Look, there's especially for
the government, I work for the government.
So I can tell you this from my experience,
a lot of times in the government,
there are a lot of incompetent people.
I'll be very honest with you.
What that means is
I'll give you an example.
The management sometimes are not very tech
savvy or they're in government.
They don't like change.
Maybe you work for the government
and maybe you haven't.
And if you've noticed in the past,
if you work with
maybe worked in the government,
people work in a lot of this thing.
They don't like this
or there's a lot of this. Right.
And there are people
one thing you remember this in America,
I'm not sure if applies.
It was once you become a government
employee, good luck getting fired.
You never get fired.
It's impossible to get fired. Right.
And there are a lot of people out there
who are not competent enough
to be doing what they're doing.
And they are the position.
That's why a lot of the projects
are either over budget.
So maybe why do you see
so so many other government agencies run?
Horribly, because of the same way people
the people who are in control.
There shouldn't be the one simply
that's what it is.
They'll give you a very good example
when I work for you
Packer Enterprises
and the project that we won
for the United States Postal Service,
the business individual who was in charge
of the project from the government side
or the US side, this individual
before him be in the
IT sector was a recruiter for the Marines.
What does he know about it?
What does he know?
Anything.
He was the guy who was recruiting people
from high school and college.
Hey, come join the Marine,
Go in the army or something.
Right.
Does he have the right credentials
to be a business person?
But not really.
A lot of time favors things like that.
Not saying it happens
all across the government,
but a lot of times it's bad management
and they don't like change.
They like things like this.
I remember going to meetings
at the government's giving them
suggestion,
Do this, this where they're like, Now
can we stick to the way we're doing?
They don't like change.
So a lot of times you could say
this is the management.
Slowly, the government is slowly changing,
but it's a long, long process.
Just just look at your website, government
agency website.
Go the old fashioned way, the DMV website
or all the IRS.
You know, we never get our taxes on time.
I got my taxes literally
after such a long time.
Tax rate is very outdated and the people
working there are out there as well, too.
All that, nothing wrong with that,
but they're not up to date.
So a lot of times this is what happens.
And there are a lot of issues
in the government.
If you work in the government,
you definitely would not.
And a lot of times
they're the one using waterfall.
So a lot of problems it can be good for
for the company who wins the project.
They can stretch it out for years
and years and get money
because government is a printing machine,
right?
You print dollars all the time.
So it's good, but unfortunately bad.
Management, so many things you can say.
So there's the answer.
That's why some places still use waterfall
and it's still very popular amongst
especially government.
But can it work? Absolutely.
Waterfall
can work. It's easy to understand.
Remember this?
This model is simply easy
to understand, easy to manage.
Each page has specific
deliverables and pricing.
When when, when a phase is completed,
it's done.
Is checkmark suitable
for a simple or smaller project?
Waterfall model works
well for small project
where requirements are very well
understood.
This is very important.
That means if you have an idea,
a clear idea, it's okay to use waterfall.
Trust me, you will see agile too.
Agile has some pros and cons do.
It's a step by step phase.
The phase
our process and complete one at a time.
Phases do not overlap.
That means design is complete.
Done. That's it.
Maybe they'll fire the design afterwards.
He doesn't have to do any work. Right.
So it's important to understand
that it's not flawed.
It's not in, it's not perfect.
It can work.
But in certain circumstances,
only when you have clear
picture simple project
and you have clear requirements.
Very, very important to understand that.
So not so horrible, but still horrible.
I guess that's
is the best way to look at it.
It depends on who's managing these
projects and everything. So
let's look at some disadvantages.
This disadvantage,
I think, are more obvious.
Once a step is completed,
developers cannot go back to change.
Previous step and make changes.
It doesn't mean that, you know,
they cannot go fixed.
Let's see
something. That's a test.
Your phone as a flaw.
No, it's
the initial functionality of that.
They cannot change it
if they want that change project
has to be completed later on.
It can be done again.
Initial requirement Waterfall relies
heavily on initial requirement.
The project is doomed
if requirements are not clear.
Yes, remember guys, there are billions
and billions of projects
that got wasted like this.
I think one of the project was by Lockheed
Martin or IBM
that took five years, $1.3 billion.
And when the project got done after five
or six years, the technology was outdated.
IBM got 1.5 were Lockheed Martin got 1.5,
$1.3 billion, but project was wasted.
So these are some of the things
because remember this
the clients does not see the project or,
the application till it's completed
and that could take five years.
They have no idea
what the hell you guys are building.
Sure, they'll have some meetings,
but they will have no idea
how the software looks.
They can only make the changes and things
once everything is complete and then
if they want to require mean changes,
they're going to pay extra for that.
Now you're probably thinking,
why do people do that? Well,
I have no idea.
I have
one of those good point,
but they're still using it.
There's like I said, a lot of people,
like old fashioned people.
They're using the old fashioned
techniques.
The government does this and that's why we
see sometime garmin's a little bit slow.
Right.
Okay. Does not allow
for requirement change.
If a requirement errors found or remember
this, this is very key.
If a requirement error, not a bug.
Okay.
If a requirement error is found or change
needs to be made,
the profile of the whole project
has to restart from beginning.
That means a new functionality
they wanted or a functionality
that they wanted us to build doesn't work
or something.
Project has to be completed it regime.
Then it can make the changes.
Remember, bugs are different,
they are not requirements.
Those are just whatever
the requirements are built into created.
We're talking about strictly that.
So don't confuse it.
Yes, testers can find issues
and everything.
They're losing money absolutely 100%.
They lose money only suitable
for small project and chemical. Yep.
You guys will see.
Actually later on tomorrow I'll show you
some figures of how many projects fails.
You will see exactly what percentage
of them for no working product
until near completion.
Again,
No working product until near completion.
All the steps have to be independent
completely before
the final product is delivered.
So that means nothing is fully working
to the very end.
And the customer
only gets to see this at the very end.
Why don't we fix the problem?
Remember fixing the the the bugs.
You do that when you
I guess you guys are for mixing this.
The requirements are different.
Remember this.
Let's say on a page there's a logging
button logging button at the top.
Right? Let's say it's not working.
You tell the developer, fix that
he'll start, he'll fix it.
But what if you decide, you realize, hey,
the logging input
needs to be on another page?
Now that is the same logging button,
but it needs to be on a different page.
That means a requirement.
Change needs to happen, right?
That is not being allowed in this.
That can only be allowed
when the entire project is done.
Yes, there have a lot of these projects
have timeline and sometimes you see
we rushed certain things at the end.
All the client remember at the beginning
you have all the,
you know, meetings and everything,
but they don't get to see the product
fully functioning because we're not
delivering them the product
chunk by chunk.
We give them the project
only when the entire thing is done.
That's just contractually how it is.
That's how their things are,
because they don't have a full picture.
Only when things are done,
they get to see that.
Oh, it's crazy, right?
So let's look at some of the disadvantage
a little bit more.
Okay. So what happens with this?
Imagine what some of the thing for
when the project starts to run out of time
and money testing is the only phase left.
This mean good project are forced to cut
testing short and quality suffers.
Remember
we are the last phase the testing.
So when let's say the project is let's say
five years long and they spend
one year on analysis,
one and a half year on design, two years
on, let's say or let's say
one and a half year on development,
now you're given six months for testing
and you have to finish the project
in five years, let's say. Right?
Not enough time,
money and everything is running short.
You have to finish.
This is what happens.
This is exactly happened.
The requirements are not met.
Do they have to start again?
Like will you project?
What will happen is the project terminal
will most likely get delayed.
So let's say if a five year project might
become five and a half year or six years,
they will complete the project. They will.
Is it going to be a good quality project?
Only when the customer interacts
with the system afterwards,
then they'll find out
if it was a good product built or not.
So you see here
this is what happens all the time.
Secondly, because software isn't produced
until the end of the project, that means
the entire thing is not fully functioning
until the end of the project.
You never really know where you are
on waterfall.
Probably the last 20% of the project
always seems to take 80% of the time
because you might think that,
you know, quality might be a six month
thing or testing
might be six months thing,
but it might take longer,
it might take absolutely longer.
I tell you, absolutely.
A lot of projects like this has happened.
If a project she said,
if a project gets developed in five years,
maybe the time it is is is out of date.
Obviously it happens all the time, guys.
It does happen.
Unfortunately.
That's why they say government
runs slow and government
doesn't know what they're doing,
especially in the IT sector.
It happens all the time.
Project gets delayed,
so many things happen, budget gets cut
and by the time things come, guys,
that's what we talked about.
Evolution of technology, right?
Technology is changing so fast.
And if a project staying five years
and after five years, maybe that software
is not even needed or maybe it is
too outdated, new things have come.
Well, then they have to sign
another contract to build one again.
Right?
So these type of things do does absolutely
happen.
Does it make sense?
So for any questions, anything, testers
kick in after everything is done.
But remember, sometimes I've seen
this guys in in waterfall projects.
Sometimes what happens is sometimes
they don't even hire the testers.
They might have one or two, but they hired
a bigger team later on in that project
because what are they going to do
at the beginning?
Yes, there's some documentation
and things like that,
but they'll be sitting there
and getting paid.
It happens to but some time happens.
If you want job security,
you want everything like that.
You know, boredom
a government is good to work for.
You'll get your paycheck,
you will never get fired and it's fine,
but it gets boring.
It is outdated. They don't use.
And not just that, guys, I don't know if
you guys have worked with the government,
but a lot of the government agencies
use AI to give you a real example.
They Internet Explorer nine or 11.
Yes. In government projects you will see
no Google Chrome or things like that.
You will see that
there is a lot of problem
because to have changes and things
like that, even to download a software,
let's say on a government computer,
there's a lot of restriction,
a lot of people work and things like that.
It happens all the time.
So I got paid three months
to on my last contract to sit around,
wait for my government issue laptop.
Yeah, it happens.
Absolutely happens.
Guys,
I have worked on a project for for three
or four months where I didn't do anything.
I just got paid.
But that's how the government is
sometimes.
Like I didn't say
it took my security clearance.
I one time took two months.
I literally did not do anything
and they paid me.
But that's their slow.
I'm not going to say
don't pay me the paycheck,
but that's how their profit process is.
Developers in you left wherever they were
eager and it's sometimes a dependent.
They can be nice to
so remember also government you know it's
they're just outdated software's outdated
getting done
a lot of paperwork,
a lot of hierarchy things.
It's just I think all governments operate
like this, not just our government here.
A whole across the globe.
They're the same way.
It's just how it is.
And people in charge,
you know, you can't fire them, right?
It's impossible to fire government
employees.
You can just find
just like you're going to private sector
firing someone in government.
It's it's a pain.
It's a big
government.
Does work for lazy people. Absolutely.
Is it possible development team
without a test?
Yes, it is possible.
Technically, they can do manual testing,
but is it going to be
an efficient Mustapha? Most likely not.
Absolutely not.
Someone asked
who is involved in the maintenance base.
Maintenance phase
is not for every project,
but maybe there's one developer,
one tester.
Sometimes a company will keep that, Hey,
just give us some maintenance for next
six months. Support.
Usually how that works,
they're usually one tester
or one developer
just to make sure everything is good.
Government can be boring. Yes,
it can be boring.
Just paychecks are good
in the sense of job security.
That's the one thing you get.
I know a lot of students.
I remember
when whenever in the past batches,
you know, tell them how government works
and everything
when they work, they tell me,
Oh my God, Samir, you're absolutely right.
Exactly what you taught us in
class is how it is.
And surprisingly,
if you're in the Northern Virginia or D.C.
area, you guys locally most likely
will be working
for government projects here.
You will deal with that some more.
Remember this
manual testing is obsolete.
No, absolutely not. Road mental test.
It can never go away.
It's always going to be there. Absolutely.
Because you can't
you can do things with manual testing
that you can't do with automation.
It's just
that it's not really a skill role.
That's the only thing.
I guess.
A couple of more slides
left, guys, before we wrap up.
Our first.
But thirdly, I should say that
you've got to schedule risk
because you never know
if you're going to make it until the end.
You've got technical risk because
you don't actually get test your design
until the make project you got
and you've got product risk
because don't even know
if you're building the right
until it's too late to make any changes.
That's what happens in waterfall
that unfortunately you have no idea.
Remember guys, I said in the design phase
right in the design phase,
the architects decide, okay, how much,
how many servers they need or what?
Say what if we want to scale the system
and everything, you know, later on,
to give you an example of this Amazon
get millions of customers every day.
What if Amazon didn't think of, hey,
next year
you might get 1 billion customer, right?
Let's say for example
if they don't have the right hardware
software for their they're screwed one one
When triple the customers come right
their system is going to crash
and it happens
sometimes you probably have seen some
some website crash on let's say
Black Friday
BestBuy.com Amazon they crash sometime
because everyone jumps on that.
Right?
So those type of things happen
that those type of things
are basically supposed
to be designed in the design phase.
They make up the plans for that.
But what in your waterfall project?
What if you decided realized later
on, hey, the volume is increasing,
what happens?
The right?
You can't really do anything over there.
You can obviously go back
and add a requirement.
Hey, add service you did.
The project has to be done completely
and then you can add those things
later on as a new contract
or a new new project.
Basically
upon.
Yes, you will learn manual testing.
Absolutely. Yes.
Manual testing will teach you.
You'll be learning that
probably not next week.
The following The manual testing
is important for this for entirety,
and you need more manual
testing and automation both.
You need to
you basically are both guys.
You will do probably 30%
manual, 70% automation.
You can be in the testing industry
without manual.
How hard is it to do transition?
We've had actually quite a few students
who have transitioned from
testing to developers.
It's not a hard
you just need to learn a little bit
more programing
once you get into the field, work
for a couple of years or years or so,
you can easily
you can easily actually transition
that very doable.
Finally, and and finally, most important,
it is just not a great way of handling
change.
See, at the very end
you realize what really want.
So this is for you guys
waterfall methodology.
Same thing when we look at basically
as the
same SDLC process, but you cannot go back
and make any changes.
Who owns the risk?
The customer or the developer?
You mean the risk of a project
augur failure?
Or which one?
Can you elaborate on your question?
Well, the risk can be sometimes
look good question.
What what can happen is in this situation,
the company can blame the government.
Well, you didn't give me the requirements.
We built exactly what you wanted, right?
They can always do that.
They absolutely can do.
Government basically
are going to lose the money in everything
if you look at it. Why?
Because at the end of it,
they're the one who tells you what I want.
If you ask, build me
a green car with this, this feature
and I give you all those features
later on, then you realize that hey,
I want this features in, etc.
I want this modification. Well,
you didn't give it to me.
I just built what you wanted. Right?
So the government is holding.
There is the the company that's building
the product is not going to say anything
like that. They were like well,
this is what you guys paid.
Is this what you want?
If you approve those requirements
at the beginning, remember this,
those requirements in this part,
the government would approve, Right?
I built you what you wanted.
You don't think of those things.
That's not my fault, right?
That's
what the company is going to say usually.
Can they be a fly? Yes, they can be.
If they had better team
members, better business,
and maybe they could have given better
suggestions. Sure.
But no company is going to say that.
I give you a real example. HP
took a
project that was supposed to really see
we internally,
we talked about, hey, this is not possible
in one year, three years.
And we communicated this to the
the to the United States Postal Service.
But they were, hey,
get it done in one year, one year later.
Told you guys this already.
So, you know, company is the company
is not going to take that blame it all
it was going to come back onto the
the people who approved the requirements
which is eventually going to be at the end
if you look at is the government itself.
They wanted that product we developed you.
That product doesn't work too bad.
That's what you wanted.
So comes down to that.
And if you look at all of this,
this entire process is exactly like SDLC.
Just we cannot make the changes
if requirement is clear, check.
Now, that said, design,
you cannot go back and make changes
because now you are in design.
Some flaws in there.
But still, who or who pays for this?
The change.
If there's disagreement on contractually,
they might ask the company developing.
They might ask for more,
you know, probably money
for if they want the changes
or they might be part of the contract.
If any changes come after five years
or whatever, they can make.
The change, it all depends.
It all depends
if those are final details, depending on
how the contracts are written.
And that's something,
you know, you test are developers.
We're not part of that
super upper management.
They're the one who try to
know SDLC
is the entire based on SDLC
is the implementation.
Remember, this software development
lifecycle
is how software is supposed to be built
right?
How you implement it, how you go day,
day about it, how you develop it is
the process is the methodology,
like waterfall and then agile.
This is the same SDLC,
the same exact thing.
Yes, Waterfall and Agile are two different
because it's the way remember this
software is
built in the same format,
but you know, some
some methodology doesn't
want you to make changes, some can long.
It's the same process of how it's built.
We're following the exact same,
some where the customer can give feedback,
some can I get feedback.
Right. All those changes
you're going to see tomorrow,
you will see the agile side of it.
How that is more popular.
Why A lot of
sorry, private side.
Private side uses agile versus
why they don't use waterfall.
You see the advantage of there.
There's some flaws there too,
but you see as far as why more popular,
what you can do in that process versus
what you can do with it.
Let's say for example, in in Waterfall
and you make decision which one is better.
Majority
private sector are going to be agile.
Yes, probably faster, absolutely way
faster than and customer interaction is.
You're going to be seeing
that in the Agile methodology.
So you get to see all of that
more in the Agile.
So it will explain that
I don't want to go into today
because it'll be way too much information.
There's a lot of different meetings
in that, a lot of different terminologies
in adults, so we'll cover all of that
tomorrow basically.
But for today
this is what we have for today.
That's tomorrow's class.
Are any questions, anything
didn't make any sense, anything like that.
If you have, please do ask.
I'll spend next 5 minutes answering that
and then we're good to go
for your first class.
All clear. Okay.
Someone asks if you upgrade.
This is do we need to follow all the other
fees in a small, smaller format?
Kind of.
It depends, but kind of.
You follow
all that if you want to make changes.
All right.
That is basically what Waterfall
and SDLC is guys today
who are choosing which method.
Good question.
You and I Tester
developers business analyst.
That's above our pay grade.
That's
going to come to the top management.
They're the ones who basically decide that
many people who know
Agile will talk mental.
Just absolutely anyone and everyone can do
manual testing
has their methodology, doesn't matter,
whether it's waterfall
or whether it's agile,
it doesn't matter at all.
All right.
How you don't get tired of reading
comments like, Oh, I don't.
I've been doing this for so long.
I just I just want to make sure
that you guys understand this is
these are important concepts, their theory
and everything.
I just try to make it fun, you know,
because this
this kind of stuff
can be a little bit boring if,
if I don't get your interaction
and make you understand the big picture.
So I like doing this part.
When we get to Java
so when something does not work done,
instead we get out things like that.
When things don't work,
you ask them in the support channel.
So when you do support or they ask
or you ask questions,
our team members will help you out.
They can say thank you.
That's
And yet tomorrow,
guys, we will get into online only.
Yeah, they'll I'm sure they'll get on
with your resume and help you out.
So if anything like that,
come don't worry.
The team was there any time.
Let's say things are not working,
some will jump on there to help you out.
Can you
can I recommend anything on this part?
You can. What?
Honestly, there's a lot of content
out there when it comes waterfall, Agile.
It's all theory out there.
You can there's not a specific one
I can recommend just look at for tomorrow
because the more is a little bit
more deeper.
And so I would really appreciate
if you guys do look at some quick videos
so you can understand some of the
terminology that has a lot of terminology
should be done in general.
We will give you instruction this year
for that.
So Dawn will download Java.
Anything will give you the videos
for that.
And I think by Thursday or something
and then you can do it
guys, don't worry about all of that stuff.
By the way,
if you haven't, let me see your site
in one
second.
When it comes down to downloading
and things like that,
let's do
when the story here guys
when you want those let's say
for example download videos
and things of installation on YouTube,
go to syntax TV, just go there and guys
you will find some of those instruction,
but don't download anything at this point.
You can do it.
By the way you get there.
You definitely can absolutely subscribe.
We don't have too many,
so you can subscribe.
You will find some of the installation
and things like that over there
and they'll share with you next actually
on Thursday, before your class starts,
we'll give you all the instruction
in the world how you can do all this.
Should I then install? Don't
do anything at this point. Not yet.
Waterfall is a risk for tester.
Not enough time.
I wouldn't really sure like you know
it can be risky,
but for you as a tester
you won't have to worry too much on that.
But. All right.
All right, guys. I think that's it.
I believe I answered
all question on YouTube.
Please do.
Just definitely check Agile tomorrow.
I think that's give me a little bit more.
Can I work personally for a company
as a tester?
You absolutely can
remember
every company has tester,
so you definitely can.
All right.
All right, then.
I guess we're good to go
first. Class one down.
Many more to go.
I'll see you guys tomorrow.
Have a good night.
I'll upload these on canvas
and see you guys tomorrow for
I just do a check, canvas, counter, see,
see what we're going to cover
and just watch quick video.
See tomorrow, guys.
All right, have a going, guys. Take care.
Thank you.
Thank you,
everyone for the participate in.
We love that.
Awesome.
Thank you, guys.