All right, guys.
Seems like we have enough people
to get started, Right?
So let's get started.
How is everybody doing, guys?
I hope everyone is doing good.
Seems like there's a birthday.
Okay, Stephanie,
Happy birthday from Syntax.
Right.
So hope you get a good job
after this course.
All right. I'm good. Thank you.
I hope you guys are having fun with
what's called
was Selenium.
Did we all complete the homework?
Guys?
I hope everyone completed their homework.
Right.
Some people I got got some messages
where you guys can find one
element, right?
I think was covered.
That's on review.
Right? Yeah.
You guys had to use the X path.
Yes, exactly. Okay.
Okay, good.
I hope everyone
everyone had to look up what X path is.
What kind of what kind of X path you had.
We have right.
Okay, you guys Googled it.
Okay, good.
All right.
And I hope you guys assigned not.
I hope you guys were using the web element
objects.
Right.
Hopefully you guys didn't just use driver
that find elements.
I hope you guys use the assigning method
that we have done
at the very end of the class.
Last time. Right.
So, all right, let's do a quick recap.
Right.
So what did we do last class, guys?
What did we learn about last class?
Okay, we talked about the locators.
Right.
Okay.
How many locators do we have, guys?
And so many.
Okay, we got eight locators.
Right.
What kind of locators do we know about?
Well, I'd name
right.
We have class names.
What else?
Web experts.
There we go.
Selectors.
Right. Link tags, Partial link techs.
Right.
Okay, So how do we interact
with the locators, guys?
Where do we have to go
in order to see these locators?
We have to open up our Dom.
Right.
So how do I open the DOM guys
when it's a right
click on the left side, right
to right,
click on the application
and go to inspect.
Right. Okay, good.
All right.
What is in other words,
this Dom calls guys.
What do we call it?
Source code.
Okay.
What else?
The whole.
The whole Dom guys.
I mentioned it last time. There we go.
It's called developers tools.
Right? Or dev tools. Right.
Okay, good.
All right, So we
we said that there are eight locators.
Why do we need so many locators?
Guys?
Okay, so
some locators might have duplicate
values, right?
And the most important thing
is because not
all of the locators will be available
for us for this or that element
whenever we inspecting and whenever we try
to interact with this or that element.
Right.
Some of them can be dynamic. Exactly.
That's another reason that we can
we can have another option to use
different locators so that we can interact
with those elements.
Right.
And there is one more
one more reason why we need so many
locators, guys.
And you want anyone remember that?
So we said there is duplicate values,
right?
Developers might not provide
all the locators in their.
Some of those are only applicable, right,
for some locators.
Right. So
some of the locators may not be applicable
for all the elements.
Right.
So like link tax, a partial latex,
you can only use use it for links.
Right. Okay.
So what's the tag for the links, guys?
So if we have a
tag and we'll look at the HTML,
it's an eight tag, right?
What what do we call it?
Okay.
It's a hyperlink, right?
It's an anchor tag.
Right. Okay, good.
That is very good. Okay.
All right.
Okay, guys,
any questions from the last class?
Any questions on names?
IDs, class names, Link to any of those?
How do we use anchor tags?
We are going to be using them tomorrow,
guys.
Okay,
so today we're going to cover Xpress.
Tomorrow we're going to cover CC
selectors and attacks.
Can I cover?
Yeah, we are going into details today.
Okay.
Okay, cool.
All right.
So let's get started with X path.
Right?
So today we will be covering only X path
because there's a lot of things
that we need to do today
and some of these things may
may look a little bit
difficult.
Right,
Because we will be typing these X passes
inside our DOM and then we will be
covering advanced X path as well.
So that's, that's going to be
a little bit difficult at first,
but then we'll get more practice on it
and it's going to be all good.
We will be comfortable with everything.
I won't be covering homework guys, okay.
Amazon should be covering the homeworks
or if you have any questions,
you will do it on review.
But I mostly try to do the new topics
and more,
and we'll do the reviews on those topics.
Okay.
But if you have any issues on homework,
try to reach out to your.
I'm pretty sure you have groups
right already.
So try to reach out to your group mates
or try to just post your issue
and just syntax support
and we will take a look at those.
Okay.
All right.
So X path, guys.
Okay.
So we know that X path is one of the
one of the eight locators, right?
So why do we need X plus?
What do we know?
So I told you guys before to
to do some research.
Right. So let me see.
What do you guys know about X
or did anyone do any research on X path
if the others don't work?
We can use X path.
Okay, so there are two types
relative and excellent X.
That's good.
We can locate our elements.
We use X path.
Okay.
Let me do this.
Why do we need
x path or c select selected?
Okay.
First of all, why we need it?
Because sometimes developers may not
provide all the locators in our HTML.
Right? So let's get this clear in here.
Developers will not provide
all the
locators in HCM.
Right.
Okay, so what would be the second reason
why we need X path and c skies
whenever we object and not have idea.
So we'll go for X path.
Okay.
Helps find elements more uniquely.
That is correct.
So single and double slashes.
That's very good.
So there's one really important point
with X Path and SAS guys,
it is that we need x breath and c assess
because we can locate elements
with give with any given attribute.
Okay.
So before let's take a look here.
Let's say this using an textbox.
Okay.
So this user name textbox into you
has ID class tile type, right.
And name.
So from our locators
that we already covered in here,
we have name ID and class, right?
So there's three different
locators that we can use
by just having the Selenium library.
Right.
But if we use an X path in this case
and let's assume
that our element doesn't have neither name
nor ID nor class nothing,
it has just type, maybe just a placeholder
or a style, right?
It has a style in here.
So let's assume
that we only have type and style.
So in that case,
you can't be using any locators
like name ID or class or link text
or anything.
You have to go with CSS selector for X
because this will help us to use
or to identify any element
by any given attribute.
Okay, is that clear, guys?
And I hope we all know
what attribute is already
right?
Okay, good.
All right. So
let me put it here by using
X path
and C as a selector right
within identify elements
if any of them
actually
it will allow us to use type, correct?
Yes. So let's actually go to Facebook.
Let me inspect this page as well.
So let's see
here.
So we only have here
IDs, right?
So if we don't have any
what's called
any locators,
then we can use any of the attributes.
Right.
So the attributes, what's the
what's the color on the attributes in here
guys,
when we use the when we expect the page.
What's the color on attributes guys.
Yeah. Brownish or orange,
whatever it is. Right.
So any attribute that we can see
and we using X,
we should be able to use those. Okay.
All right.
But before we get to use and before
we start actually writing the X Path,
let's go ahead and answer this question.
What is an X plus?
Okay, So we know
besides that it is one of the locators.
And so what is X path?
Does?
Yep, it is a locator.
Besides that
includes attributes and its value.
Okay.
Anything else?
Anyone? You guys.
I thought you guys did a research. Now
it is.
There we go.
So X path is like a query language.
Okay, So that it helps us to identify
elements uniquely on the web page.
Right? So X plus
is like a
query
language,
which helps us to identify
elements
uniquely
on the web page.
All right.
Okay.
So now what
we are going to do, let's go back in here.
So now what I'm going to do is
let's talk about the types of the
let's talk about the types of the past us.
So the does is anyone familiar
with types of the X
but anyone did the research on this
query language is when
the language of writing
or finding some elements right?
Not only the elements it is,
it is a language
to consequently find something.
Okay, So if you heard about the databases,
you write a structured core language.
Okay, So you use structured query language
where you come,
where you start from the top,
you go one by one
and you can secretly find some answer,
okay, okay.
So the types are absolute and relative
X path is right.
So types of
X path in here.
So to do
absolute
X, right?
So okay, so we have two different
types, absolute and relative X, right?
So we'll go over the X path first and
then we will go over the relative X path.
Can you call query as a script.
Yes. You can do that. Yes.
Okay guys.
So in order for me
to identify the element by X path,
we have to write some,
some query language inside the DOM.
Okay, So what I'm going to do,
I'm going to press some buttons right
now, so please follow me
and there will be a text box
where I'm going to start typing my ex.
Okay,
So I'm going to go ahead and click on Mac.
You can go ahead and press command F
and on Windows you could do
control S okay.
That way you can see that
there is a text box
popping up in here
and you can see that you can,
you can
type some X path or selector or whatever
it is.
Okay, I hope everyone is on the same page.
I hope no one is confused right now.
What is going on
passive today?
What's going on, guys?
Everyone is tired
and everyone needs a vacation.
I guess.
Okay.
Long day.
All right, Hands on the keyboard.
Okay, good.
All right, guys.
So we have this selected
text box in here, right?
So that we can start writing our
X back.
Right?
So absolute X path or
it's also called a native X pass, right?
So it starts from the very bottom
of your HTML code.
Okay.
So when I say the very bottom,
it's going to be the edge HTML tag.
Okay.
So exactly from the root of this page
HTML document that we can see in here.
Okay, So absolute X plus, you has to go
step by step from the very, very top note.
Okay.
So if I go ahead
and put a single slash
and start typing h html, you can
you can see immediately
that this h HTML line
is getting highlighted with yellow.
Okay. So if I just typed in,
let me actually collapse this one.
So if I just type in H
for a slash and h html,
you can see that here.
This h HTML node is getting highlighted.
Okay.
So that means we highlighted
the whole frame
or the whole what's called
the whole web page in here.
So we are on Facebook right now.
We just highlighted this page. Okay.
So what if I want to move forward
right now?
Okay.
So if we look at our HTML right now,
so there's only a couple of lines
because I collapsed everything, right?
So if you look in here,
so there's second and third lines.
There's two more lines in here
which has head
and the body right.
So if you look at the head
and body, you can see there and little bit
shifted to the right then.
H HTML, what does it mean, guys?
And no one knows.
So these two in here,
these two are shifted to the right.
Okay, that's very good.
Kevin Yes, they are.
They are children. Exactly.
So that means that means that head
and body,
they are inside the HTML.
Okay.
So if you look
vertically, guys, so whenever
I open up the head right now,
you can see the matter.
The script is style.
They are shifted more to the right,
which means that
these all know are inside the head now.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys?
Any questions on that?
So if you look in here there's script,
there's div, there's div inside the div
because it's a little bit
shifted to the right look
exactly like one
block court,
one block of code inside the other.
Right.
And even even in Java guys,
whenever we start typing.
Right. So any code in here.
So if you look I have a main method
and then the actual code goes
inside,
it is shifted a little bit to the right.
This way we know that
this block of code is inside our method.
Okay. Pretty similar, right?
Pretty similar logic in here.
So. All right.
So if I want to move forward right
now, so we need to do it one by one.
Okay.
So if you if I put a forward slash
in, do head in here.
So now you can see that the head line over
there is getting highlighted
right.
They don't have to be. No,
they don't have to be shifted.
No, it's just a format.
Right.
So it's easier for us to read as
as whoever person as developers
or it automation people.
Right.
So if you are a technical person,
you need to format your code
so that it's readable, Right?
Okay.
So now, guys, I put after the symbol,
I put another slash and I go ahead and
typed in head in here and you can see that
this head note is getting highlighted.
Okay?
Nothing is getting highlighted in the
in the Web page because there's nothing
no, I don't think there is
any elements inside the head.
But I want to skip this head
and go to the body.
How would I do this? Guys?
Any guesses in here?
How would I go to the body
instead of head?
Why can I do slash and body in here, guys?
Why is this not working?
If I do a HTML slash head slash body,
why is this not working?
Double slash?
Not really.
It's different route.
Okay.
Body is not inside of the head.
Absolutely right.
So guys, when I said that head
and body are inside the HTML
and here we go
in one by one, step by step.
Right?
So head is inside the HTML,
but body is not inside the head.
Right.
So what I need to do in here,
I need to delete this head in here
and just put h html and body.
So in this case, guys,
since we said that head
and body are children of the
h HTML, right.
What does head and body are to each other?
Guys, brothers
or in in other words, they are siblings.
Okay, so there are siblings.
That's very good.
Okay, So we will be coming to siblings
a little bit later.
But for now we have HTML as a parent
and then head and body
are siblings to each other.
Do they fight a lot? Not really.
Not at this moment.
Okay, guys.
So seems like right now
they're understanding
each other pretty well.
Okay.
All right.
So so now we are in body, right?
So if I want to
if I want to, let's
go to the first division.
Right.
So if I want to go to the division guys,
what I need to do,
I just need to put as div, right.
And you can see that we're going
down, down
and we're going one by one
through each and every note.
Okay,
so if I open up this div and here we have
a lot of different things in here as well,
so I can do another division in here.
And again, if you open up this one,
there is another division so you can go
they've div so
it depends on what kind of tags you have.
Right.
So you go one by one through to the tags,
starting from the roots,
starting from the very top.
Okay, so this is how you construct
the absolute x path.
Okay.
So that's how the the absolute x backwards
relative x path works
a little bit different.
We'll come to this point right now.
Okay.
Any questions on this?
And one more thing.
One more thing, guys, before we move.
So absolute X path, guys,
it is not used very much and we will come
to the differences of absolute
and relative X path is a little bit later.
Okay.
So now let me just copy this.
So here absolute X plus
start
from the
starting note in H html
and we can say that it always starts
with a single slash.
Okay.
And then what I'm going to do,
let's give it an example here.
Is that in here?
Okay, any questions, guys?
Any questions on excellent X file?
Okay, cool.
All right.
So now let's go to the
relative X five.
Okay.
So the relative X class is the most used,
I think,
locator.
If I'm not mistaken, after the item.
Okay.
What if you need this first,
but not the second?
Okay, That's a good question.
So let's go ahead and do this one.
Okay.
So let me close this one. Okay.
So let me
until this point.
Okay, So we are here.
So we have the first date, right?
And then the second date.
What if I want to go to the second one
and not the first one?
Guys, how would I do this?
Then we can use the indexing.
Okay, This is called indexing in Express.
Okay, So what I can do,
I can put the brackets in here, square
brackets, and put two in here,
and we can switch to the second division.
Okay,
so this is going
by index in here.
So it starts from zero.
That is correct.
But this is this is for x path.
For x, it's called going from indexes.
Okay.
It starts from one on x,
but usually when you code,
when you put the erase or any
what's called array list elements
right there
starts from zero.
All right. Okay.
So let's go back in here.
So now
so relative
x path is the mostly used after the ID.
Okay.
So there is a very good advantage
advantage for relative express
because for relative class,
you can start from any node of h HTML.
Okay.
So in absolute X path,
we have to start from the starting node,
which is h HTML, right?
So in relative X path,
you don't have to worry about it.
You have to you can start
from wherever you want to start.
Okay.
And I'll show you how to do this. Okay.
So let me put here starts from any node
in h HTML
and then what we can say it starts
starts with
double slash.
Okay.
So if you want to
if you want to write a relative X path,
you have to start with double slash,
right X path from the tag of our choice.
Exactly.
It's also complete of full X plus.
Yeah, it will be a complete x plus, but
it will call it what we call relative x.
Okay.
H html body needs to
that.
I'm not sure why that's happening.
Are you on the same page?
I hope you are on the same page.
Or you could share the screenshot
and we can see
we can take a look
why it's different in yours.
Okay. All right.
Okay, guys.
So now what I am going to do here
is let's start either
down side in using relative X path.
Not really.
I don't think so, because the relative
x path is one of the really
versatile locators that you
can use while interacting
to locating the elements.
Okay.
That's why I said after the id
x path is the most used locator while
while interacting and running automation
we would mainly use
relative versus absolute.
Absolutely right. Yes, that is correct.
And I was going to come to that point
where we will discuss
about the advantages
and disadvantages of types of X.
So. Okay.
So all right, let's write our first
X path and here I'll give you the form
of the okay of the relative facts
path is pretty easy, but it might look
a little confusing at first, but
it's not when you when you practice
and when you get used to it.
Okay.
So let's throw the here syntax for
relative x path and here.
Okay.
So we said that you have to always start
with double slash.
Okay.
So I'm going to start with double slash
and here and what I will do is
I'll start with the tag
and any tag that I want.
Okay?
Or any tag name that belongs
to the element that I want to locate.
Okay.
So I'll start with the tag name
and then what
I'm going to do, I'm going to open
and close the square brackets.
Okay?
So and then I'll put an X sign
and I will start writing
that attribute that want to use.
Okay, style, class, name,
whatever you want to use.
Okay.
And then after I mentioned that,
then what I need to do,
I need to put an equal sign
single quotes in here,
and then inside the single quotes,
what I put,
I put the attribute value
that I am using right now.
Okay,
Attribute value.
Okay, So this is the syntax
for the relative x path
and now what we are going to do,
we're going to be writing some X stuff.
Okay? If this syntax is not clear, it's
okay.
I'm going to write
a relative X stuff in here right now
and then you can see how it actually
looks like.
Okay,
so like a complicated order in Starbucks.
Exactly.
Yeah. With all those milks and
splashes of vanilla and all that stuff.
Exactly. Yes.
Different attributes
you can use in reality.
Exactly.
There is no in not only in relative right.
And expanse
you can use any attribute you want to use.
Okay.
Let me write one relative x path, guys,
and you can see how it's actually written.
Okay. All right.
So how do we start with our relative
X path, guys?
First of all, let me actually
we I want to locate this textbox.
The textbox for the email. Okay, guys.
So here what I'm going to do,
what do I start with?
If I want to write a relative,
what do I want to start in here with?
With a double slash.
Right? Exactly.
So I start with a double slash. Okay.
So now I know that this is my
this is my element, right?
What is the tag?
So this element, guys, it's input, Right?
Okay.
So what I'm going to do in here,
I'm going to put
input in here.
Okay. That's fine.
Let's go back and click on this thing.
Okay.
So input.
So now what
I will do square brackets in here.
Open and close at sign. Guys.
I'm going to put an ad sign in here
so I can now here
after I put the side, I need to choose
which attribute I am going to use.
Okay, So, so
I'm going to come back to your question.
Okay. So let me finish this.
I'll explain it one more time.
Okay.
So attribute
which attribute do we want to go with?
So what kind of attribute
do we have in here, first of all of us.
So we see here type right
class and here name ID or place
holder, whatever.
Right?
So what I'm going to do
is let's pick
the ID, the easiest one for now, right?
So what I will do,
I put an ad sign in here, I'll go with ID
and then equals sign.
What is the value of my ID guys?
The value of my ID is email, right?
So if I do an email it will highlight
that exact element in here.
Okay.
So what I did
double slash tag name, right?
The attribute and the attribute value
that said guys,
okay, is this clear?
Guys, any questions on this? Copy this
and it's here.
There we go.
Okay, so now here, guys,
I want you to pay attention to one very,
very important thing.
Okay?
So whenever you're writing an X
path in here, what you want to do after
you wrote your path, after you have your
your element identified in the DOM, right?
What you want to do, you want to pay
attention to the very end of the textbox.
And every time you do that,
you have to make sure
you have one of one.
Okay.
So if you have one or two or one of three,
that means you didn't
identify your element uniquely.
Okay.
Whenever you have one of one only,
then it is clear that your your
your element or your x pass located
that element is uniquely
and there's no other match for that.
Okay. Exactly.
Because there there might be some
multiple attribute values
which are the same.
Right.
So that's why, guys, whenever you done
writing your express in here,
you have to make sure that it is
one of the one.
Okay.
Any questions, guys?
Yes. For the absolute is the same,
but we won't be using absolute
absolute X path at all.
Okay.
Because absolute
X path is very risky to use.
And I'll explain to you
a little bit later why.
One second.
But you see, Eugene,
that's exactly why we don't use the
that's one of the risks, why we don't use
absolute X path.
Okay.
All right, guys.
So now let's talk about why
we don't use the absolute next
path, guys.
So if I want to detect
or locate this element by using
by using the
absolute X path,
guys, what do I need to do
in order to get here?
Guys, too much, right?
So you need to start from h html,
you have to go to body,
then you have to go to other divisions.
Right?
There is a form, there is inputs,
there is all that stuff.
So your x path is going to be very long.
Okay, But
okay, you can use the absolute
X path in this case.
But what if, guys, what if your developer
makes any changes on the website
and he adds any division in here
between this and this one guys,
then what's going to happen to the fact
that you just created
guys?
Then it's going to mess up your X path.
It's not going to work at all
because you have to go back
to your code
and change that locator, right?
So that's one of the very big reasons why
people
actually don't use the absolute express.
Okay.
And it's really long
whenever you want to locate
and a different locate
any different elements inside.
Very different nodes. Okay.
So that's why it's really easy
for us to go with relative X path,
because you can go for any tag
you want, right?
You can start from any tag you want
or from any node if you want to start.
Okay. All right.
So where did I get input from?
It's from here, right? This is my element.
So whenever you go here,
click on this magic arrow.
Come back to your textbox.
You can see that each and every element
they have your
they have a tag name first, right?
So that's how you start your X path.
And I think set up asked
why double slash because relative express
always starts with double slash
tag for creating your account.
Okay, let's take a look at that.
Okay.
What's the tech for create
new account goes in here
say color.
It's an attack right?
So it's right here.
So we're having a tag
and then we have this button.
Okay.
All right.
So now actually, let's.
Let's do this.
Let's identify this element, guys.
Okay.
So there is one more really
what's called really big advantage
of relative express
that we can actually use
while locating the elements.
Okay.
So let's actually identify this. Okay.
So let me
remove this one. Okay.
So this is our element
that we want to interact with.
Okay.
How do we how do we start doing this?
Okay, so what do I need to start from
if I want to
if I want to write it relative, us
double slash
and then okay, my tag is a right.
So let's go back in here
and this is my element, right?
So my square
brackets right.
And then what can we use in here?
So if I use the class guys in here,
which one do we prefer to use in here?
Guys.
So there is class.
Okay.
ID okay
guys, we're talking about the ID here.
What did we what, what did we say
about these kind of ID values?
If ID has numeric values,
that's why it might be dynamic, right?
Same thing with a class, right?
So there is a couple of things.
Last in here, there is data test ID,
whatever it is.
Right?
And then there's role as a button in here.
What else do we have
in here, guys?
Okay, you used row.
That's fine.
What else do we have in here? Guys?
We besides, besides the attributes?
Do we have anything else in here?
Guys, we have a hyperlink.
Okay, this one.
Okay, what else?
We have a text, right?
So this is one of the biggest advantages
of X based.
So you can identify an element
by its text.
Okay, Here
we have a lot of mass in here, right?
So we have seems like it looks
like dynamic X,
I mean dynamic ID value or dynamic class
values, right?
So in order to be for us safe, right?
So rule and data ID, these are really,
really rare used attributes.
They might be removed in the future
by developers.
You never know about that. Okay.
So in order for us to be safe
in this case,
what we have on hand,
that might not change at all
in the future,
guys, is the text of this button.
Okay.
And you can see this
text button inside this a
okay, well, create new account.
What how would this change in the future
guys create new account is always create
new account.
Right? We're sign up.
Yes but it's I don't think it would change
really frequently, guys.
Okay.
When you
when something goes into production.
Guys, this is finalized.
Okay, This is finalized.
I think unless your client
is really forced to change it
and there should be a huge reason
to change the text or to change something
existing already
I'm talking about the buttons
or or the all the design of the
what's called off the web page. Okay.
When something goes to the production
guys, it's really rare
that you're going to be changing
existing things.
You can add more functionality
to the website, but it's really rare
that you will be changing
the existing small text or whatever it is.
Okay, unless the client is applied.
Yeah, exactly.
So, okay, so we have this text.
Okay, So what I'm going to do,
I started with double
slash attack square brackets, right?
So what I'm going to do now,
since we will be using text,
what I can do in here, in do text
and open and close parentheses,
what I'll do is equal to and then
single quotes in here
and I'm going to copy this text in here.
And what I will do, I'll just paste it
inside my single quotes.
Okay.
Is this unique?
Goes the
the element that I just identified.
Yes. Right. Because it's one of one.
So it's a valid relative path
which located
element uniquely.
So let me copy this
right.
And let's put it here.
Identifying elements by this text.
All right, There we go.
So you have a tag name,
You just put a text in there
and you put the actual text
inside the single codes.
No, we don't have an F sign.
Exactly. That's a very good catch.
Whenever you're using a text guys
inside your relative text,
you cannot use the X1.
Okay, So if I put and sign before text,
this is not going to work
because text is not an attribute, right?
So you put an act before the attribute.
Okay, guys, is that clear?
Any questions on anything we've done?
So far with X?
Pascal's?
The syntax for
text test or text
in the X path?
Yeah, for the text, yes.
So let me actually put the syntax in here.
So again, it's fine to copy this syntax.
So the tag name, right.
So here,
since we are identifying it by text,
you will be pasting in here
or inputting text without a net sign.
And then here just the text value of that
element.
Okay,
any questions,
guys?
I'll clear.
All right.
So let me.
Okay, So now, guys, since
7:00.
So let's do a couple of more things
and then we'll get point.
Okay? All right.
So in Java, guys, I'm
pretty sure you remember
the string manipulation, right?
So whenever you have a condition
where you want to verify
or you want to put
a condition for verifying the
the string that has some partial values
equal to each other, what method
do you use, guys?
Line 25. No. Any tag name?
Any tag name guys. Okay.
It doesn't have to be an A, okay.
Any tag name because let's go ahead
and take a look at the log in in here.
Okay.
So now look,
the tag name is different for this one.
Okay?
But it still has the text.
Okay. So it doesn't have to be a tag.
Always.
Okay.
All right.
Let's see. Equals contains, right?
Because you looking for the partial value
of the
of the string.
Okay, so now in an X path, guys,
whenever you have a very long, very long
attribute value
or very long text that you want to
you don't want to really write everything
down in your express, there is a method
which you can use and express as well,
which is called contains.
That way what you can do, you can just get
the partial attribute value
and you can put it inside your X.
You don't have to put
the whole attribute value or
the whole text inside your X pass
so that it's not that long.
Okay.
So in here,
as you can see, this class value
limit to read this, this class
value is very long, right?
So what else do we have?
Let's actually identify
this textbox again.
Okay, let's use different
different attributes in here.
Okay.
All right.
So identifying, identifying
elements, using
tens method.
Okay.
So what I'm going to do in here,
double slash again, guys, tag name, right?
Square brackets, guys.
So now I will start typing
the actual method in here
and then we'll go through the attributes.
Okay.
So what I'm going to do and here
I'll start with typing in contains
and I will open and close the parentheses.
Okay.
Once I did that
inside the parentheses of contains method,
I'll start typing my attributes
at sign and attribute.
Okay.
So now here we don't use the equals sign.
What we do we're going to be doing comma.
Okay, comma
and then single quotes in here.
And what I will do, I will do partial
attributes.
So okay, so this
one is going to be a little bit confusing,
but whenever you get more practice,
you will get more comfortable on it.
Okay, double slash tag name contains
method.
You start inside the parentheses,
you start with the attribute,
and then instead of going with equal sign,
you'll go with comma
and then single quotes
and the partial attribute.
So it is harder by adding
instead of equals.
I'm not sure why
why this is made this way,
but it is probably
when you do contains
instead of doing equal sign, it's
it's getting it's
accepting two different arguments.
Okay.
So you're basically passing
two different arguments
in here as we did
when when we were doing set in
setting the property right,
in setting the property you pass where
what driver
you want to use comma and then what,
where your driver is located.
Right?
So this is probably the same way
they made it.
Inside this method.
You put the attribute comma,
and then the second
value you put is your partial attribute
found.
Okay.
All right.
Any questions
before we move forward, guys?
Now? Questions? All good.
Okay.
Yeah.
It's like a constructor or just a
method was two parameters.
All right.
Okay, So now let's go back in here.
So I want to identify this text box
for email or phone number.
Okay, So where do I start with
what I start with?
Help me out, guys.
What I need to do first
for relative express.
There we go.
So double slash input tag in here.
All right,
let's go back here.
This is my input.
So now, guys, since we set that
in Relative Express or any PATH,
we can be we can use different any
any of the executes right in here.
What I want to use I want to use place
actually.
Okay. So you can see that
it's a bit longer
the value it's a bit longer in here,
right.
So let me use the placeholder
in this case.
So square brackets in here, like
what I need to do is
I, I'm going, it has spaces.
It's okay, It's okay.
We'll figure it out. Okay.
All right.
So what I need to do in here is I'll start
with my method,
which which is contains, right.
So contains open
and closed the parentheses.
Right.
So inside the parentheses, what I need to
specify is my attribute.
Right. So side.
So now I am using the place holder.
Right.
So what I'm going to do at same place
holder comma
and then single quotes in here.
So I need the partial value of this place.
Holder Right.
So what I can do is just
I can put an email in here
and this will identify
my element is unique.
Okay, Is this clear, guys?
Any questions on this?
Nice.
Okay again guys, double slash tag
name contains attribute
and then attribute value.
Oh yeah, absolutely. Guys,
you will have a lot of practice.
Okay, guys,
I'll give you some homework. So
you won't
be able to use ignore case in here.
Now. Okay,
so let me confidence that.
Okay, there we go.
So we have an
example in here.
Does uppercase and lowercase matter?
Of course. Yes. Yes, guys, it is.
It should be.
Let's actually check in here.
So it should be case sensitive. Right.
So if I put e
what's called
not the capital or lowercase in here,
it's not going to identify my element.
Okay.
This should be uppercase.
Why? Why is this working
if it's mail, guys,
not email, but just male here?
Exactly.
Because it contains that sequence
anyways inside that value.
Right.
Okay. Nice
as email and phone number.
The reason I chose Placeholder
is to show you that we can use different
different attributes than the locators.
And because
the value of the placeholder is long,
we don't want to use that long values.
Okay.
So contains you usually use for the for
the elements that you want to shorten the
the attribute values for elements.
Okay.
What do we do once we find the value
of those x path locator mean what do we do
once we have the expats like this,
we will be going over the script, right?
So after I explain you these
how we handle all these
and what kind of methods
we have with X plus, we'll go ahead
and do some automation on this.
Okay?
Can you use name? Yeah, absolutely.
You can use name.
Yeah.
So can we use what kind of Java methods
are you talking about.
Start
with etc.. No.
So this one is contains
is the same as in Java.
Right.
But we also have starts with which
I am going to explain you right now.
Okay.
But starts with
is a little bit different than in Java.
Okay but this is I, I talked about Java
so that you guys know that it is
similar approach.
Okay but they are these are different
because you're writing this inside
the extract.
This is not a Java code, right?
So you're writing this inside the X
to locate the element
to have an access to the HTML.
All right.
So there is one more thing that I want
to show you before the break, guys.
So we talked about containers
and we also have in Java,
this starts with okay, so
starts
with will
identify
the element
with starting the partial self.
Right.
Okay.
And then that we need to memorize
it would be okay.
Sure.
Okay so let's get through the
through all the x path types
and what we can do with this and then
I'll tell you which ones are really useful
during the automation.
Okay.
All right. So let's put the
mic copy this.
Let's put the syntax in here. Okay.
So instead of just contains
what we will be doing,
we will be using starts with
starts.
But here it's it's written differently
right starts
dash words in here and then you can do
partial
starting attributes out.
Right So it's pretty much the same thing
but we using a different method here.
Okay, So let's go back in here, guys,
and see
what we can do
is let's identify
this this button, guys,
this is our button.
So how do we want to identify this?
Let's go step by step.
Okay, let's let's finish starts with
and then we'll go to the ends with.
Okay.
All right.
So here we have a button attribute, right?
Double slash button
button attribute in here.
What do we want to use in here? Does
let's see.
You want to try using the class
and you want to
because it has a very long value in here.
And we can use starts with
in here.
Okay. So
the square brackets in here
then starts with right
parentheses
and then inside the parentheses
what I can do at class
comma single quotes in here and let's to
four to
or after you, whatever it takes. Right.
So I just chose the starting value
of the class of the class attribute
and it located my element
and it located my element.
Unique right is in this dynamic.
That's a very good question. Yes.
So since we have numeric stuff in here,
we can change, right?
We don't want to use this, right?
So let's go ahead and use a different one.
Okay.
So starts with what do we want to use
the guess test idea.
Okay, let's use the data test idea.
Right.
So data the test ID
and then the value would be let's do.
All right.
So if we use this, it is one of one.
So that means this
this X path is reliable and it is
uniquely identified that element.
Right.
How can we write it using text?
That's that was actually the next thing
that I was going to explain.
Okay.
So let me copy this and go here.
Example.
It's pasted in here, right?
So now, guys,
so this button has a text as well, right?
What we can do in here,
the same way we identify the text
we can identify with starts
with or contain.
Okay.
But instead of these attributes, guys,
let me delete this attribute.
What you can do,
you can simply put a text in here,
open and close parentheses,
and then instead of broil
since we using this starts with
you could just put
LG the starting point of that text
and this will locate your element as well.
Okay.
Any questions on this
text?
I think it
is a method, but I'm not sure it's 100%.
If it's a method, it's an expression.
Okay.
To identify the element.
If you can't locate, send us a screenshot.
We need to see or expand.
Why doesn't I like the text?
Because it highlighted the actual the
what's called
the actual element in here.
Okay, that's enough for us. Okay.
It doesn't have to.
It doesn't have to highlight
the whole thing
as long as you have when it collapses,
as long as you have this located
or highlight it, that's enough
for you to use in your selenium
script.
Okay.
And the most important thing
that I said, guys, about the
X path is when you have one of one,
okay, sure.
Here are the most files.
Any questions before we
move forward, guys?
So make
I'm not sure if Let me see.
I'm not sure if we can make this bigger.
Let me check if I can make it bigger.
Guys, let's take a break. It's 816 already
sick.
A 15 minute break in here.
And then what we can do,
we can continue from there.
Okay.
So we'll come back 830
on the right.
There shouldn't
be anything wrong with that X plus
Comanche plus.
Okay, let's try this.
Let's see.
There we go. Nice.
Thank you.
They're well, they should be fine.
Give us different
you know, these are the different values,
right?
These are different values.
So the test that tests test
idea has a different value it.
The text is different.
And here, let's
see a screenshot.
Well, your your expert is wrong.
It's not test it's text right
and then you'll
log should be starting with the capital L
and you put test in here it's text
I think you misspelled the.
All right, guys, let's get back.
I hope everyone is back or any
and let's continue with our next class
phase everyone back
hopefully let's see how many people got
open this.
All right.
So we covered the starts with right.
We covered the contains methods.
And now
let's go ahead and talk about to end with
okay so ends with it's
it's not implemented in expats
right now they removed it it was before
there was a version
one of expats there was ance with before
and then they upgraded the x path
to version two.
Now this method is not available.
Okay, so let me put it in here.
Was used in x 1.0
and but we are using so any any
what's called
any browser right now is using path 2.0.
Okay.
So they removed
whoever is upgrading the X path
as they remove the they remove s
with method from the x back to.
So this method is not available right now.
Okay.
Using 2.0
and this method is not
available.
Okay Yes, it's better if you memorize.
I mean you don't really have to memorize
the more the more you start using them,
the better you get, the more comfortable
you get in using this.
So you don't really have to memorize, but
yeah, these things,
they need practice only.
Okay,
So for it
or there's no need for it anymore.
There is.
Oh, there is no need for this
because you can use contains.
Right.
So I don't know why they still keep
this starts with you can use contains for
for the ending part
right or the beginning part or the middle.
So it doesn't really matter
any part of the value.
You can use it with contents right.
So for this content
is pretty much the perfect use.
Exactly. Yeah.
I'm not sure why they keeping this starts
with in here in these cases.
Okay.
You can use contains in here
in absolutely everywhere
because it's like a wild card right.
So you can use this starting
with starting a partial value
or the ending partial value
doesn't really matter.
You just contains with that. Right?
So but I'm not sure why
they keeping this starts with
they can probably remove that as well.
All right.
So now, guys, let's talk about the
the tag names in the
in the HTML. Okay.
So what they mean, what they stand for.
Okay. So let's talk about that.
So They
a lot of
what's called
a lot of tag names that we saw
were div in here.
Right.
What do we know about div?
Do we know what it stands for?
Guys?
Exactly. It's a division, right?
It's simple.
So this is the division
of some part, right?
So if you go here you can see that
if I just hover over my mouse
inside the HTML,
you can see this, this division covers
the whole log in part where you
where you enter email, password,
log in button, all of that.
Right.
So it's just basically containers.
Exactly. Yes.
So if there's a division,
anyone know what IMG is?
So pretty straightforward,
right? It's pretty
easy.
It's an image, right?
So most of the time it is
an image or any symbol on the web page.
Okay.
What do we know about H?
Anyone knows about H? Guys
header write simple.
It's a header.
So most of the time
you will see a header in
a in tables or in just, just any websites.
Okay.
So any, any header off the website.
Right.
So H1, H2.
Exactly. Okay.
So do we know what p stands for guys.
Anyone notice p in
any h html or when you inspected the page.
Exactly.
That's a paragraph, right? So
paragraph, whenever you have
a story or anything
like two or three sentences in there,
the developers say they put it
usually inside the paragraph.
Right. All right. So what about l I guess
it's a list, right?
So, exactly.
So when you have different
different choices
in there,
you can put them inside list, right?
So that it last.
Anyone knows what is U
Allardyce.
Just the UI.
That's the it's not a URL right.
Unless almost almost
on the line.
Not really.
So l i is list
u l is an ordered list.
Okay.
Unordered lists.
And what about all L guys?
So this one should be pretty
straightforward
order list.
Right? Okay.
All right.
So we have divisions,
we have images, we have headers, right?
So and then we have order lists.
We have an order list.
We just have less. Right?
So there's different different tags
in HCM.
Okay.
So now let's
go ahead and create a new package in here
and do some automation here.
Okay. So I created Class three package.
And what I'm going to do,
I'm going to create a Java class.
Okay? So
that's
the amount.
All right. So we will be working.
So let me get the main method,
get the main method in here,
All right? Okay.
So we will be working on this website.
Okay.
So we already worked on this,
but now what we going to do?
We will be using X path all the way along.
Okay.
So for this example.
So first of all,
what do we need to do guys?
So we have a main method, we have a class
in here, What's our first step?
We need to set the properties right?
So system that set property
and we have to pass
two different arguments in here.
So one of them is web driver
Chrome
driver.
And then the second one is where
our chrome driver
is located right.
Okay.
So after we set our properties,
what is our next step?
So we need to launch the browser
now, right?
So what I'm going to do,
I'll have a web driver.
Driver is equal to new
chrome driver.
All right.
So now after we have the object
of the web drivers and now what we need to
do, we need to navigate to the zero
right driver yet.
And what I will do let me set this.
Okay.
I hope you guys have this URL.
Yeah.
Anyone
that marked.
Okay, very good.
I just send it as well.
Okay.
So we're going to be
navigating to this website
and then so we know
that we have to log in first.
Okay.
So I'm going to click
on this magic arrow in here
and back here.
Okay. So this is my element. Okay?
So in order for me to start
with an X path, what do I need to do
first?
Anyone know
we need to go to
we need to enable our selector box, right?
So how do I do that?
I ahead and do command s right.
If you're using windows,
you do control F Okay,
so now we'll start
with double slash, right?
And we will start with input, right?
Because this is our tag name.
So now what do we want to use in here
guys?
What do we want to use in here?
Which attribute do we want to use?
So we already have our tag name in here.
I'll do a
class.
Let's see.
Okay,
so let's go ahead and use class guys.
So class is equal
to single code and text.
Okay? Okay.
What identified our elements
is this element unique goes
no. Right.
So that means we cannot be using
that class attribute because we have
two different elements right now. Okay.
So in order for you guys to see this
second element.
Okay, so we know that it identified
two different elements.
So for us, I want to know what is the
second element that it located right now.
So what I can do there is arrows in here
up and down.
Okay, So you click on Search next,
it's going to go to the next available
element.
Okay.
So you click on Arrow, back up,
it's going to the first element.
So this is how you
go through the elements
that are located in here in your DOM.
Okay,
so we have to have one of one in here.
So what we need to
do is we need to change the
okay, so I want to use ID
in this case, but
I don't want to use the whole value of ID.
Okay.
So what do we want to use in here?
We can use contains right?
So let me delete this.
Okay.
So what I can do contains
and then parentheses
inside the parentheses.
What am going to do?
I'm going to put add sun and ID
right comma in here, single quotes
and they're good for us.
Is the last the last part, right.
Which says username. Okay.
So what we can do
is just put the username in here
and it will identify all elements one one
and it is okay.
So what I will do I will copy this X pass.
Now I need to go back to our
script.
Right.
So driver, start find element.
What am I finding it by now?
What is the located that I'm using?
Guys, I'm using an X path, right?
So if you look in here
we have an option to use X path.
So let's go ahead and put it here
and inside the parentheses,
double quotes and insert our x path
to close this.
What do we need to do in here, guys?
Do I have to perform an action
right away?
What if I don't want to perform an action
How can I do this?
Not necessary. Okay.
We need to store it inside the variable.
Right?
So whenever you find another event,
you are getting an element
in return.
So the use name
is equal to this.
And then
username
send keys.
So our username is tester, right?
So this is our first element,
right?
So I, I input a username.
So now it's time for us to go back
and locate the password.
Okay, let me delete this one.
Okay. So now
help me with identifying
help with identifying
the second element,
which is password textbox.
So this is my element.
What, where do I start with?
So double slash and input, right?
So which, which attribute
do we want to use in this case, guys
type.
Right.
We can use type because it's short
and we're using X class.
We can, we can go ahead and use
any different attributes for this element.
Right?
So X sign type here is equal
to single quotes and password.
Right?
There we go. So we have one off one.
So that means we identify
this element uniquely.
And I'm going to copy this,
go back to my script
and I will do web elements.
Password
Z, Perfect driver
find element
but X plus
this this in here
and then plus four.
So keys it is test
right?
Okay.
So there is one more thing
that I want to show you guys.
Whenever you are using the
the existing methods
like driver that find element right driver
that find element,
how do we know that we can get a web
element in return? Dice
or we could do driver dot get title guys
how do we know that
we getting a string in return
in this in this case
anyone
any ideas.
Okay.
So whenever we start using
the methods right it shows us right away.
So whenever I do find element in here,
it shows me
the return type on the right side.
Okay,
so you're getting a web element object.
If it's void,
what are you getting in return, guys?
If it's void, you're getting a string.
If it's void,
we're not getting anything right.
So there's no return. Okay, good.
All right, so now it's time
let's go back and click on this log in.
Right.
So from here,
it's the log in.
All right, So we have the same
we have the same tag name, right?
Double,
double, slash input, square brackets.
What do we want to use in this case, guys?
So we have ID class,
we have name type value type should work.
We've used type before,
so let's use value.
Okay.
Let's
see if we can use value in this case.
So assign value is equal to
log in.
There we go.
One of one. It's unique, so it's good.
So now what I'm going to do,
I'm going to copy this X path.
We'll go back in here
and I'll do web element
log in button
equal cool driver
find element
by Express and I'll paste this in here.
So what kind of action
I would be performing on our log
in button, log in button, not click.
All right.
So we have identified using our password
and log
in button with the values in here.
All right.
So let me go ahead and run this guy.
Let's see.
It's fitting.
There we go. So we use three X classes.
We could send keys to username password,
and we could click on the log in button.
All right.
So pretty easy and pretty straightforward.
Any questions on this, guys?
All you can do is
any questions on absolute
and relative expects guys
rights.
Okay, So no questions. That's good.
So it is a little bit
confusing, guys, but
we'll be practicing a lot
and we will get as much comfortable
as possible by practicing these experts.
Okay, So now, guys,
we passed the absolute and relative
X path is in here.
So now what I want to show you
is the advanced X stuff that
so this is going to be a little bit
confusion in here probably,
but it's easy as well.
Okay.
So the
okay anyone
anyone did a research on advanced
X factors?
Anyone know what advanced
X path is on the
if there's no selector that we need. Yes.
So you can say that.
Exactly. Yes.
So most of the companies
guys in most of the company.
So in my company, in my company we use
you could use any different locator
you want.
But in my company
mostly use IDs and experts.
Okay.
So if we don't have an I.D.,
our developers
usually don't have a lot of different.
Okay, So most of the time
where we need to use X, okay.
Because X is very, very versatile
and very very convenient for us.
Okay.
Do companies dictate what to use?
Some of them do.
Some companies do,
especially when you go to the
if you land on a government project.
Okay.
Because they want they they want
they want the code
according to their format,
according all their structure
and all that stuff.
Okay.
So but most of the most of the private
projects, they don't really care.
They don't really care
as long as everything works.
They don't mind using X path
or different different locators.
Okay.
I remember I think it was one of the guys
that he was in one of the batches
he thought a job
and I think he used something different
and I think he almost got fired for that.
So I don't remember,
but usually doesn't happen.
So don't get scared, okay?
It doesn't usually happen.
It's if you if you if you start working
and they told you that
this is a must and you don't do this,
then you have a problem.
Okay.
But if they don't say anything
about these kind of stuff, so you could
you get to use anything.
Okay.
I work with Maven, correct? Yes.
Training
and orientation are really, really
important guys.
Okay,
There is one more thing about absolute
and relative expert
that I want to show you.
Okay?
So in absolute path, guys,
so we talked about that.
You need to start from the very,
very starting note in HTML, right?
So in relative expo,
you can do
you can start from note
and what you can do
is going back and forth.
Okay, So let's say
let's say we started on this note,
we can jump to this back here
or you can jump
you can jump from this note to here.
It doesn't really matter.
That's why relative X is very,
very versatile.
Okay.
So you can jump to the
to the next note
or you can go to the previous note.
Okay.
And I'm going to show you how to do this.
But in absolute X path,
when you start from
the very top, you
can you can only go forward.
Is that clear, guys?
Any questions?
Let's.
All right.
So advanced X path us so advanced
X path is
is based on parent
and child and also sibling relationships.
Right.
As we talked before
in the beginning of the class, we said
there is HTML
that is parent and then head and body.
It's child children, right?
And then head and head and body
will be siblings to each other.
Okay. Yeah, there is ancestors as well.
There's a lot of different, different
keywords and expect that you can use.
Okay, so now let me put it here.
Advanced X path is based
on parent and child.
Child and
sibling
relationships.
Okay, So now
let's start with the following siblings.
Okay, So
identifying
elements by
following sibling.
Okay, So I'm going to put a syntax again
in here.
Okay.
It's it's very similar to what we've done
with relative X,
but it is considered as relative X path.
But it's on top of that.
It's in no bid advance
than the usual express.
Okay, so we have a tag name,
double slash tag name
square brackets attribute
and then the attribute value.
But then after this,
what you want to do in here,
you want to put a single slash
you want to write down following
sibling,
and then you put double column in here
and then the tag name of the next
following symbol.
Okay.
So this
this is probably confusing right now,
but let's go and see how this works.
Okay.
Let me go to one side.
My choice, you guys
know this one
here.
Have you worked on this application
before this or no?
Same value in two boxes?
Not read this is.
Yeah, it's about to get stuck. Exactly.
Okay,
this is okay.
So this is the syntax
where you guys are going to be doing
all the projects when you start
doing the framework and everything.
Okay, so
let's see
if this was a fast or beautiful.
Okay, let me find the first one.
Um, on set,
you guys,
I forgot what the password was.
Oh, you already done the project.
If you guys have the
the password for this, I will send it
because I'm not finding it right
or the admin.
Is that using it. Oh I think one second.
I think the input the right one
potentially the No.
I headed somewhere once every once.
Oh there we go. Yes.
Thank you.
I was missing one
area.
Okay.
Thank you.
Nice. Okay.
All right, so we logged in and here.
Okay, so I'm going to go
to this page.
Okay?
And then what
I will do, I'm going to inspect.
Okay, So now what I want
to do, I want to
I want
to identify.
You don't have to, guys.
You can.
You can follow me right now, okay?
You don't have to log in right now.
Okay.
I think Jamal then is he sent
the password, but the username is admin.
Okay.
Username is admin with capital A
we we have a passport and live chat,
so please use that if you want to log in.
Okay, but
just follow me for now.
Okay. All right.
So what I want to do, you can see here
there is a calendar
symbol or image in here. Okay?
So you can choose any date.
So I want to do
I want to click on this small calendar.
Okay, So
but here I only have this.
This is my element, right?
I only have the class.
I have the source.
Right.
And I have something different in there.
Okay.
So there's nothing that I can use
right now
to locate this element directly.
Okay.
So what I will do in here,
I will need to use the advanced X back.
Okay, So
let's go ahead and open up
our selector box in here.
So now,
since we're using the following sibling,
it means that I need to start
from the step before.
Okay, so let me look at the
at the sibling in here, which is input.
Okay.
So if you look at the input right now,
what does it have?
Guys, can we can we locate this directly
without doing anything.
Goes do does it have
the locators that we
can use in here.
Yes. Right. Okay.
So what I'm going to do in here,
I'm going to start with the input
IDs unique.
So what I'm going to do,
I'll start with the input tag.
Okay. So a double slash.
Okay, input.
And then we said
we're going to be using ID, okay.
Is equal to
single quotes in here and let's see.
So calendar from date, right.
So I'm going to post
the value in here. Okay.
So we have one of one what identified this
element uniquely, right.
But this element is not our target
the next element is right.
So what I will start doing in here,
I'll put a single slash
and I'll start typing following that
sibling double column
and then the tag name
that the element I'm looking has.
Okay.
So in this case we have I am g in here.
So what I will do,
I'll just put IMG in here
and you can see that identify
the next sibling of the calendar
of this input element.
Okay. Is that clear, guys,
Any questions?
So I see there is question
why we need to use advanced X style.
Okay.
We use the advanced X path
when we cannot locate
the element directly by a relative x box.
Okay.
So if you look in this on this element,
it has only class,
but I don't think it's unique.
Okay.
If you use that class, I don't there
they're probably two
or three elements in here.
So you and you don't have other IDs, names
of different locators in here.
Okay.
So if you are using the following sibling,
you need to start from the element
before that.
Okay.
So in this case, the element before
that is the input tag.
And we can identify this by IP.
Okay.
So you identify this element by ID
and after that
you go to your following sibling.
Okay.
A source would be unique,
but it might not.
It's really long and you can
you can use contains in this case,
but that might not be unique.
What if sibling cannot
can also not be identified?
Then we're going to go to parents
and ancestors and I'm going to explain you
what's called a number.
I explain you that in a little bit. Okay.
So we go step by step.
For now, let's understand
how the following sibling advanced
X path works
for following sibling path. Yes.
Yes. After the following sibling,
you only need to use the tag name.
Okay.
Okay guys,
there is one more thing for X path. Yes.
So you're saying you using
you can use the indexing as well, right?
So you can use indexing in some cases
whenever
like it's not unique or anything.
Right.
So you can use indexing, but it's not that
reliable.
Okay.
So try to avoid using indexing
unless you are forced to use those.
Okay.
How to distinguish if it's unique or not.
So how do we know if it is what you need?
This element, this this one or the element
that we just find out?
How do you distinguish?
You could just write a next path for this.
Okay, So go ahead and write an X path for
image class and this value
and see if it's unique to.
I said it might not be you.
There is numbers.
Yeah, that might be dynamic.
Exactly. Yes.
So, okay, guys,
the reason we're doing this,
the reason we're doing this is because
we want to learn the advanced X stuff.
Okay?
So that's why
you can probably
you can probably identify this element
with class attribute and class value.
This is fine, but our purpose is to learn
how to use the advanced X back.
Okay,
So let's focus on Advanced Express and
what's called
and use following siblings
for this example.
Okay, So here
we are again
identifying the element before the one
we want to actually identify.
Okay, So we can see here it has ID.
So these are most reliable ones, right?
So we're going to use
this will identify that element
and then we step over the following
sibling.
Okay.
The class is not unique.
There you go.
You're confused about the elements
we use this for.
Which one?
This one, the input one.
So we using this to identify
the next element.
Okay.
All right, guys.
So let me copy this.
Where is this?
Paste this in here.
Okay, Now let me go back.
Let me delete this. Okay.
If you were about to use
the relative extract,
right for this image,
how would you write X Factor?
How would I start in here?
Okay, double slash image.
Right.
So you have
you have a class, right?
So let me use the class
is equal to the date picker.
Right. So.
So this and paste it in
how many elements did I find out
to. Right.
So this is not unique
and you don't want to use source
because it's too long, right?
Even if you do contains it might be not
okay.
So it might find another element
with the same containing string in there.
There you go.
Source is not unique either.
Okay, that's good to know. Okay.
So that's why.
Now, guys, this element,
you can not locate this element
by just writing a relative X plus.
Okay?
That's
why you need to write an advanced path
so that you can move through the notes.
Okay.
If you move through the notes,
then you can identify that element unique.
Okay, so in this case,
since we identifying this element.
Okay, what I can do,
I can start with this input element
and then jump on this one
because the previous element
that I am identifying it has ID
and we already know that IDs
are most reliable and unique, right?
So we can use this ID
and then jump onto the next sibling.
Okay.
Any questions, guys?
Sure. In case
parents of child
following knot, it's going to be now
it's going to be a little bit different.
And we
we will be going through it right now.
Okay.
All right.
So siblings are fine.
So now let me go back here
and let me put identifying elements
by preceding siblings.
Okay, guys, I didn't have a source for.
You mean if it didn't have this s r c
No, no, no, no.
Guess.
All right, so here's why we're not using
neither class nor source in here.
Guys, what's the reason?
Because they are not unique.
Right?
But what we want to do,
we want to identify this element
as unique as possible.
Right?
So that's why what I need to do,
I need to identify the element before
and then switch to the next one,
because the the element that I want to
I want to locate
it doesn't have any unique locators.
Okay?
That's why I need to move
through the nodes inside my HTML.
Okay.
I hope this is clear now.
All right, so let me copy this one.
Place it in here.
So identifying elements
by preceding sibling.
Okay,
so the same thing, double slash, right?
Tag name attributes, attribute value.
But then instead of following sibling,
what I need to do,
I need to go to my preceding symbol.
Okay, so right now
we just went to the following sibling.
Okay, so now with the preceding sibling,
we will be going upwards
or you could say backwards in the HTML.
Okay, so let's go back,
open up here, let's open Amazon
Amazon.
Amazon. Okay.
So there's a lot of stuff going on in
here, right?
So let's inspect this page.
So let's do this.
All right.
Okay.
So in this case, guys,
I think we can identify
this element by by using text.
Okay.
But we will try to identify this
by using preceding siblings. So
basically,
once, correct?
Yes, exactly.
So you're trying to find that unique one
and then move to
the one that is not unique. Correct.
Not the locator, the element.
Right.
The element which is not unique.
Okay, guys.
So what I want to do, I want to identify
this element, which is the return okay,
so we know that there's one
way to do it with the text.
Okay.
But what I want to do in here,
I want to go to the to this one first,
okay?
And then jump to the previous one.
Okay. Is that clear, guys?
Is it clear what I'm doing?
Any questions?
Okay, cool.
So where do we start in this case?
So I want to identify this element
first and then go.
Go back
to the preceding sibling.
And here
I give you an example.
Yes, this was an example, right?
This in here
that the first one that we did,
we're going for advanced X path
because we cannot identify one element.
What would the regular relative expect?
Okay, in here,
how would you identify this element
with the relative X by the source
attribute is not unique.
The class attribute is not unique. Okay.
So you have to move inside your HMO.
Okay.
All right.
So here, let's identify the first element
that we need to add here.
How how would you identify this element,
guys,
by using what's OC?
So double slash
span right then square brackets and here,
what am I using?
Can I use class here?
Okay,
let's use class and see if this is unique.
Okay, so let's use class
is equal to
let me copy this.
Okay.
Is this unique, guys?
It's not unique, right?
So it found three more elements in here.
That means we won't be able to use class.
Okay, So what we can do in this case,
we can use the text
that this element has, Right?
So I'll go and do text.
Right.
And then
equal to this single quotes in here
and then and I think
all this right now,
this one is unique, right?
So we have this as unique one.
Okay, So now but my purpose
is to go to this path, right?
So where am I going right now?
I am moving to my preceding sibling
from this span.
The taxes here
and orders is a text.
Okay, so now what
I will do, I'll put a single slash
preceding sibling double column again.
And then what is my preceding siblings?
Tag guys, the tag is span, right?
So if I do span, it moves one up,
so it goes to my preceding sibling.
So this will identify this as unique.
Thank you.
Yeah.
You can use
you can use the text for return. Yes.
I'm just doing this
so that we can preceding siblings.
Okay.
You can use text for that.
Copy this is
this is
all right.
One more time, guys.
I'm starting from the next element.
Right.
Which is the and orders element. Right.
So identify this by
let me actually this
I identified this element by its text
and I want to move one sibling up.
So what I will do,
I'll go with preceding siblings and the
tag name.
Okay.
How do you know that an order is text? So
you can see this.
It's inside the span.
So this fan is open
Spanish closed in here.
And you can see the text.
Usually it's it's written in black font.
Okay.
So that's
how you know that this is a text.
We use the unique
locator of one element up
or down.
Exactly. Yes.
This is what we do. Right.
All right, guys, any questions?
Any questions on following and preceding
siblings?
Clear. Okay, good.
All right.
So now let's move to the parents.
Okay.
So copy this
piece by
point.
Okay.
So this is going to be the same syntax,
but what we're going to do,
we're going to change the little, right?
So it's not going to be preceding
sibling anymore.
It's going to be parents.
Right? Yes.
I told you guys last week. Right.
So it's going to be a little intense.
Okay.
And know that it's a little bit confusing,
but you just need practice.
Okay, guys.
And it's all going to be all right.
Okay.
But here is tag name.
But this is a
parent.
Tag me.
Okay. All right.
So now let's move here. Okay.
So what if
I want to identify this element's parent?
What is my parent right now in this case?
Guys, the tag, Right?
So if you look in here.
So if I collapse this, right,
if I collapse this,
you can see that they're gone.
So this the upper node,
which is your element within,
is going to be your parent.
Okay. Yes, exactly.
Span is inside a so here,
if I want to identify that element,
what I can do is slash
parent
and then double colon again
and the parent tag name is a right.
If you do this,
then you can see that it is highlighting
that parent element.
Okay.
Any questions on this, guys?
Any confusion?
Oh, good.
Correct.
This is going from child to the parent.
Okay.
So if you want to go from parent
to the child, what you can do
is remember that absolute expert
that's in absolute X spot.
What are we doing?
We're only moving forward, right?
So you don't have to do anything.
You can just put a slash
and move to the next one.
So where is that?
So in the first acts of with X back
when we were talking about it,
so body
is what body is child of your HTML?
Right.
So this div is the child of your body.
Okay,
so there's nothing like different keywords
for moving from parent to the child
where if you want to move
from child to the parent,
then you have to have an advanced X path.
Okay?
Each slash is a move forward.
Absolutely right.
Okay.
So let me
copy this and
things here.
So now let me show you
the one for ancestors.
Okay?
Copy.
Yeah.
Copy this as well.
So it is exactly the same.
But instead of going to the parent
tag name, you want to go
answer in here
and the ancestor tag name in here.
So what is considered to be ancestor guys?
Does anyone have an idea?
So it's above the parent?
Absolutely right.
So if you see anything above the parent,
okay, that's going to be your ancestor.
Okay, so grandfather, grand grandfather
or whatever, is that So here,
let me last this one.
So for this span,
what can be our ancestor guys?
So my tag,
if my eight tag is my parent, right?
So it can
be the div
in here or it can be the division here.
Right.
So let's actually go here.
Okay.
So in Facebook,
let's identify one of these.
So okay.
All right.
So let's do this, the email textbox.
And here let's, let's identify
this email textbox first.
Okay.
So double slash input
and square brackets.
You can use ID in here. That is fine.
Is equal to
email.
Right. So now I have this.
This is unique.
So in here, what is my parent guys?
My parents.
My parent is the division, right?
And my ancestor
can be above my parent, right?
So we have a div in here
and we also have the form.
So what I can do in here I can do
slash and
then ancestor double call.
And again let's put a form in here
and you can see that
it is going to highlight our ancestor
or anything
with the form tag
which is above my parent.
Okay, is this clear, guys, any questions
on this
Again, guys,
anything above your parent in HTML
will be considered as your ancestor?
Okay,
so I'm just going to copy this back here.
Is this here?
Okay.
So now, guys.
Exactly. All of us,
all of this are the same.
It's just up to you
how you want to move through the HTML.
If you want to move
forward to your sibling or
you want to move to the preceding sibling,
you want to move to the parent, it's
all up to the age, similarly all up to you
how you want to identify your element.
Okay, let's write a div.
Okay, so let's do instead of form,
let's see a division. Enter.
So instead of so if I do I ancestor as div
it will identify the very first one,
the very one at the top.
Okay.
Because we said that your
ancestor will be considered
what's called
above your parent.
Okay.
So that's why it will go as high,
as high as possible
to the first division, correct?
Yeah.
We are identifying the parent
and ancestors.
Right.
Or we could just put identifying elements.
Elements, ancestors.
All right.
And parents.
So all the other divisions that you have,
they will be ancestors.
But if you just put the in here
as ancestor,
it will identify
the very first one at the top.
Okay.
For the specific one,
you can use the indexing or just slash
by slash, right?
So can put another slash in the division.
It will go on and go on.
Okay.
Or you can do this. I don't know. Yeah.
If you do Div three, it's going
to another way.
Okay.
Any questions? Class
with this form?
It's not them. We can go but exactly.
So first you need to go
and find out the element which is unique.
And then from there,
which is really close to the element
that you want to find out
that you want to locate.
And then going from there,
if it's sibling or if it's parent,
whatever it is,
that way you can identify and use advance,
okay.
All right.
So let me show you
identifying elements by indexing.
Okay.
Now, so if we go actually here.
Okay, So we had two classes in here right?
So what we have is still I am g
at class is equal to
copy and paste in here.
Right.
Okay. All right, guys.
So here
we have two different elements, right?
If you don't have an option to use
preceding or following siblings
or parents forms, ancestors,
anything like that,
only then you can go and the indexing.
Okay, So if I do it here
and I put two in,
in between those square brackets,
which element is going to identify
guys?
Any thoughts?
So if I put two in here
would identify the second
element?
No. Why?
So let's do this. I put two in here.
Why did it not identify?
It didn't actually
it didn't identify any elements.
What's wrong in here, guys?
Any thoughts?
No tag. Okay, That's that.
That's very close. Yes.
What I do to identify the second
the second calendar in here
by using the index,
because we're using an index in here
and it's not seems like it's not working
at class two.
Let's
let's see if this is going to work, too.
This is not working.
All right.
Okay, let's see.
Image two.
Okay.
Image two is not working, guys,
any other thoughts?
See, they start from one.
And here.
Okay, guys, in here, what we need to do,
we need to go.
So since like in here,
don't have a tag, right?
So that we can go to the second one.
We need to get this whole element
into the container here.
Only then
we can identify the second element.
So how I'm going to do this,
It's pretty easy.
So I'm going to take this whole element
inside the parentheses
and what I'm going to do
with the square brackets,
and I'm going to put two.
Okay, So now I identify
the second calendar image on my page
by getting the whole element
inside container
and then specifying its index.
Okay, So before guys,
when we did this, where was this?
Yeah, when we did this absolute X plus,
we can put two or three in here
and this is going to work
because it's going to look the data
for this third division only.
But here you getting the whole element
and you need to put it into the container
and then specify
which element you're looking for.
Okay.
Any questions on this?
Let's get back
identifying element
by the area
you have, which is
you mean the HTML code has bugs?
Now, the HTML code will never
have a bug, right?
Because
this is how it's written and
it's our job to locate the elements.
Okay.
If you are talking
that you can see the element
and you can not see in the HTML,
then it's a defect.
So that's that's a different story.
But usually, guys,
most of the time you won't be able
won't have any problems in HTML, okay?
And you can't really go
and complain to developers,
Hey, you didn't put ID for this element
or you didn't put name for this element
because this is how they built it.
And our responsibility is to manipulate
everything inside that HTML.
Okay.
Yes, you are.
We are doing this to check bugs.
Absolutely right.
But we're not checking the HTML for bugs,
guys.
We're checking the functionality
of the web page for.
Okay, so this is two different things.
So if I click on log
in, you can see it in the HTML,
but if I don't log in, that's a problem.
Okay.
So that's the defect of the functionality.
Is that clear now, guys?
So we're not checking the HTML for bugs,
we're checking the functionality
of the web page for bugs.
Okay.
Your HTML is only
it only helps you to identify
and perform actions.
So if those actions fail and you don't
get the expected result,
only then it is a defect.
So if you don't see an ID
for some elements, it's not a defect.
Okay?
So you just have to manipulate
and go back and forth.
Use X path, different ways
to locate those elements.
Okay.
Any other questions?
And the website is not built by the HTML
only.
Exactly.
The website is built by h html.
I'm not sure if it's filled
with JavaScript or any other ones,
but I'm assuming it's
the frontend is filled with JavaScript
and the design is for it made with c ss.
Okay.
So if you have frontend developer,
you're going to be using HTML, CSS
and JavaScript or whatever you're using.
Okay, So JavaScript will build
your functionality.
H HTML will give you all the attributes.
See us, we'll give you the styling.
Okay,
This is how it works through the front.
Is that clear, guys?
Any questions?
So there was a lot of information
to today.
There's a lot of notes here.
Any other questions?
Brian Fries Yes, exactly.
Told you guys it's
going to be a little intense,
but tomorrow
we're going to have more fun, guys. Okay.
I promise Tomorrow
we're going to have different topics
and it's going to be more fun.
All right.
Yeah. I want you guys okay.
Is it Asgard fun?
No, no, no. It's my, my, my fun.
Okay, so it's going to be fun.
Okay.
All right, guys, any questions?
We're going to have a pizza party.
I'm not sure, guys.
I don't know
who's inviting where
can you go back?
Dying?
Not yet. Okay, just a little more. Okay.
When I get.
Let me give you the homework and then.
And then you can.
That's fun.
Little Caesars on me. Sure, sure.
If you find a job in two weeks, then yes.
Okay. This is recorded, guys, Just.
Just for information.
Okay?
This is.
You can show it to me if.
Michael,
if you find your job in two weeks,
I'm getting you a pizza.
There you go.
What a motivation.
Just Michael, though. Yeah.
Okay. There you go.
Class three recording. Exactly.
Yes. Okay.
Yes, I'll push the code
if there's no questions, guys.
Okay, Let me give you the homework.
Okay.
I'm pretty sure you are excited
for the homework, right?
Because we didn't really
do much to do.
All right, So let me just.
Students. All right.
So yesterday
was a lot of theoretical work.
As I said, I don't like this theoretical
stuff myself because it's pretty boring.
Okay, But,
well, we have to go through it first
so that we can start implementing stuff.
Okay.
We use any unique locators?
Yeah, absolutely.
Guys,
you can use any unique locator instead of.
Yes. Okay,
So let me tell you this.
Go in here
is here
o in your in the homework.
No, no, no.
In homework guys try to use X path.
I want you to use that
as much as possible for this homework.
Okay.
And guys,
I'm going to warn you for this homework.
There is a trick for this homework.
Okay, So let's
see if you can come up with ideas.
Okay, So what I want you to do
guys in here, so navigate to this side.
Okay? Click. Start practicing.
Okay, So I can start practicing.
This is going to open up, click on simple
form demo.
Okay,
You click on simple form demo,
you enter a message in here,
click on show message.
You the browser.
This will be easier, right?
Okay, let's see.
Let's see.
Okay, cool down. Yes, guys.
So get a break.
It is easy, but not with x path.
Okay, let's see, guys.
Let's see if you if you
if you have any stoppers in here.
Okay.
So I want there it should be
it should be a tricky task in here.
Okay.
But let's see if you can overcome this
for tomorrow.
Like, super easy.
Yes, right.
Would be would be super not easy.
Yeah.
I'll sent this homework
actually in the course announcements.
Okay.
There you go.
I just sent it to course
analysis of particular.
Okay.
Does it, does it need idea.
So No, no, no.
This it does give me that idea
kind of rap battle.
No I'm bad at that.
Okay.
I'm bad
notes here.
I'm going to push them right now. Okay.
Right after the class.
Okay, guys.
All right.
If there's no questions.
Yes, we can wrap it up. Guys.
I'm pretty sure you guys are all tired.
If no questions, then we can wrap it up.
Okay.
Thank you, guys.
I hope
you guys practice.
Okay?
Please try to complete the homework
for tomorrow. Guys.
For tomorrow,
please take a look at CCS selector
and please take a look at web element
commands.
Okay.
Tomorrow is going to be more fun, guys.
I promise.
Okay. It's not going to be like this
tomorrow.
We'll have more implementation
and have more automated stuff.
Okay.
I am from Tajikistan. Yes.
All right.
The commands
know there are different commands.
They are web element commands.
All right, guys,
have a good night.
Stay safe and please keep practicing.
Okay?
I'll push the code
right after in 5 minutes.
Okay.
All right.
Thanks, everybody.
Good night. And stay safe.
Bye bye.