All right, guys, let's get started.
I hope everyone is doing good
and everyone
got some rest and completed the homework
that I gave yesterday.
So how was yesterday's
class, guys?
I'm pretty sure everyone loved it.
Since we had a lot of stuff to talk about.
A new favorite word, pagination. Good
that everyone completed the homework
with calendars, text.
Any questions on the homework
was a little mixed.
But then why was it mixed?
Homework was easier than expected.
Okay.
Sorry. You weren't at yesterday's class.
That's
why we didn't have a lot of fun yesterday.
Because you were absent?
No, Nobody wanted to talk
yesterday.
Let's see.
Locating by Exfat works
for web element.
Well, I didn't get the question.
Why? Why? This is.
Oh. CheckBox has the tag input.
Okay.
Oh. Okay.
Let's check this out.
Okay.
So these checkboxes right.
Let's see. Okay.
So you are.
Let me see.
So you locating the label? Right.
So you locating the label.
And when you click on it, it's.
It's getting checked.
Correct? Yes. Okay. Okay. Okay.
I see.
All right, So here's the thing.
So when when developers built it.
Right.
So when developers built it,
they may throw
the label and the checkbox itself
on their each other.
Or they they may.
They may do it
as simply as we have it in here.
Okay.
So the checkbox itself
has an input in here,
and the label has the label tag in here.
Right.
But even manual, you guys even manually
when you click in here,
if I click on pending approval,
it's getting checked.
Right.
So this is how this is configured, guys.
It's not. It's anything that we can do.
Okay.
So this is how it is developed, guys.
So even manually, if you click
on the label, the checkbox is getting
is getting
what's called is getting checked.
Okay.
So web element contains of two lines.
No, it's two different web
elements. Right.
One of them is the label off the checkbox.
The other one is the checkbox itself.
But they the functionality is
when you click on the label,
it it checks the checkbox as well.
Okay.
It's it's still two different,
two different elements considered.
Right.
But when you click on the
on the label,
it gets checked in the checkbox as well.
Okay.
So that's just a functionality?
Yes. Most of the time with checkboxes
and radio buttons, guys,
even if even if you click on the label,
the checkbox
and radio button gets selected.
Okay. So this is how it's actually built.
You don't have to go inside that
square and check it.
Okay.
And in
automation, guys, maybe so in automation.
So you have that if conditions. Right.
So if you locate the checkbox itself
with input,
you won't be able to have your
if condition.
So that's why you have to locate the label
so that you have
so that you have the text.
Okay.
All right, guys.
Any questions?
Any other questions?
Okay.
If not, let's do a quick recap, guys,
what we've done.
Last class,
we said one favorite word of pagination.
What else, guys?
I hope you guys are active.
More active today than yesterday.
The thing we have a lot to cover
today. Yes.
We will be covering a lot of stuff
today as well.
Okay.
So yesterday
what we did is we covered calendars,
right?
Okay.
Type of calendars
and the pagination of the table.
Right.
So we did a couple examples
for pagination.
We saw what
how the web page
can behave when you change the pages
on the web tables.
Right.
And how what kind of errors we might get
when we change the pages,
when we navigating through the table
pagination.
Right.
Okay. So
and then we've talked
about calendars, guys.
So what does the calendar consist of
if we look in the HTML
guys, what what are we going
to see?
It's it's it's consisted of table, right?
It's similar to table.
We have a header,
we have the tea body, right.
So and we have months and a year.
Right.
So the last time we covered the calendars
here, we had the month and a year
a stored inside that dropdown.
Right.
So today we will be covering a little bit
different calendars.
It's not going to have any dropdowns.
It will have the same
the same structure as we had
last class with dates,
but not with a month and the year.
Any questions from the yesterday's
class guys?
Any questions from pagination?
The practice. Okay, good.
All right.
So I'm going to create a new packaging
here.
Okay.
Instead, and what I will
do, I'm going to create a new Java class.
And I'll say
calendar handling.
Okay, So today we're going to be doing
we're going to cover
a couple of different topics.
So what we're going to do today, guys,
we will be handling
another type of the calendar.
Okay.
What we're going to do,
we will be working with the keyboard keys.
Okay.
We're going to do we're going to take
some screenshots, guys.
And what we're going to do,
we will be going over the actions class.
Okay.
Four different things occur today, so
please pay attention, guys.
And in the second half of the class guys,
I want you guys to pay
really close attention
because we will be downloading
some jar files.
Okay. So
now let's get started.
And it's
okay.
So, calendars, right?
So let me go in here.
So we will be working with calendars on
this Web page,
which is the Delta Web page.
Right.
So if I click on the calendar,
you can see that
we have two different calendars right
away, two different months, two different
weeks in here. Right.
And the dates we have double.
So in the previous example that we did
yesterday,
the calendar only had one month's inside
that element.
Right.
But here we have to deal with both
and we have to keep everything
as dynamic as possible.
Okay.
So, first of all, guys,
whenever you navigate to this website
and you try to
when you click on the calendar,
what are you going to look for?
So let's say you take a vacation.
What are you going to
fix first in here?
So is it a date? Is it a year?
What are you looking for in here?
Departure date and return date.
Okay. Say the year. Okay.
So from to date, The month.
Right.
First of all, what you need to do.
You need to get the right month. Right.
So the left side of your calendar
that we opened right now is going to be
what guys
current months.
But also even
even if I go next, next in here,
what am I going to have on the left side?
Guys?
Departure. Right. Departure date. Okay.
So what I'm going to do on the left side,
I will choose the departure, right?
And then on the right side,
I will choose the return date.
Okay, So first of all, whenever we open up
this calendar, what I need to do,
I need to pick the right month.
So let's say
I'm leaving in December, right?
I'm living in December. So my
my December has to be at the last.
If I'm leaving on 15th,
I need to click on this.
If I'm coming in January,
I need to click on this one.
Right.
So departure is going to be on the left
and the
what's called the return date
will be on the right hand side.
Okay.
Yeah.
You can arrive in the same month. Yes.
But with the with the implementation
today, today
that we're going to be doing,
we won't be arriving the same month.
Okay.
Because if you do it with the same month,
it's really easy to implement.
So we want something
a little bit advanced.
Right.
So, okay,
so now let's go back to our code.
And here
and let's
copy this
and let's change
the world.
Okay.
So when we navigate to the
to the Delta website,
what do we need to do first? US.
Okay, So we need to locate the element
which which element
that we're looking for in here.
First of all, what we need to do,
we need to expand the calendar itself.
Right.
So what I need to do,
I need to locate this calendar in here
and what I need to do,
I need to
click on it right so that I can get it
expanded.
Okay.
So let's see what we can use in here.
Or we go.
Seems like
there is an idea that we can use, right?
So let's take a look at the idea in here
or let's just
calendar label another label, Right.
Okay, that's fine. We can use this.
All right.
So let me copy this idea in here.
Let's go back to our script. Right.
So create a web element in here.
Calendar is equal to.
I forgot.
Find element.
I place this here,
and what I simply need to do
is simply need to click on it
so that I can have it expanded.
Right.
Okay, So let's go back in here.
Let's actually refresh
so that everywhere
everything gets the default.
All right.
So let's click on this.
So when I expand this, okay,
would I expand this?
So let's decide
when we'll leave in first.
It's October right now.
So let's go ahead.
It's October right now. So let's go.
Let's go in December.
Okay, Let's go in December
so that we can have more manipulation
inside the
inside the calendar.
Okay. So.
So before
I. Before I do anything, guys,
what I need to do,
I need to go to December.
Right.
In order to do so,
what do I need to do, guys?
I need to click the arrow. Right?
So what I need to do in order
for me to click the arrow,
I need to first locate this.
Right?
So let's locate this.
We have a text in here.
So what we can do,
we can simply create a next path, right?
So let's see. It has an
tag in here, and text
is equal to
next, right? It's one of one.
It is unique.
So what we can do is
we can simply copy that X path.
All right.
And let me create a web element,
next button,
and let's create this
X path.
There we go.
So we have this element, right?
So now, in order for me to go
to the right months, what do I need to do?
Guys?
Which
what do I need to have on hand right now?
Guys, it's like twice.
Well, right now,
if we click twice on this,
we know that it's it's
going to be a hard coding, right?
So we don't want to click twice, right?
What if we change the month later on?
So before we get to the month, guys,
what do we need to know?
We need to know the months.
What we have on the left side,
you don't see my screen.
Okay, I'll get All right.
Okay, guys.
So what we need to do,
we need to make do we need to know
the month of our departure first, Right?
So what I'm going to do, guys,
I'm going to go ahead in here
and I need to get this this month.
Right.
So what I can do in here
and we click until December
found not really right.
We won't be doing it this way. Okay.
So what I need to do in here,
how am I going to.
How am I going to locate this element?
Dice in here?
So I have a I have a span tag.
I have a text which is October,
but I want to keep this as dynamic
as possible.
How am I going to do this in here?
It doesn't matter
what text I have in there.
I need to locate that element.
Okay, Before we get text, how am I?
Am I supposed to locate this element
by simply class name?
Right. We have a class name in here.
Right. Okay.
So copy this.
All right, let's go back in here.
So what I am going to do is
departure months, right?
Is equal to driver.
The find element
by class name.
And I'll just paste this class
name in here.
So now this is my element.
So now what I need to do, I need to have
that element's value, right?
So I need to have
the text of that element.
So what I will do,
I will simply create a string in here.
Departure month text
is equal to
departure months.
Get text,
right?
We're not we're not clicking on anything
right now.
Right.
We will be clicking
a little bit later.
Okay.
So now, guys, okay,
so we opened up a we opened up.
Let's go back here.
We opened up a calendar in here.
So now we know when we'll leave.
We know
that we're leaving in December, Right?
But we don't know how many times I need
to click in here.
Okay.
So what do we have to use in this case
in order for me
to get to December in here, guys? Why?
Right. Because.
Because in white loop,
you don't know how many times
you will be click
or how many times you will be iterating.
Right.
Okay, So let's go back in here.
So what I am going to do
is create a wire loop.
What am I going to have inside
my condition?
Guys in here, Boolean value.
Okay, What kind of what would be
visible text is not in December.
Okay.
Really good. Right.
So what I will have and here
I need to compare the text that I got
and the x all departure months
that we want to go.
Right.
And in this case
it's going to be December.
So in order for me to perform
any action in here,
my months cannot be equal to December.
Right.
If it equal,
if it's going to be equal to December,
then I don't need to perform
any actions in here.
Right.
So in here, guys, what I need to do,
I'm just going to put an exclamation mark
and say that while my month
is not equal to December,
only then what I will do,
I'll go ahead and click
on the next button.
Is that clear, guys?
Any questions?
Okay, so now let me run this.
Okay, Let's run
this and see what we're going to have.
So if I run this right
now, what's going to happen
are we're going to stop
in December, guys?
Well, we should write.
Okay.
Navigated here.
What's going on, guys?
Okay.
I think it failed right now.
Line 20.
Okay.
It couldn't locate the element, right?
We have no such element exception.
Okay, So let's go back in here.
Let's check the element
again.
Okay.
There we go.
Input.
So see, guys, this is different now.
Okay,
so if you look in here, guys,
the ID that I chose before,
it was input return date.
Now it's input departure date y
because we have
we did some choosing in here.
That's why it might have changed.
Okay, so let me run this again
and see if this is going to change again.
Okay. Now it clicked.
All right.
You can see, guys, that it's
it keeps clicking
until the next button is what?
Until it gets disabled.
Right. So it's key. It's keeping
to click
on this button until it gets disabled.
And you can see that
it's August 20, 22 already.
So we don't need this.
We only need December 2021.
Right.
So how can we fix this issue?
What do you guys think?
What is going on in here
and break the loop?
We don't need to break the loop
right in here
because whenever this condition
is not met,
it's going to be clicking.
If you put December 2021, it's
not going to work, right?
Because let's open this up.
So in here, guys, what we did,
we only located the month,
month
and a year are two different in here.
Okay, so we only located the month.
Any thoughts?
Nice.
Let's go back to the code.
And here.
Okay. So
could the year.
We don't need the year, right, guys?
We don't really care about the right now.
Okay, guys, here's the thing in here.
When I go to my first iteration,
what is my month text in here?
Guys,
let's go step by step.
Okay, So when I first start my iteration,
I open up a calendar.
So I got the text right.
What is my text
in the first iteration, guys?
October. Right?
So, okay.
Does it equal to December?
No. Okay, I'm going to click. Okay.
So when I go to my second iteration,
what is my month in here guys?
Is it
is it November guys?
It is still going to be October
because after each iteration,
we're not checking
what text we have in here.
Okay.
We're
not updating the text inside our script.
So what we need to do in here
after we click in here,
we need to re assign this variable
and we need to get that text again.
Okay.
So now after second,
after the first iteration, I get the text.
It is November now.
So now we're checking November.
It's not December, so click Now it's going
now I'm going to get the text again.
And now it is December
and I will not go inside the Y.
Okay, So let's run this and see
if this is going to work.
A navigated here. There you go.
So now what happened
is we stopped in December
and our December is at the left side.
Okay. Is that clear, guys?
Any questions on this?
Pretty easy, right?
Okay, so let's close this.
So now what we need to do in here,
we chose our we know where and what month.
We'll leave it.
Now, what we need to do,
we need to choose the departure date.
That is why
we don't get the expected outcome.
Absolutely right. Yes.
So here, every time you click
on the next button, what you need to do,
you need to get the text
so that this variable gets updated.
Okay.
If you don't do this,
this variable will always stay
as October.
Okay.
All right.
So now what we need to do is
we need to come up with a date
when we're leaving.
Right. So December 2021, in here.
So now what we need to do,
we need to start looking inside the dates.
All right, so let's go back in here.
Let's see what we got.
So this is my table.
All right, so where do I need to
go in order for me to start
what's called
to start choosing my date? Guys
t body.
Right. So
here, guys,
since this is the table, right?
And the same table is applicable
on the return guys,
so the only thing that I can go
is going to be the T body, right?
So we can simply find the T body
because it has a class attribute in here.
So let's check if this is going to be
unique enough for us.
Right.
Instead of going from the table,
what I can do in here,
I can simply go start with t body
and let's put a class in here.
C let me copy this
basis in here.
Okay, so this is one of one.
So pretty good.
It's unique
enough for us to use it, right?
So what do I need to do next?
So I located my body.
What is my next step?
So I just leave it like this.
Store it in a less.
Okay. The whole body.
This is one element.
Why do I need a list?
We need to go through the data. Right.
So first of all,
I need to go through the rows in here
and then I have to go through the dates.
Right.
So there you go.
So now we have in here, I'm going through
each and every date in here. Right?
So let me copy this now. Okay.
So now what we can do with this,
We can store this inside
the list of web elements right?
Some element we can say
departure dates
for the
x path
is this X factor in here
and less import this list.
Util. Okay. What's wrong guys in here
find elements right now so
this should resolve the issue in here.
Okay. So what do I need to do next? Okay.
I have all the dates inside the container.
What am I going to do next?
We need to loop. Right.
So let's try to for loop in here.
All right.
So I am
iterating through elements
for departure date
departure dates, and here.
Okay, so now what date our leaving guys
want to go on? 19.
Okay, so let's go in 19th. Right.
So if we want to go on 19th, how,
how do we want to do this
and f condition.
Right.
So I'll put an f condition here.
So what I'll do departure date,
what I need to do
first I need to get the text
and then I need to compare it to the
my expected one and here.
Right.
And then what I need to do,
I simply need to click on it.
And after I click it, guys,
what I need to do,
I need to stop my iteration
and break the loop.
Right?
Okay, so now let's run
this and see if we can get December 19th
on our calendar.
December.
There we go.
So we clicked on 19th.
We navigate it to December
and we clicked on 19.
Right? Pretty cool, right?
So we don't know how many times
we need to click.
We set the condition, we built the logic,
and we don't have to do any hard
coding in here, right?
So we we chose
what day we're going to be departing.
So now what we need to do,
we need to choose
what date we will be coming back right?
So in this case, what we need to do,
we need to focus
on the right hand side of our calendar.
Right. So when are we coming back?
Now, guys.
When do you guys want to come back?
Never.
Should we just buy a one way
ticket. So
a month vacation.
Okay, so let's come back on February,
right?
Depends where we go.
We don't. We don't even know that. Okay,
So we don't know.
We don't know where we go. And guys.
Okay, so
let's come back.
Let's come back. Maybe.
Yeah, February should be fine, right?
So if we want to come back in February,
you guys.
So what do I need to do in here?
Do I have to
locate this next arrow again in here?
Guys?
No. Right.
We don't need that because we already have
that variable stored in our code.
What I need to do, I need to locate
the month on the right hand side.
Okay?
Okay, So let's go ahead and see in here.
Okay,
So I think we can use this class in here.
So what I will do, copy this.
Go back in here
and I'll create another web element.
And I'll say return
months is equal to forever
find element
like class name
basis in here.
Right.
So and then what I need to do,
I need to get the text right.
I want to try to find
elements.
Text. Okay.
All right.
Okay.
Do we have to locate the year as well?
Guys? And here.
What do you guys think?
No. Right.
Because we're looking at the first
February that is coming in our calendar.
We don't really care about the year.
Even even though
if you want to come back in January,
I mean, if February 2023,
you won't be able to go there right.
Because the I think
the calendars on the
slight website, they're only
for nine month or something like this.
Okay.
So you can't really book
any tickets in advance of three years.
Okay.
So we're just going to be looking
at the next available temporary in here.
Okay. So I got the text.
What do I need to do now, guys, look
at the table.
We need another while, right?
So we need to start
clicking on the next button
so that we can get the right month
and the right,
the right calendar on the right hand side.
Right.
So what I'm going to do,
I'll have a while in here, Right?
And the same way as we did
in our departure.
So month tax is not equal to
February, right?
What we will be doing
will be clicking on the next button
and at the very same time,
what we need to do,
we need to get the text
after each iteration.
We didn't talk about the date yet.
We know that we're coming in February.
Now, what we want to know,
We want to know what date
we're coming back.
Okay, so here we're on February.
What date?
We're coming back, guys.
31st. Good one.
Yes, 31st.
Okay.
All right. So let's come back.
I'm 20, right?
So let's come back on 28th.
So what I am going to do now, let's locate
this.
Let's see.
Let's see the table in here.
Okay, So we got the table.
So the same way as we did with the other
or what's called
with the other table in here.
So what I can do, I can simply go ahead
and change that class name in here,
and I will, I will copy this
and what I can do.
I'm going to store everything in the Web
element and list of web elements.
All right.
And and dates, elements.
I express
pasted in here.
Right.
So once we have everything stored
inside the list, what I am going to do,
I will simply iterate
through each and every date.
All right, element
turn, date
dates in here.
And then what I will have I'll have an if
condition and here
I need to get the text
and then I need to compare with
this date that will be coming back
and then
I will simply be collecting and
breaking my information.
All right.
Okay.
So let's run this
and see if we can get the expected result
and navigating.
Now, December 19th, February 28.
Right. Pretty cool. Right, guys?
So we'll leave it on December 19th
and coming back on February 28th.
Okay.
Any questions, guys?
Any questions on how to handle
calendars?
All clear. Good.
So now the last thing that I want to do in
here is just to click the dump
button, right?
So what I am going to do
is just locate this.
There is a class name in here or just done
button, so I'm going to copy this
and I'll have another web element
forever
Elements, Last name.
It's all right then.
Button that.
All right, All right.
Okay, guys, Any questions on here, guys?
Hopefully not,
because it's pretty easy logic, right?
Getting focusing on the departure first.
Then we will be focusing on return
for a second
and we will be clicking on done.
Okay.
All right.
No question.
So let's move forward. Right.
So there's one more thing
that I want to show you guys
right now is
how to work with the keys on the keyboard.
Okay. While writing this script.
Okay.
So working
with keys.
Okay,
so let me grab something out the X path
for the audience.
Okay.
Good for
copy this.
Is it in here?
Okay.
All right, guys.
We all know this website, right?
We all
we did a couple of examples on this.
So let's see.
Let me open this up.
And you. Okay, guys.
So this is the website. We know.
We know the log in and password, right?
So what we're going to be doing in here,
guys,
we will be entering the username
and password right.
Can I sent the link or go
and the previous code.
There you go.
All right.
I guess so.
Here.
Well, we navigate here manually, guys
and I type in the first name.
How am I going to get to the next
available
textbooks without going in here by mouse?
Guys, just have a tab, right?
So if you click if you hit tab right now,
I'm going to be moving
to the next available textbox, right?
And then when I enter my password as well
without clicking on law again button,
what can I do in here, guys?
Enter Key.
Right?
So if I click enter, I will be logging in.
Right? So.
So there is a way to do this same thing,
which by writing is selenium, correct?
Okay.
So what we are doing in here,
we're navigating here,
we have a username and password, right?
So we're sending keys in here.
So after I send keys, guys, what I will
do, I will need to hit tab, right?
So it's going to be pretty simple In order
for me to hit the tab
after I enter my username,
I'm going to put a comma in here
and what I will do, I will do keys.
That tab.
But as you can see in here,
right after I type in keys guys in here
you can see there's
a lot of different keys
that you can use users tab and add in here
there is arrow down
last, there's a backspace in here, right?
So there's control,
there's delete, there's
a lot of different keys
that you can use from keys
from keys class.
Right.
So in this case
what I am going to do in here just hit tab
and after I enter my password in here,
what I need to do, same thing in here.
Keys that enter right here.
I'm clicking tab,
moving on to the next available text box
and then hit then enter
when I enter my password.
Right.
So let's run this
in here
you go.
We're locked in right pretty quick.
Right.
So if we're doing this right,
if we do tab,
if we do keys enter,
why do we need that clicking there, guys?
Why do we have to click on the log
in button
all without this one?
So after you tab without this.
No, that's.
There's no logic behind that.
Right.
What are you going to be sending keys for
or you mean right after this one?
Right after this one.
If you're talking about this one, it's
not going to happen because what
you need to do,
you're sending keys in here
and you want to know what element
you're sending it for.
Okay.
The point of the tab is
this is just an extra.
I want it to show that this exists.
Okay? Yes.
So yes, correct.
So if you click on tab,
you're switching the tab.
I mean, you're
switching the text boxes, right?
But when you switch the text box, you need
to tell selenium where to send the keys.
Right.
Still, you're just switching the
what's called your cursor
to the next to the next available
text box.
Okay. You're not finding that element.
Okay.
Because for you visually, you understand
that.
Okay, my personal is on this
on the next textbox,
but your selenium will not understand
that.
Okay.
So this is these keys that tab keys
that enter and everything.
These will work
most of the time with the robot class.
Okay.
If you use tab,
you have to find the element. Yes.
In any time
you will need to find that element
because your selenium
will not know what element you're on onto.
Okay.
Yeah.
So no point is just extra that so
that you guys know that this things exist.
Okay.
So you can manipulate with the keyboard
keys as well in your
in your selenium script
so far there's no point of tab in here.
Okay.
But if I click on Enter Guys
what's the point of having actual click?
So I don't have I don't have to locate
the login button in here
and I'm just hitting enter
and I'm logging in.
Okay,
but what would be the difference, guys?
Is there anything that I'm going
to be missing at that point?
I want stored where
I want stored as a variable?
Okay.
So okay, guys,
let's put the question like this
What's the point of doing keys
that enter and doing
log in button dot click.
What would be the difference between this
exactly?
You're testing
if the functionality of the button works.
Absolutely right. Okay.
So when you click in
here, when you have a log in,
log in, button, double click in here,
you testing the functionality
of the button.
Okay.
And when you hit enter,
sometimes when you hit enter, enter,
it might log in, but when you click
on the log in button, it might not work.
And your job is to find out
what actual functionality
that button is performing.
Okay,
any questions on that?
All right. No questions.
Good.
Shouldn't you test both features?
Not really.
When you do an automation,
you don't have to do this, okay?
You don't have to do this kind of stuff.
When you're doing automation, it's always,
always
recommended to perform
to use the selenium methods
as click or send keys or whatever.
This yes, this is just a no.
This is an additional thing
that you should know, guys.
Okay, I don't think you will be
using this, but this is just in case.
Yep. Click makes sense for automation
purposes.
That is correct.
All right, guys, any other questions?
All right, guys.
So what we're going to do now,
it's 805.
Let's take a quick break.
Okay.
We're going to take a 15 minute break.
And then when we come back, guys,
I want everybody to be ready at 820
because will be downloading some draft
files.
And I want you to follow me in that. Okay.
So we will be downloading some draft files
in order to take some screenshots.
Okay, guys.
So take a break right now.
Come back at 820.
Cool.
Okay, guys, let's continue.
Yeah, I hope everyone is back
and let's get to downloading
some dark files.
All right?
Okay.
So first of all, guys,
please pay attention
to where I'm going to download it from
and how I'm going to import it.
I mean, I think you guys already should
know how to import some of our files.
Intelligent, right? Or to your project.
Okay, So
what I'm going to do in here, guys, I will
add the new tab of the chrome.
I will simply
type in maven repo.
Okay, enter.
So the first link that you have
is maven repository dot com.
Okay.
So I'm going to click on that.
So is everybody navigate it to maven
repository guys.
Does everyone on the same page?
Okay, good.
All right.
So now there is a search bar in here.
What I am going to do,
I'm going to search for comments
space.
I'll make it enter
and you're going to see
a couple of common libraries in here.
Okay.
But what we need in here,
we need the first one.
Apache Common IO.
Okay, so click on the first link here.
Okay?
You should be seeing
all the versions in here.
Are we all on the same page?
Base?
Okay, good.
So now what I will get,
I think rather than the latest stable one,
I am going to click on the 2.8.0.
Okay.
You went to the page search for Common IO.
And click on the Apache commas. IO.
It should be the same for Mac and Windows.
Yes. Okay.
Navigate to the link guys.
Okay.
Just complete the capture
in there.
Just click.
I'm not URL back and it should navigate it
to the right page.
Oh, because what you're doing is
you're you're,
you're accessing the chrome
which you open with your selenium.
Okay so that's why I probably.
Okay the version 2.80 in here.
Okay. 2.8.0.
Okay.
And you click on this,
we'll see this page.
Okay.
We're all on the same page in here, guys.
Okay, good.
So now if you look in here,
there's files, okay?
And there's jar in here.
Guys, I want you to click on this.
Okay?
When you click on this, it's going to
it's going to download this.
If it's asking if it's harmful
and all that stuff, just click on
Keep.
Okay. Did you download it? Guys?
I hope everyone download downloaded this.
Okay, good.
All right.
So once you download it,
it should be in your downloads folder.
Okay.
So make sure you know where your file is.
Keep click, keep. Okay.
If it's saying it's harmful,
click on keep.
What do you have?
Send us the screenshot.
Okay,
so your downloads seems like they are.
They are blocked.
Okay.
So what you can do guys, whoever
downloaded, can you please send that
jar file in the chat guys,
you should be able to.
There we go.
Okay guys, download this one. Okay.
So people sending to live chats.
So try to download this one.
Okay guys.
All right, good.
Okay,
so now, now what
I want you to do, guys.
Okay, is same problem.
What's the problem?
The downloading problem?
What does it say?
Let me see the screenshot.
Okay.
Meanwhile, guys, so whoever downloaded,
I want you to go back to the intelligent.
Okay, so we are in intelligent right now.
What I want you to do, I want you to click
to click on file.
Okay, Click on file
and click on Project Structure.
Okay.
You're going to see another window
popping up.
We're all on the same page, guys.
Okay.
Is there anyone behind right now?
Okay, good.
All right.
So what I want you to do,
there is a plus sign at the bottom.
Okay?
Make sure you are on the left
hand side, guys.
Make sure your under the modules.
Okay?
Click on the modules in here.
You will see a couple of
jar files in here.
Okay.
So what I want you to do
then I want you to click
on the
on the plus
sign in here, Okay?
So click on the plus sign
you will see it dropdown select jars
or directories.
Okay.
Jars.
And there is
another window will be popping up for you.
Okay, let's see.
Can you try a different browser?
Seems like you're downloading an edge.
Try chrome instead and
see if that's going to work
because seems like
edge is preventing you
to download something in here.
So you need to
you need to undo in settings
and delete that.
Yeah, that's a good one.
Okay guys, we're all at the same
on the same page right now.
So now what you want to do,
you want to navigate
to the, to the place
where your jar file is downloaded.
Mine is already saved
inside the documents.
So since you guys are just downloaded it,
it should be inside
your downloads folder.
Okay.
If you do that, click
when you navigate to download,
find this commons io jar file
and click on open
all on the same page.
That's yes.
You could just apply and then click okay.
All right.
Once you've done this guys,
you will see this common IO in here.
What you can do.
Simply go ahead and click on apply
and okay, so
yeah, you could check that.
That's fine.
Yeah.
All right. Okay, guys,
one more time. Right?
You go to file,
you go to project structure.
Okay?
You make sure you are under the modules
on the left hand side
and then what you want to do,
you want to click on the plus
sign at the bottom
and click on the jars or directories.
Okay.
When you click that you will see
another window popping up in here.
And what you need to do,
you need to select the folder
where your jar file is saved.
Okay,
so you click on this, you open it.
Okay, Mine is already
mine is already uploaded in here.
So you open it.
You see it in here.
What you want to do,
you need to apply and.
Click.
Okay.
Okay. Sent you did it.
Just click okay and apply.
That's fine.
All right. Any other
people who are behind guys
out to test it a little tested later.
Okay.
Just for now, just upload it.
Anyone behind guys
cannot select the jar file.
Okay. There you go.
Refresh your page and retry
and it will appear.
Okay, good.
Try that and see if that's going to work
or let me see.
Okay.
So when you did it, when you went to
Project Structure, did you click on Jars
or directories
or you clicked on different things?
There's two more other options.
Okay, You got it.
Good.
Okay.
So everyone is good, right?
Everyone in for it.
All good.
Okay, Nice.
Okay, so what I am going to do right now,
I'm going to create a new class in here
and I will name it as taking
screenshots.
Okay, So, yeah, we'll see
until it doesn't work later.
Exactly. Good point.
Okay, so now, guys.
So now before we dive into taking
screenshots,
let's finish up with calendars in here
and let's go, I didn't create a notes.
Okay, So let's create a file
in here.
Last notes to right
as. All right, guys.
So now let's put everything step
by step on how to handle the calendars.
This.
Okay, so we have a calendar.
What do we need to do first, guys?
We navigate, let's say
let's take an example
from the Delta, okay?
So we navigate it to Delta.
What did we do first,
we need to expand the calendar, right?
So in order to expand it,
what we need to do, we can simply click
on the calendar, right?
So click on calendar.
It's going to expand the calendar.
Okay.
All right.
So now what do we need to do next?
What are we looking for in here
on our next step?
So we expanded the calendar now.
So now we're looking for our month, right?
We need to choose the month.
Okay. So what we need to do,
locate the month.
And in our script, what we need to do.
We need to get the text
right.
So once we got
the text would have everything on hand.
What is the next step, guys,
we need to set a condition.
Right?
So our condition would be
if the desired text is not visible,
what we're going to be doing,
we will be clicking on next.
Right.
So if the text
is not
visible right, what we're going to do,
we will keep
clicking on next.
Right? Okay.
Once with found our months,
what do we need to do?
Let's put it here as soon as
we sound right.
Our desired months.
What do we need to do?
We need to grab all the cells
from the table.
Right?
Grab all cells
from the table.
Right.
And then once
we have all the cells inside, our list,
what do we need to do?
We need loop through the cells.
Right.
So the cells
right.
And then what we need to do in here.
So we start looping in here and then once
cell values
right, is matched with our condition,
we're just simply going
to click on a matched date right?
Once the cell value is
matched, matched
with our condition,
what we're going to do,
we will click on the matched state.
Okay, six steps
right on how to handle the calendar.
We click on the calendar,
locate the month and get the text right.
And then if the desired text
is not visible, what we're going to do,
we will keep clicking on the next button
and as soon as we got the desired month,
we need to grab all the cells,
stored them in a list of web
elements, loop
through each and every cell, and then
set a condition once that value
our condition,
then we can simply click on that date.
Right.
Any questions on this, guys?
Should be pretty straightforward, right?
Okay.
So now coming to the next topic.
So we downloaded the jar
to take the screenshots.
Jar file
will help us to save the screenshots
inside our project or inside our computer,
whatever it is inside our system.
Right.
Please put in the note which one?
What do you want me to put on the note?
The update.
Okay.
Get the text
and keep
updating text
area.
Okay guys.
So now we we got the jar file, right?
That's going to help us to
save screenshots in our system.
So now before we take any screenshots,
I have a question that
why do we need screenshot in testing does
testing for the record
for proof of bugs right
to show the failure
to have some documentation
and to verify the test result?
Okay. Very good.
So basically
screenshots are taking for proof, right?
To get some screenshots,
whether you have some errors,
whether your test has passed.
Right.
So in testing
it is very to take screenshots
in order to prove that our test case
covered the certain functionality.
Okay guys.
So let's put it in here.
In testing
it is very important, important to take
screenshots
in order to prove
that our test is
covered.
Certain
functionality.
Okay, so you take screenshots,
you show it to
you attach it to your ticket
or you have it inside your reports.
So once nothing is not working,
you show it to the developers.
You create defects
or you attach it to your ticket
saying that, Hey, this is past
and this is my screenshot in here.
This is the proof.
Okay, Diego,
you guys already met Diego Ready
to vote.
Okay.
Oh, manual testing. Okay.
I thought he was only doing API.
Okay, good.
All right.
Okay.
So screenshots are very important, right?
So in Selenium guys,
in order to take screenshots,
we will be using take screenshot
interface.
Okay.
So it's going to be a little bit
of a different syntax
that we will see in a usual scripting.
Okay.
But it's not a big deal guys,
so you don't have to really memorize that.
Okay. Because we will be
you be
having common methods,
you will be building
those functions in your common
methods class.
Okay? So you don't have to really this.
You just have to memorize the logic,
how everything works.
Okay, so in selenium, in
to take a
screenshot,
we will be using
takes
screenshot
interface.
Okay.
All right.
So now let's go
and start our implementation.
Okay.
So what I want to do in here guys,
let's actually go in here.
Let's get the whole thing.
Okay?
So what we're doing here,
we're navigating to the same website
as we've done in a previous, right?
So and then what we,
what we're going to be doing
after we're low again, What I want to do,
I want to go ahead and take this
screenshot.
Okay.
Oh, screen recordings.
Oh, okay. So that's a good question.
So screen recordings,
I seen it used in selenium,
but I've seen it using different tools.
Okay, so I've worked with Test complete
these are some
outdated tools.
They are used in government
projects. Okay.
So most of the time to,
to record your screen,
what your actions are,
you will mostly be doing that manual.
Okay.
But I haven't I haven't seen this
happening with selenium, Java
and this kind of framework.
Okay?
If you're recording your screen,
that means you're using
some completely different tool.
Okay.
All right.
So now, guys, so everyone is clear
what we're doing from line 12 to 19.
Right?
Any questions on this? We're not.
Okay, good.
Okay, So we're trying to log in
and take the screenshot.
Okay.
So first of all, what I need to do,
I to create an object of the
of the take screenshot interface.
Okay.
How do I, how do I create an object of the
an interface guys
in Java Java
with inheritance.
Okay.
What else need to make it indirectly.
Right.
Okay.
All right.
So what if guys have you heard of?
I'm pretty sure you guys heard about down
casting and up
casting in your Java classes.
Right? There we go.
Good. Okay,
so what I'm going to do in here,
since the screenshot is an interface,
right?
I'm going to
down cast it
so that we can match it to our web driver.
Okay.
Because we will be using this object
in order to take some screenshots.
Okay.
So what I'm going to do in here,
I'm going to start with take screenshot.
Okay.
As is equal to right, we don't have a new
or what's called new keyword in here.
So what I will do, I'll do a down cast
and here to the driver.
Okay Any questions in here? This
so you might get a little confused.
It's okay guys.
I'll try to explain it as
as simple as possible.
Okay.
So we're creating an object
of take screenshots interface
by down, casting it to the work driver.
So now what I'm going to do in here,
I am going
to use the object that I just created
and I will get the screenshot as okay,
so there is a method in here
inside that take screenshot,
so I'm going to use this method.
Okay guys.
So there's only one method
that you can use in here.
Okay, so now when I use this method, okay,
I need to specify
what am I getting in return?
Okay, so I need to specify my output type
in here.
Okay.
So inside the parentheses,
what I will do in here,
so you can see it's asking me
to put an output type.
So what I will do,
I'll start typing output type dot
and I am getting a file back.
Okay.
So what's happening in here?
I got this screenshot in a type of a file.
Okay guys, is that clear?
By using the object of this,
I am getting a screenshot
and I am getting a screenshot
of a type of file.
Okay.
So once I get it right,
so I'm getting a file
and I can assign it to a variable right?
So where is it going to be saved?
I'm coming to that point.
Okay. Step by step dice.
Okay, so what I'm to do,
I will store this
into inside the variable.
So since I'm getting a file in return,
I will be storing inside the file
variable.
Okay.
File I am.
I'll name it as source file.
Okay.
Is equal to
get screenshot.
Okay, so let's import this.
Okay. All right.
So now here.
What we did
we have is object of the take screenshot.
We get the screenshot in here
and we are getting a file in return.
Okay.
So let me put a note in here.
The screenshot is turn on this step.
Okay. All right.
So we took the screenshot.
So now what I need to do,
I need to save it somewhere, right?
So that I can go ahead and access it on.
Okay.
So what I need to do in here,
I will be using
a class which is called file utils.
Okay.
So the jar file
that, that we just downloaded, the common
IO is going to help us to copy
save it inside our system.
Okay.
So what I'm going to do I'll do file
utils.
Okay.
And let's actually do this.
You can see that it's coming from Apache
Commons. IO.
Okay,
so that means downloaded that jar file.
We uploaded it inside our project.
Everything working fine.
Okay.
File utils dot.
So when I put a dot in here,
we will have a lot of different methods.
So the one I need to use is
I need to copy the file.
Okay.
So for me to store this somewhere
since I already have, let's go here.
I already have a source file on hand.
I need to copy this and paste it
to the desired location.
Okay.
And how I'm going to do this?
I'm going to mention this.
Everything inside this parentheses.
Okay,
so what I am going to do, first of all,
what I need to mention is the
the file that I'm working with.
Okay?
And that file is stored on line 22.
Okay.
So I'm going to copy this variable,
paste it in here.
So I'm telling that I'm telling my
my Java that, okay,
I need to copy the file which file
this source file that I got on line 22.
Okay So I'm copying this.
Okay.
So now what
I need to do, I'm going to copy this
and I'm going to have
a completely new file
in the new location.
Okay?
So what I will do in here, I'll do new
file. Okay.
So inside the parentheses now
I need to put the destination of the file
that I will be pasting.
So what I am going to do in here?
Yes. Seems like
we uploaded it again.
Okay.
Like try to see
if you can re uploaded again
or you can go ahead and check
that project structure
and you should be able to see this common
IO in here.
All right, guys.
So now in here I need to specify the path
inside my system
where I want my
my screenshot to be available for us.
Okay, so if I don't specify
any folder outside of my project
like we like we've done with drivers,
what it's going to do,
it's going to get saved inside my project.
Okay, so what I will be doing in here,
I'll put it past me.
Okay, so I'll name it as screenshots.
Okay, So this is this Smart bear, right?
Smart Bear website.
And what I will do,
I will need to say admin log in.
And whenever you're trying to save a file,
you need to specify the extension
of the file.
In this case,
we're getting a PG file in here
so that we can view it later.
Okay.
Any questions on this, guys?
Do you want me to repeat one more time?
Yes. Okay.
All right.
So now, guys, let's start from line 21,
right?
Creating an object of screenshot Dom,
casting it to the driver.
Okay.
And then what we're doing on line 22,
we're getting the actual file on hand,
right?
With taking the screenshot.
It's not saved yet.
It's nothing. It's just a file.
Okay, so now on line 24,
what I need to do,
I need to copy this file
and I need to paste it to the location
that I want it to, that I wanted it
to be existent.
Right.
So what I did in here,
I'm telling this
method that, Hey, this is my file
and this is my path
where I want that file to be saved.
Okay, So inside my project, right,
this screenshots
and Smart Bear will be created.
Okay, so these are two new folders
that will be created automatically
after my execution
and this file will be created inside
these two folders.
Okay.
These two are random names.
These are random names. Yes,
that is correct.
Smart pair.
I chose pair
because this is a Smart Bear website.
Right.
So screenshots, we want to save all the
screenshots inside our screenshots folder.
Right.
And then at the very end
I just name it admin log in
because we're just logged in
as an admin over
why we have an error.
I'm coming to that point guys.
Okay.
All right.
Any other questions, guys, before we move
forward, where's the screenshot folder?
Well, we didn't run it yet, right?
So that's why it's not created yet.
So the screenshots folder,
we don't have it.
So if I run it, it's going to get created
automatically.
Okay. Yes.
These files will be created inside our
our current project
because we're not specifying
any different project.
Okay.
Or any different folder outside.
So if you start from C folder
and go on, go on,
it might get created in a different one.
But here I don't specify anything.
So we are creating everything
and saving everything
inside our project.
Okay.
All right.
So now we have an error in here
which is not going to compile.
So what I will do in here,
Did you guys cover exceptions
or any exception handling in Java?
Okay, good. Nice.
Okay, so I am going to do
how do you handle an exception in in
Java class guys
try and catch blocks.
Right.
So this is how
we will be handling this in here.
So what I will do, I'll try.
Okay.
I'll try to
copy this.
Okay.
And if that doesn't work, I'm
just going to catch the exception in here.
Right.
So I think it will throw us.
I'm no exception in here,
if I'm not mistaken. Yes.
So it throws an exception. What?
What does it send for guys?
What is it? Oh Exceptions stands for
input output exception.
All right, So since we're
getting this screenshot, okay,
we're getting the screenshot
we're inputting and then we're trying
to output inside our project,
right so it might throw us an exception.
So what I will do,
I'll do I'll exception in here.
Right.
And then what we will be doing
will just want to
print the secretaries.
Right.
Okay.
Any questions, guys, on this?
Okay, all clear.
So now let's go ahead and run
this.
Why did it open for?
Okay, guys, so open on other screen.
That's fine.
So we just logged in in here.
Okay, so now let's take a look at our
what's called
at our project directory in here.
So what changed in our project
guys,
we have a screenshots folder.
All right.
So if I expand this,
you can see there's a smart pair in here.
The folder that we added. Right?
And there is an admin log in PNG.
So if I open this, you can see that
you have a screenshot
over here already from that admin log in.
Pretty cool right?
So you don't have to go ahead and manually
take a screenshot while you're running
everything you can just get the screenshot
at the very end of your step.
Okay.
So you just need to.
This is as I said, guys, it's a little bit
going to be a little bit confusing,
but it's okay.
So that I think you have steps in here
in your role.
Remove that s letter and it should
work.
Yes, that jar file was for screenshots.
I mean, it was for having
copying and pasting,
but these taking screenshots,
this take screenshot
is coming from selenium.
Okay.
This is coming from
selenium style is coming from Java.
Okay.
File utils is coming from comments that IO
or do you have the same issue in your
in your your URL you need to make it htp.
Okay, you have it https.
That's why it's not working.
Okay guys, any questions on how to take
screenshots, what else we use there?
There are some plugins that we're going
to be using later guys, for Excel
because you will be getting the data
from Excel
and inputting inside your web pages.
Okay,
So you will be having these input output
jar files later on during the course.
If it didn't create this
anything, just go ahead and refresh this.
Okay. So go to file,
reload all from disk.
Okay.
And that should pop up for you.
All right, guys, anyone having issues with
getting the screenshot
or is anything
not clear
or. Yes, try
to try to store everything in PNG, guys.
Okay.
Because sometimes when you
when you start JPG
and some people use Mac, it might get
a little bit of a problem on opening.
Okay, so pkg would work for both.
When we load it doesn't work.
Let let's check your let's
check your intelligence.
Okay. Send us a screenshot.
Let us see what's going on.
What is the error.
I want to see the whole error and s
I think you have a space
in between in here.
So try to reduce
try to remove that space in here
and see if that works.
All that works. Okay, let's see
the okay.
The path. Oh,
okay, guys, please take it.
Take a look at the at the error guys.
It says driver
executable is not soundguys.
Take a look at just system
properties.
It's failing on line 16 guys.
So that means
on line 14
you have an S, you have this web driver,
the D is capital for you.
That is that is not correct.
Okay.
So what will happen
if you don't create a new file?
You won't get a screenshot, right?
You won't have the populated
inside your project.
So if you want to do
so, there is
so most of the time, guys,
you don't have to take a screenshot
of each page that you going to write.
What you are concerned about is
when your
test fails, you need to take a screenshot
or when you test is passed
you need to take a screenshot.
Okay.
It doesn't override the existing file. Oh.
So if you want to run it in the
in a different class,
in a different example,
you need to change the name
of course. Okay.
So if you don't change the name, it's
going to get over it.
Oh, that's going to be so.
You mean in here we will have a file
that we have in storage?
That is correct.
But that's going to be in Java storage.
Okay.
It's not physically.
We won't be able to see that.
Okay.
But in here, what we need to do,
we need to get it inside our project,
and then we will be able to see.
All right, I guess.
Any other questions?
Seems like not
quantum mistake.
Good.
So if we copied on a folder.
So the
the type of the data,
you need to specify it here.
Okay.
So you need to give it a name
and specify the extension
in here. Yep.
You can use the same thing.
Exactly.
So in order to get it inside
the inside the desktop,
you need to go through each what's called
through the C users desktop
and then the and then mentioned this.
Okay.
But even
even if you put it in the desktop, Right.
So what would be the reason you need it
in inside your project
in order to access it real.
Quick.
Right.
All right.
I guess any other questions? In
fact, no other questions.
Taking screenshots
for deleting. Yes.
You can do it manually, correct?
I'm not I'm
not actually sure if
if we can delete them through selenium.
I've never done that myself.
We will be when we start when we start
going through the frameworks guys,
you will have,
you will have taking screenshots
automatically.
You will set it up the way that you start
your test whenever it ends, it will
get the screenshots with the new name
and everything will be dynamic.
Okay guys, so you don't have to worry
about the this names
and that it's getting overwritten
right now that it's hardcoded.
Yes, it is hardcoded for now,
but when you start with your framework,
you will have everything dynamic.
Can you also select the area? No,
you won't be able to do that
so that you still
if you still have a problem,
please ping this syntax support.
Okay.
It's failing on your
on your line
nine team
so that's not finding your elements.
Okay.
So please take a look at that.
Oh, it worked.
Okay, good.
How to do it with pagination?
Okay guys, as I said, right
So you taking the screenshot
at the very end of your test?
Right.
So as I said before, guys, this is just
the hard coded version
of taking this screenshot.
Okay, so since you say
you want to take a screenshot
for each pagination,
write for each pagination
when you move to the next page.
Right.
So what can happen in there?
You can use different tools. That's one.
Or as I mentioned guys, you only need
the screenshots
to be taken at the very end of your tests.
Right?
You don't need each step
to be taking the screenshot for.
Right.
So if you move one step
you don't need to screenshot, right?
So what you need is
when you finish your test,
you need to know if it's or fail.
Okay.
So just one screenshot is enough for you.
You don't need to go through each
and every step of the screenshot.
If you have 25 steps in your
in your test case,
you don't want to get 25 screenshots
right.
What you want to do,
you want to e 30 a test case pass or fail.
Okay.
All right, guys, any other questions?
All right, cool.
Okay, so now let's move
to the new topic in here.
How do you not overwrite the image?
Just change the name in here, okay?
Change name in here
and it won't overwrite.
Okay, so let me go to the notes now.
Okay, guys.
So now what we going to be doing?
We will be.
We will be going over that action class.
Okay, So Anyone did research on actions
class guys?
Does anybody know what actions class is?
What we can do with actions, Class?
Not really this time. Okay.
All to interact.
Exactly right.
So actions is given by selenium
to capture the keyboard and mouse events.
Okay,
so what kind of mouse events do we have?
Guys?
Okay, left click
to scroll.
Right. Okay, right clicking.
Okay, so you can,
you can move to an element, right?
That means you're hovering your mouse
over some elements.
Right? There we go.
We have a right click.
We also have double click right.
And what we have is we can drag
and drop some elements, right?
Okay.
So these actions are captured
inside the actions class.
Okay, so let's put it in here.
Actions class, right
is given by Selenium.
Selenium to
capture
keyboard and mouse events
such as
floating here, move the element
right within drag and drop
and then we can do double
click in here within
right click as well.
Okay.
So these kind of, this kind of actions
will be using actions first. Okay.
So let's expand this and let me open up.
Let me create a
new class and name is Actions
Class statement.
Okay,
so this and here
and what
I want to do, it's fine.
So let's actually set this one So
or it's okay.
So I know.
All right.
So I'm just going to change the URL here
for Amazon.
Okay.
So now let's go ahead and explore
a little bit inside the Amazon,
see what kind of
elements we got.
Right.
Okay.
So in Amazon,
we've got a lot of different elements.
We got a lot of links, dropdowns, buttons
in here.
We have images, right?
So what we are going to do in here,
so is you look at this element in here,
right.
Hello. Signed account and lists. Right.
So I'm not going to click on it.
I'm not going to do anything.
I'm just going to move my cursor on this.
And you can see that the new element
is popping up for us in here with a new
with a new button in here to interact
with.
Okay, So I didn't click on this.
I'm just hovering over my mouse
and what I see in here,
I see new links,
I see a new button and I see new options.
Okay, So what we're going to be doing
in here, we will navigating to Amazon
and we are only going
to move over our mouse in here
in order to see all the options
on our web page.
Any questions before we start, guys?
Okay, good. So now
let's go in here.
So I navigate it to Amazon.
What I need to do in here,
I need to know that element,
the element that I am going
to interact, right?
So in order for me to know the element,
what do I need to do? Guys
locate the element.
Right?
Are we moving too fast?
Guys?
Okay. All right.
So what I will do in here,
I will click on Inspect.
Right.
So what we trying to do,
we're trying to inspect that element.
Okay.
So this is the element
that we will be interacting with.
And again, guys, what I'm doing,
not clicking on this element,
I am only navigating my cursor
on top of that element
and I see new elements popping up in here.
Okay, So what I need to do,
I need to click on this magic arrow
and locate this element, right?
So let's see.
Come on.
Okay. Again, you're
okay.
So this is our element, right?
And here
we have a lot of different
attributes in here.
Which attribute do we want to use in here?
Guys?
Idea. Right?
Simple in here. We have an idea in here.
So what I am going to do, I'm
going to copy this.
Okay?
Go back to our script in here.
So what I will do,
create a web element, right?
Saying that
counts and less
is equal to driver.
That client element
by ID and
paste this in here.
Okay.
So now, guys, so I have this element
so we know that I don't want to click,
I don't want to perform
any actions in here.
What I want to do, I just want to
hover over my cursor
on top of this element, not click
right and see this pop up in here,
the new options and this button.
Okay, So for that,
we will be using an action class.
Okay, So in order us to use an actions
class, first of all, what we need to do,
we need to create an object of an action
class.
Okay,
so what I will do in here simply actions,
right?
Action is equal to new
actions.
Okay, so creating an object,
let's import the class.
Okay, so now we created an object.
Okay, But then
it's requiring us to put here
our execution.
Okay? Our execution object.
In this case, guys, what is the execution
object that we have in here?
It is our driver, Right?
So this is what we form our actions with.
We click with send keys.
This is our execution object.
Right? So I'm going to copy this. Driver.
What I'm going to do,
I will paste it in here.
Okay,
So now what we have on hand right now,
we have an element
that we want to interact with
and we have an actions class
object, right?
So what I will do in here,
I will use the actions class object
that I created
now, and I will perform some more actions.
Okay, So action.
So if I hit DOT in here,
you can see that there's a lot
of different methods in here.
We have before with double click right,
we have the regular click,
we have contacts, click,
we have move to element,
we have click and hold guys.
Okay, so we have drag and drop in here
as well.
Okay, so what I am going to do,
I am going to choose moves to element.
Okay So if I choose move
to element, it's going to ask me
to, to pass in here
the element that I want to interact.
Okay, so in this case, the element
I want to interact
with have stored already on line 19.
So I'm going to copy this
now, paste it in here.
Okay.
Handing over the responsibility. Exactly.
So basically I'm telling my actions, Hey,
now you perform
some actions instead of my driver.
Okay,
so now I'm using move to element, right?
And I need to specify the element
that I need to interact with.
Okay.
Once I do this, now what I want to do,
I want to perform this action.
And in order to do this, what I will do,
I will simply
go ahead and perform.
Okay.
Any questions, guys, on this is
pretty straightforward and easy, right?
So basically,
you looking for your element, you create
an object of your actions, actions, class,
and then you perform your actions.
Okay, So let me run this
and see what
we're going to have on our Web
page. Why?
Just come in here.
All right.
So you can see, guys,
we navigated to Amazon in here, okay?
And you can see that we had that
new option popping
up in here with this
with the sign in button.
And this pop up was showing right now that
we manage.
No, you won't be able to manage
the speed of the move. No.
All right, guys, any questions?
Any questions on how to move your cursor
to a specific element?
19 to 21.
So on line 19,
what we are doing here, right.
So we're locating the element
that we need to to interact with.
Okay.
And then what we need to do,
we need to create an actions class object.
Once we do that by using the object
we just created,
we are moving to an element and
we need to specify
which element we will be moving to.
Right.
So in this case, we have it
sort of on line 19
and in order to make this happen,
we need to perform that action.
Okay.
Okay, cool.
Any other questions, guys?
Okay, good.
All right.
So now let's go back to our problem.
Let's go to this website.
Okay.
So in here, guys,
what we will be doing,
we will be dragging this guy
and dropping it over here.
Okay So it will be navigating
to this website.
What we're going to do.
We will be getting dragging this element
and dropping on the other one.
Okay. So
essentially this
quick.
Okay. All right.
So now let's get back in here
and create a new class.
Okay.
So this name is Drag
and then
copy is
and it's
just the usual.
Okay, guys.
So we're navigating to that
to this website, right?
So let's
go ahead, take a look at.
Yeah. Okay.
So first of all,
what I need to do is I need to have
the elements on hand,
right In the previous example,
what we've done
is when we navigated
to the Amazon,
what we need to do is we need to store
that element that we want to interact
inside the variable.
Right? Same thing in here.
What I will do,
I will inspect this page and
I will need to locate
the elements
that I need to be interacting with.
Right.
So which element
I need to interact with guys in?
Drag me to my target.
Okay, so one of them is this one.
Do I need the second element in Here goes
Yes. Right.
Because I need my target element as well.
Right.
Okay. So let's go one by one. Right.
So I have this in here, so let's copy
this ID, right.
It has an ID, so that's good.
Let's go back in here.
Where? Element
right next to
drag ball is equal to the driver dot fun
element by I.D.
and paste this in here.
All right.
And then let's take a look
at the second element that we have.
It has idea as well.
So I'm going to copy this back
above element.
Drop a ball right.
So the driver
element, my idea again
and I have it this way.
Okay, so we've got two different
elements, right?
So we want to interact
with these two elements.
So now what is my next step, guys?
There we go.
So we need to create
an object of the Actions class demo.
Then I'm coming to that point.
Okay, so let's go step by step one by one.
All right.
So actions, action, right, is equal to new
actions in here.
And what I need to specify
here, my driver.
Okay.
So I have my elements, I have my actions.
Class object.
So now what I need to do,
I need go ahead and start
performing my action.
Right.
So by using the object
that we just created,
what we can do in here,
there should be a method drag and drop.
Okay, So if you look in this method,
it's expecting us to pass
two different web elements in here.
So one of them is going to be
the drag couple, right?
And the other one
is going to be the target, Right.
The target element
that we need to drop it into.
Okay.
So I'm going to
use this. Okay.
So the first element that we
have is our drivable, right
pasted in here.
The second one is the drop bubble,
which is our target, right?
So in order to make this action
actually happen
what we need to do, we need to be form.
Okay, so let's go back in the
to the website in here so
we can see that in here.
Guys, there is an iframe, right.
Which is covering our focus
to actually go ahead and
manipulate with the two elements
that we need to write.
So how do we handle this situation, guys?
What do we want to do, switch to?
Right?
How do we switch to the framework, guys?
How how many ways of switching to frame?
Do we know?
Okay, index right
name or idea, name or idea?
And then the last one is by web element.
Okay. So let's take a look.
How many frames
do we actually have in here?
All right. Let's see.
I afraid
we only have one frame in here, guys.
So can we use can we use indexing in here?
Guys? No.
Why not?
We only have one eye frame on this
page, right?
It's not going to get confused. Right?
So we can simply use this.
We can switch our focus by the index.
Right So what I am going to do
going to do driver,
but switch to the frame.
And what is the index cards in here?
Is it one
hour index?
Oh, okay. Okay. Okay.
So we have a mix in here.
Okay.
Is it zero or one guys?
It needs to be zero.
Right.
Okay.
So this is our.
All right.
So now let's
go ahead and run this script and see
what happens.
I hope it's
not going to open up on the other system.
What happened, guys?
Here you can see that
we simply got this element
and dropped it at the other
onto the other elements.
Right.
Okay.
All right.
So this is one of the ways of dragging
and dropping the elements.
Okay.
So I want show you
I want to show you another way in here.
So let me common this out. Okay?
So guys,
hold and move.
Yes, almost that.
Okay, so let's see guys in here.
So manually, guys, what?
What am I doing? First steps.
So if I navigate to this page,
I start interacting
with these two elements, right?
So first of all, what I am doing in here?
Manually
clicking first and doing what guys
clicking and holding it right?
So what I want to do in here,
action dot click and hold,
okay, so click and hold.
And what I need to do,
I need to specify the element
which I will be clicking and holding onto.
Okay,
so now once I clicked and hold onto it,
what do I need to do guys?
I now need to move it right?
So I need to move it to an element right.
So here
I'll do move to Element
and then we already know what element
I will be moving to.
It is the drop label element, right?
So once I moved my
my dragonball onto the drop,
what happens next?
What do I do next.
Okay so I clicked on
hold move to an element.
So now what I need to do,
I need to release my mouse.
Right. There we go.
So what I will need to
do, I need to release my mouse.
Okay.
And then so this action to happen
is what I will need to do.
I need to perform. Okay.
But before I run this code,
there is one thing that I need to
mention in here. Okay, guys.
So when you are using actions class
and you have more than one action
back to back.
What you need to do after the last action
and before you perform
what you need to do.
You need to build everything.
Okay, So basically what this method does,
it builds
all the actions that you have into one
and then it's going to perform.
Is that clear, guys?
I think it's going to work
without the build as well,
but this is the recommended way to do it.
Okay, exactly.
So if you have a method chaining,
absolutely right.
Use build after the last action
and then perform.
Okay, so
let me run this now.
There we go.
So it tracked and dropped
onto that drop able element
right.
So let's close this.
All right, guys,
any questions on actions class
or taking screenshots or, handling
the calendar, scars?
Okay.
So today seems like it's more interactive,
right, guys?
It more
no more concatenating with x-pac
no more while with for right.
There we go.
I can show the notes. Yes.
Okay, so let's go over the homework
actions and action.
You mean this action?
If you're talking about this actions
and this action, then actions is a class.
This is an object, right?
All right, let's get
that homework
for you.
I'm not really sure
which actions and action you're
referring to.
Then you elaborate on the question
so that I can answer that correctly.
Okay.
So homework, guys.
Let's to this.
Oh, I'm not sure about action.
Okay.
I'm not sure about action,
but we won't be using action.
Okay.
So we will only be using actions.
Action is probably an interface. Yes.
All right, guys. So here,
I want you
to navigate to this American Airlines
and interact with the calendar.
Okay?
Select the departure, Select
the return date,
select the destination as well.
Click on Search
and quit the browser. Okay.
So if you click on this guy in here,
you will see
the exact almost exact same right
calendar
that we worked on on Delta Airlines.
So select the departure
and the return date.
And here, select the destination guys.
So from here
we can select the destination.
And from here you can select
where you go into and click on search,
right?
And then quit the browser.
Okay. Is that clear, guys?
Any questions?
This is how.
This is how it's built, guys.
Okay, So you can do this
and you can actually do this in here.
Oh, that doesn't work
with that.
It's weird.
I thought it was a return and
departure.
That seems like not so.
This is how it's built, guys.
Okay, so whenever you want to depart,
you have two months in here.
Whenever you want to return,
you have two different months here.
Okay?
After you go.
All right. Guess is the homework clear?
Any questions?
Yes, I'll push the code. Okay.
I guess I'll push the code
right after the class
based on difficulty.
Okay. Today's and
yesterday's class.
Okay, guys.
So yesterday
it wasn't that difficult.
Okay?
Today was more interactive class.
Okay, But we use the same logic
as yesterday and today,
because in the calendar handling,
we use the same logic today as well.
But the only difference we had is this
why loop and clicking on the next button
and having the for loop at the same time?
So that was the breaking point
for everyone.
Okay,
so I think everyone got confused in here.
Why? Why?
We need the while loop, how we're dealing
with for loop and all that stuff.
Okay.
But in terms of in of difficulty,
I don't think it's
too difficult to understand.
Okay.
You might not catch it at first, but then
if you look at it, you will be able to
understand what
is going on.
My brain.
Believe me, guys, I have had
more than you do right now.
Okay?
When I when I was when I was studying
syntax. Yes.
Let me focus the
one more.
Of course. Announcements.
Any other questions, guys,
before we wrap up
the class?
You guys,
you guys are asking really good questions
until you guys are confused.
Okay, so when you're confused,
you guys don't want to talk at all,
so that's not good.
Okay,
so if you're confused,
you got to let me know.
Okay, guys.
All right, guys.
Till more classes last for us.
Okay, so more classes last.
So please, please practice.
Please complete the homework
and I'll see you next week.
Okay?
We're going to be doing
some more fun stuff next week.
Okay?
Okay.
You have more fun tools to learn.
Okay, guys.
All right.
All right, guys.
Take care.
Everyone, please practice,
and I'll see you next week.
Okay? Thanks, everybody.
Goodnight.