All right,
guys, let me.
Yes, ma'am.
Got to get
last number.
Students, seven
points.
Start with
the get.
Okay, guys, I'm not talking about trivial.
I'm talking about class number six.
What are the things we learn in the class
number six?
Tell me
which object model design paper on file.
So now we'll start from page.
Object model Design
images.
What is beige object model Design.
Let me call it design.
What is the reason we call it design?
High school.
Okay.
Well, it is a pattern to organize a code.
Right. And expect.
So basically, basically,
according to this, on
whatever
the screens we have in our application,
according to those screens,
we create separate classes.
Right.
We create separate classes
according to this concept,
according to this pattern in our framework
and in these respective classes,
we put all the Lupita's all the functions
which belong to this particular screen
in the application.
What example,
if we talk about loading screen, right?
So in login,
we have a login page in our application
for that, we created one particular page
which is log in Beach.
Now all the
locators are related
to this particular login page.
Your username be your password,
be your logging button.
Your error message may be forgot password
link if exist.
Maybe a logo.
Maybe something else.
If all this locators
you want to protect one please.
Then very
you will put all of these things.
You will put these locators in Laguna
Beach plus
in Laguna Beach class.
What is the reason behind this?
Because if I'm using this particular
username and password see log,
it is kind of mandatory operation.
Without log in,
we cannot perform any of the operation.
So if I had 1000 guests
in 1000 because this I have to call this
driver or client element,
I need to use a name.
And equanimity was name
because it is a we.
Now let's consider tomorrow.
The leopard is always instead late.
So if developers change in this username
and password for you
something for example, the locator
which we are using it change the locator.
The locator.
You have to change this locator 1000.
This is now because you're calling
this particular one it 1000.
This is where 96, by the way, that I.D.
raid.
So your maintenance name will increase
because of small change
in the application.
So your framework is prone to change
and your maintenance time is going high.
Right.
So to avoid this problem,
to get rid of this issue.
What we have to do, we have to change this
only in design method.
So according to page object modern design,
by then we can keep this new data
in one place and everywhere, wherever
I want to use this particular locator
instead of using this idea.
But what I can use,
I can simply use one particular key right?
So now my key is being called everywhere
and my locator is placed in one place.
Maybe someone might look at a desert,
one place only.
This time
instead of changing it 1000 places.
I have to change it.
One place, right?
And then one change
will fix to my entire script.
So it will going to save my name.
It will make my framework more robust.
And the tool
industrial everyone.
So now page object model design better
allows us to
create
pages
according to the screen.
Plus this new
is according
to the
ages.
The application
replace
all those
functions
of this particular
class into this particular page
and it's printed class
A. Now,
let me give you one just one example.
Right in that one
example would be more than enough scene
I am providing here.
This time you'll see
if I open this page.
Right.
Let's add this one employee search.
You'll see in the background
I'm providing user clicks on log input
rate, user interface valid
a domain of user name and password.
Correct
categories.
So here you see
user name begins to employee list.
Now, precondition
I already provide precondition.
I already provide in my
command, in my
background.
Really?
Exactly.
Preconditions.
We have already provided in books.
So my precondition it means open browser
method is being closed from my books.
Right.
Then again, I see a lot of information
is available right in this background.
Now see how I can replace
how I can replace
these three steps right into one.
What I can do.
I will simply go in my login feature
and you see this is my log.
Integrate
students.
Now, in this login page,
I'm going to write here one thing.
Public void
log Sinek
and I'm writing here.
See username.
Please don't send cookies.
So their data is coming from my history.
It could be any string they
and then
password on send
keys.
Then come password.
So here.
Now see this username
and password
arguments.
I'm calling in my log in function.
Correct? Correct.
Now, now what I'm going to do is here.
See here.
If I go instead of writing
these three lines, read these three lines.
We will put this new little successfully
logged in.
Read a solution. Also, they're not ready.
So what I'm doing is this time
I'm going to write here, right?
I'm going to write here.
Very simple function this time, see?
And what function I'm going to write.
I'm going to write here.
End user is logged in
with valid, valid
email credentials
and credentials.
So now see, this time
what's going to happen?
I'm going to commit these three lines
Instead of these three lines,
my one step will work and
it will start with the end.
Yes, you can start
even with stocks as well.
Trade.
Let me start with when nothing
legally nothing
you can start with.
Then you can start with
and also write both because in given
you don't know
how many actions are performing,
it's a precondition
you've already provided.
And I told you,
even if you provide only start
as street sign, that is also fine.
That is also fine.
Correct.
So now then we can replace this
three steps with just one.
Now, this time
because of using one particular function.
So every time I don't need to call,
see here now, every time I don't need
to call this log in page, start
logging button, don't click everywhere.
Right.
Or this two steps everywhere instead.
Now I can simply create one step
and then one step I'm going
to call one function from my actual page
and that function will work.
So how?
Let me show you this time when I go here,
Let's see in my employee feature,
I think employee search feature, right?
Employee search feature.
I'm going to write this for best.
Let's say, and let's create this template.
So I am writing here Test
now. We'll see what I'm going to do.
First, I'm going to create a step for this
particular one, right
and is equal to true.
I'm like, forgot that.
Yes, I forgot that.
Let me do it.
Yes, Yes.
Anyway, it will give me
it will give me the step.
Yeah.
It gave me this to see that you.
So let me copy.
This is Tidbinbilla is full login
credentials in which
each of the steps
I have to put this function
log in the steps
in which page I have to put this
in login page played in log in steps.
Fine.
So let me put this function here.
See how this things work now
instead of calling username,
password and login button.
This time I'm going to call for this page.
Log in page dot.
Can you see it is giving me the function
logging function based
logging function.
Now tell me this data
we can call from here
username and password.
We can call from various
where we have username
and password in my configurator.
Remember
I'm on
guys configurator
dot property value username
I can provide right case
basis description.
Not any.
Is it correct?
Is this correct?
But one more thing.
Yet after the username and password
I have to call log in Bertelsmann
database
logging button.
Don't click.
So now my this logging
function is having entering
the username field
password functionality and log in within
doc click functionality.
Correct?
Correct.
Makes sense.
And this function
I'm coming here in my log in.
So now if you see my
if you look at my agents
in any of here now
see it's converted to just a one line.
Just one line instead
of three names.
So now let me show you
how these two scenarios work.
I'm going to change the tag for these two.
And this time I'm going to run it.
Let's see
this run smoke
working
fine, taking the data.
Right?
Whatever the field I want to take the data
from.
Right.
You're just picking exactly from there.
And this now this time function, I'm
calling from my perspective page
object model designed.
Right.
So similarly for all the other class, this
we can write the functions
in the respective pages, right?
If you want.
Right now
we don't need that much a function,
so we're not going to call all of those
functions into the respective pages.
But you'll see here
I just made one function along
with the locators in one particular class
according to Beach Object model design.
By then in when I actually implemented
and called it in my particular step.
Right, it's working extremely fine.
So the intention
was to remove overall steps
and then after execution,
if I look at this part,
if I look at this bar, PFC,
instead of providing three steps grade,
I provided just one step where it is
working fine.
Mention the basic
and you see that to get accomplished.
Whatever we were looking forward to,
we got that.
Similarly, we can change whatever
we want to change in wherever we see, or
we can call this particular
one in a big jump.
We can go and find no issues
so far.
Any questions in this part?
Students
No question.
Clear.
Yes, sir. Why not?
So what I did, what you what I did
this particular code
instead of calling this username
and password, we don't.
Same is everywhere.
Everywhere in other classes.
Also like creating the object
of this class log in page
dot username logging
based out of my spawn.
Logging
based on the log in content. Right.
And then performing operations.
I'm calling
what particular function. Right.
So that function I created in my page
itself, again, I'm depleting my words.
I am creating my page
and contributing a function
in the page itself, in the ad
and also in background.
They are seen in both scenarios.
Yes. Got it.
Got it.
I can go to the next what we did.
So one step we didn't
because we added in background example
simple would.
Yes. Yes. Correct.
So next time I don't need to call logging
dot username door
and then call that little bit of the key
from the configurator.
Instead, just call this logging function
every then you don't need to write
even multiple steps in feature file
when you use any
when logging in password
and click on logging button.
Not just one
particular step in feature file
will handle all user is logged
in with admin credentials.
Correct.
So just single line single line function.
We will call in that function
with postpandemic work.
If we get the username and password
from configurator
member configured proper.
These is the file in which we mention
it automatically from logging,
which is going to be correct,
in which we mention user name and password
rate.
MySQL in configurator is the class
in which we are actually
reading the properties we have mentioned
in confidence properties by.
Okay, so config reader is nothing
but a function but a function right?
That is reading the code,
reading the properties from configure
properties like okay
this is my is Dempsey.
So now in business
that what I'm doing instead of calling
like this log in username and password
and simply calling log in page
the object of my plus function
and in this function
because I need to pass username
and password, I'm simply passing username
from my config properties contributor
and password also from confidence
rate is equal name record
students.
This part you know even how we are getting
this username and password.
This part you know when you well right.
This is the object of your login page.
Correct and this is the function.
So everything is treated
and explained individually.
The first one is the object of the class.
Let's take in log.
It is the function that we have defined
in that particular log beach class.
And then that look, the arguments
which we are passing, the parameters
which we are passing in,
passing it from our configurator
class, Any questions
so far in this particular part?
Any question
nutrition
methods could be good or not.
And when you push
open, shall we cross it further?
No. Students
where it shows error like this.
Very serious. So one,
let me show you my code.
We just executed
this code red C noida. Don.
It's working fine.
The government says please ask
why do we have a printed in the light
above
here?
This one
then this one.
This particular one.
Because.
Because we were passing it
right for the verification.
So what kind of user we are passing,
whether we passing admin user
or we are passing something else.
Right.
So that's why when you created
this particular one, C is doing admin,
we are handling
MAID,
so we must, we must have passed this.
Let me open my log in feature.
See here.
That's one because I wanted to check
remember
welcome admin text we got when we enter
when we logged in as an admin user.
So when we logged in
as an admin use of the message,
we got this welcome data, we got it.
So we need to capture
that particular part.
I told you in the class three, I believe
Class four I believe it was class
three of Class four.
Then I told you that this particular
username
and password
example staple is not limited to one.
Is that right?
We can use this case in multiple steps.
So intentionally I provided keys both
using one step and third in another one,
and then we can verify it either
with the existence of this particular
look at what I did or you can get captured
that based on this welcome any grade.
So you can see which is this.
I told you,
you can handle it and you can use it.
Right.
So the intention was to show you
in the case that we provided examples
table is not limited to just one step
because before that
we were doing all of those things
in one step right here.
Also, be positive in one step. So where
you know, some people are
passing the data in one step here,
so you're passing the data in one step.
So that's why I should to give you
the difference
in between data table and example.
Stupid.
Anyways, what is the difference
between detectible and examples?
Table students?
Jimmy, come on,
what is the difference in someone?
Data table walks only it one step made.
But when we talk about examples table,
we can use it for the whole scenario.
That's what we are doing here.
They do not see we are passing the data
in multiple systems we are passing.
This gives in multiple steps.
So what holds the nebulas?
It will work.
Now you got 1.3.
Still, if you have any question,
please feel free to ask.
I would be more than happy to answer. So.
All right,
guys, now
now let's talk about ones that you come
ready to learn something new again.
Students
Great.
If you guys are attentive in the class
today, I will leave your class to a great.
If I followed you, then I take it then.
Yeah, I'm doing it anyway.
Next to start.
See? Don't leave us
nice and easy.
Not too good.
Seriously.
Okay.
Three, maybe three.
Five is very early.
It's too early to hit.
Final
race winner in drink username
or let's say I'm
a great password.
Great.
Right?
I was talking about 3 minutes
and Nicola was asking for 5 minutes.
Okay.
Or or let's say one more thing.
See, let me give you one more example.
He had been enforcing this username
or password or I'm passing
data, so let's see.
I want to bust employ Addy.
I want to bust in 8786 right.
This is the employee I.D.
I want to pass now.
Tell me if I'm busting seven, eight, six
as an input employee.
Right.
And I provide a solution
using normally daughter
gives method and providing 7x6
in this particular field.
Okay.
Yet I'm providing plus name using same
gives middle name using psyche's last name
using changes and employ it using same 776
Now when it comes to a solution,
I provide a solution a set dot
assert equals two values I should expect.
One is expected, one is action.
So one is coming from my feature
frame through
which I am providing the data here.
All right.
So again, what I'm going to capture
this particular employee
after paying the employer getting and then
these two expected in actual values.
I'm going to compare using the solutions.
That's what we generally do.
Correct?
Correct.
Now, now if I use the same gives
method here
and I provide seven, eight, six.
Right.
You'll see already one employee
an existing here.
Can you see
and if I provided 76 what would happen
the employee and becomes 245411076.
So in this case my assertion is
going to be parsed or three
being made to feel
similarly when you work in real time
technicians, when you work in building
projects, right, So you are more likely
to get the fix where you want to think.
You're supposed to bring back some data,
but before entering your data,
there might be some data
already available.
There may be some data already
available, right?
So dark clear is the method
in selenium
have that we generally use before
sending some data
so that we can clear the field.
So that we can clear the rate. No.
Now let's think let's think about
like an automation engineer.
We don't want to work multiple times
the bleed in implementation
in one day, in execution multiple times.
But let's see about the current scenario
that we have right now in the application.
So when I go in my framework next
on any page, let's take a log instance,
the really basic one.
I'm providing this
same operation here, but it
any place.
So if I want to make sure that there
should not be any data available before
sending the data in this particular field,
I have to call
clear my 38 first.
Got to make this.
I'm just calling them here
like this.
Correct.
And then again,
I have to call this login page
or password field door clear like this
right
now. Imagine. Imagine it.
How many places I provided this
and then how many places in my script.
We have provided this data
a lot of places, right?
And this is just this project.
We're using nuances two times,
2000 times.
So just it is just a small project.
But they're also they're also we providing
they take multiple places.
Correct? U.S.
gives method.
So I am supposed to provide this clear
method everywhere
if I want to get the clear fields
before passing the data
and I don't want to do it again and again,
fine.
So now, now, according to the framework,
what standards?
See, according to the framework standards,
we have to come up
with a universal function
for sending their data.
In all the fields of my application.
We have to come up
with a universal function
for sending their data
in all the fields of my application there.
If I send my data by default,
it will clear all the fields.
It will save my value
and it will perform the operation.
Understood what I'm seeing.
So that is just listening like a story
and then I will implement.
Yet I will show you how to implement.
Don't believe me, I know how to read
and I will tell you
how good my code
is working in a single shot.
You can see
and you have been watching it, right?
So just believe me, I'm
going to take you to any other place.
Great.
But this explanation is very important
to believe you.
Thanks for your belief that
maybe when you've been hired
by. All right,
the monthly record is pretty.
And Maryam's favorite word is beautiful.
This is the seventh time in seventh class.
I can see
it goes to God's will.
Only that we know
a lot of places in India.
Nice.
All right, fine, fine.
So what I'm saying is Italy's. Yes.
Silva got correct.
Lot of killer made for her,
but is on this talk about,
you know, poetry
things should even heart rate
because name is waiting you always think
of particulars is likely to select
like I would not I
would not be so shocked surprised
if he changed fate.
If it changes name from the heart.
Obviously
for those who don't know, it was like,
is it is.
He was a famous poet.
Yes. Gudu
gudu gudu gudu
already gets back to the point.
Back to the point, you know, for embracing
all of the perseverance.
You are very dedicated.
But I can see that.
So guys, what I'm saying basically is,
according to the concept,
according to the standards of framework,
instead of writing this,
it gives method here and gives
method there not clear method
here, not clear
whether this is not the best approach.
The best approach is to write one
universal function
and that function is accountable.
But those same they do not everywhere
make this metric common method.
Yes, and
I will make this matter in common.
But there any other solution for me.
So here, here we have to come up.
We have to come up with this
universal function right.
It's completely final exam, getting.
Sometimes you don't get so
in this particular
in this particular common methods class.
Right.
We have to write this universal function.
Okay.
Now in this function
we will implement the functionality
which will clear my fixed plate here.
What I am going
see I'm passing username value.
So this particular door said this function
will work only for user name,
right? Only for user name.
This then gives function
will work only for password menu.
But now the function
which we will divide that function.
Same function.
We will call for the user username.
We will call for password
we will call for plus.
Then we will name last name.
It will call for user name
password confirm password
for every single thing for employee
search by name.
By any rate, for every single place
where we need to send same this method,
we will simply call that particular method
that particular method
another concept of Java,
another concept of Oops.
We are going to implement
that is polymorphism.
The concept is retained
polymorphism, dynamic
polymorphism,
simple language method over they
took remember it
polymorphism body means multiple
form is a means form.
So more mixture polymorphism.
We have two types of polymorphism,
the static and dynamic right
polymorphism combining
polymorphism type polymorphism
exemplars method overloading in method
overnight rating.
So we are going to implement better
rating. Now
right?
I don't know. Yeah.
You tell me whether I'm correct or not.
Fine.
So now see how things work here.
If I need to provide 80 as a username,
I need to provide.
I need to provide
false name, middle name, last name.
So many values
about polymorphism asks for one.
Definitely so one was the explanation
correct the mod.
So now on all these places if I call
this same gives method again and again.
It's not going to work
because dart player Dawson is not clear.
Dawson is.
I'm going to write 12 or 15 or 16
unnecessary lines in just one,
two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight
because I don't need to do it.
I don't want to do it.
Actually in Stuart
I will call the same function
every bit, same function everywhere.
So I will wait one function here.
Right, for Java
and that function will work here.
Look here, here, here
in all these three places was understood
and that's going to be one.
Let's go ahead and implement it,
emulate the function
which is common across all the framework.
What is the place? Which place is this?
Which place?
We have to write this function.
Eight Common Methods.
Excellent days. Let's go ahead.
What is my common with this?
I know your days.
Let me open my common methods. Right.
And let me write this function here.
Right then we is
if I want to use this function vertically,
which given I am to use first, I want to
use this function throughout my project.
Let's start one by one
throughout my project.
So first, making
public
exist modifier.
Now I want to use this function better.
I don't want to create the object
of this class again and again.
Make it
static.
I don't want any return type
of this method, no return date.
Right.
Because this material performs
an operation employed
in the name of this function, because I'm
going to send the data everywhere.
So I'm going to provide
the name of this function and send it
next.
Any question in this work,
do you think it is at all good claims?
No, it's not rocket science.
It's simple. Very simple.
One great.
Who is this?
I don't know anybody.
Almost rocket sense polymorphism.
No, you'll see. It will be easy.
So Sigma is what I'm saying here.
What I'm saying first,
according to the concept.
Right.
According to the concept of method
over 80.
Right. I need to boss element. Right.
And that element will overlaid
with the current one.
For example, if I'm passing here in digit
E next day making passing digital
in the same operation
will be performed on integer B or not
there.
So things work.
Let me explain you first again
just to brush up your one six.
If I write any function,
the function name is a right,
so I'm passing here in digit
eight comma be
right in providing here z is equal
because is equal to eight plus B getting
it means three plus two.
So here
when you actually call this function,
you will call three two,
right?
You can call this function in your main
method.
Three common two.
Next time,
if you want to call this function,
you can call for comma place.
You can call next time eight comma seven
next time we can call three
comma one five or something.
Can we do this?
Can we do this or not?
It means what we are doing.
We are overwriting, we are overwriting it.
Correct. So what is important?
This part is important.
What we are mentioning cutting.
So now I'll meet.
According
to this concept of method of writing,
we are going to perform our
operations on work on integer
one, characters
on byte, on long and short, where
we are not going to perform long,
we are going to perform our operations
on very minute
days.
User name is a string or user
name is very limited.
Password field is a string or password,
which is very relevant, very simple.
So let me write web element
and I'm providing just an element,
just a name element content
categories, just to name Fifth element
second thing.
Second thing in the same function.
See, great.
I got my element, but here
the intention is to send some data.
The intention is to send some data.
So what I have to pass now,
I have to send some data
in the data I pass in the form of string.
So I will write a string, played string,
and the name is a text
to send something like this exclusive.
Understood,
Understood.
So first thing, see how easy it is.
Now see, I'm writing here.
Element dot, dot clear.
So first it will make my really clear
segmenting element
not sending use words and keys
x to sync simple text to simple.
Now this method is really
this method is really
now see
now see how this method is going to work
this time.
C Let me go into my log instance.
Let me go into my log
in two steps again and
let me take any, any method.
See this one for example? Great.
For example, this one,
when I'm passing works and it gives method
I don't want to use right this time.
Let's take in scenario first,
which we can easily execute
because we are in any
big meeting.
This one only. Right?
So see what I'm going to do this time.
First, I'm going to like send text.
Can you see the method is coming?
Same next place, click
here, send text method.
It is asking for two things.
Element.
So tell me where MMS coming from. Where
pages Page's login page dot
username
username.
Now it is asking for the second parameter
is string next to do it.
So the string is coming
from where you see from this step.
Only it is coming
here from this step only just coming in.
You see, I'm handling the parameters,
your username and password.
Correct.
So let's take a username and
username.
Ready now. See,
I changed my function
similarly here.
Also here also I can call this same next
log in page password field comma password.
Wendy Right now see how easy,
how easy this function becomes.
Great.
Just one like now
this one name is going to
this one line is going to clear the data,
which is already available in my field.
Second thing, what it does, it will send
the data, whatever the data I'm sending.
Right.
So now let me go to my login page
and here I'm calling these methods
like this.
Don't send these methods to places.
I'm calling this word here.
It's not clearing any privileged data.
So do I need to call methods like this?
Do I need to call methods like this?
Tell me.
No, we don't need to call these methods
like this.
What we can do is simple.
Same text, same text here,
direct it, user username to trade, comma.
The data data is coming
from configurator fine.
So take this configurator.
Don't get property value. Fine.
Take the data from username.
Similarly going to say next great
password field dark
password first comma configure.
Don't get it property value password.
So now I don't need this to even
see close.
Now this is the perfect example of method
over writing.
Next time.
How how interview
one Ask questions in the interview.
They never ask questions like this.
What is their definition of polymorphism?
Our are experienced people.
They are not expecting definitions
from you.
What they will ask you is always
how much would you rate
yourself on Java out of five to yourself?
And then you say, I would rate myself 3.5
out of 3.5 out of five
is it will get white text grade
3.5 with almost 70% rate.
So you are considering your subject,
you know, 70% of Java.
Excellent.
So the most important topics
of one of the most important
topics of Java is oops concept.
Fine.
Can you please tell me in your project
when you implemented oops concepts.
So now this time
you have to explain that how
you have utilized Java in your framework.
You see two three examples
I can show you making this right
and then providing this is a
D made it public.
That is the process of data binding.
Wrapping up our data in a single unit.
The process is what we called
ramping up of data
encapsulation rate encapsulation
one concept.
Second concept acquiring the property
of one class
in another class is what we call
inheritance.
So you see common methods part.
So for inheritance we use which keyword
extends keyword we are using.
These are not here 3030
Overriding method
overriding is the example of polymorphism.
So you see
this is the polymorphism cutting.
This is the polymorphism.
No, the why you make this method public
because you want the username private.
So you made it
public grade concept of access modifier
void non treating type.
This is constructed by we use constructor,
we use constructor right.
Constructor has been called automatically
to initialize the object
of the class
to initialize the object of the class.
Right?
So when we create the object
with new keyword, this constructor
is automatically been called.
If there is no constructor we create,
then there is a default constructor
available in Java
right.
The definition of constructor
is basically the constructor
is having the same name as that last name,
but it looks like a method.
Correct?
Correct.
So Java is everywhere.
Can you see how. No. No.
I hope you're understanding
how you can to correlate your Java
concepts in your framework.
Strings.
Things are making sense now.
We are working
right
now. Let's proceed for the next project
for our No.
So no, we don't use those methods.
Usual common.
But there zero means I'm going there.
I'm going to come on with this
because our entire class or to the right
is depending on common method.
So don't worry I will be.
You can find me always in common.
But this class you'll see
this is the common methods.
This is the only two liner code
we have written.
We will change.
We will gender entire code variable.
We were passing this to dark side
gives method attribute.
We don't clear,
we change. They don't want.
We do it
because we need excellent piece of code.
Right? We need masterpiece. We do
like I said right.
Just two more classes and then you will
get the fully functional plane.
But the lot of things
we are going to implement.
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
We don't use good governance.
Sector six What I'm saying we don't need
to use as of now because transactions
we make the keys,
there is a public keys we're using.
So the functionality we store,
the functionality, we make it seal, right?
So we never allow our users
to change those particular locations.
We we make them private
and we provide the keys as a public one.
Correct.
So this locator is safe in one place.
Everyone needs using
what keys here in their
duty.
One insured insurance data, the security.
That's what we are achieving here. Correct
or replace Now
do common do common
operations.
We are performing in an application.
One is sending the data.
It is already played.
We can function for today
and now this function is working for me,
which is clearing the fields
and then which is sending the data
I will show you right
when we actually implement this part,
I would choose it.
Then Me What is the second operation
we perform every
now in the
Let me look using
no time for screenshots.
No, no, no, no. Front click operation.
She got this for me.
I'm able to use it but can not explain it
exactly like so many as I read.
And you have to explain later
whatever you are doing,
you just need to explain it.
Simple.
Just see whatever you are doing.
This is what we call explanation.
Getting terminology is something right.
Even if you read, if you say
for pure 60% of the design, right,
if you are knowledgeable.
Right, and you use baking terminology,
that is also point.
People will get the idea
that, okay, he knows everything like that
because
the moment you have confidence, right.
And then if you start speaking, the volume
rate of your voice and your voice speeches
and they will go higher
because of confidence,
not because of the terminology,
that's why we always at
least have the knowledge, right?
If you have a knowledge,
you will be on a different level
when it comes to confidence.
Think it, then you make it.
Yeah. Now you're not fake anymore.
Remember one thing,
you got six months straight.
Why can't you sprint
grade the people in the industry?
Right? They were only three or 4 hours
in a day, max.
Two weeks for the label
was not more than this.
Working professionals.
I'm talking about them. Right.
So less than 5 hours,
five days, 25 over 30 in a week.
You're also running the same thing.
Spend 50 hours on your practice
for six months.
It means you're already having one
European time experience
and you are not big anymore.
Great
doesn't make sense to you, right?
If you practice practice in practice,
it means just consider yourself
believing yourself yourself
Good. Working on your dream project.
You're getting this environment time
and put your money in extremely important.
And for that for that there is no excuse.
We have to spend time
because this is something
you need to understand.
One thing is what is the difference
in between Mississippi and villages
was to segregate these two things
extremely important.
That's this what we are going to chart
the moment you start
understanding the difference
in between Beijing and Mississippi.
Right?
And then you invest your time accordingly.
You see, this is my necessity
is spent 90% of your time or necessity,
and this just 15% of time
you can spend on your paycheck
unnecessarily.
Unfortunately, train what we are doing.
We are spending 70% of pay on the things
which are below
complete pleasure category, not necessity.
Right.
Go and grab a sandwich.
Necessity not simply just
sleep for eight 9 hours, complete sleep
so that I don't get dark circles.
Necessity later
whoever says you have to sleep 8 hours
been 9 hours.
Otherwise your brain will not work.
Stop making excuses just because
you want to sleep more hours straight.
You're just afraid of this sort of
because you're afraid of this, you know,
wrinkles on your face and so many things.
So if you really want to achieve
something in your life,
you really want to do something.
5 to 6 hours sleep is more than enough.
6 hours more than enough.
You just have 24 hours
and you can't sleep.
Do 3% of your time everyday.
You can't do that.
Yes, yes.
That's what I'm saying.
Six is new work. No.
Fine.
So far, so good.
Yes, Correct.
And if you want to him right.
What you have to do,
start sleeping 5 hours.
Great. What? We are in the same boat.
We are in the same boat.
I always wish that I can sleep for 6 hours
in. All right.
Now, the point is, if not, don't sleep
when this debate induces sleeping.
You give this correct look.
Now, the point is, if no one is sleeping
for more than 5 hours,
maybe a lot of operations and support,
if no one is sleeping, everybody is doing
18 hours, 19 hours.
People are awake.
Makes you better waking up
within 19 hours.
But still problem.
Problem is seen just not sleeping. Right.
So the difference Asian in between leader
and this is is still required.
I see
already is the
next operation which we are going to do
is click operation. Okay
now now see one more thing
when more will see,
let me show.
I'm glad.
I'm glad future geniuses
are attending my classes.
Maybe, maybe they had experienced on
base 21 or 22 something. So
maybe.
Right.
You're making a pipeline for us
for 22, 20, 30 batch
and then further from the code,
what was it, 18
nights?
You should you should add in.
Now, remember, guys, we are projecting
digitally three dot sleeper
every match multiple times, right?
But but actually
when we use this particular application,
when everyone uses
this application, everyone.
So what happens?
Excessive use of application
makes it slow.
Correct.
Integrates existing use of application,
makes it very slow.
So now sometimes if sometimes my selenium,
if it is so fast,
it won't, it won't break rate
and it will make my script fade.
Correct.
This is what happening
with me is what happening with this.
One more in me.
For example, if I click into the username
and password blinking on logging button,
sometimes you must have observed it.
My screen is just rolling and running.
Right?
It's rotating, but it's not uploading
completely in the time it's load.
It gets loaded right after that.
If I want to click on Dashboard live,
see or click on Beam option, read my test
because it's going to fill
because my selenium is not going to wait
all that time in.
That gives what I have to do whenever
I come across this type of scenario.
Right?
I have to provide one condition
according to the way we have in selenium.
Guys tell me we have implicitly
we have
explicitly rate fake based.
What is the example of implicit week
I gave you?
I gave you this example based on
what is the example of implicit
would
implicit
wait based on being explicit best true
to driver
not managed or would start implicit
to wait five or more time,
You need to start thinking, what is this?
This is implicit
which which is depending on time.
Once again, 10 seconds, 5 seconds.
Another very good points in my right.
Thank you for remembering
with this point. Great.
I'm going to give you a very good concept.
See? So now, now here,
see what we are doing.
So this is driver manager
by Mozart in particular,
five SEC instance against 20 seconds,
whatever their name. Why?
Because this type of rate is relying
on the name one time
and again is also a type of things
like a bit of nine, five, six or nine.
Another way is explicit to right.
It doesn't require time.
It's not depending on time.
Instead it is depending on condition.
So tell me by looking through
the application here are very nine on time
or are we relying on condition?
If I want to click on emotion,
we are relying on condition.
I want to know the speech.
I want to know my element.
So whenever my element is ready,
clickable, then only I want to click,
read,
or I am going to see that, Hey, Selenium
v builder time,
my element becomes clickable
and when my element becomes clickable,
then only go in and click on.
That's what we are going to do, right?
So now the things
we are going to implement first click
function inside click
function functionality.
So before clicking for that particular
element, it will read builder names.
My element becomes clickable
and then only selenium will perform.
Click completion. Understood.
So not normal click operations
not required any more.
This universal function for click
operation with the it is required
and this could
a student's
must.
So I hope you guys are understanding
what I'm saying.
Right.
And it's not
my lecture is not leading you to
of late
nor did
but I will remember this property
right
So now no, I'm going to read one function.
See, my function is public state.
Big gig.
Wait, get wait.
I'll read
this function will return the weight
dying rate the read which I want to make.
I want to provide this function
will return with that particular big.
Understood.
So now when we talk about explicitly
or implicitly, we have one implicit.
We have a function called
implicit would wait for explicit way.
Do not have anything like that explicitly.
We have something else.
What is that?
The meaning of being for explicit
which would be a for explicit guys.
Come on, wait.
Trendy, but wait until it's coming from.
It's coming from the driver
V It's coming from the driver.
Big guys.
Remember review number four
after your synonym class,
then I was explaining the difference
between implicit and explicit way.
It was Thursday, remember?
And they're temporal you to me, right?
So basically the implicit way,
depending on time and explicit
work, depending on condition
and I gave you the example is but
fine, fine.
So now this function, this function
will return the big distinction.
Yep. Nice.
No. Alexey, no.
Alright,
so now see what I'm going to do here.
I'm going to write one function here.
Function is big driver, big rate.
I'm creating the of this in the new
driver week in here.
Then media is which driver
I can use the same driver which I have
the same driver we can use
driver.
Right.
And here here
I need to provide the time frame.
So just doing 20 a.m.
in seconds, such as of
15, 11, ten, whatever their name.
Now see now see one very excellent thing
we are going to implement.
Now what I'm going to do
I have to use this driver don't manage
your time would start implicit with here.
Also I'm using this date
and providing this file
again I see again I see this is hardcoded
in you see the is
this part is also hardcoded this time.
Okay.
In second this is also hardcoded
and according to according
to the definition of the framework,
we should not pass anything
anything hardcoded
for we should not pass
anything in hardcoded form.
Correct.
Is this correct face?
Fine.
So now now I have one particular place
called constants.
I have one place called Constants
right now here in this constants,
what I'm going to write to see, I'm
going to write a public static
find the that is my name is a string
or it is an integer or it is what?
What kind of digital behave in by
integer in. I am writing here.
See in please see
we tried implicit way.
Let's see then
let's say
ten and I'm writing one for public.
The mistake.
Public static final is
it needs to
be let's see, 15
maybe you can take any of the number
according to your choice.
So now see this time.
This time, if I go here, I don't need
to call this five directly speed.
Instead I can force
constants dot implicit object.
It will take weight from my constants
class.
Similarly here, similarly here.
Here.
I'm going to call constants.
Don't
explicitly
and it will take the code
from my constants class.
Right. So next time.
Next time, wherever you call this
implicit weird, but how does it know
the number count
meant this implicit weight, right?
This Implicit weight and explicit way.
If you go
if you go in your constants class,
you'll see
we are passing ten or 15 here or not.
So the value of implicit with an integer
is how much
the value of this particular variable is.
How much. Then, Right?
And the value of this explicit
weight is 15, right?
So now this ten and 15, wherever
we will pass this particular part,
we make this common throughout my project.
So we just need to call implicit.
We just need to call explicit
wherever we want to call it,
and then it will give me ten and it gets
we don't need to define five individual
different weights everywhere.
We don't need to do it anymore.
So far, is it clear to you or not?
Clear.
Excellent.
Let's proceed further now, After this,
after this, when we actually work
on this particular part, what I'm saying
here, this particular part,
this particular function is going
to is going to return
is going to return this particular break
rate, this particular width.
So this particular function
is going to return this rate
in which I'm going to wait
for particular element for how much time.
But how much time?
15 seconds. Right.
So whatever the element
where I am going to provide
this particular big time,
it will wait for 15 seconds straight.
15 seconds. Fine.
Now see how we can utilize this particular
method called get rate.
This is the way
this method is returning me.
What based on this method
is returning rate but not condition.
Condition is still remaining.
Great condition
is still yet to be implemented.
So what I'm going to do now,
I'm going to write another function
in this class, in that function,
I'm going to define a condition.
And in that condition
I'm going to provide this spread.
So condition is the one function.
In that function I'm calling this and both
this function will love it one time
and that function will call in a click
method.
Right? We'll call this in click method.
So now let me write another function here.
I'm writing here public is dead big void
rate for
capability.
Great for applicability.
Great. Fine.
So I need to wait for element, correct?
Correct.
We need to wait for particular element.
So let me boss here that element because
which element I want to it
every single element.
I want to wait what Every single element.
Great.
Again, the concept of method overriding
polymorphism concept.
So what I'm writing
see I'm saying get wait
until
extended conditions
are expected
conditions, element to be eligible. Right.
So it is asking for which elements
of my web element
of simple.
Can you see just one line of function
and this one line of function
sees big builder time.
My element becomes clickable.
Now see, everything is that I'm interested
with every single thing
is that I'm replaced. You see the element.
The element is coming from somewhere else.
The web is coming from one function.
In this work, explicit name is coming
from somewhere else.
The driver is coming
from somewhere. It's getting
correct
an industrial
so far.
Do you guys have any question in this part
so far?
Do you guys have any question
in this part?
How about others?
Clear.
All good.
Nice, nice.
Let's go ahead and it
see how I'm going to use this function.
So far we have just defined it, right?
We have defined the function in this.
According to this function,
we are going to read
according to the condition
which we have provided.
Right.
But still, the most important point
using this function in a major operation
is the still pending.
Right. So let's do it.
I'm going to write
one function called Public
static void click right click method.
I'm going to use this click play.
Now, in this click one,
what I'm going to pass is,
I want to click on one element
or multiple elements.
Come on.
We have so many elements, right?
We have so many elements.
If it was just one element, right,
why do we need to implement this
universal function?
We have to click on some we none.
We have to click on search option.
We have to be option and employ employed
used in point of mission.
See so many business rate
one at a time obviously moment
if there is no look,
it means want it to one day again
and statement finally and state
and I can make that
because nice
All right so I'm going to implement again
the same concept
that we have been using
lot of polymorphism to date
we are calling rate
now see now see how easy we made it.
I'm waiting wait for click it will be
wait for click ability for element.
Fine.
And then what I want to do element dart
click simple again you see
element or click right now
this tweet for click it will it be
called appear element will come from
this work for applicability
will break in the expected conditions.
Then the time element becomes
clickable element This coming from script
based on the weight
radius coming from one function.
In this function
we are calling the driver big
in the way we defined in our constant
class, in the driver, which is coming from
a global level to push and thus to know
dependency on Haiti hardcoded data.
Now see now
see how we can implement simply this time.
Go here, this time go here.
Instead of using this log input from God,
click.
Simply
replace this part with click method.
It's asking for log input and provided.
See? Can you see
that is on
right now.
Now let me execute this particular one
because here, here in this function,
let me show you in this particular step.
If I go inside this
and if I go here inside
this log in function,
you'll see I am calling this newly
developed universal functions
atrium common methods getting
categories.
So let's execute this.
So it gives method is working fine, right
click method is also working fine.
Everything is working
absolutely fine or not any time
group
or working fine.
Okay.
The first high rate.
Let me commit this code forced.
Otherwise people will ask once again.
So before they ask
if we commit before Class seven
committed.
I'm very much habitual
not working with mentally on people.
So now
let me push this code into the repository.
It's pushed code is already available
right.
People who is built
who still are not aware
that I am within the code and busy typing.
Right. I'm telling you,
everybody should be ready.
Specific add something.
Yeah.
Show them to great.
So guys code is already committed
in a variable rate.
You can take a key from the repository.
So far.
Any question in this dark scripting,
please ask if you have any
any questions So far?
No question.
Don't worry about this particular common
method straight.
All these three functions rate
all these three functions.
I will explain.
This functions once again after the break.
Don't worry about it. Okay.
So let's meet after the break.
Fine.
So now
to reduce the
to reduce rate,
this use of code rewrite again and again
every now and then in the framework rate
wherever we need.
So gives we are calling them matter
directly from selenium.
Interestingly, restricting it
to just one particular element.
And then Norvig
providing hardcoded gateway take slip
providing hardcoded implicit
with hardcoded explicitly.
Right
and then simply clicking operation again
and restricting this particular method
to one particular element
to get rid of all of this problems,
to get rid of all of this problems.
We came up with two universal functions.
The first one is send a text.
The first one is
send a text and the second one is click
right.
Second one is click it.
Now, in this two functions,
we identified a couple of more scopes,
a lot more scopes.
So here, before sending their data,
I need to have my fields cleared
right?
I need to clear the field
so that there should not be any privileged
data available.
Right. If I can do it.
If I want to do it explicitly
without function, then what I have to do,
I have to call.
I have to call this particular clear
method
everywhere before sending their data.
Right.
Does it make sense
to write this element out?
Clear view everywhere before is
one example. If we are
performing this training operation,
it did this so it has to be able to read.
Not clear.
And then this goes to the business
name to write send his method.
Does it make sense? No it doesn't.
It doesn't.
According to the principles of object
oriented programing language,
we can use it.
One place in Java says radio function it.
One doesn't use it everywhere.
Trade with the concept of polymorphism
object oriented programing method.
All right, so we are doing it simple.
We are
writing this function in one place, right?
Extending the property of this particular
class everywhere.
And now, because my function is a static,
I don't even need to create
the object of the class
can simply call this method everywhere.
All I need to do
is according to my current condition,
according to my current text,
according to my current element,
I need to pass this button with this.
So this is a generic, but I would
I can pass user name.
It will perform the action on user
name. Right?
I can pass password.
It will perform the actions on password.
I can pass some other employee ATP. Right.
It will clear the pool.
It would be internally installed.
That's
what my say thanks to method does you
guys nice second thing.
So again thing we were waiting
this traders
legitimate were waiting
when everyone had already exhausted.
This is not a good practice right
we have implicit and explicit
both in synonyms the way we use them.
That was the question.
So we came up with the ends of it.
Yes, we can use
both implicit and explicit,
which according to the needs
of my framework in my application right.
So implicit,
which is the one which is relying on time.
Right.
So wherever we come across the situation,
the condition in the application
or in the framework
where we have to provide the rate
which is right on time,
we will use implicitly
we will read the data from exceptions
mostly, yes, sir, yes.
But most of the times
we read the data from Excel file
because we perform data driven based right
data driven test.
So data driven just implements
your scripts, executes a couple of times,
you know on thousands of users.
Right.
And the best part is you don't need
to maintain this sheet trade.
You get this should from many investors
they already have this data.
Should we just put this should
in your script, in your framework.
Right. You read the function
to read all of these things.
So function is always the same.
The function which we have written, right.
It's all about number of keys
that you have more or less right.
And the name of the files
that you need to change
the same function controls C control.
We put it into the accelerator
called this accelerator everywhere
based on the process.
Right. And then simply called exit
the stored
nice.
So here he had understood
one thing that yes,
we have one explicit condition
because the second really
common object, it
might application is click operation.
Sometimes my application is not loading.
I'm having this issue right.
So for performing click operation,
if my application element is not there,
then my selenium would make
it will make my script feel unnecessary.
I don't want to.
I don't want this to be happening
right in my application scenario.
So what I did here,
I came up with the function
and big function
is giving me a big build time.
One condition is make
what is the condition?
According to the web primary,
which is a category of explicit rig,
we are going to rig, build a time
my beam element becomes clickable.
In the time my element becomes clickable,
my beam driver is going to read
Wake Radius.
That's what I wrote.
One function called
Wait for applicability.
Which element?
So element is generic one.
I simply provided web element element.
So this element I can provide user name,
I could provide login
button, I can provide beam option,
I can provide any employer
option, employee list option
and so on list is very low rate.
I can provide anything simply again,
the concept of Java
polymorphism method or what
enemy Polymorphism.
That's what we are doing making
right now in this function.
Like I said, there is no hard
coded thing at all in my entire framework.
So what is the next thing?
The next thing is the rate
which we are going to provide
should always come
from one particular function.
So that function
we have written over here,
this function is specifically written
so that this particular method
will repeatedly read, which will explicit
with which explicit will driver be fine.
So I would work disregarding me based on
the time that I'm going to provide.
So again,
not even time I'm providing hard.
The time is also coming from
one particular class
where my fields are constants.
So for all the fields which are constants
which are not going to change
throughout my project code,
my framework state right,
those things I keep in mind
constraints, class, right?
Those things I keep in my constants class.
So from Constants Class, I'm calling this
explicit, I'm calling this implicit here.
Understood.
Now let's go into this particular part
straight.
Let's go to this particular mark
and change and change here.
Rate change in all these operations.
First, go here,
this log in button, not click.
Can we change it to like this click
log in beech start log in.
Can we do this weights similarly this one
and we do the same next
log in page thought
password.
So it is asking for their data. Fine.
So their data is my password.
Simple
right?
I don't need this bar then.
Here I can also send text
log in page or username comma username.
Really?
I don't need this
but see how I'm going to reduce my code.
Now those lending functions become red.
Lending functions become a function
of just two or three or four lines.
It includes a solution also in this three
or four lines, it can use a solution also
restored
it. Now
again here, here, let me change it.
Click on login page dart log in.
But then
here also
certain text guys I'm changing
only the things made
which we have to change
password.
Great.
So now see earlier
it was a function of one two, 345 lines
right now
it converted into just two line thanks
what was coming out the previous lines
that is helpful for comparison.
Yes he is correct
I'm not going to delete anything.
Nobody gets totally
I'm not going to do anything.
Fine.
Now going to this employs search systems.
See this time also what I can do.
So please see click, bash dart
in more simple
way here. Also
click bash dart
employed is to work on
rate case
here to see this
data rate the data which we are passing
so here I can rate
send text for my employee list page
dart ID employee search karma.
And then this is simply
even this value.
Also we get bars from where they sent me
this value.
Also we can pass from where
students
we can pass from configured properties
like we can pass it from examples
to when we get buzzing from data table.
We can possible
extend its invite rate multiple places.
You got it.
Is this correct or not?
Students
BMC And what a single example
Example statements
with scenario outline We have seen
data table with key without keys.
We have seen directly passing
in the future files.
The steps we have seen passing the data
from configured
properties, separate
config properties, target property value
we have seen,
and then passing the data from Excel by.
You have five ways
anywhere read multiple vicious
to crime
final.
Now here the next important point to click
again here search button
are right
so for that you'll be having separate
rating stations for that
I will take those stations
just one session, 3 hours.
Every single question will be answered.
Of course
I would remember the dates, right.
So that is a series of steps
which we should remember.
Like I said, you don't need to remember
every single line of code
right?
You don't need to remember
every single line of code.
For example.
For example, if you know what this page
object model is, right, what you want
would be a first approach for page
object model is to
what?
I'm just giving you one example.
If you are aware of page
object model designed by then.
So what would be your approach
to implement page object murder design?
But what is the first thing
you would release?
You will create pages package, right?
You will create a package.
Then what
you will do, you will make the pages.
Then what you will do
and organizing package with the locators
right then
you will find the elements
and put them there.
After that.
Plus no constructors right after that
constructor, Correct.
Simply this is the page object model.
Right.
So now tell me to expand this.
You are
in the
we'll extend this you want explaining
with that See you know this already
it's all about having a belief that
yes I can remember
and I will remember for sure.
What is this framework?
Just 2530 classes, five six packages,
one application.
That's it.
We need to remember how difficult
even on fingers
it is configured for of a below 60.
Things that you need to remember next in
your brain is an ocean, right?
It is just a drop in an ocean,
not the money you don't need
the moment you allow negativity,
but we entered stemmed into your mind,
right?
Your downfall starts normally
again, as we know.
Not even this My trade in classes
with me on many classes.
You guys think eight plus 311.
That's right, guys.
Just 11 classes.
All right, next
one employee list page
or MP, Common value
X, Y, Z to find.
We have changed dysfunction, right?
We have JS dysfunctions in those steps.
Now, let's talk about the third one.
Third one.
There is nothing to change here.
Fine. There is nothing to change.
An employee steps.
Might be a lot of things to change.
Yes, correct.
So let's do it.
Click.
We are changing this thought emotion.
I hope everyone is understanding
what I'm doing right.
Rich and music class. It's okay. My
same things to
an employee page fours to me, comma,
whatever the value we're passing.
So it it would be
whose name is this?
No one in a among right?
I wouldn't know the combinations.
What I mean
So dig straight
so employ a dark last name.
Gamma ray, M s
this is first name
and then
click
start save button
comes looking for this.
Maybe that to
Silvana
M was the only
the right Correct or not,
I was going to miss a blessing.
It was going is gone
So now
sent text or it employed or first name.
This is the locator and.
This is the key we are calling Find.
Got it.
One of the most amazing
thing Brain could get has ever 20
Amazing guy. Yep.
Great human being.
And now here you see
simple click operation
great with eg new employee beach dart dart
Silverton
cool.
Then click on
this dog and employment it again.
Come in this part.
I hope this would be the last function
for this.
Just this last function.
So click
fish.
Know why I'm doing this?
Because I know if I don't do this
and if I ask you get a change
of second parameters in line
number 80 and 83 is a sure
line number 1883 80
line number.
It is already collected.
Oh, here.
You mean my last name?
And he finds her
copy.
That's why I'm doing this.
Because I know if I tell you to do it
right after something,
I will get some responses
in this index of order.
My code is not working. What happened?
That's why I'm not letting you do this.
I'm doing this
password.
I got one message right.
Why are you always?
My code is not.
And I was answering this.
I mean, I had no clue
what the ones that were to responsible.
And then finally I had a blank.
I'm sorry.
And make sure it will not work next time.
What else?
I can see
employed list for the right word.
Deshmukh.
What is the easiest way to find
a mistake?
Good.
We did the best one there.
Even worse yet, some things about this
typing
are easiest way
to find a mistake
is to read the console properly.
Whatever console. Since
late whatever console is.
Once you had that kind of observation,
remember guys sharp sharper observation
being a due engineer, right?
I'm telling you, from my experience,
it is one from best. When
who is
this legend?
It must be the instructor.
Remember this?
What I'm saying basically is
observation is very important.
We need to engineer.
Very important.
If you know how to identify, observe
the tiny details, minor details
of the application rate.
Believe me.
Believe me,
the bug free software is getting deep.
The delivery of this type of software
is guaranteed.
If there is an engineer
who is working on testing department.
Right.
He's a keen observer.
It was predicted.
I'm telling you this from my experience
finally
finding nano milk.
Finally, because I have a fever
the next way optimality.
I'm taking this.
We never had a class on trading
console already.
Find everything I will be needing,
but I will.
What is console basically. No, no, no.
With just a blue because of early morning.
Right.
And you shot it
like 330 of all in this window.
Obviously Golden glove is very normal
if you it is very normal
in this case.
All right.
So now every single step is fixed
for same text and for completion rate
here.
I mean, I would trade for medicinal.
The next one
if condition nine.
Which one?
You mean?
So the one
if nine when I have condition
scroll up. Sure.
Screw this one
for clicking on checkbox.
Okay, fine.
Take it.
Water.
I mean you want excellent work.
Amazing.
Pay attention back then
and copy code from the native.
Well,
it's some poetry going on little bit.
Plants.
Nice, Nice.
Competition begins.
So now with reality,
we have one Shakespeare also in the bench.
Once I see
a lot of good lines in
there can be generated nothingness.
Yes. Yes we can.
We will. We will.
We will now
see Write majority of your code.
If you see majority of your code is now
commended, it means we are not using it.
Only a few lines of code we're using.
Can you see, guys, I left this code
so that you can compare somehow, right?
You can compare this code somehow.
And if there is anything
which I missed rate
in converting it from normal methods
to our universal methods.
Right.
You can do it.
Don't
please don't send me message that, hey,
you forgot to convert those two methods.
I'm still saying again.
I mean in advance.
I'm sorry for that.
Okay.
Not even heaven, but do not even know.
That's
what I'm telling you. Not even language.
20. Fine
so far against these two functions.
So for these two functions,
keep this for functions actually
are this functions clear to everyone
I really needed.
And this you started yesterday.
I wasn't needed.
I thought of you
all for hard.
Not even required.
Not even for it.
Not even you're required after you run up.
You made your code
and you committed to the repository.
Not even a person declared the script
will execute itself automatically.
That kind of a that kind of setup
we are going to teach you, right?
We will teach you that sort of right.
All you will get is when you wake up
in the morning, you will get one email
in your mailbox, right in your mailbox,
and in that box, one email will be there.
That email will say, Hey,
you're doing this
because it's executed nine plus one print.
This is that is an option.
You'll go ahead and check.
So by the time you come to the office,
right,
you already have a plan in your mind
having a plan in your mind that,
okay, I need to work on that part
because that is fitting.
Now, that's
great.
On the
exactly
note, trust a lot of trust issues
will be executing from going from. Yes.
Yes, sir.
Latest last word.
One step from command
to rinse without intelligent.
Right. And then the primary step? Right.
The main step would be not even command
prompt required,
not even computer required.
So like that, by the end of the course.
Right.
You will learn that. But also nobody.
So we would like I said, right,
there is a series of steps
and we are taking you
through all of those steps one by one
by now.
Now, let's talk
about another important point.
Okay, Let's talk about another one.
What is that?
See some times you perform, click
operation, write in your application.
Sometimes you'll click opposition works.
See, as a Q engineer,
you have to think for all
the possible combinations
that you can face.
Not all the companies
use very different playbooks.
Not all the companies use the company.
No. Martin is rate
framework depends on the project,
the requirement of one particular
application, but the concept is seen,
for example, nowadays, majority
of the organizations prefer to work on it.
You can put a framework right?
Vanessa What 90% of organizations
prefer to work on it,
but it
now might
be possible that the name of this basis
object model would be different,
such as convert pages,
control trainers, write or conduct
execution classes, something like this.
But seem okay.
Java code will always be written in Java
memory will always produce
but not examined.
It's not like it will produce more
not dissimilar instead of contradicts, but
it's not going to happen.
Correct.
So you need to understand the concept.
Business is also famous.
Can we do all interesting?
You do? Yes, sir.
I will tell you to do this.
I will show you how we can do it.
Distinct is the one
that we take you to that part.
Okay? Just
fine. Now,
sometimes people like Operation Great
and it happens. It works.
But sometimes we come across
an issue in the application.
Remember the history?
Listen to me carefully. No.
Now I'm coming to the point.
Sometimes when you perform click operation
in your application, what happens is
basically it doesn't click.
But when you perform manually click
rate,
you're able to click
when you perform it manually.
But when you send this click operation
using dot click
method, it's not able to click on it.
Why is it so?
I asked why you logs do I select
sometimes?
Have you ever have you always studied?
This is still a limited exception.
A couple of more exceptions.
Right? Element
not applicable. An exception.
So many things.
When element is not applicable
at this particular point.
Some other point would take the click
like this
and then it provides the coordinates.
Something like this.
Right now
no element not applicable exception.
So many exceptions are.
I don't want to go
into digital, but my point is
what is the alternative?
You have to click on that element.
If click method is not working, you're
getting
kind of excellent data.
We have JavaScript executed,
perform, click completion.
Do we have it or not?
In there is not a function
we are talking about function
that is remember in there is a commander
and that is a function.
There is an exact command.
When you talk about JavaScript,
JavaScript, this particular function,
we have to write a function
for JavaScript, but we have any function.
Let's See
if we get stuck in the application
right where my click operation
is not working, what is the alternative
I have in my project?
Do we have an alternative
right now?
Right now with the existing setup,
I'm talking about Mohammad
and for the Einstein.
Albert my mother, the Einstein.
Do we have any sort of break?
No, no, not yet.
So what I have to do as a Q engineer,
as an automation architect,
as a senior member of the testing team
order, complete project team or something.
It's your responsibility
to think of all the possible scenarios
and implement them in your framework.
So let's set the model.
If you get an opportunity,
where do you have to build the framework
from scratch?
This all or the options read
this all are condition
you should keep in your mind
when making the framework
understood,
because when you go for the review,
definitely senior technical guy
or senior architect
was going to ask this question, Hey,
what is the alternative
you have in your framework to complete
Method is not going to work
at that point of time.
You should be able to explain
that we have this alternative
understood, right.
That's that's the most important point.
See, now from the explanation
point of view, I'm extending,
what is the reason why I showed you the
positive data from five different sources
so that when you go in the job
and when someone ask me
you should not stuck to one point decay,
I can bother to to function feature.
I know
now you have so many things to explain.
So many things that I can easily do
from example
Quantic properties from feature file,
from Excel file, from here and from there.
So many places,
great viewing.
It shows
that you have a diversified experience.
You work on multiple projects
and this type of experience come
when you generally work on two, three,
four projects.
In one project.
You cannot do all of these things right.
You'll always get stuck to one particular
functionality, one particular agenda,
one particular decorum that you said
in the beginning of the project.
Right then throughout the project, just in
a five things, you change a lot of ways.
90% things are seen
that you don't really follow.
But if you have this much of diversity
in your learning,
if you have this much of a method
to implement right,
and you know how to implement
all of these things
and you know
the way you guys have been told Java
rate the way if you are able to explain
Java like this, believe me, believe me,
this is what even many professionals,
they don't know Java like this.
The way you know
what certainly is a perfect experience,
right?
I told you that they also don't get to
restrict yourself free to one application.
Go take any application
and write your organization script.
No, you have a but great.
So just consider Amazon is your project.
Make one framework.
Try to automate Amazon.
Make one framework right to a Gmail, make
one framework right or something else.
The more framework you already designed,
the more experience you will get right,
and you will definitely learn
in one framework.
Something else in another framework,
something else.
You will learn so many things. Right?
Right now we are going to read
a couple of more functions.
If you come across Amazon, there
you see a lot of just one
exercise I'm giving you, right?
Just one exercise.
Then you see Amazon,
how many dominos you see
every year and every now and then year.
And that is a drag down
values, a lot of problems, right?
So everything you should read this link,
plus what you should write
just one function for positive
what would it the best thing
just one functionality with some function.
Right.
So try to create one single from scratch
for any e-commerce application trade
and try to write this data
gives universal functions.
Right?
One more function select function right.
And then use that particular function
across multiple web elements
and then try to get the values straight
to perform this type of operations.
And believe me, once you're done, once
you're done with this type of practice,
great,
you will be able to explain from your own.
Then you don't need video recordings again
and again.
You don't need conceptual understanding
because you already implemented
the concept on your own.
So now that is no one will can explain
this concept better than you
for the things you have been
getting.
My point based.
So once this. I hope so
great and great.
Yeah, you'll be that.
So if not the argument
because of security issues.
Something else maybe.
Right.
Let me give you one really good
application.
This application is there.
I hope we are done.
We have worked on this particular
application rate
in this application. It's a simple one.
This one
right.
Take this application or any
other application you can take No issues.
So many applications you have, right?
If you are open to work, you will take
a lot of things to work upon.
Fine.
So now let's talk about the alternative.
What is the alternative of the click
JavaScript executable?
So first the jardiance is the best rate.
It has so many so many functionalities
to implement page so many functionalities.
Okay, so let's consider it as a task.
They create a function, create a function
rate.
Again, I'm repeating, let's take it
as a task for tomorrow's class.
Create a function
which will be universal function.
And in that function
you have to write for select class.
For select class, right?
So based on maybe visible text
based on maybe index or whatever.
Right.
Implement the functionality
and basic across multiple drag.
Don't save function write,
just override that element.
Trying to find the data.
Try to find the element
of selected performing.
Can you do it for me
guys?
Can you do it?
Image elements
Obviously initially ingenuous.
Second task.
Well now the second task
is going to the employee list.
Select any employee.
Right now
here you have to modify the details.
What do you have to do?
You have to modify the details.
Now you'll see this standard is one.
Now can you see
guys, can you see nationality? Yes.
This is the dropdown
and you see marital status.
This is also a dropdown,
right?
You should be able to click
on this checkbox.
Right.
Provide This name grade,
provide this data, change it, select
the menu from here,
read license expiry date selected
date of birth selected from here.
Now here.
See the the universal function
for selecting the data from the dropdown.
You will be that function
you can use only in one scenario names
can you see the scope
students.
Can you see there's a scope?
Great.
Okay.
So now I want you.
I want you to do this one.
Okay.
For me.
Shenanigan marital status for see post.
You should be able to modify
all the details of. This employee
yes or not?
Yes, I would be
going after the class.
Maybe after the class I will get
after the class.
I think you might date right now. Right?
It will be lost somewhere.
Fine. Great.
So now let's write
the alternative function of click.
So first, what I'm going to do, I'm
going to simply read one function
that will return me,
my JavaScript executor object.
So public
when I see this function is returning me
JavaScript executor then do
I need to write
void here?
Do I need to write waiting days?
Then me
I'm ready to get get genius
exec to to execute
so it will return JavaScript execute
an object
no return
element point element technologies
on read your JavaScript execute.
So here it returns
JavaScript execute fine.
And now,
now I'm going to repeat my function.
So what I'm writing see
JavaScript execute is
is equals to
is this correct?
Order was executed
because this function is going to return
my JavaScript execute object
right?
Fine.
Is it like unboxing
kind of. Now?
Now the main operation
which we are going to perform,
what is that what we want to do
with the JavaScript case?
What we want to do is with the JavaScript.
It is an alternative,
complete method. Great.
So we have to click, find.
So I'm going to write public static void
is click JavaScript, execute that link.
All right.
So now I, I don't know, rate on which
particular element I need to perform this.
Just click.
So let me provide again
my web element, which is identity one.
There exempt any element. Click
click.
Guys understood
why I provided web element.
Fine.
So I'm typing here, get double script,
execute the dart execute script and he had
what generally rate are your names of zero
or click arguments of zero dot click.
Is this correct correct?
So we take the disguised dummy.
It's indexed, Correct.
Is this index correct or not?
No. It's going to.
Okay, fine.
So far, so good.
Everyone.
Everyone So far so
fine.
Now let's come here.
What I'm going to do is again, I'm going
to take this scenario picture, right?
And in this scenario,
I'm going to take just one condition.
This one is right.
So search employed by i.t.
I'm talking about one
hypothetical situation.
What is the argument of zero represents?
Oh, we go talking about
where there's no common methods
that you this one you mean
arguments of zero. Right.
But this is a basics index of JavaScript
the basics and takes great arguments.
So zero. No,
let me consider this in any rate.
So guys, I'm going to use
just one scenario.
Let's make a hypothetical.
So here I'm using this particular one.
Now, what I'm trying to show you
is basically
when I try to log in
to this particular application rate,
let's say here after entering
the username and password
onto this particular screen
and click on log in button, let's
see if my application is not working.
They're not taking click on Pim option.
Just consider for a moment. Great.
The button is not able to perform action
on Pim option.
Right?
I'm talking about one condition here
guys again.
So now now this what I'm going to do
is see, I'm
going to change
here in this particular step.
I'm going to
change this click operation for Pim option
instead of this, I'm
but I think just click bash. So
and you see this
instead of performing normal click, I'm
going to perform JavaScript click,
let's this type
it to click again.
Nice.
Raise the click or not perform click
operation using JavaScript also, right.
So in case you're not quite ready
when your normal click is not working,
you can use can we leave both and add
something like switch case?
Oh, it's not preferable trade data.
It's not preferable.
So one egg, one thing, rate switch.
And guess what is that gives you employed.
If it is working, you produce not working.
Ah no.
How would you know?
How would you know? Sometime next click.
Sometimes it doesn't
rate if it is intermittent behavior
of the application that appears.
Sometimes it doesn't appear something that
you you never know.
See, right now
we're executing right on local product
and here we're executing
just one just because we're good.
This gives the member, when we execute it
in parallel, using this to
how JavaScript works,
That's what you didn't understand.
Like every is JavaScript,
execute JavaScript,
execute to interact with.
We can use but we have rate.
We generally use this Berkeley
JavaScript executed.
We know normal selenium methods
what they is JavaScript execute
to interact with good UI element to work.
It's not interact with algorithmic,
but when talk about selenium, it interacts
with a,
you know, basically document object
more than break
java script execute it.
My question is
what is there difference between normal
blink and JavaScript executed
come on days?
What is the difference in between
JavaScript executing normal thing?
They mean
based on
whether one is or two clicks.
Only one thing is an element error
double digit.
Anyway, if we want.
Sometimes I believe know nothing,
start like that.
You're starting to see
what it's all about.
Interaction Video click is interesting
and video JavaScript is directly
see when you talk about web
element, right?
When you talk about click matter,
new selenium, right,
it interacts with your DOM.
So you click on a web element,
maybe different from other browsers.
So still enable private text to condition
force.
This element is visible
so element is visible.
We are from do what is don't videos
the original code
guys remember what you doing.
Let me show you.
This is your law.
This is your Dom right now
when I'm hovering my mouse here right
you'll see things are highlighting here
in they're correct.
That's what it is saying.
That's what it is doing here.
The element must be visible and is must
have a height and width greater than zero.
This coordinate should be
greater than zero right looks appear you
UI interaction.
That's why we called
you like distinct user interface.
Distinct because you are interacting
the user interface.
The things you see on
the screen is the UI.
This is also what we think, right?
There's one
that Indian is printing this thing.
It is viewing thing, right?
So now here you see what it says,
but in JavaScript
clicks does not check
this preconditions before clicking
right.
Whether it is available,
it is visible to the screen.
What is no coordinates? No, it's a mouse.
Click on an element symbol and then click
Whether it is used, such is input.
It fires the elements click even simple.
So it means it interacts with code.
It imprints directly with code.
It's not looking for the element
which is available in there.
Don't understanding my point,
it's all about interaction.
Variable click method is language.
Your JavaScript model is going.
This is one of the most important
interview questions
that understood the difference
in between JavaScript.
Why JavaScript execute and works?
Because JavaScript executed the
with the code, not with the UI element.
What happens next?
Understood what I'm trying to you
now. Now let me show you another point
here.
See, when you see
any normal click method right
there, just going to this click method
declaration,
it came here, opened this one.
Now their definition, which was here,
the rate which we read the definition
you will find here
for this particular function
they come on
the element class directly.
Well we've been automates this
I believe for this particular one
great wide click method.
So here inside this,
if we open this click method
that must be written. Yes.
Yes. Correct.
So one is interacting with the core,
one is letting the UI element break.
What a simple explanation.
Just think like this.
Okay.
For a simple explanation,
one is interacting with the code,
one is interacting with the UI elements.
Understood.
Click is interacting with the UI element
JavaScript execute that is
interacting with
interacting with your code
and gets to know
by playing
Now your browser for the
now see guys
So far what I'm doing so far more time.
The first First of all, everyone,
at least in this point,
whatever the things we have created,
everyone reached this point
like let me commit the code to this point
so that no one can ask any question
question.
It's done. Code is dead in the right now.
So far, object
code is available in the repository.
All right.
For now,
see what I'm going to do right here,
right now. Right now.
You'll see in this application
what is the problem here?
Because is
we are still executing our script
from multiple places.
We are still executing on a script from
place, from
multiple places, for example,
and another class.
So in general.
So I have two regression and smoke right?
If I want to run a smoke or regression
from just one place,
do I have any option here for that?
No option.
Great notion.
Fine.
But now, now you'll see
the beauty of MAVEN project,
which we are going to start
change there next.
No need to change script now.
We are actually looking
into the framework part from here.
When Morgan is starting,
open your open
your Google browser and great maven.
Sure, fire is
flagging
what you need to type.
Maven Sure.
Fire like you.
Okay.
This moment you're battling it
as everyone open
this maven show for plugin, click on it,
click on it, it open this page.
Apache Maven project
It's open
it, open this particular page.
No, no, no I open Maven.
Sure Fire plugin. Right.
I open this thing and I am
this pretty get it.
Is everyone with me
at this point?
No. Because look,
even if someone was about to ask David
not ask.
Nice go blue. Go,
go, go down
go down and see you're using best in
can you see using testing to get everyone
see this
using the stingy
go down this go down
using this energy. Okay
burst into.
Click on it, click on it,
click on it, click on it.
Can you see it is saying using suit.
It finds
anybody.
Once it is using suit, examine,
find everyone,
copy this part, copy this part
is everyone copied this.
Come to your project.
I'm going very slowly
so that everyone can see what I'm doing.
Come to your project open.
Right. Examine, find
open one Getting simplified.
Go all the way down
to their dependencies tag
and then pass it basic.
We don't need to do anything
under dependencies.
We don't need to do anything.
This and the dependencies.
All right.
And now here based
don't rush.
Don't send 1 million messages
of having error rate.
Okay everyone,
until this point.
No, no, no.
Remove this three doors from here first
and remove this three doors from you.
Remove this three Laughlin,
remove these lanes of three dot
remote that we want guys
nice now here now here
before plugins
because plugins is a part of build
so my plugins should come under the bed.
It should come and that would be the tag.
Right.
So before my plugins and after my plugins
after my plugins,
I have to write this really back
and you see what I did
before my plugins and after my plugins.
I would wait change the way they use here
and under build.
I have plugins.
Under plugins, I have one plugin.
Great. See.
So from this plugin to plugin,
I have one plugin
in plugins.
I can have multiple plugin in big.
I can have multiple plugins module.
Correct.
You know this had a great one
but in one best I can.
Multiple packages in one big attack
in a multiple classes in one class.
Like in a way people functions
from extended or similar.
Similarly here, in one way
I can have multiple plugins in one plugins
I can have multiple plugin detail
and this tool.
So far everyone, everyone understood.
No, no, no.
Simply remove this three lines.
So examples, files, suit, excrement files
and so big simplifying
these three lines, these three things.
Wait, wait, wait.
Like I said, login is great.
Nobody's noticing
it isn't going to make it chameleon.
It will change its color, so don't
wait.
Remove these three lines.
Everyone remove these three lines.
No, no. Normally no one exists.
And because we didn't completely.
That's what I'm saying.
We didn't completely create this.
What I'm saying
Hold your horses guides Now
here simply right are code includes
includes blade includes Take
Everyone road.
This includes open and close includes
inside.
This includes inside.
This includes.
Right.
Another big goal include.
What is that?
They code include again, open and close.
This tape include
Can you see gains
include and include here?
No, no.
What are you what do you have to write
in between this to include?
You have to write double stuff.
You have to read the will Star.
Double star means your project repository.
Understood.
Double star means
your this particular project
being assigned to see
then slash stop.
It means under is RC
you will be having particular
part in Java.
You'll be having this particular mark.
Right When you provide this star,
then you have to provide
the name of your runner class.
So which level class I want to run?
I want to smoke dark java
with file extension.
With file extension.
I have to provide
so smoke as my java class or not.
Tell me
guys, is this my
Java class or not?
So now, now if you see right now.
If you see if I want to run my smoke
right, I can simply run it from here.
Can you see a
lot of you already provided not see
this particular day sort of one great
this double stop rate
it means they had an acute build
this point till this point your Java board
then this is thought is under this
there is one package
fine whatever
the bigger general in that big get find
a smoked door java
and then configuration file restraints
include this for execution how things work
I tell you, don't worry.
So this is what I'm talking about.
Your Apache raid Maven.
Sure. Fire plugin.
What it does basically
like for sure for plugin
this build tool in tomorrow's class.
Right. I will give you
a brief introduction about it.
I Will give you the brief detail
about it. Right.
First I'm just showing you as of now,
if I have multiple execution points,
this is not good practice.
If I have a single execution point,
if I have a single execution point,
that's what I need in my project.
Right?
So now, from now onwards,
we will not change anything, right?
We will not execute some time regulation
sometimes no.
If I want to run a smoke. Right,
I can change here.
Smoke If I want good indication,
I can change integration if I want to run.
What that see?
That's it.
I can look understood.
Understood.
Based.
Fine.
Now. Now, can someone please
copy this particular part?
Someone copy this particular part?
Yes. Get sensitive obviously,
and be straight in the group.
So then if anyone has any edit
they can solve and they can use it.
Just one. This one. Dun dun dun dun dun.
That's it. That's it.
Like all the all exciting guys.
Basic
Mustafa,
please correct this error after the bell
after this two is free
Gillespie can use slash
Yeah him.
I know this is still.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
No, no.
After this.
Once everyone once
everyone had this party.
Your machine.
Please let me know
once everyone is dead to this point,
let me look.
Fine.
Now see.
Now see, I'm going to.
I'm going first load my project.
If there is still an error,
even after loading the page,
even after loading the Mavin project.
What do you have to do?
Guys, at least let me explain.
Rate.
Even if EDM exist,
even after loading the moment project,
if it exist,
what do you have to do guys is
change this M5 to for
change this M5 to enforce windows two
guys 3.0.0 hyphen m5
we have this virgin M5
if even after loading the project,
if someone is having
the error changes to M4.
Right.
So let me reload my project now.
It says can not reconnect.
Fine.
Now it's working fine.
It's working fine for me right.
It's done.
Maryam, what is the status?
No, I'm
played. It's good now.
See, I told you.
Give me some time.
Include Maryam, please remove the space.
Do you see any space here from my side?
No Space raid.
Please remove the space
if you change it to import raid.
If you change it to import
raid Mine is a still great.
Did you update the project?
Did you reload the project? Will you
not you Maryam?
I mean the yours is done already.
Great.
Then change it to him for you Forget.
And it takes time to refresh.
It takes time to refresh. Great.
So whoever is having is still room for it.
Fine guys
I asset name for only for those for whom,
after reloading the project is still in
place is giving the error.
They can put it as an alternative raid.
But couple of others always you know
start from info only
they're too good on first priority but
invite was the compatible one I give you.
Is it as a workaround alternative for them
for not the military
one understood.
Yes. Maryam, first raid your debut in five
Denote your project.
Give it some time Exit your IED invasion
raid closing echo one
It will be gone.
Alright guys.
So far so good, everyone.
No, that's fine.
That's completely fine, Warwick.
So now see the GRC,
the main point rate. Why?
Why we implemented this particular part?
Because.
Because this particular part,
if you see RAID,
we have single execution point
and from today onwards
we will not execute smoke remnant class
regression class. No.
If you want to execute them,
we can execute this from here
on this tour
and this tool.
How we can execute here. See
here, you see?
Can you see this one option?
Everyone
in is it is never an option.
In the top right, top right corner.
Click on it.
This is your project name, right?
Everyone can see the project. Me
expanded,
expanded.
It gives you life cycle here.
Can you see they've taken everyone
open this lifecycle
Now see in this lifecycle
you have so many phases clean, readily
combined based baggage, verify, install,
side deploy lot of things for now.
For now, just focus on clean
and this focus on clean
and best understood two things
focus on clean and test.
So first, let's run clean.
So how different clean double click on it.
Simple, just double click on it.
Now see what happens.
It it is giving me one thing.
It says Build a success.
Can you see it says build a success.
A Katrina.
What happened?
Yeah, sure.
See here, here.
Can you see?
It is never an optional
on this.
Click on it.
You will see a screen like this right?
And then it says process terminated.
Remember why it's terminated?
Why you terminated the process.
Did you close and open your dirty,
close your ID and open it again.
Please
close your intelligent and open it again
and then reload the project.
I still see this option. Reload trade.
There is click on it, reload option
and then it will be working
point
like now open it under lifecycle.
Today you see
there's way nature.
It means it is working fine.
And here just double click on clean,
double click on clean.
If you are working on clean
and it says build success,
it says Wilson says
it means every single dependency,
every single plugin, every single dot,
everything is perfect.
Everything is perfect.
In your project,
there's web Windows Access, the student,
that's where it says Big success.
Fine.
Remember one thing, even
even if you're good, even if your code,
for example, if you're executing Benson,
it is out of this team nine is free raid.
So when it comes to development
and employment paid
in the time you get build success message,
you cannot deploy your project
based on the deep despite
this is a development boom moment
you can deploy it on to the production
server cutting
so Maven doesn't allow you to deploy.
It will open the production on film
unless it is 100% correct.
Hundred percent correct means all there.
Just because this should be executed,
it should be fast.
Understood.
So even if nine is positive,
one is still it will give you
a you're not will success rate.
No, I think that you be doing eight.
What is the meaning of this
big message and why we didn't really use.
Yeah.
Wait, wait, wait.
There's what I believe is
the one way we use clean.
I will tell you that nobody
I also had these rate of Totally.
I know, I know why Why we have this
I'm here. Exactly.
See, now,
when we actually execute this test rate,
it would be best if I double click here.
Then it will execute this this move. Plus,
in this smoke,
whatever the things we have right,
it will execute based on the XY.
I'm double clicking on test
now see what is happening.
It is taking running run.
Nurses smoke,
it is taking on or tell me this.
Everyone is executing.
I'm damn sure they can see the response
of application
here.
Fine. Now see guys here
it says
best run one failure zero and a zero
skill zero.
The desert is best.
Run one.
No failure, no error, no escape.
Big success.
Can you see?
Can you see this? Will success?
No, no.
Let me show you something.
Can you see it
for literally here in this target folder,
you see all these things kick in.
Bullish team on the board
generated resources MAVEN status.
Sure. Fire reports.
Best guesses Can everyone see this?
Can everyone see this
now? See,
just double click on this clean
option again.
Double click on the screen option.
Run this clean again.
And when you run this clean again,
this time if you go,
that is no target folder in your project.
On the rewards for the execution.
All the reports
for the execution is gone. Now
is and you see
all the target reports read files under
their target report is gone.
Why is the reason behind
this memory tool is the intelligent one.
You have a lot of ways
created every time, a lot of friends
you create every day, making target
like your reports
make other logs
and everything and unnecessarily.
It is increasing the size of your project.
So even if your actual code
is not that bulky,
if your actual code is not that bulky,
these files are meeting your code
in actual bulkier than ever before.
And this tool
and according to the standards,
they should not be having a bulky code
right in the framework
attribute should be really laid to it.
Now you'll see
if you get in this framework rate
is that any driver will find having five,
six, seven in the door.
The x if I look over driver folks driver
I know if I have to
execute my script across five browser,
you know if it5
but I will not find such a screwdriver
not to exceed g driver, not to exceed
eight driver or d exceeds the funny
or proper driver or to exceed
it will increase
the size of my project a lot.
To me
it will increase the size.
It makes my code bulkier.
So while putting this quarter to the cloud
and if someone is trying to download
this good, it will take a lot of time.
Right. That's why we nucleated with code.
Now you see that is no bulky
journal plate.
There is no mention of Java
you need to provide.
You just provide one thing.
What is that dependency?
And when you provide dependency,
it works automatically for you.
Correct?
Correct. Fine.
So so far, this clean and dust part clear
clean
is to clean your target folder to remove
all the unnecessary logs and everything.
And best is to execute your project
from one particular location
and the stored.
It says build success.
It wins. It is working fine.
You it
says will success.
Yet the one that we can do it
when we are actually working
on the execution of scripts.
Right.
And when we are writing new automation
script then definitely we can use
definitely we can use no how, no break.
I don't I'm not in a brick as of now.
No brick. I already give you 25 next rate.
We are in a flooring now
we are in a flow right now.
Let's complete couple of more points.
What if this feels weird?
A failure message.
Let me show you.
Let me show you See if I go this time.
If I go
this time, there can be intentionally
if we intentionally feel this, okay,
here, here already.
What I'm going to do is see
I'm going
to call this logging function fine
instead of this username intentionally.
I provide wrong of this navigational
pointer exception in this case.
Right?
Intentionally.
I'm doing it
and we will do it in different days.
We still have to go to class.
You know we don't have to go,
I will tell you that.
So we continued.
Anywhere else, we can change it.
We don't need to change in class now.
See what was going to happen this time,
even without putting a lot less.
We can override. This takes in the class.
Okay. How
how is it possible?
Miracle, maybe.
Or the scenario
can be worked without working? Yes.
If you outsource your project, it.
If you outsource your project, then you to
then are just failures.
No, no worries.
Let me check.
Very rudimentary, dangerous point.
So this should be this one.
Great.
Now I want to pass hardcoded data
for a moment
in here.
Let me check with scenario with security
this 2.0 or do we go here and check smoke?
Funny not it makes it look this time
what is going on
with scenario?
It is taking
maybe maybe a couple of scenarios
we have with destiny,
maybe a couple of scenarios.
We have a need.
I want to make a train
which is not failing in this in any
let me do it for this one
that we change this name for the scenario.
Just give me a moment and it says hello.
Okay, give me any condition.
Give me any condition
which I can put here, which is,
which is a wrong any condition.
I'm giving just random error.
One from here and from here.
Right.
And then the
executed from here flows administration.
The project loaded.
See that
finally.
Finally. See,
it says here, build the failure.
Can you see this test run
one failure zero.
And there's one skillset right?
So when your best case rate
when your best case three
is actually feeling
it gives you will failure it wins.
Build is not success.
And if it is not success you cannot deploy
your go to for the environment.
Understood this
understood this
deep fine.
So now first
let me change before I forget this.
We we are going
we are going to heart with end point.
We are going to find now you see
now you see here in my smoke.
Right in my smoke. If you see. Great.
Tell me how many
a how many reports we are generating
is of not
how many reports we are generating
is just one HDMI output.
Basic rate.
But but there is
another report that is another report
which we can generate
when we actually execute our gives
graph on dot.
Excellent point.
Excellent input. Now let's see.
Let's see this report. Right, Let's see.
This would be the best part of this class
pretty see
here we have to write this report
would be my decent report.
This report would be my days,
decent report.
And I am awaiting this report under my
under my target folder
with the name key component.
Jason
understood.
Understood.
One point I missed
it is taking care of your report
that you're generating.
It will also take care of the report,
generating this pretty
is also a report part where it takes
care of the report in your console.
You see all these steps
which are printing when we execute,
you know, all the steps
printing in the console. This
in this console, when
you see all the steps of printing
it is because of this pretty
so it generates the reported
it will get it takes care of that
their reported console or read
this one is issued
and this one this one is good report
all read
now now we are going to follow one guy
today
one video is very good.
We are going to follow this guy.
This guy did a very good job for us.
Is it second report?
Yes, it is our second beginning.
So today we are going
follow one very intelligent, very good guy
who help us in creating a one
very beautiful report.
Okay, now see, who is this guy?
Open browser.
Open your browser.
Everyone open your browser.
And right here. Good. Kimber,
Meghan
report subject to December seven Report.
Everyone searched for this government
report.
What can you see?
This guy Damien's.
I don't know how to spell this name.
Damien's depending.
Whatever it is, it is Damien
This guy. Damien.
Everyone is the first to link Damien.
Click on it.
Click on it, click on it.
This beautiful guy is Damien from Public.
Can you see this part?
So, Solomon, you look like Damien.
See? Excellent.
Right,
Right
to see, isn't it?
Isn't it?
All right, Bye bye. Bye.
Now. You'll see here.
Now you'll see here it says Melbourne
Release Plugin Maven Release plugin.
Great.
Prepare for next to development edition
right now.
See these guys still active.
Last updated on November 13th 2021.
Can you see?
Okay now you see here
we have to use his
plugin this is his plugin.
This is his plugin.
We have been used by before
using this bulky plugins.
What he created for us right.
We have to do just one thing.
See here it says
Melbourne model for the converted body.
Put this into your next image
see how do you know JenWagner
why is this guy is this guy is explaining
because he knows better.
Elwin has all the Einstein books why he's
giving this instruction, what he sees.
He says Maven model for the cucumber
reporting.
Put this in to your bomb dot
assembly and run in re and verify.
So Consumer Reports will be generated
in target
Katoomba HDR will report
it is explaining you this thing
in you case.
So what we have to do we have to use
this could do more reporting in our medium
to right then we have to run MBM verify
so this report will be generated.
I met my target folder, my main target.
There will be Uber HD will report on read
on. Right.
Can you see?
No, not look it closely Now
look at this closely.
See here you see Braille maven
central reader 5.6.2 Right.
Going to see this is the Virgin Red.
This is the Virgin. This is the big find.
Don't do anything
read not. Don't do anything.
What I'm seeing now, see here,
you'll see from this plugin to this plugin
in, someone sent me the link
and I can share the link with him.
Which
one minced
or any one.
And by the way, there is no competition
there to whoever is sending the first will
the prize so take is not going to give you
any of any prize for sending the link.
But it's going to happen.
Disappointments every work.
Nice.
I still remember 14 minutes
soil read in this photograph.
In his photograph
I saw first I thought to 1 billion
It is attending my class, getting a black
three piece tuxedo kind of thing
like this
also and it's the first impression
rate is the last impression
and I was willingness to know
that we generated something like this
just an upper the sports upper
features linear right
because you want to hide
your millennial status
that's what you're showing yourself
as a millennial.
Great claim here.
Excellent Like it.
Fine.
So now we see this particular part,
this black part.
They see. So
this part
we already have a budget maven plugin
maven should display in part
we already have or not any.
The only thing the only thing
we don't have is this line is to failure.
Ignored. What does it mean?
It means that if I'm executing my way
deep like this because this
any one of my best is free rate is still
it will allow me
to execute my for test cases.
It will allow me
to execute my further discourses.
So best failure
ignore do I do keep this particular
I need to
keep this particular line in my bottom
right
exit will find the right after
my includes take
include state means the last include
not the forced include otherwise
you will eventually end up inside
include I would say to my included here
pasted here understood
all the geniuses understood
but I will have to read this test failure
ignore outside clause take
do it, do it
as everyone
it makes obvious
they're going to know
now after they see this plugin
you already have here.
Great. This plugin you already have here.
It means this part
you already have getting
correct case.
This building already have this plugins.
You already have this plugin,
you already read.
Now copy this plugin concrete.
This plugin builders plugin not plugins
copy plugin to plugging,
copy this plugin to plugin
and then and then paste to this plugin
right after this particular.
Like you'll see
I'm just giving you this piece to read.
You know, you can identify it.
See this plugin that we have?
I'm going to make another plugin
take from here, so this is my another bit.
You'll see this is my under.
Can you see everyone
again?
No questions for Raed.
Please read Fine
by Shall we start now?
Shall we start?
Can you show from which part
you copied the one.
Not on the second plugin.
Read this plugin.
See from this plugin to particular.
This plugin
read from this plugin to this plugin.
Just copy it and then listed.
So the first plugin that we entered.
Okay, this is black.
I'm not able to see your comments
because a lot of code in front of me
in the chain.
Nice,
nasty, nasty.
Here.
It says group ied make dark monster part.
Can you see Ghobadi here?
Needless to talk
right
Melvin Cucumber reporting
This is the artifact.
Maybe we don't need to change group
in activity or read
group obedient or directly.
We don't need to change it is virgin
check virgin above for all the geniuses.
This is not the virgin name Chick.
What it about?
It means are to check virgin above.
Okay, let me go in the Chrome browser See?
Because he provided this in the link.
That's he says check virgin above.
So above means here.
Which virgin is this
right now it is 5.6.2
race.
Can you see
5.16562216 56.2
16v 56.2.
Everyone is using their ordinary click
with a actual word.
So here he is.
We have to rate 5.6.295.6 to understood
understood everyone.
Now this feeds this phase.
We are not going to verify why
because here he will see.
Here he was seeing.
If you see played
yet it sees run and then verify.
Are we running ambient verify
we are running clean.
And second thing what we are running
we are verifying of your testing
first right.
So the phase should be is
the phase should be test All right
The phase should be test
so far.
So what everyone
know it says project name.
What is the project name?
It is simply
my project name is a
Jared was for let's see,
whatever the project number 11
find it would take the same name.
What behavior
in chat in his bachelor carrying
it says This is optional.
This is optional is skip so remove
because this is option.
This is optional.
So removed
that is again I'm saying this is optional.
So remove name number. My bin.
My in my code.
This is line number 99. I'm removing my
look.
I'll read.
All right, guys.
Now this input directly
this input that it receives.
This is my project directly under under
project that it it is just some reports.
I do not have any decent reports.
Silva.
Silva, please give me just 15 minutes
and then we all will be on break again.
I'll give you a big break.
Not even for minute, just 9 minutes,
because we we're something
very in between of something
very important already.
There's one just 8 minutes.
Just 8 minutes.
So, guys,
we do not have any decent reports, images,
some reports in our plugin date.
So let's remove this part. Also
line number 102 after slash
that is adjacent to post
I had removed from Slash.
So now you see
I have just these two points.
Can you see these
have just these two points.
Can everyone see this?
And then my decent file
would be my report by trade.
So support
wildcard spaten would be gorgeous.
And so I will keep it as it is.
And after this.
After this.
This part is optional.
So from here to this point,
before configuration, from classification
that it be
built the line above configuration,
everything is optional.
Simply building
again, I am doing it
from classification line number 108 in my
my screen 108 line number
in one dwindling number my screen
above configuration
line build line, remove
everything understood
and this everyone what I did
find now
still sees 5.6.2 and read made
Let's reload project
Let's reload
the project.
Once you reload blade Once you reload
let me first run it to immediately.
So when we run in being clean, this should
give me the build success message.
Build success will success.
It means it is working fine.
See for me also read
but actually it is working fine.
Okay.
But actually it is working fine.
So now let me go back here.
If we make it through test
because I want to show you something.
Let me go here.
I want to use this particular synergy.
Great. So it would be this print.
Let's see, scenario would be like batch
11 point.
Let's take this scenario
into consideration
or point
this part I'm providing in my grade,
and this time I'm going to run this part.
See, now you'll see after execution
completed, it was still rotating
and it gave me one message.
Code maven Kumba reporting
generate execution for the project.
Each item is delivered, prayed about
to generate the report and you'll see
January 23 Team name The master talked
to my reporter Pastor prayed.
It generates one report and the target
to produce and contains one features.
Now let me show you this.
Let me show you this beautiful report. See
if I here
can you see to commit a team of reports,
guys, see how many reports?
We have generated a lot of reports. Right.
Let's dig this one report
what have you features.
You see what begged for
the steps for failure.
We have a lot of reports.
Okay, but. But.
But see, see?
Right click here.
Open in browser called Chrome.
Now see, there you go.
There you go.
Based.
Can you see the report?
Everyone
Great
if you want to check is features here
features.
It says one feature positive
reporting rate is tips.
Scenario one.
Scenario positive hundred percent
is steps three, steps 100% correct.
Now click on this log in feature,
click on this log in feature.
This is your background.
In this background.
This is the step.
This is your scenario.
This is your hook.
This is your step.
This is again, your hook
scenario name is bench 11 rate
validate to me
before hooks three, then it steps,
then after hooks it, execute
and you see three bust for log in feature
scenario one month to three time
duration
is this No way, no skip, no pending,
no undefined
date.
Very easy to understand
what time you executed
did with time it job in this project.
How many discussions just one chrome
features click here it says
feature from peg see big statistics
and you see is smoke executed
match executed.
It is based the statistics here
100% execution
you see bars 200% of 100%.
Graphical reports
rate raise, graphical steps.
Fine, click on steps.
You'll see this show for every step 100%.
It means how every step executed 100%.
Execution of every average duration
is 2.07 3 milliseconds.
Maximum duration was 5.937.
To start, the application indicates
total duration
is this one played failures?
You see, because there is no failure
rate students.
So for any question in this part,
what I've explained
just now,
even I have read
when I have a rating policy,
I'm on saving grade.
Let's find the big time to update the
No, I don't have this much operation.
No, no, no.
See, that's the problem.
I told you in my trade under plugins,
we have to add plugin
under plugins we have to add plugin.
You see my build and plugins is there
and then plugin is under plugins.
Your plugin is the plugins.
There's the problem
I get.
I showed you. Right.
This is the gap
I gave you there after plugin.
You have to add another blending.
Yeah.
Great.
All right, guys, any question?
Could you show your report, please?
Yes, sir.
Why not? There you go.
This is my report.
Is there anyone who has any question
about this particular part
of this
that you see here?
This features bags and steps and veneers,
all four on the top right
corner, top
right corner and just click on tags.
Then you will see this data statistics.
I'm assuming my report
might be a little different than other.
Does this answer
then you have to become a Damien.
So I think in that case,
if you were to make your report unique,
you have to become a Damien
made master.
No or report was added
only one in your error rate.
I can see that.
But what is the entity in the console?
First, instead of taking this matter
in the report for us
to edit in the console,
reading the console why it is that it is,
you will see that caused in the console
or right
for us to commit this code
before anyone ask about it.
But code is committed.
All right, guys, do we just abbreviated
naming that a class or gender dependency?
No. We will update a big name in the donor
class.
We will update our dependency as well.
Don't worry.
I will tell you this tomorrow
I will delete the story
of any commitment.
Project means I'm committing every single
to every single plus segment.
Okay.
All right, fine.
Okay, next.
Now let's I think
please continue to study.
Right.
And tomorrow, hopefully, we'll be
completing our class and only moderately
because we have just two or three topics
to meaning we will cover those
3 to 4 topics and then we will be back.
All right. Find it.
Get everyone.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
I do not. My throat is completely damaged.