All right, guys, let's get started
with our last class of selenium, right.
How is everybody doing?
What's going on, guys?
I hope everyone is doing good.
Yeah, I'm good.
Thank you.
Last class with me, guys.
Then after this,
I think you'll continue with tests
and you'll start with cucumber.
The homework is in progress.
You miss me?
I'll miss you too, guys. Okay.
I'll probably be on the mock interviews,
but I doubt it.
I'll see if I can take some interviews
at the at the end of the course.
No, I don't think I will be teaching
any other subject
with you guys.
And never before.
Thank you.
Thank you. That's because of Michael.
That's not because of me.
Can I interview you?
Okay.
If I interview you, you'll probably fail,
Michael.
Okay.
Now, remember, remember, you need to fire.
You need to find a job in two
weeks, right?
So that I can.
So that I can get you a pizza.
If not you getting everyone
a pizza, right?
That was a deal, right?
Okay. All right.
This is recording, guys. Okay.
This is recorded one more time.
All right, Michael, I need to check.
I need to check your graduation date.
Okay.
Oh, wow. Okay, everyone.
Everyone is against Michael now.
Don't you grab.
Yeah.
After you pass
the mock interview. Exactly.
What if I don't take Michael's interview?
Then he'll probably pass.
But we'll see.
We'll see.
Well, Michael passed the mock interview,
but failed the real one, too.
What?
What's going on, guys?
Good. Okay, so I will prepare the pizza.
Okay, Mike, just.
Just make sure you don't
send me in the interview, okay?
That.
That's not a good
that's not a good practice.
Or sent creepy voicemail.
Yeah, that.
That works too. You.
I didn't specify
what kind of jobs you're supposed to get.
Okay, well, we'll see
what kind of jobs you'll be applying.
Okay.
All right.
All right, guys. So
let's get started
with the last class
of our selenium, right?
So we'll be going over the page model
today.
I'll show you the initial designs
of the framework that you will be working
in a real job.
Okay, So like, I've seen like
80% of the time, I've seen the same design
as I will be showing you right now
at work.
And we have the same design
at work as well.
So it's pretty popular design
that everybody uses at work.
So and it's not that difficult. Okay.
But before we dive in, let's do a quick
recap of what we've done yesterday.
Okay.
What kind of topics did we
did we cover yesterday,
guys?
All right.
We we went over the uploading the file.
All right, So how do we.
Okay,
so we went over the JavaScript executable
right?
How do we upload the file guys?
See? Okay, it was simply sand keys.
Right.
So what do we take
a look at before we do that?
Guys, whenever we try to choose,
whenever we try to click on the choose
file or upload the file,
okay, So we
would need the path of our file, right?
And then we need to take a look
at the input tag.
Right. So once it has that input tag,
then you will be able to send keys to that
element.
Right? Pretty easy.
So what if sand keys doesn't work?
Guys? What?
What are you going to use then?
Actions.
If keys doesn't work, you will be
you should be using the robot class right.
Okay.
All right.
What about a JavaScript execute or guy?
So what do we know?
What what can we do with JavaScript,
execute or guy?
So what is JavaScript executed in general?
It's a library, right?
It's a library.
Okay.
The library that presents
the present is selenium,
right?
Okay. It's an interface. Good.
So we could do scroll up and down right?
It executes different programing.
Languages like Java,
Python, C
sharp, right.
Okay, we can open a new tab.
We can scroll up and down right?
We can highlight that element, right?
We can.
And then what we can do is
we can scroll to a specific element
right?
Okay.
So JavaScript
executed as a little bit of different,
a little bit of a difference script.
You have to downcast it to your driver
and then there is
a built in script that you have to
you have to use in order to perform
some actions.
Right? So what about the click guys?
When are we going to use the JavaScript,
click JavaScript, execute
or click
when regular click doesn't work, right?
So how many ways
of clicking on the element did we learn?
Guys? Three. Right.
So we have JavaScript executed, clicked,
we have a regular click and then
what was the third one
from the actions class.
Right. Okay, there we go.
Oh, right.
Okay, guys.
Yep. And we have
what's what's the correct answer?
What kind of functions you can handle.
So that question.
Okay, so you can answer that question,
execute script and execute
async script, right?
Because
we talked about JavaScript,
Execute is saying that it
has only two different methods, right?
But if the interviewer is talking
about the actual actions as functions,
then you need to tell them
what kind of actions you can perform.
Okay, So you have to
you have to create a conversation
between you and your interviewer, right?
It's not just you answering questions
that are being asked, right?
So you have to sometimes
you have to ask them clarifying questions
so that you know what to actually
tell them.
Okay.
All right.
Any other questions, guys?
Okay.
If no other questions,
then we can get started
with page object model.
Okay.
So did anyone do a research on page
object model
guys, what is the page object model?
Why we need a page object model
and what does it help us to do?
Yeah, well, not yet, right? Not.
Not yet.
No. Hands on the keyboard and hand.
Focus on the slack.
Right.
Okay,
so we're creating an object of every page.
Okay, good.
It's a design principle.
Okay, What else?
What else?
It's a design pattern. Yes.
All right, well, Page,
there should be a separate page class.
Okay, very good One.
An application from one place to another.
Okay.
Writing are elements
where I using page factor.
Okay. Very good.
All right.
So page object model. Right.
So it's a design pattern.
All right.
So basically, we will be designing
our project by using this model.
Okay.
Page object
model is a pattern for enhancing
test maintenance
and reducing your code duplication.
Okay.
So it's going to help us to
to make a lot of things reusable.
And you don't have to duplicate them
every time you are starting
or you're performing any actions
or you're executing it.
Test case. Okay.
So, so
basically what we will be doing right now,
we will be dividing our project
into four different packages.
Okay.
So the four different packages will be
it's going to be your
base class,
it will be your common utilities,
it's going to be your pages
and it's going to be your tests.
Okay.
These four.
So let me actually open
this thing
and see.
ia0, all right.
So four packages, right?
So let's check my art skills in here.
So we're going to be having four packages
in here
in our project. Go.
Okay.
So basically, guys,
what what's happening in the page
object model is
we will be having a separate class
for each and every page
that we will be working on.
Okay. So let's say in here,
let's go back here.
Let's refresh 12.
That's right.
So whenever we navigate to this page,
we already know that
this is a web page, right?
This is a log in page that we need
to enter our username password,
and we need to click on log in so
that we can we're able to log in, right?
So anything that is any elements
that we will be interacting on this page,
we will be storing it in a separate class.
Okay,
So everything will be checked separately
so that it is organized
and you will not be able to
you it's going to make your life easier
so that you don't duplicate anything.
Okay.
And we'll go one by one in here.
So first of all, let's use this one.
Okay, In here.
First of all, let's go over the
test.
This package.
All right,
What can be the base of our tests?
So what are we actually doing?
Every time, whenever
we start our execution or whenever
we start our test case.
So we're actually opening the browser,
right?
So we're launching the browser.
So basically what we're doing is
we are initializing our web driver, right?
So here what we can do,
we can put
open the browser, right?
Or the launch the browser in here,
what else?
So we open the browser.
So every time in the test case, so we open
the browser, we performed an action.
What's going to happen next?
No, no, no.
We already perform actions, guys. Okay?
We we open the browser,
we navigate it to the URL, right?
We performed a lot of actions.
And then what's
going to happen in the end?
We simply quit the browser, right?
So we open the browser and quit.
The browser is going to be our phase
based thing to do.
Okay?
This is going to be our baseline, right?
So quit the
browser
here and within three sit here.
Right. Okay.
So this is going to be our base test base
package. Okay.
So we will be adding something else
in the test phase.
You guys going to be doing it later on?
Okay.
Because you will be taking screenshots,
you will be taking some
you will be doing some other actions
before you open
and after
or before you close your browsers.
Okay.
But so now let's keep it very simple.
Opening the browser and closing
the browser is going to be our baseline
of our pattern and design.
Okay, So the second one in here
is going to be our util.
Okay, so utility
utility package, utility package.
And here,
let's take this over here.
Okay.
So what do we have inside
our utility packages, guys?
So what can be the
the common things that we can add in here?
So first of all, the common
methods, right?
The common methods are
drivers will be initialized
in here, right, guys, don't forget.
So whenever you are opening
and closing the browser,
your driver is going to be initialized
in here.
Okay, But
are you talking about the actual chrome
driver and Firefox driver
libraries?
Okay, so first of all, we're
going to have common methods.
All right.
What else can we have in here? So
so common methods are like
the really using
are we using methods that you can perform
some actions on the web page?
Right.
So sometimes whenever you start
guys, whenever you guys start
API's, you will be
having some common methods
for APIs as well.
Okay.
So I'll put here API
common methods, and then after that,
whenever you start with a database,
with a database testing guys,
you will have some common methods
to connect to the database,
to execute some queries
and to close some connections and so on.
And you can also include here
database utils in here as well.
Okay.
So these kind of
common classes
you will be having inside the utilities.
Okay.
Any questions so far, guys.
Constants configures constants they
they will we can actually put them in the
in the utility as well.
Okay.
But constants those
you don't have to have them
in the utility.
Okay but it's up to you guys
how you want to implement it.
But I think whoever is going
to be going over the frameworks,
you guys will be putting this inside
the util class.
Okay.
But configurator, I think
if I'm not mistaken, I'm not sure, guys,
how they're designing right now.
It might be in
the test phase as well. Okay.
But right now, as I said, guys, let's keep
it simple.
Don't rush into config spreaders
and constants right now, but just keep it
simple.
Let's try to understand
how the actual design works.
Okay? All right.
So now utility is fine, test
phase is fine.
So now we will be jumping on the pages.
Okay, So pages is going to be our third
package where we will be
having classes
for each and every web page.
Okay.
So let's say we have a log in page
and here
we will be having a class separately
for this login page. Okay.
And what we will be having in those login
page pages,
we will be only having the web elements.
Okay.
So what we're going to do,
we will be storing all the elements
from one page that we will be interacting
with inside one class.
Okay, so let's say we're interacting
with username, password
and log in and here where is
this located is located in the login page.
So what we're going to do,
we will be creating a login page class
and we will store
all the elements
that we will be interacting with.
Okay, so username element, right?
And then
password element
and then log in
button element.
Okay. So
and then whenever will log in, Right.
So whenever will log in in here
once the password,
I forgot the password
but whenever will log in guys,
whenever we log in
we will be landing on the dashboard page.
Right. So. Okay. Thank you.
Let me put this
see. All right.
So whenever we are logged in, right,
so we will be seeing a dashboard page.
So anything we interact
with on the dashboard page,
we will be storing that elements
inside that dashboard page class.
Okay. Is that clear?
Got any questions in here?
Okay, good.
All right, so the last one and here
what we will be doing, we will be
performing an actual tests.
Okay?
So this is going to be our test package
where
we will be performing actual actions.
Okay.
So, so now, guys,
if you look in here, so we have
we already know where we are
opening our browser, right?
We know we have common methods in here.
We already have the elements.
The only thing we have to do
is to actually perform actions.
Okay?
So we have elements.
We have opening the browser.
We even have the common methods or
any methods to perform the actions, right?
So the only thing we need to do
is to implement them
inside this test package.
Okay, so let's say
we're, we're doing a log in page
testing, right?
So what we will be doing in here,
we will have a log in page test
class, okay?
And you will perform actions
if your any if you're working on dashboard
page, Right.
So dashboard
a task class and you will be performing
actions in here as well.
Okay.
Any questions, guys?
So pages. Yes.
So pages will only store the elements.
Okay.
Any other questions
before we move forward?
All right.
Like no questions. Right?
Okay.
So let me minimize this
and let's open up and you
noting here
with class 12, right.
So page object model of this.
So yes, seems
kind of unnecessary right now.
Yeah, I guess so.
It will
you'll see how it's going to reduce
your duplication
and it will keep everything organized.
Okay.
So Page object modeler, right
in here.
So basically in here, page
object model is what?
It's a design pattern, right?
Which allows us to
maintain our tests
and reduce the code duplication.
Right.
Is a design
pattern
which allows us to
enhance
maintenance
and reduce
our code duplication.
Okay.
All right.
So the main advantages of the page
object model guys are here
as let's put the
Vantage's
page object model in here
first of all, it is code reusability.
Okay, So basically code reusability.
So let's go back.
Or is that art that I created in here?
Okay.
That basically all the elements, let's say
we have ten,
ten page classes in here.
So basically,
if you identified one element
that can be reusable in different,
different test cases,
you don't have to create
that element again, right? So
in our previous
executions, you can see that, right?
So let's see, this is the thing.
But in our previous executions, guys,
if you remember, whenever I am performing
any actions on this web page,
I have to create a main method.
Again, what I have to do, I have to locate
the username and password elements.
Again, I have to launch the browser again.
So everything we're doing again and again
in order to perform
some action later on, right.
In this case, you won't be doing
you won't be creating your elements
over over again, and you won't be
launching and initializing
your web driver again and again.
Okay.
So the second one is going to be code
maintainability, right?
So this is going to be very easy for you
maintainability.
So this is going to be easier
for you to actually maintain your code
because everything is going
to be organized in separate packages.
So you will be knowing
what's going on and where.
Right.
So if you look in your errors, let's
say your no such element exception,
you know what elements is failing
and you already know what page you need
to go and take a look at that element.
Okay.
The other one is the object repository.
Okay. So
as I said, guys, each page will be defined
as a Java class, right?
So we will be keeping each and every page
inside the separate classes.
So so
we will be storing all the elements
inside those
repositories.
So one class for one page
is going to be called repository
in this case.
Okay.
And of course,
the last
one is going to be your readability
where it's going to be really easy
to read your code, really easy
to follow your code, what is going on
and where everything is coming from.
Okay.
But if you look in any of these
so this seems like
everything is a little bit of a spaghetti
in here, right?
So if I'm not, I don't remember
which one we've done.
It was pretty.
The thing was this one.
Yeah.
So anything we've done like this guy,
so it looks like it's
a little bit of a spaghetti in here.
So a lot of different code,
a lot of different variables and
a lot of different initial.
These stations again and again.
Right? So.
All right.
Okay.
So now, guys, so now how to
actually design, right? So
page object model guys
in order to design the page output model,
there's two ways to do this.
Okay.
So there one way is the page object model.
Without the page factory,
and the other way
is the page object model
with the page factors.
Okay.
And I'm going to go over what page factory
is, how we're going to implement that.
Okay. So
how to
implement, okay,
a object model
without
page Factory
and the second one page object
model with page 50.
Okay.
All right, guys.
So so
basically,
let me actually put this in here as well.
Page Factory Guys is a simple class
which gives us an opportunity
to interact with
with our stored elements inside
each class.
Okay, So page Factory
is a class
which allows us
to interact with
store elements in each class.
Okay, so let's put this in here.
We'll see how this is actually implemented
a little bit later.
Okay? All right.
So now, guys,
what I am going to do, I'm going to start
creating
the packages that
I just mentioned in orders
that I think is behind this.
So let's see. Yeah,
I just mentioned in here.
So we will be going over these one by one.
Okay.
So what I am going to do in here,
I'm going to go ahead and
create a new package or
that's fine, can have inside the syntax.
So what I will do or create a pages
package.
Okay, then
create a test package.
And what I'm going to do is
utils package
and then
I will do a taste test base package.
Okay. So
now just, just listen for now.
Okay guys,
because I will be jumping all over
all of these packages that I just created
and you will,
you might get confused
whenever I'm doing that.
Okay. All right, guys.
So remember what?
Remember
I told you guys to create two functions
to open and close the browser, Right?
So I hope you guys did this
because we will be using that right now.
Okay,
So what I am going to do in here, I'm
going to I'm going to create a new class
inside my test place.
Okay.
So what I will do and here
I will create a base class
in here.
So this is going to be our baseline.
Okay.
So what I will do, I'll quickly
create to two functions
to open and close the browsers.
Okay?
So what I'm going to do in
here, I'll do let's do public
void right.
And say open with
specific your.
All right.
So if we want to open with specific URL,
where do we want to specify
that URL guys
as a parameter?
Right. Easy. Right guys.
So what we can do and here we can
have a parameter as a string data
type, right?
Euro. There we go.
So now what I want to do.
So in order for me to open up
a browser, guys,
what do I need to do?
So we need to set properties first, right?
So we'll let's go back to any class,
I guess, in here.
Okay, guys.
So we're setting up the properties, right?
So what we're doing,
we open up the browser in here,
we're navigating to the euro.
So these are the three lines of code
that I need here, right?
So I'm setting up the property.
I am initially launching the browser
and I am navigating to the euro, right?
So what we can also do, any time
we open up the browser and navigate
to the euro, what we can also do is
we can set an implicit weight
and we can also maximize our window.
Okay, so what I'm going
to do in here, Driver Dot
manage the windows and
maximize this, Okay?
And what I can do, I don't need this
because if I do this, it's
going to open up on the net on this screen
right now.
So and then what we can also do is
driver, let's manage
the timeouts right?
Implicit wait for 20 seconds in here.
Right? And
let's go kind of
seconds, Right.
Okay.
So we set up the property, we have the
drivers set up and we have
we maximize our window
and navigate to the URL
and we set the implicit way, right?
So this is how we open
with a specific URL.
So now let's go ahead and
create another method
to tear everything down.
Right?
Okay.
So now, guys,
I want to tear down everything.
You also put this outside the method
that is vertical.
Yeah.
So that's that was my next question, guys.
Since I don't have to write,
I don't want to initialize
my web driver again and again.
What we can do, we can simply go ahead
and put that outside of our methods.
Right.
So public static, right.
Let's try for
driver and here
and what we want to do,
we want to initialize
inside
inside our open was specific zero method
and now in here guys so
in here what I want to do is simply write.
I want to quit my browser.
Right.
But what if guys sometimes
in between our execution
or after we open up the URL
and we initialize our web driver,
sometimes something happens
and our driver gets to.
And now guys, what's going to happen then?
So what if we get another pointer
exception from our driver?
Guys?
Exactly.
So we need to make sure
we need to put a condition
where we check that our driver not null.
Right? So
in here, only when my driver
is not now, only
then what I'm going to do,
I'm going to go ahead and
quit my browser.
Okay?
All right.
And let's actually put these
methods as
static methods.
That's fine.
Okay. So now, guys,
does anybody know what this one code
I want to leave a description
of what my my method will do in here.
Okay.
So what I'll what I can put in here.
This method will navigate
to a website
by the given zero.
Right.
Does anybody know what this one is
called? Yes,
it is a comment, but in tech world,
you won't be calling this as a comment.
It's not an annotation right.
Or let me leave this in here as well.
So this method
will quit
and open
browser right.
Okay, guys.
So this description in here
on top of the methods
that you will be creating
in the future, guys,
it is called a job at the
do not forget this
because you will be using this term a lot
when you find a job.
Okay.
Yep. Java.
Exactly.
Let's put it in here.
Actually it is a window.
Okay.
All right.
So any questions on these methods, guys?
Okay, Everything is clear.
All good. Right.
So now what I am going to do
inside my utils package,
I'm going to create another class.
Okay?
To create another class in here,
and I will name it as common
methods.
Okay, so this is common methods.
This class will
have all the common methods
that that are reusable for us.
Okay. So
if we have time today, we will be creating
we can create couple of common methods
that we that are reusable in the future.
Okay, So
now, guys in here.
So let's say I have a method and I want to
I want to have an access to the web
driver.
Guys, how would I do this in here?
So I am in the common methods.
So what I want to do,
I want to have an access to the web driver
that we initialize interface plus
exactly what we need to do.
We simply need to extend that
class, right?
So what I am going to do extends
space class, right?
So this is the base class
that we have inside our test base, right?
So now whenever we create methods,
if we want to use the driver right inside
our common methods, we already have it
initialized inside the base class.
Okay, so you only initialize
your web driver once in here.
Okay.
So you already see in here, guys, that
we are we using the same code already?
So this line of code in here will help us
to initialize the driver in here
and you can reuse this inside our common
methods.
Okay.
Any questions on this, guys?
Okay, cool.
All right.
So the point
because okay, so
because common methods
they are considered the methods
on on actual actions on the web elements
in the base class.
You're opening and closing the browser.
Do not performing any actions
on this specific element.
Okay.
So, so
your baseline is going to be opening
and closing and your common methods
will indicate the actions
towards the elements on the web page.
Okay.
All right, cool.
Okay, So now let's move to the pages
package.
Okay.
So what I will do in here,
I'll create a new class
and name it as a log in page.
Okay, so we have a log in page and here.
Right.
So what I will do.
So as I said before,
so all the elements that are
that we
will be interacting on a specific page,
we will be storing them inside
each and each separate class, right?
So right now I need the elements
that I will be interacting
on the log in page.
Okay.
So if I go back in here and let's look out
from here.
So this is my login page.
So there's three different elements
that I want to interact with, right?
So first of all,
what I want to show you in here, guys,
I want to show you the page object model
without the page practice.
Okay?
So what I will be doing in here,
we already know that
we will be interacting with three elements
username, password and log in button.
Right?
So what I will do,
I will start creating those web elements.
Okay, so I'm going to do public
web element
username field is equal to
driver.
Okay, so if I do driver in here guys,
I don't have access to driver.
How would I get access to driver Guys
in here?
Okay.
Extent What are we extending guys?
Are we extended common methods or we,
we can extend the paste class.
Why common methods and not base class
based class?
Exactly right.
Common methods
have the base class driver as well.
Right.
So if we extend right,
so we if we extend the common methods,
we will have access to web driver
and we will have access to common methods
which we will be performing
throughout the execution.
Right.
So if I go ahead in here, extends
common methods.
We're having access to the base class
and we're having access
to all the common functions
that we will be creating
inside the common methods.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys?
All right, So we have a base class.
We have common methods.
So now we have a page class, right?
So what kind of inheritance am I having in
here?
We're having a multi level inheritance.
Right? Exactly.
Very good.
Okay, so how can you achieve
the multiple inheritance guys
with an interface?
Good.
Okay, beautiful.
All right, so let's go back in here.
So now we have an access to driver, right?
So a driver that
find element, right?
So let's inspect
this.
We have an idea in here.
So grab this idea real quick. I
So this is my this my first element.
So public
web element
password field
is equal to the driver
assigned element by
let's see if we have an idea.
Okay. So
yeah.
Okay.
Then the last element that we need to
have is
logged in button
is equal to driver thought find element.
Let's see what we got in here.
We have an ID, so the fact
and pasted into.
Okay, so now guys what we did in
here we stored that elements
only corresponding to the log in page.
Okay so we have a login page class.
We have login page elements
stored inside our login page plus.
Is that clear?
Guys, any questions on this?
Okay.
All right, good.
Okay, guys.
So now let's go ahead.
No, no, no. For now.
You're still listening, guys.
No, no typing.
Okay, So now, guys, what
I will do in here, So I have a base class.
I have common
methods, and I have the log in page.
So the only thing left for me
is to go ahead
and actually execute
some actions or execute some test case.
Right.
So what I will do, I'll create a new class
inside the test package.
Okay.
And I will say log in.
Test.
Okay.
So this is going to be my class in here.
So for now, what I'll do,
I will create a main main method in here.
In here
so that we have an execution point.
All right. Okay.
So now, guys, in here,
how do I start my execution?
Guys,
how will I be able to have an access
to the setup
method that we created inside the base
class?
Except
without extending the login page? Guys
create an object.
Do I have to create an object?
And here does
it static. Right?
So since it is a static, what we can do,
you can simply call that method
by the class name.
Right?
So what I will do in here,
I'll go base class
that open with specific URL
and inside this is
what I will do.
Where is that?
You are located right here
and inside the parameters
it's going to accept one argument.
So one line of code where
we're setting up the properties, we're
launching the browser
and we're navigating to this specific URL
that we just mentioned in here.
Right? Okay.
So now what I want to do,
I want to perform some actions, right?
In order for me to perform some actions,
I need access to the elements.
Right?
So how do I have an access
to an element in here? Guys
passing books in alphabetical order.
Yeah.
So it's basically we're keeping everything
organized as much as possible, right?
So extending common methods,
I need access to my elements, guys.
So to the elements
that I will be performing actions
call.
We don't have methods, right?
I just need access to these elements.
Guys, how do I have access
to these elements from this page
for from this log in text,
we simply need to create an object, right?
So in into test
actually guys, in test page
in test classes, guys,
you won't be extending anything.
Okay.
So you will need to create an object
of a certain page, page class
so that you can use it
inside your actions.
Okay.
So what I will do in here, log in page.
Right. Log in
page is equal to new
log in page. Right.
So we created an object of that class.
So now we have access
to those elements, Right?
So what can do in here?
Login page that username field
that send keys
and I will be sending my
username right.
The second thing we want to do
is log in page
dot password field,
send keys and I'll be sending my password,
which is this weird thing in here right?
And the last thing we want to do in here
is to access my log
in button and simply
go ahead and click this.
Okay.
And after we click right.
So we won't be verifying anything for now.
But what we can do will be simply
closing that browser.
Pretty cool, right, guys?
So six line of codes in here
and you have access, you are opening
the browser, you are performing
a lot of actions in here
and you're closing everything, right?
Pretty clean
and pretty organized in here, right?
So you have four different classes
and you can perform a lot of actions,
right?
So let's now run this and see if
if we can have some good
outcome in here.
All right.
Opened there.
So you happened very, very fast. Right?
So it inserted the username and password.
It clicked on log in
and then it quit the browser right.
All right, guys, any questions on this?
Any questions on the on the design?
Any questions on any of what we've done
on the first half guys?
Why do we have these separate packages
to keep everything organized nice, right?
So you keep everything organized
so that you don't duplicate,
okay, You don't duplicate
and you won't be reusing a lot of stuff.
All right?
So if you can see in keep here,
you initialize your web driver
only once in base class
and you can use this in logging task.
You can use this
in common methods in the future
and you can use this in log
in page a class.
Right. So
this is very useful for you
to reduce the duplication and
to keep everything organized.
Look at different test cases.
We keep adding them to the same package
and different class.
Absolutely right. Yes.
So if you're working on a different page,
Right.
So you're going to add
a different page in here
and you're going to add the different page
test in here.
Okay.
So if we could keep that organized.
So you need to know the basics
of that action
with selenium
right after this, your you will be
you will be good to go
with creating everything.
Okay.
I'll show you guys how to do this
with Page Factory, and I'll show
you guys how to have different
classes in here as well.
Okay.
Yes, we we'll have more examples.
We will have more examples for now, guys.
Any questions?
Yeah, if if no questions.
I'm planning to give a break, guys.
So let's see.
This seems like no other
questions so far, right?
So if no questions,
let's have a break until 825.
All right.
So it's 808 right now.
So let's have a like 17 minute break.
Yeah, that's
sharp.
You can type in your question in here.
That's fine.
Common methods class.
It's empty right now.
All right.
Guess I will see you at 825.
Okay.
All right, guys.
So let's get back.
Yes, that's good advice from from Zambia.
Try, try and catch in that case
because that
that's
that's a random website, right?
It's not going to happen every time.
I think
try, try, try and catch
and see if you will be able to handle the
right.
All right, guys.
So let's get back to the page
object model now.
Right. Okay.
So we went over the packages,
the pages task test phase and utils
and went over the page
object model without the factory.
Okay, so now what
I will do, I'll show you the
what page factory is
and how to implement the page
object model with page factory.
Okay.
So what
I am going to do right now,
I'm going to create a new Java class
inside the pages, okay?
And I'll name it as
log in page
with a factory.
Okay.
And for us,
in order to get to the access to,
the driver, what we need to do,
we need to extend the common methods
right.
Okay. So
let's see.
All right.
I guess so.
For the page factor, you guys.
So it's going to be a little bit
of a different syntax in here
that we would've seen before.
Okay.
So what we are going to be doing in here,
So we're going to be using a page factory
class,
which is an invoice
built page object model concept, okay.
For for the web
Java that we're using right now.
But it is very, very opt.
Okay.
So for us,
in order to use a page factory class,
we will be using annotations at find
by okay to locate the elements.
So at sign by annotation
will help us to locate
and identify the elements.
And before guys,
if if you see in here what we used to do,
we used to have driver
that find element, right?
And then we were specifying
what we're identifying that element by.
Right. So instead of doing this
in page Factory
we will be using sign by annotation.
Okay.
And I will show you how this is done.
Okay, so let's say we are automating
the same page
as we have done in the previous example.
But right now I will be identify, find
those elements and no bit of a different.
Okay, so what I will do in here,
I will start
by my annotation of find by.
Okay, I'll put a sign by
so I'll open and close the parentheses.
Okay.
So what I am doing
and here I am trying to,
I'm trying to locate
my username, my username
textbox in here. So
what I will do.
So signed by annotation,
I open and close the parentheses.
So now inside the parentheses I need
to specify the locator that I am using.
Okay. So for the username.
For the username textbox
we were using ID right.
Which was equal to the
let me get this
here, which was equal to this.
Okay.
So once we've done this,
so now what we need to do,
we need to simply have web element
variable.
Okay, So what I'm going to do,
I'm going to do public
web element.
Okay.
And I will do
username.
Thank you. Okay.
So this is how we will be
locating the elements from now on.
Okay.
So find by annotation your
your locator, the value of the locator,
and then you need to come up with a name
for your variable.
Okay. Is that clear? Guys?
Any questions?
This is how we will be storing it.
Yes. All the all the locators work too.
I will be showing them one by.
Okay.
By username I.D..
I haven't seen that one before.
Okay. All right.
So, okay,
so identify the username textbox.
Okay, so what I am going to do now,
I will be identifying my password.
TextBox. Okay.
So again, find by annotation
in here, open and close parentheses.
So this time, instead of using that ID,
let's use the Exfat.
Okay, so I'll put the Xbox in here.
Equal sign
and I will need to insert
that Xbox in here.
Okay, so let me grab
let's see.
Okay, so the input tag in here.
So let's come up with the x path.
One input tag
and use an ID here
equal to
this.
Okay. There we go.
So we can copy this
and I'll paste it in here.
Okay.
So once pasted in here,
what you need to do,
you need to come up with
just the variable.
Okay.
All right. Any questions on this? Guess
no questions.
Yeah.
So this one, this one seems more clean
and organized, right?
Instead of doing this
every time driver find alignment.
This kind of looks
like a spaghetti as well.
But if you look at this one, it's
a little bit different
and a bit organized, right?
So let's identify our
last element in here.
So again, signed by annotation,
open and close parentheses.
So now this time, let's see
if we can generate a CSF selector in here.
Okay, so let me delete this
for the log in button.
We have an idea
what was the shortcut for IDE for CSS
Selectric us
tag the pound.
Right?
And then the value of the idea.
So we have input this and this one.
There we go.
So we found this. So this is our success.
So now let's go back in here.
The simply and here
I need to specify my locator
what I am going to do instead of typing
in that whole system, select a thing.
What I'll do, I'll just do
CCed is equal to
and then I'll just paste
in here and I'll save public
web element
log in button
right.
Okay.
So this is how we will be
storing our web elements from now on.
Okay.
So we won't be doing any drive
or find element.
We won't be doing any find elements.
We will be using ET
find by annotate options.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys, Any questions?
Driver It is ne.
Eat it. Okay.
So I'm coming to that point right now
with this driver.
We will need.
Okay, so now, guys, this is
this is the required way.
Okay,
so this is not a preferred way, guys.
Okay?
So whenever you have,
whenever you have a framework in place,
you will be using this
this format of locating the elements.
Okay.
So now, guys,
what I am going to do in here.
So what we did in here?
We just located the elements.
Okay, So what we didn't do in here,
what if it's a dropdown?
The dropdown is still an element, right?
So you can, you can simply identify
an element with this.
Right guys.
So dropdown is still an element.
So you have to, you have to locate that
element first in order to interact
with a dropdown.
Right.
Okay.
All right guys.
So what we are doing in here guys,
we're just creating third.
But what we need to do in here,
we need to initialize these variables.
Okay? So
if you look in here,
this driver find element
what it's going to do, it's
going to initialize your element
automatically.
Okay?
But when we're using the find
by annotation,
you will have to use page factory class
to initialize those elements.
Okay. So how we're going to be doing this?
So in Java guys, what do you use
to initialize the the variables?
Guys in your class
Now what do you use
in order to initialize?
What is the thing
that helps us to initialize
the variables?
Any variable guys in in Java?
What concept would I say?
Not not equal sign or anything.
What, what concept?
So let's say
I have a private variables in my class.
Okay, so how would I initialize those
encapsulation closer.
Okay.
My constructor. There we go.
Absolutely right. We
constructor to
initiate initialize our variables.
Right.
So now what I am going to do
guys, I am going to create a default
constructor in here.
I hope you guys remember
what constructor is right in Java.
So what I'll do and here I'll do public
log in with Page Factory, right?
And now this is my constructor.
So inside my constructor,
in order for me to initialize
all the variables inside this class,
I will be using Page Factory.
Okay, so what? I will.
I'll simply go type in page Factory dot
and you can see that
there are some overloaded methods.
Okay, so I'll use this method
which is which is X expecting us
to different arguments.
Okay.
So the first argument is
we need to specify what
is the object that we we will
initializing everything.
Okay, so what is the object that will
initialize all our elements? Guys
in selenium, it's a driver, right?
So what I will do,
I'll simply put a driver in here.
So the second argument that we need to
pass is which
what variables
we want to initialize, right?
Or which page of the
which variables
and which page we want to initialize.
Right. So
and in the second argument,
we can simply pass this.
Okay, so what we're doing
and here we're initializing
the elements
by the given work driver in here
and we're initializing the elements
of this specific page.
Okay. Is that clear, guys?
Any questions?
Okay, good.
All right. So.
So now we initialized everything.
So now let's go ahead and
start the actual testing.
Right.
So let me.
So what I am going to do, let me open up
a new Java class right
in Java class and say
log in, log in, Test where?
Page two.
Okay. Main method in here.
So what do we need to do in here
now, guys?
So I have my main method.
What is my next step
constructor?
So any
I want to start a test guys in here.
Okay, so we need.
Okay, so we need to call
the setting up the method, right?
So what I will do
based class, the set up
or was that open.
Right, open, open
with specific URL in here
and what we are going to do
is going to be using the same URL
paste this in here.
Right?
So now how am I getting access to the
to the elements inside this log
in page with page factor, You guys
create an object, right?
Okay, so let's create an object login page
and we can say,
okay, that's fine is equal to new
log in page session.
Right? Okay.
All right. So we have an object.
We have access to all the
all the elements,
which is in that specific page.
So now what I need to do in here,
I need to simply
go ahead and perform my actions. Right.
So this is admin.
This is going to be the password
right?
And here what I need to do,
I need to simply click okay.
The now we clicked with perform action we
we we entered username password
we clicked on log in button.
Right.
So what I want to do now
I want to go ahead and take a screenshot.
Okay.
So I want to take a screenshot in here
and then what I want to do.
So let's actually log in here quick.
Now, is this the password
should be the
password right?
And then.
Okay. All right.
So what I want to do,
I want to get this text in here.
I want to print it out in my console
and then I want
close the browser.
Okay.
So now, guys,
what screenshots
you will be doing that later on
when you start with an framework,
guys, you will be doing that later on,
but we'll see if we can create a method
for some other actions today.
If have time.
Okay.
All right, guys.
So here
I want to take a screenshot in here.
What do I need to do?
What do we use
in order to take a screenshot?
Guys?
Okay. Creating take screenshot. Okay.
What is it?
Is it a class or what?
What is it,
guys? It's an interface, right.
So we need to downcast it to driver.
Okay, very good. Okay.
So take screenshots this is equal to so
take screenshot. So
there we go.
So how do I access that driver.
Guys in here
we can simply go with base class, right?
Race class driver
because this driver is a static variable
so we don't have to create an object
of that class.
Right. Any questions on this, guys?
Is everyone clear on this?
Okay, good.
All right, so now what
we need to do, need to get the screenshot
and we need to have a file on hand.
Right?
So get screenshot as
the output of a file.
Right.
And then what we're going to have,
we will actually have
a source file on hand for you.
So let's import this class.
Okay.
So now, guys, what we need to do,
we need to simply copy and paste
right.
Let me take a look at the screenshots.
Okay?
So we've got them in here.
So what I am going to do is file
utils, right?
I'm going to copy
copy the file.
Right.
So what is the file that I'm copying
is the source file.
Right.
And I'm going to make a new file in here
and I will specify the destination.
Right.
So this destination
is going to be our screenshots folder.
So let's create another folder here,
which is our mass,
which is our project name, right?
And then what we can say
we can name it as Dashboard dot PNG
and then we can surround this
with try and catch
more actions.
Okay, So okay,
so we're going to surround this with
try and catch, right?
So now guys, what I want to do,
I want to once with logged in
once we took this screenshot,
what I need to do is I need to go ahead
and get this text in here
and print it out in my console.
How would I do this
now, what would be my next step
exactly?
We need to create a dashboard page
class first.
Why Are we doing this guys?
Why do we need to create a dashboard page
class?
Organize? Okay,
so we can sort the elements
but can't?
Can we just store them inside
login page guys
because it's a different page?
Absolutely. Right.
So we are locating a different pages
element right now, Right?
So what I am going to do in here
inside the pages
package, I will create a new class
which is called a
dashboard page.
Okay, so
let's refactored this
dashboard page in here.
Right.
So now I need to locate that element.
So let's go back in here
and start inspecting this page.
Okay, So let's go in here.
Let's see what we got.
So we have an ID in here,
so we might as well use this, Right?
So go back and again, guys.
Now, Driver, find elements in here.
What we're starting with,
we starting with find by annotation
open and close parentheses I.D locator
and then
the pasted value
and we just create a variable here, right?
So you say, well I'm
so now once I did this class,
what is my next step?
What am I missing in here right now?
Okay, that's a good point.
We're missing a s we're
missing
two extra and the common methods, right?
Because we need
we need access to the work driver.
Right.
What else, guys?
We're missing a constructor, right?
We need to initialize those elements.
Right.
Okay, So let's create a
constructor in here.
Okay?
And then let's use the page factory,
initialize the elements with our driver
and that elements from this specific page.
Right.
Any questions, guys?
I hope all clear
everything is going organize
right.
Okay, so
now we have this element stored in here.
So now what I need to do,
I need to go back to my actual tests.
Right? So
for me,
in order for me to have access
to that specific element, what
what do I need to do?
I need to create an object
of the dashboard page, right?
So I'm going to create here just in case.
Right. Dashboard page.
You can see dashboard page in here,
new dashboard page.
All right.
So after we take the screenshot,
what I want to do,
I want to get the text
and it's going to give me a strange value,
right?
So text is equal to this.
And then
what I'm going to do,
I'm going to print that out.
And once I did this, what I will do,
I will simply go ahead and
tear down the browser.
Okay.
Any questions
before I run this, guys? Yes.
That's why I said guys don't type, right?
Because I told you guys
I'm going to be creating a lot of packages
and a lot of classes.
So I'll be moving inside of that.
Okay, So let me run
and let's see if we have printed
they welcome text
and we have the screenshots.
Oh, why is this event happening in here?
Okay, so it happened on this train, guys.
Okay, so we can see this
welcome admin in here.
Okay.
And let me expand this.
So if I expand my screenshots,
you can see that
I have two different folders.
One of them is our maps,
which we just created.
And if I expand this
you can see the dashboard PNG.
If I click on this, you can see
the screenshot in here.
Okay, any questions, guys?
Who was having any confusion is guys
okay?
Pretty cool. Yeah. Right.
So everything is organized.
Everything has its own place,
guys, so you don't have to
make everything mix
right? Yes.
So from now on, guys, from now on,
I think you guys covered
how many classes of tests You guys
two. Right.
Okay.
So I think I'm not sure how many tests
and classes you're going to have,
but you will you will be using this object
model through
the end of the course.
Okay.
Words, APIs with
with test engine,
with Cucumber, with sequel.
Everything
okay.
Just one class
remaining for theoretical part.
Okay, good.
So after that, you start developing.
After that
I think you will be covering Maven
and then you start building
your framework.
Okay?
So once you build your framework,
you will have this page
object model design,
You will have MAVEN included in there.
So it's going to be pretty cool guys.
Okay.
And then at the very end
you will have a very, very solid,
solid framework on hand.
All right, guys, any questions on this?
Any questions on how to implement,
implement page object model?
Any questions on what it is?
Any confusion, guys?
Well, you just need to practice. Okay.
If it's if it's confusing at first, it's
okay, guys.
You just need to take a look at the code
and everything and all the packages.
One more time when I push the code.
Okay,
So that's going to be more clear for you.
Lines 2025 228 Oh, here.
Okay, So once we take the screenshot,
we'll have a file on hand.
Right.
So what I need to do with this file,
I need to copy that file
and I need to store it somewhere.
Okay.
So basically what I'm doing,
I'm copying this file and storing
this as PNG g inside the mess folder.
Okay, test for dashboard page.
We need to repeat all code for log in.
Oh, for now. For now.
You have to repeat that. Yes.
So now you have to repeat the log in page
what's called log in test
or what you can do.
You can create a method which logs in
so you can create a method which logs
in to this specific your row
and then after that, perform that perform
any other actions you want.
Okay, so the exception.
So basically
when you copy the file, right.
So it it might throw you
an input output exception
because what you're doing
you taking the screenshot, you grabbing it
and you're
pasting this inside your project.
Right. So it might throw you an exception.
So that's why we are,
that's why we are surrounding it
by try and catch
our common methods.
Class is empty, guys.
We don't have anything in here.
Oh, y it might.
Okay, so it might throw an exception.
Okay, so let's open this.
What?
Okay,
so it might.
So you can see that in here, right?
So you can see
it might throw an input output exception.
So what we are doing in here, you're
you're trying to get a new file
and, you're trying to input it
inside your project.
So if something goes wrong, Right.
So if you can't copy
or if you can't create that file
or if you can't get the screenshot
and you're trying to copy
non-existing resistant thing,
only then it will throw you
in an exception.
Okay?
So that's why you have to surround that.
You have to surround that
with try and catch.
All right.
Any other questions, guys?
Okay. Seems like no other questions.
So what we can do
now, guys, we can go to our common methods
and we can create couple of common methods
that you guys
can reuse, reuse
during your project or during
what's called after you
build the framework.
Okay. So
the whole process of what
which process
do you want me to repeat?
Oh, page object model.
Okay, sure.
So let's see in here.
Okay, so as I said, page object model is
is a design pattern, right?
So it helps you to
to enhance the taste test maintenance
and the
code, the application,
the whole process, the example
you're talking about,
the last example, this one.
Okay. Okay, sure.
All right.
So in here, what we're doing first, guys,
whenever you start automating
and you have a page
object model, you have a base class,
you have common methods, right?
So what you need to do is
you need to create a page class, right?
Because you need
to store everything in there.
You need to store all
the elements in here by
by annotation of find, by,
and by having a constructor to initialize
all the elements.
Right? By using the page practice.
So once you have done this,
what you need to do
is you need to create a
test class widget which is going to be
under your test package, right?
So and then you will start
to perform actions.
So right now we have this opening
with that specific URL
and then what we have in here,
we create the object
of that class
that we have created for pages, right?
And we stored all our elements in there.
So now we have access to all the elements.
We can perform actions by sending keys
and then by clicking on the log in button.
Right?
So after we're logged, then what happens
is we want to take a screenshot right?
So we take a screenshot.
So now what I want to do,
I want to interact with the welcome
element, but
this element is on the dashboard
page, right?
So now since this element
is on a different page, what I need to do,
I need to go ahead and create another page
class, okay?
So that I can store that element
in that class separately.
So I started this by ADD
signed by annotation.
Again, I have my constructor
and then what I need to do,
I need to go back to my task class.
Okay?
So in order
for me to have access for that,
I need to create an object again
for that dashboard page.
So I have access.
I get the text in here
and I store it in a string,
I print it out,
and then I close the browser, make
sure.
All right.
Any other questions, guys?
The paint.
All right, let's see
if there are any other questions before
we move to to developing
some common
methods.
Open the dashboard
or guess.
All right, guys.
So let's go ahead to our let's
go to the common methods.
Okay.
And let's develop
a couple of methods that we will be
reusing in the future.
Okay.
So what would be
So let's develop a function
which will send some text.
Okay.
So let's develop a function
which will send some text
to a specific element
and a specified text.
Okay.
Well,
you can follow now. Yeah, that's fine.
Guess I mean, you can, you can type in
now, but I need you to be active.
Well, right.
So that we can build these functions.
Okay, so what?
So if I want to send some text guys,
am I getting anything in return?
If I send text on the on the textbooks.
No. Right.
So if I want to create a function in here
or if I want to create a common
method, is this going to be
what's called
what is my what is going to be my return
type thing here?
Void, Right. Because
we're not getting anything in return.
So what I can do public void.
Let's do send text
right.
Okay.
So you can type it in after after this.
After the class. Guys, it's okay.
I'll push the code. Right.
Okay, guys. So I'm sending the.
So now I want to know which element
I'm sending the text to
and what is the text that I am sending to
that I'm just sending.
Okay, so where do I put those?
Where do I specify the element
that I wanted to interact with?
There we go.
So we have parameter. Right?
So I can say that
web element.
Element, right.
And then here
my text is going to be as string.
So now guys, what I am going to do,
the element that I passed in here,
send keys.
Right?
And the value in here is going to be text,
right.
But so once I do this right, once
I do this.
So what if the text books
that I'm trying to interact with
has already the text guys,
what do we need to do?
Make if condition not really right,
we can simply go ahead and clear
our text box right?
We can simply go ahead and not
clear our text box and then enter
and then enter the text
that we specified inside our friend.
Right.
And what I going to do with that?
Leave a Java doc in here.
Okay.
Saying that this method, this method
sends
sense text to a given
web element.
Right?
Okay.
How do I add a job with that? Okay.
So what you need to do
you need to do is slash double star
and press enter.
Okay, forward,
slash.
Okay, first slash double star
and then enter.
Okay, so you have to parameters in here.
So this
this what's
called
this method will send text to any element.
With any text you need to select,
you want to specify
right?
Yes, it will work,
but it won't give you the parameters.
Okay.
So if you do it without double SA,
it will work, but it will not give you
the parameters in here.
Okay.
All right.
Oh yeah.
Those are the parameters that you can
you can also add in here.
I think you can also
add the author in here.
I'm not sure if this is going to pop up
right now.
Okay.
Seems like this is not built in here.
That's fine.
All right.
Let's see what else we can add in here.
Yeah, it should be a little bit different.
Okay, guys, so let's do this.
Let's
see. Okay, So
how many way did we say
we can switch to the frame?
Guys? Three.
Right. What?
What are those ways?
Idea or name?
Right.
Okay.
By index and
and by the web element.
Right.
So let's let's create
a method which switches to the
to the frame by the given web elements.
Okay.
Or let's do it by the index guys.
So if I switch to a frame,
am I getting anything in return? Does
no right.
So the method we will be creating right
now will be void as well, right?
So public void.
Let's do
a switch to
frame in here. So
in here guys,
since we are switching by index,
where do I need to make the change?
So we need to add the index inside
the parameter.
Right. So integer
index in here.
So what I need to do driver
that switch to the frame
and we need to paste the index in here.
Right.
But so we need to be very cautious in
whenever we these kind of common methods.
Okay guys.
So what is
what if there's no frame with
think there is a frame.
There's no frame guys on the page.
So in that case,
we need to take some action.
Okay.
So if there's no if there's no frame,
you will get an exception.
Right.
So what you can do in this case,
whenever you're using this method
and if there's no frame or
you're using this method right now,
everything is fine.
There is a frame.
But in the future, developers
remove that frame, right?
So your your your step is going to fail
when you when you switch to the frame.
Right.
So in that case what we can do
we can wrap this up with a try and catch.
Right. So what I'm going to do in here
I'm going to do try
right and
copy this right
and what am I catching in here?
What kind of exception am I catching?
No such frame exception, right?
Absolutely right.
So what I am going to do is simply
put in here no such frame exception.
E Right.
And what I will do
will print the stack trace.
Okay.
Is this clear, guys?
Any questions
for frames? Yes.
You need to switch back
to default content.
Correct. Why?
Oh okay.
So why we okay here.
So this switch to frame method
that we are creating
is for for the test cases
where you switch to the frame
and you perform
all the rest of the action
inside the frame.
Okay, so this one.
So you can also create a method
to to get back
to the default content
and we use that in your actions.
Right?
So you want to so if you
you can't really
go back right now in here,
you can't really do default content right.
Because everything should be in a small
chunks, right.
If you build a big chunk right now,
you can't really add anything
in between, Right?
So in your common methods, try to divide
everything in small,
small chunks as possible.
Okay?
So that your future executions,
they don't get interrupted by your common
methods.
Okay.
All right.
So here, guys, what you can do,
what you can do as your homework
or in your free time
whenever you want to do it,
you can create a the same method in here.
But having with different, different ways
of switching, different.
Exactly.
This is what you need to do
if you want to have switch to frame
by web element
and switch the frame by ID or name right.
So you need to overload this
method and change a little bit inside.
Okay. Keep the same name guys.
Keep the same name,
but just overload these methods.
Okay.
So now you can see how we are,
how we're using an inherited multilevel
inheritance, right?
How we using overloading right now?
You see that
old concepts are coming around right now
now? Yes.
So you should be adding
Java doc for each method.
Okay, Get this in the habit, guys,
because when you start working,
you will see Java Docs on each
and every method in the framework.
Okay.
Because sometimes
whenever a new person comes in
and they try to look at the framework,
they might not know
what that method does or what
function is performing.
Right?
So that's why you need these Java docs
in order to give the description
so so that other people can understand
what is going on.
So in here, let's put this
so this method
will switch to frame
by index.
Okay.
Any questions, guys?
You can also guys
go ahead and create methods for selecting
from the dropdown right.
Or switching to the to the child window
question.
Okay. Yeah, that's okay. That's okay.
All right.
You just need a little bit practice. Okay.
So if you're confused, if you're confused
in some topics, it's okay.
Just practice a little more.
It's all going to get along okay.
So once implementations often,
I mean, do you.
Yes, I read I read Java Docs.
Yes, sometimes not always,
but sometimes I read Java Docs
if I don't know what is going on
with a method.
Okay.
Because we all have we have in our
framework pretty big methods,
not only the common methods but
in different implementation classes.
You will be going on, you will be going
over those in, in framework building.
Okay.
So if you especially
when you have long methods
and big implementation in one method, it's
it's useful.
It's really useful
to have those Java docs.
Okay.
Why read the file that is created?
No, no, not really.
All right, guys, we have 30 more minutes.
If you guys have any questions.
It doesn't have to be regarding
the selenium.
You can ask me regarding the jobs
or anything like this.
I'll be happy to answer.
If not, we can finish.
Finished today's class.
Yes. There is one more slide
that I will be uploading.
Okay. Wish
so. At that time
we didn't have these common methods.
You should start. You should start with
with Java docs in in Java classes guys.
Okay.
What was,
what was the hardest part of starting
my first job.
The thing that the meetings
I think the meetings, guys okay.
The meetings are the hardest
because you didn't really attend those,
so you just keep quiet at first
and then you observe everything.
You don't have any.
No, no, I didn't have any
previous experience with coding guys.
Okay.
Syntax is the only
is the only experience that I got.
I remembering all the steps.
Okay.
So in the interview, guys,
in the interview,
you might forget something.
It's. It's okay, guys.
Okay. It's.
It's normal.
We're all human beings.
You will you will forget stuff.
I forget stuff and it's not don't
really worry about this.
Okay?
So when it comes to interview
preparation, guys,
you will have more, more information and
and we'll give you a lot of stuff, too,
and we will support you.
Okay. So give you interview questions.
You will be going over those.
We'll have mock interviews.
So that's all going to be
that's going to work out very well.
Okay.
So don't be too worried right now
about the interviews.
It will be for real interviews.
Okay.
From my own experience. Okay.
How well you're going to be prepared
if you study.
You will be prepared. Very good.
Okay.
So from my own experience in syntax,
so a lot of my friends in my group,
we all found jobs within the three weeks.
Okay.
So it was like seven people
or eight people.
Okay.
So the more you study, the more you share
with your teammates, okay, the better
you get.
Okay, guys, So try to work with teams.
That's going to give you a lot
more information than even
I am giving you.
Okay.
You study for like 5 hours a day.
So in my situation,
we were in class students, right?
So we were there every day.
We were we were at syntax every day,
guys, seven days a week.
We used to go there like 2 p.m.
and would finished like 8 p.m..
And then we just I used to do Uber at that
time.
Which states has more jobs available?
I'm not really sure about that, guys,
but I am sure that D.C.
area has more government jobs than other
states.
Is the last classes of Java.
Okay.
If you have some
some difficulties with Java
guys, as I said, practice or talk to your
talk to your teammates
guys share with with each other.
That way you will have more practice
and that way you explain something,
you get
you got something from your teammate
that's going to be very good for us.
How many interviews I got until I until
I got the job.
I think I got my my offer on the second
or third interview.
You do?
Did you take the first offer
just to get in?
I was going to take an offer.
Just the first offer.
But then after that I got another offer.
It was better. So I the second one
already conference a
Is it competitive in the market right now?
Is that what you asking price
How long did I stay?
I stayed for about five months
because I was forced to leave.
So I was a contractor
and all the contractors got laid off.
Okay.
At my first job, it's not that they didn't
renew. They
the budget got cut
so they had to lay everything
everyone else.
Okay.
So like, I think they laid off
like more than 100 people
at the at the same time.
How fast did I find a new job?
So it was it was December, guys.
So I went back home for a month
and came back. So
so I started applying in January
at the second half of the January
and I just got in in, in February.
You guys
Okay.
So probably two or three weeks
work and stuff is very similar guys.
Okay.
So once you dive into the framework,
that is exactly the same.
Well, the the process is the same. The
what's called the page object model
that I explained is the same.
So it might be different tools, Okay.
Which you need to which you need to learn
and it's fine guys.
You will have time to learn, but
everything else should be the same guys.
Okay, I would need another month
or two to prepare myself
for interview after completing.
If you ask me, don't do that.
If you ask me, apply right away.
What if we have passing
the mock interview?
What if you have trouble
passing the mock interview? You
If you study, you won't.
Guys,
how long did it take
for me to feel comfortable at the job?
What I'm doing right now,
depending on the difficulty
of your framework
okay, some frameworks are really easy.
Some frameworks, as I have right now,
it's pretty complicated.
Okay, so we're using different tools
on top of selenium
cucumber Java, we using some other tools
and it's it's a little bit complicated.
It's a for me probably 2 to 3 months.
There's a short period of time
between jobs.
That's me.
I'm no they don't.
I mean, if it's, if it's like a year
then they will ask you what's going on.
But if it's like a month, then now
you could just tell them
you had a vacation or some
half cheese, half pepperoni.
Okay, Just a heads up.
All right, All
good.
Okay, I'll note that down.
Maybe I should put it in the notes
in here
and find.
Oh, okay.
Well,
you can explain the situation, right?
If you find the new job,
like two months ago.
And now you look
and you can explain the situation
in my situation, I mean, it is what it is.
I mean, I got laid off
because the budget got cut, right?
And they don't really look at this
like, hey, something is wrong now.
They will look more at you. It's okay.
So what?
You know, if you know, then it's
they will hire you.
Okay.
I saw something about a program
that we've been covering
and what would be our answer program.
What do you mean by program?
Are you talking about
the programing language?
Oh, tools.
Okay, So if you're asked to do something
with your tool, with with
the different tools, you can tell them
that you never use those because.
They will look at your resume.
You have Java, you have Selenium,
you have Maven,
you have cucumber test and G, right?
And you're going to come at
you and ask you JavaScript,
right?
And you can say that I am willing to learn
absolutely
right.
Okay, you're a fast learner.
Okay,
let's see if you fast find a job
in the years you suggest.
If we need not more
that I would
for the experience
guys, that I would leave it to Samir
and A so they would suggest to you
the better way.
Okay.
Like extra tools.
You want me to mention the extra tools?
Extra tools like Serenity
is getting really popular right now.
You can take a look at that
tool.
There's catalogs studio, which I hate.
There is also task complete,
which is really, really outdated.
It's using really government.
Okay, no
more selenium classes guys.
It's all done.
This is everything you need to know
in selenium.
Hey, it means no more me.
Yeah, absolutely right, guys.
No, no, no.
We do a virtual hag when you find a job,
Michael Okay?
Otherwise, otherwise, it's
where we can dance the night away as well.
If you find a job. Yeah.
If all of you find jobs
really, really fast.
Anything, guys?
Okay.
Lots of good deals. There you go.
See what
what I am willing to do for you guys
so that you guys can find a job.
These students have left since the start.
I'm not sure about that, guys.
I don't really keep track of that.
All right, guys, any other questions?
All right.
If there's no questions, guys, good luck.
Okay, I'll take on the VA system.
Okay,
But luck, guys, there's a little bit left.
Okay, Let's push it a little bit more.
So two months left right now
and you will be on the market.
It's going to be a lot of fun when you
start looking for a job, guys, it's
going to be a little stressful,
but it's going to be a lot of fun
when you start taking interviews.
Okay.
So thanks, everybody, guys.
Good luck.
And I hope you guys find jobs
really, really fast
because they
the market is really hot right now.
I'm getting emails every day even though
I haven't applied for like two years.
So yes, I'll push the code guys.
You'll have everything updated in
canvas as well
and I will probably see some of you
on the mock interviews, but I doubt it.
So if I don't guys, then good luck.
Second
half of the January is going to be good
the market wise.
Okay.
All right, guys. So have a good night.
Good luck again, guys,
And I'll probably see
you, some of you in the mock interviews.
If not, have a good one.
And I hope you guys find jobs really fast.
Okay. Thanks, everybody.
Have a good night and stay safe.
Thank you, guys.