Well, let me start that
morning
and I'm going to share my screen now.
Physically,
nobody's been able to see my screen.
Can you see my screen now?
If you want.
But still, in these two glasses case,
the so far where we did best, Angie.
Right.
It started from the request annotation,
correct? Correct.
Soon we will be celebrating the success.
So soon, maybe in January
we will start this grand celebration.
I want every one of you to join.
So let me create the perfect package
for our third class
for like.
All right.
So let me first create a new find
from here.
So in the last class, guys,
what was the first topic of
it is looking all.
All right.
So the is in the last class
we discussed from
we started our discussion
from hard session right in our test. And
so we are
going to do a quick recap
and then we will switch on for new topics.
So guys, tell me what is hard assertion?
Well,
let's let's talk about what is a session
like to validate
our application.
We need
a session all the way to date
the fields of
application.
We need a session like
so if we talk about a session, right,
there are two types of a session.
We have discussed
two types of a session.
We are about out of it.
About the first one is
the first one we have is hard a session
within that first category.
The hardest session.
All right. When
it comes
or when error exists,
it stops
execution, correct?
That's why we call it part of session.
The another one we have is stock.
The session.
Now, what is what is the session can be
correct.
It allows us
to execute our code are complete code
and it captures
all the errors.
In the end, it gives us
one consolidated output like
it gives us consolidated output.
Now, in order to get this
consolidated output in the end,
which method we need to call right,
we need to file.
So we use
a start all method
to get
consolidated or
collective.
That is
correct.
Is this case are not like
then what was the next thing we discussed
after the session
before that also.
Okay, fine. All right.
So before that, also we discussed
a couple of things, but let's talk about
yes, we discussed about
depends on attribute.
What is this depends on attributes, race
allows are.
All right. Yes.
Well, my one test case is relying
on another one.
For example, my logging test case,
my log in test case,
I relying on launch browser test case
or my verification test case
relying on logging test case.
In that case, what I have to do is
I have to use one attribute
go depends on attribute
and when I write this depends on attribute
in my method,
which is rely on another method
carefully guys,
when I have to see
when I have to check one method
which is relying on another method
I have to write.
This depends on attribute
and the method name, which method
being the method
on which my current method is relied.
Correct.
So this depends on attribute.
For example, if I'm using for validation.
So inside validation
I will write a direct.
This depends on attribute
is equals to my log in method.
This is just an example I'm giving, right?
So what it does, it
basically executes force.
The method on which you are relying
and then executes
your actual method.
Okay,
let me show you this also,
my verified dashboard page
method is relying on log in method.
So when my this verified dashboard page
test is relying on another test,
I am writing depends on methods
and in this attribute
depends on methods attribute.
I'm going to mention the method, the test
on which my current test is relying.
So my current test is relying on log in.
So I am writing
this based on method is equals to log in
and then it will execute log in this post
and then verify dashboard.
Basically
clear
on which
test the line
of or
depending.
Then what was the next thing I
yeah.
Elizabeth Correct. Correct.
If it is not allowing us
to execute the previous one, how
it can allow us to execute the next one.
No, no priority
priority was the topic of force station.
Right.
I'm talking about the second class topics
then just in assembly.
Right.
Configurations,
different types of configurations,
how we can create this test
and do not similar using intelligent idea.
Right.
We have seen all of these things
in our previous class
setting how we can create this test
and do not like symbol.
I already told you we all knew right now
what we have inside this test
and do not exemplify
the question is what we have
inside this particular fight.
So remember guy is this test in the DART
segment is your configuration file.
You can see
this is the engine of your vehicle.
This is the big bone of your body right?
This is the backbone of your test engine.
So if you are talking about test
and you don't take middle plane,
you need to make sure that whatever
the customization
and configuration selection be selection,
inclusion, exclusion you want to make,
you will make all of this
customization inside your one class
that is your test
and don't accept.
For example, if I have 100 classes
and I want to execute 50 classes
from five different packages,
I don't need to call every single package
and then go ahead and right
click and execute.
No, I have this test
and do not examine file.
I will mention all of those classes
which I want to execute
irrespective of the package
it is coming from.
All right.
We can mention these things inside
one class.
We can even include
an exclude their methods test
which are available
inside this particular class.
So it is a high level of customization.
If we go straight down inside this,
then we can even include exclude classes,
packages, methods and every single thing
we can exclude or include
according to our requirement grade test.
And you don't extend this by configuration
file allows us to
do this clear.
It allows us
to execute all of our
test kits. This
according to our
requirement
in this file,
we can include exclude
methods,
classes,
packages, packages
during execution, correct.
Now, if you remember,
we have discussed this how
we can create this ten or symbol.
So to do this,
what we have to do is we have to first
rename our best and you submit file
and then we have to create another test.
And otherwise, what would happen
if you already have Windows ten?
Do not file in your project
and if you try to create another one,
then in this case what would happen is it
will override your test and you don't
see you guys know better than me.
Now, you guys ready to
write it? All right.
Getting
baked.
Great. Good to see you guys.
The way you're responding. Great.
So now after this,
when we have multiple files,
So what is the need to have multiple test
and do not single file?
The question arises here this
if I have one test and duratex
and one find it should be no,
then why do we need multiple configuration
file for one project
then it sure
basically remember one thing.
The scenario here is
we have so many cases,
so many requirements, so many scenarios
and conditions in one project,
obviously for execution,
for example, sometimes I need to execute
only those test cases,
which is a part of smoke testing.
Sometimes I need to execute
only both those test cases
which are a part of regression test.
Sometimes I have to
test called acceptance testing.
Sometimes I have to test say sanity test.
Or it could be any of them. The right
smoke testing, retesting, sanity testing,
regression testing.
Most of the times we do just to the first
smoke and the second is integration.
All right.
Now I have 1000 test cases, right?
I have 1000 test cases and I want
to execute all of them in a single shot.
Fine, I can do this.
But if I have 1000 test out of this,
I need to execute only those test cases
which are belong to particular category.
So for this reason it is a best idea
to create one separate configuration file.
I did this test and do not accept 1.38
to 1 configuration file.
What this condition did,
which condition that condition is
grouping.
All right.
We can create one group of test cases
and we will create.
We can create one configuration by now.
This particular configuration file,
this particular test
and do not accept
will find will always exist.
Your test cases
belong to this specific category.
Dinara This is the next point
I'm just talking about.
One party of
that is of how we can create smoke dot,
SML integration, dot symbol
or any other detect symbol.
Correct. It's a requirement.
So what grouping does basically
group
allows you
to execute
specific test.
Get this
belongs to
that particular
correct
let's say if you want to execute only
this gives this belong to small category
definitely you can do that similarly
for duration similarly for any other one.
Right. We can do that easily.
Clear.
Make sure when you do this groupings
there is another attribute called
Always Run.
Always run is equal to why?
Why did you do that?
Because we knew one thing
if we don't right
always run is equals to true in our free
condition.
Enforced condition
then my best guess will be thing.
That is for sure,
because my precondition in most condition
is not a part of any group.
Mike That's a part of group.
My precondition and forced
condition is not a part of any group,
correct?
So to do that,
what we have to do is basically
we have to make this precondition
in most condition always, right.
So to do that, we have to use one
attribute called always run is equals to
connect.
And this is
superb.
All right.
So these are the things we discussed
in our last class, Correct.
Another thing, image label report.
I hope many of you guys
have found this one, right?
This video.
Okay.
So what this image label report
does, basically,
we need one artifact, right?
And to show this artifact,
we need one report based and allows us
to create one beautiful photo
deep in permit three dot issue report.
Right. This is indelible report.
Don't ask me
how we can add this report in our project.
So we had we have to add one listener's.
No, you don't have to do this
for your project.
Eugene.
This is for your project, right?
So you need this image label report.
This then allows us to generate
a report of execution.
Having the extension
dart, HDMI and
then explains
our details or institution
right.
All these movements in an
the configuration,
your data is always removed.
All right,
let me show you why it is happening.
If you click on Run,
if you're going to edit configuration,
you'll see these.
Are there different classes?
Correct. Okay.
Because you're creating a new class
and your cursor is on new class.
Like for this class, right?
Test and your text symbol file.
So here if I check it is available for me.
If I create new class
and my cursor is on the new one,
then definitely it will be updated.
There's no problem.
Yeah. In case of one test
and do not single file.
If you have one configuration file,
you have to create it at once.
If you are increasing it,
then just put your cursor on the point
and then it will work for that test.
And you've got a symbol every time
you're
going to, for every symbol is fine, right?
I thought for every project
my project is just one
is still we are in a same project.
Like I said, we can have multiple test
and single file
for one project, correct.
Now the next important point is
if you observe in our application,
whatever we are doing, it
is if you see we are passing this data
in that application rate
as a username, as a password, correct.
We are passing this data,
We call this data hardcoded,
right?
We are passing out coded data here.
But the problem with this kind of data is
it is not acceptable
in your practical industry.
If you go in any organization,
if you are working for
any company or for any project
or any client or customer.
And if you write your test cases like this
where you're passing the data, hardcoded
your test, this will not get accepted.
All right.
Can anyone think of the situation
why this hard
coded data is not accepted?
It is not acceptable in any industry.
No demo.
See signal credentials can always change.
Trade
credentials is something
always changes.
Find liquidity.
You want to think
Here you are exposing your data
right?
Right now what we are doing,
Let's consider one scenario.
Let's consider
one practical scenario of Amazon.
What you did is how many users Amazon has,
what you think about it,
how many users Amazon, as
many carry.
And everyone, every single user of Amazon
is able to log in
to the application, correct?
At least three
write days.
Every single user has its own user idea
and a password.
Do not tell me.
Now. Let's say Jamal
got a job in one company, right?
And this company has a customer. Amazon.
Now Jamal bought one requirement
where he has to execute the test.
Guess where he has to perform
logging in the Amazon right?
If you pause this data like this for admin
and then password hardcoded data,
but the requirement is
he has to execute this log
in functionality for 1000 users
or later for 1 million users.
Right.
For 1 million users, he has to execute
this script with this type of arrangement.
With this kind of arrangement.
The arrangement he has right now,
the one you can see on my screen
right.
Will he be able to execute
this particular script across 1
million users?
No. Right.
If he wants to continue
with this same arrangement,
what he has to do,
he has to write this script,
this particular valid login
method for 1 million times.
And every time
he has to change his admin right.
And the new user password right.
Getting my point or not
getting.
So now we don't have to use any.
No, we don't have to use any other thing.
Right.
We can even store
every single thing in a map from the java
knowledge Black
That is good and value players, right?
That is also fine.
But remember I told you we are using
a very integrated and advanced tool.
Quite stingy right?
When we come across this type
of requirement, right when we come across
this type of requirement test indices,
you don't need to be identified.
You don't need to use a
map, you don't need to use any form
for any other loop.
Right. I have my inbuilt concept.
If you use this inbuilt
concept in your class, you will be able
to log in across multiple users
with the help of a single method.
For example, this is my single test.
Guess right?
This single test will work across
multiple users.
I don't need to write this test case again
and again and again.
I do need to do that.
Very simple to understand this.
Interesting.
Yes. Data driven testing.
This is what we call data driven test.
What is data driven test?
When your test executes
across states of data
or multiple set of data
right across different types of data.
We call it data driven testing.
So now the next concept,
which we are going to implement
here is your data driven testing quite
it's going to the slide first,
we are going to pass this test
parameterization rate.
Interestingly,
you'll see
it says parameterization in testing
can be done
with the help of data provided annotation.
This is the concept editor data provider
which I was talking about.
All right, excited
data provider annotation.
This data provider is a method annotated
with the array data provider
which provides the data inside our method.
How are we going to implement it?
We will look into this. Don't
worry about it.
Okay.
Now remember
this method must monster data
the array of object.
All right.
The array of object.
Remember this so it steps to parameter.
We will look into this later.
First.
First, we will create this part
data provider class.
So I'm going to create it
right click Now another Java class.
And inside this class I'm going to write
data all the way to
connect
Great state.
I didn't get it Black
Yeah,
I'm making sure that no one pays
any insurance, anything.
I'm just making sure for everyone.
That's why
all guys.
So now, now I already give you
one practical situation right by.
Do we need
now let's go ahead and try to implement
this data provided a class.
All right.
So first to right this data provider
right before writing this data provider
class, what I will write,
I will write my scenario,
whatever the test, I'm going to execute
and then we will implement data provider.
Then we will integrate data provider
and test together.
Correct.
First part,
which you guys are already aware of.
Great first part
This is the work
we are going to implement so that you guys
will have some familiarity with the topic.
And then slowly I will take you to
implement data for the later assignment.
You don't need to change any things in it.
That's the best part.
You don't need to change anything.
This you will take care everything except.
All right, now let me show you.
So the first thing which I'm going to do
here is I'm going to write my file.
Everyone knows it.
We private driver
or do I need to explain
the I'm writing everything right?
Everything I'm writing. Okay.
So please take care of this thing
and please make sure that
if even if you are writing,
even if you're writing the code with me,
and if you think I'm writing too fast,
please
interrupt me and stop me in between.
All right. I won't be back.
Do it.
Because this class is for you
guys, not for me.
Okay, Now,
let's go ahead.
I'm going to write my method
first before my pen.
I'm going to write
y because Pre-condition, condition.
Correct.
So now I'm going to write.
It is
like open the browser.
I'm going to write my method guide.
Can I copy at least the part of my Chrome
browser from any other class?
Can I do that
right?
This is my
precondition, right?
This is just a precondition
Is everyone with me.
We have written just a precondition.
We didn't do it.
We didn't write anything after this.
Shall we proceed further?
No. Students
Okay.
Now the next thing I'm going to write
for my public void next.
See? Well,
remember, this is my main test case,
so I'm going to write
the latest, right?
Yeah, for sure.
Now I'm going to write here is driver or
client element, right?
We have already just look at that
biodata idea.
What is the idea here?
We have fixed
this then you guys already
have these things correct?
Everyone has this
dot. S.E.
again driver dot element, bi dot IED.
So here I'm going to write.
So the
they should be like this, correct?
Do let me know
what is if I'm doing something wrong
after this.
After this,
I am going to verify something on my page.
Right.
So we all know our applications
and takes each out of me so fast, right?
It needs some time to load the page.
So I'm going to provide one bit
driver dart,
manage dart ammo dart implicit rate.
So this wait would
be my next if by clicking
okay and the code to verify let's say
welcome to simple again
I'm going to write web element
welcome attribute is what's to
I'm going to write it as
or let's not verify anything as of now
because the main point is data driven test
nothing else.
You're not going to verify something,
just a valid log.
We are going to check find after this.
The next thing is, guys,
precondition done.
We have one web marks implicit wait,
we have one.
So that one is in precondition, right?
This is my actual test.
After launching the application
before in before log in.
Right.
It is working there inside the method.
This is my another method.
Right? Can you see the scope?
It will work only for that condition.
It will not work for my actual test
now. Always after method right.
Public void
addict.
This is the code
we all know so far. Right?
If I'm going to put it by a grouping
so I will write
one thing as
always run is equals true for this one
always run is equal to two for this one.
Now. Now
the main implementation five times three.
If I'm posting this data here
just for admin and this credential,
I will not be able to execute
this particular script for multiple users.
Right
now I want to execute this script
for multiple users to do that.
What I'm to do see,
I'm going to write here
public
Object
and here I'm going to provide this
and somebody
tell me if I write this public
object, this end log in data,
this is my function name.
What does it mean?
What is this object?
Why I'm calling this object?
Yes, this is to the array. Correct.
But what is this object? Yes.
Correct. Object is the parent class.
Every single class study in Java
is a child of this object class. Yes.
I think we are coming on that.
We are coming now in this object.
If I'm expecting a string, can I get it?
If I'm expecting something else,
but not a string,
can I get it?
What is the reason?
Because my object is a parent.
Plus I can expect anything in return.
Right.
So let's go ahead. Correct.
That's my anticipated plus.
Now, when I say to the any
right
when I say this to the VI,
we'll need this to the error here.
Can somebody
guess?
Yes, yes, yes, yes, correct.
So let me write this.
Let me write.
You all are intelligent objects.
Great.
I'm going to write of these data.
Right?
This is my
now I want to check.
Right.
That my log in functionality is working
or not across three users.
How many users goes across three users?
So I'm going to write object.
It will ask.
It will ask to define
the overall length of my addy.
So when I say three users,
it means one three username and password.
What would be the numbers?
I need to put here to define the size
of any
the array that can accept
my three different credentials?
It means three users.
Again also as I'm repeating myself, three
username, three password, correct, etc.
if I expect and if I had right to do,
then what would happen
to username and password?
This will be your number. All
this will be your number.
All the rows.
This will be your number. All
this will be your number of columns.
And with new keyword
you're defining correct?
Are you understanding what I'm doing here?
How we define the size of this area?
Okay. All right.
Whenever you guys think that you're not
understanding anything, do let me look.
All right? It's not a big deal at all.
They will stop.
We will read it again.
We will go through it again, and then
we will implement it again from scratch.
It's not initialize.
Okay?
Sure.
Why not?
This is the last part of your code joining
the error down is the method
as opposed to condition
we use right to close our browser.
I already explained
to you the difference in between driver
dot doors and driver dot click.
All right.
Shall we proceed further now?
All right, so here what I'm going to do
is this object class,
the parent class I'm calling, right?
I am going to define one to the 80.
When I define this to the
that this would be the object
of my to really and the length
I'm going to define.
So I have defined the length of my
to the 80 because I know my requirement.
What is the requirement
I need to pass username and password.
It means two parameters.
No, it can change.
It will change.
Let's say
I want for username and password setting.
That is also possible.
We will do that also.
Don't worry,
this is the another part will do right.
We will going to see that part.
Also don't worry about the
it is completely customizable.
Don't worry about it.
So now here I defined it to the anti.
I created the object of this to data
and I provided the length of the array.
Now this is the time to fill the values
inside this to really write.
Let me open this to to you more
so from here.
Let's go from this.
At the moment I see
three comma two what would happen?
It says one, two, three,
two, one and two.
Right.
So this is the size of eight
I have defined, which is are two direct
two dimensional.
The right one dimension is this one
one dimension, is this one correct?
I have to pass I have to pass my username
and my password,
correct? Yes.
So how many users names
I can pass now inside this?
This is the memory allocation, by the way.
What I'm showing you right
now, which we cannot see up
three.
So user name one, user name two, end user
name, Right.
This is the combination we have to make.
So we have defined the size of edit.
Now we are going to fill the values
in all these columns
one by one, in all the cells, one by one.
Correct.
Let's go ahead and fill this venue.
I'm going to write you
here.
I'm going to write my data all
zero comma, zero.
What does it mean, guys?
Vanessa zero zero.
Yes, this is my first option.
So in my first to sell it any more,
should I write
correct.
Now I need to write the password.
So to write the password,
what would be the coordinates?
I have to pass the zero zero.
What it mean now for password
zero one.
Correct.
So zero and one and this I'm going to pass
for my password.
So this is my password?
Correct.
This It happens for one user right now.
Let's go ahead and do it
for the many users as well.
Now, 10 minutes for the second user.
For the second user,
what would be the coordinates?
One comma, zero. Right.
And then also one comma, one
similarly to comma zero
and two comma, one.
Is this correct for us to do first column,
First
column, fine.
Then second row,
first column, second row, second
then third row, first column, third row,
second column, static.
But still, I'm having one error here.
What is visitor?
Can somebody guess what?
Is this error?
Yes, the return type is missing.
So I'm going to read again.
What we should return from here is
knowing this Outward Bound is not possible
in an how index out of both.
Whatever the length we defined,
we followed the same rules.
Right?
I am going to limit.
I'm going to define this return
type as our data.
Now, see, no matter.
Edit So this is a table I've made.
I've created one table that contains
my three username and password.
Correct.
Now what is the next task?
Next task is to use this username
and these passwords
where in my method
in my test, actual test.
So what test indices?
You have to define one attribute.
Which attribute
which attribute.
Right? At the rate
data provider.
Right.
You have to write the date data provided.
The moment you write this data, the data,
this log in data
will be the name of your data provider.
This log in data
is now not normally method,
but your data provider.
Plus this is your data provider and
you are missing one some import, right?
Instead of writing this, Olena
simply write a data provider
and write this or do the test
and annotations here in the import.
The way I have written it is my signature
like this and just put started
so it will import every single thing
even Jamal instead of this dot
data provider right?
So here you'll see.
I could just stop.
Yeah, correct.
So it will give you
all of the methods
and everything from test and annotations.
Right?
You don't need to write any other thing
by proxy
for today's data provider concept.
Clear or not, everyone,
we have created just a data provider.
We didn't integrated
with our current method.
Now the next actually we split it, right?
This big topic is between smaller pieces
and we are now trying to understand
every small piece, one by one.
This is important, right?
First we wrote Normal Method,
then we created a
hollow cylinder
that is defining the size of the array.
Then we feed all the values inside ETI.
It is giving you the error data,
why you're putting comma in between.
These are the coordinates, right?
So in between the coordinates
you cannot put this comma.
So just remove.
Can you see anywhere comma I've placed
so that we need to check that
we need to check why it's not coming.
Ideally it should come,
but even if it does not coming,
sometimes we have to write.
All right.
So now this is the time.
This is the time to integrate this data
provider.
In our best case.
The last part is this one and this part
very invariant.
I don't have anything,
just this method direct.
We have this false condition
in almost every class where we perform
the log in, not all in.
This is the next thing
we are going to do that already.
We are going to check in the application.
We will see everything
now. Now let me do one thing right.
Let me copy this from here
and let me open.
Come on.
Our application,
the right now
for the first user,
I think we are okay with this admin and
this is the password.
It is working fine,
but we need two more users.
Do you guys have any credentials
which you have used to log
in which you use to log in apart
from admin?
All right.
Let me check if I have
all I knew a couple of them shard one.
That is fine, but what is the password?
I'm not sure for this one.
Let's check.
Let's create a couple of them.
Right.
So let's see.
I'm going to write the user for
Michael
Lopez, and then
the user name I'm going to write is
Michael.
One, two, three, four, five.
Password is same
state.
Now, let's try to log in with this.
Yes, we are able to log in right.
So now the next user,
the next user, which I'm
going to provide is
and the same password.
And again, in the third iteration.
So you want me to create another data
or we can use this admin one as a third.
What do you want guys?
You want new one?
Okay, wrong one is coming on the started.
That is different scenario.
We will work on version one is one.
Don't worry
because we are not right now.
We are not using the method we are.
We are verifying the error message. Right.
But if you want, let me go ahead
and use it.
See, I'm going to write it in one correct.
But there is no verification point.
That's why.
See, it will give you plus
because it will give you an error
after clicking on log in button.
But still we are not using it. Fine.
So now different three username
and password
in my data provider
plus correct my data is ready.
My data provider concept is ready.
This is the time to integrate
our data provider
in our actual test
last stage right before execution.
So let's do it in this part.
What I'm going to do here is you see,
this is my actual method
and I'm going to repeat
data provider, right?
You have to right. Data provider
is equal to
the name of your provider.
What is the name of your data provider?
It is
log in data.
So I am writing this log in data, huge
fine, fine.
Guys.
Now what is the next thing it says?
All right, I am calling this log data.
What?
How many strings we are getting from log
in data from every single row?
How many strings we are getting this
whole string static.
So if we are getting to a string
from there, we need to handle those.
The strings rate.
We need to catch these two strings
inside our test
right.
Getting my point this. Yes.
So we need to pass what?
We need to parse the parameters.
So I'm going to write string.
The first parameter would be my username
and the second parameter
you would be my password.
Correct.
Now, yeah.
Because of the poverty issue,
power is low.
So that's the reason you put that.
All right.
Now we are not going to use this direct,
hard coded data anymore, Right?
So let me delete this data.
I'm going to delete it and simply I'm
passing with this username history.
And here also
I'm going to pass my
password is correct.
Now, if you see guys, if you observe
closely what is happening here,
in my main function, in my main
function, right, which is for valid
logging data, if you see here I'm
passing username and password,
this username
and password is going inside my method,
but this username and password
is coming from my data logging data.
Right.
If I go inside my logging data
you'll see three different username,
three different password
are actually coming
and they are executing
with my actual test case.
So in this case, in this case,
my test case will execute three things.
Correct?
Is this correct based?
So let's go ahead and execute this now. I
am going to run my data provider.
They will.
Yes. Yes, Mike.
Yes, That's what I'm telling you now
right after this execution.
This is the next topic
to open your browser.
First.
Right, guys?
If video stops, right,
If call stops, please
don't leave the call in between
because might be Internet issues.
This right now it's not yet,
but if it is there
now see it executed for the second user
right
and this time
it is going to execute for my third user.
Are you guys noticing this is the wrong
password I'm going to pass here?
See all of my three test kits executed
Now, if you see here in the reserved,
right,
it gives you all the three options, right
when you log in, but it is giving you
username password, very log in, different
user username password when you log
in, different username password.
Right.
That's how you can execute your test
cases right across different set of data.
This part,
the data driven part is clear or not.
Anything
is it clear for everyone?
Think it was in session.
Perfect. So guys,
because the power is not here.
Let's take a break for 20 minutes.
And after the break,
I will tell you what all are the changes
we can do in this part. Right.
And how things work generally.
Definitely.
The question is, in my pipeline,
I really like I said,
everything, everything
we are going to discuss
about it, fine days.
So let's take a break for 20 minutes
and see you guys up to 20 minutes.
They'd be okay.
No, I already told you before even
executing this slide that we not verifying
anything after clicking on log in,
but then it will give you an error.
But after clicking on log in button,
we do not have anything to verify.
Right.
So it is taking click on, log in
and then fill that point.
Only we put our execution script right.
We didn't write anything after that.
That's why it's this fast.
If I put this
error message, credentials
and any other thing verification point
right
there, I will get some error message.
Okay, So it's 2044 here. Great.
Let's make it 21 five.
Okay.
20 minutes
before the break, we have seen
how we have executed.
Right.
My one best guess across
state of data, across
three username and password.
I executed my one best guess.
Correct.
But the question is
but the question is how it is knowing
that I have to pass username in username
and password in the password.
How is it possible?
So let me tell you this. Here
is if you see,
when I defined my method to make them,
I took best guess, which is my request.
Inside this I am writing here is spring
username comma
spring
hotspot.
When I am writing this
I am defining the order.
What is the order?
The first value, the values
from this column.
From the first column. Right.
The first column values
will always come in my phone's display.
All of this
in the column.
Values will always go in my
statements.
Getting a
now, Now what is the issue?
What is the issue here?
See if I change
late, I'm not aware.
Maybe I am writing like this
in first column.
I have used a password
and in second column I've used to mean
what would happen in that case.
It will take this user name
as human nature in 1 to 3.
This one and it will take password
is and mean.
Yes, we will not be able to log in
in this case. Why?
We will not be able to log in in this case
because the order is changed
now, we were expecting something else.
It is giving us something else.
So now let's try to change the order.
Right. For two users
to correct.
But I'm just telling you this part, right?
I'm just telling you this part as of now.
So now let me put one thing here
for maybe a session.
So inside my log in,
I'm going to write for this welcome text.
I I'm copying this data.
What is this the element of my welcome
attribute, Right.
The only thing I'm copying is my welcome
attribute element.
You all have this element, right?
I'm copying it just to check
whether my log in is working or not.
And then I change the parameters.
So inside my data, when I click on log in,
after clicking on log in, I'm seeing if
if my welcome is displayed.
Right.
If it is displayed, then please stay.
This is fuzzed
ends,
right?
This is
the correct.
So intentionally you'll see I'm passing
username instead of password in a password
instead of username.
Correct?
One correct username and password.
Third invalid credentials.
The combinations I am passing in this now,
see how it works.
This will do a question migrate
how it will identify which one is username
and which one is correct.
Now you'll see here,
observe it closely instead of username.
It is entering password and instead of
password it intended username right there.
So I'm not able to log in first.
When Now.
Second is because I'm writing
correctly username and password.
I will be able to log in.
Michael.
One, two, three, four, five
and then correct password to see.
I'm able to log in.
Now. The third one is again
invalid username and password.
No wrong credentials obviously
stronger digits again not working
right and then it will close my browser
for sure.
Right. So now what is happening here?
See, just one best guess is fast
and to test
this are pre
usually correct but right now
just really show you this part right.
I'm not using a solution just to show you.
All right
If you one day I will use that also.
Right.
I just wanted to keep it simple.
That's why I used
a third card also to write
fine.
All right.
So that is understood. Yeah.
I can invest, investigate.
You need to put this way, guys.
Right. The necessity.
Make it easier just because we need to see
what we actually doing.
Right. What are we doing?
Actually, we need to see that part.
That's why
I am putting enough ends doing this again.
Sometimes
in your actual
execution, then you will be having 1000
functions, 1000 test.
If you put going this again
for every method, again, if we take it
just to execute right there,
you don't need to put that much of it.
If your application is very responsive,
you can simply execute
your test cases
right in a single to intentionally.
We are putting this much of work here
so that we can actually see
what we're implementing.
So remember, guys, when you use this data
provider class, the order
you must remember rate
the order you are following
to enter the credentials,
the username and password.
Okay?
And in the same order,
the way you enter the details in your data
provided,
you have to mention this parameter
string username is being password
or if there is any other parameter,
you have to make sure that this username
is coming under the username
and password is coming another person.
So all that is important to you.
Clear.
All right.
Now the next important point
today's the next important point here is
for three users.
Five users.
Let's 14 users. It is fine. Right?
Right now I have this country,
you 14 users also it is fine
even for 20 users.
What if I have 1000 users?
Is it a good idea to write this data?
It is less for 1000 users, no.
Right.
We do not have that much of time to write.
This data
provided a class for 1000 or 2000 users.
In that case, data
provided is not a good idea.
Remember,
if the volume of your data is small,
data provider is doable, is feasible,
but if the volume of your data is large,
your data provider is not visible.
In that case, we have to go with one
separate Excel file.
One separate is data file.
It could be Excel, it could be JSON,
it could be properties, it could be CSP,
it could be any other file. Right?
So in our framework, we will see how we
can pass our data from simply
static.
This is the answer to the question.
One is for records, right?
Well, is it
convenient for large volumes of data?
So the answer is for large
volume of data, it is not convenient
for small volume of data.
It is convenient for you, Mike.
You ask the question how it will identify
which one username password
I already answered the question right now.
The the third question you ask that
question as to remember can we change?
Can we change the size of any.
So on studies, Yes, we can change how?
Let me change it.
Instead of writing three,
I'm writing four.
Right.
And then one more username and password
I'm passing here.
Right.
Can you see here I have two plus three
common zero and here
I have to pass three one.
Right.
Because my for
my four draw is extended right here.
One right standard that is for true.
So I am passing this data for four to
the actually
not only here
but in every single framework
you have to implement that concept.
That's why we taught you that part.
Again, we will see how we can do that
and which is specific data
we need to pull out
from the Excel files. Right?
That is a separate session for that.
And do we do that for sure?
Don't worry about it. All right.
So this time, this time when I execute
my best guess, tell me, guys, across
how many users my best
guess will execute,
How many times my best guess will execute
or correct.
So let's go ahead and run.
Ideally, they should be private.
They should be public, right?
Because you never know you're
going to their accurate animator's rate.
So they should be public. You can use
in way
in real life examples being examples.
We don't use data provider
that often, right?
We use Excel by most of their times
since this is a part of syllabus
and you should know
in case if you come across a situation
where you have to implement
this data provider class, the next way
we are teaching you this concept, fine.
So now if you see the overall test
pass to and failure to write,
it means how many test scores
as it were executed for initial,
I have just one test case
since it executes across
four different sets of data.
What you see here is that four different
sets of data we are getting for
it means what
the size of your ETI can be changed
according to your requirement.
What is that answer to your question?
All right.
So so now
so far, data provider class is done.
Let's go and check the slides.
That ought to be right.
No, while we cross 52 already.
So data provider methods compared
and returns to the array of object
we have implemented.
We have seen the test were done
once for each set of data
is specified by the data object.
Data object.
Remember we have seen this data
that was the object.
This is the whole look for you guys.
What you have to do is you have to add
five different employees, right?
Using your data provider concept,
you have to pass false name,
last name, username and password.
All right?
And then you have to verify
that your employee has been added
successfully and then close the delta.
Okay.
This is your task.
Now the next topic is listener
fine.
Now let's talk about listeners
with important topic.
They before going into the listeners
right before going into the listeners,
let me ask
how many of you ways
you still remember the concept
of interface
right?
What you have inside interface based
methods without body correct
and implemented methods basically, here
we are going to talk about new topic,
which is listener, right
is the word is self-explanatory.
Listener means the one who listen. Right.
So here who is going to listen as the
listener is going listen us not right
while it's not is going to listen us.
We have to understand this.
Okay Remember, I'm going to write here
listeners fine
to listen
every minor detail
of our
of our execution
right.
We need
what we have to do,
basically, is if I want to monitor
all the small details,
I know we are getting the report.
That is fine.
We are getting so many other things.
That is also fine.
What listeners does basically if you want,
is specific going up information
in your execution report, in your output.
Right?
So the basic of listeners
we are which we are going to learn here,
it gives us some additional information,
right?
What it gives
maybe gives us some additional
information, which is very specific.
We can select which information
we need, which information we don't need.
All right.
Now, when I say we can select
which information we need
and which information we don't need, it
means would weaken,
provide the definition of method,
the body of the method
according to our own requirements.
Right
According to our own requirements,
we can define organic.
Vladimir We can define the body.
Now, when I'm saying we can define
the definition, we can define the body.
It means what?
We have to use one interface that
allocates.
We have to use one interface for this
name, right?
What is that interface?
Let's see this
listener is defined as an interface
that modifies
the default existing behavior.
Listeners implement the interface
which interface
I test Listener.
This is the interface
we have inside testing.
We are going to implement this test
engine.
Listen,
if I test listener right, I make the you.
What is this?
I tested this now
how we implement this particular listener
what are the implementation
methods or methods without bodies
are available inside this listener,
inside this interface
and how we can provide the body
of these methods.
Every single thing
we will see into returns.
I'm just trying to explain right now.
It is used in Selenium by implementing
the listener interface that can also find
now the next point it allows
customizing testing
did reports or results.
So there are many types of test engine.
This nurse available. Right?
We will see all of them.
We can define and change or modify
the test in default behavior.
Whatever the output we are getting.
As of now, we can change this point
according to our big flag.
To me, we can define our requirement,
our need inside the method of the body.
And then when we execute, this
listener will provide the output
according to our own requirements.
Ladies understood Concept of listener.
For example, for example
Node is working for some X-Y-Z clients.
IT Bank of New York.
Now in his in this project
there is a requirement
whatever the test
because this you are executing
I need the name of only
test cases which are paid
correct
in the report proclaimed can ask anything
great client can ask
to snatch some stars from the sky
and then you have to implement
that logic as well that if
so, clients is.
I need report in this report
you need to specifically mention
only those discuses the chirping.
At the same time
Mike is working for Amazon, Lexy
and in his project
the requirement is I need execution
reports having the name
only for those test scores which are
correct
guys listening to me or not.
Now know that
if that is something else,
what I am saying basically is
both Mike and Node are using simplest
in the project.
Correct.
At the same time, they're working
for both different clients and these two
different clients customers are asking
for two different requirements.
One states use test and G.
Give me the report inside your default.
I need only those test cases
which are paid
the name of those test cases
at the same,
another customer is asking for the report
having all the names of those tests
because this skip
right when you have same structured when,
you have same framework.
When you have same default behavior.
How you can generate to different
report is nurses.
I have an interface, implement
my interface, implement me
all of my methods,
and then give the definition, the method,
the body of my methods according to
your own needs right, we got the solution.
We've been going
to implement
this particular listener interface
and then in the method body we will
provide the body according to our need.
Correct.
That is makes sense.
Fine.
So now explanation is done,
definition is done.
Let's implement it.
I'm going to write you as
business.
Okay.
Right.
So this in this next class.
Now I said
if I have to implement
any interface in Java,
which keyboard
I have to use, implement state,
so I'm going to write, implement
which listener I
we connect
originates now.
Now if you go here,
if these
types of listener interests and you can
you see
I astute listener I reporter
I am method interceptor
I'm going to use this I test listener
this one we are going to use
now inside
this listener I have on start method
on finish on to start on first year
artist Skip
right on this success
I recognize
I this listener
now we are going to implement
all of these methods one by okay
so I'm going to write here public
mind.
I will stay on this
part here
because I'm going to use my it.
So another is I test, I test
it is right
I'm going to get for every single method,
then I'm going to implement. Right.
This interface in every method, I'm
going to capture the result.
Okay. So here I'm going to write the body.
So my body would be let's think
that I'm going to write right now.
Very simple requirement, right?
I'm not going to take any advanced part
because we are keeping it
for our framework in framework.
We will implement a couple of more things.
Right now since this is a basic
and the elements of testing.
So I'm telling you the basics of listener
so that you guys can easily digest it.
All right. I'm going to write here
the starting test
with the
what does it mean?
This particular
method on test is start returns the name
the name of the test case,
which is going to execute it first,
which is going to execute it for us.
So I'm going to write the design dot, get
on test
start
method will give you the name of the test
which will execute
in the starting of the execution.
Clear
The first method which we have implemented
on test start.
I can customize this message as well.
You can write
whatever the method you want to write.
Okay.
Yes, exactly.
Exactly.
The first test is the first test you need.
It will give you that.
Now let's take another method.
So I'm going to write
public void
on test of success.
So again, the first thing is
I test result because that is it.
I'm going to capture
and inside this I'm going to write it is
this is
test fast, right?
And then if you want to
take the name again so you can start
gaining
radiance or you can simply write
one more thing here like this, it's just
we are
we are capturing the
final screenshot at the end after success.
If your test is success,
you are taking the screenshot.
So you're writing this,
you can customize it, right?
Like I said,
according to your own requirement.
Now the third one, the third one is public
void on test
it right for the starting
for success for Skip.
So again,
I just I'm going to write here.
Fine And then I'm going to write this
if it's success is
the name correct?
It's the start.
Then test sex is then test done.
All right, now see another one
or test failure rate
test case is.
And then I will capture
the name of the test.
Correct.
Now The next one is
I'm going to take
another one. See?
Just come on.
I'm going to write another method called
There is another method
inside this on test failure,
but within
this percentage.
All right.
So in this one also,
we need to pass this test result.
And then let's see,
I'm going to pass here.
This just
anyway, you're not going to use
all of these methods, right?
You will use either for test to start,
test to success test skimmed this to fail.
But still I'm telling you
all the other methods as well.
All the methods which again have yet
for these important
methods are already implemented.
Right.
So let me give you to the last one.
I'm going to write public
void on start point on
like 16, the 16,
this one on test failure
but within success percentage.
This one someone
going to
that's fine.
So now another thing here
is I'm going to write
I test
on fact I'm going to write this context
as well
to get the actual context
of your test cases.
So here I'm not going to put anything
because method is not going to use much.
And then the last one I'm going to write
is for on
finish again the same.
So nobody because I don't need it.
On test Failure on Best Escape
Artist Success on test is start.
I have used this this nurse implements my
I test listener interface right now.
How these methods work
how this all of this methods work
this is something noticeable right
We have all these things with us.
But the point is how we can implement it,
how we can use
this particular list
in this class for my project, remember?
So let me explain you this point.
Where do I go?
If you see guys
in our project, we have,
let's say one, two,
three, four.
If you have four classes like this
or we have so many classes, I'm
just taking the example of four classes.
We have one configuration file.
What is the name of configuration
file based
in our test?
And we have
there is no property file.
We have great so far in our test
and we have DOT exemplified by
this is my configuration file, right?
It's just in Duratex.
So now what I want basically is
I'm going to write my list
net inside one class.
So this is my list.
Say I want to use this list.
Not across my class one, Class two,
Class three, class four everywhere.
So do I need to remind this list?
Not everywhere.
No. What I need to do
is I need to define this list.
No, In my standard or text.
From here, I'm going to get
my final report.
But in my this test
and do not take will file if you'll see
my a seven part
C to buy C three and C four.
All these four classes are covered.
Right?
All these four classes can be executed
from test and do not accessible fine.
So this is my common execution point.
This test segment is my common execution
point
from where I can execute
all of this classes at the same time.
At the same time, I want to utilize this
listener concept across all of my classes.
So what is the best place to put this?
The best place
to put this listener in my configuration?
Correct.
When I execute my test and do not examine
it, will use this listener
for all this classes.
It will give me the report
according to my own requirements.
Gauteng
Does it make sense?
The diagram in the explanation
make great.
Now the next point
which we are going to do is
we are going to implement this list
next in our question.
So let's say this is our test and class,
correct?
Let's deliver this group.
We don't need this group
any more right now.
We don't need it.
I'm going to write my list
next before test.
Right?
Even if I have multiple tests,
my list will be executed.
Right. For Will execute across all this.
So it will be defined above test.
All right.
I'm going to write it phase.
You'll see this step coming.
Right, listeners, inside this list.
Next, it will ask for the listener.
Right.
And inside
which class have this list nervous?
Tell me
that I have listener
guides.
Can you see
what is the part
correct
Class C
Listener's correctness.
Now, now let me do one thing.
Can we take any class right
for the listener, for example, I'm
going to take the basic one next C
the precondition
and the post condition one.
This is the class.
So my class name is precondition
in post condition.
Okay, fine.
I will go get
inside of my package.
One right, the class, one package.
I'm going to write it for class one
dot in.
Let's take any class
from class to find Don.
So if I go into by a C my any other one?
Let's see
if white is not taking me the class one.
What happened to that?
There is no column
class one package I'm going to take.
But it is not taking
it is not allowing me.
It is just giving me two options.
Class two in three.
There is no C straight here.
This is what I'm thinking.
If I know what is, what I will do
basically is
let me copy this class from here.
Right here. Auto moving.
All right. Nice.
I'm copying my post
condition class from my, say,
package class one, two, package
class three.
Would that be okay?
Right.
I just copied one class.
Not a big deal
from one package to another.
One dot.
Now it is giving me
this particular class point.
Now see,
inside of my class three listener
business notes is available right
when I try to execute this.
Not observe this ridiculous
before class
executed before my third executed it.
This is starting first with the name
first method
color code
inside listener's.
Okay, let's do it
in my list
notes.
Let me define unique messages right.
Let's not is
starting first with the name right?
The listener has asked
that first
and then again here
Listener.
It's Skip case.
It's not nothing.
Their kids tickets is fine.
No, no, no, no.
Record is not possible.
Nothing else look different color.
You mean to put any external or something
year old
in the console
you're talking about?
No, because isn't normal.
So that's
I mean the normal class
that maybe everything normally class
we are writing, it's class.
So I don't think it is possible.
Now come on and do not act similarly.
We have implemented it here.
Okay,
now see it this time because I put more
descriptive messages
right inside this part.
So now we will see
more clear output This time.
What I'm
trying to show is when you put listener,
it executes all the test cases
the way it was executing earlier,
but this time it will give you additional
information, what information?
The information you need
according to your own requirements.
It will give you that information. Right?
So if you see it, this list is a starting
test with this name.
Name It captured the first test,
It executed.
It is going to execute
which test it is mentioning here.
And you see
then after passing exams, Miss
none has bothered test
and we are capturing the final screenshot.
Correct.
Now list starting
first with the name again.
The new test gives one.
It is going to execute.
It is giving you that name
after passing your sister's bars.
But the test
and we are capturing the final screenshot.
Correct
is starting
their test and final positive screenshot.
Now why we are not getting any message
for failing to skip
10 minutes.
Yes, that isn't this total test
run three passes three
when all of them pass.
We are not getting nothing.
The estate.
Now let's do one thing.
Let's go inside this class
and here I'm going to write
for this particular message,
this particular method I'm going to write.
Let's see,
is this condition true or false?
They tell me.
So this test will pass or fail
will connect.
Now let me execute my test
and do not exemplify this type.
Can you see the difference now?
How many of you guys can see this
list?
Not failed the test case?
Which test is second method? Right?
So it completely depends
on your floor execution on your results.
Now the same execution is happening,
but the result is changing.
According to the the output is changing
according to results.
Right now,
if Mike wants all the test cases
which are skipped,
you can implement if no once
all their test cases which are free ticket
they the same items.
No class you both have to implement
and then for your different customers
try to fulfill their different needs.
You can use the same interface. Yes.
Okay.
This is what let's let's test inside list
now we can do one more thing.
What whenever test gets
will take this screenshot
Whenever test gives us
take the screenshot.
If test is to skip, skip
to take the screenshot.
And what? Let's not do this.
Let's take the screenshot of your test
cases.
This whether it is fail
or it is closed or it is skipped.
All right is Skip.
This gives us some time signature
Mike you're executing test get this right
now because of so much load
your application so much load
on your machine Sometimes your machine
is skipping some of your test. It's
okay.
It means
it is not able to execute your best guess.
That's what we call it.
Skip.
This gives now when it is skipped
this for which all other test cases
that have been skipped by your browser
or your machine, it will take,
it will make a report and it will give you
the name of all those tests.
It's clear.
All right, guys.
So far in these constants, whatever
the concepts
are we need to do it on.
Yes, Yes, we need to we will see that
it is a part of framework.
How to do you don't know if your think
that this is our building on this
and if we don't
but we will see that, correct?
Correct.
That's
what I explained in the starting point.
You can customize your output
state
view when you're writing the code, right?
You're writing the code
and the recording is already available.
Right.
For SML class, you can go there.
All right or I will share that with video
also for that so that you can go
and you can check
how to create the classes.
Well,
obviously, Mom, without practice,
nothing can be done.
Nothing can be achieved.
Practice
is must every single point of time.
Practice is must.
All right.
So is so far the topics
which we have discussed.
Do you guys have any question or is there
anything that you guys understand yet?
Yeah, sure.
So from from my package one, right.
Everyone has this package.
This is the class, right?
This is the class.
I copy
all how to copy out.
So first,
just go into your class one package
inside your class, one just write
control, see?
All right, click here and then select
control, See or copy from here.
Right.
Once you copy it,
Come on.
Once you copy
it, click on your current package.
Where do you want to pasted right click?
And then based here or simply control,
see from here and control
B here right
now. Is it clear
more then?
Does it make sense for everyone? No.
You're
more most welcome. So.
All right,
So now let's move on to the new topic.
That's how we generally implement
our listener part
implementation done
lights are completed,
not topics.
So we are not going to
look into this lights
any more here because lights are done.
State topic is pending.
All right, one more topic.
We are done with the basic of this.
Okay, fine.
Now putting
know like I say, slides
and not topics
right now.
Let me ask one thing, guys.
One hour only.
Nobody.
Yes Break is also here for 10 minutes,
maybe 15 minutes.
Yeah.
I'm always open for negotiation days
getting.
All right.
So now let me ask one thing, guys.
You are very hard
working professional in your company
and you are writing your code days
and nights all the time straight.
You are not going online.
Journal Wayland Breaks.
You're not taking any vacation.
Still,
you guys are working on your weekends
and every single thing you're doing.
After three months, you guys have executed
and you guys have written.
I, I was also in the company.
That's why I'm like, I saw you
go for consistent three months.
Then you worked this much hard.
You wrote 500 test.
Get this.
All right with editing test annotation
500 times, you wrote 500 test cases.
Now, after 2 hours,
you have a meeting with your client.
All right, let's after one hour,
do you have a meeting with your client?
Your client needs one thing, Words
that your client needs to make sure
that whatever the things you have
written so far, you want to execute.
So he needs report
because after one hour your client,
you have a meeting with your client,
and your client wants to show
all these things
to the senior management, right?
Your client will not ask you
to give the report after one hour. Why?
Because in the presentation,
he also needs to get this report correct.
Your He needs to read the report
in the presentation.
So what he needs,
they make you have 500 because.
Yes I do have
quite good and executive in 5 minutes
and give me the reports in 10 minutes.
I will put it in my PowerPoint
presentation.
And after one hour when we are meeting,
I will open up
this light and Mike will drive the show
and he will explain this.
It is a static.
Now you have a situation where you execute
500 cases in 5 to 10 minutes.
If you see the current structure.
What we have right now here, right,
if you come across this situation,
can you execute 500 test
cases in 5 minutes?
Can you do that?
Yeah.
If you ask this question,
they will stop that in three weeks.
They will avoid it.
The noise.
And my question is with the current setup.
Right.
The current setup
which we have as of now. Right.
With this setup.
But you guys think it is possible
to execute your test cases,
which are 500 in just 5 minutes?
No, we do not have any existing.
So to break.
Got it.
Now now let me show you
let me show you the approach
for doing one approach.
Why extended test?
And this is yes,
you have how many test cases is this?
500 test And this is. Go ahead.
We will execute it.
Right. How we can execute it, guys, this
is the topic we are going to implement now
that I give you the
overview, I give you the requirement.
What is the need now? Solution.
All right, let's going
I'm going to create
or do you want me to create new test
and it takes similar failure.
This one is fine.
What you want new
so the effector
this one I'm going to write test
G three defective
and to create a new one.
The existing guy is still
the guy is didn't fix this issue
See how arrogant the guys are?
They are not ready to fix this issue.
It is available
every single day for this building.
This building create
client.
So I got this test, a new detection
missile, guys.
Correct
static.
Now always tell me how we can
automate automated.
I gave you the command last week,
correct.
Go. I'm happy to see that
Everyone knows it.
Fine.
So what I'm going to do is
I'm going to delete all of
these methods in the classes
which I don't need yet
because I have so many.
Right?
So I'm just deleting
all the classes and like I'm keeping
just do not one
just to
I'm not even talking about the method. So
like any
if you're not getting this option,
what you have to do right.
Let me share that video
once again. Bitrate.
I already gave you the video How to create
this test in do not accessible fight.
Okay.
What need to do is
you need to go inside your modules
and check first time to create the test
and you it from there.
All right.
So I will I will give that. All right.
If we keep discussing the topics straight
from the last week,
we will not be able to budget for that.
All right.
It is already in session recorded, right?
No, no worries.
No, I can totally understand
that you are not able to relate with this
because you missed that point.
I can totally understand.
But what are your difference
for your help?
I'm saying this wasn't.
Can you please help any to create a test?
Do not accessible fine.
By the time I'm just writing this
so that it would be helpful for her
and then she will be able to understand
what we are doing here.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
All right.
Any your problem is resolved, you can go
ahead and create this test already.
Already.
Let's proceed further.
Fine. So now what I'm going to do is here.
First, let's talk about list now.
Right? We are taking the list.
That is the list.
That is something
we are going to consider it as a
necessary evil.
Right
inside this,
I'm going to write the code
for my listener right
class name required.
So it is my it's not available days
that is correct
or not.
Now, I am going to write
a couple of things here.
See, I'm going to write my test
name as
well.
Latest.
Okay.
I don't need anything.
See? Fine, fine.
I'm not doing anything right.
Guess what I did?
I just added one listener
so far and I am just renaming test.
Especially test right
now. Next thing
I posted for
the next thing
is I'm going to write
as can you see this tab parallel?
It says you want to execute
your math impediment.
It means let's say you have
three different test in your one class.
You want to execute
all this three in person.
Then I'm going to say yes methods.
If you want to execute classes,
experiment, you will write classes.
I'm going to write a methods.
Method means what?
The request annotations clear, guys clear
and the request annotation part.
And then
I'm going to write it
as the count as equals to three.
It means what? Maximum?
Maximum three thread you need to execute.
You can generate three type
write.
Now let's consider any class.
For example, my
data provider class
right inside of my data provider class.
How many test I have right now is one.
Can we do it three yet?
Come on.
Is it correct?
Grace I have to test in my data
provided class now.
Correct.
What I did, I just copied my same method.
So more times. Okay.
My same method. Just two more times.
So all in all, three test
I have now in my data
provider class
or let me do one thing right.
I'm not going to copy this first.
I'll keep it as it is.
Okay, fine.
This is my data provider class.
I'm going to create completely new class.
Okay.
So that
it would be easy for you to understand.
I'm going to write a new class
as bad and then
test this to correct.
Is this correct?
New class?
I now take any class.
Any class, right there.
We have multiple data available, right?
Multiple test available.
So I'm taking only my data provider class
because in my data provider
I have right now one test case,
but I can make it to three as well.
Just give me a moment based.
I didn't copy anything so partial.
Okay, I'm going to copy this class only.
Right.
So let me copy this.
Fine control.
See, it is split up my performance. Now.
See you correct
again.
If you want to see how I copied
going to data provider,
copy the code and paste it in
your parallel test.
Test class.
Correct.
Okay.
Case for you everyone.
Now let's create a simple test for this.
Well, log in to
log in three.
Fine.
When I say we need log in,
we have to put in the correct way.
This is my username.
This is my password. Right.
And let me delayed this third one
and then I have to change this one to
do. And this one to do.
This one to
any confusion.
Any confusion.
Why I change this data
and how I changed it.
I don't want to execute it
for full different users.
Again, I am just shrinking
the size of my eddy, right?
So how many users I have here
is three username three password.
Correct.
Since I am going to use this data
for a valid log in.
Remember for valid log in.
So I should use only valid data rate.
So I'm using validity. Correct.
This is my valid data.
It will execute not only in this method
but also in this method
and in this method.
All in all, I have home in it
just because this guys tell me. So
let's go inside our test class now.
This is my class I am going to execute
so which is available in my package
dart class three dart
this test to
detect.
I'm calling this class, right?
I'm calling this class
now how it will execute.
At the same time, I'm going to take
another class as well along with this.
So this another class, finally,
when I say parallel is equal to method,
it means your test.
India's asking, Hey, you want to execute
in parallel fine based on what?
I need to distribute your test cases.
So I said, distribute
my test cases in parallel
based on the methods
when I same methods go inside your class.
This is your one method.
This is your another method.
This is yet another method. Correct.
So it will distribute
your test cases based on your method form.
Correct. When you mentioned here.
Here parallel is equal to methods.
It distributes of your test cases
based on your methods.
Got it.
Inside this class
you have how many methods?
No issues.
It will be distributing betterment
inside this class.
We how many methods, right?
No issues.
It will distribute that in methods.
All right,
So let me take any class, let's say
sort a solution to find class, right?
How many tests we have to write.
It means soft assertion.
Two is something we can take.
So I'm going to take it in my test and
you're not closing that tab.
You're not closing the tab
if you'll see rate test started.
But it doesn't. And it didn't. Right.
So you have to end it.
Also, there's the reason
parallel is equals to methods
should come before
this greater than single.
Alright
so now see guys
here I'm
going to write for my soft assertion.
Now if you see I have multiple this
because this year
in two classes
so far these parallel methods
better latest data count
three two classes.
This class we have created, this class
we have taken from previous package
so far in this in this code writing.
You guys have any question
before even execution?
I'm asking it
so that I can write it once again.
I can explain it once again from scratch.
Do you guys have any
gains, disability
or status? Yes.
Yes. Static, Correct.
If you want to increase or decrease,
that is also fine like this.
I'm asking all in all, five are.
No, not actually should read.
And then execution means see.
Let me tell you what is it?
What is the meaning of parallel execution?
This is my mistake.
I didn't explain that part.
First wire diagram.
You guys need diagram explanation. First,
you have
come on.
Now, I'm
not able to attach my digital board
here because I my optical mouse.
Fine.
But still, I can explain.
Now, see, guys,
what I'm trying to show you is here.
Let's say you have
this one, this two,
and it's three, right?
Three test.
Should please
make sure what what I'm explaining.
Right. These are benchmark attention.
Should if I already explain,
read this parallel in line nine.
What is this better in line?
So let me tell you once again,
it means it will distribute
your test cases during execution
based on the methods and the request.
Annotation is what it is
your distribution points.
So let's say
you have this much of methods which
will execute all of them in parallel.
Now see two types of execution have
right now
we are doing this is what we called
sequential execution.
What is sequential execution?
It means first one will execute first
when test, one will execute first.
After completion of test,
one institute will execute our
this to test three will execute.
Right.
This is what we call sequential execution
in a sequence right now.
Let's see if this is taking 2 seconds.
This is taking 3 seconds.
This is taking 2 seconds.
So what is the total execution time?
The total execution time is 7 seconds.
I'm just giving one example.
Now, when this experiment
is equal to methods, this is already test.
This is a dry test.
This is a direct correct.
When, say, parallel is equal to methods.
What it will do,
it will execute one at the same time.
It will open another browser and executes
due to at the same time
it will open another browser
and it will execute speed. The
it takes 2 seconds,
it takes 2 seconds, it takes 3 seconds.
Fine.
Overall result will come in.
How much time? Just in 3 seconds are near.
You were executing this things
in 7 seconds.
Now you're executing this things in 3
seconds.
Got it.
This is what we call the pattern
execution.
Yeah, correct.
Even if it is one class
in multiple methods,
it will execute these things in parallel.
All the methods.
Number of methods.
Correct? Correct.
Shall we execute is ready for. This
Melia.
We can take five. We can take three.
I just take four. Right. It's up to you.
You can take anyone.
Can you see the latest steps?
This officer trained two classes on
executing in parallel.
Right?
It is opening the browser fine.
Yes. Yes, exactly.
Can you see too many Chrome's
available now?
Right?
If you go here it is
executing something else.
It executing something else.
It is executing thing is it is executing
something else for different test.
Get this. You'll see why.
My third count is how much four four
is available here.
Computer That is great. Don't worry.
See, I will give you the downsides
of this as well.
No issues. Yes. Why? Four?
Because my fourth
grade account was there. They
see. I'm just
checking one by one, one by one.
Now see four threads open.
If I have ten test kits. My six.
I've been waiting a stage.
Okay.
Once I'm done with this four,
then it will come the remaining six,
then four will come in another batch.
Now see, it is reducing metrics. Why?
It is reducing my threads
because my test kits are completing again.
It opened one right?
It will not open more than four
more than four windows. Why?
Because my trade account is four.
So eight one time,
four test kits will execute.
Now see, one is closing, one is opening,
one is closing, one is opening.
So it is just going on and on.
Builder time why it is coming like this
Because in my data provider class
I have three test.
In three test I am passing data
from three username and password.
It means the main test. Yes.
All in all I have from data provider.
So I'm having from softer side.
All in all, I am executing how much I am
executing 11 main plus 211 right.
With the help of four things.
Right right now the question is
if I execute all
of them one by one,
everything was passing,
right?
Everything was passing.
Can you see how many browsers it points?
One, two, three, four.
After some time another browser open right
after some time, another browser open.
See it says is a limit instant eliminate
exception.
All my in print right
when you this
when you do this next to the client.
I read they did that also
now tell me guys first thing
now just for better results
I'm going to delete one class.
I'm taking this one
class called soft assertions here.
I have two methods, right?
So let me again execute it.
Just two methods. I'm not giving much.
No on my system.
Otherwise my system will crash.
Your system will crash.
Everyone's system will crash.
Okay.
See two times opening the browser.
Can you see here it is opening
the browser two times this two tabs open
even though I have four three count, but
I have what I two has to do will not use.
Just two will use here. Right. You'll see
it is executing just in
the two browser.
Right.
Test two paused one find invalid log
in is passed when it log in page.
You don't see no.
Yes, exactly.
Now see what is the problem
when you use this in in parallel,
the first disadvantage is it
gives a lot of load on your processor,
on your machine, on your device.
All right.
It reduces the overall performance
of your application
if you're executing
and if you're generating so many threaded
one time rate, so many trades at one time,
obviously it will increase the load.
When it increases the load,
your application
has to send responses
on all the browser at one time.
Right?
This is practically not possible
to provide equal response
on all the browser.
Sometimes it passes the correct response,
sometimes it doesn't.
Right.
Because so many tricks, so many requests
are coming in better than execution.
Right.
So this type of better execution is not
what are the.
But still people are executing things
in parallel.
Then why? What is the alternative to this?
So The alternative, I add 45 processor.
Yes, vintage supercomputer.
But remember, we have alternative
with the same kind of process.
And what is this?
We have seen indium great.
What we have,
guys, it's been indium. Great.
I hope you guys have learned this.
Selenium components.
Selenium RC is the minimum.
It is the minimum driver in Selenium.
Great, great guys.
Yes, Correct. My
guys.
How many
of you guys have heard about Selenium?
Great.
Yeah. Great, great,
great, great.
So basically, I hope you guys have studied
the components of selenium
rates and indium RC, Selenium, IED,
Centennial Driver and Selenium grade.
No worries. I will tell you this.
What happens is
fine.
So basically
up earlier
when selenium come, it came with one on 80
that maybe heavy JD up
dimension that yes we have eclipse 80.
Similarly
selenium used to come with its own 80
the minimum 80. Okay
now this selenium,
it was not that helpful.
So they came up with a new tool
called Odyssey Remote Control,
Selenium with remote control.
Obviously it was not remote control like
this or any other remote control, Right.
It was a soft remote control,
but then also it was out of school.
Right. People didn't use.
Then they came up with selenium primer.
So now what is the
can someone please send?
So I think I'm missing something.
Can someone please send a copy of this?
Call the paste this code in the check
associated to Mars.
They will.
Thank you, Jim.
On now
selenium the driver.
The best part is you can integrate
the selenium with driver,
with your existing project,
with your existing ID.
Right. You can use it.
So now the point was
there were so test cases we identified
and there was a need to execute
all of them in a single shot.
Then they came up with a concept called
Selenium.
Great in the synonym grade.
What you generally do is it is
a combination of multiple systems, right?
It is a combination of multiple systems
where you make one host and multiple fault
rate,
one server
or multiple port from one device.
You control the execution
from all the devices and then you execute
test cases in parallel.
So at one time you can execute
five, ten, 15, even 20 test
guesses and the efficiency of execution
in selenium,
great is higher than testing there.
But you won't get this much of real test
cases correct right now
when you're executing you in five
or six are getting many them are failed.
Why they are failed
because this is not efficient.
PURNELL Execution is fine for two or three
or four tests.
This is fine by act
destined for large volume of test cases.
Yes, we need selenium grade.
We need a specific, dedicated cloud
such as Perfecto in market.
There is a cloud called Perfecto. Right.
So it gives you dedicated system
which are available.
Obviously it is up to the base, so
don't even think of purchasing it perfect.
But what it does,
they generally provide perfect.
You guys generally provide dedicated
system for the execution of your own
best guess, right? Of your own project.
So let's say you hired
three server services there
on selling them grade in Perfecto.
So that three high process sort
system will be dedicated
only for your execution, right?
So there you will get more efficiency.
But yes, nothing comes free.
Nothing comes for free.
Okay, For free.
We have stingy for free.
We have selenium. Great.
All right.
So testing in parallel, we are done.
So for any question how to execute test
cases in parallel using test.
And you know to like
any question based, not efficient,
not failure, actually not efficient
guys better
look, this thing is useful judgment.
That's what I'm saying.
Selenium. Great.
We have read like I say,
that is also parallel testing and incident
that is more efficient. Yes.
Right. Exactly.
So for example, but it is recommended
way to keep your protocols
as near as possible.
So it will not give much distress
and much load on your device.
Correct.
So your test is
so you can execute them in 3 to 1 type.
Like instead of executing authentic
one time,
it will give lot of note on your system.
You can keep just two or three
and then at one time it will execute
towards the best cases.
Oregon. Yes.
Muscle? Yes. Correct.
In many organization,
if you go, there will be the right.
You will be
you will find this selenium great concept.
This.
All right.
So first let me come with the code
is so far any confusion,
any doubt,
anything you guys didn't understand code?
I've already pushed in the repository.
You will find this code there
every single thing.
You will go from there.
Now, so far, whatever the things we do,
every single thing
I pushed onto the repository.
But my question is from the extension
part,
from the understanding part,
conceptual wise,
do you guys have any doubt
yet what in
every single thing is on
every single thing,
nor you're deleting the name, right?
If you delete the name of your test of,
this it will give you the error.
The very first thing.
What I did was I just to make this
upgrade goes
I would say just two or three or four,
not more than that.
Yeah, it can do that. Mike,
your question is fine.
Let's say I have five thread count, but
I have just to test against that is fine.
All this thread count
takes care of your number of threads
open for every single class.
What example here if you have this this
then it will execute for it one time
because my state accounted for.
Okay.
I have so many open,
I have to close all of them.
Yes. Yes.
You can say it is in a batch. Right.
So for for and then to break like this.
Yeah.
That includes exactly.
All right, guys,
any other
question?
All wheel drive,
all the method in one class, Not in,
but that's like
again, like, true.
Even I never implement
this in my company site I have dealt with
so far how many projects even don't
remember that count.
I never did this there I've been in
unless I have some dedicated
cloud for my project.
I never implement this
because the selenium grid already company.
So we are using selenium.
All right obviously you go for the reason
why you never put it in, but it
got it done.
Well see these are their topics, right?
These are the topics of your test energy.
So we have to explain each and everything.
Make then
implement. Experiment is equal to methods.
Data count is equal
to five index security of 500 test This
When you want to execute your
classes in parallel,
then you use parallel is equal to classes.
Okay.
All right.
So guys, you guys need break now
or we can continue.
All right, let's take a break, guys.
Come on.
Go ahead, guys.
I don't have any facility for this yet.
All right, So let's meet after 40 minutes.
Maybe
one for, one for
I think we did already for team.
All right, guys, break for 15 minutes.
See you guys up in 15 minutes.
Okay.
All right, guys.
So now what we are going to do is so far
we discussed
how we can create the listeners,
how we can execute our test
cases in parallel mode.
Right?
But one thing I can see
whenever I go inside to my classes here,
see how many classes
I have data for later class.
So whenever I go inside of my class, I'm
my deconditioning connect.
I'm using my post condition here
right?
If I go in my latest stuff
again using the condition
again, I'm using post condition.
If I go in any other package, let's
if this is my package
again,
my precondition, again my post condition,
it means more
the same code, the same piece of code.
I am repeating again and again and again.
So let's see if I have 100 classes.
I am going to write hundred times
precondition hundred times post condition.
That's what we are doing right now.
Correct.
I need one improvement in my project.
What improvement the improvements is.
I don't want to write this condition
in post condition and break times
in big classes.
I need to write this three
and post condition
just one time in my project
and this one time mentioning B condition
post condition will execute
across all the hundred classes.
This one where we have this form.
Can you tell me
in our project
in Centennial where that's
what I'm asking form is a file
right where we have this form
finding that project.
Then we have
you have eight but we do not have bom
bom is completely irrelevant topic
as of now right.
We're not talking about bom
because bom is something else.
Now we are talking about
customization, the improvements
we need to make, right?
We don't need to write
this much of things here
and there and there
and there's so many preconditions
and conditions.
No, we are not going to use it.
Yes, we can do that.
We can do that.
But for that we need to understand
what is BOM where we find this form,
how we can use form
and then we can integrate with this
form is on the way.
It is in the pipeline,
it is on the way right now.
Form doesn't exist in our project.
Now to do this,
I have to make some configurations.
What kind of configuration?
See if I'm in. Right.
If I'm trying to log in here,
I'm trying to log in
here also everywhere.
This is fine.
We are using data provider class,
but in all the classes are
we providing data provider law?
We are passing this admin password
every time we need
password values at the same time.
Let's see, I'm executing my script
right now on Chrome browser.
I want to execute my script on Chrome
and Firefox on IP or it on safari
and opera on five browsers,
one script executing on five browsers.
This is what we call
cross browser testing right.
If I want to do it
with this existing setup, can I do that?
No. Right.
So these are the loopholes I can see
in my existing structure, correct?
In my current setup,
I can see all these loopholes.
We will overcome all these things
one by one, plain phosphate.
We will talk about configurations.
What is the configuration,
the configuration that says which browser
you need to select, which application
you are trying to navigate,
which user name you are trying to use,
which password you are trying to use.
Correct.
You can send the browser
and in Firefox find it will execute you
the script on Firefox, you will see
Chrome, it will execute a script on call,
you will see Oprah,
it will execute on Oprah.
You'll see it execute my all this
a script on syntax
and when we find user Amazon environment
fine you just need to change your data.
One place you don't need to pass
this you are in here anymore,
right?
First thing you need to pass
your username and password yet anymore.
You don't need to do this now.
The configuration
which we are going to make
in such a way that the one place
we will change the things
and this things will be applicable
to all of my project process.
Okay, these are the configurations
we are going to make now.
Make sense.
Let's go ahead and do this
first thing.
What we have to do is
we have to put some of the basic
configurations
like template correctly.
You see,
we need to put basic configuration.
I'm going to start
with very basic configuration. Great.
So to do that, let's create
a completely new package.
Okay?
I'm going to create
a completely new package.
My package name,
I'm going to write as config.
What is this config?
I'm going to write
all my configurations inside this.
All right?
Remember when you write this config fight,
you create one class,
you will create one file.
Basically having an extension, call
it dot properties
because you are creating
some of the properties.
So do that.
You need to create one file
having the extension corridor properties.
If you ever deal with this DOT properties,
find this.
Is there anyone dot properties, correct.
Right. In Java.
So let's do that the same thing.
How can we create I don't know ways
tell me how to create content there
properties
is this correct
or not.
Can you see
I am consider properties now insight
is that anyone who has a confusion
how I created this fight
the click on the complete package new file
and then right confident properties.
This file will open up here.
I'm to pass some of the properties.
For example,
the first property is my browser.
So what is my browser?
Let's say I'm using my chrome as of now.
The second thing is that
you are all of my application.
So from there I can see that you are in
any from any class.
Let's see here I'm going and I'm copying
this property.
Hard thing
is I'm going to write my user name here,
which is paid to me.
And fourth thing
I'm going to write as my password quality
just for things.
I'm thinking guys see
my browser name of web browser.
If we will create a setup like this,
if you just change from here
instead of chrome Firefox,
it execute your script on Firefox.
We will going to make this system break
for that you are in.
You will pass from here.
You will
pass username and password from here.
These are something which we are passing
in almost every single class,
but we are writing the code again
and again and again.
I don't want to write code again
and again.
I'm going to write it at one place
and I want to utilize it with this.
Getting my point
so far. So
now this is my properties file, right?
This is my properties.
Like I need to read these properties as we
are getting my point
days, I need to read these properties
as well or not
because this is just an explanation.
This is just a declaration, right?
I need to read these properties.
To do that,
I am going to create another package here.
In this package,
I'm going to I'm going to write.
I'm going to keep all of the code
which is coming under the category
of utilities.
What are the utilities?
For example,
I want to write all of my common steps.
I want to write all of my reader classes
and every single thing
I will write inside utilities.
These utilities help us in executing
our test case throughout our classes
available in my project.
All right, let me write your class
the very first thing.
Remember, guys,
this is your configured property by
you have written some of the properties,
but still you cannot use this properties
directly in your project VI
because this is not the Java code.
You are using Java code.
So now you need some Java code,
you need some Java code
that can read this particular properties
site.
Correct?
Correct. Or not really.
We need some Java code.
So to do that,
what I'm going to do is inside
my utils I'm going to write another class.
Let me create a class called
on Big Reader.
This is my class
y configurator because in my config
reader class in my configurator class,
I am going to read all the properties
from property properties.
All right.
This is the point from where
I can use
all of my properties in my project, right?
I'm trying to translate my Bon
Java stuff into Java
step by using this configurator class.
So far so good, right?
Should you pursue further,
I'm going to write your public
safety by
reading the properties.
All right.
I'm going to read the properties.
So the properties of what?
One file,
which file considered properties by.
So I'm going to write here
the file, but the file path
of which file
my considered properties file.
But I'm going to utilize here.
Okay.
So if you read some file, there is a class
which I'm going to use
which class classes that
remember one file
input stream.
How many of you guys know this file input
stream class.
All right.
We generally use this particular class to
check out a file right to check on file.
Now it is giving me one.
And what is that?
It says an exception to method signature Y
because under
the exception file, not found
what we should do.
In that case.
Is this out with private resources?
Try catch block
all what it does.
Let me read it
and let me write it inside of my catch.
BLOCK So inside my catch block, I'm
going to write it
like this
file not found exception.
It is giving to find.
And here I'm going to write.
I'm not going to stick place
right now.
Is this correct? No.
Now I'm going to do one thing
because the state is reading
the properties.
The file is still yet to be implemented.
So I'm going to implement that code
properties.
Right.
To read the properties,
I have to call my properties
class and here I'm going to write this
post.
I'm going load the flight.
Fine. Again, it is giving me an error.
Now what is this error?
Let's check once again.
I'll input a stream list Java.
I'll input stream of three.
This should be loaded
because I have the load.
Fine.
Now it is giving me again
the exception that is Iowa exception.
Fine.
One more exception.
It means one more cricket block.
So I already have.
I'm going to put my
which block gets block.
So I'm going to write it if I
exception E
and he and again, I'm going to write it
that if
remember you have opened the file,
you have load the properties,
you have read it, but don't forgot,
don't forget to close this file.
So if I start close, you have to close it.
Also right
after reading, you have to close it also
getting my
point guys,
so far in this code, any computer,
this is just one method,
just the one generic function
which will read all of my properties
from the properties file.
And if I use this particular function
anywhere, anywhere
in my project, it will give me the result
of from the properties.
Fine. Correct.
Now, if I observe closely
in my continuous properties file,
I have four different properties here.
This in one file I need just one property
that is doesn't name in one method.
I need another properties.
That is username.
Right.
But here it is
giving me all the properties in a bunch.
Right.
So is this setup correct that I'm getting
all the properties that I need?
Just one instead of getting one.
I'm getting forward from here,
but I need one at one time.
So based on what I can,
access is specific property.
Guys,
any idea
on what I can get this specific property?
I think meanwhile, I'm putting the coming
this method in the
any property file
guys, any idea? No.
Can you see these configured properties?
These are the keys.
Remember
you are in browser username and password.
These are the keys.
Then if I'm coming to that part
because this property is right,
it will give you an error.
Now I'm showing you how it will get out.
Yes, we have to read it based on keys.
When we need a username,
we should need username or we should get
only username and password
we should get password.
Only Another method I'm going to write
is public.
Typing
is free,
but I'm going to get
property value
based on what I'm going to get this
property value based on the key point.
So here what I need they return.
What return?
It should return my property, dot
property, dot get property value by
date, property
value bucket based on my key.
Now if you'll see
I need this
get property value from this property part
from this property,
but it is not returning.
This method should return.
Property is then only I will be able
to catch that property in other method.
So to return to get something
from this method, what should I change?
I should change this way
because this is not acting right
and then this properties I'm using in
this method as well.
So let's do one thing.
Yes, let's do one thing.
Remove it from here. Bye.
Because I'm going to use this
property here also.
So I'm going to write Stop start
time.
It is giving the Arab.
So I'm going to write it as static
properties as thought.
Now, can you see
here I have to write another method called
instead of Void and Deeds properties.
Now it is giving me the error.
So I'm going to read one part from here
that these properties
now here
also exist public static stream
fine gate property.
So I am going to write here is
a return
drop dart
gate.
Now how this works, let me write it.
When coming back, this method
reads
Single value
based on the
If I now see
this method will read all the properties
from your dart properties.
Fine.
Right now you have all the properties
inside this object, this prop object.
You are calling this prop object
and you are saying get property
from these properties by which property
based on the key you're passing.
All right.
So from where you can pass from
your function, you can pass
or it should be
gate property, not gate property value.
If you take your method like
so you have to write a string key here
is spring key.
And then this key you need to pass.
This is just a parameter, right?
You can pass any other parameters,
no issues.
And the beach party of last year tell me
this 1015 lines of code we have written.
Let me explain you once again.
See you guys.
This is my non Java stuff right?
Fine.
So to fix this, to fix this post,
what you have to do basically is
write
first.
You need to check this method.
Make sure your this method is same is my
this code is same as mine
and then it will not give you two zero
now. So you guys,
again, I'm explaining no issues.
You have these configured properties
right here.
This is your non java stuff
right now in this non java stuff,
you need one class
from where you can read inside
Java right?
Is it clear?
Is it clear
to non java stuff?
If you want to read you need some code.
This is the code to read.
The property is quite correct
to read the properties file.
This is the method we have written.
So this file we are talking about,
we have taken this file by our file
import stream.
This is the code of your java
to read properties.
What you need to do is
you need to call this properties portion.
It will load the file.
It means it is loading.
It is loading all the properties
from your dart file
into this properties
object into this properties object.
Now you have all the properties
which are available
in your configured properties file.
Correct.
Once you load all of the properties
from your configured properties
file inside this property,
you will close this, connect
guys these three lines of code.
Understandable.
Everyone
know now if you see in this method,
if you see in this method,
I'm not getting anything in specific.
I'm just reading I'm loading
all the properties in this drop object.
Right.
But if you see in my configured properties
here, you'll see this browser.
You are in username password.
These are unique keys
and then I have unique keys.
My requirement would be some things
I knew just user need some guidance.
I need just password sometimes I just
need a browser or sometimes I just need.
You are right.
It might be possible
that I don't need all of this for keys.
It wouldn't be that
I got it.
So here, if I go inside my configurator,
I made it static.
Right the properties as an instance video.
But now what is the
access modifier here? This
for these properties?
Someone was asking private.
If I make it private I wouldn't
be able to use anywhere else by default.
It is available for right.
So in this dual method, obviously
I can write inside one method, right?
I'm defining it on a class
level instance media by
so that I can it in
both the methods from this method.
From this method I have load
all the properties in prop object
and then I'm returning this prop object
from this method.
Right?
So what this method is giving,
this method reads
all the properties
and having this inside prop object.
Right?
And this method is returning this prop
object.
Correct.
So far,
this is what this method is returning us.
This method is reading and loading
all the properties from quantum
dot properties file and it is keeping
all of this thing in my prop object.
And this method is returning
with this prop object.
So far so good.
Now forget
about configured properties,
whatever the things we have in configured
properties, we have all these things
in my prop right now.
Let's focus only on this prop
and this bug.
And that's now clear until this point.
Okay?
Now just focus on this prop object.
I have this prop object with me.
Find in another method.
In another method, I am saying
I'm going to get
the benefit of the property,
not properties property thing.
All right,
so this prop has all the properties.
I need one property. Fine.
This method says unit one property.
Go ahead.
Tick.
Based on what I'm seeing,
based on key rate I'm seeing based on T.
So your method says only prop
dart gate property.
It means that on this prop
you have all the properties.
You can get one property based on what?
Based on the key
let's say you plus browser.
So from these properties,
these properties have your
this prop
object has your browser username password.
You are a duplicate browser,
so it will not give you all for this time.
Going will give you a just browser clear
gain so far.
Is it clear or not any
kind of?
Obviously you need practice.
All right.
Now shall we proceed further, guys?
Okay.
Now see,
the next thing we were talking about.
I hope I'm not going too fast.
He has an
So now remember,
we were talking about this
three condition,
enforced condition, right?
We used to write inside every other class.
It's time.
Get rid out of this situation. Right.
I'm going to create another class.
I am calling this class as
common methods.
All right?
What I'm going to do is I'm going to write
method is common
methods.
Thank you, guys.
I have created another classes,
Common methods, Class VI because.
I need to keep all of my code.
This code, this code.
Write this code
that I don't want to write this code again
and again in every single class.
Guys getting my point
like so
now let's proceed further in our common
methods.
Right?
I'm going to define my driver also here.
So I'm going to make public static
web by word timeline.
Now, the point is why I'm making
this driver is public.
Remember throughout your all the packet,
if I make it this default,
then what is the issue?
The issue is this my common
method is available inside this utils.
If I want to use all of my common
methods, my precondition
in most condition
outside the package in any other package,
then this driver
I will not be able to utilize this right.
That's
why that's why I'm making it as a public.
Underscore the concept
by making it as a public
protected.
Also you can use for as a percent.
I'm using public or right now,
you can use particular
issues.
Fine. Then
since this
is my precondition,
this is my precondition.
I'm going to right before method, right?
Why? Before the method?
Everyone knows guys
always run as equals.
Photo
What does it mean when I say precondition?
Tell me
I want to execute before my best case
state Precondition.
What is the Let me copy
this code from my data provider
which will open browser.
See, I don't want this code.
I'm just deleting it from you.
Right?
I'm deleting it
from here.
Just one class.
I'm taking data provider class.
You can also do the same thing
from data provider.
Remove that method and just paste it here
is do you want me to explain it?
Once again, going to your data provider
demo class.
Remove this edited before from there.
Right with the before method and then
keep it inside your common methods.
Do it like this.
Then everyone.
Now I said already,
I don't need to pass this.
You are in here.
Correct.
I don't need to pass this.
You are in here.
So what I'm going to do is first I'm going
to I'm going to read the properties
from where
I'm reading the properties in which class
springs we are reading.
The properties in
UTILS is a package inside config reader.
Right.
I'm going to write Configurator Dark
read properties.
This is my method, right?
This is my mother.
Now it is asking file but why?
It is asking for files.
But that is because we provided
one string file portrait.
So it is to read the properties.
I am ready.
Tell me which file I need to see.
So I'm giving the part of this content
or properties how to provide the path.
Right click
copy path absolute path
copy and is pretty
guys got it
configurator
not properties vehicle from configurator
it is asking for file
photo employing file path
you can take this file but from configure
properties right click copy part
copy the path infrastructure
and continue to study
in my common methods.
Make sense of Firebase.
Now I'm going to use switch case the
I'm going to write
switch.
I'm saying in my configurator
you're already editing the properties
file.
I need gate property
which property I needed my browser name.
All right.
When I say I need my browser name right,
I will keep this code, this code
inside of my browser,
so my browser name would be blocked.
Let me state it and I see
I'm writing here.
See if case switch gets right.
If the value of my case is chrome,
then execute this code
which caused this code.
Otherwise break.
And then if my case is the
Firefox
right, then simply print one thing here.
We call this things let's say
or we simply write right.
Whatever
the path of my browser, let's say browser
not available.
You can put the browser name right.
You know, our ecosystem guard side
properties and everything in between.
And then again here we to break it.
And the last one is let's say you
just need to provide default case here.
Default case is through new
what I'm going to is runtime exception.
What I'm going to write invalid
counts and find
Now see you guys
in this code.
So far
in this code so far,
I'm reading the properties from this file.
I'm getting the properties
based on this value, right?
These are based on this key.
If my key is equal to this
density, if my
key is equal to this,
this code will execute.
If my key is equal to Firefox,
If my key is invalid,
this code will execute.
This is this which case.
The statement
so far?
Is it correct?
Let's proceed further.
I don't need this anymore.
I don't need.
I'm going to write here configurator
dark gate Property value.
What is my property
this time you are in simple
isn't making your very easy
right this time just to pass the you are
it will get the value
you're opening, the browser
you're launching
that you are navigating application
and then wait.
Now your method is ready.
Correct.
Guys, is this correct or not
funny?
Go back to your builder driver
demo once again, go back to this part.
You'll see this is your post condition
again. Just got it from here.
Your post condition
and press state here only
this is your post condition right
now every time.
See you guys how this things work
every time
in every single class
when you have to open the browser,
when you have to open the browser
as a precondition, what it will do,
it will read your properties
by post, right?
It will take it on
to the basis of your keys
and then it will upload the data.
Getting my point.
It will also close your browser this time
if you'll see.
This time if you'll see.
Let me show you another point.
I'm going here in my data
provide data for later.
They will now see
till this point
of time I was passing data from my data.
Correct?
Correct means.
Now I don't want to pass this data
from my data way pass
right?
I don't want to pass this data
from my data provider class here.
So what can I do?
I will write this data provider.
Correct?
Correct.
Here.
Here, because I have everything
available in my common methods
against everything
I available in my common
methods, correct
guys getting my point.
So to use to use the properties
and the features
of my common methods in my data provider
which oops concept
I will use
extend.
Correct.
So I'm going to write here
expense my
common methods from your business.
But now see
inside of this
here, right?
Instead of this username
and password, what I can pass, basically
I can simply pass and the keys
configurator door
gate property value based on
username.
Correct
guy is getting it or not
in here.
Also simply pass password.
Right.
So now username password
also coming from property is fine.
You are also coming from
properties file
browser name is coming from properties.
Fine.
Everything
all right?
Tell me where are you right now?
Where you've lost?
You are in this class
or you are in data provider class.
Guys, tell me,
how can you be in
both the class at one time?
First
I had completed this common methods right?
And then we will switch on
to the data provider.
So right now
this is your data provider
class guys.
All right, so guys, see what I did
inside this data provider class?
The very first thing is
I extended this common methods here.
First thing here,
I'm just taking I'm just giving you their
time so that I can explain,
okay, let's do like this.
This part methods.
How many of you guys are done with this?
Common methods?
Elena Common methods. No.
Common method.
Mars Common method.
All right.
Completely. There is no use.
Completely common methods. Most
them.
And no, please let me know. Right.
Once you're done with this Common methods.
Just two or three lines. Yes.
And that's all great.
Fine. Nor
because this code
we have copied,
we have just added this line
and we added this line.
This and this.
You can write configured properties
in just 2 minutes, right?
Just for words. You need to type.
And these values
you already have strict not.
Why do you need to
write it once again, just go in
your data provided in any other class.
Right?
You have already just copied
from different listed.
You don't need to type it.
Yes, you can mark no issues at all.
You can.
You can no issues.
So this part days everyone
is done.
Now let's come in to data provider.
The first thing is
we extended this common method here.
Correct?
No, no, no.
I'm coming on their subject.
I'm coming on.
They don't, but I'm coming on it now.
See, guys, I said when I need to extend
properties of common method
inside these inheriting
all the properties of common
methods, correct?
Correct. This.
So in my common methods, you'll see a
driver is also available, which is public.
Correct.
When I'm having this driver instance
already here
and I'm inheriting
the properties of common methods,
do I need to mention once again
this driver to you and me?
No. Right. Anything.
But still, even if I deleted it,
I'm not getting any errors in this.
Can you see?
I'm not making any other correct.
Now, after this. After this.
Do you think that we need this?
A string username and password yet
related.
Now see, your method looks for short.
Correct?
Right guys, your class looks very simple.
Even though we are not using this data
provider, I'm keeping it as of now.
Here. Right.
If you want to delete,
you can delayed because we have this
in any of the classes.
But and also you are not passing any data
which is hardcoded.
So in many
make sure base
when you're passing this keys
these keys must be seen right this
this must be seen with the keys
you're passing in your methods.
Remember example
I'm passing this browser with small B
so it should be small B here chrome,
but small C there should be a small C
Similarly here,
if I'm passing this username
so it should get small if there is a small
similarly for password.
Also correct.
Fine.
So so far in this data provider
class, is everyone done with this?
What I just explained?
Don't worry, I explain this concept.
Tomorrow is then no issues at all.
I'm just asking this so far.
Is it correct?
Is it clear to everyone?
Yammer so correct.
Exactly.
Fine.
Let's go in our best in the class. Right.
Let's go in.
Any other guest in the class say this one.
Right. And
we are going to execute this data provider
this time.
C So I'm going to write here is my
data provider table.
Now see guys, when I'm executing my data
provider, they will get right
in my data provider.
If you observe,
I don't have any precondition,
I don't have any forced condition, right?
I'm not passing any data hardcoded,
but still
I'm going to execute my
data provider.
They will see
well, this is open
browser null pointer
exception in common with 39 number 70. I'm
okay, I'm
open my common methods.
No, I'm.
I must have missed something yet
I to check that
there's the problem
in my config properties.
I have passed the part of common metrics
because it was expecting the properties.
Fine.
So let me copy this spot from here.
Coffeepot
for configured properties and then.
And then I have to pass
a correct 48 point.
Let me pass that. Correct.
But now this time,
if I want to execute this data
demo right.
I was giving the wrong part.
That was the issue.
Getting serious.
It took the precondition from where?
From your common methods.
Right?
Passing the data from where?
From your property site.
Right.
And then post condition
for closing the browser,
working fine from your common methods.
Once again, your test got executed
right now see the best part.
Let's start searching here
and this single class from here.
Very latest that go inside the class right
deleted from here, go here,
deleted from here,
deleted from here
and then simply extends your
common method.
Right?
Half of the code will be deleted
from all of your classes. Why?
Because you are not writing your
you're not writing your post condition
again and again.
The same precondition and post
condition will be utilized
in every single class from now onwards.
Make sense
students.
What happened?
Everyone slept like
yesterday.
So what I am seeing basically is the good
bit of it in your all the classes
wherever you have this precondition
and post condition
launching browser, closing the browser,
launching the browser,
closing the browser,
delete everything from everywhere,
from all the classes,
and instead of de just exchange
the common method in your class,
then you're going to extend the properties
of your common method.
Then it will work.
It is working in this way,
so it will work for you as well.
Great as go going and enjoy it.
I'm going to complete the session
guys.
Tell me
just five more minutes
and five for five more minutes
and then you can
no noise.
If you still have any issues
in the support, we will give you
Great summary.
All right, guys,
So far, whatever the things,
whatever the things we have implemented,
what do you guys think that, yes,
it is understandable for you
conceptually,
if you are having any errors in the code,
fine.
I'm going to commit to Michael.
I can totally understand.
I already pushed the code
in the repository.
You guys can find this code there.
All right, everyone.
It is not data hiding.
Basically, data hiding is completely
related to concept, which is logical data.
This is your functionality, right?
This is not your data.
When you keep your data inside one phase
data file, for example, in Excel file.
Right.
And that find your keeping close
to your calling database
a key that is data.
Yes, exactly.
Correct.
There
you go.
Black
of the symbol file.
You can use your only right
and you can see.
Thanks. Well, I didn't change anything.
I'm just joining one class.
That's it.
Black code for you is here.
I don't do this yet. It's
I have this button filled with water.
All right, guys.
Yeah, Yeah, correct. Mike
True. Yes.
And you
know, Eleanor, this is bad.
Sure.
There you go.
This is a common metrics
injurious to health.
Not good, not recommended
a black.
You need to check with your driver
actually exist unit
to check the location of the driver.
This driver find it.
But where is that?
Can you please post the screenshot
in the support?
I will look into this
shot.
This is your symbol by
already guys,
so I think I'm done for today's session.
If you guys have any question you can now.
Thank you so much everyone.
Guys,
if you have any question, please ask.