All right, let's get started.
All right.
For every day, right.
705 every day.
Good.
All right, guys.
Good evening, everybody.
How is everyone doing?
I hope everyone is doing good.
Yeah.
I hope you guys got everything from GitHub
and canvas, right?
Because I uploaded it today.
I pushed the code
and I uploaded two classes.
Two slides for selenium.
Okay, good. Yeah.
All right.
Okay. I hope.
I hope you had fun yesterday, guys. Okay.
We're going to continue
learning more stuff today about selenium.
And I hope you guys did some research
for today's class.
And we will start by doing some recap.
Okay.
So, what did we do last class, guys?
What did we do
yesterday?
Okay, so we started
the first class of selenium
get versus navigate.
Right will launch the browser,
launching drivers,
navigating to the websites right quick
versus closed.
Okay.
We'll learn about set properties
and the methods.
Okay, that's very good.
So before we do anything right, so when we
create a class, we import everything.
We import our libraries,
we import our drivers.
When we have a class
before we dive into coding,
we need to set our properties right.
So what do we have
in our properties, guys?
What do we need to mention
inside the properties?
The driver we're going to be using
and its location.
Right? So we're setting the properties.
We're telling Hey, I'm using the chrome
driver and here is where it's located.
Right.
And then afterwards
we can launch the browser.
We can navigate to, to any website we want
and then perform any actions accordingly.
Right.
What else did we learn?
So we navigated to the website.
We move back and forth right? We quit.
We closed the browser.
What else, guys?
Okay, so parsing this thread, right?
So that's one of the things that we learn.
We also learn how to maximize and make
the make the browser full screen, right?
Also learn how to refresh the page.
Okay. And what else, guys?
What else?
What did we get
when we first navigate to the
to the website?
What did we get from there? Exactly.
So we got the title.
And what else?
And the current. You're up. Right.
So let's let me actually create
a new package in here.
Um, class.
There are two, right?
And I will create a new Java class in here
and just name it as recap.
Cancel this.
All right.
And I hope everyone,
everyone resolved their yesterday's issues
with all the libraries
and all the drivers and everything.
I hope
everyone has their selenium and drivers
up and running.
Okay.
I don't want anyone to be behind that
because this is the second class.
This is where we start interacting with
the browser, with the websites themselves.
Okay.
That's that's really important today.
So, okay, So yesterday
what we said
was we set the property first, right?
So system
that we set the property
and then and the first argument,
what we've done is web driver
Chrome driver.
All right.
And in the second one
we had the drivers
chrome driver
Right.
So now after we set the properties,
what is our next step,
guys?
Create an object, right?
So let's go ahead and do that.
Web driver.
Driver
is equal to new chrome driver, Right.
So what is this line ten going to do,
guys?
Is this going to launch the browser or no,
it will open the browser,
but it will not navigate to anywhere.
Right.
So let's go ahead and navigate
to, let's say, Facebook.
Okay.
So driver that get
and we can do it.
I think we can do this. Be right in here.
So let's see how that's going to work.
So what is what do we want to do next?
So I navigate it to the website.
What do we want to do next
before we even do anything
on that website?
Guys, when we're navigating
to the Facebook right now.
So there we go.
So what we want to do,
we want to maximize our screen, right?
So what I'm going to do simply driver
that manage my window
and I will be maximizing it.
Right? Okay.
So now what I want to do, guys,
I want to verify the title again.
So right now
we won't be using any assertions.
We will be just simply using the if
conditions that we've learned from Java.
Okay.
So what do I need to do?
First, I want to verify the title in here
so we maximize the window.
How do I get the title, guys?
How do I have the title in my coat?
Simple, right?
So I'm using the driver
object in here again.
And what I do, I get the title.
What am I getting in return in here
is string, right?
So what I will do
string title
is equal to this.
So now let's actually go in here
and navigate to Facebook.
Okay, so this is my Facebook.
I want to verify if the
if we have the right
if we have the right title.
Okay. How do we want to do this?
How do we want to approach this?
We can use a NEF condition, right?
So if my title
let's do it ignore case
or let's just do equals, right.
So that we are we are 100%
what's called Sure that everything,
even if it's capital letter
or not capital, it doesn't really matter.
Everything is equal as my title,
which I got right.
So I think it is Facebook
log in or
signup, right, if I'm not mistaken.
So once that condition is matched,
what I will do, I'm
just going to simply print out that
title is correct.
And if it's not,
then I'm going to have another condition
in here.
Right.
What I will do,
I'm just going to print out
that title is wrong.
It's correct and it's wrong.
And after I did that, what I want to do,
I want to terminate the
my execution
and I want to close the browser.
And what I simply do is here
I will simply add the driver that quit.
Right.
Okay.
So let's do actually that.
So after I maximize my window,
I want to wait for 2 seconds.
Guys.
How would I do this?
I can use the threat dot sleep.
Right?
So I want to pause my execution
for a couple seconds in here
after I maximize my window and only
then start getting the title right.
So what I will do in here
throughout that sleep
and this exact millisecond,
so I'll put 2000
and I will just add an exception
to my method signature.
Okay.
Any questions before I run this?
Guys?
Okay, cool.
All right, so let's run
this and see if this is going to work.
Okay?
All right. Running this.
Let's say.
Okay now. Oh, it maximize over here.
Okay.
The title is wrong. What's going on, guys?
So it maximize over here. Guys,
I think
this because this one is my main screen.
That's why it maximized here.
But I'm pretty sure you guys should get
this one as well.
What's wrong with this? Why?
It's skip this one.
Why did our what's called
why did our condition
not meet?
Because the condition is false.
Where
what is the.
Did we make a mistake in here?
Let's go and see here.
Yeah. Okay.
Okay. This one.
This one should be capital.
Okay?
That this one should be capital.
So let's run it again and see
if this is going to work.
There we go.
So it maximized over here. It closed.
Oh, is still wrong.
Okay, sign up.
Okay. You is capital as well.
Okay.
Rerunning it again
until we have the correct title.
Okay.
So let's see.
How do we know if the title
what the title is, guys?
So now the title is correct.
Where do we get the actual title from?
It's on the tab, right?
So if you look at the tab right here,
so this is your title.
Whenever wherever you navigate,
you will have a title of that page.
Okay, So this is your you are all in here
and this on the tab will be your title.
Okay. All right.
Any questions, guys?
Before we move on to the next topic,
you guys have an issues with audio
or it's
Hello, everyone.
Okay, that's not good.
Okay, let me see.
Is this better, guys or no,
that sounds better or worse
because I changed the microphone.
So let's see.
Okay, Way better.
Okay, good.
Okay.
All right, cool.
Okay, guys.
So let's continue with some new stuff.
Okay. So let me go back here
to. Okay, I hope you guys did
some research on what is the web element
and the locators and selenium.
Okay.
So anyone any guesses
what is an element, guys,
what is an element in selenium?
What do the notes,
what is a web
element?
Anything we see on the page is considered
to be a web element, right?
Anything present on the web page,
like the text boxes.
Like the buttons,
like the links, dropdowns, checkboxes.
Right?
Anything we see on
the web page is considered
to be a web element, right?
So anything we see on
the Web page
is considered to be a web element.
Okay, So example
here, buttons, text boxes,
checkboxes. Right.
Any links?
Okay. So let's go in here.
Let's go here. So
anything we
see on this page right now,
this is the button.
This is the link, right?
This is another button.
These texts, even
even if they're not clickable
and just showing anything,
these are considered as elements as well.
Okay.
Even though you can't perform
any actions on those,
they are considered as elements as well.
So where do we see any text boxes? Guys
there we see any text boxes
on this page, email and password.
Right.
Text boxes are where we type in something.
We type in some text in there. Right.
So these are considered as the text boxes.
Okay.
So for us guys, in order
so manually,
if I want to do anything in here,
we have a keyboard
we can navigate with our cursor, right?
So and come here, type it in here, type
any password,
click on the log in right or click
forgot password.
So this is how everything
manually works, right?
But in order for us to write a logic
by using selenium,
we need to interact with each
and every element separately.
Okay.
And in order to do this, we need to
interact with something internal.
Okay.
Something
internally built in in the browser.
Okay, so what I will do right now in here,
I will go ahead and right click in here,
Okay?
Right click on any place at the web page.
And I will open up one window
where we will be interacting
with each
and every web element on the page.
Okay.
So I will right click and go to inspect.
Okay, So I'll click on Inspect.
And now you can see there's
a lot of different code in here.
There's something in here, right?
So we have a separate window
opening up on the right side of the page.
Okay.
So what I'm going to do,
I'm actually going to move this
to the bottom of our screen.
Okay.
So if you go to the
to these three dots, click on those.
You will see the dark side in here.
Okay. So
I will go ahead and click on the dock
to bottom.
Okay.
And everything
will get moved to the bottom.
Okay. Is that clear, guys?
So this is going to be better
for us to learn and to manipulate
with all the elements. Okay.
I hope everyone is following
and everyone is understanding
what is going on.
Okay, right click inspect, guys.
And then if you want to dock it
to the bottom,
what you can do, click on these three dots
and then choose
whichever way you want to dock it.
Okay?
So you can dock it to the last
or you can dock it to the right.
It doesn't really matter
or you can get to the bottom.
So for me,
I like to dock it to the bottom.
It's better for me to manipulate
with everything
and to manipulate with the elements.
Okay.
He used to do it. Okay. Okay. That's good.
That's good. Almost.
Almost a hacker.
Okay.
All right. Okay.
So now.
Now we started to
install protecting this page.
Okay, So now we can see
what is how the page is written,
how the page is designed.
Okay, so
what?
So anyone knows? What did we just open?
What is this window, guys, Source code.
Okay, h html.
Okay, that's very good.
So we see an h HTML code in here, right?
Okay. That's very good. Okay.
Source code, frontend code.
Okay.
Anything else?
Okay, so there is a couple different names
for this.
Okay.
So this is called a DOM.
So Dom is Dom stands
for document object model.
Okay.
So it's we can see the HTML,
how everything is designed
and you can see the SS in here,
how the frontend developers
design it and the padding,
the background, the font and everything.
But we won't be really using
any of the CC.
We will mainly be working with this HTML
inside our DOM.
Okay, so let's go ahead in here
and put So does
anybody know what HTML stands for?
Guys?
Yeah.
So Google it.
Let's see.
Okay.
Hypertext markup language.
Right? Okay,
good.
Okay, So hypertext
markup
language.
Okay.
All right. And then so what?
What is Dom?
So we set it stands for document
object, model, right?
So this Dom is an internal browsers view.
Okay.
So this is an internal view
of the web page of the OC.
Dom That's good.
That's a good one.
Yes, exactly.
Okay.
All right.
So let's put it here. Now.
Stands for
document
model, right?
It is.
It is the
browser's internal
view of the web page.
Okay.
It is also called as developers Tools.
So also of
developers
tools.
Or you could just say, yeah, it's
all right.
Okay, so let's go one by one.
So why, why does he call as document guys?
What?
What does it mean that what,
what does it mean that it's document guys,
Where do we see a document in here.
Guys, when we inspect the page.
This text. Right.
So here,
this is considered as one document.
Okay, So one page, one page that we see
on the web page is considered
in here as a HTML document.
Right?
So it can be actually stored as
any document can be stored, any document
as PDF Excel or anything.
But here it is stored as an HTML.
So why the object guys?
Why that object?
Any guesses? Guys,
let's go back in here
so we can run this.
Every element sends unique.
Some of them, yes, some of them unique.
Not all of them are unique, but
as object, we mean each
and every line of code in here,
each and every line inside
the HTML will be considered as an object.
Okay, so here
any line in HTML
is considered as
object. Okay.
And then the last thing is why model
guys, we're not going to learn HTML,
but we will be browsing the HTML
to interact with that web elements.
Okay.
Okay. Anyone?
Any idea why it's a model?
Guys?
What does it mean in here?
As we say, it's a model.
It's like a template.
Right? Exactly. It's a layout, right?
It's a blueprint.
That's exactly what it is. Right?
It is just the layout of this HTML
file in here.
Okay.
So it is just the
layout of the HTML.
That's what it is.
So we know how to open up a DOM in here.
We know how to inspect
and we know how to view
an internal
HTML of any page of the website.
Right.
Okay,
so now guys in here,
so we opened up the dev tools in here
we see the HTML.
So now what we can do, we can start
interacting with the web elements.
Okay, So let me check
one thing in here.
Okay?
So before we interact
with the elements, guys,
I want to go over the locators.
Okay.
So did anyone do a research?
What locators are in selenium and
what kind of locators we have in selenium?
That's
okay.
Experts says okay,
okay, so we have eight locators, right?
Class tag name. Okay.
So before we move into what kind of
locators we have, what is a locator,
guys, that help
navigate
where you want to do your execution?
Oh, yeah. Kind of makes sense. Yes.
So the locator is the address, right?
Or position of the web element
You want to interact with.
Okay, so let's put it here.
Locator, do
this is an address or a position,
right?
Address for web element.
Right
position of an element.
So it's basically an address or a position
of the web element on the web page.
Right. So on the
Web page.
Okay,
So what why do we need the locators
in selenium, guys?
What do we have to do with these
two command?
Okay.
Anything else?
Use them to navigate.
Okay.
Want to interact? Right.
So we use the locators to identify, right.
To locate
or to interact with the web elements.
Okay.
So is
used to locate or
or identify
web elements on the web page.
Okay. All right.
This is clear.
Right, guys?
So we have locator is an address
or a position of a web element
on the Web page.
And it is used to locate or identify
the Web element on the Web page.
So now let's talk about the locators
themselves.
Okay.
So some people say
there are eight locators, right?
So eight
eight locators.
So what
do we know about the locators, guys?
So we said eight.
Which ones
ID, ID
name, what else?
So let me actually put it down here. I.D.
We got name in here.
Okay.
With that tag name.
Okay. Tag name.
What else?
X path.
Okay, So tag name, link tags, partial link
text.
Right. Okay.
So link, say link text.
Well, so have
partial link text.
Right. So we got six in here.
We have CSF selector
and there's one more guys.
There is a class name.
Absolutely. Right.
So class name.
Okay, so eight locators. Right.
So this, this is one of the interview
questions, guys.
So do not forget you might get this
if you have an interview
and they ask you about the
any questions from selenium,
they might start with this question.
Okay.
So how many locators do you know
in in selenium?
So you start with we know it
locators in selenium, ID name tag, name
X Path link tax, partially tax
test selector and the class name.
Okay.
So eight locators
we're going to be using to locate
and identify the elements
and we will be interacting with those.
Okay, So let's go down here.
Let's see.
All right.
So let's take a look at the sample.
This let's take a look at the sample.
So this is an HTML in here.
I hope everyone can see this. Right.
Let me zoom in a little bit.
Okay.
All right.
So in HTML, guys,
we see some different colors, right?
So let's go back. Oh, not here.
Let's go back in here. Okay.
So if you look at this, you can see
different, different colors, right?
So we can differentiate
everything that is in here.
Like, like in the coding in Java,
you see the keywords in different,
different colors, right?
So that you can differentiate them.
So it is the same way in HTML as well.
So you see the purple tag, the purple
keywords,
you see the brownish orange, right?
And we see the blue in here,
we see underlined in here, right?
So we'll be talking
about those right now. So
when you see the purple
back here, when you see the purple ones
in here, Right.
So what they mean is they mean the tags.
Okay.
So Dave, script body
spans, script or link or what?
What else do we have in here? IMG Right.
They are all HTML tags.
Okay,
so let's take a look at the slide in here.
So now if you look at so here they,
they probably use different theme,
but let's go back to our Facebook.
So if you look in here, you see this
graph, you see this style source class.
They are all brownish and
it's a little bit orange or brown, right?
So whatever you want to call this.
So these are called as attributes.
Okay.
So if you look in here,
you can see this
the value, the name, the I.D.,
the address,
these are all called actually views.
Okay.
It's hard if you're colorblind. It's okay.
Just know that the first one is always
will come with tag name.
The second one you will have an attribute.
And after the equals sign
and inside the double quotes,
you will see the attribute values.
Okay.
Exactly.
This is an opening tag,
and at the very end you will see
the closing tag as well.
Any questions on these guys? Yep.
It's like a code, right?
I mean, it is a code.
It's an HTML, right?
The red one are tags. Yep.
Opening and close.
Okay.
So or actually
it's just for HTML
scripting meaning in here.
So if you say purple
tags.
Right.
And then we have brown,
they're actually dudes.
Then I think with blue, which are
attributes values.
Okay.
Red is the tag.
Exactly.
But they're all the same. Yeah.
The reason you see here as red, because
in the sample here
they use a different theme.
Okay, so there are different
different things that you can use.
Mine is here. It's a default one.
So that's why we have this.
Okay,
so sometimes you have a black background
for your chrome,
you want to change your background.
So all those will be
will be implemented in your HTML.
What's called HTML
colors will change as well.
But the default ones,
if you use a default browser
chrome theme, that means that you will see
these colors in here.
Okay.
Yeah. Most yeah, exactly.
Most colors will do that.
And this is for developers.
We can use it to an intelligent actually.
But whenever
you are locating any elements for us, it's
I think for me personally,
I use this white one.
So this is
this is pretty good for me or is just me.
I just
got used to this one.
It's a preference, right, guys?
So it's a preference
so if you want to use a dark,
dark mode, that's fine.
You can do that as well.
All right.
Any questions before me?
Before we move on, guys?
Questions. Okay, good.
All right, so
let's then get into some coding.
Okay.
So now, guys, what we want to do in here,
since said we will be using those locators
to locate the element
and to interact with them.
Right.
So I need this Dom to locate them first.
Okay.
Before I write any code,
I need to locate the element
that I want to interact with.
Okay.
So what we're going to do in here, guys,
so we will be navigating to Facebook.
We're going to enter some text in here.
We're going to enter some password.
And what we're going to do,
we will clicking on a log in in here.
Okay.
Sounds like a good plan right now.
So but we won't be doing it manually.
Obviously,
we will be writing the logic for this.
Okay.
So first of all, guys, so me, in order
to start locating any element,
I need to click on this one here.
There's a small arrow at the very,
very left side of the DOM at the very top.
Okay, so just click on that, guys.
Just when you click
and when you start moving your cursor
over the elements,
you can see that your your HTML is moving
and your elements are getting highlighted.
Okay, I hope everyone did that.
And you can see what is going on in here.
Do you guys have any issues?
Just let me know.
I'll go over again.
Okay, good.
So now our first priority.
What am I entering first in here?
Guys, I want to enter my email,
my password, and click on log in.
So my first priority
is to locate the email textbox.
Right.
So what I will do, I will just go on
top of this email text box
and what I will do, I will click on.
Okay.
When I click on it,
take a look at the HTML now guys.
So it is highlighted right now, that line
that is highlighted,
it is all the attributes
that belong to that specific textbox.
Okay, I help everyone have this.
Everyone has the same output
as me in here.
Highlighted one line
and highlighted the text box of email.
Okay.
Is everything clear, guys?
Am I going too fast?
Okay, good.
All right,
so now what I need to do in here, guys.
So now please pay attention on
on what we're seeing right now.
So now we have input in here,
which is our tag name, right?
So we have type.
So now is class one of the locators
that we have gone through?
Guys?
Yes. Right.
So we have a class name in here.
So you see guys so now we trying to locate
these elements
by the locators that we have.
So we have class in here.
So we have a name, right?
So if we look at the locators,
we have name as well, Right?
So we have name in here.
We also have an I.D. in here.
Okay.
So if I go back first locator
that I put in here is the ID, right?
So we have ID, I don't think we have tap
index and that's it.
Right?
So so one element
that we have right now for this
email textbox, we have three different
locators available.
Okay.
So, so we can use any of those
three locators
to locate the this element and perform
any actions.
Okay.
So now let's go back to our
what's called the intelligent
and let me create
one Java class in here.
Okay.
So let's do locating
elements.
Okay?
The main method in here.
All right.
So first of all, what do we need to do,
guys, before we start
launching the browser
or performing any actions
or navigating to any website,
we need to set the property
right to system the set property.
We have web driver,
chrome driver, and then
drivers, chrome driver.
Right. So now we need an object
driver.
Driver is equal to new chrome driver.
Right.
Okay, so we have this chrome driver.
So now what we need to do,
we need to navigate to that page, right?
So we're not
we need to navigate to the Facebook page.
So I'm using this guy in here, driver
that get htp
to the dot com.
Right?
And then I'm not going to
I'm not going to maximize it
because it's going to move to this screen.
But you can go ahead and maximize
this screen.
It's fine. Okay, guys.
So I'm not going to do it because I have
to be moving around with those windows.
Okay. All right.
So now
before we locate any element, cars,
we need to pay attention
for which locators
we can use on this element.
Okay, So we set that.
There are three different elements
in here.
I mean, locators, right?
The class name and I.D.. Okay.
So whenever you start
locating any elements, okay,
you need to
attention
first if that element has an I.D..
Okay.
Because I these are always unique.
So from the locators, whenever you start
locating an element,
you need to first pay attention.
If that if that element
has a locator of I.D., if it has an ID,
that's Dom deal,
you can go ahead and use that ID
and locate this element.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys,
IDs are always unique, but
I'm going to tell you a little bit later,
some cases
that they might not be unique, but
for now,
let's use the ID in here.
Okay.
Class, no, class is not going to be more
unique now, guys.
And we will see in the future why class?
Class names are not unique.
Okay. All right.
So now, guys, whenever you located
this ID locator,
what you need to do is
you need to capture its value.
Okay, so I have an I.D. in here.
I need to capture its value. Okay.
So the value of my ID is email.
So what I'm going to do,
I'm going to copy this file.
Okay? So once I copied this,
I'm going to go back to my intelligent
and now I will start
locating that element.
Okay, so how am I going to do this?
It's simple.
So driver dot find element.
Okay to find element,
it's going to ask me,
are you finding an element,
but which locator do you want to use?
And then what I will do in here,
I'll put by and there is an I.D.
in here.
So if you look down guys, there is name X
path, link
tags, class name, CSF, selector tag, name.
All the locators that we talked about.
Okay, so in this case, I am finding that
element by the given ID inside the HTML.
Okay.
So I'll do my ID
and I will paste that value in here.
Okay. Any questions, guys?
Is this clear?
Yes. Selenium.
Yeah, it is easy
because it's straight English, right?
So it's not it's not that difficult
to understand you finding an element.
What locators you using or by what you're
finding, you finding it by the ID
and you just need
to input the value of that item.
How can you copy that element?
You mean the
this this value?
Yeah.
You could just type in email.
Yeah. Yeah. Guys,
you could just go ahead and type in here.
Email.
That's fine.
Yeah.
Just double click on the value
and it's going to, it's going to select it
and you can just right
click and copy. Yes.
As long as you don't have any typos
guys in here, that is fine.
You can Typekit in manual.
Okay. All right.
So now what we did is
we found that element.
Okay? So we found that element.
So now I need to perform some actions.
Okay.
What what kind of actions
are we performing in here, guys?
What do we need to do?
So we found that element. Okay?
We found that textbox.
We need to enter our tax. Right?
In this case, we need to enter our email.
Right. So now, in here
it is
pretty straightforward what I will do.
I found that element.
Now I will need to send some keys in here.
So when I click on Dot, you can see that
there's a method called sent keys.
Okay, so I'll click on this.
So inside the parentheses I'll open
and close the double quotes in here
and you can give any email,
you can give it a fake email guys.
Donald if you want to,
if you want to use your own
email,
that's fine, but I'll just give it here.
Anything.
Right.
Syntax, whatever it is, dot com. Right.
So this is
how we will be entering
any text on the text boxes.
Okay. Is that clear, guys?
Any questions on this?
Okay, so now what
we're going to do, let's actually
let me actually run this.
Okay.
So what I will do, All right,
click on this and I will run it.
Okay, there we go.
So we navigate it to Facebook.
We navigate it to Facebook.
What we did Will located that element
and we entered that text
inside that exact textbox.
Okay.
Pretty cool, right, guys?
So now we learn how to actually type
inside any text box
on any web page, right?
So the text that I gave in here, it's
actually the same text
that we have in here.
Okay.
I hope you guys are having the same output
as I do.
If you are having any issues,
please send a screenshot
so that we can take a look at this.
Okay.
Okay. So you're getting in on it.
Are you getting a an error
because you did find elements.
Okay, so do find element.
It's not plural. Okay. It's singular.
So if you do, if you do find elements,
then you're going to get an error.
But you need to do find element.
Okay, guys.
Okay, guys, please pay attention in here.
You need to do find element.
We're trying to locate only one element,
guys.
Okay?
So find element and then send keys
was the last
for before I type in email sent keys.
This is this is.
This is auto generated
guys this is keys to send.
This is auto generated. Okay.
Don't really pay attention to that.
All right, guys, any questions?
Is everyone having the same output?
All right. Okay.
So now it's time for us to go ahead
and enter our password.
Okay.
So I need to see your whole.
I need to see the whole error.
Okay?
I need to see the top of the error.
In fact, there's something wrong with the
you missed that. Easy.
Okay, So you're using you using a windows.
You need to use the XY.
Okay.
If you're getting the character sequences,
that's fine.
That's fine, guys. There's no big deal.
Okay, so now let's
go ahead and locate the password.
TextBox.
Okay, so what I do again,
guys, click on the arrow.
Okay, in here.
Now I need to navigate my cursor
to this textbox
because I need to locate this exact
password.
TextBox. Okay.
So when I do that, click on this
and let me see.
And then you will see this line getting
highlighted in here.
Okay.
I hope everyone is at the same page, guys.
And is anyone behind?
Okay, good.
So now what do we have in here, guys?
What kind of locators
we have for this element?
We have ID, we have name,
and we have the class, right?
So three of those.
So which one we want to use now, guys?
So whenever you see an ID,
look a go with I.D., right?
Because it's unique
and it is very reliable.
So let's go ahead and copy
the ID value in here, okay.
And go back in here.
So what I need to do,
I need to find that element right?
So driver, the
find element, what am I finding it by?
I am finding it by I.D., Right.
And then I'll pass that value.
So what am I doing with this password?
TextBox guys.
I located it.
Now, what is my next step?
I need to send the keys. Right.
So that
send keys.
And here I just.
I'm just going to send any password
in here.
Okay.
All right.
So let me run this
and see what's going to happen.
And launch this.
Go to Facebook. There we go.
So we entered our email
and we entered our password.
Right. Pretty cool.
Everyone should have this output.
So whenever you run your code,
you need to see your email
and your password in here.
Okay?
Really cool.
All right.
Nice.
Okay.
So now let's click on log in.
Right.
So how do I,
how do I locate the element first?
Guys?
What do I need to do
in order to locate the element
first
click an arrow right in here,
go to this log in button
and then click on this.
Okay.
So now in here, how many of
how many locators do
we have for this element?
Guys, we have class name and ID, right?
So in this case,
so we use IDs two times already.
So let's try to use a name. Okay.
So what I will do and here I'll copy the
the value for the name locator.
Okay, so I'm going to copy this.
I'll go back to my intelligence.
What I will do is the same thing.
Driver, that fun element.
But this time,
what are we finding? Goodbye.
We finding it by name, right?
So not ID, we will be finding it by name
and then I'll paste this in here.
So now, in this case, guys,
we don't have to send anything
because it's a button, right?
We don't have to enter any text.
So pretty straightforward.
We need to click on it right,
in order to log in.
So I'll do that
click.
Okay.
Pretty easy and straightforward
if you want to send any text and keys.
If you want to click, click, okay, easy.
Right?
So let's run this and see if.
This is going to work.
Okay, there we go.
So entering this, there we go.
So we clicked on log in.
So obviously those are not
the real credentials that I pass in there.
So this one goes to the email, you enter
these and connected and all that stuff.
So this is expected.
So that means we entered our email,
we entered our password
and we clicked on log in.
Right?
So if you enter the valid credential,
you have to log in.
But if you didn't, then
you should be navigating to this page.
Okay,
Nice.
Okay.
All right, guys.
So if you are
now let me tell you one thing.
If you are logging in,
what the valid credentials
are, sometimes since it's
an automated thing that is going on
and you can sit in here.
So Chrome is being controlled
by automated test software,
Facebook might think that it's a robot
or anything is hacking your account.
Okay, so b b
what's called beyond the look out on that.
Do not log in with valid credential
a lot of times.
Okay.
So you might have some problems
after that or your account
might get locked
or anything like this. Okay.
So you might log in once or twice,
three times, five times,
or maybe if you
log, you keep logging in that
they might
think it's a robot or something,
so they might lock your account.
So be careful.
Okay?
All right.
Okay, guys, any questions
or key?
There is no hierarchy.
Okay.
But as I said,
the ID is the most reliable.
We will be going over to assess
and other locators,
but the most reliable for now is IDs.
Okay.
All right.
So if the element didn't
if you didn't type the values correctly,
yes, your test will fail.
Okay, So let's say we typed in here
the wrong password.
Okay.
So while we and let me run this
and let's see what's going to happen,
okay.
Running this guy.
So there we go.
So we entered that email,
but it didn't enter the password.
Right?
So let's take a look
at what we've got in here.
So we got an exception, right?
So it says no such element exception.
That means that the given
the given attribute value doesn't exist.
Okay.
So it says unable to locate an element
with the selector of this one.
Okay.
So that means there's something going on
with your locator.
You need to check your locators. Okay.
If you get the no such element exception,
that means
you need to go back and check
all the values that you have.
Enter.
Okay.
Any questions, guys?
The exception is human in general.
What kind of exceptions we might face?
Or are you talking about this
specific exception?
The exception that we got?
Oh, how many are there?
A lot of exceptions, guys.
There's a lot of exceptions.
So in Java, guys, when you start handling
the exceptions, you will see
you will see a lot of exceptions in here
and how to handle those.
Okay.
So I think those are going to be
the last classes of works of Java,
if I'm not mistaken.
Yeah, that's fine.
If if the output is less than
mine, that's okay.
All right.
Okay, guys.
So now what I want to do.
So we entered something in here, right?
We entered something in here.
So now when I click on, log in,
it shouldn't log in.
Of course.
What is.
Wow. Okay.
Wow. This is.
Is this serious?
Okay, that's not with.
We're just hacked.
Okay, This is ridiculous.
Okay, This one is funny.
I was not expecting this, okay?
I didn't know there was a user like this.
Okay.
There we go. So let's do this one. Okay.
I hope there's no
there's no user like this.
Okay, now.
Okay, now, now we're talking.
Okay, so now when we
when we go to this page right
When we go to this page,
what I want to do,
guys, I want to click on forgot password.
Okay, so
now let me click on this arrow again.
Right.
Go ahead and click on forgot password.
So now let's take a look
at the edge HTML in here.
What kind of locaters
do we have in here?
So we have class name, right?
I don't see any IDs.
We have only class, right?
So we have on the class
and we also have one more locator in here.
Okay, So what is this, guys?
Is does anyone know?
So the log in is the button, right?
So what is this forgot password for us?
It's a link. Right?
So for you to make sure it's a link,
you need to look at the HTML.
Okay.
So if you look at the HTML
and that specific element has an eight tag
that is going to be a link, a hyperlink.
Okay, So you can see the link over here.
So if you click on this forgot password,
this is where it's going to take you.
Okay.
So, so this link, what we have,
we have a text.
Okay, So now let's go back to our locators
and let's see what we can use from here.
Okay?
Yes, it is always going to be the same
for all the links.
It will have an a tag. Okay.
And it will it should have a text.
Okay.
So if a link has a text in here,
what are the locators
that we can use in this case?
Guys, there we go.
We can use a link text or a partial link
text.
Okay.
So what I will do in here,
so we have this text.
Everyone can see this text, right, guys?
So we have a tag, we have the link,
we have the class target.
So now what I want to do,
I want to copy this text in here
and I will go back to my intelligence
and I will
and I will locate that element.
Okay.
So simply driver, the font element,
what am I locating it by?
Guys?
Elizabeth, I will get back
to your question right now.
Okay?
I am locating it by link text and
what I will do inside the double quotes.
I will paste this
text that I copy.
Okay, so let's get back in here.
So now how do we know it's a text?
Because it's
in between the opening
and closing of the link.
Okay.
So you can see that the opening is here
and the closing is here, right?
So if you see any regular text
in between the opening
and the closing of the
links, that will be your link text.
Is that clear?
Okay.
So let me go back to the intelligence
and now what
we simply want to do,
we can simply click on that link.
Right.
But I think it's going to be really fast
right now.
So what I want to do before,
I click on forgot password,
what I want to do,
I want to wait for about 2 seconds.
Okay, So let's do threat sleep
and give it 2 seconds in here.
Right.
And throw that exception
in the method signature.
So now let's go back.
Let's run this code.
Okay.
There we go.
Facebook.
So there we go.
So we clicked on forgot password
and it navigated us
to enter our mobile number
right.
You get the link within navigate.
Yeah. You can do that.
Yes, you can do that.
Okay.
All right.
Any questions on this, guys?
Did everyone get the same output?
Yeah, it should be waiting, guys.
It will wait for two 2 seconds.
Oksana, yours is right
because you don't find elements again.
Okay? So please pay attention.
This part of your code.
All right?
Okay, guys, there's one more thing.
Let me show you,
and then we'll take a break, okay.
So we said
we can use the link text in here,
but we can also use the partial link text.
Okay.
So if you want to use the partial link
text, what does it mean, guys,
logically, you can use the part, right?
One part of that text that you're using.
Okay.
So what we can do in here, Driver
dot find element.
So now this time what we're doing
with using partial link text
and what we can
do, let's just put in here forgot.
Okay?
And what we need to do
we need to click on that.
Okay, So let's go ahead and run this
and see if this is going to work.
Okay?
In seconds. There we go.
So now it clicked on that.
So we navigate it to this page is still
asking us to enter the mobile number.
So that means this one worked
as well, right?
So pretty cool, right, guys?
So we know how to use it.
We know how to use name,
we know how to use link text,
and we know how to use partial link text.
And now we know how to use
for different locators
and to interact
with the text boxes, buttons and the
what's called and links.
Right. Okay.
So let's take a quick break.
Let me put driver Dot quit in here.
Okay.
So let's take a quick break, guys.
And after that we will be continuing
with our locators.
Okay.
And I'll give you a task after the break.
16 minute break.
Okay.
Or let me see, what else do I have?
Okay. Type the code, guys.
16 to 18, 20 minutes.
Okay.
So we'll get back at it's 820 right now.
Right.
Let's get the break
till a 40.
Okay.
5 minutes to type it in for you.
All right, guys.
I'll see you in 20 minutes.
All right, guys,
I hope everyone had a break
and you guys had time to
type in the code, right?
Okay, cool.
All right, now let's continue.
Okay, So now I'm
going to give you a task, guys.
Complete this task,
and then we will do it together.
Okay?
So let me.
Okay.
And new out class here.
Okay, so this is the task.
I'll send you the link.
Okay, guys.
So let me show you what to be done first.
All right, So let's go back here.
So I'm going to navigate to this page.
Okay.
So this is the page.
Well,
that everyone has to be done already.
So it's 840.
We said I gave you five extra minutes,
right, guys?
So I hope everyone is back by now. So
all about the task.
Okay. Okay, that's fine.
Okay. So this is the work site.
So they will.
We need to log in first.
Okay.
We need to log in here.
So the username and password
given in here.
Okay.
So it's the username is tasker
and the password is just test.
Okay.
So what you need to do, enter the username
and to the password and click on log in.
Okay. When you click on log in guys,
what you need to do is
you need to get the title and verify
the title is right.
Okay?
And after that, what you need to do
is, you need to log out.
You need to click on this, log out in here
and quit the browser.
Okay. Is the task cleared?
Guys, any questions?
Yes, I'm sending the link right now.
All right.
Okay.
I'm going to send it in life questions.
So copy that. And
we start the task.
So seven, 8 minutes for this.
It should be done right.
The credentials are on the Web site
this way when you just navigate
there,
there is username and password here.
If you can't see the log out, just
pause,
then pause the execution before the logo.
Okay?
Yes, that that
will do that.
That is correct.
Very good.
I see there are some people done already.
That's good.
Okay, that's fine. Yeah.
If you added a couple of pauses, then
that's good.
Did everyone verify the title?
Guys?
Okay, good.
Nice.
Two more minutes
and then we'll do this together, guys.
Okay.
Now, the title is incorrect.
They probably misspelled it.
Make sure you don't misspell
the the title guys
after you log in.
The title may change.
Okay, so on the login page,
it's a web orders log in.
But when you when you log in,
that's going to be a little different.
All right, guys.
So let's do it together.
So now
what we're going to do,
you guys are going to guide me
so that I can finish the task.
Okay.
So first of all,
what do we need to do in here, guys?
So I have a main method.
We have a task in here.
So first and foremost, all we need to do
is we need to set the property right.
So system,
the set property first
driver, chrome
driver,
and then what we have and here we have our
right.
Okay?
And then we need the objects
of the web driver
in here.
Okay?
So now we have with life the browser.
We set the properties.
What is my next step?
Guys in here
we need to navigate, right?
So driver, get in here
and let me copy
this guy.
Let me copy in here.
Okay,
So we're navigating to this left side.
So what is my next step, guys.
Okay, so maximize. Yep.
So I won't be maximizing, right?
So we
will just let me just put it in here
and then I'll just comment it out for you.
Okay?
So driver dot, manage my window
and maximize right
that I want to be doing this because it's
it will maximize it on other screen
so you won't see the other actions.
Okay so now
do I have to check the title right now
guys.
One do I have to check the title?
Guys, go step by step. Right?
So you navigate, you log in, right?
So after you log in,
you get the title and verify.
So now it's time for us to go ahead
and log in to that application.
Right.
So before I do anything,
what do I have to do
in here, guys?
Go to the website and inspect.
Right.
So I'm inspecting this guy right now.
So I'm going to I'm
going to click on the Magic Arrow in here,
go to my user name, write user
name, TextBox in here.
So in here, how many of
what's called
how many locators do I have for
username guys?
Three.
Okay, name ID and class.
Right.
So now guys, in the previous example,
when we were talking about the class name
being Unique, right?
So right now in this example,
I can show you that
the class name will not be unique
because they are.
There are two classes which are
which have the same exact values.
Okay, so I have one class in here
which has t, z,
and I have the other class
which has to Z in here.
Okay. So if I identify,
why can use type or style?
Because they are not part of locators.
Okay, so locators,
they are built in features.
Okay.
So that's why we won't be able
to use other
other attributes right away?
We will be able to use them.
But it's a little bit later.
Okay.
Next,
next class, I'll show you how to do that.
But right now, let's stick
to the locators.
Okay.
So as you can see in here,
I have two classes.
They have both same exact values.
Okay, so that means this username.
If we use the class name,
it will not be unique.
Okay, so
but I have a question for you guys.
If I use the class name, which,
which element
will my selenium interact with?
So if I use a class name.
So that means I have two elements on hand
right now.
So if I, if I perform any action
right.
So is it going to be username
or is it going to be password?
It's going to be the first one
our selenium means.
Right? Exactly.
So if we have two different
that different elements,
but we have the same class names
or same names or whatever it is.
So that means if we use
that our selenium will pick
the first one it needs
and it will interact with that.
Is that clear, guys?
Okay, so that's
why we're trying to locate the element
as uniquely as possible so that it is only
okay so that our selenium doesn't
get confused
and mistakenly interact
with different elements.
Okay. All right.
So here we can go ahead and start
using ID in here.
Okay.
So the idea is a little bit long in here,
but that's fine.
Just going to copy that.
Okay, let's go back in here.
So now what am I doing next?
I copied the ID value.
We need to find the element. Right.
So driver, the find element.
I'm finding it by ID
and I'm just going to paste
that value in here.
What am I doing with this?
Look, with this element,
I am sending keys, right?
So send keys in here.
So We know that the username
should be tester,
right?
So we identify our username in here.
So now let's go back in here. Right.
So identify the password now.
So here we have the same type
of attributes in here,
but in this case let's use the name.
Okay, So what I'm going to do,
I will copy the name value in here
and then I'll do driver find element by
name face ID here and
I will send my password.
Okay.
All right, guys,
I hope you guys use different locaters
that we've done so far, like ID
name linked tax and partial link text.
So that's going to be
if you did that, that's good
because you're practicing
different locators.
So that's very good. That's
all right.
So I entered my
username and password,
so now it's time for me
to click on the log in.
Okay.
So again, going to go ahead
and click on the Magic Arrow in here.
Go to the log in
and let's see what we have in here.
So we have an ID, we have a name
and, we have the class name.
Okay, So let's try to use the class
name and see if this is going to work.
Okay, So let me copy
this value.
Okay? Sure.
If you use classy work, that's good.
All right.
So let me go ahead and do driver
sign element by class name.
Right.
And what I'm going to do, I'm
just going to place the class name in here
and what action
I would performing on the login button
was simply collecting.
Right?
So there we go.
Okay, so we clicked here.
So let me.
Yeah, this.
Okay, so we're logged in, right?
So what is my next step, guys,
we need to get the title right.
So let's go back to our code.
So if I get the title,
what am I getting in return?
Guys?
I'm getting a string value, right?
So string title is equal to driver
get title right.
So now if we want to verify this,
I will simply have an F condition.
And right.
So if my title that I just got
equals,
let's see what it is, what orders right
then what I want to see in my console is
title is correct.
If it's not correct, then
my title is
wrong.
Right?
Okay, so we got the title.
We're trying to verify this right.
And what is my next step?
Guys want to.
That's fine.
Yeah. So.
Okay, so now we need to log out, right?
So go back to our website.
So what we need to deal with,
we need to click on the log out.
So again, this magic arrow,
locate this log out.
So what is this, guys?
Is this a button?
What is this?
It is a hyperlink, right?
How do we know it's a link goes?
It has a tag. Exactly.
There we go.
So what we can do in here
we can use what locator
we can use in here.
Test link, link text. Right.
So we can use the link text
or the partial link text.
So let's go with the link text because
the our link text is not that
what's called long, right.
So is just one word in here.
So what I'm going to do driver
find element by
link text and I will paste that
and what I need to do
I need to click right.
But before we log out, guys, what
I want to do, I want to wait a little bit
so that we can see
actually that we're logged in right?
So it's going to pause our execution
for two more seconds.
So 2 seconds and add that exception here.
And then at the very end, what I can do is
to just quit my browser.
We use idea to log out.
Yeah, yeah.
If you have the log out,
I'd you can use this.
But guys,
let me tell you this before I forget.
So the idea
is as I set the most reliable locator
from any other locators. Right.
But sometimes,
sometimes the ID cannot be reliable
when it has some numbers.
Sometimes it can be dynamic.
If it has numbers, it might be dynamic.
And it might not be
it might not be considered as reliable.
Okay.
So in this case, we have to in here.
So I wouldn't really use this,
but for now, it's not a big website.
Okay, guys.
So it's pretty light website.
Nothing really changes in this.
But whenever you start working,
you need to pay attention
to these kind of small things.
Okay, So keep this in mind, guys.
IDs, if they have a numeric value in them,
they might be dynamic
and they might change time.
Time.
Okay, Is that clear?
How do we know if it's dynamic?
You won't know it right away.
Okay. That's why I'm saying it's it.
It might be finding that element
that day that you're working on,
but the next day,
if something gets updated on the website,
it might not work
because the ID gets updated
and it is dynamic.
Okay, guys,
why do developers write them as dynamic?
I'm not really sure, to be honest.
Yes, I've seen that in Facebook, actually.
Exactly.
So I've seen that in Facebook to
that ID numbers are changing
By the time.
Yes, you use the ID with two numbers here.
As I said, this
website is not getting changed anything.
But in real time, guys like Facebook,
as I said, other different
big companies, the IDs on some elements,
they might change okay
it might be that Yeah, the prevention
for hacking.
That's one good point actually.
Yeah.
All right.
So I quit this. Right.
So let me run this now.
Let's run
this and see what's going to happen.
Running this log.
Then we're here.
Log out and we quit the browser.
The title is correct.
Everything looks good, right?
I hope everyone got the same output
and it wasn't
that difficult to complete.
Okay.
Any questions before we move forward,
guys?
Okay, good.
All right.
So now let's get back to our notes, guys.
Okay.
So as we learn about locators,
we've used a couple of them, right?
So now I have a question for you guys.
Why do we need so many locators?
Guys, it
wouldn't be better for us to just use ID
or to have it.
You guys,
to minimize
the possibility of wrong entering.
Yes That's one of the cases.
Okay,
Flexibility is good.
Okay, What else, guys?
Because some of locators
can have duplicates, right?
As we see as we've seen right now in the
in what's called
the class name tag. Right.
I mean, the class name attribute in here,
we saw that it had a duplicate value.
Right.
So you can see
see you can see see in here.
Right.
So some locators might have
duplicate values in the other notes.
Okay. So let's put it in in here.
Some locators
have duplicate values.
In other notes.
Okay, Screen with the codes right here.
Okay.
Anything else?
Always have them all listed. Okay.
Who provide us those attributes?
Guys who provide us those
locators?
Developers. Right.
So whenever you look at the HTML,
this is written by developers, right?
So developers may not provide us
all the locators
for all the elements, right?
They might provide some of those, right.
And we can we have eight.
So we need to find any of those
eight inside that specific element.
Okay.
That's why it is more flexible for us.
Is that clear, guys?
So developers
may not provide
all the locators for all the elements.
Okay.
Anything else, guys?
Anything else that you can guess?
That is very good point.
Some of the locators are not always
applicable to the elements
we're searching, right?
So let's think about the link
text and partial link text.
Where can we use those?
What tag
can we use the link text and partial link
text guys or what kind of
elements we can use them for
those we have a traps.
Exactly.
So that means we using them
only for the links, right?
So you can't use the link texts
or partial link
text for the button or the text
right there or the text box.
Right.
So what you can use link
text and partial link
text is only for the links.
Okay.
That's a very good, very good point.
Okay. So
we can say some locators
may not be
applicable
for the elements we are
looking for.
Right. So
an example here,
link tax and
partial link
text is only used for links.
Okay.
All right.
Any questions, guys?
Any questions on
why we need so many locators
in selenium?
To be clear
and pretty straightforward, right?
Okay.
So what about the attack?
So the attack we said it is for
it is for links, right?
So in other words, guys,
what it's called is
an anchor tag
is also called an
and protect.
Okay guys.
So a is also called an anchor tag.
Any questions guys?
Let me see
any questions
on how to locate the elements
how to interact words,
how to click, how to send some text
guys, how to use the locators
that we've used so far.
Any questions on those?
Okay, good.
So let me see
one second.
Okay.
So let me show you one more thing.
So let me create a new class in here.
It's going to name it as Web orders.
Okay.
So what I am going to do in here,
I'm just going to copy and paste
the some of these in here.
All copy this and pasted in here.
Okay.
So let's assume that we are navigating
to the to that Web orders
website and we're trying to send
keys, we're trying to locate the elements,
input the email,
I mean the username and password
and then click on the log in button.
Right.
Okay.
So now
before, before we used to see
whenever we get the current URL
or we get the title, what are we getting
in return guys,
we said before that we're getting
a string value, right?
Okay, that's good.
So now if I find if I locate any web
element on the web page,
what am I getting in return that?
Is there anything that I can get in? Does
not really.
Not the code, but I am getting a web
element object in return. Right?
So whenever you locate the element,
what I do
is I'm getting a web
element object in return.
Okay.
So I have that web
element on hand right now.
So what we can do in here, as we did
with a string
assigning to the title, right?
Whenever we got the title,
What I Can Do Online 14 is
I can do a web element.
Username
is equal to this, and
I will need to import the web
element class in here.
Okay, so I import this,
but I am having an error.
Okay.
Why Do I have an error?
Any any guesses on this?
No, really.
We don't need to add any new so.
Okay.
I initialize it. Right.
Blake, what do you mean by send keys?
That that's a
that's a right path in there.
I'm performing an action right away,
but I need to be performing an action
by using this reference
that I just created.
Okay, so this
whenever you want to get a web
element in return, what are we doing?
We're just locating that element, right?
So what I need to do.
I need to remove this part.
Okay.
And that's going to be it.
So in order for me to get the web
element object, I need to just located.
Okay.
And then whenever I located it,
I signed it right to this
variable in here.
And what whenever
I want to perform an action,
I need to use this reference from here.
Okay.
So what I will do, I'll do a username
and then I will
have the send keys in here.
Okay.
Is that clear?
Guys, this is this is pretty cool, right?
This is
as you guys did
and in Java that is signing
some variable strings, integers
and everything.
So this will give you more readability.
Okay Now it is stored in a variable.
Exactly.
It is stored in a username
for the rest of the Java class.
But why do we need to do this, guys?
Why do we need to do this?
Instead of two lines of code,
I can have one.
Exactly.
We can reuse it right?
Can we can call it again
later on if we need to.
Right.
So now,
since we started in the in a variable,
we can use this variable
in anywhere in this class afterwards.
Right. There we go. Nice.
Okay, so here what we can do again.
I have a
web element.
Password is equal to this.
So since we performing action,
we don't need this.
So I'm just going to remove this. Okay.
And what I will do the password and
I will place this back in here
and same way in clicking as well.
So I have a web element of log in button
is equal to this.
And since we're performing in action,
we're getting some errors
in here.
And then this is how our code
is going to be looking after this class.
Okay.
So now we'll learn how to actually assign,
how to create web element variables
and assign them
whenever we locate any elements,
Any questions, guys?
Yes, of course.
Yeah.
Without knowing,
it might look a little confusing, but
it is very simple, right?
We're doing in here
a storing in a variable
and then doing an action, correct?
Yes, we storing it in a variable
and afterwards
we are performing
an action on that particular
on what's called
particular element.
Yep. Once you know
all the key words is pretty simple.
But we will be,
we will be simplifying these again
and it will be more readable
in the future classes
when you start
going through the frameworks.
Okay,
So when you start building the framework,
you will see how
how the code is very readable,
how you organize everything
differently in different packages.
So that's going to be very cool as well
in class.
Absolutely right.
Yes, we will be creating parent classes.
We will use a lot of inheritance guides
whenever we go through framework.
Okay.
We won't be actually running them
in the main method.
Okay.
So there will be some different
execution points when we start creating
when we start creating frameworks.
Okay.
I'm really surprised
you guys are enjoying this.
I've seen in couple different batches
that they're asking
why we need this
and they didn't like it at all. So.
So that's that's very good.
The format we will be using.
Yes not really, not,
not in the real lives, but in selenium.
Yes. In real life
you will have a framework.
Okay.
Which is a combination of different tools.
So there will be
a little different approach in there.
But in order to build that approach,
you need to know this first.
Oh yeah, there's there's going to be a lot
of polymorphism, guys, so don't worry,
there will be a lot of inheritance
polymorphism.
There will be a lot of abstraction
probably, I'm not sure,
but we'll see
the easy part.
Yeah, guys,
all of the concepts are easy now.
Oh P concepts are really fun and easy.
Okay, so
let me see. So
all there should be one diagram.
Okay, There we go. Okay,
sure.
I'll. I'll explain it. Okay.
One second, guys.
So let me explain this
architecture for you, because yesterday
I didn't have access to these files.
Okay?
So yesterday I wanted to explain to you
this architecture.
So as you can see, guys in here,
we have a web driver interface
that we mentioned before.
There's a protected class in between,
which is a remote web driver.
And then these are this interface
and these classes are inheriting
from this web driver.
Okay.
So we have a Firefox driver,
we have a Chrome driver
and we have an Internet Explorer driver,
or there should be
if you're using a mac, you can do safari
and all those classes as well.
Okay.
So this is the simple architecture
of what is going on behind this guy.
Okay.
Can just do web driver.
Driver is equal to new web driver. Nice
So that to keep it generic.
Not to mention either
we using Chrome driver or Firefox driver.
Can we do that?
Some people say yes. Some people say no.
Why no, guys?
Because it's an interface.
Absolutely right?
If you have an interface,
if you have an interface,
you can't create an object
of the interface directly, right?
So you have to created in directly
to the with the
inheriting and implementing classes.
Okay, It's good.
All right.
So let me see.
I wanted to show you one more thing.
I forgot what it was.
Okay, let me double check, guys.
One second.
And let me also put in here about
if two or more
elements. Same
attributes and
actually values.
Then selenium
will only interact
with the
or element
locates.
Okay.
All right.
This should be clear, right?
Does anyone know, guys?
Does anyone look into the history
of selenium?
Why it is named as selenium.
Guys?
Why this tool is named as Selenium.
Does anybody know
it's a joke?
Well, it is kind of a joke, right?
It's a chemical element, right?
So before before selenium guys,
there was a tool
which is called mercury.
Okay,
So there was one guy who invented mercury.
This is a testing tool and all that stuff.
Okay, So
but I don't think it exists anymore
or I don't even know
what happened to that.
So the
the founder of Selenium
he wanted to destroy that other company.
So the only chemical element
that can destroy mercury is selenium.
So that's
why that's
why the guy who invented selenium,
he named it as selenium
so that it can destroy mercury.
Okay. So
that that's a fun fact actually.
So and I think Mercury was
was not for free.
So that's why he,
the guy who invented selenium,
he made it free so that he can
completely destroy that mercury thing.
Okay.
Oh, you didn't like chemistry.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's pretty funny.
All right, So,
okay, guys, from today, any questions?
Let me see.
Naming the organization later
before the competitor.
Yeah, that.
That that works.
Yeah.
What a node is when it's PAC.
Oh, okay. Yeah.
And Node.
Okay, let me go here.
Okay,
so A node is going to be, as we said,
an object
is any line on the on the h html.
The node is
is the same as the object. Okay.
So as you can see in here, so head
and body are in the same node.
Okay, so h html is the very top node.
Okay.
Do you guys have issues with with audio?
Okay. Okay, good.
All right.
Okay, guys.
So as you can in here,
HTML is a very top node, Okay?
And you can see head
and body are at the same level vertically.
Okay.
So that means they are on the same node.
So this is one no, this is another node.
And if I expand the head in here,
you can see
different different nodes in here.
As we said, it's an object right before.
Node is the same thing as an object.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys?
Or any confusion is in there
each line?
Yeah, we can say that.
We can say that each line
can be considered as a node, as yes,
the top one is h html.
Top node is the edge HTML.
Okay.
And oh, the guys
and oh, okay.
All right.
So now
the fun part is the homework.
Okay.
All right.
Let me
copy this.
So I have a pretty big homework for you
guys.
Okay, So let me copy this.
All right.
So here's the thing.
So the first homework that you need
to navigate this guy in here
and fill out the form,
click on register, close the browser.
So let me go ahead and explain it
open that for you.
Okay?
Okay.
All right.
So this is the website that you need to
you're going to be working on
for your homework. Okay.
So when you navigate here
you can see there is a there's a forum.
There are a couple of what's called
text boxes in here and fields
that you need to be enter.
Okay.
So fill out the whole form in here. It
it doesn't really matter if you fill it up
with real information or fake information,
because this is a fake website.
It's not going to get captured anything.
Okay.
So fill out this form.
Click on register, close the browser.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys?
Okay, sounds good.
So the second homework
we need to navigate to the Facebook
or is this guy okay,
let's do it again.
Okay, so we're here.
What you need to do
when you navigate to the Facebook,
click on the Create new account.
Okay?
They don't create new account.
You will see this guy in here.
Okay, Fill out the first name, last name,
mobile, new password and on sign up.
Okay.
Do not go into details
with birthday or gender because we didn't
what's called we didn't cover these yet.
Okay, Just fill out the text boxes.
Click on, sign up.
Okay.
And let's see in here if I click on this.
So it's going to tell you what's missing
and what you need to do.
Close this.
Okay, Close this pop up
and then close the browser.
Why did I write Facebook at work?
This is the shortcut for Facebook, right?
With the pop up we're switching from.
No, guys.
Not yet.
No switching frames, Nothing. Yes.
You don't have to create an account,
guys. Yes.
So just click on Create new account,
fill out this information.
Okay, So you fill this out
and then if you click on sign up,
it's going to tell you
that something is wrong, right?
Because you're creating
a fake account in here.
And then what
you need to do, click on this
closed button and then quit the browser.
Okay, guys,
make sure you close the pop up.
Guys do not close the whole browser before
closing the pop up.
Okay.
All right, guys. So
I don't have anything else for today,
but tomorrow, guys, tomorrow
is going to be
an intense okay.
Because we will be going through
through the Express and SAS
and we will be going through the advanced
X path as well.
Okay. The homework.
Do you want me to post it in the course
announcements.
Sure. Yeah.
I'll post this
tomorrow.
I'm not sure.
I mean, next class guys.
Sorry. Not tomorrow. Okay. Next class.
Next class is going to be next.
Next week, right?
So next class,
we will have a little bit intense class
because we will have x CSF selectors
and we will have an advanced X plus
class. Yep.
I said, Guys, I said before
that you will have some challenges.
So this is one of them tomorrow,
not tomorrow.
Next class.
Just watch how to build the X path
for videos.
Next classes slide.
Sure I will.
I will share the next class of slides
in canvas.
Okay.
So in Selenium review,
I'm not sure if it's tomorrow, guys.
I'm not sure what kind of review
you're having tomorrow,
but we will have our next class next week,
not tomorrow.
All right.
I will also.
Yeah, sure.
I will also post
next class of subject and course
announcements as well.
Yeah, that's fine.
Actually, you don't really need
the YouTube videos, but you just need to
to look at the slides
because I will post them before the class.
So take a look at the slides in canvas.
Okay guys.
So they have a lot of explanation in their
I'm not
sure if you guys having classes on Monday
or any other days
because I don't really know the others
schedule.
Okay.
All right, guys, any any questions?
If there's no questions,
I'm giving you back 20 minutes.
But we'll probably have an intense
class next next week.
All right, guys, If there's no questions,
we can wrap it up.
Okay. I'll see you next month.
Next week?
Next Tuesday. Okay.
So I'll upload everything.
I'll push the code.
So take a look at it and we're going
to have more fun, I hope, Next as well.
Okay.
Thanks, everybody.
Have a good night
and I will see you next week
by everyone.