Okay.
Hello. One.
Hi. I am Lily, Jimmy
and Lena.
And Lena and Anna.
I am Lupo.
Okay, so first of all,
are you guys able to hear me
out there?
Okay, perfect.
And you can see my screen, too, right?
And the video.
Okay, perfect.
Perfect.
Great, great, great.
Hola, Michael.
Are you talking about Michael?
Right? See?
Are you
Hispanic?
Okay,
so, by the way, like you wrote Hispanic.
So I write it like his panic.
So Michael is panicking right now.
Okay, So let's see.
Still 55 students.
We need to wait,
I guess, for two, 3 minutes.
I mentioned that you guys should be
joining
Shark, but
let's wait for two more months
and then we'll start the session today.
We will be spending less time
chatting and in breaks
because we got a lot of stuff to cover.
And that's the reason
today we'll be doing a lot of work.
Yeah, actually, that's the problem.
Confused between evening and morning,
right?
Yeah, same here.
I'm even confused about the days. Right.
You know, these days.
Okay. Which days? Today.
And today's Wednesday, right?
Yeah, today's the second in the last class
with you.
Right.
Well, I suppose
this is how it is supposed to be,
but let's see.
Oh, I think that maybe we will be needing
one more class for debt
and we will see how today's session go.
And then I'll let you know
if I need to extend one class
or we are going to be good for, you know.
Yeah, but no, don't worry.
I'll, I'll be there with you and,
you know, coming classes
all the most really teaching
you selenium and all.
So I'll be taking classes for good again
when you are done with, you know, test
energy and cucumber.
So get totally comprises of seven classes
and 2 to 3 are
before you know in the start of that
and the rest of your
classes we schedule after
once you have
recovered you know
just energy and cucumber
and java
okay so yeah my timing was not correct.
I adjusted it today.
So that's why, you know, right now
you can slam.
I'm good.
How about you for on.
Okay, so let's wait one more minute
and then we'll discuss the homework.
So tell me,
how did you guys like all of you
try it out?
Okay.
Leena,
I'm going to walk you through that. Okay.
So one thing
I was just going to the homeworks
that you guys posted, students
syntax tolerance gel.
One thing that I noticed is majority of
you have done it right,
but majority of you actually, you know,
you are in the wrong directories.
So I remember yesterday we discussed that
you need to decide
where to you want to create a repository
and that should be the one that contains
all the files of your Java project.
Right. Okay.
This is what we discussed yesterday,
but a lot of you
I saw that went inside s rc
and then you went inside.
You know com and then classes and there
you created a opposite free.
So was there any confusion about it?
Are you guys just, you know,
I did it by mistake.
That's
are you guys able to hear me?
Because I don't see any replies.
Okay, so I asked a question and
none of you replied, okay,
so let me repeat.
I said that I was going to your homeworks
and I witnessed that a lot of
you have done it correctly, but
some of you have made this mistake
that you chose
the wrong,
wrong place to create a repository.
Like remember I mentioned that
we need to be careful
where we want to create a repository.
It should be at the place where
all our Java codes are going to be so,
but a lot of
you, you did what you went inside,
you know, S.R.
C then com
and then you created the repository.
So this is what
you were not supposed to do?
Yeah. I share your was correct.
So we so I think yours was also correct.
But some of you, you know,
you had this mistake
but that's, that's completely fine.
Albertini I think if, if I mentioned,
if I commented on that wrong
then means wrong.
If I did not comment, it means is correct.
Okay. Yes.
Today we will be learning
how to create the opposite tree.
Yeah, I'll be going over to that.
Okay guys.
So I think that.
Yeah.
Michael, you you went with way too far.
You should have stopped that job.
Is it okay, So don't worry, guys.
Today we will be reviewing that too.
And I hope
that it's going to get more clear.
Okay, So let's start our session
and we will start by
what we learned yesterday.
So first of all, guys, why do we need good
well, perfect
to keep track of our
Java course or they can be in
any other language, too, right.
And now let's come up with the question,
what is it?
And you'll get
are you already answered it?
Git is a version control tool.
Why do we call get a volume control tool?
We discussed that because
when we added a code
every time it makes them amidst
it creates a new version of it.
Right?
And in order to have those all versions
saved on our computer,
we have a software which is good.
It keeps track of all of them.
That's why we call it a version
control tool.
Okay, so
when UNIX commands,
we learn one by one.
What's the first command that we learn?
It's the first one is PWT.
What does it do?
Yeah, Who am I was not basically,
you know, we won't be using that a lot.
So. Okay, so one by one, what does BW do?
Yeah,
exactly.
For the current location of terminal,
what's the second command
that we learn less
and what does let's do
listed contents of the folder in which
terminal is an
okay third 1cd
folder name.
What does this do?
It moves the terminal
to the folder
we mentioned.
Okay, at this point
I want to ask you guys one thing.
What if I write down D
and after that I give a folder name
which is not currently present
in the directory, which terminal is
which I really like.
Get Exactly.
It would tell me
no such file or directory.
Is there.
Exactly.
So are you guys clear about this?
Right that whenever you do c, d
and the folder name that
folder must be at that particular location
where the terminal is
perfect.
So now the last command
sorry, the second last command that learn
to the dot dot.
Perfect
moves the terminal
one step back.
And the fifth one was
c d tilde.
Right.
What does this command do?
Moves the terminal
200. Perfect.
What is open day?
Three days
OC main directory
where it lives.
Okay, so hundred trees, the location
there
when we start our terminal,
that is the location
where the terminal is by default
when we open it
is not the place where it is.
Okay?
Farhad It's not the place.
Forget is
it's the actually the location
where when you will open up your terminal.
The point from which it starts,
this is called your home directory.
Okay?
You will not go in detail
that what is the home directory right now?
Okay. Just, you know,
visualize it as such.
But now.
Okay.
So I guess anything else
that we discussed, guys, any anything else
or is this all.
I think that's all
we learned.
We are command
but that is just used to, you know,
clear the terminal.
And who am I told you
your name So.
Yeah, yeah, perfect.
We learned that.
What's our observatory?
Who can tell me that?
Very good.
Entered a storage.
Right.
And a let's get is a repository
right. It's
this video
repository.
Okay.
Get as vulnerable as a tree.
Okay, let's.
Let's.
Yeah.
Get is a tool that creates a repository.
So repository is actually part of get.
Yeah.
But the thing is that okay
let me explain it to you
more clearly
get is Yeah
that example of minion I get that but
that was just to clear out your concepts.
Actually when we install get that
particular repository that is created,
get is the one who is managing it
and doing every stop, right. So
if I talk
about, you know, computer in computer
is not going to install
a cover or something, right.
It there won't be any lock or something.
So it's just going to do what
it's going to create a folder for you.
Write a separate folder on your hardest,
which saves
all the data.
Do you agree?
Practically, there's not going to be
any cylinder or locker in the computer
get is just going to create a folder
where it can, you know, actually
save all the cores on your heart.
This.
Okay, So remember we talked about this.
We said get is up to let's say
version control to that
creates
a repository.
Okay so there is
this repository
located on our machines, right.
So we can see that it's
local repository surfing.
This means that you guys
did revise everything.
And I hope that you guys also watched
the video
that I showed right?
Okay, good. Good enough.
Did you guys learn from it?
Okay, perfect.
So this means that today's class
is going to go very smooth.
Okay, Have some. No worries.
You will be covering that in class on.
Okay.
So first of all, let's quickly
start our review, our homework.
Can someone just based
based on homework and chat
so that I can, you know,
show you that?
Sure.
If you your question
is going to be answered as we move on.
Okay.
No, I need the question.
Let me go to post start.
Let's see the question is.
Yeah.
So the this
so this is the question for homework and
that briefly you know
I just two settings on my PC.
The problem in Slack
is that once you shift the channel,
it doesn't let you see the latest
comments. Okay.
Now I'm here for the purpose.
I know.
Just don't share your solution, guys
that don't share your solutions.
I have seen them all. Trust me.
I went to the channel
and I reviewed all your solutions.
Okay,
so the first thing that I'm going to do is
I'll open up my clips right?
Because most probably right now
I think I don't have any project.
So let's see if I have one
or not.
Yeah, clips.
Okay.
So I'll quickly just, you know, create
one project because I reinstalled my clips
and I don't have that Java visit,
so I'll create all of it.
You guys already have this project, right?
So you don't need to do it.
Okay,
So let's look at the question that we had.
Open your terminal
so simply, I'll go to search.
I'll open up my terminal.
Here it is.
Okay, Navigate to the folder where
you want to create that your transit free.
And I mentioned that.
Make sure you select the correct
directory.
You need to have it up
as a tree in the folder.
All the files
and folder of your Java project are
okay.
So what does this mean?
Where should I have my repository?
Which
we need to first of all, select
the point
where we want to create a repository.
And I mentioned that it.
This folder should be the one
which contains our Java project
and our Java project is in Eclipse. Right?
So first of all, what I'll do,
I'll say, okay, this is the project
that I want to create a repository for,
so I'll right click on it.
I'll go to properties
and I'll check the
location of this project.
So this is the location, right?
So this means that I need to create
repository inside
Java base. It.
Okay, so now
I'll open up my terminal and I'll see that
what's the current location?
So I'll do TWD
It says that it is in C users i.t user.
So what should be my next step?
What should I do?
I wanted to move to Atlas workspace,
so first I'll do else.
I'll see if eclipse workspace is in there.
Yes it is.
So now
if I wanted to move to Atlas Workspace,
I'll do CV at Lip's
Workspace.
Okay, good enough.
Now I want to do
pWt again to see if it has moved
into Atlas Workspace.
It has.
The next thing that
I want to do is to move to Java Basic.
So else again
and Java Basic is there.
So I'll do
Java based.
It. Okay.
Now at this point I'll do PWT.
I'll see my terminal is inside
Java Basic, right?
Yes, Jamie, you can you can simply use
KDR also, but you will
you should do that when you are exposed.
Okay.
In the start
I recommend that you use these commands
so that you know, you get more of an idea.
You can skip that, obviously.
Okay, so now I am inside Java busy.
I'll do else.
And this is the place where my binary
and source code are, right?
So we discussed yesterday
that we should create a repository
where all our Java project
files and codes are.
So should I go inside
FRC and then creator of the
or should I
created at this particular point
created now?
Right.
Perfect.
Okay.
So that was the homework
let's we'll continue our class
at from this point.
Okay so do you guys remember that
we discussed yesterday
that whenever we want to store our codes,
we will tell get to do that
and it is going to label
it and place it in the repository.
Right?
So there is one small thing
that we need to have in there.
We need to delegate that.
What is the
who is the actual person who is
working right now
and what is the email address
that he is using?
For example, let's say
there can be multiple users
who are using the same system
and working with it.
So what they need to do,
they have to configure it.
They have to pass their own users
username and email address.
So the very first step that we have to do
is we need to configure git.
Don't worry about that hassle.
I'll explain it to you later.
So before we start using it,
we need to configure it.
This configuration
is all only going to be done
once.
Once you have configured your get,
you guys do
not need to consider it again
unless and until you uninstall it.
Okay.
Because you are the one
who is working on your computer
and you will be continuously working on
that just in case.
If you want to change your username
password, then you, you may,
you know, change the configuration,
but else you won't need that.
So are you guys ready to configure, get?
Okay, so the first configuration is
to give our user name.
This can be done using the command
get configured
dash dash global
user name
and after that you are going to pass
and the user name
and whatever you want to.
Okay,
So I'm going to copy this command
and I'm going to paste it into life chat,
copy it and
along with me, open up your terminals.
Do not paste it yet, okay?
Do not paste it.
Have you guys open up your terminal?
Okay.
First of all, let's go to the home
directory
using CD Tilde,
let me know when you guys have done that.
No clear is just going to clear.
You know your terminal and two Tilde
is going to bring the term
of that at home.
Okay. Now
you can paste the command
or, you know, type it manually, get config
dash, dash global
user dot name.
And then after that, in inverted
commas,
you are going to give your own user name.
Okay.
So I have given my username
so you are going to write yours.
Once you have written this press enter
and let me know.
This command
is not going to give you any output.
Okay.
So there should be no error, no output.
We need to give good
our email address.
I should write with small g
straight the screenshot.
I was sure the screenshot.
Okay.
So for that we have get on the dash. Dash
guys who are having issues in that.
Can you share your screenshot in support?
And also over here
you need to show the screenshot to others.
I can not help you out.
Give me yours is good.
There's no I don't see a problem in there.
Do I make up user name or use user
name from it?
You have to give
a user name.
It can be your own user name.
You need to make it up,
but make sure that it
so you don't write one like writing one.
That said, I my own user name,
you can give your nickname or whatever,
just don't type in user name.
Okay.
Helmet your problem is first of all,
I told you to do CD Tilde.
It was CD space that you did CD
Tilde direction.
Okay.
The next problem
is that you use get config
dash dash global user name
and you give my user name.
Whereas I mentioned
that you have to give your own user name.
Okay.
And that's your problem.
So I see that
what you guys are doing wrong.
Okay.
So stop
everything about whatever you are doing.
Stop everything and listen to me, okay?
Give me one minute.
Everyone, please.
Please, guys, just stop typing and doing
whatever you are.
Just just pay attention
to what I'm going to say right now.
Do I have your attention?
Okay, Very good. Now, listen to me.
This is really easy, okay?
This stuff is actually very easy.
We are just doing configuration.
You will be making mistakes if you are not
going to follow my instructions.
It's okay.
So just hear me out first.
I am sure that I'm speaking.
So I'm giving you time.
Hear me out First,
make sure that your command on
desktop has run perfectly fine
and then only follow the next step.
Okay. First of all,
you need to hear me out.
So I'm going to do the configuration again
for you guys.
And this time I really want you guys to,
you know, keep up with me, okay?
We can do this together
and we can quickly wrap this up.
Are we on?
Okay, so let's do it in this way.
Okay.
Let's let's close our terminals,
Let everyone close their terminals.
Let's do it from scratch.
Okay. Close your terminals.
And now open it up.
Now open your terminals.
Let me know
when you have opened your terminals.
Very good.
Very good. Okay.
Everyone is done with that. Now
we need to configure our using them right.
The command to do that is
git config dash
dash global user dot name.
And then in inverted commas
you are going to give a user name
that you want.
Okay.
Now make sure that user name
is not having spaces.
It can have space,
but make sure it does not okay
and make sure that these spaces
are also kept clear of this.
This is very sensitive,
guys, these commander, very sensitive.
You cannot write them without spaces.
Okay, So you are going to have error
if you are going to give spaces.
So what I'm going to do,
I'm going to send this to you
as it is
so that you do not make any mistake.
Okay, I'm going to send it to you,
but make
sure that you replace the user name
that you want
with the correct user
name of your own twice.
I'm going to do that also in front of you.
So I'll open up my terminal
and I'll paste this command over here.
Let me know when you have pasted
this command.
Okay? Do not press enter.
Do not do anything else.
Now delete
only the stuff that is between inverted
commas.
Okay.
Let them make sure
that you do not make any syntax
mistake.
Okay.
After you have deleted it is anymore
everyone still
this one's with me.
You guys have deleted everything and
between the inverted commas
are we go to this point.
Now let's write down
the user name of our own twice.
So my name is Muslim,
so I'll be giving the user name
of my own name.
Yes, it is Dash. Dash Global.
I, I think that it's double dash
but not showing
over here that it's double dash.
Okay. So yeah, I think
on pasting it did not show up right?
So we'll correct it.
Let me know
when you guys have written down
the username
then.
Now make sure that this Dash global
is actually dash dash.
Just make sure of that
after giving the name user name,
just make sure that this is dash.
Dash.
I think in copying and pasting
it did not go right.
Are we all good?
Is everyone has everyone
to enter their username and this dashed
dash made this correction okay,
now let's press enter.
This camera should run without any output
and please do not do anything else.
Mohammad shared a screenshot.
Okay. Really good. Thank you guys.
See it and helped you write.
Now we know how to
you know
how the process should go.
Manmohan, I'm waiting for you.
Just simply share the screenshot.
Yeah, in notes it's
at least two,
but it's actually combining them.
But I should do this.
Nice. I think more a
okay, so
decode was to have posted in the support.
Okay. It's not.
I did.
Come on
did call big.
Okay so you are having no space
between configure
index dash global
gesture issue.
Okay guys. So make sure that you are
having the correct spaces.
Come on.
It is simple, right?
Kazim. You can also follow, follow it.
Whatever we are doing, the
okay, so Mohammad,
you are not having a space in between
configuring that as global.
Okay, So is there anyone on the support?
Let's see what caches there, I guess.
Okay, so gas, please help the student.
And I think I have spent
a lot of time on this.
Guys. This this is simple, right?
So we need to move forward forward.
What is this output like?
Are you on your on your terminal
to open up your terminal again and
and show me the output?
It means that you have entered
the wrong syntax
since
we are not going to do email part
right now.
Guys, I don't want you to.
I don't want you guys to, you know,
some of you lagging behind
and some of you moving ahead
because this is just the starting of.
Yeah, I don't want you to be confused
about it, so we'll move slow.
Okay.
How many of you are still having problem?
Raise
your hand. Let's get to work quickly.
Okay, Let's go. Get over it.
To how many of you are having a problem?
One to anyone else.
Okay, fine.
Those of you are having a problem.
I'll do it again.
Just follow me
very, very vigilantly. Okay?
Open up
your terminals.
Open up your terminal.
Once you have opened it up.
Now what you need to do.
I'll. I'll. I'll tell you.
Yeah. Open up your terminals. Right.
Everyone who was having problem.
Okay. Now
type in. Get
then give space,
then confirm
after config again space.
Then you need to type in dash dash.
Then you have to write for space Global.
Then you need to give space
and type in user dot
name.
And then after that inverted commas
you have to give your user name.
And I mentioned that
please do not have space
in your user name,
so I'll give the user name
and I'll closed in what it comments.
Okay.
Now press enter.
Now we need to configure our email address
also.
Let's quickly do that Tenga.
See your you guys will be making just this
index mistake.
Please, please make sure
that you are not making any mistake.
I have written everything.
If there is an error, make sure
that you are writing the correct syntax.
Andrew.
Your error is going to get resolved.
Don't panic.
Daunting
that okay. It's not working for me.
What should I do?
Just make sure that you are writing down,
you know,
the correct syntax.
Yeah. Just take a deep breath. Okay.
So now the next command that we have
is did
config dash, dash global
email dot address.
No. No.
Its user dot email.
And then you need to in place of your
user name,
you need to now give your valid email.
So I'm going to give my world an email
and you are going to give your own valid
email.
Answered that assignment.
Don't worry.
After that press enter.
Let me know when you are done with this.
Come on guys.
It should be real quick now because it's
the same one as you typed above.
Just its user dot email.
Okay, good.
So what does this do?
We are telling it that
whatever caused you were will be saving.
You need to mark them by my username
and by email.
Okay.
So this is the
just the basic configuration that we made.
It's a one time thing.
You will not be doing it ever again.
Okay.
Yeah, you are good. Go. Okay, perfect.
Ten got.
Now let's move forward.
Okay, guys. So
tracking our first project
using get.
So let's start the interesting part
and which is start
to track our first project using it.
Okay.
This was the configuration that we made.
Now, the first step that I need to do is
I need to open up my eclipse, right?
Because this is the place
where my Java codes are
right?
Okay, so now
what should be my very first step
is who's going to tell me
the first step
is this first step to navigate my terminal
to the folder
where I want to create the repository
right? So
this is my project,
Java visit, which I want to, you know,
keep track of.
I'll open up properties
and this is the path
to which I want to navigate.
So we have done it over and over again,
guys.
So I want you to quickly be able
to navigate to this point.
So I'll do PWT right now.
For me, it's it users outside c d
eclipse workspace
and then see the
Java basics.
And once I am inside Java, this is out
to LS to make sure that bin and SRT ad
are there at this point.
For those of you
who do not have Java visit,
you can go inside any project
that you have on your
eclipse.
Okay.
But make sure that you have reached
the current location.
Okay.
Once you guys have done this, let me know.
I'm giving you one minute
to reach this point so that we can,
you know, all work together.
Very good.
Auto capitalization
is working at this point.
Start me.
Okay, so now I'll open up my terminal.
I know that my terminal is right now
at the correct location.
I want to create a repository
at that point.
So I simply use
the common good space in it
and I'll
press enter.
Now I'll be shown a message
initialized, empty, get repository
in c users i t users equity floor space
no job it don't get.
Okay.
Have you guys done this?
All of you
successfully initialized repository.
So running this command
is going to make the repository over there
very simple and very easy.
Right.
And these serious
being in the support. Okay
Michael
you are good
it seems that initialized good repository.
Some of you may be seeing some hints
and warnings.
Don't worry about that.
Okay.
Once we have created the repository,
now what we want, we want to
get to save our codes in that that one.
Right?
This is what we want.
Okay.
For that, we have just two commands.
Get add space dot
and the other command is
get comment
dash M along with a commit message
that we have to make.
What is a commit commit is actually
saving our course to the repository.
Okay.
What is the comment
saving codes to the repository.
So whenever I see
now that we need to make a commit,
what does this mean?
Is if you are having problems support,
you need to post in support.
So whenever
I see you need to break a commit,
it means that you need to save
go to the repository.
Very good.
So now let's open up our terminal
and now let's do it.
Add space dot.
Make sure that there is space
between get and add and add
and dot.
Let's press enter.
Don't worry about that
if you like the master,
but I have not explain anything yet. Okay.
Just make sure that you are following me
step by step.
You are not missing out on a step.
Only you have to make sure of that.
It may be different for, you know,
some of you and me.
That's totally fine.
This is because of,
you know, different values and stuff.
I explain to you later.
Okay,
so the next command that we discussed
in order to save our codes in
repository is good comment.
Dash M with the message.
Let's first
comment.
Let me know
when you guys have written this. Yes.
With space.
With space is everything
should have space.
Get space command space, dash and space
in what it commands
and in there commit message.
Now press enter.
You'll see something like this
message master would come in
first command
Something like this will appear.
Yes, that one dash not not double dash.
Okay.
This is the proof
that you have successfully
saved your code in the repository.
So tell me, guys, is it difficult?
All right. So easy
now if you want to.
Okay, I'm leaning. Don't worry you.
I'll be going going over to it
multiple times.
Just make sure that you get
your issue resolved immediately.
Mine says authorized entity own unknown.
Yes. The manner that is because you
I think you did not
maybe configure your good gate correctly.
Okay.
Okay guys.
So now if you want,
get to show us everything
that it has saved in the repository.
We have a command for that.
Also.
And what is that command?
It is good space law.
So I want you guys to write down,
get space log
and press, enter.
Now, do you see that?
It says that author is Muslims Hardy
whose email addresses this one
date is Wednesday October.
Whatever time you're
and along with the
message dated please.
So now do you see that
what we discuss about get
how it's automatically doing that
we just need to type in some commands
and it's going to take your everything,
labeling them
and whatever.
Yes. And Maria, it's correct for you.
That's fine. That's fine.
If you are having other,
you know, a lot of classes, that's fine.
The only thing is that
you should be displayed message.
Okay, Fatma, your problem is that
you have not configured
your terminal correctly.
Jimmy Most probably because
you have not considered it correctly.
Yeah. I think you, you did not do this
crap.
Okay, so
what is this?
We will learning it
when we move out in the past.
Okay. So at this point
I want to tell you guys something.
I just wanted to show it
very quickly to you that.
Making permits in the repository
and by commit,
I mean saving your codes in the app.
It is really simple.
So you guys get really comfortable
when we move forward.
Now what we will be doing is
we will be understanding that
how it's actually working at the back end,
you know,
if if we know how to do something,
just, you know, without knowing in-depth
that what is happening at the back end,
it's going to be really problematic for us
when we don't deal with our stuff.
So it's important also to
learn that how the things are working
when we are working with these commands.
Do you guys agree?
So we must learn that too.
We are going to jump into that and today
we will be going over to this a lot,
making some bad comments,
creating repository and, you know,
running these commands and again and again
get add dot get come in.
We will be running these commands
again and again.
So those of you who are still, you know,
having struggling, do not panic, okay?
You will get along.
So let's do one thing at this point.
Let's go for a break.
And meanwhile
I can resolve, you know, help out students
who are having difficulties.
And after the break, we'll continue
with our lesson and will, you know,
try to learn everything else.
So are we good?
Let's let's go for a great guys
for 15 minutes.
Okay. So I am your new great manager.
That role is, you know,
now should be transferred to me.
Eight of five.
So let's meet at.
Yes. You mean you can.
Are you guys back?
I'm back from break.
Okay. Never left. Wow. Great.
Hardworking students. Good. Okay, guys. So
in the break,
I hope that everyone issues resolve
and you guys are now have now successfully
configured your good
and made the first comment
that is saving the codes in your app
observatory.
I am I write about it
very good.
Very good.
Now we will be doing step by step.
Okay so attend to that.
I'm sorry, but your what you need to do is
you need to press control. See,
that is going to take you out of this.
And the command is actually get come
a dash and push to make whatever you see.
This sign is actually my cursor
that is being you know
displayed.
Okay, guys.
So anyone who is still having issues
please support is the way to go.
Now We will be moving forward. Okay.
I'm still giving
you guys support in the live chat
because this is just
the starting of our class with kid
and you know, I don't want you guys
anyone to be left behind.
I want all of you to be with me
when I go into the actual concepts.
So now it is that time, and I hope
that I did my best to bring you all
to the point where we can actually start,
you know, the technical stuff.
So from now onwards,
please be very vigilant,
be very attentive.
I don't want you guys
making any syntax mistake and
such kind of mistakes because
we have spent a lot of time on that
and clearing that out by now.
It should be really you know, you guys,
you guys should be comfortable with that.
Okay.
So whatever I do you have to follow that.
You guys have to follow that. Okay.
And you have to understand
what I'm telling you.
So I'm going to close this terminal
and I want you guys also to do the same.
Yes. Regarding as long as I'm recording.
So let me know when you have closed it.
Okay, good.
Now open up
your eclipse.
Have you guys open up your eclipse?
Done.
Okay, so here's what we are going to do.
We will be creating a new project,
a new Java project from scratch,
and we will write down some code in it
and then we will track it using get. Why?
Because I want that.
All of you should have that project. Okay.
So right now let's pick on file
New and then Java project.
I hope that by now you guys know
how to create a Java project, right?
That's simple. So
let's give up the name, get
project.
Okay. So it says that. Yes.
Okay.
So did project with a lowercase,
which.
Okay.
Are you guys done to this point?
Jimmy It shows you new project.
You have to just flip on the I good.
Do you guys have this now on your system.
Okay so now let's do this
right click on our SIRC
and let's create a new class.
Right click on SIRC, new class.
No, no,
we can.
But you know, we are learning it.
We are not focusing right now on the
you know coding stuff.
It's just,
you know, just creating a project.
So just go with the class right away.
Let's do it.
Good.
You want
okay.
And let's click on finished
get zero one.
You can limit any anything you want to.
Okay, guys, I simply created a project,
a Java project,
and I created one class in it.
Okay. Nothing else. It's simple.
You guys already have done it
multiple times.
So I'm.
I'm supposing that you know, it.
Okay, so let's write down
a very, very, you know, basic code in it
actually.
Okay.
So I just wrote down system
that out of print.
Alan Hello Joe Batch 11 Nothing difficult,
nothing complicated.
Okay, so now let's, you know,
let's assume
that this is the code that we wrote
and now we want to
track it.
Okay?
So in order to track this project,
what should be my first step, guys?
What should the first step?
You only know it.
We have done it like 15 to 16 times now.
At least. Yes.
Perfect. Miriam.
Very good.
Navigate.
All right.
Terminal
two location there.
We want to create the representing.
So now I'm going to do this. How?
First of all, I'll open up my eclipse.
Then I will.
Right on get project
and I'll click on properties.
Okay.
Who is going to tell me that what I did so
why did I do that?
That I went to great project in my place.
I clicked on properties and this
because I want the location
where my project is right
Simple.
Okay, so what should I do now?
I want to navigate my terminal over here,
so I'll open up my terminal
pwt I two users.
Alice
Now for me it's Eclipse
Workspace.
Okay, I'm inside Atlas Workspace
and now Ellis
BWT again, I am inside it.
Perfect.
Now let's add in to see that I have
the folder get project Angela Bissett.
So now which command do I use to
change my folder?
What will be my command
CV and what will be the name of folder?
Yes, perfect CD
Good project.
Okay,
now I'll do Ellis again.
So guys, is this the right location
where I want to create the repository
repository?
Yes, this is the right location
because I want my repository
to have everything
which is inside this project.
Okay, So
now I'll also explain you guys,
everything that is actually happening.
I just closed that back
pain lane to minimize eclipse and
you know,
I'll open up the whiteboard
and I'll just draw some stuff
for you, okay?
So over here
I will try to make you guys visualize
what is actually happening at the back
end of it.
Okay.
So if I open up quickly
the location of my project
and Explorer,
uh, you guys don't need to do that.
I'm just doing it.
Show it to you.
Okay.
Okay. So this is what I get project.
And over here, I have some files,
dot settings been SA C-class bad
dot project right.
So I can copy dispatched
and I can see that this folder is actually
the current folder
that we are dealing with
and it has.
Let me draw this
folder buying binary file.
Let's limit binary
and the source file.
And what other files do we have?
Dark last that dark project and settings.
Okay.
For now, I'm just ignoring these files off
with the extension dot flashback
dot on dot settings.
Okay.
I'm just ignoring them.
Are you guys with me?
Very good.
Okay, so we have moved our terminal
to this location
right?
So what I'll do
if I want to
create a repository over here,
what I'll do.
Do you guys remember
what was a step that we do
get in it.
So number two step is get in it
to create a repository.
So let me first show you that
what will happen when we do get it.
So let's say I run the command git in it
as soon as
I run the command, get it in this folder.
What happened is there comes a new folder
and this folder is
dot git.
As soon as I run
the command, get in there,
it creates git creates
a new folder called DOT.
Get in the location of my project.
Is it understood?
Yes. Sebastian.
Just you know of giving you guys
the concept.
Okay, so let's do this
and also visualize it.
I'm going to type and get in it
and I'll press enter.
Okay.
So I need to go to view
and click on Hidden hidden items
and then I'll see a dot git folder.
It's hidden,
so I have to make it visible view
and then click on hidden items from Mac
users.
You can
command Shift
DOT is going to show you hidden files
for hard.
If if you created a new project
and you never used git in it,
then you should not be having it.
Okay.
It means that you did not follow
the instructions correctly.
So what you can do is
you can just delete this folder.
So guys, deleting this border
going to actually delete the repository
and you can initialize it again.
Okay, So let's continue
at this point.
Now you guys are mature enough
to understand
the architecture of it.
So now let me explain you
the architecture update before we move
any further.
So what do you understand
by the architecture?
When I say architecture object,
what what do you guys understand
the structure, right?
How it has been actually
so good has actually at three
stage
architecture.
Now let's have a look at that
as soon as we run, don't get command.
This folder does create.
This folder creates incentives
folder behind the scenes,
which is not visible to us.
What is happening.
These two things also are created
inside this folder.
One is called the staging area
and the other one is called
the repository.
Okay guys, are we good to this point?
Everything in this make making sense,
right?
Okay, so
this is called staging area.
This is called repository.
You get to know that how they are working
and the area where our original files are.
This area is called
what do we call this area?
Does anyone know
working directory
or folder?
Okay, so when I run the command git in it,
it says that initialized
empty
git repository in this particular folder.
So this means that up to this command,
the condition of my folder
is that there is s, rc, Ben and DOD
with the empty string area
and an empty repository.
Do you guys agree with this
is understood?
Perfect.
Okay, so now I am going to explain to you
that what is a staging area
and what is our approach?
First of all, let's talk about working
directory.
The place there are codes
are Java files, are
the staging area.
Okay, who knows that?
What is a staging area?
So who's going to tell me that?
What's a staging area?
Okay, so staging area
is the place
where we add
all the files, codes or folders
which we want to send to the repository.
And what is it you represent pre
storage, which contains
all our comments and what our commits.
Guys, we learn that. Yes.
So staging area, let's move back to this.
It means that everything
that goes into the repository
first has to go to the staging area
and then it is
it goes to the repository.
This is what is actually happening inside
get okay,
we are just visualizing it
Fahad I'll put answer you that.
Why do we need that?
But right now
just go with the flow.
No, we can answer that.
It's prep area.
I should answer that
so why not?
Will get to know
real get to know.
Okay.
But just for now, tell me that
are you guys clear with this concept
that when we use the get in it
command staging area and rapport created
and everything
that we want to send to Apple
first, we it to staging area
and then the repository.
So how many steps
how many stages are involved,
how many studios there for the code three.
So three stages working directory for code
staging, area for code
and the rapper of code.
So there are three stages
that that are involved.
Right.
So that's why I
get is called a three stage architecture.
Okay So now let's move ahead
and all the questions
that you guys are having.
They will be active.
Okay,
pass them.
I'll be going with that.
But not right now.
After some time, I'll be dead.
Just go. Go with it.
What we're going to be doing.
So now let me open up my notes and let's
go ahead.
So what is the next step, guys?
When we want to
save our code
after creation of the repository
what's the next step?
Let's use the command
git add dot.
And what does this command do?
Can anyone tell me?
It adds the file, add the files
to the staging area.
Okay.
Now, before I do that,
I want you to let you guys know
one very, very important
command that we have in it, and that is
git status.
You know, we talked about that.
It is, you know, just like a Post-it
and we can communicate it to it.
So at any point in time,
if you want to ask the status of our app
as it pre,
we can only use the command get status.
It saves nothing.
It does. No, it only tells us that.
What is the status of your app physically.
Okay.
I shall not.
Not right now. Not right now.
Follow me.
Don't do anything unless I have done it.
Okay.
So what do you guys think?
That if at this point I run the command,
get status
before running it at dawn,
what is going to happen?
What is the status of my app?
Is it.
It's empty, right?
The staging area.
What's the status of the staging area?
It's all empty.
So the get status is going to tell me that
the files are not being tracked.
Do you guys agree with that?
Okay,
so let's let's, you know, test it out.
So if I do at this point, get status,
what does it say?
Let's forget about on branch
Master for now.
I'll tell you. Okay.
Whenever we move forward,
it tells me no comments yet.
Yes, we do not have any comments.
Okay, good
untracked files,
but it should mean
that you have some untracked files
in your working area.
What are those on untracked file?
It's showing us that bin s RC
and some files that, you know, a dot
extension, dot
class, that dot project and dot settings.
So if I
open up my actual explorer,
we can see that yes,
there are dot settings
bin SRT, dot last that
and dot project.
These are appearing in red.
The files that appear in red,
these are the ones that are indicated
that they are not being tracked.
Okay.
Up to this point, guys, any confusion?
Let me also write down the files
bit dot extension.
I skipped them initially,
but just to make everything more
clear, we I have lost that.
And what else files do I have?
Settings and dot project
so it's
okay.
Use the command get status
to view the current status
of repository
files shown in red
on untracked files.
Okay.
Now we we discussed that we can use
the command gate add dot and if you add
all the files to staging area.
So what if I want to add
just one file to the staging area?
I want to save only one file.
I want to keep track of only one file.
So which command do I have for that
section?
I can use the command for
git add file name
and it will only add this massive file
to the staging area.
So Let's go ahead and try that out.
Okay.
So what if I run the command
git add
and let's say S or C?
What if I run this camera?
What do you guys suppose will happen?
Can someone tell me?
Okay, Martin,
you are saying that SRS will go to Apple?
No. What will happen
as soon as we do get add, SASE
get is going to make
a copy of the file SASE
and it is going to move it
into the staging area.
Okay. So this is what is going to happen.
Okay, let's do it and visualize it.
Git add
s or C,
and after that I'm going to press enter.
Okay, so
get add s RC shows me no output.
I want to know whether SRT has been moved
into the staging area or not.
How can I do that now?
I have the command of good status.
I can use that to know
what is the current status of the tree.
So I run the command, get status,
so get status is going to return me.
What can someone tell me
looking at the,
you know, diagram, I think that it should
tell me that SRT has been tracked
where has been dark last bad dot setting
and all projects are being untracked
right.
Simple, simple enough.
This is what I am expecting to see.
So let's see.
Get status and I'll press enter.
So it says that
no commits yet because
our app was empty
and it says
changes to be committed so whatever is to
be committed should be in staging area.
Right.
So it means that whatever we see in green
color is in the staging area.
Right
here I see SASE
get a WAN and SA symbol for dot Java.
Basically these are the inside files
that it is showing.
So we have actually RC in the staging area
and the files dot
last that dot prior dot setting
and then are still being untracked.
Okay.
Now what I want to do, I want to just see
my SRT in the wrapper.
This is what I want to do
so I can run the command.
Good comment.
Dash M and after the M
dies, after the m, we place a message
and that message should be comprehensive
enough
to, you know, make the person
who is looking at it
understand
that what is during the comment.
So what do you suggest that
I should name it.
I can name it first
trim it or I can also say
only contains SIRC.
And I say that too.
Don't you think it's a better
command message?
Okay, so if I run this command,
what is going to happen?
It is going to make a copy of the SRT
and just chilling area and it is going to
just simply place it in the report
and it is going to label it
with what things it will label it.
Can someone tell me
commit name, date time,
user name, email, address.
Okay,
so now let's do it
actually on the terminal.
Let's have a look.
Good comment.
Dash M
contains Essar Steel.
Let's run this command.
Okay.
It showed me no output.
I want to know
the status of my proposal tree.
What's what has happened
is everything that I can see.
Is everything correct or not?
I can run the command, get status right.
Okay.
So tell me guys, without running,
tell me if I run get status,
what will be the output
near?
Please support channel.
Okay.
So my output should be
that it should tell me
what are the files.
It should tell me that
what are the changes
that needs to be committed
and what is there in the repository?
Right.
These are the stuff that it should me,
it should give me all the information
about what has happened.
So let's let's run, get status and see
it's status.
Now, when I look at status,
it's it's saying that
you just have untracked files in which
SRT is not included.
It's neither in the staging area.
It means that it's in the repository
already.
Okay.
Makes sense.
Now, let me move
you back to previous status over here.
It shows me that changes to be committed
and it was showing them in green color.
So when we come
in, those changes did disappear from
it disappears
from the get status.
Okay so for a had we noticed that
just because
the bin folder is not in Untracked
Oak is not in Untracked,
it's not in staging area.
So where can it be now?
There's only one, one stage that is left.
But it can be. It can be in wrap. Right.
So how soon can you show
your screenshot in the support?
And I'm sure that
is there to help you out.
Okay guys.
So at this point. Yes.
Yes I show it does at this point.
Let's take a break for one minute.
Take a deep breath and we have
all you know, done a great job.
Let's appreciate ourselves.
Okay.
So you see, we just ran all the commands
that we did in the first half,
but now we actually that
how it's working at the back end, right?
You guys think that this was difficult?
Is anyone who thinks
that these concepts are difficult
are not understanding them.
All right. And don't worry.
I'm going to give you more examples.
More and more examples in today's lesson
is, you know, a just to this.
So we will be practicing it more and more
and you guys will be comfortable with it
if you understand how it is working right.
If you understand this flow,
then trust me,
you won't be having any difficulty.
Yes, it will. You guys will get good.
I know if the first time.
Okay, Don't worry.
Just make sure that you understand
the concept.
Okay?
Okay. So let's practice some more.
Okay.
Let's do the practice till this point.
Are you guys all with me?
There is no packet, Michael.
I just created the class directly.
Hashim,
get your issue resolved and catch up.
Okay?
We are just going to repeat everything
for errors.
Guys. Support is there for you. Okay.
Make sure that you post screenshots
in the support, okay?
And you'll get help.
Okay. So now let's do this
guys. Let's do this.
Let's open up our terminals.
Tell me that if I want to view everything
that I have in the repository,
we discussed that we have one command
for that which is that
in the repository?
No, no, no.
I'm not talking about
the folder.
I'm talking about the repository.
Get lol get log as a command
that gives us all the commits
that are there in the represent.
Okay,
so at this point if I run get low,
what do you guys expect to see?
How many comments are going to be there?
Only one or less one get logged
and I see that there is one commit with
the author name,
email address, date mentioned
and the comment message.
Okay, so this is 1b30259.
Whatever this is, it's a it's
going to be different for each
and every one of you.
It's actually, you know, a code
that get has for it for saving.
It's come at that's
how it labels the command for itself
and it's going to be
unique for every comment.
No, I haven't.
You can not.
Yes, I show like a barcode.
Okay, guys.
So let's move forward. Let's move forward.
Okay.
What we want to do next
now I want to add the rest of the files,
then class batch settings
and projects to my repository.
You guys are going to guide me that
How am I supposed to do that?
So what's the first step?
I need to run the command.
Get add dot.
What is this going to do?
As soon as I run
this command, it's going to take
everything that is there
in your working directory
and it's going to take it in
the staging area.
So now if I do get
status, let's run,
get status before running,
get that dot just to make sure
that you guys are reminded
that these are the untracked files.
Okay.
Now if I do get
at dot instead of file
name, I'm using dot.
Right?
And if I press enter.
So this operation has happened.
Everything is in the staging area.
I want to make sure that my gate
is not cracking everything.
Which command should I be using?
Get status right.
So I'll open up my terminal
and I'll say get status
and I'm expecting
now that everything is going to be green.
Okay.
It says that changes to be committed
and it's showing me
all the files that are
on track
now. It's showing me in green
and telling me that it is now
cracking down.
Okay, Now I want to
make a new comment
where I have
all these files
where I'm
just picking them up
guys too, because I have less space
now. So
your syntax
error, this is going to be your indexer.
Okay, so for that I have a command
get commit dash and I can see that.
Let's give the message
all the files committed.
So let's open up our gate
and try to do that.
Yes, well, cash is doing the support here,
so get
comment dash m
contains
all the files.
Okay, guys, now if I run, get stat
without running the command, tell me that,
what do you expect?
You'll see
because
at this point you're working directory
and your app wizardry
are at the same level
they exactly the same files.
Right.
So you'll see nothing
less.
One good status
and it will say nothing to come it working
tree is clean.
Now if you want to view your repository
and see how many comments
are there in it,
which command are you going to use?
Git log
and I'm expecting to come.
It contains s rc contains all the files
and if I have a look at this,
I have to commit
and in my logs also I have to
comments. So
let's take a break guys
for 2 minutes to line 15.
In fact, the three minute.
Let's take a break for 3 minutes.
Meanwhile,
I'm going to help you out with the stuff.
If anyone is having problems,
I can help you out to
two 915 guys.
We got 3 minutes.
Anyone still struggling with
with a command somewhere?
Send the screenshot to me.
Okay.
We anywhere in loss conditions
and the screenshot
screenshot of those
been shot.
Send the screenshot in life. Okay.
Because I cannot switch the
oc Illini.
Your problem is simple, right?
Let me. Let me answer to that once.
Okay.
You have.
You forgot to actually close the inverted
commas, right? Yep.
Come on Dash.
I'm only contains srt.
After that you did not put the inverted
commas and you press enter if you do such.
So get opens up, decode something this
and you won't be able to exit it.
So try control see all Colin Q
equals Colin Q are controlled.
It will take you out of this loop and then
you can reenter the correct comma.
Okay.
I hope that that is going to resolve
the problem.
Okay, Mustafa, for you.
Mustafa you are good.
You just made one comment.
You did not made the other promise.
You have no errors, but you did not, I
guess, stop wallowing in between you two.
Some reasons
assume your problem is that I
think that you created the repository
at the wrong location.
You need to do less and make sure
that only been an ACR over there
because you see a lot of files are there.
It seems like you created your app
was it read inside
you know your home directory
just leaning on Mac try calling Q
okay.
Apple for you
you have no issues.
You are good.
Okay guys, so
I hope that
by now
okay you did
okay.
You are good to go.
Okay.
You made the comment, right?
It's their perfect.
You just skip the second comment.
But that's fine.
You can
continue doing what we are going to do
and then after the class,
you can catch up
this step in the recording.
Okay, guys. So
now the next step that we learning,
usually this stuff
we have learned up to
this was the trust me hardest.
Now after this,
everything is going to be simple
and not get complicated.
Okay, so what if now in my looks good
After saving this,
I woke up next day
and I started to make changes in it.
I added system dot
intel and it made some changes.
Let's say I made this change and
I'm going to save it.
Okay?
I saved it.
At this point,
I made the change in my Java code.
Is this change changed file
in the repository?
No, it's not.
There.
So I'll represent change with red for now.
Okay,
so this is the file that we have.
So if I now run git status,
what do you think is going to be
the response of my get?
Okay, don't tell me the colors.
Tell me logically
that what should get be telling me
it. You
tell me that your file has been modified,
Right?
Okay.
It should not tell me on time
because it's already tracking it.
It should me that the file
has been modified
right?
Unplugged means that it's.
It's in the working right has never ever
added in in the staging area
or the repository.
Whenever we made changes in our code,
which we have already saved it's
modification right.
So this time, if I open up my terminal
and I say
get status,
it shows me two files modified
SRT and BIN and the modified is also shown
in red color.
Wait, wait, wait. Hold on.
Let me explain something.
Try to read this
What it is say changes not stage four
come in and it's telling us
that it has modified files.
Before it was telling us untracked files
now is telling us
modified files right.
Okay.
Who is going to tell me
that I made changes
in only one file, which is SRT?
Why am I getting the changes
Also in bin file?
Who can tell me that?
No, that's okay.
Let me tell you that. So
bin files,
then files are actually binary files
and they are totally dependent
on your system.
Okay, It's going to be different for you.
It's going to be different for me when
I really make some changes in our codes
are binary files automatically change,
even if we are not making any changes.
Okay.
So that's the reason
that we are being shown that
there are some changes in bin files.
So let me also color my bin file
because it's also, you know, changing.
Okay.
At this point, I want to,
you know,
add these up digit changes in my apple.
So which command should I be using?
I should be using it at DOT.
Okay.
So using this command, get add
dot is going to make a copy
of the SRT file
and it's going to add it
to this changing area.
It's also going to take a copy of bin file
and it's going to add it
to the staging area.
Okay.
So at this point,
the question is that whether these files
dot last that dot settings dot project
are these files going to remain there
or are they going to be
deleted from here?
Okay. So
for conceptual purpose, remember,
for conceptual,
we will say that they will remain there.
Okay?
They are going to remain there.
Okay.
So now let's add the files
where the command did at DOT.
Okay?
So it shows me no output
if at this point
I use get status,
what do you guys suggest will happen?
What should be the output of my terminal?
Okay.
Which files?
It will show me
in green and let untracked files.
Are you sure about it?
Okay, let's try that out.
So you guys are saying
it should show me two files
in green color?
Yes, it does. It shows me that
these are the two files that needs to be
committed.
Okay, so
now I want to commit these files.
Which command am I going to allow?
Updated SRT, and then, Okay,
I'm going to put this message.
Look at running.
This command is going to do what?
It's going to make a copy of everything
that is there inside
the staging area
and it's going to create a comment,
a new comment
DOT project is supposed to be there
and it's also going to label it
with, you know,
commit name and everything that we learned
before.
So let's do get
commit
dash m
and at this point, let the answer
put the message contains
bin and se are see
updated right
let's press enter.
Okay.
Now I want to make sure that my repository
nothing else
which is on track, modified or updated.
I sure I'm going to reply to your
and to yours to just wait
so I can run get status right.
So running at status
is going to return me.
What at this point can someone tell me?
Nothing. Right.
So if I run with status,
my working tree is clean.
Okay. I want to see
de commits in
my repository.
Get locked
said now.
Shows me three commands, all
with the message and
the first one appears at the bottom.
And then so on.
Okay.
So now
this cycle is going to repeat someone.
Someone asked me.
Yes. Every time he makes some changes.
We will have to add them to
the staging area, will have to come back.
That's okay.
This is something
that we will have to do continuously.
And now let's let's deal
with one more scenario.
Let's create a new, let's say, file
over here in this folder.
I'm going to create a new file
and I'm going to name it
text file.
In fact, I think creating a text file is
going to be difficult for you guys on Mac.
So let's do it.
Let's do it.
From the clips.
Let's go to that project
and let's do new and let's do class.
Okay?
So I want you to click Kid project.
At this at this point, did project
and click on new and click on class
and name text.
So I want the source folder to be good.
Project
everyone.
I want you guys to do this. Okay?
I want you make the source folder.
Did project and
create a class and name a text.
Let me try it. If it.
Yes it does.
So let me repeat right
click and get Project new
and then class.
Okay.
Make sure that your source folder is
get project
type in the name text
and click on finished.
No, nothing. Nothing.
You need to. You need to select nothing.
Okay.
So what we just did,
we created a new file, right
We just created a new file in this folder
in our working rectory,
which is text dot Java.
This is what we did, guys. Right?
We just created one new file.
Okay, Now I want you to tell me
what will be the
status if I run get status
without running a command.
Actually, I want you to tell me this
exactly
because we added a new file,
which is not yet in the staging area.
All render apple.
So this is going to see
that there is one untracked file.
So let's check that out right.
Get status.
There you go.
It shows us that this file text or Java
is on track.
Now, again, if you want to track this
file, guys, what what I need to do
is, Abdul,
you are getting this because you created
your file in the wrong location.
I told you
specifically to go to new class,
and then you need to remove SIRC.
I mentioned.
Okay, so we have, you know, to
to match us to do that I can use good
add text or java or I can use get add dot.
Will that make a difference?
It wont make a difference.
Why can someone tell me the reason
that why it would make a difference
at this point?
Only at this point
because it is the only file
that is a b on track.
So if I use get that done, it's
going to take every file which is only one
or so.
Let's do it at dot.
Okay.
Now if I do get status guys,
what should be the output output?
The text files should be turned
into green,
showing that it is in the staging area.
Right.
So now again, what I want is
I want it to have in the repository.
So this
and it will make a new comment
and it will label it
also, we are running this command commit.
Let's say
the message just time is going to be
new file
text dot java.
So if I open up my terminal
now and I type in, get
comment bash m
new file
text dark shower.
Okay.
So I again made a syntax mistake, right.
I forgot the semi semicolon the start
so I have to quit it.
Okay.
You can either use column Q or control
C, okay.
Now at this point, if I do get log,
I can see all the,
you know, all the full commits.
So I made full commits, right?
If I want to make sure I can simply have
a look at my wiggle
dragging on one, two, three,
four and everything is in synchronization.
Okay, so what is the question?
If there were many files
still we would use could come dash m
I said, What do you mean?
That if you have many you mean to say that
you have many files in this staging area
that needs to become added? Yes.
Remember, get commit M What it does is it
picks all the file in the staging area.
It it is.
Is it not going to differentiate that?
Okay, let me pick one.
And this answers the question of amma
y first staging area graphical
because if we want to make a
decision that we want
only few files in our comment,
then we have to send them first
to staging area because Repository
is going to pick complete code
in the staging area.
So okay,
so enough practice
or do you guys want to practice or.
MUHAMMAD I'm afraid that once
the commit has been made,
you cannot do that.
Is there any command to
to do what?
To select good dash? M
I don't get it.
So that to file.
Okay, this is what I told you.
No, get commit.
M is going to take everything
that is in the staging area.
That's the reason, guys.
That's
the reason you have staging area. Right?
So for example,
if you just want to have text or Java
your repository, what you can do is
you can use only send text
or generate in the staging area.
Okay.
Silence.
That is going to be our next topic.
Okay. Not now.
We are not discussing it right now.
How created class to on that?
Do you want me to tell you
that how I created text on Java
or this one gets you don't want that
simple you need to click on
SRT new file is to you know,
create it over there good or too
I did not create get
okay test for Java
for creating test for Java click on
get project go to new
and political class
by default it is going to show you that
this source folder is
see just delete it from over there
and then we have a name
and click on finish.
This is not did correct corrected.
But why I did it because
it's hard for you
create a file on Mac attacks.
Well so in order to save that hassle
I just created it directly
from all the there.
The purpose was to show you guys
how the gate is working.
Okay.
So don't,
you know, think that this is something
you should do or this is something
you will be doing in Eclipse?
You should all
only focus on the get barred.
Okay, So
let's what else do
we have for today? So
okay, guys, so tell me, is the workflow
Get clear to all of you.
Is I clear about that?
What's a working
directory? Was a staging area.
What's the apple?
Okay, so you are not clear about
what's a staging area
and what's the apple?
You're not clear about this.
It's going to work.
If you remember this workflow,
everything is going to go going, okay,
sure.
Okay, let's do one thing.
Let's now just delete one file.
Let's just export Java.
Okay?
I deleted text or Java from my folder
and let's also do it in the eclipse.
Let's right click on it.
Let's click on the lead and click on.
Okay,
So text or Java has been deleted.
So we had this file text or Java
and I simply deleted it from the
eclipse.
Okay.
Now if I do get status
without running anything on time,
what do you guys think
is going to be the output?
Okay, so Aleena and Jimmy,
you guys are saying nothing.
First of all, tell me is at this point
working directory
and the ripple are at the
at the same level
or is there any change is
there is a change and what changes that
it's the deletion
in this
we have text or Java and our last commit,
but now in the working library
we do not have text or java.
So do you expect that
good should be smart enough to track this?
You expect it to be smart enough?
It should be right.
So let's do this status
and see what it shows us.
Look, we see
it says that changes not stage four.
Commit
You have deleted a file, text or Java
and you need to make these changes
in the repository.
So when you delete the file,
it shows up in red with the message,
delete it.
Okay. Okay, Jimmy, That's fine.
That's why I told you that
with the concept that you have.
Okay, come with the concept that you have.
Not by running it
how to make changes in the repository.
What? What do you mean by that?
What's your actual question?
I don't understand it.
Like changes that we just made,
how to select them.
Okay, we are we are going to do that now.
We we we ran get status
and it shows us that, you know,
this file has been deleted.
So what we want
to do, we want to have this
working
directory state in the staging area.
So which command should I rather?
So let's try that out.
Let's try get at dot
and now this one
get status.
So what it did is
it took the state of the working day pre
and it reflected everything over there
and it updated the changes
it said that deleted text or Java.
So at this point
after running it to add dot
Dexter Java is going to get deleted
from the staging area.
Also.
Okay.
So at this point, is it
going to get deleted from the wrapper?
No, all everything
is there in the staging area.
So if we want to now
have this in the report,
do you guys think that we will have
to make a new commit or we can
somehow make changes in the previous
commit?
Yes, you are right about it.
We will have to make a comment.
I'll tell you.
Why is that so?
It's nothing to be confused about.
It. Okay.
So when you run this,
everything that is there in
the staging area is going to come to
a new commit.
And guys in this new commit,
do we have any text
or Java
knows?
So we have reflected the changes
in the working in the repo.
I'll tell you I shall we
we have reflected the changes
that are in the working tree in the repo.
Look at the classes.
One, two, three, four. One, two,
three, four.
Everything is the way that is seen.
Nil haven't be reflected in
what have happened to the text or java
in the previous commit,
but it's not in the new commit.
Right.
I'll tell you why is that so?
Okay, so first let's do it
and then it will come to that question.
So let's honor terminal write down, get
commit dash am
text file
dot java, delete it.
Okay, let me know once you have done it
and then I'm going to answer your question
that why we do
we have to make a new commit
and why is it not deleted
from the previous
commit?
Okay, so
now I'm going to tell you
I'm going to actually answer the question,
which is that, hey, when I deleted text
Java from working directory,
it got deleted from the staging area.
Then why is it not deleted
from the previous commit?
Why is it making a new commit?
This is the question right?
You guys get the question right.
You understand that?
What the question is all of you.
Okay, so now tell me that what if
next door Java one of the feature
which was in version three
but you don't want that feature and in for
so do you want get two
also deleted from version
three
so good is smart enough
to take care of that right
Get to smart enough what it will do
next time you make changes delete
something.
It is going to say,
Hey, make a new comment
because I don't want to you to lose
anything that you have done in the past.
So remember,
should keep track of all the history,
everything that you have done till point.
That's the reason
you cannot go back and delete some commit
once you have committed it.
It is not going to allow you to do. Yes.
Let me if I can.
Do you want to have
look at some repository on the internet,
someone's repository.
Okay, let me show you that
I have not taught you about GitHub of yet.
You'll be doing that in next class.
But let me just show you one of the
repository and show you the comments.
How how do the look of some real time
project
this is okay.
So this is all repository
and the number of comments
that are there is 720 do
so there are 722 commits
that are there.
And the interesting thing is
that I can go back to anyone
which everyone I want to,
but these are all the commits
that are there.
And you know,
if you look at the commit message
couple more glitch
fix commit time number six 2020
and less would be decimal to
double it was an overkill so
kind of that
all the comments are there
and everything is being documented
so that's how helpful you get
is for you.
Okay so does it make sense, guys,
whatever we have learned today,
are you all comfortable with that?
Okay, perfect.
So what I'll do
is okay, even if you close the terminal.
Okay Awesome. I'm going to guide you.
Just.
Just be here.
Even if you close the terminal
at this point,
it's not going to make everything loose
for you. Why?
Because you have everything
in the repository.
So what if you want to again
work in this project
and with the same repository,
what you are going to do?
Can someone tell me
you need to open up the terminal
and you need to now navigate
where you created your apposite tree?
Okay, so for me it was
just for me it was at this workspace
and then I had to
get Project it right.
So this was the place
where I created the repository, right?
So do I do do I need to use
Git in it again?
Do I use do I have to use get init again?
No, because the repository
is already there.
So if I do get lost,
everything has been shown.
If I do get status,
everything is being shown.
This means that
if I was accidentally to my terminal
I can resume my work from wherever I left
left.
Okay.
So you type in initials
and then press step.
It's going to automatically complete it
for you.
Okay, So tomorrow, what we are going
to do tomorrow, we will be
learning
GitHub.
So I'll share these notes with you.
I have the architecture of get explained
how to track the project
step by step each command
with the functionality.
I have written it. Okay.
What are going to be your errors I'll
I have also mentioned them.
What are the common mistakes that you have
that you will make?
I have mentioned them.
So as I promised to you guys
that you don't need to make notes.
I got that cover
so you don't have to worry about it.
No, no, not tomorrow.
Sorry.
That that was something mistakenly said.
Okay, so before we end our session,
there's something else
that I wanted to
I Yes, A suggestion for all of you.
Tomorrow is going to be a review class.
Most probably your next class with me
is going to be on.
I'll ask and let you know
what really on are on Tuesday.
I won't tell you in advance.
Okay.
So make sure that before our next class,
do your homework.
Go to whatever we learn today.
Anyone who wants to review the class,
my suggestion would be
instead of,
you know, going the class that we
had today, the video that I sent you,
if you followed that,
if you listened to that and tried to do
everything that I explained in there,
it's only
19 to 20 minutes.
You'll get the whole lecture out of it.
Okay?
Okay. Perfect.
So any question that you have regarding
get I'm still here.
You can ask them and then we can, you
know, end the session in about 5 minutes.
Any question, guys,
regarding to today's lecture,
those of you who are good
can you know Loba thank you for your time.
When will I be sharing the notes?
I'll share them with you right away.
I should add in course announcement
and I tag everyone homework.
I'll post it in course announcement
for hard.
You are good for hard.
Let's say.
Should I see no issue?
What's the issue here?
There is no issue.
You are most probably unable
to go to the next, you know next slide.
Try control, see our column.
Q It will take you out of this.
Can you show how you open the first goods
you want project in there?
Phillips Awesome.
Do you want me
to create the project for you?
Thank you, guys, and thank you, Leader
after Good luck.
Can I do after that?
I So what are you referring to?