Just to ask you is you
see, see, to my honor,
you have a migraine.
I think you tried drinking some some coke.
It does. It does a trick. Trust me,
it doesn't drink.
It's you.
Let's see.
All right, guys.
Let's see who is here.
Who is here?
To Mona.
Not yet. We haven't,
actually. It's already reported.
Yeah.
Let's see.
Zemo. Hey, Sam. How's it going?
How are you?
We have Catarina.
A little Christine.
No, I said that right.
Aisha from Fairfax.
I know there's two Asians.
You have Ivan
from.
From Russia.
Alan Lubo, Sorbonne.
You'll get a.
Emily. Joe, get into Zoom.
She said that she was having issues
earlier.
The emails. Joe.
Are you there?
Let's see what's up, Hanoch.
So. And
Olga, then, as
Sebastian.
But, Amina.
Sorry. Sorry.
Is it sir? His surname?
Nikolai from New York's
mayor.
Aisha. The other Asian from.
From Florida is here.
Welcome, Aisha.
Welcome. Welcome. Welcome.
Roman Silverman.
Sharif, Lenny Mariam.
And then another Mariam from
Marilyn, I guess.
Zemo says, Let me get his red ball.
Let's see. Remain.
JAZEERA
Alexei Price, KPRC, how are you?
How's it going?
Alana Alona I sit there, right?
We have two wishes and two Marion's.
Oh, goodness.
Marina says hello from New York.
CC How's it going?
How are you? Angelica.
Welcome.
CATALINA
Believe is it? Alicia?
Liz Abdul is here.
Irina.
Irina decided to show up to class.
Mohanad
Mohammed's.
Gerald Hicks from Woodbridge.
Abdul Kazeem.
MAHA It's funny
cause I'm reading a lot of names,
and I didn't see a lot of names
for the homework submissions, so
there's obviously some folks that
that care a little bit
more than the others.
Right?
Which is, which is fine.
And here, welcome.
Anna.
Maha,
this is Simon.
Sam is a Z.
Okay, cool, cool, cool.
So, guys, how's how's everyone doing?
How is everybody doing?
Today is Tuesday.
How was your long weekend?
That Was everyone off yesterday?
Did you guys have to work?
So let's see.
So much better learning.
I am not positive for COVID.
Oh, that's good. That's good.
Let's go.
Let's see who else is good.
Omran says.
Good.
Let's see.
Alan says, Tired.
Someone who was off.
Mohammed says, Wonderful work, work,
work on man.
Anna says working as always
or work, the morale is careful.
This would be my second
you didn't get vaccinated, the mayor
Oh man, that's kind of scary.
I'm hurting too much. Computer time.
Try blinking.
It helps.
Sometimes we look at the screen
too much and
forget to blink.
You're heading to Virginia next weekend.
Thanks for sharing.
I hope you I hope you enjoy it. Yes.
What is our teachers name?
Gerald says what is our teachers name?
I don't know.
It's a good question.
I didn't see Gerald.
This is Gerald.
Did you message me
with your homework assignment?
I think so.
Likes.
Let's see.
Beautiful weather in New York.
I believe you.
I believe it must be very nice this fall.
Must be very, very, very nice.
All right, ladies and gentlemen,
ladies and gentlemen,
good people to north,
south, west and east.
It is time. It is time
to continue with this class.
Okay.
How's your java going, by the way?
How's that going?
Did you guys install new clips
and everything?
And are you guys getting the hang of it?
Very fun.
Yeah. Job was fun.
Yeah, we'll see about that
a couple of months.
It's good. Good.
Very interesting.
Nice closeness.
Keep up the energy, guys.
Keep up the energy.
Having used job in 17 years.
Okay, That's good.
It's good, good, good.
All right, so let's start off today.
Let's go over real quick
what we learned last class.
Okay? Last week.
Just just throw some some pointers on
what did
what did we learn, what the recover.
Okay.
Manual testing.
Testing.
Right.
What do you mean by goal?
We did talk about SDLC.
What else do we talk about as the LC
and what SDLC?
Okay, we talked about test cases.
Okay, so can someone answer
this question?
Yeah, what is this question
with someone ask
answer this question.
Software developer lifecycle.
That's what SDLC is
the software testing lifecycle.
Very good.
But can someone talk more
about the software testing lifecycle?
Like is it a cycle that is just at random
times of the project?
Like can someone
add color to this question?
It's okay.
So that the testing phase of this deal.
So you're saying that SDLC is a cycle
that's inside the testing phase of SDLC?
That's correct.
Okay, very good.
Very good.
Very good. Very good.
I saw some other comments out there.
Someone said we also talked about
the importance of communication.
Right.
Vacation.
What else did we talk about?
We covered what?
We talked about the testing phase.
Okay, that's fine.
Okay. Never to assume
or to never assume.
Right.
As your documentation.
What what do we say about this?
There you go. Good.
Very good.
Three, four.
Yes, that's right.
That is right. Exactly.
Documents. Right.
Ceremonies is the fancy word for meetings.
Right.
Give me an example of an artifact.
Yes, Very good.
Exactly.
So someone said notes.
What contact?
Sure.
But a backlog burning burn down chart,
Not burning chart and burn down chart.
Right?
That's true.
Yeah.
Requirements very good.
Someone said string
when we're not talking about
Java here, but
the materials you have, you work close.
That's right.
Sprints are not artifacts.
Sprints are iterations, right.
In which we
in which, you know, we have to
and we'll talk more about that.
Okay. We will talk more about that.
But what else do we cover?
We covered something
like very big last time.
What what did we talk about?
Test case development. Okay.
We have test cases up here.
What what do we talk about?
So what is we spent like a long time,
We talked about user stories, okay?
We just we discuss user stories.
Okay, What else, guys?
What else?
We spent a good amount of time
talking about this
in the beginning of class, Right?
What do we say?
Okay,
we talked about acceptance criteria right?
Criteria.
Spreadsheet.
Why we test? Yes, very good.
What else, guys? Come on, what else?
What is going to be
the heart of all of this?
What is going to be good?
We talked about this.
I even give you examples of it, right?
I, I Nope, not smart criteria.
We did learn about three types
of applications.
Right.
Okay. There you go.
Finally, someone said it.
Bugs, right?
Bugs, bugs, bugs.
Right now if if I were to ask you,
what is your question?
What is your answer to this question
right here?
An error defect or fault? Okay,
very good.
Can you give me an example of a bug
log in issue?
The glitchy app?
Okay.
Very good.
Unexpected results.
I like that answer a lot.
That's really good. Mismatch requirement.
Actual work.
Yes, I show very good from Fairfax.
And yes, I show from Florida.
Yeah.
Okay. Very good.
So we talked about the
what is a bug, right.
This is a bug necessarily
something that is broken.
Does it does
it mean that the application has to like,
completely stop or something?
Is that right?
It's not right.
It's not. A bug can be different. Right.
We give an example of the customer
not getting what they want right.
And when we talked about the menu,
how it has three lines, but what happens
if we develop it with four lines?
That's not
that's not what they wanted right.
So very good.
So we kind of got our feet
wet the last class.
Okay, we're going to brush up on this.
We're going to to to talk more about this.
So all this information
is going to be second nature to you guys.
Everything okay?
We just had to kind of
throw you in the water at first.
So we're
going to cover a lot of these topics.
Again, it's going to be very good.
But today we're going to go deeper into
our our our concepts and all that stuff.
Okay. So
okay, So
there are some topics last week,
and I want to start off
with creating test cases because you guys
will create more test cases.
Okay.
And we will talk about different types
of test cases.
So a lot of you
sent me some decent test cases, right?
I could tell that some of you guys
were paying attention in class
and I could tell some
you guys were some of you guys.
I don't know where you guys were,
where you guys were doing,
but it's okay.
And a lot of you guys submitted
your assignments, but a lot of you didn't.
A lot of you did not. Right?
So, you know,
clearly some folks care
more about the class than others.
But that sounds like that's more like a
that's that's more of a personal problem.
I can't really help you in that aspect.
Okay.
But so we're going to talk about
some of these test cases
and I have one pulled up.
Okay.
I've got this test case.
And I'm going to start off with this.
This is an example test case.
And what we're going to do
is we're going to we're going to fix this,
but we are going to to fix this.
Let me explain this.
You guys can see it. Okay.
There you go.
Can you guys see that?
Okay, great.
Good sermon.
I chose this because this was almost
a good test, good test case.
But I also chose this test case because
it's going to be easier to work with.
And and a lot of you made the same
the same errors and stuff.
All right. So
let's let's first
look at the test case side.
Do you guys remember the test case,
the acceptance, the the user story ID?
You guys remember what it was?
Let me see.
From last class, a
user story idea
was what you guys number one
four, five, six, eight.
Okay, That's what it was.
Yeah, that is what it was.
So one four, five, six, eight.
So what is 405883.
Right. So that's thing number one.
We don't know.
We wouldn't
know what this test case belongs to.
Right.
So again the test case ended.
Let's fix it. Okay.
And it was 145683814568.
Test case one right.
And the test description is here.
Says this desk is verifies
that a user's able to log in with valid
Kyrgyz valid credentials from the home
page of the widow Edo edo Netflix dot com.
All right.
Just right there.
Okay.
I saw a lot of test cases where you guys
were trying
to log in with invalid credentials.
Does the acceptance criteria
say anything about invalid credentials?
Like doesn't say anything about
about testing
with within valid credentials.
It doesn't.
So some of you guys were writing steps.
Okay.
It's some of you guys were writing steps
with credentials
and then you guys were writing.
Expect some results
that were not supposed to be here.
Okay.
So let's look at the first
and the first step.
Okay? And guys, pay
very close attention, okay?
Because this is going to help you out
a lot.
This is going to help you out a lot.
And it's going to address
a lot of the questions that you guys had.
Okay.
So step number one
user navigates to the reader.
We don't read that Netflix dot com. Okay.
Does this sound like an action?
It does, right?
It does sound like an action.
Right. All the data was not provided.
So I kind of
told you to use your own credentials
if you didn't have a Netflix account.
I just told you to make something up
and pretended that it worked.
Okay, so user navigates to the reader.
We know that Netflix icon.
That is an action that's going to expect
the data Netflix home page displays.
Right?
And let's let's all do this together.
I want you to open
and let's go to that.
Okay. Bam, we're here.
It's kind of
a natural result says Netflix home
page displays this.
Well done. This is good pass yes or no?
Yes. Scope.
Okay.
Step number two user clicks on the button.
Sign in on the top right corner.
Okay. Right here.
Perfect. Did we understand that?
Is that an action?
Right. That that makes sense. Right.
So we're going to click on it.
Okay. Bam, we're done. Okay.
Okay.
So let's go back, sign and paste
this place.
Beautiful.
Well, look, we're crushing it here, right?
This is good. This is the sign in page.
That is what happens when we click on the
sign in button on the top right corner.
Right.
That's perfect.
The actual results sign in basis place.
Yes. Pass.
User navigate to sign in form.
You can and click on email or phone
number of field in order to add log in.
And so user navigates
to sign in form which is there okay
and clicks on email or phone number
field in order to add log in.
Okay, this is okay,
but what are we adding here?
What are we out of here
in order to add
right email or phone number.
Right.
That's what we're adding. Correct.
Because we don't know what log in is.
Right. Does that make sense?
We don't know what log in is.
Do you guys see one one with this?
We don't know.
Like before it said to add log in. Right.
And my question is, this is what it said.
My question is, what is log in?
You know,
and obviously it's kind of common sense.
You know, it says email or phone number.
But in test cases, guys,
we need to be specific.
Does that make sense?
We need to we need to be specific.
So, okay, I navigated to the sign in form
and I clicked on email or a phone number.
FIELD okay.
And secondly, right.
What we can do to kind of make
this better is we don't need to say that.
We don't need to say that
we're going to click on that field, okay?
We can make it a little
more like high level, right?
We can say
sign user navigate to sign in form and add
let's see and
inters, we can say,
we can say let's reword this and interest
email or phone number.
Okay then
right there. Right.
Look, look at this.
How much more clear is that? Right.
It makes sense, right?
User navigates to sign in form and enters
email or phone
number it an email or phone number
or field. Right.
And actually
that's fine
that that that kind of makes sense.
Does that make sense?
You could say field
You can even say text box, right?
But we don't need to really like
click on it.
Does that make sense, guys?
We don't need to click on it,
but we don't need to do that. But
okay, so you navigate to sign in
for an interest email
or phone number.
Okay, so what now?
The next critique that I have,
you can just
you can follow me, That's fine,
but I want you to pay attention here.
I don't do anything.
I just want unfollowed like
the Netflix dot com open it and stuff,
but I want you to
just focus on this test case.
User navigates to sign in form
and enters email or phone number.
So you know what the problem
with this step is?
That's what is the problem with this step?
You know, what is a problem with this that
No, no, no, no, no,
no, no.
That's fine.
It's too wordy. That's okay.
There are two steps.
Exactly what two steps are there
Here, right?
User navigates to sign in form.
Right.
And look and right.
This right here is one action, Right?
And then and
right here is the second action.
Right?
Does this does this make sense?
Does this everyone see that?
It's two different steps, right?
So user navigates to sign in form.
Okay. Got it.
And at this moment, this is not
this is it.
This is automatically
two steps in one step.
Okay. So
what we can do
and automatically you can see that is that
this little change is going to domino
with to the to the next of the steps.
Okay.
So user navigate to sign in form, right.
Let me copy this.
Okay. Let me copy this step.
Okay.
And I'm going to paste it here. Okay.
You're going to place it
here. Forget Watson's four.
Let's focus on three.
We got to finish this up.
Get so navigate to sign in form now.
Okay, let's delete this. So.
So what happens when the user navigates
to sign in form
that we can say what?
What are these fields called?
Okay, what are we going to say?
Because he he decided to add this.
He decided to add this,
which is good right now.
We're not logging
in. We're just navigating.
Literally,
all we're doing is we're navigating here.
That's it.
We're here. Like, all we're doing is here.
We're navigating here. That's it.
Okay, that makes sense.
Like one. What?
We didn't say we're logging in.
We didn't say anything.
We're navigating to this little form
right here.
That's what his step is saying. Okay.
Does that make sense?
Okay. Okay.
So and this is going to ask your question,
right?
So what happens when we navigate there?
We can say email or phone number, right?
And when we're indicating
the name of a field or a text box
or a button,
now that is not an expected result.
Should be able, should it?
I'm going to talk about that as well.
Okay.
We don't use
the word should in test cases.
Okay.
Because sure, it's kind of giving like
like the idea that it's okay
if it doesn't happen.
Right.
So we're going to say either you do it
or you don't.
But that's how you have to write the test
cases. Again.
So what we can say for this step,
whenever you're specifying
a name of a text box,
a name of a field, the name of a button.
Okay, we can you see how the name of the
the text box is email or phone number?
Okay.
You see, I'm
going to say email or phone number.
Okay.
And password.
Password fields
displaced or you can say are displayed.
Okay, let's keep this fields
display cool.
All right.
Does this make sense? Right.
That is what happens.
That's it, guys. That's.
That's all that happens.
We navigated here. What happens?
Okay.
Email or phone number and password
fields display.
That's it.
Does that make sense?
It seems the same as the previous step.
What is the previous step doing?
The previous step is clicking on the sign
in button on the top right
corner from the previous page.
Right.
And the sign in page displays.
Right. This is that's what happened.
That said that step how this is result
is that they are similar.
They are similar, but they are different.
Right?
Because they are similar.
But they are different.
So what happens is we can copy this.
Expect the result. Okay.
And we can paste it here because that's
what happened to the past. Yes.
Okay. Now
we need to fix the the wording here.
We can say user interface,
email or phone number.
Okay. Right.
User enters email or phone number
in email or phone number it text box.
We can say text box,
we can say field, right.
That's fine. Right?
So what we're doing
is we're going to enter.
I'm just going to enter that email, okay?
I'm just making up this date.
Okay, that's it. I'm
just entering something.
Okay.
And here. Right.
What is the expected results?
So the password is shown as the asterisk
character on the password field.
Right?
So what we can say
to make this a little better, we can say
in terms of data
displays, displays in respective right
perspective text box,
you can say displays and field displays
and text box display whatever you sell.
Does this make sense
if you see different the example
we were given and last class?
Yes. User navigates.
Yes, those are two sections,
but last class was your first introduction
to two test cases, right?
So that's what we did.
But now we're going over this.
And the reason we're going over
this is I didn't really expect you to
get a perfect score on this assignment,
but this is going to work
as an introduction
for what we're going to do today,
tomorrow, and the next class is okay,
Does that make sense?
Cool.
So but the whole idea
that I want you to understand
is one thing with test cases,
we have to be detailed.
We have to be detailed. Okay?
And we need to kind of
make sure there were
some test cases
that some of you guys turned in
where you guys had an action
in the expected results.
You guys had actions
in the expected result.
For example,
in this field, right?
Like user enters email or phone
number and email or phone number, password
instead of saying what happens
when you do this, you were saying
something like user
should be able to do something right.
That is not correct.
But is this making sense so far, guys?
Literally the expected result, right?
Is what happens when you take this action
not what should the user do,
not what should use
should the user do next.
It's literally what happens
when this action is is taken. Go.
So this is what we're going to do, right?
In order for this test to be robust,
we do also manually test with the invalid.
We're not did the acceptance criteria
doesn't say anything.
What does the acceptance criteria
say? Right.
It says that we need to make sure that the
user can log in with valid credentials.
Right. If the client wants to.
If the client wants to, you know,
come up with the requirement that says
something, users should not be able
to log in with invalid credentials.
Then we test that acceptance criteria.
Does that make sense? Right.
It needs to be a requirement first, right?
Because the truth is,
if we don't focus on the acceptance
criteria, we can get so distracted.
We can come up with so many scenarios.
Right?
Right.
That's it.
This is what they want.
This is what they get.
Plain and simple. Right?
That that's it.
Plain and simple.
But you are right.
And in most places, of course,
they're going to have a requirement
that says user shouldn't be able to
to log in with invalid credentials.
Right. So does that make sense?
Does that make sense?
Okay, cool.
And to talk about that,
if that is a requirement, right,
then it'll probably say something like
users should not be able to enter
or should not be able to log in
with invalid credentials.
And then there's rules, right?
Have you ever seen when you register
for a form, there's password rules
like passwords should contain at least one
capitalized letter, one number,
one special character,
Or sometimes they give you
a list of special characters
like it'll say something like
It needs to contain one of the following
special characters, right?
So if there is no question mark
in that lit or those options,
then to negative test that scenario,
you would just out of question
mark to the password and see if it works.
Does that make sense?
You would you would try to see
if you can break the system or something.
Kind of
you would try to see
if if the password requirement
is to have at least one
capitalized letter.
Well, see if you can create a password
with what?
With all lowercase
characters.
Cool.
So they don't ask for user cannot get.
So if they don't ask for user
cannot get in with them,
that means they are missing something.
I don't understand the quote.
Can you clarify the question
a little more, please?
As a tester, do I have any input
or suggestions what I should test
or do I just follow orders
at the best of the work environment?
You know, sometimes when you see something
that's obvious, you can kind of
say like, Hey, I think this would confuse
the user a little bit.
You know, you can make that suggestion.
You can
feel feel free to make that suggestion
worthless.
Okay, cool.
So so we'll
we're going to copy this
because this is what happens, Right?
Right.
And then look, you see, sometimes
the task is become simple, right?
Because now what I'm going to do
is I'm going to copy this step Good.
And what should I reward?
This?
What should I what should I reward? This
user enters
password
and password and password field.
Right, right.
Password field.
That's it. Right.
And then what you can do is
you can just copy this
last expected result
and just base it here.
That's it.
Keep it.
Keep it nice and simple.
You know, you don't need to reach over.
You need to add so many, like say,
like all the password shows up
with all these characters
and stuff like that unless.
Right. Unless that was a requirement.
So for example, what he had here before
he was saying that the expected result
is that the password displays what
the asterisk read that you guys see that
that's what his expect the result was
if we had an acceptance criteria
that said the password should display
an asterisk after entering it,
then we go ahead and write
a expected result like that.
Okay.
But all this acceptance
criteria is doing us is just logging
in with valid credentials.
Does that make sense to everyone?
So keep it simple.
You have to keep it simple.
Okay, so what is next?
What is the next step?
It says user navigate to sign in.
Okay, we got rid of this.
The next step was user
navigates and clicks on sign in.
But you see how there was multiple steps
here, guys, right?
User navigates to sign in form A
and clicks on
hi button
on the right side of the password field.
So I'm going into a password.
Okay. Password. Right.
I don't see as of right now
his test case says
that I need to click on a high button.
I don't see a hide button.
And also, does the acceptance criteria
say anything about a hide button?
It doesn't, right.
So we don't test it because it doesn't say
it doesn't say anything about it.
Right. So what are we going to do?
We're going to delete the step.
Okay.
Because it should not be here.
We're not testing this.
The password is shown as an asterisk.
Character on the password field and right
how one chooses to show one.
Right.
So two things
that we are now responsible
for testing with this acceptance criteria.
Right?
So and that's okay.
I can tell that he was thinking
outside the box, which is good
but we only need to
test Will read the test.
Okay. All right.
So let's see if his next step was going to
user navigate to sign in form and click.
So I see a lot of user navigates to sign
in form, but we are already there, right?
We already there.
So there's no point of having like that
step again, a user navigate to sign in
form and does not. Right? So
what we can do is I'm going to copy this
step,
I'm going to paste it here
and I'm going to say
we can just say, see
what is the name of the button,
Sign it right.
There you go. I like that.
He put it in quotations. Okay.
I like that he put sign in quotations.
Right.
What do we say if you're indicating
a button or a field or something,
we put it in quotations.
When you say
and you're introducing another step.
Dennis does that make sense?
You separate the test.
Two separate two steps.
Separate the steps.
Well, do
we have to mention the colors of buttons?
No, we don't.
Does the acceptance criteria say
anything about the colors of the buttons
that we have to test?
Does it say that the signing button
needs to be green or blue or orange?
It doesn't, right?
So we don't need to indicate
that that user clicks on sign in button.
Now, obviously I enter dummy credentials.
I'm assuming
that the Netflix than the Netflix video
basis plays right?
So that's what I want to put here.
And then I'm going to copy this, paste it.
Let's assume that that happens
or user account.
Is that what is called user accounts?
Okay. So I'm going to say
user account page displays, Okay,
whatever it's called, I'm not going to
you know, I'm not going to get upset
if you got it wrong.
But here what we can do is we can
delete
and we can delete.
We can delete, we can delete
account and
okay.
And this is step seven.
You can see and of course,
read them right there.
That was that guys.
That was your own Mark.
Okay, That was it. Does that make sense?
Okay.
So a lot of you guys were adding
more than what we needed.
You guys were a lot of
you guys were testing other things
that we didn't have the test right.
Does that make sense?
But what I the reason I chose
this was because Sorbonne
and everyone get a run, a robust system,
one he did a very good job at thinking
outside the box He did.
And that is very good
because that is what's going to help us
with what's coming next.
But these are there are just some rules,
right, that we need to follow.
Okay. That that we need to follow.
And this is, first of all, split
the steps, right?
We have to follow the task as other.
Seems. Yeah.
I mean, if you don't follow the test case
or you don't follow and either
you want to follow
the acceptance criteria,
obviously
we can come up with many scenarios, right
When we're logging in, we can like come up
with like 100 if we wanted to like
all possible scenarios that you only want
to test the acceptance criteria.
Okay, that's it.
Right?
How about test data that we need it for?
The test data would have been the username
and password last class.
I want you to use your own credentials
or to just make something up
like I did right here.
Okay. Like right here.
I just made something up.
I just wanted you guys to practice
writing a test case.
Okay, You can.
You should. You can if you want to.
You can just create a new column,
say, test data, spread test data.
You can say password.
Okay?
We can say test data.
We can say password or username.
You know, username, whatever you want.
Password.
I actually had one of you guys
give me your actual real credentials.
I don't understand why you would do that,
but thank you so much.
Yeah. So.
Okay.
Does this make sense, guys?
Does this make sense
or does it make sense?
So let's cover what we just talked about.
Okay, Let's go.
What we just talked about one,
we made it nice and it's still detailed,
but it's also high level, right?
Men, Nice and easy to the point where
I was able to copy
and paste and reword things.
I was efficient with this.
It didn't take me that long, you know,
It took me a while
because I'm showing it to you.
But at work I could have finished this
like in like 5 minutes.
Is it a simple a web application?
I don't understand the question for
how can you So test data
and credentials are needed to sign in?
Yes, right.
What does the acceptance criteria say?
The user's able to log in
with valid credentials.
Right. So we need valid credentials.
Go preconditions.
And we're going to talk more about that
in a bit.
Okay. Preconditions.
What we're going to do,
because I want you guys to use it
wisely in a different and a different test
case.
Okay.
So go ahead and take a screenshot of this
right now.
Okay.
Go ahead and take a screenshot of this
right now.
Okay.
And let's talk about some rules.
Tell me some rules. And you know what?
I was actually interviewing
some candidates
today.
And one of the questions I asked them,
I asked them,
I said, hey, if you were my lead right.
And I gave you this,
I gave you a test case, I asked him,
what would you look up for?
Like what is a good test case for you?
And what is a bad test case to you?
That's an interview question.
You guys know the answers.
I just told you the answers.
If you guys would
have said something like,
you know, just verify that
the steps are clear
that they expect the results are only what
what descriptions of what happens after
an action is taken and no steps.
There are no actions.
And the expected results. That's perfect.
Okay.
That the test case should satisfy
the acceptance criteria.
Right.
Does this make sense to everyone?
That's actually interview question.
Okay,
So very simple, very easy.
But this is all it is, guys, right?
Simple rules.
You don't need to test other things
that you don't have to test.
You don't.
They expect the results?
Don't you will
We will create a lot of tests.
This is not the only one
that we're going to create.
We're going to have a lot of fun
with this stuff.
Okay.
We're going to have a lot of fun.
I promise you that.
I won't allow any of you guys
to feel uncomfortable with this.
You guys are going to be,
like, crushing it, okay?
You guys are going to be crushing it.
That is a promise.
All right?
This was just, you know, first time,
you know, obviously first time and,
you know, obviously, some of you guys care
more than others, which is clear, Right?
We already clarified that,
which is why some of you guys did
some of the assignments.
Okay.
Can really help you there. Right. So
take a screenshot, please save it,
Sorbonne.
Good stuff, man.
Good stuff.
Okay, Can we do Nicholls
Did we do your test case?
I actually it's just
just take the screenshot
and learn from it, you know, and let's.
Let's carry on. All right?
So, okay,
so any questions so far before we move on?
Any questions?
No. All right, great.
So let's carry on.
And I want to say something
a lot of you guys,
a lot of you guys were almost like
very close.
Like a lot of
you guys were almost very close.
And that was very, very, very good.
I could see in your in your test case
that you guys were like, second
doubting yourself. I could tell. Right.
You know,
and that's something that's really good,
you know, for for most of you.
So keep up the good work, okay?
Okay.
So anyway,
we cover that and we will create more.
Okay? We will create more.
All right.
So the next thing we need to talk about
is a test plan.
And a test plan is
now that we know about bugs.
I know I messed up by putting some actions
into the scripts, and that's okay.
That's fine. That's.
This is.
We're here to learn, guys. That
that's that's fine.
The way I see more use of that
in your homework assignment
is that what you're doing?
Is that
what you're doing
or you're sharing a screenshot?
Oh, and by the way,
one more thing. Okay.
And take this however you like.
I don't mean to be disrespectful
any kind, but
are you guys listening?
If there were a lot of you guys.
Okay, so when you guys start working
right, you guys will probably be working
from home or wherever
you're going to go to the office
and they say, Hey, send me your assignment
or send me something like this.
Right.
A lot of you
guys were taking pictures with your phones
and sending me the pictures
that you took with your phones.
Right.
So my question to you is, at work,
are you going to take a picture
of your assignment
or your task and send it to your manager
or you're going to take a screenshot,
right,
using Windows or Mac or whatever
you using and send it that way, Right.
So which one are you going to do?
A lot of you guys were sending me
pictures, you know,
and I was looking at it
and I was like, you know,
and some of you guys are
are probably going to say,
Oh, I don't know how to take a screenshot
with with the windows or a mac.
What do you do
when you don't know how to do something
too minor?
That's right.
Allen You Google it.
You want to see how easy it is.
I'll show you.
Look Watch this.
Ready?
How to take screenshot.
Right with windows.
Look, this right here
and right there.
Look. Look at that. See?
That's nice.
Right? Right.
Guys, answers right there.
The other Mac can just changes
how to take screenshots with Mac.
Bam. Right there.
Right. If you don't want to read,
I am pretty sure that there are
YouTube videos on this.
Okay. If you want to watch a video
that makes sense, are you good?
Right?
So from now on, what are you going to do
whenever you send assignment or something,
or whenever you have issues with your code
and you have to contact
support team,
you're going to send them a screenshot.
Okay, cool.
I'll be all right or go with that.
All right.
So a test plan.
What is a test plan? Okay,
so now we know what's a bug.
We know what test uses are. We know what
we'll have to do. What testers.
We have a good understanding
of acceptance criteria
as we know what user stories are.
User stories are artifacts, right,
that have the acceptance
criteria written inside them. Right?
We already talked about that.
Acceptance or criteria comes from come
from what acceptance
criteria has come from what
acceptance criteria is come from what?
Yes. Farhad Exactly.
Business requirements, Right, Exactly.
And who's the one that kind of writes
the acceptance criteria?
Who's the one that the VA Exactly.
Not the place to be. A
Okay, cool.
So a test plan.
A test plan is just another document.
Okay, What is the word
for document and agile environment?
Right?
It's an artifact.
So it's just another artifact
that has the following information.
Okay. What? The tests.
So, for example,
they'll say the functional testing team
will test anything related to the UI.
Right?
Are our developers will do performance
testing or are this testers will you know
that it is this organized document
that basically says what the test.
How do we tested?
Why do we tested?
Who will perform the testing?
Where will testing be performed
and when does testing take place?
Okay.
So I'm going to address
all of these questions
like who will perform the testing?
You can say the two way team,
where will testing be performed?
I will also show you
that when will testing take place?
I will show you that as well.
Okay, so in the center, but
it's this document that has all of this
information that the test might contain,
has it can have.
And I'll show you what a test
run looks like.
We actually have one here.
It'll be like a test plan overview
list of futures, environmental needs,
and we're going to talk
and learn about environment.
So they all guys, this is so exciting.
We have so much to learn. Okay.
Now, I personally and I'll show you
some of these test questions, Okay?
But we're going to get back to this
after we start creating more test cases,
after we start working with JIRA
and everything like that.
Does that make sense?
So I want is that
is that cool with everyone?
Because right now
that you don't understand
a lot of terminology, which is fine,
but I want you guys to kind of,
you know, hear the word test plan,
kind of test Blanca,
because I know you have the slides test
case development.
We already talked about test case
development.
Okay.
We already talked about test kits.
The moment test cases. Okay.
We already talked that in a test
case is often
the reason we use the word often
is because it changes in every project.
Not every project will have
all these fields, but most projects.
Well, some.
And then I show you an example of to test
It is right.
Here's a test case right?
And then here's another test case.
For example, this test case right here
doesn't have a reviewed by field, right?
This one does. Okay.
This test
case doesn't have a created by field.
Right. This one does.
Maybe that was project
specific. It's okay.
That's fine.
So it is documentation which is time
consuming, not the actual testing.
Yes. For a hard
and there's a lot of documentation
that goes on behind the scenes.
You know, that is part of your job
and stuff.
That's going to take some time.
All right. So
so what we're going to do
now is we're going to practice
some more on on
on creating test cases.
Okay.
But before that,
I want to talk about environments.
What are environments? Okay.
And this is a very, very, very good one
because you guys know what is SDLC.
Okay, you guys know what is a software
development lifecycle.
What is the last cycle of SDLC?
When is the last cycle of SDLC?
That's not the last cycle of SDLC.
It's called
the deployment or maintenance, right?
But I'm pretty sure 150%
you guys don't understand
why it's called that or what it is.
I'm going to show you what it is.
So we use the word like live, right?
Like live application, like deployment.
What does this mean?
What Are we doing
there's different environments now.
What are environments?
All these questions.
So if we go to Amazon.com
today,
Amazon.com, this is the live application.
Okay?
This right here is the live application.
This is what the user sees.
This is what the user can use.
This is where they buy things.
This is what we call production. Okay.
This is what's called prod production,
Amazon.com, what the users use.
And we're going to write this down
and we're going to write this down.
This makes sense,
right? So we're going to talk
about environments and
environments, right?
And I'm going to say productions,
production
production is I found a bug with Amazon.
Oh, really?
That's cool.
Yeah, pretty well.
We'll talk more about that in a bit.
Olivier So good job
production.
Okay, Now I want you to
I want you to understand something because
we're going to be using look right
here, I'm going to get this URL right here
and I'm going to pasted right here, there.
This is Amazon's, this is Amazon's
production world production.
You are got
ETPs, WDW, Dot, Amazon.com.
Cool.
Does this make sense? Now
you probably start to question
or ask yourself,
So where did developers
develop their code?
Where do testers test?
You know,
did they all go to Amazon.com and test?
They're like,
Is that where everything happens?
How does this work now?
So what's called
is there's a concept of environments
that we're going to talk about,
and the environment
is there's a hierarchy, okay?
And what happens is
that in most workplaces is okay,
there's a development environments,
development environment
and it's going to be short for that.
In most places
they call it the environment of
and then comes the next one.
It's called the Q Way.
Sometimes they call it
we're going to stick to cube environments.
Go Q8
And this is we're going to call it QED.
Okay.
And then the next one is called Stage
Stage Camp Stage Environments.
We're going to say stage
we're going to set up
because we're going to talk
about different types of testing today.
Okay.
And then lastly, what happens is
we have the production
environment and it's short for product.
Okay, cool.
So this is how the workflow goes in
most of the projects.
And if you have a good understanding of
this, you will be very, very good to go.
So what does this mean? Okay,
so yup, the build.
Very good.
See, you know your stuff, but sandbox
would be like lower than death.
Right.
But we're going to talk about that later.
The Bill sandbox
would usually be like zero in this list
and we're going to talk about and
then sandbox and then dev and so forth.
So very good job.
So how does this work?
Okay.
And what I'm going to do
is I'm going to show you
a real application that we use
in one of my projects I work.
Does that sound cool?
Does that sound cool or what?
I'm going to show you one.
Let's see.
All right.
So what I'm going to do
is I'm going to go here.
This is an application
that we are working with
with one of my projects right here.
Okay.
This is what
what what it's called
Now, guys, just look at look at the page.
Right.
And I want you to look at everything.
What environment are we in?
Do you think?
Oh, no, not production.
Not development.
Sebastian, why do you say test?
What do you say test?
Some will say Dev,
some people are saying live.
Some say 80.
So we will say stage remain white U8 test.
Okay, look at the URL
whether it's a
the test environment.
Right.
The U.S. has this service
slash test. Right?
This right here is I'm using this
an excellent example
is going to be the Kuwait
Environment code.
This is the URL.
This is not what the real user uses.
This environment is what we use.
And you know what?
To clarify this,
I'll say this can be known as Q A test.
Q A test environment.
You see, this service
does everything right.
So now let me ask you this.
Let's go back here, which is two zero
to test.
Okay, double isn't working,
so I'm going to change it to Dev two.
So what should be working? Go.
And I want you guys to look at this.
Let it load. Okay.
It's the same thing, right?
But what environment are we in?
The dev environment. Right.
So we're going to copy this
and ignore the number two on the URL.
But we know that it has that right.
Okay,
Now let's go to the staging environment.
Okay, Let's go to the staging environment.
So what I'm going to do here
is I'm going to come here
just to stage right, look
ready.
And it's the same thing, Right?
But what environment are in?
We are in stage environments, right?
Stage environment
we are in and we're going to come here.
We're going to come here. Okay.
Now, the production URL
and see, I got canceled
August NCI.
Let me see if this is
if this is going to work.
I don't remember the production
world and see, I don't talk.
That's my right
now, let's
see, we find this year.
No, let's see the rule in the study.
Let's see.
Let's see. I'm looking.
Oh, there you go. Right.
This is the production.
You are out.
Okay, There it is.
And I found that. By what?
By Googling it, Right?
Because that's what's in production.
I cannot Google this.
I literally Googled,
you know, the name of the application
because I know what it is.
Right. And this is the producer.
So let's talk about this for a second.
And notice
I label a number them one, two, four.
So what happens is, okay, developers
pick up their tickets, right,
to pick up the user stories
so they're going to work with. Right.
And what they do
is they start their development, okay,
they start their development
and and they do what they have to do.
Okay?
Whenever they're done developing
whatever they have to do,
they're going to deploy that code.
Okay. I'm
no, it's accessible to to to you.
It's going to be accessible to
you guys at work.
You guys are going to have
your own environments. Okay?
You guys are going to be able
to access these environments.
Sometimes they only let you access them
because you're connected to a VPN
or something like that.
So something like that.
So in this case, developers
will do what they have to do
in the development environments.
Okay.
And and
boom, they're done right?
They develop what they have to develop.
What is
sorry,
can you assure me what they're going to do
is they're going to move that code right?
And they're going to move it to the Q
a environment.
What is an environment?
An environment?
Think of it as a copy. Okay.
Of production.
Does that make sense?
A copy of production.
Okay.
So developers are going to work
in the dev environment.
They get to do whatever they have to do.
They'll develop
whatever they have to develop.
Once that's ready,
they're going to move that code
to the Q White test environment
and the Q way environment
should have the exact same code.
The development environment has. Okay.
So you guys will do this testing here.
Again, you guys will do the testing
and the Q8 environment indicators,
and this is where you guys are going to do
your heavy testing, the logging in with
whatever and valid credentials,
your test automation, everything.
Okay, Once you guys are done,
then that's you
then you're going to give the thumbs up
and then that same code
is going to get deployed
to what we called the stage environment.
And the
stage environment is where we have
where we're
what's where we have what's called
user acceptance testing began
in some workplaces.
You may help to test here,
but the people who test here are
who do you guys know
core who are the know
not to be the client?
Exactly. The customer. Right.
This is their environ ment
and what they are testing.
Okay.
What they are testing is to make sure
that whatever you said passes, passes.
Okay.
So if you're going to do your test,
you want to say, hey, we're good to go,
everything is good.
They're going to do their testing
and they're going to make sure
that everything works right.
At the end of the day, the client is the
one who's paying for the project, right?
And they are the ones that want this
for their users.
Okay. Does that make sense?
They're the ones that are going to be
going to be heavily
impacted if there's a showstopper bug
in production.
Okay, I'm
so they're going to do this
testing to re verify everything.
They are the ones that know exactly
how they want their application to work.
Everything like this.
So this is where their testing
will take place.
Okay.
Now once they they test
and once they pass their testing,
then they're going to say,
all right, thumbs up, we're good to go.
Then they're going to deploy
that same code to production,
which is the live application
that the users use.
Okay. Does that make sense?
So, for example,
in this in this scenario here,
I gave you the production
URL for HTTPS Amazon.com.
This is what the user uses.
I don't know what their staged environment
URL is.
I don't know what their Q8
or test environment URL is.
I don't know what their development
environment URL is.
I don't know. We don't know that.
And even if we did, we probably couldn't
access it for internal security reasons
or something like that.
Does that make sense to everyone right.
Well, for all we know,
it could probably say like Amazon dot
dev Amazon
that you Wacom maybe just examples, right?
That's what you have.
So that's the way that this testing
hierarchy goes.
Okay.
First code gets developed
in development environment, right?
And this is where developers test or code
and we're going to talk about that
then you guys test in the Q
a test environment, right?
And then once you guys give
the thumbs up, it's
not going to go straight to production.
The client is going to test
and the stage environment, that's
where they're going to stay and that's
where they're going to test everything.
They're going to make sure that whatever
you said passes, actually passes.
Okay, Now how
like, how do you think it would look
if they do their testing
and they find some bugs?
How do you think it would look?
Not good, right?
I mean, think about it.
You gave the thumbs up and you said.
We're good to go, right?
You gave the thumbs up.
Your team gives a thumbs
up. We're testing. Right.
And then they find some bugs, right?
So what's going to happen there?
It's going to make you look it's
going to be bad.
It's actually it's actually really bad.
It's a really bad.
Like it's not a good thing at work.
Okay. It's not a good thing.
What happens is that the client starts
to lose trust in the team, okay?
They start to lose
trust in the team. Okay.
And and then that reflects on on negative,
you know, on negative feedback
and negative feedback isn't always,
you know, it's not going to be good.
So that makes sense.
So that that that trust, they're like,
let's say Michaele is the client, right?
And I'm say I'm a the curator.
So I'm saying, Michaele,
everything's good to go
and then Michaele test it
and he's like, Hey, I found some bugs
and he's not going to trust me
much anymore, right?
He's going to be like, like
and we're there to help with the testing.
So that's not going to look so, so great.
Okay, cool.
Does that make sense to everyone?
Cool.
All right.
Awesome. Awesome. Awesome. Very, very,
very good.
Does anyone have questions
on environments?
The testers get fired
because of negative feedback?
It depends.
Okay.
Right now, sometimes they could find a bug
that no one knew about,
and that's completely okay.
Right.
But what if they're testing
and they're testing what you tested
and they say and you said it passes
and then it fails on them.
You know,
it's not
going to it's not going to look good.
There's not it's not going to look good.
At the end of the day,
the main goal is to be able to deliver
a very working product to the
the customers,
the live customers, the people
that are going to be using the website.
Okay.
Why did you write reverse instead?
Because this is the hierarchy that I want
you guys to.
This is exactly how I want you guys
to remember this.
In the workplace,
when they tell you about environments,
everything, they're not going to start
with number one first.
They're always start from the bottom
as number one, and they go up,
okay, that makes sense.
But that's just how it is
because production
is the highest environment
and here what we're talking about
is testing hierarchy.
You guys know what testing
hierarchy is like a pyramid, right?
Whatever is on
top has to be on top. Right?
Go. Yeah, and that's true.
And that's true. Privacy.
Does that make sense to everyone?
So now going back to this slide, right,
Going back to this slide right here.
Now, you understand this diagram right?
Right now
you understand what this diagram is.
It's telling you how everything works,
how the code is more right.
Developers do their development,
then it gets deployed to the test
environment, secure environment,
where you will do your testing.
Then it gets deployed
to the stage environment.
That's where the client test, right?
If everything's got to go, goes
to production and bam.
Okay, cool.
Now you understand what this is, okay?
And here's some more notes for you.
Okay, cool.
All right.
Questions on this.
Oh, and here's a question.
Why don't we test in production? Why?
Why don't we test in production?
No, that's not a
it's already live.
No, Why don't we test in production?
Mohammed brings up a good point.
It could cause errors.
The customers are using it.
We might crush the system. That is good.
Okay, so check this out.
You remember when we talked about how much
money does Amazon make in one hour?
You guys remember that from US class?
Okay, what happens if you go in production
and you start running your test
and then you break something?
Okay, You break something.
Amazon is going to lose a lot of money,
right?
We don't test in production
because it is very risky.
Okay?
It could you could break the system.
You never know
if any other test could break the system
or break the application code.
Does does that make sense? Third one,
is it
the production environment
is there for the users to use?
Now, if the users obviously
if they run into some bugs
or something like that,
obviously those have to be addressed.
But the types of testing
that you guys are going to be doing
that we're going to be doing that
developers are going to be doing.
That's not for production. Okay.
Is that clear to everyone
now, Mohammed?
That's a good question.
They're not in production.
What may happen, Mohammed,
is that they've already done
all the testing
and now they're going
to deploy to production.
So they need that time
and that's why they call it maintenance.
Okay.
Is that what happened?
I mean, the reason they gave
the Facebook thing was some network issue,
and that was, you know,
that that obviously
who knows where may have happened.
And we're going to talk
about different types of testing as well.
Okay.
So but is this clear for everyone
right now and everything got everything
we're going to do from here until the end?
I promise you, it's going to start
making more and more and more sense.
It'll be a clear picture
at the end of test execution.
We started with the testing test
cycle closure.
Okay.
Test cycle closure is basically
in the software testing lifecycle, right?
Whenever code gets deployed
to the test environment
and you run your test and everything
passes,
that's where you can end your tests, okay?
That's what that's what it means.
Cool.
In some workplaces that varies
because you may be responsible
for helping the team
test in the stage environment.
So if you're ever in that situation,
that means that the UAE team really,
really trust your testing.
Okay, So here we're going to learn about
we're in class two and.
Okay, So before we get to Joe,
we're going to touch with you.
We're going to start with JIRA tomorrow.
We talked about test case development.
So very good job right?
Credit test.
Okay, So let's see.
Oh, geez,
I forgot the credentials for this.
Okay, So.
All right, you guys are doing very good.
So now we're going to come up
with the task. Okay?
And this shouldn't take you that that.
Okay, So
give me a second.
I want to see if this works.
Okay, Perfect.
This is an application that we're going
to be working with in class.
This is where you're going to do
all your testing,
all your test automation,
everything like that.
Okay.
What I want you to do
and I don't know the credentials,
so just make them up and pretend
that you know what happens.
So this is a test case.
I want you to create a test case.
Okay? This is a user story
and the acceptance
criteria to this, the A-C.
So this is this.
Okay, The acceptance criteria.
As an admin,
I should be able to log into syntax h.r.
Mess, say
with valid credentials can go.
All right.
This is the environment url
i'm going to share with you.
I don't know the credentials just yet.
Okay, but i want you guys
to create this test case.
I'm going to share it right here. Right.
There you go.
And I really expect this
to be submitted by.
Okay, It's not that hard.
You can use the existing templates
that you have.
You already know how to create test cases.
Okay. And so forth.
Right now, do it right now.
We're on the clock, right?
Pretend you're working.
It's 8:16 p.m. my time.
You should be finished.
I'm going to give you
until 827, 10 minutes.
That's more than enough time to do this.
Okay.
In the meantime,
let me see if I can come up with
let me see if I can get the credentials,
see, and any questions ask me.
Okay, I'm here.
I'm here to help you out.
Don't be shy.
What did I say about the credentials?
When I say anything about the credentials,
I said make make the credentials up
and pretend
and pretend,
you know.
Let's see.
See? They come together.
Just make up the credentials, pretend
you know it, and you know
the last step, the less expect
the result is okay.
Like don't stress it out.
I just want you to wear it. Right.
That's it.
Okay. Just make.
I want you to water. Right.
I'm looking for consistency.
Oh, time out, everyone.
That's a really good point.
I can look time.
I can I get everyone's
attention right here. Okay.
Okay.
So is everyone.
Does everyone have eyes here?
Okay,
One big error that I saw in your test
cases, and this was for a lot of you.
Okay, I want you guys look at the
the expected results
or the actual results.
Look, they expect the results.
We're saying Netflix home page
displays sign in page
display fields display.
Okay. Displays, displays, displays. Right.
We're using present tense.
Right. Do you guys know what that means?
Present tense.
Right.
So, for example,
some of you guys were writing
like this signing page
is displayed right now.
We have inconsistency in this test case.
Do you guys see that
you have a present tense here
and then you have a past tense here.
Okay Don't do this.
If you're going to choose one
or the other, that's fine,
but stick to it and be consistent.
Okay?
Go. Cool.
All right, cool.
But I that was something
I really want to talk to you guys about.
Done.
So go ahead, Melanie.
What did I say about the credentials?
Like, I don't know them.
So you're not going to be able to log
in, right?
I just said
make make the credentials up and pretend.
Pretend that you know what happens
after you
enter valid credentials.
Cool.
Is everyone able to open the URL,
by the way?
It's working for me.
I think if you copy it right,
it's working. Yep.
LNT is not opening.
Can you edit again, Olivier?
Just, you know, we'll get there.
We'll get there.
Alexis, What are you having trouble with?
Well, what's.
What's wrong with the URL
not working?
Did you copyright?
Can you see if you copy right.
Let me say that again.
There it is. Here's the URL again.
You can click on
it, see if
it works.
See if it works.
Let me know if it doesn't, it doesn't.
Okay.
Well, we're excited.
We're going to be writing
lots of test cases
right?
Can you click on the link that I just sent
there?
Eleni is working for Alexis.
Okay.
What do you see?
Can you send us a screenshot
of what what you're seeing?
Please? Yes.
And it's done as a screenshot.
Yeah, sure, guys.
And now guys, look, here's the thing.
Here's the way I run these classes.
We're all a team here, right?
So any issues you have,
you send them right here.
A lot of questions
and we're all going to help you out
to code.
All right,
Alan,
you could just send your assignment here.
Take A screenshot, please.
Not not a you know,
not a picture.
Take a screenshot and we'll see.
We'll see what Alan Let's see
what Alan has here
and let's take a moment
to, to see Alan's test case.
Yes, very good.
Okay, so
this is a very good test case, Alan,
But you know what I would say.
Yeah, that's it.
That's the application.
What's the problem, Melanie?
Yeah, I told you. It's.
I told you
you're not going to be able to log in.
I said that like, three times.
I just said, Pretend that you just come up
with fake credentials
and pretend that it,
you know, that, like, pretend.
Just pretend that you know
what's going to happen. Okay?
I will send you the valid
credentials once I have them.
So does everyone
look at Alan's task
is because this is a nine out of ten.
Okay. Alan, are you there?
I'm going to give you a feedback
right now.
And of course, so, Alan,
this is a very good test case.
But why would you add more to the expect
the result of step number three
when step number two was row,
you said username field properties
with input data, perfect
password field a populous with input data.
That's it.
You don't need to say that it's censored
or that it was inputted by the user.
Yeah. Go.
Let's see what Catalina says.
It's kind of blurry.
This.
I don't know when I want to see.
I can't see.
Can everyone see this?
I cannot really see it.
Can you send it again, Catalina?
I can't.
I really read.
It's kind of blurry for.
For me.
So let's see.
There you go. Much better.
Still a little blurred,
but I'm going to make okay,
so user navigate to this syntax. h.R.
Page displays.
Okay, user clicks in the username box.
What is the point of clicking
the username textbox?
You just skip that step.
There's
no need to say user click to the user name
in the user name textbox. It's
let's see.
Format says yes syntax.
Okay.
So very good.
This is a great example
of what I don't want you to do.
So everyone look at format, screenshot,
format.
I'm just picking on you
because this is a good example.
Okay. What is wrong with formats?
Test case.
Come on guys, just look at it and tell me.
Let's let's all do it. Test case review.
You guys know what to look out for now.
So what is
what is wrong with formats? Test case
What what is wrong with formats?
Test case.
Yes, exactly.
The result does an action right?
What do we say about expect
the results are expected
results action
right
or month you hit
you have as expected result.
The first one is good.
The second one you have user enters
username.
User enters username is
an action is not an expected result.
What you have a step
number is user enters username.
Okay.
What happens when the user enters
the username?
Okay.
Exactly.
Let's see a here.
It should log in panel This place
user enters enter data displays. Yes.
Yes. Very good.
Very good.
Yeah very good.
That the mirror. Right on then.
Very good stuff.
What should you put instead.
So what happens when the user enters
a username and username textbox.
Right.
The username displays in the
in the textbox.
Right.
That's what happens.
Look at the previous
is is that people are sending.
Right. So
Merriam Edge says
user navigates to okay syntax
panel page opens
user enters valid credentials
credentials can be entered
user clicks on log in button
user is logged in.
Interesting.
So Marianne from I think this was Mary.
Mary, Mary there. Can I give you feedback?
Are you ready?
I got you.
Welcome.
So, Miriam, so we need to be a little bit
more descriptive, right?
So user interest, valid credentials where
go and user clicks on log
in one guys,
whenever we are indicating a field
or a name of a button,
it should be in what?
Where should it be in?
What should it be?
Yes, exactly.
Very good quotations.
Let's see.
And everyone, let's just look at this.
Those cases in the bill
Sunset user navigates this. Yes.
User inputs username. Yes
Yes. So
now build from your actual result for step
three.
Right? Is not consistent with you.
Expect
the results from your previous steps.
So you either stick to as expected
for all of them or you continue just
an actual.
Your actual results are also incorrect.
Like for step two.
Okay. And
yeah.
And I was right and I don't see
I don't see a test description,
a test case I'd be
and everything else is very good.
I just don't see.
And are you there. I don't see.
The task is description or.
Yeah,
let's see
your guida.
Let's see.
You'll get a
user should navigate to below.
You are
okay.
You mean it?
You kind of uploaded a screenshot with
like a message of someone
got your guitar.
Not back yet.
I will understand.
Oh, and one more thing, guys.
Look, one thing I wanted to say.
Yes, of course.
Miriam, do you want to show your employer,
Miriam,
that you are worth $100,000 a year?
Or do you want to show them that you're
just like
like a high school student
going to college, right?
So you can easily fix these little errors,
right?
And bam, you're right on right.
Your test case was good.
Okay.
I had a student and I'm not going
to, you know, you know Exactly.
I had a student messaged me and
and was like, hey,
you know, Diego,
English is not my first language.
Okay?
So the wording may not look good,
make sense and stuff like that.
That is completely okay.
Okay, that is completely okay.
So don't be shy about that. Okay?
I'm not going to call you out
if you don't know how to,
you know, write proper English sentence.
Okay?
So just don't be shy.
We're all here to make mistakes and stuff,
you know?
So the whole point of learning.
So let's see.
After your Rita Simon seminar,
are you there?
Simon, are you there?
Simon There
of Simon.
Simon.
So your test case, right, is almost good,
but You're you're using past tense
with some of your what?
Some of your your expected results.
Look into that.
You'll see anything that ends with me
this past tense right.
So reworded
so that it sounds like present tense
unless you want to make everything else
past tense.
Come for hard.
Let's see.
That was
Simon. Sorry.
Sorry.
Lauren, are you there?
Okay. So sorry.
This is what's going to be.
Call it on the tortoise case.
So your step user navigates to syntax.
HRN log and you say Page appears
What page?
Okay, User enters an invalid credentials.
Credentials are accepted by system,
not error shows.
You don't need to say that no error shows
you can say credentials are entered
and field
user clicks on logging button.
Okay, that's good.
But you see what I'm
where I'm coming with this.
You also entered test data.
Everything else looks good.
Sorry. It's just what page appears.
You know, you have to you have to let us
you have to let us know.
Sorry.
Just seal for two JCR are you there?
Just seal or tomb?
So if I said that wrong,
since I take it screen displays
user inputs username enter username field
username input displays.
Okay.
And so just so your expect
the result for step number three.
You're saying
make it so that it's like
the expected result for step number two,
you don't need to say that it's
that in this place censored
in password just say know
password input this place right
and everything else is good.
The test case idea is there
the test case description.
You basically copy
the acceptance criteria, maybe
reworded a little bit so that you describe
what the test is actually is.
But overall, just so not that.
Mohammed from Gainesville
user navigates.
Okay, user types username text,
but username
box contains valid.
Mohammed, are you there from Gainesville?
Mohammed Mohammed,
Let's look at your expected results.
Okay. For step two and three,
you don't want to say username
box contains,
you know,
you can just say a username, insert
displays.
Okay, good test, case I.D.
plus case description,
even that at the date there about
four hard for hard is just like the redo
or something
for Hannah.
You there is four hard there.
Okay.
And by the way guys it's 837. Okay.
It's 837.
Let's come back.
Let's take a quick
break. Let's come back at eight
today because we have a lot to do.
List to 850.
Okay, good. 850.
In the meantime, we looking at
some of the societies that are sent here
that eight
850, everyone should be done
with the assignment
by now.
So 850
Aleksei either.
Alexei Cittaslow
from Ukraine.
Elena let's see what Elena has.
Alana, are you there
for? We need to review
the test case again.
But as a lot of there are.
Does she go on break?
That's fine.
We can discuss after
let's see, what do you have?
What do you have, Jimmy?
Yes. Where we are on break until 850.
We are on break until 850.
Was that mean you have a mac
but not a mac keyboard?
Christine, go ahead on break
and we'll talk after when you come back
from break.
You had to read those already. Come on,
let's look at them.
Let's see.
I have a mac.
Nope, you can skip.
I'm sure you can skip
10 minutes or something when you rewatch
a class
C to Mona.
Let's see tomorrow. Let's see.
What did you do to my non.
So you say display.
You may want to say displays.
And for step number two.
Thelma Tom.
Mona, you say user entries.
User name, user entries.
Username.
You want to say user entries
username in username field, right?
And then you want to say enter username
displays, right?
You got to change these steps For step
number three, user
enters password in password field
and enter password
displace write in password field.
You can say that's fine,
but you got to change
that change listings.
Why can
you send a screenshot?
Jimmy, take a screenshot. What?
What are you using?
Jimmy I can't.
So the way to take a screenshot with
that is see?
Okay jimmy it's going to be the
the windows button.
You have a windows button
so it's going to be windows
shift and three.
Okay.
Or you can do Windows shift four
and then you can select where you want,
what kind of screenshot you want to take.
So Solana,
why are you sending screenshots?
We're not sending pictures anymore.
Are you using a Windows or Mac?
Why can't you do your screenshot?
What what what operating system are using
the monarchy.
The monarchy writing test cases like that.
You're going to have to drink more.
Red Bulls.
Let's see what Let's see what Hannah the
So Hanukkah you
and I've got you there.
I mean not Ana Hanoch Hanukkah
or h e an okay
if he's not, we'll talk after.
So, Lorna,
do you know how to take screenshots
with Windows?
Yes. Aisha, I can check your.
Okay,
so then take this user snippet too,
and take a screenshot like that.
Let's see
for Farhad user Navigates to this.
Okay. Syntax.
Good. User clicks inside.
Why are you clicking inside the feel?
Don't skip small steps like that.
That's not necessary.
You want to delete step.
Step three You don't even have a step to
delete.
Step three
you don't.
You don't need them.
Let's see what all has
user admin
into username and username field.
Yes. So this task is less good
now all are you there?
No. Is that.
Are you saying that? No.
Are you there?
So no, everything is good.
But you need to put the numbers
in a different like cell.
Not in the same cell, if that makes sense.
Okay, let's see.
Yeah, There you go, Jimmy.
That's right.
Let's see.
I'll look at the keys
and then a lot of questions.
What numbers? Sorry, All the numbers.
Look, all the numbers are.
The numbers are in the same cell
as a step.
They need to be in a different cell.
See what a Katarina.
Katarina.
I hope I said that right.
The title of the moment
one does lead.
Why would you click on log in panel?
So, Ekaterina, for step two,
why would you click on log in panel?
You can just say that user username,
you know
the next step, user interest password
has same see
her same.
You want to change the expected
result of step
two and three to say it's good,
but just add an s after the word display
like displays.
All good has good stuff.
Very good.
Very good job Cassie.
That's good to see my you there.
Hope you heard that feedback
is probably not there
in Malaysia and Malaysia.
Can you send yours please.
Let's see. Dominant was it dominant?
We have dominate.
Expect the result for step three.
You don't need to say
that the sensor password displays.
You can say like a user entered username
displays, right?
Insert password place
right.
I see augment. Yes,
that's right.
Ahmed from Istanbul hosted Turkey event.
That is very good stuff
in the league and Malaysia.
Let's see if we got
username.
Okay.
Yes. Yes.
Oh a malaysia one error.
This test case is almost perfect.
One error is that your actual results
are not consistent with each other.
Right?
Remember when I said either
you stick to as expected for all of them
or you copy and paste the expected result
in the actual result box.
Right?
Kokrokoo.
Yep. Yep.
That's Angelica from Chicago.
Are you there?
So Angelica there.
She's probably on break.
Okay, good.
Yes, that's
right.
Right, Right on. Angelica. Good job.
Very good stuff.
Get tell
you've been paying attention. Wow.
Roxanna, good on taking the screenshot.
Okay, Not bad.
Not bad. I'll take it.
I'll take it, Roxana.
Okay.
PGA Overview.
Dominic Sorbonne.
Sorbonne.
You'd better have gone this good.
Yes. There you go.
Very good.
Ekaterina, I really talked to
Karina has seen her Some of your there.
Your test scores is very good.
Are you there, Azeem is to see him back.
That is him.
A scene from Cherry Hill,
New Jersey.
Amar from Chantilly.
Okay, I'll take it. Except you don't.
You didn't spell
displays correctly in the in the.
And the expected results for step two.
You can't.
All right, ladies and gentlemen,
are we back or are we back?
Let's
see, Alexis, I'm
looking at yours.
Okay, Good.
Nice job, Alexis.
Jimmy. Jimmy. Let's see. Jimmy.
Jimmy, Jimmy, Jimmy, Jimmy.
Your tusk is actually pretty good.
This good? Uh,
yeah, that's good, man.
Good job.
Job, Jimmy
stuff.
I know. Jimmy, are you there?
Can you hear me
to. You took mine this year.
This year? Where's is Jimmy there?
Oh, yeah, he's okay.
I was looking at different channels
I show from Fairfax.
Let's see, I saw automatically.
We already talked about this. What is.
Can someone help my show
with the expected results?
Please
help each
other to as well review each others.
Jimmy, help! Help.
I shall have seen about.
Oh, by the way, let me just.
NASIR We're not sending pictures
anymore, right?
We're sending screenshots
to you guys.
Will be I.T.
professionals, right?
Do you know what that means?
That means that you should know
how to take a screenshot, right?
That makes sense.
I pros.
I i tip.
I means
you will know how to use google that
I imagine.
Like imagine
now they're calling you like your friends.
You're like, Whoa, Anna's a professional.
She knows how to take screenshots.
I'm just joking.
No, it's it's
using three different computers.
Okay?
I mean, it's up to you.
I'm pretty sure you could take
a screenshot with all of those.
If you're an I.T.
professional, you should know how to take
screenshots with all those computers.
The Google.
So. Ron All right, so very good, guys.
So first of all, I want to say that
I am incredibly proud of all of you guys.
Your test cases are very
and a lot better than the ones that we did
for the assignment
and the ones that we did very, very good.
And you know what happens from here
on in only gets better.
We only keep getting better
and better and better.
And then once you guys get a job,
you start making money.
And the beautiful thing about money
is that you just start
making more money
and more money and more money.
And to those people that say
money isn't everything, I want you to say
that once you're making $120,000 a year
and they offer you another job
for $150,000 a year, I want you to tell me
that that money doesn't really matter.
Okay? I'm
going.
Does that make sense?
Right. Cool.
Very good. All right. So very good job.
Give yourselves a running applause.
Give yourselves a run.
APPLAUSE You guys are doing very good.
I know. Is like Jimmy.
Before last week,
he was like, Oh, man, I got my homework.
He just did a very good test case, right?
It just didn't take him that long,
you know?
Let's see.
You guys are doing very, very good.
Oh, by the way, I have the valid
credentials, so just message me.
But thanks so much.
So I will
I will give you guys the credentials later
because I don't want you guys
to get confused.
All right. So are we good?
Are we good?
Are we good or are we good?
Okay,
cool.
Are you ready for the next challenge
or are you ready?
Right.
All right, let's do it. Very good.
You guys are.
You guys are crushing it so far.
Sebastian, I read your comment. This.
That's funny.
Gerald Hicks.
That's fine.
What?
Okay, I see. I see Gerald Hicks.
Not that camp.
Are you ready?
So guess what?
Compared to the class from last.
Last class to this class, we know how
to one, We know how to use Google.
We know how to take screenshots.
Guys.
That's a big thing.
But you guys are I.T. professionals.
You guys know how to take screenshots and
so, so smart.
Smartest batch we've ever had
here is the smartest badge we ever had.
Okay, you guys know how to write good test
cases, and now it's going to get even.
It's going to get intense.
All right, All right, we're ready.
You guys are proving that this is too easy
for you guys, so let's take it
a couple levels more code.
All right?
So what we did right is we created
these manual classic test cases.
Okay?
Now, if you ask me, okay,
my toddler knows how to take.
That's funny, Alan. That's true.
I wish Joel was that easy.
We'll talk about Java later, okay.
Java is actually easy, right? It's.
You have to put time and effort,
and that's all it is.
Just time and effort. All right?
And you'll be okay.
It's like you don't naturally.
You like when like, let's say
tomato or,
you know, whoever know all this stuff.
Whenever someone comes to you
and they speak a completely different
language.
Right? We we always back up, right?
Because we don't know
how to speak their language.
And when someone asks us
like, learn to speak this language,
we automatically like say no, right?
We sometimes we back up and say,
Oh, no, it's okay.
It's too hard. Right?
But what happens if you practice it and?
You practice and you practice it.
Eventually you learn it, you know?
And that's the same thing with Java.
You know, it's
you're going to you're going to learn it.
You're going to
you're going to be using it a lot.
Okay. And so forth.
Okay.
Now, if I were you, some advice
I would give you is I wouldn't get upset
if you don't know
how to do the assignments.
Okay. I wouldn't get upset.
You don't know how to at all the numbers
in the world and divide them by all
the numbers in the world,
that kind of stuff.
Okay.
I want you guys when you guys are
when you guys are doing your Java,
I want you to understand the concepts,
okay?
Understand the concepts.
And you will be very good. Okay?
The concepts are so like,
very simple once you start learning it.
Okay,
cool.
All right.
So what we did
was we created a classic manual task.
It's right
like the one I have in the screen.
You guys ordered that.
Now you guys create it too. Okay?
And you guys get the gist of it, right?
And we'll practice more and stuff
and everything.
But if you ask me, these test cases
are so annoying to create, right?
I mean, it's honestly, it's
this just the honest truth, right?
It's annoying, right? It's
you know, like,
you know, you've got to go step by step.
Okay. I get it.
You know, first things first.
A lot shows from your work, right?
One, when someone management reads
this right,
they're going to look at a few things.
Okay.
This person is actually organized.
One, two.
Okay.
This person is actually detail oriented.
Testers are detail oriented. Right?
That's nice thing. How do we tell?
Oh, look, he puts the fields
and the buttons names in quotations,
you know, like that.
It looks nice and organized.
You know,
this thing makes sense,
he review to make sure that that
that the
that the words make sense of the words.
Some of you guys were sending screenshots
like this right
look at the expected result
for this stuff.
Some of you guys were sending
screenshots this
like this like displays or something
like that.
Like, like this, this stuff. Right.
When someone sees this, right,
they're going to think like, okay,
this person's lazy, right?
They can't even
they don't even take the time
to spell out this place correctly.
Right.
That's the first impression
that comes to mind.
Right.
And this can be fixed by you just
reviewing your work before you turn it in.
Right.
So there you go, man, that said.
Right, it shows a lot, right?
It shows a lot when when you're doing this
this kind of this kind of work,
they can clearly tell
what kind of worker you are.
Right.
It's not there's a reason why we focus
so much
on creating test cases that make sense.
The reason for
this is
because when you write these test cases,
they are for your team
and not just for you.
Okay. I want to repeat that.
They're going to be for your team
and not just for you.
So that means
tomorrow, if Mikel is working at team
with Tamanna and Paul and Mariam
and Fatma,
let's say they're all working on the team
and Fatma wrote this test case tomorrow.
If Mariam is going to use it,
she should understand
that it should make sense to her as well.
Okay.
If I wrote this test case, it needs
to make sense to the rest of the team.
Does that make sense, guys?
So these test cases
are not going to be for you, right?
There's a reason why
we put names like created by
so that if it's a bad test case
so we know who to go after right.
Does that
does that make sense to everyone?
Right.
Let's say Lubo is in
the team was born, right?
If tomorrow Lubo needs to use this test
case.
This test case
needs to make sense to Lubo.
Okay, is that clear?
And it works
the same thing with your team, right?
Everyone needs to to understand it
or be clear with this.
This is why we're focusing
so much on on, on
creating stamps.com
who will look.
All right.
Now, this is what we call
a classic manual test case.
All right?
This is what we call
a classic manual test case.
Congratulations You know how to read it.
We wrote it in Excel or Google
Sheets or something like that.
Okay.
However, there is another type
of test case we are going to be writing
and that you're going to be using
for the majority of this class.
Okay.
So if this wasn't like if this wasn't
like your like if you weren't
so good at this, then let's hope
that you could be good at the next one.
Okay,
So let's let's look at let's look at this.
Okay.
This is a test case.
It has everything, right? It's this is
this test verifies that a user's able
to log in with other credentials
from the home page of Netflix dot com.
Okay, cool.
We have stubs,
we have the expected results,
and then here we have actual results.
Oh, and by the way,
this test case, let's say the first step
passes, the second step passes,
the third step passes.
But the fourth step and the fifth
but the fourth step fails
at the fifth step passes
and then the sixth that passes.
Does that
is that considered a failed test?
Is yes,
Every single step needs to pass, right?
Every single step needs to pass to the
to pass.
A single step will fail
the whole test case.
Okay.
You report it to your team first. Okay.
All right.
Now there is a different type of
there's a different type
of test test cases
that we're going to write
and we're going to use the same example
here.
Okay.
So these test cases
and I'm going to give you a pop quiz
right now.
Okay.
Can you name me
the four environments in order, please?
Read the four environments
in order like one, two, four.
One, two, four.
One, two, four,
not four, two, one, one, two, four.
Scripts Copy.
Muhammad is like, on point.
You know what?
I'm not going to be upset because
that means he's writing notes down,
right? So works.
Yes Exactly. Very good.
Beautiful, beautiful,
beautiful, beautiful stuff.
If I could, I would hire
all of you in my current project.
Every single one of you.
Okay, so the next type of test case,
right, is what we call.
Are you ready? Are you ready?
Cucumber scenarios kind.
All right.
What are cucumber scenarios?
Game.
Cucumber
scenarios are a type of test case.
Think of it of cucumber test case.
The word scenario is a test case.
And what this follows
is what we call a behavior,
behavior driven,
driven development
approach.
And I'll explain what this is, the way
you guys will understand all of this.
And it's going to be called BDD.
Okay, BDD approach.
What does this mean?
This means that we're going to write
test cases
based on how the user
uses the application. Okay.
We're going to describe the behavior
that the user will take on an application.
Okay.
We're going to describe the behavior
that a user
will take on an application of.
So with this being said, right is one
cucumber.
We read our steps, we write our test
cases, certain keywords, okay,
the keywords are given, okay one,
and then we can given meaning
this will be like a precondition
or the first step that needs to happen.
Okay, so first step,
first step. And it's going to make sense.
One is the action, okay,
the action
and then is the expected results.
Okay,
I'm going to write this scenario for you.
Okay. I'm going to say, given
user, given
a public obviously given a
user is on the Netflix.
Right.
Netflix home page. Okay.
When the user logs in.
Okay.
Then the user should see
what we can change.
Then the user is directed
or you can say then the home page.
What's a page called the home page.
Then the Netflix,
then the Netflix account page displays?
Or is that what it is this displays?
Let's just keep it like this. Okay.
Okay.
So given a user is on the Netflix home
page, right.
This is
this is
this is the precondition right.
This is the action when the user logs in.
Okay. When this is the action.
Right
then the Netflix account page displays.
Okay.
This is the expected result.
Yes. Well, guys, guess what, right.
All this task is now we wrote everything.
This is it.
This is all we had to read.
That's it.
Plain and simple.
Right?
Does this make sense?
And don't worry, you're going to be using
this for the rest of the class, okay?
Because you guys are going
to be automating cucumber scenarios.
Okay, Now, these are the rules.
Okay?
But the cool thing about cucumber
is that once you know the rules,
then the rules can be broken.
You can break the rules. Okay.
So given is what a precondition
one is, the action
then is the expected result.
Now, this is a syntax, right?
A syntax that's called gherkin gherkin.
Okay.
This is
basically a syntax.
You guys know what syntax means.
What does it mean?
Oh, look at what I'm doing.
Look, Look what I'm doing, guys.
Googling, right?
Wow, Look at that. Right?
See that
kind of the word syntax in it?
We can refer to it as formula.
We can refer to it
as like a way that we write the problem
or, you know, the vocabulary in a way.
Okay, I'm
so in this case we say a syntax
that is basically that I'm saying
that that is plain English text.
Okay, okay.
The words given is English.
When is English then is English.
But this language is called gherkin.
Okay, so and what language do you write?
Your cucumber scenarios
in Gherkin.
Exactly. That's the name of that.
That's just what it is.
Okay, cool.
So what we're going to do with this is
we're actually going to
create more test cases
using version, Right.
Which is, you know,
plain English text.
But the cool thing about this
is that we can add other
English keywords like an and but Right.
So let's get this test case right here.
Okay?
And let's mess around with it
just so I can show you an example given
a user is on the Netflix home page.
Okay. And
navigates
navigate to the sign in panel.
Right. Sign in.
Oh I'm sorry. And clicks on the sign
in blue.
Right.
And clicks right and clicks on sign in.
Okay.
And we're going to specify one
on Simon
when the user logs in,
then the Netflix account page displays
and and
user accounts are
are displayed.
Right. Are things different? It depends.
I'm just making stuff up at this point.
I want you guys to understand. Right.
And so forth but does this make sense
now the whole point the whole point
of writing cucumber scenarios,
like writing cucumber scenarios,
is to make it make sense
for everyone on the team.
Okay, does that make sense?
So using these keywords like given
when then and but use them as you desire
as long as the test case makes sense,
as long as the cucumber
scenario makes sense,
then we're good to go.
Okay.
Does that make sense to everyone?
Yeah.
So we read a test case for documentation,
but the Cucumber Center is there
to summarize things for the team.
No, this is your test case.
So if you're writing your cucumber
scenarios, you won't be writing
the classic manual test cases like this.
Instead,
you will be writing cucumber scenarios.
This. Does that make sense?
So you would copy this, right?
You would copy this
and you would give it a scenario name.
So it'll be like this scenario.
What is this scenario?
We're going to say user log in
with valid credentials.
Good.
User login with valid credentials. Bam.
You know the scenario name right here.
That's all you have to do, right?
We use that on every step.
Expect the result are the last of only
a sorry, that's a good question.
It's usually towards the last steps,
but you can make it make sense.
Whatever you want.
Just make it make sense.
Does that make sense?
Yeah. I didn't use but.
But I could if I wanted to.
You can use it.
Okay.
The rules are
is that with these key words?
Right, guys,
the first letter is capitalized.
Okay, that is rule number one. Cool.
The first letter is capitalized.
So if I have this and step right here
and it's like this.
Is this incorrect?
Yes, it's incorrect.
Has to be capitalized right now.
You will have so much experience
with this that you'll start to like
really, really get get to you.
But that's it.
That's all you have to create, right?
And you don't have to go
through the hassle
of writing all of these step numbers.
This devs expect the result.
The actual result to pass.
Yes. No, no, no.
That's it right here. Done right.
And go onto the next right
now. How do you know
if this test scenario would fail?
So let's say given this given the given
a users on the Netflix home page.
Okay bump and clicks on sign in right
when you click on the users
clicking on sign in.
Okay sign in.
But doesn't work,
then the whole scenario fails, right?
And that's it.
But that's the whole scenario.
First, suppose this fell in the
in the first place.
Yes, of course we will give more examples.
Does that make sense?
That's not so.
That's how they they they do this right.
So now let's come up with more.
Give me an acceptance criteria, guys.
Give me an acceptance criteria.
Now that you guys know what acceptance
criteria are, give me the acceptance
criteria, any of them, and I will write
a cucumber scenario for them.
Okay, Go ahead.
Give me an acceptance. Go.
Go ahead.
You guys already know
how acceptance factors look like.
Go ahead
and give me an acceptance
criteria.
Oh, and
one more thing.
What you guys are doing that's got
in what point of view
that I write these scenarios
and what point of view
that I write these scenarios?
What point of view? First person. Second.
Yes. Third person.
That's right, Anthony.
Third Person. Point of view. Right.
Because what is BDD?
BDD is this right?
If we go back to what we said,
the behavior that a user
will take on an application, right?
When we're writing scenarios,
we are basically in
and I'll write this down and I'm going to
give you more definitions on this, okay?
Are you guys going to come up
with the acceptance criteria?
Would you like to come up
Okay.
As a bank account holder,
I want to be able to finish it
as 18.
I should be able to click on auto payment
for a flat list.
Let's do it.
Let's take it.
You'll get. I'm gonna take it. All right.
Take it.
Use it.
Should be able to block anyone
I want and WhatsApp.
It's nice to know,
Mustafa
what problems you run into sometimes.
So this is the acceptance criteria.
But before that, let's talk about about
BDD is behavior.
What is it
behavior? What
driven development of
good.
And we use it
we use BDD to describe business rules.
Guys, what are business rules?
Business or the same thing
as business requirements?
Okay, That's all it is. Right?
And when we write our scenarios,
when when we write
our cucumber scenarios
and we write them in third person
point of view
and third person point of view,
I'm going to say this is recommended.
Okay, Recommended.
We write them
in third person point of view
and we focus
on describing
the behavior,
right?
That behavior
that a user will take on
an application or the application
of the application or application.
Right.
So when we say describe business rules,
for example, this right here, this
except as a AT&T user, I should be able
to click auto payment for my plan.
Okay. Now check this out.
And this is the really cool thing
about behavior driven development, right?
So maybe to a click on auto payment,
right.
For a plan,
maybe I had to go to the website,
log in, go to my account,
go to payment plans
or something like that,
then click on auto payment for my plan.
Right.
It sounds like there's a lot of steps
that I have to take to get there.
So imagine writing a test case
with all these steps, right?
With Cucumber, The cool thing is that it
says, for example,
give As an AT&T user, I should be able
to click auto payment for my plant.
Okay, So what I'll do is I'll say,
let's say give me the of the page
where this auto payment for
my plan is like, you'll get it.
You gave me this, right?
So what is the name of the page
And I'm going to say in the payment
payment options page because I call
payment options.
Okay pages Now cool.
Let's just stick to that. Right.
Okay, cool.
So check this. Right.
Given
and AT&T
TNT user is on the
payment
options page
when the user
clicks on
what is there
a name of a button or something?
You see, I'm asking questions
on this acceptance criteria.
So I would be going to the bar
and asking for a clarification.
Right? But just for
several
purposes, we're going to finish this.
So and clicks on
automatic auto payment bar, right?
So we're going to say auto
payment button, right.
And auto pay,
then auto pay, let's say then auto pay
should be successfully.
And the cool thing about this is you can
use should you can use should
for to cover scenario scan then auto page
should be successfully
enabled.
Okay, ma'am.
There you go. Three simple steps.
That's all you had to write. Go.
Does that make sense to everyone?
Why is it called Cucumber?
I don't know.
I have no idea that I wish. I could.
I could.
I bet I don't have the answer to that.
Why is Apple called Apple?
You will see that.
But does this make sense?
Does this make sense?
Okay.
Very simple. Right?
Very nice. And
and this is what you're going to be
working with for the rest of the class.
Okay, cool.
Now I'm going to show you
my test automation framework
to show you
how long these scenarios can be.
Can so ignore what you're seeing here.
Okay.
I'm going to go to what
one of the files where we write these and
look at this.
You see that
this is a test case.
Okay. Right.
This is the scenario right here.
This is the test case. Okay.
And look
how many steps we have here, right?
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
It's a lot of steps.
It's a very big test case, guys.
It's a robust automated test case.
And notice for this test case,
guys, we skipped
when we skipped the one statement
we just said given and and and and
and and and and and and and so forth.
Right.
And then what is the expected result?
Then the eligibility questionnaire
is successfully submitted.
Can we skip that. Yes.
They're all Gerken. Right.
One of the rules the rules is that it's
the first letter is capitalized.
Right. Okay.
And like I said, now you know how to use
given now you know how to use
when you know when to use,
then the truth is that once
you know how to use these terms,
you can break the rules where you see fit.
You just have to make it sense.
Okay, Does that make sense? So everyone
you can say something like
given the user is on this page,
but is using Firefox browser,
you know, or something that it's you just,
you know,
that's fine.
Just just make it make sense.
The whole point is that you can use it.
Okay?
It's not really used that often,
but if you want to use it, go for it.
Okay, cool.
Does that, does that make sense?
That's and to show you an example
of what an automated test looks like,
it looks like this.
Okay There is this application
that I showed you,
the one that I was demoing to you.
Okay.
And the form is very,
very, very long to show.
It's huge. It's humongous.
Okay.
And let's see if it let's see if it works.
I don't know if it's going to work,
but we'll see.
Let's give it a shot. What do you say?
Give it a shot.
Don't worry. Don't, don't, don't.
Don't be focused on what I'm doing.
I just want you to see what automation is.
Okay?
So let's see.
There you go. And
that's the can you see?
You can automate things to work
however you see fit to watch.
Watch this. Right.
I'm going to run this test.
Okay.
And it's going to open right?
It's going to open.
What's happening? It's opening Chrome.
I'm not doing anything right.
It's going to a URL.
I'm not doing anything.
It's logging in.
I'm not doing anything right.
I'm not doing absolutely anything.
But it's it's doing what it has to do.
Okay?
It's loading. It's doing stuff.
It's me not anything.
Right? Anything,
anything, anything. Right.
And to show you even more right.
Is this okay?
I know that what's happened so fast,
but you see how fast I was.
You see how fast I was?
That was, like, right blazing fast right.
Now, watch this.
If I run, this whole desk is right.
It's going to be like this.
I'm going to run this test.
Watch this. Right.
So it's going to it's going to open up
and let's see if it works.
Okay. So it's going to go.
And this is the website that I showed you
in test environment, not prod.
Right.
Because we don't doesn't
provide some logging in.
Right.
Passing this information.
And it's not working right now
because we've got to do some other stuff.
But the whole point is that
now you see how everything is is working.
Okay.
Does that make sense, guys?
Okay. Yeah.
Someone said, Where's the code?
Yikes.
I Don't want to show you
the code. You're going to get scared.
But the code is all of this
to do all of that?
It's all this code that we wrote.
Everything Java, right? Everything.
Everything, everything.
Java, everything, everything. Java.
And you guys will know how to write
and learn how to write beautiful programs
like this. Okay, cool.
All right.
So point is, that is cucumber.
Now we are going to
write our own cucumber scenarios.
Okay, So the cool thing is
we actually have a task.
Another task. Okay.
And you guys are going to write
a cucumber scenario
for this,
except The criteria right here can
the same
one, the same task is that you wrote,
but this is that
this is what you're going to
to do.
So second, this is the acceptance
criteria.
Acceptance criteria.
I've seen them and I should be able to log
in to a syntax.
HMS Oh, give me a second
I think I know why that didn't work.
That's when I see something.
Oh, now it's going to work.
So not automated testing.
I was running, so check it out. Right.
So if I do this
and if I run this, this is essentially
the power of automation, right?
A form that would take us like
about 30 minutes to fill.
That's 30 minutes, Right.
30, 30, 30 minutes.
So what happens
is it can look at the screen.
Right?
And again,
the whole point of this is to show you
like the importance of cucumbers and those
that's all you're going to be doing.
Okay.
You see what's this long form test.
So this is a very long form.
It's completing very, very fast.
We're filling out right, selecting
like data bars, everything, entering data,
verifying information, selecting
checkboxes, dropdowns, everything.
Right.
All of this you see how fast is going.
You see like it's entering
this information, this data.
Right?
This is exactly.
Look at that. Right?
Bam, That's it.
And then done.
That's it.
Okay.
So that is automation, right?
And every single time
we would run that test case,
it would take us about 20 to 25 minutes.
And how long did that take?
It says right here, 48 seconds,
48.80 2 seconds.
Okay.
Okay. So
that is what you'll be doing.
But again, cucumber scenarios.
Now, this is the acceptance criterion
that I want you to read.
I want you to write.
Oh, and by the way,
the credentials are here.
Okay?
The credentials are here.
Okay. Hold on.
This is the username.
Actually, a lot on
this is the username
and this is the password.
So let's see.
So cucumber scenarios
ran along or before writing code
before you write your code
because they can work with
they can work as your manual test cases
and whenever it's ready to be automated,
all you do is basically
plug it in your framework and that's it.
And that all you will learn
about Don't worry
about how long it takes
to read your stuff.
It could take a while
sometimes, depending. So
the task for you guys is this
okay?
The task is to write a cucumber scenario.
Okay. That's right.
A cucumber
scenario or the acceptance criteria
for the acceptance criteria of
criteria pool.
Okay. Yes.
We're going to do it right now. Okay.
So ready?
It should take you. I'm going
to give you like 10 minutes.
This is very simple one.
So 940, we should be done.
So go ahead and get started
on. Go ahead and get started.
And you guys. No,
no, no, no.
Just in words. Anywhere is fine.
Like you could just notepad at the end.
Just going to need to see a screenshot.
Okay, You can write it in Microsoft Word.
You can write this on Notepad.
Does anyone have questions
or steps?
No, they're not.
They're not.
Can you please open the sample?
What sample?
The one that I wrote. It's right here.
It's above here.
You said
this is the example.
Keep in mind.
And I want to see and there's basically
I just want to see how you write them.
You can write them how you want to you can
use given when, then you can throw some.
And in there, that's fine.
I want to see I want to see how creative
you can be with this.
This is an example.
What what other scenario are you
are you writing?
What do you what are you referring to?
I sure
there's a lot there's a lot of stuff
that I wrote here.
Take a screenshot, please,
so I can scroll down.
Okay, let's see.
Let's see how many of you guys are
and it's fine now
and you're going to have the same thing.
Well, let's see.
The mirror says given a user is on. Okay.
And username and interest password.
Beautiful.
Well done.
Marion from Maryland says
given the admin is on the. Yes.
Oh hold on.
When the user enters
the valid username and password,
then in that statement
you don't need to say
the next two statements where you say
an interest admin for username and enter.
Is that for password?
You can delete step number two
and keep the other two steps if you want.
Marianne Yeah, it's redundant.
Beautiful man.
Man, you are like on fire today,
you know that.
This is amazing stuff.
I think really going to market thing.
You ready?
So Allen says
given a user's at the website
and the user and then so just name Yes
change that last
the second to last that
Allen changed it to when the user clicks
the log in but
then the dashboard page
should be displayed
Allen says given
welcome Daniels given very good
that's a user of the first step
doesn't make sense Alina I mean given
valid credentials user is on the
you can use a given user's on this
and that's when the user logs in
with my credentials. Yeah
Emilia says
given a user's in the syntax when the
when the user logs in
with provided username and password
wonderful
lazy user
like given your and clicks username.
Okay.
So right,
let's have a discussion right now
because I've been seeing this
and this is the first batch
I see this happening but you got someone
you guys are saying
and clicks on the textbox feel.
Why are you clicking there?
You don't you don't need to say that.
You don't need to see that.
So if you if you have anywhere
in your scenario that you click
using the where you click on password,
then delete that
because you don't need to click on it.
You either says given user
have syntax and goes to log logging page
when user clicks. Okay.
User Yes. Clear.
You know, not that at all.
Doing admin logged into CentOS
when the user is
when the admin.
Oh, so Ahmed from Istanbul.
So here's the thing with this
this is almost very good.
But you're saying when that admin enters
valid credentials on the login page
but you're not saying that
they're logging in,
you know,
does that make sense?
You kind of need to specify that somewhere
remain.
Amani from one version is given user
navigates log in page
when the user selects forgot
password option.
So why are you forgetting password
remain?
Are you there?
Does the acceptance criteria remain?
Say anything about forgot password
or anything like that?
Abdul says As an admin,
I should be able to log into syntax h.r.
Mess with valid credentials as
so Abdul Shinwari from Gainesville.
Your first step given thus
the acceptance criteria does
not what you're stuff should be
format
format.
Your first step doesn't make sense,
but the rest everything is good
in the build
says given and the admin into its user
and the admin just passwords us
so on the build
right after your third step when you say
and the admin enters the password,
then you're saying
then the admin should be logged in.
I'm pretty sure
they have to click on log in.
But right.
So you have to, you have to specify that
just SEAL
says given a user and enters
the username. Yes.
Very good.
Just seal.
Are you there just support two for two.
You. Very good stuff
given user is on the syntax h.r.
As well.
Conventions and enters the username admin
given users with valid credentials.
The user. Very good.
Not bad.
Arwa arwa out for the of monthly
from the inside of
not says
hand up there.
Your scenario doesn't really make sense.
Same when the admin logs in
with valid credentials
and asks the username and password.
That doesn't really make sense.
Joseph from Maryland says
giving users when the enters in the user
interest password.
Yes, very good.
Very good.
Ramon.
Given a user
when the user puts the data insecure
respectfully.
Okay Ramon.
That information, that data
that you have there for username
and password, that's more information
that should go with your second step.
Okay.
Rather than your first one.
Lubo says given the user's senses
and then it just password.
Password.
The user clicks on. Yes. Very good.
Good job.
Lubo Denis from Brooklyn
says Given.
Okay,
interesting.
Simon.
Good,
Good. Yes.
Mohammed from games.
Mohamed al-Fadhli Very good. Much better.
You make it easier for yourself that way.
You need to be saying
like and clicks on this God and stop.
Sorry, He says, Sorry, you shouldn't have.
You're giving us your acceptance criteria.
Zemo from talks in Arizona says
Given the admin, when the user answers
and answers and then when the user enters
the valid credentials, okay? Zuma
from and are you there?
So Zuma, if you are there,
look at your scenario.
You're saying when the user enters
the valid credentials,
but then you're repeating it again
and the next two steps.
So decide what you want to keep.
Nikolai did
given user lender
when user enters
no credentials and presses enter
okay so that's that's okay I'll take it.
But we're clicking right Nikolai We're not
we're not clicking we're not pressing.
Enter on the keyboard.
Very good. Mustafa from Gainesville.
Very good to see tomorrow
you can say to Mona
for your second step
when user enters username and password
and clicks on login button,
then users should be logged.
Right?
Make it make sense
that nyah nyah says Now are you there now?
I says given
and then then the user enters.
So you want to change your
then statements, right?
You want to say given an should
given an admin
is on the syntax h.r.
As page.
When the user enters
this and the user and enters
this password for this,
then the user right on logging button. So
go given the given
a syntax h.r.
This admin is on the syntax
h on the
login page
and enters
the username and username textbox.
You textbox
and enter password
and password textbox.
Right.
TextBox and clicks.
Clicks on the log in.
Right.
Log in and
home page
then syntax hms syntax page on this page,
this place.
That's me writing this scenario,
which is a little too detailed.
Right?
Because you can literally rewrite
this in there to look like this.
Look, given a syntax determines
admin is on
the syntax from is log in page right.
And the user name
I'm going to say example one.
Example one.
Okay.
I'm going to say this. Okay.
An example to go to would be here.
So I'm going to reuse this step.
I'm going to say given a syntax h.r.
As admin is on the syntax
h1 result information on a copy
this i'm going to pasted here.
Okay.
And the username look, check this out.
Right.
You guys watching.
So check this out
and insert username and username textbox
and enter password
password textbox and clicks on log.
Right.
I'm just going to store this all into a
when a
when the admin logs in right.
That's all I have to do, right.
When the admin logs in
and I'll just copy this last step.
Look, you see this.
So basically this right here,
this example right here is me
being a little bit more detailed.
And this scenario down here
is the exact same thing
as this up here, but just shorter.
And it also makes sense.
Does that make sense, guys?
Does that make sense,
for example, to I'm going to say
much better, but
would it be correct to use
and instead of one at the pass?
It depends.
It really depends.
It just has to make sense.
Let's see Gerald Hicks sent this.
Where's your given statement,
Gerald?
I don't see it.
I don't see the given set statement.
I don't see the given statement.
So does this make sense, guys?
Does this make sense?
All right, Very,
very good, Gerald, Just send me that.
You don't have a given statement there,
okay?
You need it, guys.
First of all, random applause
because you guys actually
wrote your first cucumber scenarios,
your first of many.
So give yourselves a round of applause.
Okay? Yes.
Method.
It's good practice
to do so all the time. Right.
So give yourselves that.
We have to put thoughts at the end of it.
No, you don't. Why you don't to
Okay.
Simple and effective, right?
That's it. Plain and simple.
Okay.
That's all we have to do.
So congratulations.
That was the first of many, again,
that you're getting new to this
you're using as your first time.
But you guys are going to be masters
at this.
Okay. Very, very, very soon.
Okay.
Especially when it comes to automation.
This is all you're going to be doing.
Everything is going to be nature. Got
cool.
All right, guys.
So do we have any questions?
You guys did a very good job today.
I think I, I,
I did.
I threw a lot of information to you today,
so I'm going to end class right now.
You guys deserve to.
And early go.
And do you guys have any questions?
Very good job.
You guys are doing great.
Okay.
And if you don't any questions,
then prepare for tomorrow
because tomorrow
is going to be a very heavy class.
So cool, cool.
So yup.
Thanks. So don't worry about homework.
I'm not assigning homework.
I just want to go to sleep and just forget
about class for a little bit.
And tomorrow we're going hit classes hard.
And then tomorrow I will also assign
I will also assign homework.
Cool.
As of right now,
just go play with your kids or something.
You know,
I think everybody here has kids, so.
So user giving users directive.
General, we need to
work on our on our statements
a little more, but I'll help with that.
Okay.
Drop the words.
Yes, I will upload the notes.
All right, guys. So
yup, yup, yup.
Sure.
All right.
Well, I hope congratulations now for that.
So have a good night, guys,
and let me know if you have any questions.
Go see.