Hello, everyone.
How are you guys doing?
So finally, batch 11.
Okay, Jimmy, Valerie, who
you are facing, Make sure that you just
posted down in their support.
General,
I'm sure Muhammad is going to be there.
Or maybe she was going to be there.
Maybe they can help you out quickly,
because
that's really important.
Let me see.
I guess that there will be someone.
Muhammad, are you there on support?
Okay. Well, let's see.
So let's wait
a little
for all of the stories to join in.
And then we will begin
our introduction session.
And by the way, I'm really glad
that you guys are very punctual,
Like you guys just join in before, like 2
minutes.
Maryam, Which screen
are you talking about?
Okay, so that's totally fine.
It's just
a text editor that I have on my screen.
Oh, well, that's a secret.
I'll let you know.
Nah, nothing messy.
You missed nothing.
I'm just waiting for the rest of us
to join in.
Okay.
So how are you guys?
How has it been?
I guess you guys join in.
It's been now one month, right
since the beginning of your session.
The five correct about it.
Okay, so it's October,
I guess you guys joined
in November, right?
Over September.
Like the end of September, right?
Okay. September.
So it's been like
two months, right?
Oh, I'm really sorry.
I'm just sitting here.
Yeah. Okay.
I'm just messing up with the months,
I guess.
Yeah. After September, we got up to.
I was just like, of the idea.
Maybe November comes before
that happened sometime.
You know?
So by far, it's been one month.
How are you guys taking everything?
Are you guys enjoying whatever
you are learning?
I guess you guys must have started
about learning
Java, right?
Okay, that.
That's good.
And of yet
I guess you have been taught by ASL
and similar right.
Okay.
So as were you had your sessions with us
learn to offer
some don't worry you and get along
okay.
They are all so perfect.
Well now.
So that's completely fine.
Trust me,
this course is designed in such a way
that it's
going to take you all to a full level
by the end of, I guess, three months.
You guys are going
to, you know, who are a little bit
behind or, you know, slowed down.
You guys will catch
up. Don't worry about that.
But just make sure
that you are putting in effort.
Okay.
And that effort should be
that you are attending classes attentively
and doing your homework.
That's it.
If you are doing that,
you guys are going to be really
good.
I'll share my experience about this.
In the last batch, which was batch ten,
there were a few students
in the starting of a 1 to 1.5 months.
They were real.
They were real slow.
But now when I see them,
I get really amazed with the,
you know, with the pace that they are.
They have gassed up everything
and how they have joined others.
So it's all going to be good.
Just get motivated.
Okay. So
let me first introduce myself
and then I'll like
to have a little introduction of you guys
before we begin our first session.
So my name is Mazen.
As you guys already know,
I've been in the ICT sector
for the past four years
and I have worked
with in different companies
on different projects
regarding automation,
testing, machine
learning as well in various languages.
Java by Tim C-sharp, C++,
and I've been with Sentech
since last one year.
I've done around four batches and
till now it's going all great.
I'm really enjoying it all.
And that's, I guess, from my side.
Now it's your turn.
So first of all,
I want you guys to tell me that
How many of you
already have
an iPad background?
Okay.
Oh, yeah, perfect.
I'm really glad to see the replies.
If you are a guy, if you guys
are being honest, that's totally fine.
Okay, so
how many of you know
how to use a computer?
Okay, now, see,
we all know how to use computers,
so that that's a win win situation, right?
Okay, let's you are the odd one out,
but we'll make sure that you learn with us
for how.
Come on, man.
Computer is a black box. Testing.
Where did you come up with that?
Oh, okay.
Okay. So
in my classes,
I have my own,
you know, pattern of teaching.
I like to communicate a lot
because it's good
to have an interactive session,
whether we are, you know, just
discussing some technical stuff or,
you know, in between.
If we are getting to know each other
better, because that's obviously
create a common ground
where we can come to the same base
and add value to each of those life.
Honestly,
you guys will be learning a lot from me
and I will be learning a lot from you.
So it's a win win situation.
So I will encourage
all the fellows that are out there
to be very interactive, very active and,
you know, be open about everything.
So we have some rules
that I always
I don't
always mention them in the start of,
you know, session,
but for this class, I'll mention one rule
is anyone in this
is anyone here
who knows Russian or other languages,
like apart from English?
Okay,
so you guys doing all that?
Okay, guys.
So the rule one is that you guys
will not be chatting in other languages.
Okay? I want to see what you are typing.
Okay, So usually what happens
is that the friends that start
communicating in other languages
and I'm like, What are you typing guys?
So don't do that.
I'll get perfect.
Sebastian What do you expect?
I like you.
Want me to Google
that and teach the class at the same time?
No, Matt, I cannot do that.
I trust you, Farhad.
I trust you.
Okay, so it says Milan.
Am I looking at
not Madeleine? Oh,
no, I don't know.
It's AC Milan or something.
It's maybe just Milan.
I think it's.
It's a place.
Good one.
Marwin.
Okay, there you go.
Serbian.
Seriously,
You guys have already started doing that.
So who is the manager here?
Okay, Sebastian.
And who came up with the idea?
Okay, as well. Did.
I'll have to talk to us about this.
Okay. So do you guys have great managers?
Yeah.
Who is the break manager?
Okay, so you
you guys have to, in fact, interview.
You will find out
there is going to be one person
who is going to be a great manager
who's responsible to remind me
and the students that you guys
need to have. Great.
But I guess that it's it's
a rule that we cannot choose a person for
the role
chooses the person itself
over the period of time.
So it's automatically, you know,
going to appear after maybe two months.
No, no, Michael, trust me with that.
There's going to be one person
after two months who is going to take
that responsibility.
Okay.
It seems like
you guys are already having a lot of fun.
I'm recording. Yes.
How can I not record this fun session?
Come on.
I can forget to record the actual class,
but not this one.
We need to use Adam.
No, Alex, you don't have to use Adam.
It's just a text editor.
Okay.
Okay, guys. So
let's start our session, if that's okay.
You guys only need to have GID,
and that will be sufficient
enough for this class.
Okay, So did you guys watch the video
that I sent?
Okay, perfect.
And anyone who is still having problem
with installation of good
please guys support channel is there.
I won't be able to help you in the life
class with the installation.
It was supposed to be done before
the class, so now you still have time.
Go to the support.
I guess there will be someone
who can help you out.
Okay, so just push your issue
with your.
Okay, great.
So you guys watched video of that.
That's really good.
Okay, so first thing that I would like
to mention before we begin the session,
you guys do not need to take any notes
for my classes regarding GED.
I promise you that I will be giving you
very detailed, very interesting notes,
and you guys will be satisfied with that.
That's my promise.
So just pay attention to the class
and with whatever stuff we are doing,
try to be attentive on that
and the responsibility of notes is on me.
Just forget, okay? So
we will be learning get
we have two classes
and we will try to move real slow
and everyone is encouraged
to ask questions, whatever
he is confused about, you can always,
you know, push your question and lecture.
I'll try to answer as much as I can.
And obviously for the technical problems
you have support channels,
post your screenshots over there
so that you can seek help immediately.
So let's start our session.
So what do you guys know that?
Why do we need it in the first place?
What do you guys think?
Okay,
so the first question, is that right?
So let's try to answer that.
Okay?
So let's assume that we are
working on some Java code, right?
And you already are familiar with Java.
So I think this example
is going to be good enough.
One day you wrote the code
and you added the functionality
of addition and subtraction.
The other day you
open the same file
and you added that code
and add some more functionality
like, Let's see that the next day
you just decided to say that,
okay, let's add
the operations for division
and multiplication.
You changed your code.
It was working fine, everything was good.
So you just closed down your PC
and you slept on.
Next day you woke up again and you wanted
to modify your code a little bit more
and you know, you want to actually enhance
the operations
that your calculator can perform.
So you added some more functionality.
And let's see that you added the
super load
and modulus.
But at this point in time,
when you check your code,
it was not working fine.
There were some errors in it.
Now what are you
going to do?
Okay, so you had one file
and off yet you have created
no backup, right?
You do not have any backup file.
Exactly.
Remember of now we do not have any good
we do not have any backup.
We are editing the same file.
We are in the same code right.
Okay.
So if set in such a scenario,
we do not have backup.
So what we will have to do,
We just lost the code
for addition, subtraction,
division and multiplication.
And at this point,
if some of our friend calls
us, for example,
Amelia calls Aisha and say that he.
Aisha, can you share your code
with me of addition and subtraction?
Well, I shall be able to share her code.
No, because it's not working. Great.
So I. She is going to say that.
Hey, I'm really sorry.
It was working fine till yesterday, but
I added some functionality
and now it's not working.
Correct.
So what I need to do,
I have to make it correct or maybe delete
the additional functionalities
and then send you that
amount.
Yes, you can. But
let's assume that the scenarios are very
complicated and there is a lot of good,
then you won't be able to do that.
I have built up a very simple example
just for the concept.
Okay, so what do you guys
suggest
can be the solution to this problem?
Remember,
we do not know about it at the moment.
Okay, So one of the solution can be
that when we created the first code
of addition and subtraction,
the next time when we want to add
some more functionality,
we make a copy of it.
And instead of
editing the previous file,
we edit the new copy of that file.
And similarly, if you want to add
some more functionality,
we make again a copy.
So what do you guys think that
what is the disadvantage
of this approach?
Okay, the first thing is
that there is going to be a lot of copies
on our system right?
Apart from that,
if we are dealing with a huge project,
we may run out of space launch system
and let's see that.
Okay, these two problems,
we need to find a way to tackle them
just tells me that if you make like
let's say 50 copies
and you want to go back
to one specific one,
how are you going to actually navigate
back to that particular
copy in which
your desired functionality is?
It's going to be really hard
for you, right?
Yes, you can name them, but
how many are you going to name
and how many naming conventions
are you going to use?
Yes, they tend to
write or you can use date and time.
But again,
you will be doing a lot of mental effort
right.
Which is going to make everything
very hard to maintain.
Okay.
So this problem came and, you know,
one day
a person was working on his project
and he encountered this problem
and he was very sad.
So what he did,
he went out in the jungle
and he just found a magic lab.
So he thought that
maybe this lamp could help him.
So he just grabbed it
and a genie appeared.
So the genie asked him for three wishes.
And you know what he asked
in his first wish.
No, he did not ask about get you?
No, not.
Not money.
No. Allen.
Exactly.
The genie said that it's impossible
now. So he asked the genie that I would
my first wishes to provide me with a tool
that can help me manage
all the cause that I'm writing.
So the genie told him that he
you can use get.
So from there, actually,
you know, give came in.
Christine Yes.
It's a true story.
It was around 9pmi think it was.
I forgot the exact day.
But from the time he was,
I guess from 1970s to 2010,
I guess, and these 40 years,
it happened somewhere.
So, yeah.
Okay.
So now we will be moving upon
the next thing that
what is
good.
Okay, guys, before I jump into
what is good, I want you guys to tell me,
are you clear about
the first point?
Why do we need good.
Okay, so now let's discuss that.
What is okay?
But before that,
we need to discuss one more point,
which is versions.
Okay, So what are you glad
that is already know about a version?
What is a version?
Okay, so
let's let's think about it.
As you all use Facebook and Instagram,
right?
So every time you get this update
of your WhatsApp, Instagram and Facebook,
what are you actually doing?
You are updating it.
You are installing new features or changes
that are in that application, right?
So we can see that any change in the code
creates new version
of it.
Makes sense.
So let's say that this is my code
for addition and subtraction.
I added it and, and I added
some functionality of
just multiplication.
So what can we call this first code that I
what kind of call it?
I can call it version one
and what should I call the second one
was and two.
Okay, I can also go call it 1.1,
you know, 1.01.
This convention will vary depending upon,
you know, the organization
that you are working in.
What's the convention they are using?
It can vary.
Okay.
So now you guys know that.
What is the version right?
Okay.
So now let's move ahead.
Yeah.
Okay.
So let's say that there is a point
who rise
to who likes to write poems.
So what he wants to do is that he wants
that his every writing is being saved
in a locker room that he has in his room.
So what he needs to do,
he needs to honor whatever he writes.
He needs to pick it up.
Let's say that he wrote some
poetry.
He needs to pick it up
and place it in the shelf.
And if he wants to manage it perfectly,
what he needs to do, he needs to label it
with time, date
and name.
So the next day
when he's going to write something new,
what he will have to do,
he will again have
to place it on the next show
and he will have to label it with
time did and name
and so on as he works.
And he will have to do this process
over and over again
so that whenever he wants to go back
to one of his previous writing,
he can't simply just
by looking at the label, do that.
So do you guys think that
this technique of organization is going
to make it very easy
for him to get back to
any of his previous writing?
Right.
But now do you guys also think that,
for example,
if he's writing a lot of things,
do you guys think it's going to be hard
for him to place everything,
label it, and,
you know, actually manage that stuff?
Is it going to be hard for him?
Yes, it will be hard for him.
So what
what if he just hires this minion
and says that I'm not going to manage this
cupboard?
Can you do it for me?
I'm just going to tell you
that this is the writing that I wrote
and I'm going to give you
some very basic information like
the name
and, you know, maybe version number.
Can you manage the rest of stuff
on your own?
Minion is going to say, Yes,
I'll do that work for you.
So he's just going to give him,
you know, his writing along with the name
and the rest of the stuff
is going to be taken care
of by this particular minion
and he's going to manage everything
in this
cupboard that he has.
So now, guys, now tell me that does
does this technique
helps him organize everything better?
It's now it becomes even easier for him
to, you know, manage everything.
And let's just say that he wants to
get back to any of his previous writing.
You can just tell them, Minion,
that he can you go back to
you know, the writing with the name
this which I gave you,
and Minion is going to go and put
it from the cupboard for him
and he's going to get that.
So now let's replace try to replace this
example with get So you guys
can imagine that instead of this writer
there is a programmer
or a tester who is writing codes
and this cupboard
is still there
inside your computer
and whatever code you are writing,
this minion is taking care of that
and he is managing it, labeling it
and placing it in the
cupboard.
And he's going to label everything
as he puts.
Okay, so let's say that this person
who is writing is John.
What is this minion going to be?
What do who is this minion?
Yeah, remember I told that V.I.
trying to implement that example
in our computer right?
This minion is actually gift
and the cupboard that we have
this particular cupboard
or locker room, whatever
you want to said we call it
in terms of computer,
we call it breakfast.
Jeffrey
up to this point,
is everything clear to you guys that how
what is it actually
any questions
that you may have?
Okay, perfect.
So now
if get is taking care of
every code that we are writing
and we said that
each changes in the code
is called a virgin.
So can I see while defining get that
get is a virgin
control tool.
Can I see that?
It makes sense, right?
Because
Kate is actually
tracking
all the versions it's managed in them.
So I can see that gate is a virgin control
tool, right?
So let's quickly define get
get is a version control tool
that keep tracks
of all the changes
that we make in our code
and told them
in the repository.
Okay, so is there anyone who does
not understand this definition?
Okay. So for hard.
No, just you know, the guys with it,
we will be coming.
I'll answer your all questions
over the period of time.
Just for now. Go with the flow.
Okay.
They they will be automatically answered
as you move forward.
You'll need to you will be given
that answer to over the period of time.
Okay.
I'm still not done.
Anyone who does not understand
that why we wrote this definition
or are we all good?
Okay, perfect.
I think this is what Diego says right?
Okay.
So now I have one question for you guys.
This repository
that I'm talking about,
where is it located?
Okay, So this is something that we need
to, you know, I think pay attention to.
So this repository or cupboard that
gate is organizing everything into
is located on your machine.
Whatever you are using. Mac
windows or any other computer,
if you are using
it's located on your machine,
not in the cloud.
Okay.
So you can see that
gate is a motion control tool
that keeps track of all changes
that we make in our code
and stores them in the
local repository.
Can I see that?
Because
this repository resides on
our computer, right?
So that's what local repository.
Okay, So now
the next thing that we will be learning,
okay,
someone wanted me to zoom in
at this point.
Okay, Ed,
are we good?
Someone asked me the question
That is good for me.
Yes Get is open source.
It's totally free.
Do we have any other version
control tools?
Yes, we have, but
the most
popular one that is being used in
the industry is GED.
So we only learn get.
Okay,
so we were discussing the problem
that we can, you know, hired
get to manage our code and stuff
in the repository.
We discussed that.
So the next problem that we have is
we need to somehow communicate
to get in order
to tell him that, okay,
this is the name of the
version that we want to store
in our locker room,
which we now call repository.
So what do you guys suggest that
how can we talk to get
Okay, so now,
just like we know over here, we
we speak different languages, right?
Few of you speak Russian.
If you speak me maybe
speaking Spanish and stuff,
but now we come to a common ground
and we decide a common language,
which is English,
so that we all can communicate.
Right?
So similar with GED,
we have a common ground
in which we can communicate.
And what are those?
What are those
commands?
No, no, Sebastian, not binary.
Those are common.
Okay, So what are these commands?
These are unique style commands.
Okay?
Now we know that it is going to be able
to understand if we give it some commands,
but where do we actually give
those commands?
Okay, so for that,
we have a software for Windows,
which is get Bash
on Mac.
We have terminal
where we can give
these commands.
Okay.
So now you guys might be thinking that
for Windows we have Get Bash
and for Mac we have terminal.
So is there going to be any difference
when we give the commands,
something like that?
So I want to mention over here
that there is going to be no difference.
Everything is going to remain
same for Windows users
as well as Mac users.
The only thing which is different
is that for Windows we use Get Bash
and for Mac, we use the terminal.
No, you cannot use Chromebook.
How about on iPhone or Android?
You have to get older.
Do you have the eclipse? All older to
Are you writing your chords?
All right on iPhone, right.
No. Remember get
is just used for managing your quotes.
Nothing else right?
So you only need it.
Various codes are.
And those are in your computer right.
Okay.
So at this point
we will before
jumping into using actual get,
we will try to learn some very basic UNIX
commands.
Okay.
So why do we need to learn these commands
is get bash separate software
get bash is going to come in same package
if you install it on Windows.
Okay.
So these basics come at a basic command
that we are going to learn right now.
We will be learning them.
We will be using them to actually navigate
into our into our machine.
Why do we need to navigate
into our machine?
We will discuss that once
we have learned these commands.
Okay.
Are you guys
with me?
Okay.
So now I hope that everyone has installed
GID on their machines and now
we will be learning these commands.
So try to follow me,
whatever I'm doing.
And then, you know, if if anyone, if you
this is any problem,
just go to the support, if any question is
there, you can ask them.
Okay.
So the first step, open your get bash
and Windows.
And for Mac users, it's going to be
open your terminal.
So I have windows
so I'll go to search bar type in git bash
and it will appear in the search and
I'll just simply click on it.
Okay.
Let me know when you guys have done this.
So I'm going to zoom it a little bit.
That's fine For Windows user.
We have it.
BASH And for Mac users, the terminal
I have a Chromebook
and a terminal.
Michael
like a
you are not on Mac.
Weren't
you supposed to have Mac or Windows.
I don't think that you knew
you were supposed to have a Linux system.
Okay.
So what we need to do,
we need to click on this Windows
and over here we need to type
in, get bash and press enter.
Okay, So it's going to open this up.
Well, Michael, if you are on Linux,
because I'm not sure about that,
I think that you are not supposed
to have Linux,
but over there also you can open up
the terminal and, you know, work
just like the Mac users are
working is going to be
pretty much the same for Linux also.
Okay. Just
in order to zoom in
and you just need
to cool control and scroll up
or click on
plus plus.
Yeah, you can open up the terminal.
Michael Okay, so the first command
that we will be learning is
who am I?
So let's type down
where am I in the terminal
and press enter.
I want you guys to paste your output
in the live chat.
Just Christine,
can you share the screenshot
of what you are having?
Okay. When my
so. Okay,
very good.
Very good.
Remember,
there is no space between who am I?
Okay.
It has to be without a space.
Okay. Don't send me screenshot.
Just copy this where my text
and you can paste simply that.
Okay. That will be much better.
Okay.
So what is your terminal telling you
right now?
It is telling you the name
that you have given to your computer.
Yes, exactly.
And this name is obviously going
to be different for every one.
My computer name is HPC X
and yours is going to be different.
Well,
Farhad, that
trust me, that will make no difference.
Knowing your computer name,
I cannot hack into that. Tom.
I know you are.
You are perfectly doing well.
Anyone having issues with this?
The support is there, right?
You guys can send screenshot
over there and get help.
Okay, so the command is who am I?
Okay, now
let's imagine that this terminal
is actually
a person in your computer.
Okay.
Are we all good with this assumption
that this computer
is like a person to whom we can talk?
And he talks back,
so we just ask him that Who am I?
And he told it
that your computer is HPC X.
So now what we want to do,
we want to ask the terminal that, Hey Mr.
Terminal, what is your current location
in the computer?
Because you know, inside your computer
you have desktop
documents, downloads and you know, a
lot of other folders and files.
Your terminal can be anywhere, right?
So in order to know that the terminal is
right now, we need to ask him.
And for that we have a command which is
TWD, So let's first type them down
so anyone who is skipping out
can catch up.
Okay, so let's write down TWD and let's
see where our terminal is right now.
So do you guys think that we all will be
having different results
or the same result?
Different right.
Because and everyone computer
the location of the terminal
is going to be different, right?
It's going to be different for me.
It's going to be different for you.
Okay.
So my terminal is currently
in C users
and HPC X
I'm I'm coming
to that go.
Okay, perfect.
So you see for everyone
the location is different.
B For my units users.
Maryam Abedi for do is abduction users.
Abdullah Shinwari
And for the rest of you, it's also going
to be different right?
Perfect.
So what does PWT
stands for?
Friend Working Directory
or in
some case we can also see
a present working directory.
So what do we understand from the term
Framed Working directory?
We will come to that.
Okay, so the pwt come out.
Is there
anyone who is still confused about
what does this command do
and is unable to execute it?
Know how to do?
Remember,
don't complicate
the knowledge that you have and mix it up.
Just understand
we are moving from very basic steps.
So what I told you,
I told you that you open up your terminal
and when you want to know that where
your terminal is standing, you use PWT.
Okay, so that's it.
That's all we know so far.
Okay, Get back.
It's good, Bash.
It's not good.
I'll explain it to you
that what is a terminal?
Okay, So first, let's move on to the
next command, which is else.
Okay, so
let's simply write down L.S.
and let's first see that
What does this command do?
Okay, For me, it's printing out,
you know, different
files.
Okay,
so this command, Alice,
what we are telling,
what we are asking Mr.
Terminal.
Hey, Mr.
Terminal, can you please tell us that
in your current location
where you are standing,
what are the files and folders
present over there?
Okay, so what you want to ask Mr.
Terminal that?
What are the files and folders
in the location where he's standing?
We use the command L.
S list ten for list content.
Okay.
Makes sense.
Okay, so at this point, I want to mention
one thing.
Folders can
are also called
decrease.
Okay, so we can
interchangeably use the terms
folders and directories.
So I don't want you guys to get confused
if I use the term directory.
So whenever I use the term directory,
what does it refer to
folder.
Right.
And we all know that
what a folder is, right?
Okay. So
if we want to clear everything
that we have written on our terminal,
you can just use the command clear
and it's going to erase everything
that we have written until this point.
So let's do one thing.
Let's write down clear and press enter.
Okay?
Let's erase
everything that we have written.
So now the first thing that I want to do
is I want to ask the terminal
the name of my computer.
So what command will I use
exactly?
So I will say, who am I?
And it tells me that you are.
It speaks, right? Okay.
So now the next thing,
which I want to ask Mr.
Terminal, is that here is a terminal.
Where are you currently?
In my computer.
So I let's say
p wd.
It's telling me that I am in C users
s p c x.
Okay.
At this point in time,
let's make our explanation
a bit visual. Also
this C slash user slash is Speaker X
is actually a location inside my computer.
Do you guys agree with that?
Okay. So if this is the location of my Mr.
Terminal, can I go to this location
manually to my explorer?
Okay.
So in order to make things more clear
what I'm going to do right now,
I'll open up that Explorer
along with that terminal
so that we can visualize
booting simultaneously.
Okay. Yes.
Now, so it does not require Internet.
Remember, we are dealing with everything
which is local.
Okay. It so
I'm going to
make my terminal a little bit small
and I'm going to minimize everything.
And now I want to go to the location
where my Mr.
Terminal is
and I want you guys to do the same also.
So for me is to be different.
And for you
it's also going to be different right?
So the first step is to go to my C,
so I'll go to my C
on windows.
Let me open them side by side.
Okay.
So for Mac users, what you have to do,
I'll simply tell you, wait for Mac users,
you can use this go and from there
you can select wherever
your location of
terminal is.
Okay.
Okay, guys.
So, Sharif,
what can you find on Mac?
And don't worry, I want to
I'll give you time to find that on Mac and
man not file which come out is not found.
Can you show you a screenshot?
Remember, guys, we have to take this class
very slow.
We need to take all of our friends
along with us.
Some up.
Some of you guys might be having a problem
because you know we are not accustomed
to terminal and stuff,
so we will take things
real slow. Okay
so for Windows user, first,
I'm going to explain that
and then we can concentrate on Mac users.
So if I ask my Mr.
Terminal that,
what is your current location,
it tells me the location
till this step for Mac and Windows users.
Are we all on the same page?
This command is working for everyone,
right? Okay.
So for Windows users, what I'll do,
let me get to my C drive in the Explorer
which is this particular drive C Right.
And after that
I need to find users in the C drive.
So do I see any users in C drive for my
from my computer?
I'm talking about my computer.
I see that for you
it may be different, maybe same.
So I'm going to click on users
and after that I want to go to into H
because for you guys
it's going to be different.
So I'll say this is HP X
and I'll click on it.
So if I see that my Mr.
Terminal is right now
in this particular location,
will I be correct about it or not?
Yes, I'll be correct about it.
Okay.
So let's whole at this point,
let's try to see to Mac users,
what do you have problem with?
Okay.
So if you are unable to find this
good option,
you'll have a option of Finder
in your Mac.
Let me show it to you if I can quickly
navigate
over there.
Okay, guys.
So if you have a go, then you can click on
Go and click on Home
or maybe go to folder.
If you do not have this Google
option available, this means that you have
a different version of a mac
or s installed on your Mac.
For that we will have to go to Finder.
Right.
So let me show you how to go to Finder.
Okay. So ma'am, you are good.
You have your finder option available.
Okay.
So what you can do
if you see if you see on your Mac
Mac screen, the top right
corner,
you'll see a search option over there.
If you click on that,
you'll be able to find a find
a finder over there.
Are you able to do that, Mac users?
I'm waiting for you guys.
Yeah.
I want you all to be good
so that we can proceed together.
Okay?
Okay. So
Mohamed al-Fadhli has shared the solution.
If you have the goal, you can simply
go to folder and, you know, type in users.
It will tape to users
whatever you type
in, whatever the path you are finding,
you can type it over there
and Maryam
what you need to do.
Maryam You have to follow this back.
Now whatever is being displayed
by typing in TWD for you,
you have to find those folder over here
and navigate into them.
Okay?
And yes,
Michael, you are good to
if that's the location that is being shown
and you are
there, you are good.
And now you can you
can you share the screenshot of
what was the problem that you are having.
So let me ask you this.
All of you guys are having on
this go option on the toolbar, right?
Is is in prison
for everyone.
Okay, guys is not present for you
or asked of you.
Is it present for everyone?
Emily is a present for you.
Okay, good, good.
Okay. Yeah.
Can you also share
the screenshot of your TWD command?
Was the result of that?
Can you share that? Yes.
And let's see.
So those of you who have the Google
available, what you need to do,
you need to simply click on Go
Click on recent folder.
Sorry,
click on Google
and then click on go to folder
over there, you can type in part
that is appearing and get back.
You can type in the back, not mine,
but the one that is appearing for you.
You type that in
and it will take you to that location.
Okay.
And for those of you who is not appearing
like the Google option is not available,
I think there's only one person.
Can you please share
the screenshot in the support?
And I guess is going to be there
to help you out
or maybe we'll classes there.
Yeah.
Well, gosh, is there
okay.
Okay. Yeah.
You also need to share the screenshot
and in the support and focus
is going to help you out.
I so what's
what is the problem that you are having.
Share the screenshot.
Okay.
Yes. So Nicolay
what what only colleague has shared
you follow this.
It's going to take you to the location.
Okay, click on go and then over there
you need to select all.
If that is appearing for you.
It's also going to take you to the
to the exact same
location.
Okay, Abdul, you are, you are good.
Okay. I'm still going to wait
one minute
for the rest of you to catch up
so that we can
then proceed.
Now, can you try this?
What Nicole shared
my. Yes.
No, I'm really sorry.
I'll get comfortable with your names,
but right now
I'll be pronouncing them real bad.
But over the period of time,
I'll get good with them.
Yes, that's. That's a good idea.
Let's go for a break.
And till then,
all of you. I can help you.
That And yes, I remember I told you
that Rick manager is going to appear.
So I guess Lugo is
you are going to be the one
who will be managing breaks to you guys.
Okay, so it's 528.
Let's meet at
sorry, not 520.
I'm really sorry about that.
The computer time on
my and my site is not correct of
it's 729 right.
829 Yes.
829 So let's meet at
15 minutes after 15 minutes,
let's let's meet after 15 minutes.
So it's going to be 24.
Okay. 45. Let's make it 45.
And meanwhile I'm still here
and I'll try to resolve the problems
that you guys are facing. Okay.
So let me just mention break.
Okay.
I'm really sorry,
but I think that I have skipped
the above problems if anyone has having.
So only the people who are having issues
can you only now
post the
screenshot because you know,
a lot of students are posting
I can I look into all of them.
Yes Marina.
Okay.
So what you should be able to look at
when you type in PWT,
you are actually asking Mr.
Trump know that where he is, right?
So Mr. Terminal is in C users.
It speaks for me.
It's going to be different for you, right?
Makes sense.
I show.
Okay, so it's different for you.
You should be able to locate this folder
for me, be six for you.
It's going to be different.
So are you able to look that
on the system?
No, Michael, nothing else.
We are on break.
I'm just, you know, helping out
other students are having issues.
We won't be discussing anything.
Yeah, mine user.
And then. Okay, this is your best.
I do understand
you were able to open that to
to home button, right?
You were able to do that.
And can you share the screenshot
of both things like your
your terminal
and the folder that that is zero.
Can you share the screenshot
if you are able to do that?
This means that you have successfully
navigated to the location where you are.
Mr. Terminals Okay, so apart from my show,
who else is still struggling with it?
Okay, so can I? Yeah.
Can you share the screenshot of your
off your desktop
like the screen that you are seeing?
I want to see the toolbar that is there.
Do you have the go option available?
Yes, I sure you are. Good.
It won't let me copy and paste. No, no.
I don't have an option.
Okay. Yeah.
So you are saying that you do not have
that Google option
on the toolbar just like this, right?
You Do not have this.
Go right.
Okay.
Anyone else who does not have this
go option?
Okay, So let me tell you.
Why is it so?
Can you just name
can you minimize everything
and then then see whether the go option
appears?
Sandy Yes.
You can ask
if you are doing correct or not.
Okay. I'm Juliet.
Can you share the screenshot
that's is going to help?
How about me?
If you do that, it's going to be great.
Okay. Sandy. That's correct.
See users admin.
So are you able to navigate
to the folder admin successfully?
Simon Nothing. We are on great.
Just helping
our students.
Okay.
Apart from now, is anyone else
having problem?
Okay, can you look a look into that
and help her out?
Thank you for your support.
Anyone else who is having issue?
Okay.
Amelia I guess, Nina,
if you look at what Amelia has shared,
you will be able to proceed with that
quick.
Okay, great. That's great news.
Okay.
I want I want you to do one thing.
I want you to remember what you
how you did that.
Okay?
Okay. Perfect.
Anyone left?
Thank you, Amelia.
And thank you guys to you to.
And trust me, this was the hardest part
we had to go through.
Rest of the stuff
is pretty much very easy.
Okay,
so, yes,
and I check that your p
w command is showing the correct.
I asked you to
share the screenshot of your
folder with me so that I can see that
if you have navigated
to the correct location or not.
Okay, I think I skipped it.
Let, let me go up and try to see that.
Yes. Yes.
And then you have done it correctly.
Yes, exactly.
You can do anything and great. Right.
We still have 5 minutes.
Okay. So it's 845.
Are you guys back from break?
Oh, that's that's good.
Okay. Welcome back.
I hope you had your coffee, snacks,
whatever you wanted.
Okay, great.
Yes. And Mac is a little bit complicated,
but you will be okay with it.
You just need to,
you know, get accustomed to it.
You will be okay.
Okay.
So let's let me give you a quick recap
of what we were doing,
and then let's start doing that By now.
I hope that all of you are at least able
to find the folders right?
Okay.
So the first step we did is that
we asked our terminal that who am I?
It told us the name.
Then I asked that. Okay.
TWD Can you tell me your current location?
Mr. Terminal
It gives me that C user, ABC X,
which is my location,
is going to be different for you.
So then we decided that we want to look,
have a look at location on our computer.
And for that purpose I went to the C drive
and there I look for users
and then I'll look for HBC X
and I clicked on it
and now I see that my terminal
is currently
in this particular location.
So are you guys able to find the location
of your terminal
in your computer?
Okay, perfect.
So now let me give you
some details about this.
So this slash is actually
determining the next directory of folder.
So the first folder is C,
And to differentiate
between this and
this folder, we have a slash
and to tell us that
now the next folder is starting,
we have an agenda
slash and folder name
does it make sense?
These flashes.
Okay, so now the interesting thing is that
if you look at this pad
and on windows, if you look at this bat
over here and you click on it,
C users, HBC X and C users
is it's going to be the same.
Is it same for you guys?
Okay.
So does this mean that we
have navigated to the right location?
Yes. Okay.
So now I want
why are the slash is different
there over here backslash.
Okay.
That doesn't make any difference.
Okay. It can be forward or backward.
I'll explain it to you further in
the course that what difference it makes.
For now, let's assume that they are saying
yes for hot.
Okay,
So now whenever we close our terminal
and we write down TWD,
is this location always the same?
Okay,
so whenever you close your terminal,
remember
close your terminal and open it up again.
This location is going to remain the same.
Let me show you.
I'm going to close my terminal
and I'm going to open it up again.
So now I'll type again.
What's the command
to know?
The current location
of the Metro terminal? TWD
It is same.
So every time
if I close and open my terminal
and the very first thing I do, I do TWD,
this is going to be the same.
So again, I see that this particular
location is the home of my Mr.
Terminal, and I see that.
Okay.
So I can also say
that this location is my home directory
or home folder.
Okay.
So now whenever I say
navigate to your home
directory,
will you guys be able to understand that?
What am I referring to?
I am referring to the very first location.
When you open up your terminal,
the terminal is over there.
I'm referring to that particular location.
Okay, So this was just to let you know
that in future
we will be using the terminal home
directory
so that you can understand that.
What I mean by home directly.
Okay, good enough.
Now, at this point, if I want to ask Mr.
Terminal
to give me all the file and folder
it has in the current location,
which command can I use
else.
Right.
And if I press, enter, it shows me
these files and folders.
Now I'm going to compare
just to be assured
that this command is actually up to go.
I can create or not.
So let's start that. Okay.
I have my downloads, I have my downloads.
I have my documents. I have my documents.
I have my desktop.
I have my desktop creative cloud creative
that so so
it's actually giving me everything
that it has
and its current location.
Okay,
so now
it's time to learn the next command.
No, for it does not show it in folders.
Okay.
So now what if you want to ask
Mr. Terminal
to move into, we want to ask Mr.
Terminal to move into another location
from its current one.
So basically,
if I simplify it, we are asking Mr.
Terminal to change the folder right.
Okay.
For this purpose we have a command CB
folder name.
CTE stands for
Change Directory
and you guys remember that?
I told you
I can refer to folder as directory.
Okay,
so now let's do one thing.
Let's take on Mr.
Terminal from its home directory
to this desktop.
So what am I supposed to type in
in the terminal.
Okay, I type in CD.
Is that it?
C d and then the folder name to
which we want it to move.
So I'm going to type C, D, desktop
and then I'll press enter.
Okay.
So now
this command did not give us any output,
but I want to know that further
my terminal has actually changed
is its folder or not.
So for that purpose, which command
can I use?
I can ask Terminal that.
Hey, can you tell
me your current location?
So for that I'll use p WD.
Okay.
So now it sees that I am in C users SBC
and then desktop.
So this means that RCD desktop
has successfully executed.
Okay.
Now let's also do this on our Explorer.
I want to go to the full under
where my terminal is right now.
So what I'll do over here,
I simply click on desktop and right now
my terminal is in this location.
Okay.
So now I want to
ask Terminal to print all the files
it has in desktop.
What will I do for that?
I'll say again. LS
okay, so
all the files
that are there in the desktop,
they are being displayed over here.
Yeah.
My Mac has some permissions issue.
Yeah. Jimmy, don't worry.
We will be going over to it
multiple times.
Okay.
Okay. So right now what we did,
we navigated into
desktop using see desktop and then
over here
what we said that
ls to print
all the files that it has on desktop.
Okay,
so not all of you are able to do that.
Some of you are having the problem
that no such
file are directory.
Okay, so what I want
you to do is make sure of one thing.
Okay? See?
Okay.
Make sure of one thing
that when you did ls
in your previous previous step,
your desktop was being displayed in
that command is in there or not
like it's showing for me.
Is it showing for you to.
Okay my for those of you
who are unable to see desktop,
Allen said that.
But those of you
who are able to see the desktop guys,
you must be having some problem
with the syntax.
Okay.
For those of you who
cannot see desktop in that, it's
can you tell me that?
Why it gives you an error of that.
No such file or directory?
Because let me explain it to you
because right now
what you are doing
is that you are inside this folder
right now.
Your Mr.
Terminal is at this point and it has,
let's say, one two folder, E
and B and four in front of it.
And there is a seafood
which is not in that location.
You are asking Mr.
Terminal that he can you go to C but Mr.
Terminal only has A and B in front of him
so that's
why he's unable to go there.
Makes sense.
So what you will do, I'll tell you.
Okay, Sandy, for you,
you have already successfully
navigated to desktop, okay?
So you don't need to worry about that and
do for you R2.
You have also successfully
navigated to desktop
and now while you have also navigated
to desktop
successfully successfully.
Okay, so for those of you
who do not have a desktop
in the class,
you won't be able to navigate to that.
What you can do, you can pick
any of the folder that is being displayed
and you can use see the
that particular folder name
to navigate into that.
I'm going to repeat it. Okay.
So for those of you
who do not have desktop,
you can simply pick one of the
one of the items that is displayed.
It can be documents or downloads
and you can simply write CD
instead of desktop.
You can write
down downloads are a document
or you are a good
okay.
After that you can do lists
and see the files and folders
that are being displayed at that point.
Farhad How do you know
which is the folder you can use?
The command?
LS It will display
you all the files and folders
to which you can navigate.
Okay guys. So are we good till this?
I perfect.
So now we moved into another directory
or folder.
We learn that what is the command
that can be used for that?
Now let's learn the last command.
That's fine now
so you can move to different one.
That's fine.
Okay, so the next one is
what?
If you want to say that here, Mr.
Terminal,
can you move
once folder back?
So for that we have a command
which is C this space
dot, dot.
Okay,
so let's try that out
right now.
If I want to check my current location
of Mr.
Terminal, what is the command
that again,
I want to check the current location
of my Mr.
Terminal.
It's TWD cousin and Abdul
current location.
So it is inside desktop right now.
I want it to move one folder back.
What should I type in?
I should type in city space, dot, dot.
Right.
And then I'll press enter.
Okay.
Now I want to make sure that terminal
has moved
one step back.
And I want to ask that
what is your current location
again?
I'll do TWD right.
So now I'm sure that my city, dot, dot
actually
works right.
CD space dot com
might see this based on the.
Okay,
so let me just close everything
and let me just open up my nodes
and ask you that
we have learned up to this point
full commands
which are pwt ls
CB, dot, dot.
Okay, I'm going to write them down
in small letters.
Okay.
So for PWT, what does PWT do
guys?
Okay, what does LS do
and what's the purpose of CB folder?
The name.
Okay, so what will happen
if your feed folder name
The folder name you are giving
is not present in front of Mr.
Terminal.
What will happen?
It will say no such file or directory
right? No.
It will give you the URL that
no such file or directory.
So city Dada.
What does this command do?
Go back one folder.
That's
okay.
So now let's do this.
I want you guys to stop
everything that you are doing.
Take a break from your computer
and your terminals
and you guys are going to do now
help me on my computer to do the stuff.
Okay?
Yeah.
For not giving you a little break.
Yeah. I need I.T.
support. Okay, guys.
So I tell you the task that I want to do.
So what I want to do is I want to,
first of all, find
that where my terminal is is.
What? What do I do?
PWT So,
yes, spotlight, search the terminal.
I'm on Windows. Okay.
So the first step is to open up
my get bash, Right.
So I'll open it up.
Okay.
And now I'll type WD
right.
Okay.
So it is showing me the location.
Now I want you guys to tell me,
what do we call
this location.
Okay,
exactly.
We call it home directory. Why?
Because every time you close
the terminal, when we open it
up, a terminal is sitting over there.
Okay,
so now
I want to see
which folders are present
in the current location.
I'll do ls right.
It will list every folder
that I have inside.
Okay. Very good.
Now I need to change the location
of my terminal
to let's see
the folder. ABC.
So what I will do?
See the ABC.
So let's do see the ABC.
It shows me no such file or directory.
Why is that so?
Because in the current location
terminal doesn't see any see right.
Okay.
So this means that terminal
can only go to the files
and folder
which are there in the current location.
Right.
So let's see, I want to go to documents.
So what will I do?
So I do see the documents right
now to make sure that terminal is actually
in documents. TWD
Now to print the contents
of the location, document.
LS Right.
Now, if I want to go to
let's see
to have a folder in there.
Yeah, I want to move one step back.
What will I do?
C d dot, dot. Right.
Okay,
now again, I want to move to desktop.
I'll come to that.
So I'll say c d desktop
right.
Okay.
So now let's view
the content of desktop LS.
Now let's go into the folder, get
now let's view
the content of the folder, get
okay, perfect.
Now let's make sure that
what is the current location of our Mr.
Terminal?
It's inside.
Get now.
I want my terminal to move one step back.
I want to make sure it has moved
one step back.
I want to move one step back again.
I want to make sure it has moved
one step back.
Okay, great.
Okay, great. Perfect.
Perfect, guys.
Really impressive. Really impressive.
You guys did an awesome job.
Yeah, I can already see that.
Perfect. Sure.
Yes. Michael, I have a great student.
Okay, perfect.
So now tell me, guys,
do you understand how we can navigate
in between folders using these commands?
Is it difficult?
Right. It's.
It's so simple.
Pretty straightforward. You. Right.
Okay, so now let's do one
task together.
Well, let's clear everything
and let's close our terminal.
Let's do it from the very scratch.
Okay?
Okay.
So the first step, what I want to do,
I want to open up my gimp bash for Mac.
Obviously,
you guys are going to open up your
terminals.
Let's now do pwt to see that
the current location is HBC X.
For me, it's
going to be different for you.
Okay. Are we all good until this point?
Are we?
Have you all done that? Okay, done.
Perfect Now let's open up
this location in our Explorer.
So for me, I'll go to this
PC, I'll click on see Drive
and then I'll go to
the users and then I'll go to HPC X.
So this is my current location for you.
It's going to be different.
Let me know once all of you have navigated
successfully to the current location,
which is home directory off your terminal.
Okay, perfect.
Very good.
Now I want to view
the content of this folder.
So what I'll do
is I'll do
ls right.
Okay. Till this point,
I hope that none of you
is going to be having any problems
and we all will be on the same page.
Let me know if you guys are done
with this point and then let's move
forward.
Very good.
Okay, so now for me,
I have desktop, so I'll go to desktop.
For those of you who do not have desktop,
you can navigate to document or download
or any any other folder that you see.
So I'll use the command, see the desktop
and I'll press, enter
Okay, Over here
also I'll open up my desktop.
Now let me just
create a new folder
inside my desktop on the Explorer
and let's name it Bad
Lemon is smart.
So on Windows you just right click
and you can create new and folder
and on Mac also you will be following
the same steps You can simply click on
right click on your space and know
create a new folder.
So now if I'm terminal, I do ls
What will happen?
Okay, so when we are not learning that
right now, now what I do ls At this point
I can see that batch 11 is smart
is appearing
right. Okay.
I want to move my Mr. Terminal inside.
Batch 11 is smart.
What I'll do.
Okay,
so in the Explorer, I'll just click on it.
Okay?
And This point, if I do ls
what's going to be the output?
Nothing.
Because I have nothing in there.
Right.
But what if I create a new folder
saying that ABCD
and now if I do ls,
what will happen?
Yes, because you have to type full name.
So I'll do
what?
Only A, B, c, D,
what will be the command does?
I want you to remember the command.
Okay. Let me repeat the question.
I want to
know.
Okay. I want to.
Sure, I want to do ls
and I want see which folder is there
inside?
Batch 11 is smart,
ABCD is the right.
Okay.
Now if I want to go into ABCD,
see the ABC.
Right.
Okay.
Perfect.
You were all able to do that
with me, right?
Okay. Pretty simple.
So we will be just learning one thing
more and we will be
done with these commands. So
I want to check
which is my current location, BWT.
Okay,
if I want to move one back to my home
directory and now we know that
what is our home directory, right?
For me C users H speaks.
This is my home. Verity Correct.
It's going to be different for you guys.
If I want to move back to this point,
what I will do.
C D dot, dot It will take me to batch
on the spot and then I'll do C again.
It will take me to desktop
and then I'll do KD dort again.
At that point I'll be at C users.
X Do you guys agree with that?
I'll have to do c D, Dada three dials.
Okay, so we have a shortcut.
Command for that, which is CB
Tilde.
This command takes you Mr.
Terminal back to the home directory.
Tilde This line is called Tilde.
Okay, I show you cannot do that
because it will expect it
to be in front in that folder.
Okay, So if I do see the tuner
and now if I do p wd,
what do you guys suggest
should be the output
of my master terminal
which is C users HPC X for me.
Right.
So let's do pwt
it C users HPC
x, right.
Okay. Very good guys. Really good job.
You guys have done an awesome job.
I'm really impressed and
let's take a break for one minute
and then we'll move forward.
Well, Joseph, you guys are great students,
so yeah, how to write Tilde
on the windows It's going to be along side
below your escape and on Mac.
Can somebody just help out your friends
saying,
okay, I'm coming to
that, I'm coming to that.
Okay, so it's 625 one, then break.
Okay, let's breathe then let's read out.
Let's relax ourselves.
You know?
Then we'll begin.
Yes, it's.
It's morning now.
No, Aisha, I'm
from Pakistan. No,
not that much, but I watch the maths.
Okay, so it's.
It's one minute our break is over.
Okay, let's get back to work.
We can have chit chat off after that. Yes.
And from there.
Okay, guys, one minute is over. Right.
We will be having chit chat.
But for now,
we have a lot of work to cover.
Okay, So
why did we learn all of this?
To navigate into the different folders
and, you know, do stuff like that
we will be witnessing that right now.
So you guys have had clips installed
in your systems, right?
Can you open
that up for me?
Okay.
So just open up your clips and.
Okay, have you guys open it?
All of you.
Okay. It's all of us.
Open. Perfect.
How many projects do you have in there?
Wow, Four hot grade
millions. Wow.
Okay, So do you have this one
project named
Java Basic?
Okay,
so let's do this.
I want you
to be able to move your terminal
to the folder Java Basic.
So this is the task
that we are going to do.
We want to be able to move our terminal
from home directory to the folder
where our Java Basic is.
How do we do that?
Well,
number one, okay,
if it doesn't have most of our Java basic,
it's going to have some other project.
You can use that.
Okay.
Okay. So what is going to be our very
first step?
I want you guys to guide me
as well as you know do.
Everything on your computer is also.
No, Alex, we are not doing that. The
first thing is that we want to find out
what is the location of our Java.
Right?
Perfect.
So how can we know that
in order to do that,
just go to your project.
If it's basic, that's fine.
If it's something else,
you guys can select any.
Any project, right click on it.
Go to properties
in there,
you'll see the location.
Okay,
so what should be my next step? Guys?
Can someone guide me?
Well, okay.
Select any of your project
to which you want to navigate.
Right click on it.
Then go to properties.
Okay,
Now I'll open up my Kit bash
and obviously for Windows users,
you can always make users,
you can use terminal.
So first of all, I'll do
which come on, mirror, step by step guys,
we need to move step by step.
No shortcuts fun.
Now when you will mature, you'll go up.
Then you can use shortcuts.
Okay, so be ready.
It says that my master terminal
is currently
in C uses HPC X, right?
Till HPC? Yes.
So what is the next folder to which
I want to move my terminal?
Its atlas workspace.
But first I need to make sure
that workspace is in that location.
I'm not
so I can do else
and it shows me that
it is there right?
So what is going to be my command
to move terminal to eclipse workspace
C D Eclipse
Workspace right.
I'll press enter
and then
again TWD to make sure
I have reached this point.
So I'm an eclipse workspace.
Okay, I am in Eclipse workspace.
So next caller is
Java base. It.
So first I want to make sure
that our basic is there
it is zero
if I want to go into that simply
c d java base it.
So now we are.
Mr. Terminal is at
the location of our project.
What if I do
less at this point?
Mary were you able to locate it
in less?
Yeah.
You're spelling is wrong
for hard.
You must be having the same problem.
You can share the screenshot in support.
Okay.
So let's do our last.
So in there
it shows me two folders s, r, c,
and then
if you do not have Java Basic,
you can choose any project.
Okay, so now if I want to
quickly look into my
Java basics
and make sure that these two folders
are over there,
I can simply right click on it
and then I can click on
where is that
option?
Yeah, properties and I can click on this
this arrow key.
It's going to open up that folder
for me.
If I go into Java basics,
I see that I have binary
bean and sa c, these rest
or the folders are not displayed
because they are not actually,
you know, the proper folders.
They have a dot different extension.
So this command does not show the
these folders.
Okay.
So this is the main task that we will be
doing when we will be working with kids.
So tell me, guys,
if I asked at any point in time
that, Hey guys, I
want you to navigate your terminal
to one of your Java projects, Eclipse,
will you guys be able to do that
in no time?
Right.
It's pretty simple.
You guys will be able to do that.
I'm pretty sure about it. Okay.
So, yes,
for those of you,
if you are still struggling with it,
let me know at the end of class
so that I can help you out.
After the end of class, I'll still spend
5 minutes to make things more clear.
Okay,
let's take a break for 2 minutes,
and then we'll
discuss the new.
Yes, we can.
But for now, I'm not going to teach you
that because, you know, we want to move.
Stepwise shortcuts are there?
You guys will be using shortcuts
all the time, but always first
we have to learn the basics.
Okay, perfect.
Okay.
So meanwhile, tell me, guys,
what do you do apart from?
You know, coming to syntax
and attending the classes?
Okay. Wow.
I learned.
I will word that after, you know, after
the class and also during the class also.
Okay, So don't worry about that.
The word work word
teenager is a teenager. Word
mom, duties, catcall.
Okay, Alex, that that's what we all do.
Work and forum.
Okay, great. That's great.
So you guys are all working
and, you know, taking classes
along with that.
That's really great.
Must be having a lot of hard time.
Okay.
You are a lucky one. That
so by the end of,
you know, one or two months
it's like, you know,
this was our first class
by the end of two, two months, I guess
slowly you'll get to know each other
more and more over the time.
But for now, it's
a little bit
we are a little bit strangers
to each other.
So who was our great manager, by the way?
I forgot his name.
Okay.
Lubo.
Okay, little boy,
you are the break manager, okay?
Yes, the break is over.
So let's get back to our work
work.
So remember, guys, what you were talking.
We were talking about Gabe.
So we now understand that
what we are using get right?
We know that it's a volume control tool
and we know that way to use it
and stuff like that.
So you guys will be doing this.
Okay?
You are having your eclipse
and there you have
your Java project right?
And inside this Java project
you have multiple folders, maybe
CRC and Binary.
Is it correct?
What are you is is this correct?
Okay.
If I tried to
draw everything that I have drawn
in Eclipse on your
Explorer window and computer,
I would say that you have a window
in which you have
a folder with that.
Let's see.
I'm just imagining this battle. Okay.
And the last thing is Java Project.
And in there
we have, let's say, two folders.
Okay, SRT and
then so
if I see this,
am I correct about this?
Like,
I can show you that also in f lives, I
Java and under it I have SRT
and inside my explorer also
inside my job basics.
I have been in SRT right.
And the location of my Java project.
I will go to this point. Okay.
So now this is the location
where we are writing our code, right?
Our Java code.
This is the location
where we are writing it.
If you want
to track this project using gift,
what we to do,
we need to create a repository.
At this point.
Do you guys agree with me?
We need to place a cupboard over there,
a locker room in that location.
Okay.
I'm going to repeat it again.
So I'm saying that
we are writing down our code
and it lives inside
Java project right?
If I want to get to track my codes,
what I need to do, I need to create
a I want geared actually
to create locker room
or a repository, right.
I want get to do that right.
Come on. You can see a locker room
repository all interchangeably used
for the same thing.
Okay.
I want get to create that.
First of all, the point is that what
will be the location of that
repository?
Can it be anywhere on the on the computer?
What if I place it
somewhere, you know, on my desktop
where my jello projects are not lying in.
Right.
It's not going to work.
Why? So this is the condition of get
it says that, hey, if you want me
to keep track of your goods,
you need to place my code
on the same location where your codes are.
Okay,
That's the condition
that we have to follow.
Let me write that down for you.
Okay, guys, here,
I want you to remember this line.
Okay?
And make sure
that you never make this mistake.
Everyone, I'm still telling you
you will be making this mistake
and even future, despite of me
telling you that that's totally fine.
That's how you learn.
But always, always make sure
that you are creating
that covered repository in right location.
Where is that?
Where is that location?
Where your codes are? Right.
I'm going to answer that
for a fact.
So for this
particular project that we have off
Java Basic,
what is going to be the location?
Let me show you.
If I go to properties
and I click on this show in System
Explorer, it's
going to open the folder for me.
Okay, So I'm in Java codes
in this folder.
No, Where are they?
Inside.
Do I have to go inside Java it.
Okay, inside Java Basic
in search of music.
I have S.R., C, Ben, and some other files
that are there.
They are all the part
of my Java code right?
So I should create the cupboard
over here at this point.
Not inside s rc
not inside Bean
not inside any other folder.
I want to create it
at this particular location
I'm coming to that for
I'm coming to the okay,
So if we have a general project
and we want to get to keep track
of all of our codes in that project.
So the first step is
we have to ask, get to create a covered
repository at the same location
where our Java codes are.
Okay, now how do we do that?
I'm going to show you.
So first of all, the very first step
is, okay, so let me answer this question.
So it is look, is it look at it.
We're not SIRC Your job was Gerald.
Are you talking about your Java codes?
Okay, Your Java codes are inside SIRC,
but the other files that are there,
they are also going
be part of your Java project, Right?
So we created
inside that folder
question.
But you set store wherever our codes are,
restore all the programs on.
SIRC because
I'm going to tell you that.
So let me quickly answer that question.
So the question now here is that
let's say
this is our source
and inside that we have
different right
Class one, Class two or class two, right?
All the Java codes are inside that.
Are you guys with me?
Am I correct about this?
Right inside source folders,
we have class one, class to class.
See what our packages
you have created whatever there is.
Okay, apart from that,
let me create a bigger folder.
Also let me call it Java basics.
Okay.
So now
apart from this RC, you have let's see
some other folder of files, let's say bean
or you know, some file that you have
when you want to
create a repository for your chords,
you have option either
to created inside SRT
or inside class one or inside class two.
But what will happen
if you created inside class one?
Let's say
if you create this repository inside
class one, it's
only going to keep track of the codes
which are in your class one
right?
If you created in class two,
it will only keep track of your codes
in class two.
Okay.
What if you created inside SIRC only?
What if you created inside SIRC?
Then it will.
It will store everything which is inside
SARS in class one, Class two class, three.
Okay.
What if I create our opposing tree inside
our basics?
What if I create the repository
inside your business that it's to store
everything which is contained
inside our project, our basics, right?
So we can create it inside class.
We can create it inside class two.
But the best practice
for creating a repository
is that you create the repository
for the whole project
right?
So if I want to create repository
for the whole project, where should I be
creating it?
Inside Java Basics, right?
I should be creating it inside Jarvis's
nine will
automatically have everything
which is inside SIRC inside.
Then inside any text file
that is due.
Okay guys,
so this concept is clear to you right?
Okay, very good. Perfect.
So now we need to learn the next steps.
How to
navigate
to the folder where our Java project is.
We already know that.
I think we know.
No, no, no, no.
We don't need to spend time on it.
We learned it right.
The next step is how to create
our repository.
At that point
and then
how to store
and save our cool
in that repository.
And that's it.
Only two steps are left
and then we will be able
to store our goods inside that repository.
Okay, guys.
So this is what we will be covering
tomorrow.
Okay.
But we're not done yet.
We are not done yet.
Wait, wait.
Today, the last thing that we want to do
before we end the session.
No, just just 5 minutes.
We want we have one task at hand.
We still have 5 minutes, guys. 5 minutes?
Only 5 minutes. Yeah.
Just 57 will end after 5 minutes.
Okay,
so we still need to configure our target.
So first, when we install get,
we have done no configuring.
We have, you know,
we just install it.
We have not to tell the get that.
Who are we?
What is our email address, what is the
username password and stuff like that.
Right.
So we need to configure give
and tell is then what is our username
and what is our password?
We have to do this for that.
Also, we have commands
which you guys will only run once
when you install it.
You only need to run these commands
only once.
Okay. We will be right through them.
I guess it will take around 15 minutes,
so let's postpone it for tomorrow.
And I guess it's good to
leave the lecture at this point.
Okay.
I was just testing You guys
know I'll be sharing the coolness
with you.
I don't mind that.
And let me show you one thing.
I was telling you to not make notes.
Right.
So here's what I have for you guys, okay?
Everything that I have written
for even the less
next lectures, I have written everything
so you guys don't need to make notes
and stuff.
Okay, I'll be sharing
the whole workflow with you
and everything is going to be there.
I'll share these notes also.
And one thing that you have to do for me,
make sure that before
you come to the next class, revise
everything that we learned today
and, you know, try to practice
to open up your
terminals and navigate
where your project is.
So the homework shall be
open your terminal and
navigate to the folder
where your
Java basic
or any other
Java project is.
List down the contents
of the folder
and. Take screenshot
and post it and
students channel
number four
and the second homework.
Second homework.
I'm going to you a dot to
was to get the video
I will be sharing
some notes.
I'm going to just upload them
on the canvas right away.
A video is going to be available to
you guys
a little bit later,
but notes, I'll just put them on canvas.
Okay.
I'll be just sharing with you
these text knowledge for now.
The other ones
I'll share with you after class tomorrow.
Okay?
Because there is some stuff
that we still need to cover.
I don't want you to,
you know, mess up tense.
Okay, guys.
So I guess I'll see you tomorrow.
I hope that
today was a you guys enjoyed the class
and had fun.
Yeah.
Anyone who still wants to stay here and,
you know,
I'm just going to walk you through
the steps.
If someone missed that, I can repeat that
dressed as we won't be carrying anything.
You any recommendation for the videos
I should watch.
I'll be showing you the video.
I'll be sharing the videos with you.
Don't worry.
Okay? Okay, guys.
Good night, everyone,
and I'll see you tomorrow.
So, who was there all?