Yeah,
but not
again. I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Yeah, actually, I clicked on it.
It was like resume recording.
I just read it.
Got any idea about Dockers?
Okay,
no idea.
Okay, so let's first discuss the use case.
So Dockers in industry is usually used by
DevOps team.
They are the one who are responsible
for making the considerations
for helping you out
whenever you need to work with Dupuis.
Usually developers and testers,
they do not go in depth of Dockers
as it's a complete different domain.
The people who are responsible,
who are working with on cloud
and the people who are working on DevOps,
they are the people who are responsible
and they should be very much familiar
with this.
But as you know that today
in work environments, sometimes
you have to play a diversified Google.
So it's very good that if you have
some initial basic information
about what Docker is, how
you can utilize it and stuff like that.
So we will be going
just the basics regarding Docker
and we will do one example
and I will try to incorporate
some more example
if the things are not getting complicated
because trust me with doctors,
things can actually get very complicated.
But before that
I want to make sure that you,
all of you have Docker
installed in your system.
Were you able to install Docker?
Okay, perfect.
That's the price of Didn't
you guys get any error
by installing Docker?
Is it done?
I'm worried whether you install
the right thing or not.
That's
because it took me like half an hour to
resolve the errors that I had.
Okay,
So have you also included the doctors
in your environment that
Yeah, I'm
actually surprised.
Okay, so a simple test can be that
when you run Docker,
it should give you something like this
so quickly check
whether it's there or not.
And Docker dash dash version
is something
that you can also use for effect.
That's that's great.
Really.
Docker dash dash version.
It's going to show you the origin of the
that installed and you can also run Docker
which will list out all the commands
that you have for.
Yes, this one is great.
Perfect.
Yeah, that's the problem you like you add
automation engineer is not DevOps, right?
So now this can be tricky.
Okay, so let's take one example.
So let's suppose that
Mariam is working on Windows
and she has developed a testing script
for an application.
So that testing script requires
some dependencies.
You guys know about dependencies, right?
Whenever you are writing script,
you know that you
need to have some kinds of dependencies
that must be there.
For example,
it can become a testing unit of selenium,
chrome, web drivers, anything.
So now what happens
is that Maryam just finished her work
and she wants that
script to be tested by Fahad
that let's say,
and Fahad has
does not work on Windows.
He has, let's say Mac operating system
then Do you guys think that Fahad
will be able to run the script
that Maryam wrote
without any difficulties? So
no, he will not be able to run it
because the dependencies
for Mac and dependencies for Windows
are going to differ a lot.
So he will have to most readily
take just the basic code
and install all the dependencies
all over again and try to run that script.
But obviously he's not,
you know, a free person.
He has a lot of busy schedules,
so this can get actually very
difficult for him. So Dockers
is what helps
Maryam and Fahad run this script
without making any changes
and we are going to see how.
Okay, so what actually happens
we use in Docker Docker containers
and the container.
Let's see,
this one is the Docker container.
Let me just name it, Doctor Container.
So this Docker container
is going to include all the dependencies
that are required.
For example,
large Node.js let's say is required
and let's say Selenium is required
and the version is also something
that is important.
So let's say Selenium three is required
for this particular application and
the database that is required is MongoDB.
So these are some dependencies
that are required for this application.
And along with that,
let's add one more to
here is our actual script
and it can have like less attacks.
So what will Liam do?
She will use a container
and she will have all her dependencies
along with the script
that goes into the container and she will
then send
this particular container to her heart.
Fahadh is going to have another Docker
container
in his own system
and he is going to
then copy the container
that Maryam sent her
and basically he will just run that script
and it's going to work really fine
without making any changes.
So that's a basic, simple
use case of why and how Docker works is
there is a theater everyone.
Okay,
so this is going to help you out a lot
when you are actually working in your work
environments.
The different kind of environments
like one is working on
Mac, one is working on Windows.
And trust me with one thing, even if you
are working on the same operating system,
the difference in the
difference
in the versions of dependencies,
it can also affect the working
of your application.
So let's see if I'm a person
who is working on a system
on the same operating system.
He has Java version 1.7 installed
and you are using some different
Java version.
So he will not be able
to run your application.
So with the help of DRS,
he can easily run that.
So Docker is used to make the scripts
and to system independent.
Yes. So basically Docker
makes everything independent
and it's not dependent exactly on whatever
is installed in the system, but rather
whatever is being shipped to you.
Okay, so let's discuss how
it got the name Docker container.
So do you guys know that
what our dock was actually
those huge ships that you see at sea, at
the sea have never seen that
at the dock.
You call it the Docker
actually got its name from over there.
And as you can see on the symbol, it's
actually a big real fish
with some containers on.
So basically it's like a shipment.
So as the name suggests, dockers
and as the picture image suggests, use
for shipment.
Okay, So now the next thing that we will
discuss, Okay, let's get into a little bit
of looking
at how Docker works on your system
independently.
So you guys have an idea
of virtual machines right now.
You know what our situation is right?
So can somebody explain me
that what somebody does a machine
baked goods?
Is it the operating system?
Virtual machine is an operating system.
Emulates your system
binary code for individual system.
Yeah. Those enough?
Yes. The demo.
No, it's not definitely in the cloud.
That's not a condition.
Okay.
Let me tell you a vague definition
and then we can
go into the depths.
So this is my computer.
Okay,
so what does my computer actually have?
It has some kind of hardware, right?
And in this hardware, I have
CPU, I have RAM,
I have hard drive and, you know,
some other utilities.
Okay.
So now what happens is that
in here we have our operating system
installed at this layer
and then we have
a screen our monitor
where we actually see things that
are displayed to us and the follow up
graphical user interface.
So basically what our actions
we are performing on the screen,
they go to our OS
and our OS basically allocates
resources in RAM CPU
for that particular operation
and returns as the result.
And in terms of which, we can see
something happening on the screen.
So that's how our computer is working
right?
Okay.
So each operating system has upgrade now
you guys know
what's the kernel?
Okay.
So kernel is basically the essential
part of the operating system.
And this goal is it relies
between the hardware and the OS.
This is the main communication line
between
the hardware of the computer
and the operating system.
And then the operating system is actually,
you know,
displaying everything on the screen.
Okay.
So now when it comes to virtual machine,
let's say this is my computer
and I want to have a virtual machine
on this particular computer,
is it possible
for me to create a VM on it?
Okay.
Has anyone of you saw that saw
that computers that have two windows
installed like on the same system,
they have
Linux distribution and Windows
boot at the same time.
Okay.
So it's practically possible
that you can have on your Windows machine,
you can have one
operating system of windows running
and the other operating system
off of Linux running.
Or you can also have Mac and Windows.
This is quite possible.
So what actually happens
when you create a virtual machine?
You basically install another OS
and it's going to
and now your resources are being shared
between both the operating systems.
So you are actually sharing your hardware
resources
and running dual
operating system in parallel.
So now the important thing over here
is that these both ways are independent
of each other.
They do not rely on one another.
So let's say that you had
you have a task running on Linux.
It's not going to affect anything
installed or running on Windows.
So they both are completely independent.
So that's how actually
virtual machines are working.
Basically, they are utilizing
your hardware resources.
Okay, Is this clear?
Okay.
So Dockers is now something
which is very similar to
virtual machine.
It is very similar to a flow machine.
The only difference is
that Dockers is quite fast and light.
Then an actual VM y
because of its infrastructure.
Virtual machines usually have.
If you go into depth, let me show you.
Yeah, this
is the one.
So this is the infrastructure
of a container, whereas this one
is the infrastructure of virtual machines.
It has some both operating system and
hypervisor after that, some of the layers
and then you get to run the application,
whereas in containers
you have operating system and Docker
engine.
After that you can just with you
run your applications
and this Docker engine is very light.
What do I mean by light?
I like when I mentioned
that this is a lightweight
operating system or lightweight engine.
What does it mean, small loading
time? Yes.
And what else?
Fast. Okay, good.
So tell me, is Linux lightweight
or is Windows
lightweight?
No, it's not that much that your Mac
should be making noises. Yes.
Okay.
Linux is actually lightweight vibe
because as we discussed in our
classes, that any Linux distribution
we do not usually have
a graphical user interface, although we
can have a graphical user interface,
but usually command line is preferred
and that's the reason it's lightweight.
And apart from that,
it gives a lot of compute power
that is not being utilized,
but the resources can actually
utilize all that compute power
to run that application.
So whenever there is some words
that is lightweight,
so in sensitive application, it's
all this prefer to be run.
So on our servers,
usually Linux is being deployed
and not some kind of Windows or Mac OS.
Okay, so talking about Dockers, Dockers
is going to be simply just like our VM.
The only difference
is that it's lightweight.
Okay.
So I can now see that inside your Windows
operating system you have installed Docker
engine and if you remember
while installing you enable
the virtualization, right?
So virtualization is enabled
and you can create Docker
containers and each container
is going to be allocated
some resources from the hardware.
So it's just like a completely independent
space for your ports
to actually run.
Okay.
Is that really
perfect?
Now at seven, let's go for a break
right now and we'll be back.
It's break is on seven and 730.
Sorry, I forgot.
Okay, it sounds tidy. Okay, my bet.
Okay, Just give me 2 minutes.
I just have to, you know,
prepare for my fastest.
Give me 2 minutes and all of the back.
Okay?
Yeah, I'm just coming into minute.
Okay, So
let's continue.
Now, we understand that
what a Docker container.
The next thing that we'll be discussing
is a Docker
image.
So we already discussed about Amazon
machine image.
Docker image is just the same exact thing.
So I want you guys to tell me
what's the upper image
layers.
Oh yeah.
Blueprint screenshot.
Okay, so let's say you have an application
which has some requirements.
So this application let's say uses, as we
said, Selenium 3.0
and it has
Joe 1.8.
Okay.
So this is an application that we have.
So and Docker
image of this particular application
is going to be a file
with an extension of why
I'm using it. It's
going to be a viral file which is going to
contain all the information
of the dependencies, our
requirements
for running this particular application.
So it's going to contain some
wild information
in which we mentioned that
this particular image requires
Selenium 3.0.
Joe 1.8 MongoDB and Test NZ.
Okay, why do we need it?
We need it because whenever we want to run
this particular application
on our Docker container,
we are going to start that Docker
container by using this particular file
so that it is configured
with all the desired
configurations or dependencies
that we need.
Yes, Lord TB is actually getting famous,
but still
the other one is being used by
MongoDB.
It has a very nice actually interface.
It's very easy and user friendly.
Okay, so Docker
images, everyone care about Docker
images.
Okay, now let me show you some.
Okay.
Now what we are going to do basically in
because you need to just
understand two concepts that
what are containers and what are images?
The rest of the stuff is pretty
easy.
But again, we
will not be going into creation of images
because that is a complicated thing.
We will just
stick to
the simple things that Yeah, okay.
So far, let's say I give you a task.
I see that.
Hey, can you deploy selenium?
Great in Dockers?
Then what are you going to do?
Yes. For hot.
Okay, so you are going to say Docker
Selenium
three.
Okay.
So now the good news is that
selenium is maintaining
I app three four Docker images.
So you are going to get over here
a lot of Docker images,
like if you want to apply Selenium
bread into Docker,
you will get the image for that.
And if you want to have
a standalone system,
standalone Chrome, you will get,
you can also have an image for that.
So let me show you.
Now, creating an image for selenium grit
is going to be actually very difficult.
So they already have it on GitHub,
so you never need to achieve it,
you just need to
find that particular image.
Okay, so here is the link.
Let me share it with you guys
and let me show you
how the image actually looks.
Okay, So this is the image of Docker
compose file
and it contains all of the requirements
that it needs to download for selenium.
Great.
So version is three services.
It says that download file,
it mentions
then the image of that particular chrome
which needs to be download.
So it's going to go to selenium, it's
going to go to local
and it's going to download the Selenium.
This particular Selenium version.
Then it's going to
set up the environments, it's
going to set out the ports
that it requires to communicate.
And again, after that, it's also
getting the image for edge.
This is the image length.
From there it's going to download it
and these are some
environment settings
that it's making for Firefox.
It again has some leeway.
And so for
and yeah, the last one is the hub,
so it has some
image for hub and integration
of course also.
Okay. So
apart from that,
let me see what other images do
we have?
So you guys can either go to GitHub
and search
for a particular image
or you also have a document hub.
And in Docker Hub,
I think you do not need to.
Yeah, you do not need to sign it.
So if you go to Docker Hub,
let me share the link
for this to
that.
So in Docker Hub you have different
kind of images available
depending upon whatever you need.
You guys in have that image downloaded.
You already have installed three images.
Send the total Eastern shore
house environment
they were going to start from from this.
So get from the video. Okay, that's fine.
I actually did not follow that video, so
I don't
know whether downloaded data,
but that's fine.
Okay. So
let's say
if you want to have Ubuntu on your
Docker container,
you guys can have this particular image.
And what you need to do
is simply run the command Docker pool,
Ubuntu and it's going to start running of
this particular operating system
in that particular container.
And for Windows that see
you can, you guys can have Python,
you guys can have Mongo by
and you know a lot of
alienated
soft images that are even new to me.
So yeah.
Okay so that's how you, you guys can get
a pretty good image
and start working with it.
Okay so let's now
go to our next step
where we will discuss that,
how actually we can use selenium.
Not, not great because it is going
to be actually very difficult.
Let's go with an example where we actually
run our code into a selenium
Docker container.
So what are we going to do right now?
We will be writing down the test prep
and usually what happens
is that we have the chrome installed
on our windows, right?
So here is the Chrome browser
and here is our script
and we have Chrome driver
also configured along with it.
So Script uses Chrome Driver
to run our test cases on the Chrome
browser.
This is what usually happens, right?
The workflow.
Now what are we going to do?
We will be
creating a Docker container.
In that particular container, we will be
launching a Chrome browser
with a Chrome driver
and we will be writing down
our test strips on our computer.
Now we are going to run our test cases
inside the Docker container.
Okay.
Can you just tell me the advantage
of this particular
technique?
You do not need to download dependencies,
but right now
you will have to download the dependencies
because you are writing down
the selenium code and script etc.
inside your
computer.
Right.
We are just in Docker containers.
We just have the chrome instance
we launched.
Okay.
So the purpose and the advantage
of this technique is that let's say
you have an application and you want to
test it for different version of Chrome.
So let's say
you want to test it for version 3.8,
version 3.2,
version 3.5.
You need to
test your application
for these three versions of growth.
Do you think that doing this
in your own machine
without the Docker images is going to
be easier?
Like, how would you do it
if you if you do not know about
how the new tested forward
and see point 80.2 and 3.5
but well this one is
simple.
Exactly.
You will simply uninstall your chrome
downgrade to a previous version 3.8.
Let's say install this driver and,
you know, run the script.
Then you will uninstall it or downgrade
to three point to run the scripts.
Then you will uninstall again, go to 2.5
and test your script.
So you see it's going to be quite hectic,
will consume a lot of time
and doing this one
by one is going to be very hectic.
So in order to help you out with this
problem,
Docker containers play a very vital role.
What you can have when you are installing
this particular chrome instance,
you guys can control
all that which version of Chrome browser
you are actually trying to install
in this particular container.
So you can either have warranty one day
once you are done with volume 3.8,
you guys simply with one command
can stop this particular conversion
and start a different version.
Let 60.2.
Once your tests are completed on this,
then you can start testing on 3.5
with just a single command.
Or you can also do one more thing.
You can have separate containers like 1
to 3 for containers, each
running a different version
of Chrome instance. And
you can run your code
in all different versions of call
and test it.
Yes, exactly.
Mohammed That's why they use DRS.
Okay, So now I'm going to also
give you a brief introduction regarding
setting in grid and setting it up.
So a selenium grid
has some basic components.
What are those basic components?
I believe that you guys have studied
about Selenium in the introduction
and obviously in interview preparation,
you guys would have
gone through that, right?
So what are the basic components
of selenium with
simultaneous automation
components, not talking about advantages
of using selenium, with
Okay,
so a selenium grid comprises of nodes
and hub, right?
So a selenium grid
will have a node
and top.
You know,
you did not learn trade actually,
but I am sure that you guys were
taught a little bit
about what are selenium grid.
I will, I taught to selenium right.
Okay. Yeah.
I am sure that I gave you
an introduction to these.
If not, then you guys can sue me for that.
Okay.
Well, did I say any more
than two sentences right now
nodes have all taken Hamlet.
Thank you for having my back.
It is
like salmon was just fade out of that.
No, you never mentioned it.
Okay, so at least even if you do not know
in depth talk that how a synonym grade
actually works, which you will
by the end of today's session at least.
And I believe that I also mentioned it
in the of this classes
but you at least you should know
that whenever someone asks you that what's
a synonym grade?
You should know that it has a hub
and it's a structure of performance.
Okay, So I'm going to explain it again,
that how it actually works.
Just to give you guys an idea, I'm
not sure whether we will be able to run
some codes into that and we do not.
But I am sure of one thing
that if any one of you after this
class wants to work on selenium grade
and run some test cases,
you guys will be
and should be able to do that.
Oh, I'll share a link
just after the class.
When you get some time,
try to practice over there and write.
Write down some food
and run your tests in parallel.
It's nothing new.
Everything you guys have been
taught is going to be there.
Only one thing is going to be different
that out I'll be mentioning.
Okay, so in Selenium, great.
We have a hub.
Let's say this is our hub
and we have different nodes
and let's say
this is our script.
Okay?
So one of the purpose of selenium great.
And the advantages that we discussed
was that it can run
test cases in parallel right?
It can test your test cases on different
browsers.
In parallel
are the same browsers in parallel.
So let me call it Hub,
Let me call
this node.
How many nodes does
this selenium grid has?
It has three nodes.
How many hub does it have
got it?
How can there be more than one hub?
Okay,
let me first extend the functionality
and then I'll ask this question again.
So what's the purpose of up?
So let's say that on this particular node
you are using coal.
On this particular one,
you have the instance of Firefox
and on this particular node
you have the instance of edge running.
So basically all the nodes have some
instance of browser installed.
This is your hub and this is the script.
So script is going to go to the hub,
and hub
is now going to distribute the test cases
to particular nodes.
So basically what it's doing, it's running
your Sam's Prep in parallel
on Chrome, on Firefox and on edge.
So that's
how parallel testing is working
when you are using
Selenium grit, you do not need to know
how actually Hub is functioning
or how actually the node is working.
You do not need to actually get
in depth of that.
That's the part of the architecture.
Okay,
so now
you can see that hub,
this kind of something like that, it
actually distributes
the test cases between different nodes.
Okay.
Now setting up a selenium grid,
configuring it into your system is again
going to take a lot of time.
Whereas if you use dollars
just two commands.
So if I asked you to set up
a selenium grid
using dollars, where are you going to do
exactly?
You would go to this image.
So we have this particular
image off Docker Selenium for
star selenium grid, and
you guys can see that by default
it has grown
edge Firefox images and one hub.
So what is a Firefox image?
It's actually unknown Selenium
slash node, dash, Firefox
and after that
the particular version of that Firefox
similarly adds selenium slash node edge
and the particular version
of that edge browser.
And for Chrome,
also selenium slash node pool
and the particular version of that Chrome.
And then in the last we have Selenium hub,
the image of hub is going to be downloaded
and this hub is going to be interacting
with all the nodes.
Okay.
Now one of the very interesting things
when we are working
with selenium,
if you are using Dockers to run this,
how many containers are going to be there
when you download this thing?
And great image?
Is this an individual image?
Okay.
So actually in case of selenium Grid
Hub is going to be in container,
it is going to be in a separate container.
This node
is going to be in a separate container
and this particular node is going to be
in a separate container to isolate,
to isolate their working from the hub
so that they are not at all
dependent on each other.
So one of the very big advantage of using
this technique is that
how do I get rid of this,
let's say in runtime?
So you just got
you just want to, let's say, test
your script on five
or let's say three Firefox browsers.
What you are going to do
is you will simply use one simple command
Docker scale up Firefox X,
and you need to mention the number
of instance that you want to scale up.
So let's
say you want three instance of Firefox.
It's going to create three different
containers,
each having
Firefox
and they will also become now apart off
great
and your test cases
will also start running on
these newly created
instance of Firefox.
Okay, so 730 let's go for a break
and then we'll be back at eight.
Why the redundancy
of using the same browser to dance moment?
Because there can be a scenario
where you need to test it on, let's say
version three of Firefox and version two
or Firefox and Virgin
one or Firefox.
Okay guys, I'll see you at eight.
Okay.
So I hope that you guys are back to
and we can proceed on with our
next example.
Okay, perfect.
So we have discussed up till now
that what are the containers, What is
Docker image, how we can
use Dockers to deploy selenium bread.
We also discussed about
standalone com instance that we can use
to deploy our selenium scripts.
Okay.
So this is like the basic applications
that we are discussing
when it comes to testing,
but whenever you are working in a company,
Dockers will see Dockers implement it
very badly in a lot of applications.
Their people need to ship
their applications to a system where
they want to run them in an environment.
So that system is not actually
part of the problem, that it's running
independently from everything else.
If you want to run like this is how
actually dockers are used in the industry.
So one of the very good example of Dockers
in industry, let me give you that
quickly before we
actually jump into the example.
So I have witnessed this myself
that there were three applications
actually which were running
one of the computers that I was using
and each had each application
required
different
set of dependencies.
And the major issue was that
let's say app one.
So this one required Node two
and this one was requiring Node three
and this definition required 0.8.
So no matter
if there were different
versions of the node, still
they were able to run in the same computer
in the different containers.
So that's just again, one quick example
of how doctors are use in the industry.
Okay, Now what are we going to do?
We will be doing a very smart example,
I guess, and after that
our class is going to be almost over
because
running Docker,
I guess we have covered almost
all the basic stuff.
So now what we need to do is
we will be actually
implementing this particular scenario
that we discussed.
We will be launching a clone instance
in a Docker container
and we will be writing down
a solutions script.
We will be running our test cases
on this particular container.
Okay.
So as we all have
doctors installed,
it's not going to be a problem.
So if you open up
your Docker desktop application
and go to your images,
you will see something like this.
For me, it's selenium
standalone form and I have two images
of basically selenium status,
but you may have some other images.
What I want you to do right now is
remove the images that you have.
I'll keep this one
because I want to use this.
I want you to delete
the images that you have
and continue along with me.
If you go to containers, let me see.
This one is already running.
I don't want it to run right now,
so I'll just also delete
this one.
In fact, let me check.
Do I want to one?
Okay, so I'll keep it running
because I actually want it running.
But I believe that
you guys do not have this one.
So delete everything, right? No. Whatever.
You have images of containers
and let me know.
So I'll just share the updated
containers, images that
you need. Okay.
So the first step is going to be
to pull these standalone code
instance image into our Docker
and get that Docker container
running.
Okay, this error is appearing
when you are trying to bleed this.
Okay, it's fine. Just don't delete it.
No worries, it won't be a problem.
Okay.
So I will just share the command with you
guys.
Let me find it.
Was I guess this is the one.
Okay.
There you go.
So, yeah, yeah,
especially for me, because a lot of folks
are doing the system.
Okay, so
this particular command there,
are you going to run it?
Let me show first.
So you open up
your command from Git terminal.
If you are on windows,
you can use command prompt.
If you are on Mac, you can use terminal
and first run docker dash dash version.
Make sure the version is there.
If it is, then
the next step that you are going to do
is run this particular command run
dash dash de
for four, four, four
and then Selenium standalone
column 3.1415920210647.
Just hit enter
and this command is going to run.
Okay.
For me it says that error because
it's already running
so it's not going to run for me.
But I suppose that it will start
downloading some stuff for you
and will start showing you progress
that is downloading.
Yeah, something like this.
Okay, good.
So we'll complete
good. Awesome.
I guess it's done for you,
the rest of you.
Do you have the same output
sweating? Yeah.
It will take some time for some people.
For some it will work quickly,
depending upon your internet connection.
So it's going to vary.
Okay, So now what have we done
actually in this command?
We this is the link to this Selenium
standalone code
container image.
Okay.
When I say standalone, I mean that
it is not a part of some grid,
it's just an individual
Chrome browser.
So selenium slash standalone
dash Chrome and along with that for
and this is the link
to the image of that particular container
which we want to launch.
Okay, Docker run
Docker is the command
which is used to run the container.
Okay.
And now Dash B is actually
going to allocate it some port number.
So we are allocating the ports
that for to this particular container
and this is the size of the container
that we want to have.
So this is basically
that we are allocating the hardware
resource, our memory
to this particular container.
So I have allocated over here to G, B
You can also change the size
if we want to, but I guess right now
this one is sufficient enough.
Okay.
So after downloading
this particular image, it's
going to run a container building
that container upon this image
and it will have a code
instance running.
Okay, let's do one thing now.
Open up your Docker desktop
and you will see something
like if you go to container images,
you'll see something like this
standalone file, are you able to see it?
Okay. Okay.
Now this is the image
that has been downloaded.
So image is just a file we.
Do not actually we now need it.
We can if you want to.
We can delete it too.
But if you delete it, I believe that
container will not be able to sustain.
But we are not going to be actually
working on this particular image.
Let me see.
This is container, not image.
Then you need to click on images
and then it will take you here.
So this is the
way from here.
You can see the images that you have.
Okay, Now go to container apps.
There you'll see
something like this.
Heisenberg's Selenium standalone.
Do you see something like this?
Okay.
Mohammad Z, your yours is the best one.
Romantic tools
and that's fine.
The name scanner
you need to click on Containers
Containers app.
Okay.
The only thing is
that the port should be that upper.
Okay, now click on this particular sign
open in browser.
When you click on this,
do you see something like
this opened up in front of you?
Okay,
so now it's meant this is a place
where you can actually connect
to your chrome that is being launched
inside the container and you can just have
a basic visualization of it.
You will not be able to see it in
detail, but, you know, just
a small visualization of it.
So if you want to see if any thing
has been running on this particular
Chrome instance region,
we can simply click on console over here.
Okay.
So right now when I click on console,
do I see any sessions?
There is no session running
because we have not yet run any script
that engages this call and run some tests.
It I can click on refresh.
The result is going to be the same.
Okay, let's minimize.
Okay, Now I want you guys to open up your
intelligence, open up our MAVEN project.
A new MAVEN project is going to work
pretty fine.
Have you open up the projects?
Okay, now
what I'm going to do
is the boundary symbol.
Do you have this file already,
or do you want me to share it with you?
Do you have this boundary item?
Okay, perfect.
Okay.
Someone would share this in the comment
if anyone wants to have it,
copy this from book X and load
from the comment off the command
that I did
under custom it.
This is your java.
I don't need it, so I need it.
Okay. So this is my
I have created a class called test
and over here I have written down
some food out the
giving you this code
in the chat.
Okay.
Let me know once you have this ready.
Okay. Have you.
Have you guys prepared this file?
Okay.
Do you guys know what is called,
like the fourth grade?
Should be.
Is it the port for
selenium bread is like that apple.
So do you guys know what support? No.
The question marks.
Okay, let me just let you define it.
Okay.
So we all know that we have in our network
an IP address, right?
Okay.
So where our traffic needs to come into
this network
should flow to this particular IP address.
That's it's .1.1. So
whatever Internet traffic is coming,
whatever is coming to
the network is flowing inside the computer
to this particular IP address.
Now, this is not some
physical division, rather it's again,
just some logical division.
Further after the IP address,
the network is divided
into ports. So
this is
okay.
Now, this is our computer.
Let's US CPU or any other network
card, maybe
it's also inside the computer.
Now, whenever it wants to
look at some information and some data,
what it does
is it's looking for some information.
It is going to go to port number 80
and it will get the data.
If it needs to go
look for something related to Brett,
it will go to the division, that dropper
and it will look that particular data.
The advantage of doing this for division
is that if there are no codes,
then all the data has is like letter
and the network card or CPU,
whatever is responsible
for bringing you the information.
It will have to look into all the network
information that is there.
It will have to look from HTP to SMP.
Then again, some other information that
is there until it finds its desired one.
But with the division of ports,
it already knows that.
Okay, if I'm going to be looking for
a CTP
that I just need to go to port number 80,
if I will be looking for something
regarding this thing in red.
I just need to go to look at that.
Jeff So now I believe that to understand
that when we mentioned the port over here,
we are actually mentioning the division
in how our network
has been Division.
Okay, Now let me open up
the code for you guys, Okay?
Yeah, here we go. So
in this particular example,
we are not using any
any chrome driver, our browser
that is located on this particular
machine.
Rather, we are using the driver
and browser
that are located in the container.
So we do not need to set up
our drivers actions
in selenium whenever we have deal with
some of some driver
that is not actually on the machine.
We use remote web driver.
So if you want to initiate instance,
we will say
try local remote where private driver
is exposed to new track local.
So we are basically just creating
a new thread for us.
Driver
Okay, now
we have to tell
our driver that oh sorry,
we have to tell our selenium
that we're that driver, this remote.
That driver is actually looking at it.
So our remote work
driver is located on the local host.
Therefore what does it mean by localhost?
It means that same particular machine
that I'm working on.
So let's say if I want to run the script
on some kind of server
that is not like in the same building,
or maybe it's not on the same machine,
I'll just give the IP address
of that particular server over here
and it's going to actually run the script
on that server in real time.
So right now we are using local course
because we are running
container on the same machine.
The port number is tetra for VI,
because when we ran the container
we mentioned that the port to be used.
Is that proper?
Let me show you the command.
Here is the place
where we are actually giving the force
to be used by this particular container.
Okay.
So after that, what we are doing, we are
calling out
chrome options equals
the new chrome options.
Driver dot set.
At this point we are saying that
you are sending that remote that driver
along with they
you are so replacing in the remote URL
for the chrome
which is this particular one.
And then
we are navigating to google.com,
we are getting the title
and printing it out on the screen.
Okay, So now let's do one thing.
We can run this script
through command to terminal.
Also using the MAVEN test.
I believe that you guys already know that,
but unfortunately
I do not have that setup,
so I was just running it from over here.
It works the same way.
No difference.
And that's the only thing
that I want to show you
before I do
this is I'm going to refresh it right now.
No sessions are there?
No. I'll just simply run this
particular script that I have written.
Simple, simple script, which.
Okay, after running it,
I'll simply refresh the session
and you guys can see that a session
just appeared over here.
A new session has been created
for this particular script
and I got the output google.com
and there was no browser actually launched
into my system, but the browser actually
launched inside the container
that you just created.
How are you guys able to run it
for your
issue? Yes,
your issue is because of the fact that
your chrome driver
and version do not match.
You can do one thing more.
Just make sure that you
delete the darker
that image that you have and get get it.
Get it again. The same one. Okay.
This error should not be there
because I was also facing the same error
and problem was that
I did not have the correct image.
So I'm going to share the image again.
And you guys, you can try it out.
So Docker Docker is another headless
process.
In this particular example,
we are using it as a headless
HD browser,
but Docker is not actually that.
Okay.
However, in this particular example,
it's being utilized in this scenario.
But actually the purpose of Doppler is,
as I mentioned, to have
standalone independent
processor running on it.
So this particular Chrome
that we are running on, it is independent,
not affected by my system.
You guys know that on my system,
the chrome driver that the chrome
that I have installed
is let's say which version is that.
It's the latest one,
but that the one that I'm actually
testing on right now
is 3.141 on your systems.
Also, there is a different one
that is installed.
But right now
we are testing our application on
previous version.
The older one. Okay.
What about the rest of you? Is it working
if you guys did?
Okay, any questions?
So This point?
Shh, shh.
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh,
shh, shh.
No, Mohammed, even if your room is different on your system, it should not affect.
Because are
running our test script in the doctor's
right now.
So if it's not running,
it means that you downloaded
the wrong image for school.
Or maybe on that food,
something else is already running.
So what you need to do is stop
all of the containers, delete them
and after that try to
re initiate the process.
Okay, So
over here we see that
we have different chrome
standalone Chrome versions available.
It's just so every time you perform
the task,
you have to leave
the content that you're in for
No logo.
Now let's see if this one is done.
And we have tested it because, you know,
I would not have actually written
any test script over here,
but I can write down the pool desperate.
If you guys have any desperate
written, you can share with me
and I can show you how I can run it.
So if I want to run it again,
I can run this in the same container.
Once again,
let me show you.
Now, there are two instances
of the same container created.
This is the container
already that we have.
And we can always, you know, run
multiple description
the same one if we want to.
If not, we can create a new container.
Okay.
Do you guys have any script
which might be, you know,
a longer script than this one.
I believe that you may have.
I think I would have to go
very deep in the system to find it.
So if anyone can share some discussions
with me, not on multiple files,
but on a single file from some selenium,
that would be appropriate. It
is. Okay, so let's do one thing.
I have not experimented it before,
but I think we can do this right now.
What if I do thread dot
sleep and I give it a pause
for like, how many seconds is that?
10 seconds.
Mohammad, I'll try to help you
out of the blocks because.
I'm not sure
if you use the correct amount.
It should have worked.
Okay, guys, so this is 10 seconds, right?
And let's do one thing.
Let's run another container.
Let's try it.
Run under the container on port number
four for two, four, four, two.
Let's try this.
Let me open up the containers now.
Okay, So I just ran
the same command
and I changed the port number.
So you guys can also do the same thing.
Just change the port for four, four, two
and you'll see Docker
container running on this port.
If you open this decent browser,
it's always running.
But no, it's not getting me
some information.
I think I now understand why.
Let me just delete this one.
Let's try
this.
Okay. So we cannot do this.
Unfortunately, what I was trying to do,
what I was trying to do,
I was trying to launch
and others Selenium
standalone Chrome on same port.
But I believe that we cannot change
the port numbers like this,
they should be find it
behind the scenes in the that same way.
So I think in order to do this,
let me see.
Okay let's know
open up a new one.
Still did not work, Mohammed.
Let's see it after that. That's
how we
can do with different browsers
for different browsers.
Let me let me show you.
Okay. So
I think this is the command that will
get us
the image for Firefox.
So it's going to take some time
to download the image.
Okay.
So it's going to take some time
to download while it downloads.
Let's discuss some more stuff.
One it once it is downloaded,
we can simply go ahead and
try this out.
Okay.
Let me now
just show you how we can set up it.
But it's going to also happen once.
This download is complete.
Okay, let's
wait for this download to complete.
And meanwhile,
do you guys have any questions
or any confusions regarding the stuff
that we have discussed far?
Let me know.
I can answer you up queries.
And meanwhile, no questions.
So next time I have a task on Docker
and I rely on
you guys to help me out,
I should not have any questions.
I knew that to understand. Right.
Okay. Mohammed, apart from Mohammed.
Okay.
Asked him, is there.
Yes, ma'am.
This new image is for now Firefox.
Just just read it.
What does it say? It says that Docker run
port number 4445
size 2G, G, Selenium standalone Firefox.
With this version. So nice download it.
Let's see in my docker
containers.
Do I have any firefox
instance?
Yes, it's there.
So. Okay.
So we are also going
to open up the console for that.
No sessions are there right now.
Okay. Now let's do one thing.
Let's quickly
create a new project.
Let's not change this one.
Instead Create a new million project
limit.
Why don't you try with the Firefox one?
Maybe this is going to work for you.
Okay.
Test two new window.
No, I start working
your issue.
Let me tell you what.
So if you your issue is
only the incompatibility between the web
stream, between the chrome driver
and the Chrome browser
that you have installed inside the Docker,
the issue is nowhere else.
This is the only issue that you have
how to get rid of it.
The only solution is to download
the correct image, but as you have
the correct image already, so
I think that we will have to take a look
ourself in that.
Okay, So I'm going to copy
the same code that we have over here.
I'm going to copy this now.
Let me copy this.
All shampooed
and paste it in here for test. Do
I believe that
the did
I miss something
more?
That driver.
Oh, I need to reload
dependency me
Yeah, it's not good.
Okay.
So what will be the changes?
Should I make some changes in my remote?
You are? Yes.
I need to change my port number
from 2 to 4 to 4 to 5.
It's going to be Firefox. It's
and this is not
going to change easily. Yes.
The rest of the stuff is going to be,
I believe, from industry.
Okay, let's run this and have a look up on
both of five.
Okay. Got it.
They got it over here.
So it's working on it also.
Okay, now let's do one thing.
Let's try to do both the browsers
in parallel.
So we have to wait in both of them.
So I believe that it's going to work.
Okay.
So then Stencil is created over here
also and over here also.
So right now I'm testing on both of the
both of the code
but both of the drivers in parallel.
But the only problem here is
that it's not actually parallel
because I'm using two different scripts
for this purpose, not the same script.
Okay, So it's not an actual parallel,
rather, I am just,
you know, finding my way around the
in order to be able
to test parallel
a script should be the same.
Having different scripts is
not good enough.
Okay,
so is this clear to everyone
what we have discussed until this point?
Guys, if you have any questions
or concerns regarding Dockers, go ahead.
Be open about it.
Okay. Perfect.
Mohammed, I told you
the only problem will be with the version.
That's it.
It should be working to it.
We were just restarting your system.
Unplug the power cables.
You know, insert it again
and maybe it will help you out
from there.
You know, the first solution,
the most working, ineffective solution.
How can we open like five Chrome browser
at the same time?
Okay,
so if you want to open up the five browser
at the same time, you just need to do one.
I believe
I was
trying to do that, but unfortunately.
Okay, so
let's try this.
the local host is actually not
responding in this situation.
Let me see.
It should be responding.
This is Yes,
yes. This is the one that I entered
for four, five or six.
But localhost is not responding
to this machine.
Was it not responding this
for particular port number?
Maybe it's being used for other
data transfer.
Okay. I
okay. So
the problem over here,
when I'm trying to launch
and then the chrome instance
on a different port number
because obviously
if I want to launch another container,
I cannot launch it on the same port
because it's already
been assigned
to one of the Chrome instance.
But when I tried to launch it,
let me show you
where it start.
Okay.
This that proper table for five.
When I tried to launch it on this one,
it's not going to actually run it. Why?
Because in this image
be behind the scenes
when I'm doing the command should be.
Although I mentioned the port but
behind it the when the image is created
the port range is also defined
in that image.
So when I tried to run that on a different
port number, it gives me an error.
Although it starts running it,
you guys can see over here what I did
the before six and if show you dockers
X running this image on top of four six
but I'm unable to see anything
when I bring this up because the port
that is hardcoded inside that image
which communicates with my
of this particular chrome in order
to bring this, the response is different.
So right now 4446 is trying to communicate
with 444 or five you do,
which I'm not getting a response.
So in order to be able to do
this, we need to make some changes inside
that Docker file.
Also Docker image, which is what somewhat,
you know, at one step.
So we will not be dealing with that.
But let me show you
how it's working in the case are
great do guys get the reason that why
why are we unable to actually launch
another instance of chrome?
You guys get the result.
Do you want me to explain again?
Okay, so just
just mention it.
You know, I will always explain again. No.
Okay, so should I.
I'll start from the very beginning or.
Should I just explain that this problem
and I'm
going to explain the whole process.
Okay, guys, just stay with me.
I'll be explaining the whole process.
Okay? So.
So when I see a selenium image
of a standalone
Chrome instance,
it means that there is going to be
configuration files
that it needs to download in order
to establish a container,
in order to establish a container
which has
a Chrome browser
and a Chrome driver.
Is this clear to everyone?
Okay, now
this selenium image is going to be
most probably some file
which contains
all the necessary installations
that need to be met right.
Okay.
Now, behind these installations,
when they are being done,
there is going to be
some kind of coding involved.
Do you guys agree with that?
There's going to be a code behind
that which will be actually generating
this container
on inside of it.
Right.
Okay.
Now, when I picked up this image
and I run this image
and I say, okay, run the container, it
actually what happens, it
creates a container
logical insert instance.
And along with
that launch is a driver. Now
it's this is our web page on a computer
and we want to have
a, you know, just a vague
data of whatever is happening
inside this particular Chrome browser
or whatever is happening inside this
sorry, not browser, whatever is happening
inside this container.
Right.
You want to have this information, but
this screen
is showing us whether is happening
inside the container, Right.
So you guys can imagine
that there is a port.
So there is a port in this container
which we connect
to the website, our Chrome browser,
and it tells us everything on the screen
that was actually happening.
So just like localhost for for five.
So I'm telling that
if we connect to this particular port
now, this port
when we run the container and the
when we download the image
and run this container,
this particular board is being fed
some data
and it's hardcoded inside the image
that what's the port number.
So let's say the port number for Chrome
is that graph for
right now
when we run the image,
we tell that on this port in our system,
do you have to run the image?
So now we are changing the
and are saying run
the image on port number,
this one.
So whenever we connect,
try to connect to it,
it's going to go to four four, four,
five and see for some data over there.
But do we have any data coming on 444
or five?
No. So that's the reason that we are
unable to see anything, how to change it,
how to be able to
look at some data,
how to be able to actually work with this.
I'll tell you the way
you need to go inside selenium
image
and change the configurations over there.
Okay.
But I believe that
that is actually something at once
and you will not be dealing with that.
But I can show you some configurations
how they are actually being done.
So we were discussing before
about setting in grid, right?
So let me show you over here
not to make sense to all of you
dockers,
those who I am over
here.
Now, do you see that inside Selenium hub,
It's allocating the port
like the port and further selenium.
How best to do that graph.
Now it has allocated it inside
the image, the whole port range.
Now if we are running anything over here,
we will be able to run
and scale up our instance very easily
because we have defined the whole range
and allocated it
inside the image.
Yeah, and remember one thing,
this is
I think, something that can be asked to
you guys
that what is the port for Selenium
image.
So remember that it's actually tetra for,
but the range for Selenium
great is too big for to do that.
Okay.
Now what we are going to do let you see.
So we might be asked
what is the port option in grid.
Yeah, you can be asked
that like you should know, it's
just like
you should know the port for HTP.
It's 80.
So if you said to
someone I have word on selenium grid,
if you say that, if you claimed that
then you should know that
the range is usually triple
4 to 2 tetra for.
Okay.
So after this example, I'm going to show
you just how to test
only selenium library too, for a moment.
Well, well can see that
I know what's the selenium grade,
but I have never actually worked on it, so
that's a better way of putting it forward.
Okay.
So let me just quickly show you a document
and some examples
how we can work with selenium grade.
Whenever you have some free
it three times, just make sure
that you practice it
using it and using dockers.
I'm going to help you out to run selenium
grid on your system.
Using Docker lets you just find
the correct commands for that
and I'll be showing them
you see,
where did that one go? So
okay, so
the first command that we will be running,
I want you guys to open up your
commands, run and type in Docker.
Well, Selenium.
Oh, it's just
now so there's a slash between this
second command is dark purple
and selenium.
So node slash role
that it's
okay.
So what do you think it's doing?
It's actually
downloading this Selenium hub
Docker image
because
you can see that we are pulling,
we are saying,
Hey, Docker, pull the Selenium.
No selenium hub image.
And then we are saying, well, selenium
node, cool.
And then we are going to say
pulled selenium node,
Firefox
slash, Okay.
And run this command.
My I guess my internet is pretty slow
and you Google them up.
That's how you get them.
Yes, exactly.
You lose that command to download
or command
to full selenium pass to full
selenium node
and like, okay,
so the next command that you need to run.
So for those of you who have successfully
done this, what do you need to do next?
You need to run this particular command
Docker, run dash D, slash
B, So in the M hub.
So this is going to actually run,
start running the Container Stadium hub.
So first of all, we downloaded the image,
now we are
running that container.
So what they are
is it's mostly
like, okay, support is already allocated.
Yeah.
So this is because that's what it has
some on potential for.
There's already something running right?
So you need to and everything else
so you get the next command
that you need to run is this one.
So you are not not, not
this one is the wrong command.
Sorry, I just copied it, but unfortunately
it did not copy.
This command is
going to actually link your
it's going to run your selenium
node and then link it with hub six.
And this one is to run the Firefox
and link link and with the help
that let me know
once you guys have run this,
these commands it's
first they are
the reverse run
the selenium hub.
I seem to underscore man
the one that I mentioned names
setting them up So you slash
how did you run this.
Okay.
Zuma What the error.
Okay, maybe call it an IP.
No, Why should we go out night
Okay, so, well,
we just need to correct our commands.
Let me find new command
because it's just about,
you know, launching the Selenium hub.
It's not that difficult
and it's some problem with the commands.
Let's fix them and
after that, I'll show you some
something about Selenium. Great.
And then we can call it the night.
Okay, let me see.
Selenium is.
Are you having the same problem?
Okay, let's do it from GitHub
hubs and nodes.
We can try these commands.
Okay, so I'm going to share the link.
So for Mac users,
you guys are going to follow
these set of command and for Windows users
to be following these commands,
let's try them on.
Okay. But before you do that,
just make sure of one thing.
You do need any containers you have.
Okay, Delete any containers
of it.
This one ran for me.
Now let's check the other one.
Okay. So it's going to do take some time
and download it.
So these command
are most probably going to run.
And once you have random all, most probably your grid is going to be there. So
after
that you are just to go to the
you are a little confused
and let me tell you the world
that you need to visit.
Which one is that?
Let show it to you.
Once your grid is up and running,
then you need to visit this particular
you are okay.
So after running all these commands,
click on this local stack upgrade console.
There you see that you're at one place,
your Firefox browser be accomplished,
your Chrome browser will be.
And if you want to
scale up your own browser,
if you want to scale up your Firefox
browser, the command to do that is
let me see the command to do that is
Firefox
still up?
Okay, so this is the command
to add more containers.
So. Okay.
Now let me show you what will happen
once you have everything set up.
Meanwhile,
it can continue running in the background.
Let's go ahead with the next command. Just
see. Okay.
That downloading for me.
The other one. Okay.
So just make sure one thing.
If you are using windows, then
most probably this command is redundant.
Motions is not going to work.
So you have to make it one liner
and for that you need to delete this
this symbol
in order to make it one liner
and then try to run it.
So right now
you are installing Selenium Hub
along with our, for instance,
and then we'll be running one for
Firefox. That's it.
I'm not going to be running
for the edge one.
So after that
the grid is going to be complete.
Okay, So now
let me share the website with you guys.
We is going to come very handy for you.
Okay.
So, okay, this is
how it's going to look like
when you visit your console.
You will have one instance
or multiple instance of
chrome or Firefox right now.
One, two, three, four, cool.
And two Firefox are running.
You guys can scale them more
if you want to.
Okay.
So after that, the main thing is the code
that we will be discussing.
So here is the code given
for this particular
task is the only thing
that is going to be different
when you are writing than the code
for selenium.
Grid is going to be
the portion where you said
the remote that driver is.
So if I show you
the rest of the code is going to be
just exactly the same.
And over here
what they are doing is let's see the class
name.
Okay,
we are setting the driver local host.
This time is stacked up here.
Can someone tell me that?
Why is it tetra for this time?
Whereas the Chrome and Firefox
are running on different port numbers,
The chrome is running on.
Let's see, the chrome is running on
Firefox
by 901,
whereas boom is five nine that will zero.
Then why are we giving tetra
four over here?
It's local. Yes.
You mean that
that is defined by local host, right.
I'm talking about the port number that is.
Why are we giving tetra four?
We are giving tetra four
because this is the port number of the
selenium hub.
Right.
Because our hub is on the port number.
Tetra four.
Let me show you
if you see that
your hub is on death row four,
whereas your other instances
are on 59015900.
So you are going to disconnect to the hub
four now.
Okay, Then
you will be writing down your browsers
for Firefox, for Chrome and that's it.
So else
that you will be needing to change,
I believe.
No. Okay, I'm going to share this thing.
Just go through it and try to do this
example of selenium grid.
In this you can this in parallel.
Even if you are unable
to complete this one, it's
that's totally fine.
My system is still waiting
for the download to complete.
If you have on your system,
if everything is done, let me know
so that we can
double check that.
If everything is running up tomorrow
or something.
Okay, So guys,
do you have any other questions regarding
whatever we have covered till this?
Fine.
As you see right now, I have one
on my selenium grid,
one instance of chrome running
and it slides.
Yes, I have the slides
and the notes assured
assured them
but you guys are on the canvas.
Okay, so don't worry about it.
Just make sure that regarding Dockers
you understand what is Dockers?
Why do we need and when our Docker images
you understand that
and you have an idea
that if you want to set up a you know
and you want to set up a Docker container
using an image, how can you do that?
So simply, if I asked you that,
can you create a darker image
that has a standalone fire
for a Firefox instance.
Can you do that?
Okay.
And if I ask you guys to run
some test cases
in that particular container,
that Firefox container will be able to do
okay,
So only Mohammad will be able to do that
and the rest of the people
will not be able to do that right.
Eleni is saying yes, you are right.
Absolutely right.
You have to review it like this
one was simple, right?
Everything was so, so simple.
At least maybe.
Maybe
I'm saying that because it was simple for.
Me and for you guys,
it was complicated, right?
So tell me which client was complicated.
Quickly.
Tell me,
because then I'm going to end the session.
I want to know,
which point did you not understand?
Maryam, You are one of one third
of a girl, so that's not a problem for us.
I don't know.
How do I want?
Oh, okay.
So, Eleni, your is.
You are not entering the commands
correctly.
I'll have to help you with that,
I believe command not found.
It says because.
Because, because. Because
syntax error
Docker compose scale 2.5
you have them for now
just just amend disk command
because in order
to be able to use this one,
I believe you should have a I am a flat
for quite
of you are unable to run
even the first command.
Okay Eleni, I'll have a look at it.
But first let me talk to all of you guys.
What did is the difficulty
that you find in dollars?
I don't know.
I'm getting the sense that you found it
pretty difficult.
Is that true?
Well, you did not see anything,
so that's why I would be assuming things
right
leaders for now to maintain this concept.
Okay, you are confused.
Confused about which particular thing
can you mention?
Data?
Well, technically speaking. So
I have covered the basics
regarding the Dockers.
So if I will be adding into the class,
that is going to be
some really smart stuff,
which I honestly think is beyond the scope
of, you guys, because that is going to be
really, really tough to get it.
It's just the simple things.
So Motorola,
I'll have to talk to this and discuss
whether we need to, you know, include that
complicated stuff or not.
But right now I want you guys to tell me
I still have done
just tell me out which things confuse
you in Docker.
I can make them clear.
I know that because honestly speaking,
I don't know what happened to you guys.
I taught you the whole batch.
Right now you do not even communicate.
You were so much responsive
during the batch, and you always know that
if you are not going to give me feedback,
I will not know which topics
to spend more time on, which topics
I be explaining more
I should be going in depth
when you go in response.
Otherwise you are not paying attention or
I assume
that you are understanding everything.
So both things are
bad and your feelings so
at least you guys should be mentioning out
that okay,
this is something that we find difficult.
And I'm again and again asking and I
don't know why are you guys afraid of me?
Like still,
are you afraid of me? Don't you don't me.
Like, it's been six,
seven months that we spend together
like, so you guys can always ask me
questions, right?
You can ask me to repeat again.
I'll always do that for you guys.
Any questions, any topics,
any topic do you want me to repeat
from today?
Yes. Mohammed, Our last answer that
yes, asked him.
I'll tell you that life is not worth it.
Okay?
Just just leave that for now.
So. Okay.
So I think that
now it's time for my assumption
that I would think is understood.
Okay.
So I'm not to people in this group.
Okay, guys.
So regarding Dockers, I'm going to repeat
once again real quick that what
what are the things that you should be
comfortable with of our Dockers container
what our Docker images, what are,
what adoption
images, how to
you how to set up a container
using Docker image.
So you know what is a of container.
It's an isolated motion in your machine
just like a virtual machine just lighter
in with it helps you run your application
independent of all other system.
And when you talk about Docker
image, Docker image
is like a configuration file
that is there.
And then we want to build
or create some specific container.
We can use
that particular configuration file
so that it automatically builds up
that particular container.
So instead of that
we can create a container
and install dependencies
and utilities on it.
Mainly we can use some certain Docker
image file to create a container for us.
So that's the concept regarding Docker
container and Docker image.
Now the next thing that was discussed
was regarding
how to connect your Selenium script with
instance of
Chrome
or Firefox running inside a container.
So in order to create a container,
first of all, you need an image.
So right now in this example,
we need an image
which is running a chrome instance, right?
So we search for that particular image
and downloaded it in our computer.
The next thing we did is we initiated
we ran that particular.
So at that point we had a container.
Well, let me quickly do this.
So we had a container which had form
and the driver running and we got it.
Byron Next command driver pull, selenium
slash standalone chrome.
Okay.
After that
we wrote a script in our intelligence
and, we
in which we sent the remote red driver
and we said that
hey we do not want to use the web driver
and located in our system
regarding want to use the one
that is located inside the container.
And we gave it the address
of that particular container.
So the address of that particular
container was localhost.
And along with that,
the food number was mentioned
on which our container
was actually running.
So this
script connected with the container
that was running and starting
started to execute our goods over here
and returned the results to us,
which were visible to us on the console.
So this is what we have covered today.
Apart from that, I told you about Selenium
grade that in grade B have Selenium
hub and, Selenium node, just like this one
there is that. Yes.
And you can run
multiple nodes having different browsers.
You'll connect your script with the hub
and run your ports in parallel.
We are not going to be actually doing this
because this is
still something complicated.
But what you can do is I shared with you
one link to website if you want to.
If anyone wants to try it out,
you can on your own.
But I will not be going to that right now.
And apart from that, I think
yeah nothing else.
One one more thing
that I'd like to mention.
Let me have a look.
In fact, no, I think that is going to be,
again, something interesting.
I'll let me see the answer.
So when you run the code
and it goes through the grid,
the automation is running
as if it is a headless driver
because you do not see
the automation on real time.
Yes. As you do not see the browsers.
So it's actually a headless browser.
It's not going to actually
launch something out there.
The everything that is going to be
is inside
the container.
So if you guys have done
and if if you will be getting selenium
examples
on the I believe
in assessment.
So there you'll see that it's
it does not launch any browser
when you run it.
So basically I believe they are using
headless browsers in Docker containers.
So again you will you guys be using Docker
a lot on your work.
This is no well you'll be asked
a lot about Dockers in interview.
No. Will you be asked that
Do you know Dockers in an interview. Yes.
How do you want to reply to that.
Do you know. Have you worded Dockers
if this is something
that someone asked you in an interview,
how are you going
to reply to that?
Okay, you guys can answer like,
No, I haven't,
I haven't worked extensively on Docker,
but yeah there was one project in which
I just got familiar to it,
so I know I understand that
how Docker works, how it works.
Okay, let me, let me rephrase. Okay.
Understand this
whenever it's very important.
Okay.
Whenever an interviewer ask
you some questions regarding off topic,
which you are not very knowledgeable
about,
your answer, your exact precise answer
at that moment is going to define
whether likes you
or he dislikes you.
Okay, So you always need to make sure
you are defining your answer in a very
intelligent way.
So if I were you
okay, want you guys to ask
me this question?
Okay. Now I'm the student
and you guys are interviewing me.
So ask me this question.
Don't change the question.
Okay?
So I'll say I have not worked
extensively on Dockers,
but I have just the basics.
I Know how to install it.
I know how to configure it.
In my in my one of the projects
with one of my colleagues,
he was actually working on that.
So I got I got a chance to work with him.
And in there what we actually did, we
set up a standalone Firefox instance
in one of the Docker containers
and how we did that.
We for that we downloaded this image
from the GitHub repo
and we set up another container
after that we use the remote that driver
to link our script with that
particular Docker container
and run a few test cases over there.
So this is the basic introduction
that I have for Docker.
I have not worked very extensively on it.
So what do you think?
Is my answer good enough?
So now you see, I told him
that I do not know Docker.
I can read my message,
but along with conveying that message,
I told him that I have the potential
to actually learn
and I have the potential to actually,
you know, if he gives me
the task of a docker
is something that I need to work on.
I have that potential
that I can work on this.
So this is what you need to do
whenever you
encounter something,
something that you do not
extensively know off, just show
whatever you just show him.
Just be honest about it.
That okay, I have not worked extensively,
but you know, make a story around it and
deliver your answer
in such a manner.
So whatever I
give an answer, have I showed you
how to do it?
Okay, great.
Thank you.
So I believe that I showed you
how to do it.
I showed you how to answer the question.
Do you know Dockers?
I believe that if someone asks you,
you'll be able to answer it.
Write that down on a piece of paper.
You know, just
I believe I said just did that.
And you.
But right now learning it by heart.
So just, just make sure
that you are able to answer it
and that's it.
Okay, guys, that will be it for today.
And I'm late.
I believe that
tomorrow we're are going to have a class.
I'll let you know
if No, then I'll let you know.
To most probably,
we will not be having a class.
Okay.
So but if you have, I'll let you know.
Well, I sure I can do that for you.
But unfortunately,
the problem is that your
you are a female
and my wife is not going to match.
By the way,
let me tell you something funny.
There was one person, he was an Indian.
He was giving some remote interview.
And trust me, what he was doing.
He had his headphones on
and the mic was also there. So.