Thank you, ma'am.
We are recording us there.
Have you watched Group one flip grade?
Have we improved on acting?
I just got back from the
from my home town.
I was busy somewhere else.
Will watch these your videos now
as a long while in muscle and muscle
animal. So
you guys can also start following me.
I was trying to find Java basics
rap on guitar, but I could not find it.
Is it? Yes, it is still there.
But we have made it private.
So those who are invested in in the code,
you guys can send me your
username for the gear tab and I will add
you as collaborator to that repository.
They are private now so that only
you guys can access it.
So create a new project
thinking
it's fine.
Dennis Or should we send you
your GitHub username and password? No.
Simple one.
No, no, no.
The simple project.
What becomes private on an on GitHub,
something that was public
became private on GitHub.
Now so groovy. No, no, no, no.
Simple simple Java project
then Dennis
it's the it's the or almost
all the repositories.
We will make them private.
Guys, give me a thumbs up.
Once you are done creating the project
and that we will discuss
on some other class,
you'll get to, or
maybe you guys can google it or ask them.
I only have command line app option.
Yes, that is fine.
I have installed some extra plugins.
That's why I see all of the other options.
It's fine.
We will not be using the sale in idle
or a simple one.
We will be adding command line app.
What should we name it?
Namely on the name of your wife.
She will be happy
the time near me.
What should I do?
Dawn's housing
if I don't have a wife? You.
You are the best man on earth, man.
That's
nice.
And then click on Finish,
start from the elder
one and
well, by the way,
before we start the class,
guys, tell me honestly,
what did you do to my last server?
Ordered it.
I saw the video
and Diego shared
the admin username and password with you.
Right.
And I know if you guys have the admin
privileges, what happens with that
next piece of thing?
Right.
So he shared the actually
this was the this, this was the admin one
who use this username and password
we just followed.
Know you guys are not that gentle
means
that you will only follow the instructor.
I know.
Definitely
you will try everything that is possible.
And then because it is simple, you get the
guy. I'm just kidding.
I was just checking what happened.
Maybe I can find some.
I'm sorry.
Just a dump project
and just a Java project.
Sebastian, are you guys good?
Everyone has a Java project
now, so let's start from here.
Guys, If I have a website
like, for example, Amazon or Facebook,
why don't I use my personal laptop
to host that website
to store all the code that is executed?
And you guys see the those web pages.
Why, why, why,
why not use the local computers
like for example
when we're here WW dot Amazon dot com
that the code for that
website is stored somewhere right
that code executed and you guys see
the output
do you guys know how to create
a simple website
how does the code look
like for a simple website. No
let me show you
maybe let's take this one.
You guys don't need to follow me.
You guys can watch the video later on
because I have this to show you.
A lot of things.
So then I will say,
then you guys have to follow me. Okay?
Otherwise, just focus in here.
I named my project Stephen Jenkins.
Is that okay? Yep.
So let me extract the code
for this website.
So once I extracted that,
this is how it looks like.
So if I add this index dot edge
demo, you see,
this is how this website
looks like from my local computer.
And this is how these websites
are structured usually.
So if I write it can open it with
and maybe we just showed
you poor.
This is the code behind this web page
that you guys are seeing.
So is most of is now right now HD, HTML
and CCed.
So for example
what is
the title.
So for example
if I want to change may be about us
because something goes.
If I save this
and reload
this page, you see about match 11.
So it's, it's like any other program.
It's not right.
There is a great humor on SD email
being called as a programing language.
So this is just
markup language.
So all those things that you guys see on
a web page, they are also coded
in some kind of languages, for example,
who have that look and feel.
We use SD, email and C
CST to have a behavior.
For example,
when I am when I click on somewhere
and when it takes me to the other pages,
all those things, they are all coded
in other programing languages like Java
or maybe using JavaScript
and then to store
the data related to that website.
We use
database programing languages like school
and other.
So this is how things look like.
So what happens in the industry?
Developers,
they will be changing this code to
meet the requirements
of the clients, right?
Once they make all the changes,
they will show those changes
to the applied and once the
before they the show this to the end users
they actually don't store
that copy that they show to the end user
on their local computers.
Yes because they are developing something
definitely they will be having a copy
working copy on their computers,
but they create
a computer on the Internet,
on some kind of
cloud.
They put all of this code that you guys
see in here inside that computer,
and then they share their
dentures for that computer
in the form of these
two. The developers did that.
Let's declare next. Those are shared.
Then they
register these domains
which will once some end user
will type in that domain.
For example, WW dot, Facebook, dot com.
So there is a very big register
that all the internet providers have.
They will look for the server
from that you are l for example right now
I'm using the internet as strong fiber
so they have
that I have access to that register
once I hit WW dot Facebook dot com.
They will check the actual server
behind that link
and it will take your request
in the form of
executing most of the form.
But most of the time
I should keep the request to their server
and this web page will be loaded
inside your browser.
So once the developers they keep
on developing, adding new features,
keep on pushing that code to that machine
and the end users
can see those changes right away.
For example, the clients.
So so they all the developers,
they also use a lot of a lot of the tools
that look similar.
For example, an idea to manage discord
and repository management system,
to give the history of the code
and then other tools
to build their projects.
Maybe one, for example, of Gradle
or something like that.
So once you have this website,
once that website is posted to that link,
then the job of best stocks
we will need to we just want let know.
You guys don't need.
So once you have that link.
So for example then the job of like that's
the stock support example
client asked that maybe he wants to
once we are on the about this page
so maybe I don't know
client wants to see about batch 11
when we are on the home page
and when we are on our clients page, then
clients want to see if that about batch
1110 is too bad about us or not.
So this is the requirement that
you guys have, so you will take this link
and then just start
about testing the and then
that that that Bob Bob on that website.
But why we don't use our local computers
to do all of this
because we have a lot of issues
with the local computers.
So first of all they are
limited in system resources.
For example,
Abram base
processor, Internet bandwidth.
All right.
So, so the normal Internet that we use
in our homes is
it's not that good at that that great.
Imagine the traffic to Amazon, right?
There are millions of requests.
So we need very high speed Internet,
huge amounts of disk space,
RAM and all that.
And this is how the servers look like.
They are very big giant computers.
They are not like teeny tiny computers
or laptop
that we have in our homes
and they are very small history.
Granted, no one is allowed
to enter these buildings.
They are all connected to gigabytes
of gigabytes per second.
And in the internet,
speed is very, very high.
These they have special
equipment to pull down all the systems,
3 to 4 layers of security,
physical security,
cyber security and all that.
Because imagine the Jeff Bezos has Amazon
website
hosted on his laptop
and maybe I don't know and let's just
say is the laptop of Jeff Bezos
and now he is the owner of Amazon.
So they have very good security,
physical security, cyber security, and now
huge, huge beams,
technical teams to manage all lots.
Even if I show you
this. So
this is Microsoft servers.
The Microsoft even have developed
a container.
They put all of these computers
inside these big, big giant containers
and they place these containers
under the sea
because it's easier to pull down.
Under the sea, he dissipates
than dissipation is easy for us.
These computers, they are very sensitive,
will be dark matter and all those U.V.
radiations
that we receive from the open, open
sky. So they have to protect that as well.
So they put this under the sea
and they observed huge
performance gains and all huge
benefits in other areas as well.
For example, the computers that they use
inside these containers, usually
the computers, they fail on a daily basis
because there are lot of.
So if you guys watch it carefully,
there are multiple computers
that are connected
in areas of the servers.
They are nothing but multiple computers
connected and added. So
it's very frequent that on a daily basis,
maybe one or two computers, they fail
and then they have to replace them
with the other computers on maybe
hard disk
that are connected to these computers.
They fail or they have replaced some other
equipment inside of those computers.
So but, but the results were impressive.
And now they are extending this project.
But still, I will not
recommend to use
any services from Microsoft
because you guys, you and you guys know
why, right?
This is
so that's why
we have these systems.
We had a room for server in our company
in there about this watchmen working there
as we were mentioning it, server rooms
all the time.
One day this poor guy asked me,
Who is this server?
Why he is not coming outside.
I want to see him
because half of the index lasted five
plus exponential.
There
he is.
You guys know those who are aren't asking
why Try to upgrade your windows
to Windows 11?
40 years of experience.
They have been working in this sector
for 40 plus years
is one of the top
ten biggest companies in the world
and still you cannot drag
and drop things in Windows 11.
That's why that's why you should not use
any services from make this up.
If someone cannot build a good Windows
in 30, 40 years,
why would someone want to buy
services from that company?
Because then why do you make fun of Mac
users?
They are because one step ahead
from that Microsoft guys,
they took the kernel from Linux.
They didn't build anything on their own.
They do all the underlying structure
from Unix and Linux.
They just gave them the UI.
And now you guys see the Mac
and you have to pay thousands of dollars
to buy that.
So if we if we have to
if we use our personal laptop or computer,
we have limited of system resources.
We have to
keep it up all the time.
Right?
It needs
to be connected to
our supply
because imagine
guys that you are hosting your website
on your local computer and
you only turn
it on in the morning and then
turn it
off in the evening before you go to sleep.
Right? Imagine the website like
I think their revenue is millions
or at least thousands
per second
each Second it's $4,722.
So we have to make sure that all
those laptop computers are servers.
They are up all the time
because even if they are not on
for a single second,
it can cost you thousands of dollars.
And then you have to make sure
for the security,
then you have to make sure
that that thing is accessible everywhere.
So that's the reason we want to put
everything inside those servers
and then we share those resources
with everyone.
I think Elon Musk started
going in on his own
computer and running server
during the day and ordered at night.
It was
in nineties before we went,
even before that nineties global,
you know, the internet Sweden
that in those days I remember at least
first I have to dial a mobile number
to connect to the internet
and then I have to wait
for like 15 minutes before
I can get speed of like
three cables per second.
So it was fine in those days,
but not today.
If this I remember, I used to buy packages
like for example,
I don't know, a package for three,
three, maybe, or five,
maybe or ten maybe on mobile phones.
So it was okay in those days, even
in early 2000, it was okay, but not today.
It's so that's why we
want to put
everything on servers.
I used to play Counter-Strike with 36.
Gave you back in the old days? Yes.
Do you guys know about this?
So you guys know
all about the SDLC software?
The development lifecycle.
Right.
But do you guys also know about this
software deployment
lifecycle?
So how software is deployed?
Okay, you guys don't know.
Okay.
Is it okay if I take like one extra hour
today from you guys?
Maybe those who know something,
you guys can watch
the recording, those who can stay.
Please, please try to steps.
So what do you guys think
once the website is developed?
I was in Internet shop. Internet cafe.
I turn it on and go to my bed and a cup
of tea outside to open the browser. Yep.
What was the browser?
Internet Explorer.
You knock
and then yes,
I believe you. Or.
And by the way, after 15 minutes
there,
it takes 15 minutes to load that web site.
And after 15 minutes,
once the website is about to load,
we get an error from Internet Explorer.
That Internet Explorer has crashed
and now
we have to redo all of those things.
I have personally observed
that experience that.
So as as we have a software
development lifecycle, we have software
deployment lifecycle as well.
For example once.
So this is from where
all of these things start.
Like for example, if someone say,
I want to build a a website,
so developers will build that website
as well, test that web size
I do team will deploy that website
and all the prompts,
but from the editor starts
every from where everything starts
planning or idea, right?
Maybe there is a client
who has an idea of something
and they want to build
build those things, right?
So it starts from an idea
and the first step is idea, right?
And then definitely they have the budget.
So offer to the idea they, they, they,
they go to the
some kind of companies who provide
the development services
and then they tell them the idea
and they start working on Mark designs
right after the idea.
So second thing, we have multiple designs
in which the look and feel and all of
those features are discussed,
what the mock designs are, the final
graphic designers, they build these things
over the client, say, okay, maybe
this button should love, shouldn't
have this color, it should look like this.
We should have these tracks in here
and in here and all those things.
It's kind of a blueprint.
And with this mock design, they also
produce a document, the
from client side.
We have some team members
and from the companies
who are providing services,
we call them as business analysts.
They have good knowledge of technical
things and a good knowledge of
business domain as well. So
do you guys know the
name of that document
which the beard develops
after having the meetings
with the clients?
Yes, It's very important for Jenkins
that you guys first understand.
So it is called SRT
Software Requirement document.
Yeah. If,
for example, if I can show you
how does it look like?
It's a very ugly document, by the way.
So these are how it looks like
for all the all the features.
We have a feature ID, for example,
if someone wants to have a payment system,
they will give it
that payment system and ID
and then they will describe, okay,
this is the number, this is the future ID
and this is what we want
inside this feature.
So they will discuss.
They will write all the basic flaws.
For example, once they click on a button,
what's going to happen next
once they enter the current information?
What should happen next?
And all those steps, right?
If basic steps,
how to go with the alternate
steps and all that,
what should be the preconditions?
For example, a user must be logged in
before he can pay the money, right?
And then the post conditions
and all and all that.
So it happens for
with all the features that
are that
that, that they need to be developed
in their website.
Look, Michel, this thing
so this is the second thing
that is developed
it will help you greatly once
you start your job.
So every time I teach Jenkins,
I give at least 30 minutes.
Overview on all the process
and how everything works.
I'm shocked to learn
so that you guys can understand from
start learning how the flow looks.
So once the study is developed,
the next step is that that study is handed
over to the architects.
So architects,
by the way,
these are the software architects,
software architects, A,
s, R, D,
and the developer SRS.
It is then another document that both the
that discusses
how much RAM we will be needing,
how much hard disk
we will be needing, how much processors
we'll be needing to build this,
which kind of tools will be used,
which programing languages will be used,
which ideas will be used, which
all of the tools, softwares, programing,
languages and everything that is needed
to produce this application.
They are discussed in this document
by software architects,
and then they also design the glasses.
For example, the developers will develop
maybe 15 glasses.
These will be the names of the glasses.
Inside all those glasses,
these will be the meters.
They will contain this functionality.
Once this method will be called,
this will happen and all there.
So all those teeny tiny details other than
the actual code are mentioned inside.
This SRS is software development
lifecycle part of software dev lifecycle,
just like SDLC. Yes. Yes. Mohammed
So once
they have this SRS, the actual developers,
they start coding those classes of meters
and start building the code base.
So from here the coding starts
software requirements
specification, you'll get that.
So from here the developers will start
developing the code.
So the developers
big SRS and start the code.
Meanwhile, in the same time,
the best as they
they'd be s, r d and start
designing the test cases.
The code is yet to develop,
but because you guys will be having
the requirements so you get you guys
can start writing all those scenarios
and all those test cases
right?
And then you will take help from B as
if something is not clear
or from your test
layers are from architects as well.
So this is
from where you guys will start working.
Yeah. So lots of the code is developed.
Then the actual software
deployment lifecycle
starts from here.
Is it clear guys, all of these six points
before
we're jumping to the actual lifecycle?
So first
developers will develop the code
on the local computers and
will push it to the
dev servers.
It's the deployment and deployment.
So do you guys know
about the type of servers
that companies have, like for example,
dev server
for us out of Australia and server
and then production server
or yes,
they are called environments as well.
Yep. Yep.
So you guys know about environments,
right?
Okay, perfect.
So deaths are servers
and worse
the is deployed to their servers.
Then they will check if everything is
working fine on the server as well
because on your local computers
you might have a different version
of Windows or different operating system,
different hardware requirements.
So some things that work on your computer
might not work on a server,
so they make sure
before they hand over the code to you,
before they hand over the actual web
app to you, they make sure that it works
good on the dev servers.
So once it works,
it works good on the server, then that
thing is deployed
on the US server.
Okay.
And then you guys can start the testing,
right?
So here you guys will be needing Jenkins.
Okay, so what do you guys think?
If I have to pass to something again
and again, for example,
regression testing,
the companies,
they test all the existing features
before they deploy them
to the production servers.
So what do you guys think?
Is it a good idea
to automate that as well, or
we should do it manually
before each release?
We have to test the existing features
right?
And there is a team involved in here guys.
Did either team involved
and here, for example, their team
make sure that something is deployed
on the Dempster world and
that same thing is also deployed on
the server.
Then same is deployed
on the spreading server
and then the
same is deployed on the production server.
So can you guys imagine the time
it takes something from this
dev server or dev environment
to reach this production server?
And how many employees are involved
in these deployments?
It depends on the size of the company,
but usually
3 to 5 persons
are involved
even in a very basic web
just for the deployment.
Yes, it depends on the product,
but at least 3 to 5 persons on
or even in a very, very basic, simple.
And by basic,
I mean, let's say the hello world.
Okay, you guys,
do you guys know the Helloworld?
They are called dev ops guys.
The so this is the Helloworld.
Even if they have got deployed,
the helloworld,
this is the most
widely developed application
on planet out.
So at least 3 to 5%.
So who manages all these servers
and all these deployments and everything.
So Jenkins with Will will
actually replace these 3 to 5 persons.
Once we've set up a Jenkins
we will not be needing this
3 to 5 persons,
maybe one person will be enough
who will take care of the servers
and the Jenkins as well.
Right.
And everything will be automated
if we don't use Jenkins, what happens?
Developers send an email to the devil guy
and then they ask him to deploy
that application.
Then the professionals
have to do the same.
Once you have to deploy that same thing
on staging duty and all those servers,
you have to repeat that process again
and again, taking approvals
from your manager,
the team leader and all that.
For me, it used to take weeks before,
even if I am just adding a single
line of code, it used to take weeks
to get that line to the production server.
It's that slow and a lot of approvals.
A lot of my emails
to other teams are involved
to make sure that everything looks good.
So Jenkins
helps us in this, this, this pain point.
Once we have Jenkins set up,
I will just click a button
that will be deployed
automatically on the dev server.
It will be tested
automatically on the server
it once their traffic issues are passed,
that same will be deployed
automatically on the QC server
and on the US server.
The Jenkins that you guys
will be setting up.
The best guess is existing test
cases will also be executed
automatically if all the cases boss
their thing
be deployed to the staging server,
automatically,
the production automatically,
and all those test cases
that you guys will specify
will be executed on those servers.
Yesterday I was dreaming about this
spool and review and job.
I woke up and a big headache
like I was in battle.
So let's start from the very basic
Hello world.
Yeah.
So let me write or I
Yeah so and let me actually
it will be super super fast so let me put
but I don't sleep and let's say maybe
I don't know 2 seconds.
So this is very, very simple. Yes.
Now you guys should follow me. Yes.
Jenkins, do the deployment
and best execution of your best case
is automatically on a server
which you are doing of Java.
You are using
now, Will.
Why? You want to know that I'm using
Java nine to
you guys can use any word and
but if you guys use Java eight
it will be good
because I think the maximum version
that Jenkins response
is Java online
to make sure everyone of you have Java
eight
mind don't give
four look it's intelligent not Java.
Login loops are available
in almost all the Java games.
Offer them 1.5.
So you guys have been executing everything
inside the till now, right?
You contribute ten,
then you see the output
but this is not how it works
on the actual production servers.
On the actual production server.
This code is compiled
and then is deployed on the server
and then the command to execute
that server is sent.
So for example, if I have to
execute
discord, so let me,
let me copy this main or Java
and look for the third file in here
and let me copy this address.
So why is your Windows DART team?
But Intermediate is like
so you want to know the actual reason.
SIMON So for example, if I
if I do that,
for example, if I chain this,
you see my color, it it now
changes, right?
I don't look great,
but if I change it to light team,
it reflects good light on my face.
You see, now I look pretty.
There's the reason
I use the light team and
I got.
I have also learned some tricks
from ladies.
Right. So nice.
When you sit in front of interviews,
please make sure you have
good light on your face as
so once I have that
on my computer, for example,
I can use that light
for kickoff.
So for example,
most of the most of the things,
this is how they are compiled
and deploy it.
So for example, if I see a silly
do you know why
when I write my scenario in feature
file step which are not implemented
or not highlighted here,
so it is not related to the class
for how to plug in and intelligent
that we need to install.
Maybe you can send me a direct message.
Let a student ready
by the hand of the game
next time and
you guys not need to follow me
in here as well.
Okay.
Just I just wanted to show you
this is how things are compiled.
So, for example, if I have to do that
ranting, this is what I have.
So the Java compiler is called Java.
See, this is an application
that will be compiling 40
and then we specify the
name of the class.
So you guys see now we have this
main dart class.
Main dart class.
So discord
that was there in this main dart,
Java has been compiled to be bytecode.
And if I want to run this bytecode
on my computer, then I can simply say Java
and then me.
Well, let me check.
What was the name of the package?
Oops, give me one
one page.
Capital M
Okay,
so we have
we have moved to this directory.
Now, if I want to compile this, I say
man or Java.
It is compiled now.
I will see the compile code
and if I want to run that I see
and I see my output right.
So on production servers on your life,
this is how your code will be compiled
and this is how it because that executed
on production servers,
there are no ideas on production servers.
It is only in your local computers.
So you guys see and now I see the output.
So this is how the code is compiled
and executed.
Now let's try to do the same with Jenkins.
So are you guys logged in in Jenkins?
Okay,
follow me, guys. Log in to the Jenkins
as element.
No, I have revoked the privileges for you.
You guys don't have any access.
Now, you guys can create the project
and execute it.
I don't want to be doing the same thing.
And yes, I am definitely afraid of you
and the companies who will be hiring you.
They should also upgrade from you.
Please, please write in your resume
and that you are an adventurer as well.
You take risks,
you can destroy the self, etc.
and you can delay the production
release maybe by weeks.
I missed the last class
worth the Gardasil.
Or should we register then if they are
available in post announcement?
Yes. So this could take a little little.
Let me know guys.
Once everyone of you are logged
in and you see this page
five plus years in this point
it looks different.
I am better due to the latest work done.
I actually had to do it.
I was planning this to do it
for a long time, but you guys forced me
forcibly to delete
something.
Yeah, but
then I need.
So let's create a very simple project
and let's try to learn
how everything works from the very basics.
So this is how is very simple
Job is created.
Okay, so let's see a bit of a guide.
When you name a project in Jenkins,
put your name as well
with the project so that you guys
don't mess up the other projects.
All you guys can remember
the name of their project
so you can give any name to your project.
I clicked on new item
and click on this
freestyle project.
Click on this freestyle.
What is the username and password
you're signing course and down to?
I could not find it, I think.
Are you guys good?
Can I move to the next step?
So if you can. Okay.
So this is how I'll do it.
By the way,
the projects are called jobs in Jenkins.
So if you guys hear this terminology,
don't be afraid.
So they are called jobs.
And now let's see, maybe
if I want to execute that
for pipeline, I will teach you later.
So now let me push
push this code
and you guys can use the same board
from me.
You guys don't need to follow me here.
I will share building.
I created a simple project
like for me to build
a repository.
You guys don't need to follow me,
so I am just creating a new repository.
So let's say I am starting from the ready.
Ready, start.
So batch 11
Jenkins
I create the repository.
So this is how you guys will put your pass
if you are starting from scratch,
send me a picture of it. It's
so now if I refresh this page,
I should see my project in here.
Okay.
So the things, once
they are developed on the local computer,
they will be posted to the YouTube
and from the GitHub,
the Jenkins
installer will fetch that code.
And if you want to do that, you have to
go inside this source
for the management system.
Now you guys should follow me.
So inside the source code
manager system, if we click on gate
and if we paste, here is the link.
If we paste this link
now, Jenkins will effectively data
from this repository
and it will create a job
in here. Okay.
So for example,
if I click on Apply and Save
you guys also see this
same page.
Oh right.
So click on build. Now
and once you click on building now
and click on Console output
model, what are you doing
backwards selection, backwards,
backward selection in your keyboard.
Okay,
so you guys see that Jenkins has already
fetch the code from the GitHub
and it has stored
all the code inside its project.
So if we go back
and if we click on Workspace,
so you guys will see that. Now
you have all the folders
and everything
that you had on your local computer
which you push later on to your new tab.
Now it is not slow.
It should not be slow this time. Yes.
So all the folders code
and everything has been pushed
to the Jenkins and it has fetched
all the information from the YouTube
and it has created
a directory, a repository,
as you see on your local computer.
So for example, if I go inside seen tags,
I see main door down the door.
So everything is first
from that repository.
Yeah.
And now anything that I can do
on my computer, on my local computer,
I can also do that on Jenkins server.
All the commands that I want to execute
on my local computer,
I can execute those commands
in here as well.
So for example, if I click on configure
something,
I can, for example,
write,
I can click on Build
and if I click on Execute Shell
so I can write any command
to do anything with this project
on the Jenkins server, for example,
I can compiled this code and I can execute
this code on this Jenkins server.
So for example, I can see
what was the main package name.
So Java C
and then Main or Java
and then I can execute
this code
using the same command that I did
on my computer.
They're going to send you
these commands as well
that we know
once you guys have written these commands.
So you have to go to build a section
and then you have to click
on Execute Shell
and then you have derived these numbers.
So click on Apply and Save
and let's click on
Get It. Now.
So this this day is not capital.
Give me one.
So go back to project,
click on Configure
and change this
to low look
and click on big.
Now again for
I don't know if the Java Sea
or not on this computer
that is but
yep we need to install
the Java compiler as well.
Okay.
I don't see the console
when I click build now.
It would not take me to the next page.
Are you guys clicking on console output?
So if we go back to the
let me go to go back to the dashboard.
So you guys have put it
in all of your projects, right?
And if I search for my
project, I see my project
enter
and then
have you guys clicked on this builder?
Now? Okay,
so after that,
you guys have to click on in here
and here
to get to that console
like this.
Yes, that means there is
there was an error, not there.
Now, did you click on Builder?
Now. Yes.
Affiliated.
Okay.
It says file not found,
which means Which means
we have to specify the directory.
So go back to project
side B workspace.
Give me one moment.
This.
Let me fix it
and then you guys can follow me.
Did you delete your package
name on your intelligent?
Yes. Yes,
I did. That
and now should work.
So we have to navigate to that folder
as so you see on Jenkins.
I see my output as well.
Yeah. The code is executable.
It was compiled and executed on Jenkins
as well and it is successful this time.
So let me send you the updated commands
and we have to navigate to
that folder as well
before we can execute to.
So update your projects
in the configure session section
and then click on Apply and Save.
And now click on Build Now
and let me know if it works this time.
Log on why my workspace is empty near you.
Execute your report so
and then you click on building.
Now. Okay.
Do you guys see your output?
How many of you see the output?
Like, for example, if I click on this
learning, I'm getting
good enough
votes works
branding and new.
Okay, let me change the number of execute
as we are doing.
It is
let me make the number of executables 50
wide.
The idea will be
the there is one two.
Now you guys should be able to execute
your code in parallel still pending.
None.
There are.
There are I there 50 executables now
so you guys can execute 50 parallel jobs.
So you see Java project Nicolae executing
you'll get us better projects
like our project failed
and there are a lot of ideal execute those
now I missed that part where.
Do I play the code? You just send it
lady code.
Apply the code
like playing music.
Where should we put the code? Yeah.
So this is where you guys should.
Oh, do so.
Go inside your project
and then click on configure.
Once you click on configure,
do you guys see this page?
Those who are having issues?
Do you guys see this page?
Now you have to scroll down,
scroll down, scroll down,
and then you will see build
section, have to click on that.
So and this is what you guys will see
if you have not done this before,
this is you will see build
and then you will see and build a step.
Do guys see this option
add, build, step?
So you have to click on this
and then you have to click on execute
Shell. So
click on Execute Shell
and then copy and paste code
are you go now.
So this is a very simple script
in which I am moving to a directory, then
compiling the code, using Java compiler
and then running the code using Java.
Here.
Now click on apply and see.
That's it.
Now you guys should be able to build
and see your output.
How many of you still don't
see your output?
Once you click on this console?
Are you getting any errors or issues?
What is the error?
Send me a screenshot.
How many of you are getting errors?
I don't see the console.
You have to click on build
now before you guys can see the console.
And also you have to click in here.
So first you have to click on build.
Now then click on the
output in here
and then you guys will see the console.
So you guys see, I am I told you guys,
even when I tell you
how one times
that you guys have to follow me
or still made his on repository
new tab dot com lot more simple product
and now who didn't push anything
to that repository
and he don't see the output
so you see that's why I don't believe
why you didn't use my link man
then that's why you get that
is because you don't follow.
Let me tell you the repository now
does not.
It is mine
gone to due to a source second or syntax.
So let me show me your project
configuration.
Write the execution.
Come on.
And you guys click on Execute Shell.
Okay.
How many of you are getting errors
in Jenkins First?
What is this?
Jenkins First,
tell me the name of your project
then is what is the name of the project?
And you see,
I told you then if you have to
give, you have to write your name as well
in your project.
That's why it is not working, man
Okay, You did it for that project.
Come on, man.
I was fixing that project for you.
Then what is this behavior?
And then
do you guys want me to revoke
the delete privileges as well for you?
All right, guys.
So this was a very simple project.
We created a very simple
Java project we posted to get Hub.
Then we created a Jenkins job,
which fetched
the code from that great repository,
compiled the code
and executed that code for us.
It's good.
It's good, but it's not that good, right?
If I have to do it manually
by clicking on that link,
then what is the point?
This automation, right?
So we will go next step in the automation.
What we will do, we will now make Jenkins
automatically detect
if there are new changes in the code.
Jenkins should automatically detect it.
It should of first fetch
the fresh board should execute,
it should be tested and we should see
the output automatically.
Okay, so good.
Do that
we have to go back to the project?
Like for example, this was my project
and again we have to click on configure.
So I would fix that.
Then in check, if someone is available
in this sports channel.
So once we are inside
the configure project window
and if we go inside, this
builder triggers
a section, do go see this section.
So we have to click on the spool. ACM
and then we have to put
five staff in here.
So what is this pole ACM?
What are these stars?
So Jenkins uses a special language.
It's called cron job.
And using that language, it's
like the regular
that you guys learned in Java.
Yes, we had spaces in between.
It's a special syntax in which you can
almost specify any type of in parallel.
For example, what I am doing in here
right now, I am saying to Jenkins that,
Hey Jenkins, after each minute,
go and check of the repository.
Go and check this repository
for any new changes.
If there are any new changes
to the fresh code
and compile it and execute it. Now
once we specify this cron job,
what does my project
deleting by itself
Can't find it Now by Niccolo.
Someone else is deleting your project now.
I will reveal
all the permissions from you.
If you guys are doing this,
you will only be able to see,
Please don't do this.
Don't delete the project.
So for those
okay, it will waste more time
of this class.
So in here I am specifying
doing that after each minute
to go and check of that repository.
If there are new changes,
fetch the fresh code and execute it
automatically
and we can specify any interval.
For example,
let's say your company releases
the new features on every Monday
or any or every Tuesday.
Or maybe let's say you want your record
after each hour
or after every hour,
every minute, every second.
So you guys can specify all of these
things maybe on the first of every month
or maybe in the first week of every month
or maybe first day of every week.
So instead of learning this
all new language,
we can do the same that we did
for the regular expression.
Let's say, for example,
if you have to specify that my code
should execute on every day at 7 p.m.,
this is what you can do.
Cron job to
execute the
code.
Let's say maybe I don't know, every Monday
so you guys can specify
zero zero or both start and then Monday.
So you guys don't
have to learn this language
because it's like it will take next
six months just to learn this language.
This in 400am on line
one expecting to follow zero weird days.
We have to specify
jenkins as well
so the syntax can be slightly different.
So instead of this, we should say
Jenkins to execute the code every word.
Okay.
So most probably on the
IRS, I can check, but I will it later.
Okay.
I will check the logs.
Order this one.
So for example, by setting the schedule
period two 1513 and three stars,
you tell Jenkins to schedule
build every day of every month.
So if we go and specify that in here.
So it also tells you spreads
load evenly by using edge three.
So it's a better syntax
if we use that too, but we're
have so this is Jenkins is sending you
that this code should be executed
last on Thursday
March 24 at this time
and the next
it will be executed on Friday, March 25th.
At this time.
So tomorrow you guys can specify
maybe you want to execute it
on the next month, next year,
every 15 days or something like that.
So all the code,
instead of learning these dogs,
you guys can Google it
and can most probably like
you guys will find the answer
on Straggler Flow
somewhere else.
So let's try the one minute thing
so that we can test it quickly.
So I am specifying five stars.
How do we get
commands on their
SO do you guys see
this would have last executed on
March 21st, blah blah blah
and we execute this.
So if we specify a five stars,
it should execute after each minute.
So now, after specifying these five
stars, don't
do anything, click on Apply and Save
and observe this.
Guys observe this.
I go inside my project
and I change the code maybe from 10 to 5
in here clicking on
Give the option all yes policy
and then mute.
So if I change the record
and if I push it.
So if I go in here, no,
I'm committed.
So don't wait and push.
So are you guys done three
putting those five stars
because all of your projects
will be executed
automatically after I push this.
Okay Observe this, guys.
I put I say commit and push.
The code has been pushed.
Let me check
if we see that on GitHub. Yes.
12 seconds ago.
And now you see it automatically scheduled
the build number five.
I didn't click build it.
Now, do you guys see that
all of your projects,
they are started automatically.
So as a developer or as a tester,
we don't need to do any of the things.
We will develop the code once
code looks good, once the task
this is looks good,
we just need to push the code
and the rest of the things will be done
automatically by Jenkins
compiling the code,
checking for the errors, running
that code, executing all of their test.
This is everything will be done
by Jenkins.
Just need to push your code.
And you guys can also do this your builds
and you will be working on larger
applications. It
might take hours to complete so you don't
need to sit in front of your computer.
You can configure Jenkins.
Jenkins We will, we will execute
all the code
will fetch the code automatically
and if you get any errors, it will also
it can also send you an email there.
Tasker I was executing a project
and while executing all the test
cases, maybe, I don't know,
let's say all the desk is his boss
or maybe some best guess is failed.
This this was the issue.
This is this was the error.
We have to delete package name
before pushing always.
No, no, not always. You just.
Well I am just doing it so that the code,
the script looks simpler.
No, but we don't need to delete anything.
We can write any script or anything.
I'm just making it simple.
So now let's try to push the project.
Or the MAVEN project. Right. That's it.
That is the actual thing
that you guys will be working with.
This was a very simple project.
Now let's move to the actual thing,
the things that you guys will be doing.
Okay, so you guys understand now?
Jenkins Once we make
changes, it
fetches the code from your local computer
right after reporting,
it will be pushed to the gear tab.
And from that tab everything else.
After that, they'll pushing your code
to the production
server will be taken care of by Jenkins.
I don't have number five.
It's fine.
You don't have number five
because you execute your code 18 times.
Now, how can you have number five?
Come on guys,
you are about to leave Syntax
a go back
and you will see number five as well,
which
do you guys want to have a break before
we start with the actual things, maybe
fix your issue with if you are a guy,
if you are getting any issues
or anything.
Okay, guys, please fix your issues.
Posting Discord Channel.
There is no one available in this port
channel, so expect that other solutions
will help you out.
And I will take rest for 15 minutes
and we'll see you
after that.
Can anyone help? No, I'm super,
super tired.
Help each of the base
graduation
should be configure.
Okay.
So most of our it is going
after each minute,
but because there are no non new changes,
that's why
it is not executing it again and again.
We didn't say a Jenkins to execute it
again and again again
we said that
hey Jenkins, if there are new changes
then execute the code but keep on checking
after each minute, after every minute.
That's what we said.
Can you spend one more time
the Blade Command.
So the first line is we are moving
to this repository, which is bombs.
I saw second person bags.
So the folder in which we are moving
with the help of the command,
then we are compiling the file main door
Java inside that repository
and then we are executing that code
with the help of Java application.
Sebastian Good. Now
show me
you guys can see my configurations,
You guys can also see my configurations.
Then if you can see me,
see it on your own,
these are my configurations.
All I see them. Good stuff.
That's it.
Then click on Appliances next
work line is same.
Are we on break? Yes.
I will be back in 2 minutes, guys.
I hope you guys are back.
So everyone is good now.
All right.
So you guys see that
the code is automatically fetched
and as is executed by Jenkins.
And so the next thing you guys will
be doing on your jobs is related to the
movement project.
So almost everyone is good except El-Enany
and Simple Java Project. One
elevator.
What what are the issues? You are?
We are two saved.
That is.
And this morning, best of all, you.
All of you guys will Good.
It should be
Java Sea, not Java, but Lightsail
will now
you are good.
Now is there anyone else
who is getting any issues?
We are to see it.
That is the that it is updating.
So once we go back
in here.
So this is the project we are all in here.
So you you will,
you will see that the build will trigger
automatically in here
and you can also delete from the numbers
and the date and time as the neck
and new build was triggered.
Indeed, when the changes were pushed.
And so guys is Jenkins the way to automate
without saying the browser
opening and going through the commission?
Yes that's what we will do next.
What we will do now.
So click on new item and
MAVEN project us
the give your names and the next time
initial announcement. But
and this time click on MAVEN project
and start
instead of freestyle project.
Are you guys done?
Let me know if someone is still doing it
then this time Maven project
give it a name and and your name
or. Or use this name someone already.
Guys. Come on guys. Why?
Why are you using my same
same name as mine?
Please use your name.
Come on.
That is five years of experience
and this is what you guys will do.
So make sure you have your own project,
okay?
Now we will make some changes
in the MAVEN project
and the changes
I have made those changes already,
but I will tell you
what are those changes
and why we why I have made those changes.
So the first change
that I did in your project
was to because
on servers on Jenkins, there are no
yes, there are browsers,
but they are like they don't have screens.
We don't see the outputs of browsers or
videos that we play on the servers, right?
Unless we are connected to the server
from our computers.
So what we do instead of like for example,
this is what happened,
what what you guys have been doing allow
the let's for example
on your local computers let's say,
I don't know, maybe if I have to
the smoke test I will click on this
run button, then the code will be compiled
and the execution will start right
and it will open a browser
on come to the right
and I will see the actual visual as well
how the test cases are being executed.
But on Jenkins, we
don't need it, right, because that
that's the whole purpose of Jenkins.
We want to start the execution
automatically.
We want to last.
We want to sleep,
we want to it and we want
we are interested in the end results.
Now we have done all the debugging,
testing and everything on our local
computers, everything is working fine
and now we are automating it right?
We are not right now
fixing the errors in test scenarios.
Everything is done.
We are now moving that well,
testing the code.
Yes that that is the had left browser.
Do that for now.
We don't need to see how to disable
this chrome opening.
This is how we disable it
inside. Go inside. Your command matters
now you guys can follow on your own.
You can make changes to your project
or I will push these changes
to the Cucumber framework.
Batch 11 repository
and you guys can copy paste.
From there.
I will suggest you to just watch me
and then maybe later on you can follow me
if you are not that fast or good enough
to make changes and all that.
So if I don't want to see that
browser opening,
there is this class that is called
Chrome option.
So we have to create the objects.
I'm commenting on the simple code
in which we create the in which we created
the object of chrome driver
and we set up it and then we assign
it to the driver variable.
Now I am creating an
object of the Chrome option class
and I can
the properties for the Chrome browser
using this class.
So for example,
there is this property that is called
headless.
Yes, yes.
We're going to
and have this headless property.
Once I have set up,
I am forcing those options.
So the constructor of Chrome Driver
and once I do that guys,
once I do that, I'm done this.
If I now
go and and execute,
let's add the smoke.
You guys will see.
Everything will happen.
All the is will be executed.
But no will be open.
You see when user did you see.
All the steps are executing right now
but no browser is open right now.
Do you guys see the same effects
on your computers now as
command of the existing code
inside your common methods?
And replace
or replace that code with quote
and this time, yes,
all of your test cases should be executed,
but you should not see Chrome
browser opening on your computers.
You give me a thumbs up once you guys get
the same readers
same but failed.
I so you can use my my project
and you can use my failing
is something different.
Maybe your best guess is failing.
Just make sure that the browser
is not opening this time.
So let me push.
This changes
and let's
let me share the link with you.
So this is the riposte
in which I am making changes. Nice.
Those who are unable to follow me
or are getting any issues on your projects
Please use this in this project.
So this I'm now back to
the MAVEN project job in here
I go to
source code management,
I click on Gate and then paste this.
You are all
so this time
because we created in MAVEN project.
If you go inside of the build section,
you guys should see the bombed out
XAML automatically popped up
and you guys should see this new
X box
that says Golden Options.
Do you guys see this option
window?
Once all of you are done?
So if you are unable to follow me
because we have to cover more stuff,
you can do the practice later on
and you can just watch the video
right now.
Since the desktop does not open,
the browser will still screenshot
everything will be happened.
Mohammad All the features
screenshot has not to do nothing
to do with the things I like opening
the browser.
It is done
automatically behind the scenes,
even if you minimize your browser
during the test.
This application
still these screenshots will be taken
so do you guys see this bomb drop?
Example
Now to execute the Runners
project, we have different parameters,
so to execute those runners
we have to write this command.
It is built in.
You guys know how to execute
MAVEN projects
with command line.
So you guys are already familiar
with this command, right?
Been installed
right
minus D is equal to test
and then now we have to specify the runner
that we want.
Right?
So let's say, for example,
I want to execute this smoke
machine, send you this to install
inside the golden option.
Guys, write this.
Come on.
As it was
and let me know
what you guys are done.
And now click on apply
and yeah,
and click on the.
So right now we will see all the execution
from this so we can control output.
So for faster to effect
all the required dependencies,
then it will set up your project
and then it will execute
execution.
So guys,
can you please not take one building out?
But I think you have already done there.
So it might take some time now
because all, all of you are fetching
all of your projects
and patching this thing now.
Okay, stop it now. So
yes, you guys, can
I give you the privilege
to cancel something
so maybe you guys can cancel?
Yes, it's fine. Finished?
Almost.
Silva,
please don't send me the same logic.
My poor server and not handle
50 plus projects all completed.
Build the sandbox.
It's fine.
It's.
I didn't build it.
I didn't configure it to be super,
super fast
because it cost law and
I think your signal's
funding.
So, guys, this server is
set up for you
to have some lightweight practice,
and that's why we set up the server
to have like only four gigabytes of.
Right. Okay.
So on your jobs,
you guys will be having much better.
So it's fine for now.
Hopefully it's not going to be trashed
before we understand the concepts of
No, no, you guys will see the output.
And let me just give me one moment.
I recorded already.
I will miss you so good.
I will miss you guys guys.
But I'm working on with batch.
Well, they are not that funny right now,
but I think I will make them funny.
I So the smoke is being
is running right now.
Maybe the morning is bad today.
How many students are there?
There are 177 students in Best Barstow.
If they don't laugh at your dogs,
they need to see the doctor.
Then they do laugh.
But because there are
a lot of the lot of students,
that's why they kind of have this issue.
The management is not that good.
So Chrome driver was successfully started
and and there
was two or three classes. The
I don't know
the men were testing class
I guess they they had some kind of issues
so they didn't feel that good
but I hope they are good now.
How many students?
I heard there's like 200 in the start
there were like 200 or ten I guess
then or five students.
And right now 177.
So these these are the numbers.
These weren't some of the seven.
They will stick at the end.
So they are almost done with Java
for the classes remaining with Java,
they have already started Selenium,
so maybe two or 2.5 months
they will be
by new dude and pencil, you know,
they can see it.
You see one, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight.
So let me, let me cancel it.
Okay. So the best guess is being executed
right now.
The best bars, they are going to use it
in successfully logged in.
So you see all the test cases
they are executing,
but we don't see any browser
or something like that.
Right.
They will do later
when no one else is online
and blended successfully.
So we see all the output in here. Okay
guys,
maybe you can follow the video later,
but try to just watch, try to just
see what I am doing
and then maybe you guys can do it in
in your free time
on some new pencil. Mine.
I don't know.
I just canceled randomly.
Had to make a moves.
So you see, I see a success.
Everything that you did, all the best.
This is boss, and everything looks good.
But then if I go back to project.
Does anyone make fun of you?
Only a few students
feel, Feel means or not
that someone is messing with.
I got finished unstable.
So this is how the MAVEN projects are. Go.
And if we go back
and if we click on configure,
you guys know about the cucumber
reports, right?
We can also generate those reports
on on Jenkins.
For example,
if I go inside the boss to build
actions,
the fourth option is cucumber reports.
If I click on that
and click on Advance
in here, I can specify the pattern.
For example,
there can be multiple JSON files
from which your report is being generated.
So I can specify right now
I am saying, Hey Jenkins,
hey, whatever
the plugin is, that is the report.
I think it's called Cucumber Report
generating plug in.
So right now I'm saying don't care
about any of the folders
and don't care about any of the subfolders
inside.
Inside of those folders.
Just look for the file
that ends with the dot JSON extension.
If you find that file leak that
and generate a report report
using that file.
Okay.
And you guys can add
more possible actions.
For example, if you want to build
other projects when this project is done
or if you want to publish things, or
maybe if you want to trigger
other projects.
And there is one more thing,
I can also set up email notifications.
For example, if the desk this is a pass
or failed, I will get an image.
So let me try that.
Last time I allowed
these folders to do that,
they assigned the presence of to
two other
email addresses and Google blocked us.
So I disable that.
So we can specify the emails in here
and I can just show you
how the emails will look like.
So for example,
you guys will get an email like this.
No, what was my email?
I think this one. Yes.
So all the things that
yes, we need to build again.
So you see
this was telling us the testing pipeline.
So Jenkins sends you an email containing
all the information
that you see on your console output.
It sends
you all that output inside an email.
And from that email you can check
if the desk gives you that pass
fail divide. They are fairly wide.
They are pass.
So you really get these kind of emails
one month's considered.
Okay, so if I click on to now
not launch this one.
Yes this one actually.
So the second build build has triggered
guys can you please stop your products
from then you cancel the execution
so that we can quickly see that.
Otherwise it will take a lot of time.
No, I can also cancel your Dennis.
I can cancel all of your projects
plus delete all of your projects
plus block you from log in to Jenkins.
So can you please cooperate with me?
Why are you building again?
To show you how the report looks like.
So the project has been built,
and if I go back to the project now,
this time
you guys will see this report option
as well if I click on that.
So the same report that you guys see
on your Web,
you guys will see
all those reports in here as well.
You can also configure Jenkins
to send these reports
to any of the images for your managers.
All do their best years of yourself,
right?
So I can go add employees.
I can see 11 best bars, how much time
they took and how everything.
Later you will tell us what is freestyling
job three side jobs mean that
whatever you want to do with that project,
you can write your custom scripts alone.
Now that project can be anything.
When we create a MAVEN
project, Jenkins starts
automatically
a lot of things for us, for example,
and MAVEN
project management projects then.
So it will, for example,
fetch the bomb file automatically.
It will set up all the directories
automatically.
It will do a lot of things
automatically when we create a project.
But if we create a ceasefire project,
none of this will be done for us.
So freestyle
projects are like, for example,
if you are using your custom builder
tools, custom scripts and all that, most
probably 99% of the time on your jobs,
you will use MAVEN projects
or GRADLE projects.
So this is how we can generate reports,
We can execute MAVEN projects,
we can build the trigger, we can build the
we can trigger the builds automatically.
Now, there is one more thing
that every time we execute discord,
we have to go inside the configure.
Let's say this time
I want to execute the regression
so I have to manually go and change
the configuration inside in on jobs,
you will not
maybe want to give out
anyone everyone
the access of this configure tab.
So how do, how can they specify this?
The the test where they want to run
without messing up your configuration?
So there is this option
that we can select.
It is called this
if says this project is parameterized
so we can pass the parameters
to this project while running
instead of changing things at run
before running during the configuration.
So we don't want to share.
We don't want anyone, everyone
to have access
to this configuration tab as well.
We can limit that as that.
And if limit that,
we should have a mechanism to post
external information
to the project to during execution.
So we can also do that
with the help of parameters.
So for example,
if I click on this project,
this parameter, identify
people on parameter and let's say maybe
let's create a twice parameter.
Okay?
So let's say
let's call it runners.
And the choices
that I want to give to the end user are,
I don't know
what kind of.
Werner if you guys have
a pattern of selecting a period on the
empty first option,
then filter down those and second option
regression. Now
how we can send these reports
that matter that I will not tell you
otherwise you guys will get blocked again
from Google.
Just specify the email
in the email notification tab
and the email
will be sent back to my copy.
So I have added the parameters and
the name of the parameter is a random Yes.
I don't trust you guys.
It took me more than two weeks
to reinstall set up.
Best to configure everything please.
I don't want to trust you anymore.
I don't have two more weeks.
Okay. It's
so in
the Google section
in here.
Instead of hard coding this small,
this time
we will use the dollar sign
and then we will write the name.
The parameter that we want to connect
to are the this this in this project.
So if I click on Apply and Save this time,
so this time
you guys will see a new option
It says you just need to was saying build
now now would say now just saying
build it with the parameters
So anywhere in your script
where where do you want
to post external information
you can do that.
And if I click on Build with now,
I see all the options
that I specified in that box.
And let's say I want to smoke.
I select that option. I click on Build
and now the information will be passed
externally and we can use that information
anywhere inside our job.
We want to wait another two weeks
just to learn.
Jenkins We should, guys.
Don't press build now.
So yes.
Oh, by the way.
So these are called
Jenkins with parameters
as conditions
still show us how to do everything
automatically
woke us up.
I will show you. But
not right now, maybe.
Yeah.
I just want to make sure
that you guys are ready for your jobs.
And then maybe after you guys are done
with the regiment, prep prep
and all of the things we can host, I can
I will
arrange another session
to discuss the things in detail
for the Jenkins.
Okay.
But right now I want you to start
applying on the jobs as soon as possible,
because right now a lot of it is super,
super hot batch and students
getting three of our five qualifiers
each student.
I mean, it's crazy.
It never happened before.
Three offers past
five offers is still much.
We are also surprised so want you guys
to jump in the market as soon as possible.
Yeah so we see our output
and this time we build the project
with Barenaked us.
Right
now there is one more thing.
Do they care about interviews? Yes.
No bigger.
But they will be lenient.
They will be
and they will be relaxing you. Right.
And the interviews will not be not,
not will not be that hard.
When there is a shortage of developers
or testers
in the market,
they they are not that straight.
It's our this market actually slowing down
because of the law.
No, no. US market is is not slowing down.
It's opposite for the US.
Companies are moving from Russia
and Ukraine where they will go.
They have to keep their business,
they have to keep their running.
Right. They will look for other markets.
Yes, it's bad for maybe Russian students
and Ukraine renaissance,
but all of the students, it's good
right now.
And actually it's not bad
for Russian students as well,
because you guys can start you can guys
you guys can start applying on U.S.
jobs as well.
And There are 15 companies,
more than actually 15 companies
which are interested in the talent
from everywhere.
So I will share those links
for all of those companies.
And the only thing they do
is they hire investors
or developers for the companies
that are working in the United States.
So you guys can also be working
from anywhere
and the company
and the salaries will also be good.
Not that good for the for example,
if the student is living right now
in the United States, not that good,
but they will be compatible.
Yeah. Yep.
From Turkey as well.
So guys on on your actual jobs.
Yes you guys will be
might a good thing
only one project on your Jenkins
but Jenkins also offers
you flexibility that you can gain multiple
for example
if the test cases are passed
from on the U.S.
servers, then maybe you want to trigger
the test cases on spreading
or on the unity server.
Once everything looks good on those
servers, maybe then you want to trigger
the deployment on production server
and the testing on on production server.
And you guys can also divide your things
in multiple projects.
Then one, because let's say for example,
if a project is taking five logs,
so can execute that project in parallel
or you can chain those projects.
This is,
these are called pipelines in. Jenkins
So now I will show you how to build
pipelines in.
Jenkins So once you are on your dashboard,
if we don't pass the mock interview,
can we still go on the market?
If we want, you guys can go.
And the chances for this audience
to pass the mock interviews,
those who will be posting the interviews,
there will be higher chances
of those students.
Actually companies will companies
will realize, okay,
they are also good students
because of you,
because you will be making
a lot of mistakes in the interviews
and they will realize, okay, maybe
if someone is at least doing something
better than you,
then they should quickly hire that person.
So You will be beneficial for others.
Silver, please go in the market right now
without forcing the mock interview
so that others can get jobs quickly.
If definitely, man, if the mock interviews
fail, it means you are not ready.
If you cannot answer those questions,
it's worth the point of.
Going in the actual market
am going to find out.
And you
tired of this
bias?
If you find me missing,
maybe in next 2 to 3 weeks,
please tell police
that they should contact Silver.
Yes, Index will arrange mock interviews,
so let's create these pipelines.
Yeah.
So if I.
If I am on dashboard
and if I click on this plus button,
I can give the pipeline here,
I will helper
Silver, Aisha
pipeline.
Okay. So
please
explain pipeline one more one more time.
So for I have you ever seen how the
cars are built in factories
you see
so so tell me this fraud why
why don't they put all of the equipment
on a single index
and do all of the things on a single? Why?
They have multiple machines
in a pipe, in a
in a line that are going individual task.
Why not put everything on a single machine
and make that machine build
the God of all you?
Everyone is doing the part they know,
but they can also put
all of the things right on a single line.
Why install so much equipment?
Why not program
a single robot to do all of the things?
Make it faster? Yep.
So guys, what happens
if I do that?
It will slow down the process. What?
Once a car is built from start to end,
no new car will enter that assembly line.
If I make a single machine,
do all of the things.
It will be complicated.
First, it will be complicated.
It's not manageable.
We can not do it.
In all these scenarios, it's not possible
to put everything on a single dex
and programable to do all of the things,
sequencing the entire thing.
Unless and until one complete
car is finished,
I can not start manufacturing
the next car.
If I set up multiple pipelines,
I can build things in parallel.
Right. So that's why we create pipelines.
That's why we don't put everything
in a single project
so that it's more manageable.
It's to repair it.
It's like creating modules.
One module is doing your things.
If that module is not working,
we can either modules can still continue.
Yeah.
So there's the same,
the same logic happens with the pipelines.
Yeah. So for example,
once I
created
this pipeline, I can say maybe build
pipeline and I can create it.
So I am saying,
let's say maybe start this pipeline.
The first project should be
let's say this, you'll get a project.
Okay, Yeah.
And I can say number of beers, maybe two.
Okay, maybe one will be good.
So this number of two,
I will tell you once I see their name.
So refresh frequency one,
which means we should be okay.
Let let me first build it and then I will
show you are these two options.
But jokes aside, we will fail.
Are fossil three real interviews, right?
No, no, no.
You guys will not fail
to go to the interviews.
You guys will fail
at least 10 to 15 interviews.
Are we following you?
Yes. You guys can follow me if you want.
So if been good.
So this is the name of my pipeline.
Don't touch anything.
Just make sure that you guys please don't
make your guitar as your first product.
Otherwise all of your beers
will be triggered if I trigger this.
Your guitar, please do something else.
You skip my question now.
Can you please reposted?
Don't worry.
You will have at least five interviews
in a yes.
Four are.
Yep. You are right.
Previous bachelors
they are now making making excel
sheets then are they are special.
They don't even remember
on which company have applied
and in which state they are right now are
they are dealing
with each are interviews are technical
so they make associates.
Okay I am on in on second
with this company,
third round on this company.
This is the name of the person
who contacted me.
This is the name
of the company and all that,
both creating a
project and company investors.
You guys will be creating the pipelines?
Yes, You guys
will be creating the pipelines there.
So you want to divide.
Your best guess is
you will be deciding which
pipelines public
list and the best tool
to market with this.
So can we get BP and get the job quickly?
Okay.
So if you can apply and then you
so right now
there is only one project in my pipeline.
Yeah, but if I go back and if I say
if I,
if I select that project, then I will say
and what does that mean?
So if I consider
have you guys gone, gone
through the slides of Jenkins
or and G, Okay,
I will share the slides as well.
So if we go
and pause to build actions,
you guys will see
there is this option, build
other projects.
And if I specify in my project in here
what was the name of my project, XYZ
and we can.
Yes, you guys need more practice
or trigger only if the bill is stable,
which means the first project
is the project from your meetup.
Once Jenkins execute that project
and if there are no issues,
then only start executing this second.
And I if I click on Apply and Save,
and if I refresh this page,
you guys will see.
Now I have two projects in Pipeline
and if I want to add more project
to this pipeline
now, I can go to my project
and I can link projects to this pipeline.
For example, configure
and then build other projects.
And then you guys tell
me the name of your simple Java project,
which is working fine, but
yes, for hard,
I click on Apply and Save
and if I refresh yet again.
So now I have three projects in Pipeline.
And the beauty of this pipeline is
I only need to trigger this project.
Okay, So if I click on this first,
this project will be executed.
Once it passes
the it will trigger the next project.
When that passes,
it will trigger the next project.
And I can also add
a things in parallel.
So for example, if I go
as good
to the project of next pipe
in the same next block.
Yes weekend, yes we can.
Yes we can.
So for example,
if I put comma and let's say
I, if I use the
project from Emmett,
I click on Save and apply
and if now I refresh it again.
So you see, after
this second project is executed,
it will trigger all projects in parallel.
Okay, offer this
and you guys can create any branch
in here.
Yeah.
Things will be executed
in parallel in sequence,
whichever configuration
you guys want to have in your projects.
And what,
what will happen once I click on this one?
All all of this will be triggered.
Yes, the parallel is faster yep.
So if I now click on Run.
So right now
this project is being executed.
Okay, we see the output. Yes,
it means job.
It means job.
So it has triggered the next project.
If I click on this slash right now,
this project is being executed
and this job.
Yes, in parallel, in sequence,
in any configuration
that you guys want.
Is there a relation between what you said
there, done or not?
So you name that.
It is totally different thing.
It is something that Selenium provides you
if you want to execute your tests.
This is on with multiple projects
like for example in Firefox, Google Chrome
or you want to split if they feature
their selenium provides in.
Here is something that a Jenkins provide.
So do you guys understand
the purpose of pipeline
execution in parallel in sequence,
multiple configurations
that will help us select, say maybe,
maybe let's say
B this, this,
this thing contains
the important test cases.
Once this justice is passed,
maybe you want to test for two branches.
Yeah, one will deploy decode.
Once all the test cases are passed,
one will deploy the code on a server,
the other will deploy the code
on staging server so you can
and do things in parallel
on multiple servers.
Yeah.
So this is how we can build pipelines
with Jenkins.
Now let me check
if we are missing something.
So there are slides of Jenkins
that I would share with you.
So I have tried to put all the scenarios,
all the advantages, and this advantages
and everything inside the slides
with pictures and screenshots
with all the steps that I followed.
These are actually the same things
that I even just showed you
about the ground of
That's it.
So pretty much everything is cleared now.
And now you guys
should be good with Jenkins.
So the things which are related to theory
and your interview questions,
they are presented in slides and the steps
are also pleather and sliders.
And if let's say something still confuses
you, you guys can contact me.
Actually, I was busy with Batch.
Well,
that's why I could not make you a Jenkins.
Otherwise I am.
I was teaching Jenkins
for the last four batches 3 to 4 batches.
So that's all that happened.
And accidentally
I don't know the ago shared the admin
potentials with you and you guys.
Oh, my God.
Having destroyed everything,
there are some other important things
that I want to show you.
You guys will not be able to see them
because you are.
You do not have the admin
username password, but now you guys
might need them on your jobs
if you are hired for a
better position,
let's say a technical
test lead
or a senior test or something like that.
Yes, I have done this intentionally
not because
I want you
to start applying on the jobs right now.
And we can we can do another session
on Jenkins later on, maybe.
Yeah, but if you guys watch the recording
and if you go to the slides, I hope
now you guys are good enough
that everything will make
everything you make sense.
Has even. Yes, you guys will be able
to find your colleague. It'll
slides I will share on canvas. Yep.
Actually I can do that
now. I want you, every one of you,
to practice with them and projects
and create pipelines
as anyone created by Bernard.
Do we have access? Yes.
Do you guys have new guys?
See the option? Yes.
You guys should see the option.
And you guys please confirm quickly.
If you guys see the option
for creating
pipelines. Yes.
You guys should have.
Your slides are now also available.
So these are some of the settings all
although almost all the companies,
they hired a separate team members,
separate teams
install and set up
all of these things for you.
It's not your job,
but it's good to have this
knowledge as well so that you can guide.
Maybe your team.
Later on months you guys will be promoted,
you will be dealing with a lot
of things.
Please share the notes that you wrote.
Thank you.
So I have pushed that or on this
this project to get proper discipline
for notes and sample.
So the most important thing is this manage
plugins as we have plug ins for the clips
and embedded gear
that adds new features
to our core software.
We also have this option in Jenkins.
We can install plug ins
that gives us more functionality.
For example, these are these reports
that you guys have seen.
It's because of this Cucumber report
plugin
that I installed in Jenkins
and I even saw so many other plugins.
Sure.
So all of these plug ins,
they are installed
to make this Jenkins work.
So if you guys want to install
the plug ins.
You guys can also do it.
Just click on in here.
Let's say maybe, I don't
know, pipeline for pipelines,
we have multiple
So for example is looking for this
this pipeline is also
this pipeline feature
is also because of this really
the pipeline is not available
in the port of Jenkins.
These reports will give them the reports
that are being generated
are also with the help of a plug.
The GitHub
is also possible with the help of plug in
and this maven is also installed
with the help of plug in.
So Jenkins. Do not provide these.
It's all because of these plug ins.
Yeah.
And you guys can also install it
as we have
a repository like for example
Maven Central for hosting dogs.
We have a repository for Jenkins as well
a special repository in which
you guys will find a lot of
plug ins related to all of those things
security email credential,
a lot of plug ins,
a lot of plug ins.
So you guys can introduce
so many things in your Jenkins
You can customize in many, many different
and this is how you make it work.
This configure system is very,
very technical
and there are very, very few chances
that you guys will deal with.
This number of executable
simply means how many projects
you can run in parallel
if your hardware supports it.
Why, period?
How much time?
Jenkins should do nothing
before starting the next job.
This is the you are told that is appearing
in here, the domain that we registered?
Yes. It is something very, very advanced.
You cannot predict who you will
manage of this.
This you guys might need it
the manage plugins,
but other of these things they are
they are not your job
and you guys, if your task
if you are executing slowly
you guys can check the system information
and the load statistics in here.
So this is the big where we started
executing all of the things,
the graph that you guys see,
these are the system resources.
So this is the machine
that is being installed in here,
the Java Environment API, Java
specification.
This is a Linux system.
It has the architecture of AMD for 64.
These are the environment variables
that we selected, all the plug ins
that are installed,
all that information.
Now if you guys want to dig deeper,
I it's possible
to install Jenkins on your local computer,
your laptops as well.
If you guys are interested,
I will suggest you to install it
on your local computers
to learn all about Jenkins
wiring.
Coding is something you don't need, but
there are multiple formats in
which all of the files are encoded
for you would be a duty of 17.
So you guys remember everything is
converted to bits, ones and zeros, right?
So there must a mechanism
who tells us that if let's say
and then ones are stored in
computer memory, what does that mean.
Right.
If there is a combination of five
0 to 5 ones, what does that mean?
All of this information
is coming from that encoding.
All of these rules
are written in that encoding.
So what does those ones and zeros means?
It is it is written in encoding.
Your computer reads that information
from that, encoding
that you provide
and then converts back to your ones
and zeros to characters
like ABC or Special
that you see on your keyboard
and it draws all those things on you.
There is right now there is
UTF 16 that sports, sports
all the human languages that we use,
it has all the alphabets for Chinese,
Arabic and English.
UTF eight is simple one.
It has less, not less options.
UTF 16 contains the information
that what does those ones and zeros
means on your computer
and your computer takes help from that
encoding to convert back of the data
to correct the emoji,
the special symbols and all that.
This is how important words are.
So give me access to jobs code.
But it does not work in my P.C..
Are there any any other questions, guys?
How to find out who delivered something
like your project, for example?
You guys don't need to do it. You have to
do you have to check the logs.
Also the when you were born
guys, you guys going to follow this video?
If you want to explore Jenkins more,
you can install it on your computer
and play with it.
But it is not required.
It is not required at Max from testers.
This is what they expect.
You should know how to create a job.
You should know how to create
a pipeline project and how to pull ACM.
And no, not that much.
Are there other questions guys?
How many years are you learning?
I started learning in 2013.
It's seven, eight,
nine nine.
When is dividing?
In September on 22 September.
And give me our regular moment project
that we created.
Is it only me? Yes.
I see.
It is only you you.
You guys will be rich not only next week,
but in the not in the next month.
But in the you guys will start
getting rich in May or June
will use
all my issue with my cucumber for hot.
Tell me the name of the project.
Yeah.
Shallow.
Well, you mean your intelligence
or you still remember it?
I use this spring so that students forget.
So I tell them, You guys remind me at the
end of the class and everyone is super.
They just go to sleep,
they forget and they never bother me.
But you still remember, man.
Yeah.
Danny Jack, Maven, Austin Project.
And it works right then, but I don't know,
maybe Farhad now know
that after restricting us,
you see who we know?
Your tricks? Not guys.
Please don't tell.
Actually,
all the teachers are doing it in here.
Method.
Learn them. Tell
you. Yeah, I will.
I will show you later. Means never
one syntax Syntax
and I will come back to the question.
And the session ended
and they never answered.
Sometimes the answer right away though
it depends on the question
if that is useless question
and you should know the answer.
That's one instructor usually
responds like this.
It happened with me too
along the out of next week.
It's not about complication.
I don't think so.
In syntax there is someone who do not have
the proper knowledge to teach.
It's not about knowledge, I guess.
At least it's not the case with me.
I don't think I have. You guys have.
Have you guys ever?
Have I ever not answered your question?
Have you ever seen me
that I said, let's say
maybe I don't know the answer
or maybe I will tell you later.
It's very rare.
But then the question is super,
super dumb.
Then you actually start to do this. But
it's happening right now too.
You see,
sometimes I think maybe when we are tired,
then then all all is being recorded.
Why am I why am recording this?