That's
kind of the.
Yeah.
They're going to start
early.
So yesterday what you were doing.
Let me just open up the notes for the
so that we can continue
from the same point doing of.
So the last example which we were learning
was to do
a comment
in which sorry
we had to create two branches in parallel
and then merge them to single main branch.
And in there we witnessed
another kind of merged
legislative need which get close to
the first one was fast forward.
The second one we just discussed
that we did not know that
what kind of merge this was.
Okay,
so let's get into a little bit of you
before we actually begin that of
let's see,
how much do you remember?
Okay.
So this is the scenario
that we have right?
We created to run this planet one,
planet two.
Now tell me, guys,
if I want to merge, let it so and mean
what kind of merge strategy
is going to be used by here
the faster because it is going to check
that if see merge
manage created the branch
the last minute merges
right now
that is the last limit still see merge
it will say yes when use
last forever
most technique and in there
are see merge will start
finding do see six of other
now when you want to merge
that one with the main
this path are going to be possible. Now
no this time fast forward
is not going to be possible.
So what will happen
so there there may be some polarity.
Is it necessary
that we will be having a merge
try conflict.
We will be having a conflict.
Is it necessary?
Yes. That's not necessarily.
Those of you are saying
that you only have a conflict.
No, it's
not that we will be having a conflict.
The right answer to this question
is that now
you will have to do a manual merge
or maybe you're just going
to choose another strategy of merge
with this, which is called
Three Minds are recursive merge,
but Anthony Ramos are recursive merge.
There may or may not be a conflict.
Conflict is like, you know,
another part of the story.
It may be there.
It may not be there
when there is a conflict.
We are going to do that too.
Okay.
So let's assume that none of the user
planet, one of planet to make changes
on the same lines of the food
anywhere in the project.
So tell me,
is there going to be any conflict
then?
Okay, There is going to be no conflict.
So this is going to
come in here.
Okay. So what will happen
if there is no conflict?
Let's say we are in the condition
of no conflict, so it will happen.
There should see five go.
What should happen? And you guys predicted
merge happen and what what
happens when a merge happens? Yes.
Now what will happen?
These two comments are going to get merged
and they will create a new
comet
which will have both DC five and six.
Cool.
And what class seven? What do you mean?
That in one class?
This is not for class, this is for Comet.
Okay?
And it's not going to combine
classes
at this point to combine the both cause.
Okay, so
main class
will get to the poles of we want to do
if the codes are not on the same line,
it does not have a conflict.
It might be nine nine number then.
Yes, obviously it's going
to incorporate the code for both of them.
If the line numbers are conflicting, then
we will have to resolve that conflict.
Madam, does that answer your question
that you
were downloading right and then merge?
Okay.
Those of you who have questions,
I shall let some of some it up
in one statement because it gets out of me
to read it in bits.
So maybe I lose track.
So try to sum up all the question
and one step.
Okay guys.
So I will deal about this
recursive strategy, how it's working,
and I'll answer the question.
So if you have any, you just have them
prepare to discuss them.
I'm with you about this
if we have no conflict.
Okay, so let's discuss the case
when there is a problem.
Now let's sit that
in C5
there was a mean file
and you think there are all coming.
That's and let's say that in here
we have ab1
and also in C six we had up B one.
The user one of that one made some changes
on me and P one on line number
three and line number five
also the user to make some changes
in the main and P one on the line numbers
three and five.
Okay.
Now tell me that
when we are going to merge, C five
is going to be a conflict.
Yes, because the same line numbers
have been changed in the same files
and did does not know that which one
is the updated one
and which one do you want to actually
assignment is that this is the updated way
you are updated.
So what's going to happen
A merge conflict is going to be a get
will not be able to resolve
this kind of conflict on its own
and it just going to ask you to
resolve it so it will open up
something like we witnessed yesterday.
These dots that you had had and
like this time with
I guess there was
mudslides or incoming side,
there is going to be one code
and there's going to be the other two.
You can either decide to keyboard
for that.
You see these lines
or you can decide to
simply get one of the two
that you're going to see.
And depending upon which code
you actually need.
So it's possible that you say, okay,
I want to keep the changes made by user
three and I don't want to have the changes
buttons one
So you can delete this line
and keep this line
for the one and choose to keep this line
and delete this one.
That's your choice.
And once you have resolve the conflict,
you run the code, it's working fine
and you're sure about it.
Then what's going
to happen? You are going to
come at it.
So it gets merged
to resolve the conflict
and you merge.
Okay, so this one,
this is a clearly
unsupported recursive merge.
And this one also in this.
Like we have to just discuss
do one extra and course
that's it.
Okay, so now we are going to do something.
Examples.
So yesterday what we did, we actually
so this step we were done,
we merged our code of planet One
and applied to into our main branch
and we did that stuff
in our local repository right.
So all of you have crashed up
to that point.
I believe.
So we will be starting
from that point over and
I want you guys to open up
your GitHub accounts
of this.
So let's go to the zip screen,
which we had that
sort of system for.
Okay. So I'm going to
open up this
diagram
again that is going to redo this stuff.
Now, my showing you the map
to how you can proceed with merging
if you want to merge on
GitHub, then we start blank.
New exercise.
Mine was not working well yesterday.
How soon you can get the code
from my GitHub or anyone else
but doing this example over and over
again, it's not going to be possible.
I'm really sorry.
It's going to take a lot of time and
I cannot do that.
I have a lot of the new stuff
to teach you guys.
So if you want to have the code,
you can have my code, I can schedule
and I can
you help us get the pool to the method.
I talked to you
yesterday and then we can do
this.
Mention the steps.
If you remember.
So okay, yesterday what we did is that we
solved the conflicts on the local
and we pretend to be a team.
The WHO has downloaded the apple
known to Apple and checking the code
that if it's working fine.
Yes if it's that personality,
merge them locally.
Okay. Let's assume that he was successful.
We check the code and he has
done everything locally
and he wants to update them.
So what he's going to do,
if he wants to update the remote
from the local
and he has merged everything,
what should be
his next step?
Cool.
He already pulled up
so I will then he put plugin he's
now doing updates on local right.
Yes comment and then he will push the pool
updates and the view.
Let me show you
get log of
the plans have been more successful.
It is our last commit
which was made on Saturday,
January 29 at this particular time.
So we did that actually.
Thank you for having my back over here.
The Yeah we have another
yes. Now
I have the option to push it
and update everything,
but we will not be doing that
because I want to teach you guys
another method of doing this on GitHub.
Okay,
so now I'm going to open up the GitHub
and I'm going to show you guys
how you can proceed
with doing all the stuff on this
particular platform.
So right now I'm going to pretend
to be the person who worked on
Planet One.
Okay?
I was done working on slide one
and I'm sure that my code is correct
and I want someone to review it and merge.
So what should be my step?
What should I do?
Make upload request? Yes.
So simply click on all requests
and create a new request.
So my piece is going to be made
and I'm going to merge
my Planet one, including.
So I have selected base as me
and the one branch
which I want to merge this planet. One
at the non
nuclear class
I've just been made over here
and that at one point you
and then I said
create a pull request.
Okay, so
now what is there?
We can see that
these are the changes in both the
and both the branches.
So this is some additional code
that I have in Planet one
which is not going to be there
in my main works.
I can review that over here.
All right.
And I'll check it down in my
local computers.
Right now you are just using GitHub.
Okay, So I do not need to go into my local
review and I can have a reviewer
reviewer assigned.
But right now
you do not have any assigned.
I'll just assign syntax and badges myself
labels and I would say
it's an enhancement.
None, nothing else.
I want to sum it up
and I will just write the comment
that I have successfully
completed
the feature Planet one review
and please let us
okay, let me know what you guys
have done to do this one and then we'll be
proceeding together forward
then.
Now say create, upload, request
so as being the person
who will not like one, I have successfully
created a pull request.
Okay, now let's click on our A system
you give me.
Now you can follow me
after this particular
stuff that you have done.
We open up a pull request.
Just if you want to do that,
you can simply do that
on GitHub.
Okay, so now what?
What is going to happen?
The team is going to have a look
at the requisite attributes.
You say that, okay, I got a pull request
so that let me have a look at that.
You'll click on that pull request
and then you'll see that
there's a pool request.
Say that we dropped
that one has been added successfully
will say, okay, let's have a look at it.
It'll click on it.
And he'll say, okay, let's have first
look at the files
to review the code with the.
He said that everything looks good
and then he'll go back to the conversation
and okay, wait, I'll go back to
the set.
A wait a second round.
Second has backstory, but I can select
was just in file changes.
And what is this?
Why is different file changes?
What do you mean by this?
I don't understand.
What is mine
different than yours? But.
Okay, so
like it's yours is also read.
It's not false.
It's just that the view is different.
Let me see if how to change the view.
You're showing everything in one thing
and that one's different.
Okay, so then you has that.
Yeah. Okay. Unified
and split.
Yeah. You can change the view.
Follow over here.
So don't get worried if it's unified.
Also, like, yeah, it makes sense to let's
have a look at unified one.
Exactly like it shows me now that
instead of this line,
this line is going to be present.
This is the addition of the lines.
And these are also addition
of the lines.
Okay.
Now let's get back to the composition.
Let's move it out.
At this point, you guys find some error.
I've I've been lucky.
I found some error
and I do want to merge it right now.
So what I would say, I would say, hey,
I've found that
your work has some errors.
Can you please
resolve them
all? Let me know.
I'll just comment on it. Right.
So this is the
conversation that is going on.
This was the message.
And then I applied this message.
Now the plan one user
is going to have this message
on his previous right to view it
and it will sit.
Okay, well, let me correct the error.
After getting the error, he's
going to again update the message
and he will let the person know
that, yes, I have resolved it.
I was resolved the conflict or errors
or whatever was there.
Can you not try to pull it
on budget again?
Why not?
Sure I can do that right now.
Let's say he again.
You view the changes
and this time he said that,
okay, everything looks good.
Go back to the optimization, see
everything that's good.
Perfect.
Breaking sounds as my sound breaking. Nice
of breaking.
So let
all in.
Great.
So now, once
we have entered this comment message,
what we are going to do is to communicate
just to make sure that the conversation
is nice and good and everyone
who goes through it also gets to know
that what the progress is.
And then this is the point
where we will merge the branch
by clicking on this button.
It shows us that this branch
has no conflict with the base client.
It means that it will be merged
automatically.
Now, from the options
we have different kind of merge,
slash and merge, rebase and merge.
Okay. So what does this do?
Create a merge coming
all commits from this branch
will be added to the base,
but they are a merge come in but
it will take all the commits of the off
the child branch and put them in
the parent branch.
Squash and merge scratching
merge is going to basically
squash all the comments in the child
branch.
Make it one comment
and only add that particular company
commit in the baselines.
Right now
we will be just using create a most common
the first one you logically need
discretion merge and rebase
and once we are not going to be going into
that so
simply select it.
Our most common.
After that we will simply click
on Merge to request.
So this is the commit message
that is going to be placed.
This is our email address.
And then after that
you will simply click on confirm merge
and it's going to start merge.
Okay.
Well, the request
that says fully merged and close.
Now if I have a look at my request, it's
not going to be
there because let's resolve
we have merged it.
So this point,
do you guys have any questions?
Okay.
Let me show you on our system.
Now we have read it one add.
If I have a look at the comments,
the feature update,
one has been added successfully
and then after that commit the most commit
that it's there to.
Okay.
Meanwhile, let's say
the planet two was also added
and this person who was working on
it also wants to merge in the main branch.
So what he will do again,
he will go to pool request
and he'll click on
create new request.
This time the base is going to be main,
but the other one
is going to be Planet two.
To do that, see that it shows
the message can automatically merge
because there is
a conflict now.
So it has already did
detected that.
But still we can create a pull request.
So we will be creating
first upload request.
I have added the feature to
and then will create
the pull requests.
Last time it was joined
us that no conflicts.
The branch is able to merge, but this time
you get a message to this branch.
Have a conflict that must be resolved
and it's showing.
It's showing us the file
which says conflict.
So main Java has some politics right
now. Let's assume that this one request
of visible to are keenly
and he clicked on it
he said okay apply it to
is that I want to add this feature
to let me click on that
and then he'll say, okay, it is a conflict
and it wants to be resolved.
Okay, let's resolve it.
Simply click on resolve Conflict
and it's going
to open up the school in front of him
like this.
Now he needs to select that record.
Does he want to keep.
So this is the code
coming from the planet to merge and
this is the code which is already there.
They are both in conflict.
So in this scenario he will say, okay,
I need both of them
because they both are a unique feature,
so I need to move those lines
and we'll have both the codes
in his file menu job and after that
he will click on Mark as a result.
So resolve this conflict.
Let me know that
we are going to click on Mark as result
of the conflict.
Okay, now let's click on Mark as a result
of its results.
Now we are going to click on commit marks
just once.
Here is all the conflict.
Now we have to commit the merge,
so we click on commitments
to leave a message called Click
successfully
Resolve
and ready to merge.
Well, we asked you got five of the lines
or different numbers
and that's why do not have a conflict.
Remember I told you guys that the conflict
is going to be there if
same goal is going to be there
on the same line
number.
Yeah.
Okay. Now
will say comments
and after making a command
will click on large pull request
and then can follow
certain rules.
Okay.
So my it's all set up.
I have successfully been like that too.
I can simply go to my
code now and I can see that
I have successfully merged it.
Let's have a look at comments.
So back to feature has been added
and then after that we have
let us commit, which is this one.
And if I show you
there have to just create at this point
it has the full code for planet
to kind of one.
Okay,
so that's how you do a merge on GitHub.
So it's your own choice
whether you want to do it on GitHub
or you want to do it on local,
that's that's personally dependent on you
in your work environment.
It's going to be I do
I will recommend that whenever you are
working on a project you want to merge,
just do it locally on your own system
because before merging,
I really want you guys
to be sure that the code is working
and there are no letters and then only.
So you cannot have
this approach also that you
don't do repository on your system.
Switch to that branch.
Updated check
whether everything is working fine.
Fine.
If yes, then you can simply come to get up
and resolve that conflict.
Result of move.
So that's how you are.
Okay.
So to this point,
any questions that you may have?
Nothing that
and now we are going to discuss
a few more information.
I think we will go ahead and
the largest in the
what we don't even need to go to our ID
does all that you can do it and becomes
Yeah obviously like
just like we did on the remote right now
we did not have to go to our I think
we simply merged everything on the GitHub.
We did that
without using any of the stuff.
Okay.
So a little bit more
I'll teach you about GitHub.
If you click on inside
and then you click on what
here you can see
our is the workflow how they are
merging into mean, at which point
where they emerged
and have a view of that
by clicking on inside and then network
not done.
Today topics are almost ended,
but you still have some examples
that I'll let you a few more.
So Okay, so I'm going to say
but what do you mean was in GitHub?
Don't we need to pull that
most code to our local.
Okay.
So even when we have emerged in GitHub
and we still want to work on that project,
obviously
then we will pull that go into our logo
to update our local repository.
Okay.
And apart from that,
do do we download a new clone?
If you are on a
new system,
you do not have that project already.
Then you make a new clone.
But if you already have that project
then you do not make an import.
You simply pull it right? Yes.
I should go ahead.
I think your terminal
the only push left now
we do not need that
because we did it on GitHub.
Yes, exactly.
We did that on GitHub
and we would not need to push everything
from our local to remote
because we did have a GitHub.
Okay.
So yeah, this is let's do one thing
now, let's open up my funky one.
I'm opening up my funky folder
and doing a big bash.
You two.
I also recommend that
you guys do the same.
I open the funky
that we created yesterday and
I open up a big bash with you.
I do get more.
Just see the colors that are different.
Okay, so is my
local repository
of this particular user updated
that this
this repo updated to a more or not
the saying no.
And what's your opinion the rest of you
just to negate
how much you said yes so right.
You mean yes or no.
So I'll repeat my question.
I will repeat my question.
The question is that
the user funky
who was working on Planet One,
does it have the updated wrap,
which we just did some updates on?
No, it does not have it right because
this is the funky user who worked on
Planet One. I got to
ask that.
I give you that information.
The funky user. What about that one?
So it does not have the updated wrap.
So he needs to update his record.
So what he will do is get fetch.
He sees that
there are two updates.
The main and the planet launch.
So if he wants to update the main
branch, what
he's going to do
first to check out the mean
and then he ready to get
cool.
So after checking out Main and doing
Get cool, he is going to have
the updated code.
So we to mention this also
in order
to update your local branch. So
and then just before the
the let's do the thing for user
junkie there is my user jump in this.
So I open up
and I open up the git bash at this point.
Now I also want him
to have the updated code,
so get
Jack out
me make sure that
that you are in the chunk
you want the check user
effect to see that
whether if he needs to update
yes he does need to update
and now get code
he all also now has the same updated code.
The update is that is zero. Okay
now let's start working on you require
let's do one more example
of the same stuff that we have done
already.
Let's start
merging.
Okay.
Let's assume now that there is a new
requirement requirement which says that
work on feature law.
And so he has to
work on one one
and funky has to work on
good, lawless, convoluted, convoluted.
What's the meaning of
file deletion like the Mathematica code
should work.
Yeah.
So get log is going to actually get you
a little bit confused over here
because it's going to show you it's random
and the only thing I would recommend
that you get from at
this point is the hats and the commits
that they are finding.
Apart from that,
I think if you get a log, one line,
it made me a little bit better picture.
Okay.
So now these are
this is a kind of better picture
for your file logs.
This is a little bit to.
But the most important thing in this
is that your origin slash made
is on this particular
kind of that's that's it.
This is your important
information that lead to
your original
planning to then
on this particular company.
But this log does not give us
very good information about
whether this commit
is included in our main branch or not.
This this information is not included
in with log
in order to have a good of logs.
I would recommend that
you go to your particular branch
on the GitHub and click
on this particular comments over here
and then you'll see
a nice and good history of the comments.
So whenever you want to have a look
at the logs in multiple branches
this go to GitHub and utilize whole.
It's a better
okay, so let's open up
the requirements
so you have to work on one one.
So let's pretend to be chunky now.
Okay. So junkie is there
Oak Island Chunky Score System.
So Junkie wants to add a new lonely one.
I'll open up the console.
You are looking at
what is going to be my very
first step
yet one
one, one.
And then check out of that one.
Check out one more
of this.
Basically drawing
a new
update
with me branch.
So this is our main branch,
which is no update.
So this is just one.
And we created a new branch to let us see
more and more
open up
our intelligent junkie over here
and how I switched to the branch.
I need to make sure of that.
Yes, I only need one for each.
Then I'll add and plus one more than one.
And our moon is going to have
some kind of attributes.
Let's call them color only for now.
And training.
This what
else does it have ready is
saying
like intensity
in our main branch.
Oh, that's some
features of that in
11.11 or
the new
one one
you guys
Not until this point.
Probably the next step is going
to be simply to commit this over here.
So get add dot get comment
dash AM and it'll make the commit
they're find that
one feature
as been added.
So I just made a comment
with all these features on one
line to name it means so.
Okay so now
let's
pretend
to be working on
some funky
I to responsibilities to work out the move
to and make some changes in Sun
a bit. Sun.
I have an update.
Yeah I just it's not
so this is the responsibility of funky
left open up the
project for funky and I have it here.
Here it is.
So again, the first step is going to be
to open up the terminal for Funky.
So make sure that you are terminal
for funky and then
create a new branch.
That branch, let's call it
what we want to.
So we are going to play
simply a new class named Mode
two and same features we had for than one.
We are going to add them over here.
Well, I have to be very honest with you.
We do have a way of doing that.
But I would like to,
if you that I never commend you to use
your get with ideas
and never rely on that.
And personally, I use that I have a don't
have my own system
figuring it.
Okay.
Now in our main mode, what we are
going to do we have to make some updates
regarding one
but this time and let's do one
less accidentally, let's say we press
or here we started
deletion or modal features.
We did not did this on purpose. That's it.
Just by mistake
on purpose.
We are in general purpose,
purpose.
Okay.
So these are changes that you need
and have.
Okay.
Now only one job is left
for this particular user.
You also needs to do some updates in Sun.
So what do you think?
Should those changes be done right now
or should you create
a new branch for that?
Well, I should be totally dependent on you
that your own personal choice.
But obviously we are
we are seeing that we are assuming
this is a big project complex group.
So I want
honestly want to have a new branch.
No, I would like to on this front
for the update.
So simply say let's make our comment
bit at DOT,
get permission that I am
the new feature on to have been
and now I'm switching my terminals
that is now by now you guys should know
how to make your comment
once you have added that.
Okay so this one everyone is with me.
Are we all synchronize?
Okay, let's do one more thing for both
the users who worked on one
and two,
let's push these branches to guitar.
So for chunky
get push dash
you are region more than one.
I will press enter so if I have pushed
this bunch to the more and for funky
get push
that you do origin mode to
so both my branches are company
and they are sent on GitHub.
Okay now we want to also work on
the update strike in this time.
So for that
for creating a new branch also.
So we should be create the new words from
this person
who was working on more diversity
creative, not from
us. Well,
it depends upon few conditions.
Well,
obviously it's pretty logical, right?
I would just let you know
the updates he wants to make are on.
So right.
He wants to make updates in some
of those updates.
But any just dependent on whatever he did
and see if
okay if they are very dependent on CAA
let's say by chance
they were dependent on CAA,
then he will be creating it for CAA.
But if they are independent
then he will be creating for
the file. That's six.
Is this clear to everyone?
I said now maybe is like kind of what
it to your already I guess
I'll agree so
as we are not dependent on CAA
the updates to be made in sun I'm
not dependent on what we didn't see it.
We will be creating a new branch
out of five guests
and six
sun updates.
So let's go to our user
who was working on to that.
Which one is that?
Yeah, that's funny.
So he was first
checked out to the main branch
and then he will create a new branch
name sudden update
and then he will check to this
an update.
Okay he is in and sun updates
now kept to minutes.
Read this one and let me know.
Oh you deleted your watch.
Just you have it on your remote right
that from your work
so let's open up our intelligent
and let's have a look at the
funky one.
Okay so
simply we'll go to our
solar system.
Maybe
and we will change the name from moon to
planets.
No, no, I'm sorry, son.
I'm just one sun. So let's see. Let's.
I want to change this. Time to end.
So that's one update that we did.
I also want to, in my name,
make this an integer,
that this temperature
best known in digital world.
So integer
being 17.
Okay.
So the updates that you need,
we can update the template.
Just string to end.
And then when we made the update
that we just
changed the temperature
and moved the and got it.
Come on.
Okay, you guys let me know
once you are done with this.
Okay? The next step is to
make a upcoming so get add dot
get comment
that share the updated
features of sun.
Then add.
Okay. Yeah. Good.
We made the comment
I'm going to show you on simulation.
We simply made a comment like this.
Pretty nice and simple.
It does from here.
And the name is nine
Learning
just like this.
Okay, guys, so let's come to the point
where are we going to merge
everything before that,
I want you guys to tell me
I need to push some of this to do mode
or to right.
So simply I'll go to my funky
head of said get push dash.
You are edge and
sun of the
Oh yeah do that to.
Okay now tell me,
do you want to resolve them on GitHub
or do you want to resolve these conflicts
on a local computer?
Make sure
that both are going to be just the same.
So let's choose one platform
and we can work over do
a branding
which was used more at work.
Well, if you are an experienced person
and you trust team, these are teammates
that they will be working time that
obviously you'll be using GitHub more.
Yes, that's right.
But if you are an inexperienced person
who does not trust your teammates,
then he is going to use the local one.
You need to download that check.
Go to my one
and then you will be doing all the stuff.
So at work, mostly GitHub is used
because they don't have time actually to.
You know, that's your logic and stuff
you don't do.
They don't do that.
Well, imagine in a company that
a person is no
checking your codes again and again.
Now we have leaders coming to you.
Hey, show me out, Show me a cool letter.
So this just doesn't work over there.
Everyone is responsible for their role.
So if you mess up your images
from home and
some dangerous use.
So when you have
that kind of responsibility,
trust me, your your brain,
it doesn't let you make mistakes
it makes sure that you are responsible
enough to do that
break.
Right.
Let's give a break to Dan and oh,
how about that?
I think you guys need great excuse
for breaking it
at 730.
Let's meet at 1145.
Okay. You want 10 minutes?
All of you are good with ten.
15 is good. Okay. I hope to fortify
and then we'll be
resuming from this point.
But so
we are back.
And let's start
there.
We left having
pushed the next branch on GitHub.
Yes, we have got this sun up.
This officer.
Let's open
the GitHub, Let's go to our system
that lets you branches up.
Okay, so we have the moon one, two and sun
updates on this particular
branch.
Okay, Now let's do one thing.
Let's start opening up the pool request
and most branches
one by one.
So let's first of all merge
the branch seven
into the main branch.
So what do you guys think?
What kind of merge is supposed to happen
When we was one
with the main four,
it's going to be fast.
Very much so.
Something like this is going to happen.
Right?
Okay.
So we will go to our pull request.
We will go to now new upon request
and then the base should be made
and we should incorporate
more one.
And with that
we okay, now create one request.
The one has been added.
We merge
that nick on create pool request for
good.
Right.
Okay.
So as this is a password merge,
I told you guys that are not going to
no conflicts when we are doing a pass.
All right.
So it's good
value to be merged.
Thank you.
Because is the comment that we can have
I'm just showing you that command
right now, a chat history
regarding a particular branch
and then simply merge full
and confirm the month.
Let me show you the code
move.
One feature has been added
is merge into my main branch.
So this is something that we are done.
We let me know
when you guys are done to this point
and then we can proceed further.
Well, to delete a branch, you can
let us try
to delete this planet too
because we do not need it.
Right? So
go to settings
but things we can do it from here.
Let me just quickly check the
branches,
actions and security
system
for somewhere zero here.
I just forgot that.
Okay. So
you do
okay.
View all matches and then okay.
Perfect scenario.
You need a branch,
you simply click on your branches
and then we can delete them from here.
So if you want to do one,
we can simply click on this button
and it's going to be deleted.
We want the planet to
get to leave that to
now. Planet one on Planet
two are not visible.
Okay, so now let's open up a pull request
to merge
a start
A first,
let's say we want to avoid sun updates.
First of all,
I want you guys to tell me one thing is.
The merge going to be of it or not?
No, it's not going to be
if that's our merge because the committees
we have changed
is there going to be any conflict?
Okay.
Is there going to be a conflict
way, way
and do not just copy
one of what people are saying?
Use your brain
and then tell me, will there be conflict
that be So when does a conflict occur?
First of all, let's review that.
No, that's not the product you is change.
Remember I told you that a conflict occurs
where the same lines are changed
by two different
persons, when same lines are changed
by two different persons.
And then there is a conflict
because given is unable
to decide that,
which one do you want to keep?
Remember?
So now tell me, do you guys think that
there will be a conflict?
Let me show you what changed to solve it.
We changed it to end and in our main
we changed it to
this one.
Was this change by anyone else? No.
So when get made the branch
this town was different
and now in the branch it was added.
But now when it's going back,
when we are merging it,
it's still the same.
When this particular branch
was made right.
The history of this particular line
has not changed
at that point.
So the history is still the same.
When spine to merge that back
put the line,
then there should not be a conflict
according my concepts.
Right.
So as everyone hear about this
that there is not going to be a conflict.
It's anyone who is unclear, not sure.
Let me know.
We can go into more depth of this
and have this conversation.
Okay, so you guys and
so let's try to open up the pool request
and let's make a new pool request.
So that updates
able to merge, create, pull request.
I'm not going to put any message.
I'm just tired of that
say checking
the ability very do no conflicts
because the history is same of that
particular line
when the branch was created
multiple requests from
and we are all over
no conflicts at all.
But this time
the strategy use was a little different
and it was a premium march.
We now we want to march
this one to
tell me, will it be faster? Much
not a lot fast,
but at the end
it's going to be other coercive
merge that is going to happen.
Are so let's create info request going to
be equal requests
to create request.
Okay.
Says that this branch has conflicts
that must be resolved
and these are the conflicts.
Let's have a review.
Okay.
Now it's
giving us
those particular
few pieces of code that were in conflict.
But I left some space intentionally right?
I left some space intentionally
in order to avoid the conflict.
But still, it's giving us this conflict.
Why is that so?
Part?
Yeah, well,
a big spaces, just like spaces, Yes.
So what we did
is that this code is very similar
to this one, right?
Like almost everything,
all the lines are same.
So giving you a little bit intelligent to
sort it while merging it.
It recognized that
although the line spaces are not the same,
but still this code
is like very much close to each other.
So there might be a conflict.
There might be, there might be not.
So instead of doing everything
on its own, it gave you the
authority to choose.
Which one do you want to keep.
So you just simply remove these names
and then also like remove the space.
And I would say, okay, now
these variable names,
I don't want to have the same one,
so same mental one
then one one and one.
Okay.
Do you guys get this concept that
why are we having a conflict over here
although the left spaces.
So it's a good thing for us right because
the variable names were all the same.
So we wanted to know that
if we had not named them
same, same then most probably
there wouldn't have been a conflict.
But that's why we are putting a conflict
that that's a good thing.
We know now that this button up
code needs some amendments.
Obviously, that's resolved that conflict.
Click on Mark as resolved
and then commit merge.
No conflicts
other little from merge and everything is
up to date
in our solar system.
So what we should.
Well what of the code is more complex.
So Mohammed,
the first thing is that you would be
obviously two people
who are voting on the same project.
The probability
of having the same variable
is very less. Why?
Because
you name the variables
in an intelligent way.
You name them so that
they define what ever you are doing.
So if you're already given
different features
that obviously you will be having
different variable names.
But if you get the same name,
then they are going to be errors and bugs
and you need to like debug it.
So obviously
it is not going to do everything for you.
There is some caution
that you have to do on your own to.
So that is this is the complete
workflow of our branch
and you see how
simple it becomes
when we are working on this using branches
and stuff
to work on the same project. Yes.
And that's because we are using
the same variable name.
And apart from that also
we are also having seemed like a pool.
So that's why
now because there is a
merging and
resolving conflicts
clear to all of you,
you just have to be very clear
about the concepts we are using.
Very simple code.
That's the reason I use doesn't look good
just to make sure
that all of your concepts are clear.
Over all of these classes.
I tried my best to incorporate each
and every use case that benefits,
but still there will be some scenarios
which I hope
it will be impossible
for me to go through, because
obviously all of you,
when working with be using
different kinds of approaches
to, you know,
work on branches and stuff like that,
you will be using different approaches.
But if
you understand the concept of everything,
how a conflict arises to resolve that,
how does it happen?
If you understand
these concepts, I am pretty much sure
that you will be able to easily
resolve them and work your throughout.
So this project is going to be
a very good practice for all of you
to actually work on it
also and get your hands dirty or do
anyone who has any problem
while working on the project
and doing it in
the settlement shall tag me
and I'll be there
to help you out with the get part.
Okay, so now of your comments, simply
click on these comments that we have
and if you want to any
at any particular version,
simply on
the code that we have for this
that talks us to
that, it takes us to that particular code
and what else we can do.
We can also click browser at this point.
It would then work out,
which would be like our
that was up to this point
to the first commit.
If I want to have this go up,
I can simply download the zip file
for this code
and I can have this put the source code
on my system.
So that's a shortcut way of getting
to previous comments,
taking them in your system if you want
a previous version or something like that.
One of the things
that I wanted to show you is that
I don't want you guys to follow me.
I'm just going to show you on my system
with the correct
use of one second.
Okay?
So just pay attention
to whatever I'm doing.
We know how to write someone.
We can call if you want to, but right now
we are not doing that.
Okay, guys.
So over here, what we see
is that we see a lot of comments
that are one, two, three, four,
five, six, seven.
So at any point in time
we want to just delete this comment.
You want to read this, come in
and do that.
Okay.
How will this coming?
We will never guess that.
Okay.
To the command to delete your command.
It's not recommended.
First of all, I not teach you that, but
it's not recommended.
Make sure that when you are making
comments you are very vigilant about it.
But obviously you can,
you know, by mistake.
Some make some make a comment
and you want to.
That can happen.
So in order to welcome it,
you will simply use the
command, get reset.
That's
my typing
for you.
So that's the command that we use
to delete the
first coming,
the latest one and move our hat
to the second last comment.
Get reset.
I had one
so you will see when I run
this command might he did user
the one is going to disappear.
So let me run this
and now let me show you the last.
Is that the move
the the last of it that we had?
Yes, that's removed.
So that's how you made your leave
your comments in the
local repository. But.
Okay,
So now if you want to observe, delete
this particular command in your import
repository, you have pushed it
and you want what you needed from
over there also.
So what's the activity that.
Okay, so
let's see,
we can use the command we push, but right.
Not saying that it's not possible. Why?
Because we deleted one
which was already there in the requisite
three and not seen that there is already
some of in order to do this push,
we have a command
which is with push force.
So we have to force push it
and then it's going to be deleted
on the remote.
What about the history?
The command is gone now delete it.
We have deleted it.
There is way to restore that.
But I don't remember.
The command
did restart.
Maybe
not the person is not pleased or
let me set them up.
So if we use get reset command
you can have that come back.
This is the syntax for that.
So whenever you need it simply no ruler
is meant to be your best friend.
Okay, so now let's discuss
a few other things that we have and
yeah,
one thing that I wanted to discuss
with you guys
in your settings on GitHub,
whenever you want someone to collaborate
and work on your app
is typically what you do.
You simply
go to the settings of that repository
and then you go to collaborative of.
Then you have to get the best
before you get up.
Give me a moment.
Let me check my password.
I think after that
you add people, so add people and get
someone would give me the yo yo user name
anyone.
You have that file.
But I have not
unfortunately had anyone
so that's going to be here.
I'll click on ADD
to the user and now the person I sent in.
Why do you need to go to your Gmail?
What it is associated
with this particular GitHub with
you are going to have a message.
You go to that email
and you will see a pattern
in why you need to accept that can work
and then you will be able to work on this
so I can go ahead
and just accept whatever.
So I'll just
also in the right circle
and just to give you guys an idea
at people
and to people out there.
So that's how I'm inviting these people
to work on my right.
So now Say has accepted my request
and she is a collaborative now.
She can work on this particular episode.
So now she let me make a push
and pull from this very
so whenever you want your friends
to work on the same project,
invite them as a collaborator.
And apart from that, in the branches,
we have some branch protection rules.
So if I want to add some rule
on the main branch,
I can click on Add rule
and they are going to be different
protection techniques
which I can have for this branch that says
acquire pull request before merging.
So whenever anyone wants to
merge he has to
make upload request force
the data pool request.
There is not going to be unloads
like an animal
this and no one is going to be able
to push to my branch,
almost to my branch,
without making a pull request.
And in order to approve the request
required approvals,
I can see of approvals required before
it's able to merge,
I can select one that's upon me.
Okay.
So then other options are also there
that we can
check in
or check out if you want to, have them.
So these are stuff that you can do
with the branch
protection rules.
We can also change the branch and select
any other boss over here, move
one more to whatever.
But unfortunately we cannot
restrict users to push in
main using these rules.
We can restrict them one merging data,
but we cannot restrict them
from pushing the domain directly
in this limited version.
For that I can.
We have to go for enterprise rules.
Last time I checked,
that was the scenario of, I don't know,
maybe they have updated something or not.
But last time it was not like that.
So guys, please make sure
that none of you is pushing and I'll be
on. What else do you need inside?
We have discussed about it.
We can have a look at the network
from over here.
And then I need your opposite tree.
I'm going to show you how can delete it.
So in I'm Indonesia
opposite to you go to settings
and then at the end you see
delete this represent you can delete.
And once you have entered this
and deleted this, you cannot have it back.
I mean, maybe
show you
some of the tools that we have on our
that help.
So this is one of the three
of one of the previous is
31 coming to start on me
if I show you development
night set up main
Wow so they have named it after do
own matches
pool requests.
There's only one request that is pending
and you guys can see the how they have,
you know
now name them fixed
all the unrelated variables.
Code one
night star has been added
updating my step and feature file
the project update update.
Some status
details are updated from the example.
So everything is no right align.
That's the project
of one of our previous batch
which needed
Don't
let me show you
the government history also.
So this is the first comment that I made
this the basic structure of the project
which I will be uploading
and from over there
you guys will be working.
What is going to be the workflow?
I'll let you know tomorrow.
And then each and every one of them has a
contribution.
DEADLINE
How did you
you collaborators who accepted you, right?
So simply,
I'll go 2 seconds of this collaborators,
and I can see that only group was pending.
The other people have accepted.
So now you are a collaborator
and so one is also
collaborate.
Okay, now
some other information about GitHub.
So on GitHub,
you guys going to find out we have it
how you are programing, you
need anything like any coding stuff,
you can have that on GitHub.
It is a very important, which
is being gained by a lot of big companies.
For example,
if you want to have a selenium Docker
container image,
so you can simply write non
selenium Docker
image.
Yes, I've shown the out you see in.
So there are two branches
from that selenium tree
that they're working on right now.
Over here the whole code is uploaded
but this particular
repository, there are 108 contributors
and there is a detail read me
so I know you will be working on project
and will be also adding a read me
and there will be a detail instructions
about what
this repository is about.
What is this community
about how to start this project,
what kind of browsers it uses
and what are the different demands
that you can use over there?
What is a hub and what is a node?
And using different violent machine,
what you need to do.
Like a lot of information
there is in there
everything that you need to know
if they have a very good document of that.
So this is the documentation
of this particular project.
This is an open source.
So that's
why everything is visible to everyone.
But obviously
when you do work in companies,
you guys are not going to be
working on open source thing.
We will be working on some
dedicated task of
Now this for stuff I went through.
It's very simply that my work is used.
Let's say this is an open source project
and I want to work on it.
So I don't simply for this is different.
Working means
just like cloning this repository,
but in the sense that I'm able to
contribute to it without being invited
as a collaborator,
I can contribute to this positively
without being invited as a collaborator.
So I can simply make some at it
this and have a clear request. Open
the review my code of the thing
that I have made some work contribution.
Then they can simply help me out to.
They can simply do the emergency.
Thank you to me.
I they'll say, Hey, stay away from that.
That's it.
So for me is something that you guys
will not be using forever.
Okay.
So any questions
that you may have let me know else
I think we are pretty
much done with everything
related to better.
And that will be so vital.
One that's for any questions
that you may have.
And then we can end our session today.
We will be having a session tomorrow
in the morning and evening seven
to discuss the project
and give you the best.
Well, nobody don't
even because you are not going
to the right email address, a lot of you
are going to make this mistake.
Make sure that you visit the same address
with which you have registered.
You get out in order to see what.
No, you will get that.
Okay.
Any more questions?
No questions.
I'll be all good now
let me get because that was easy.
Really?
Okay. Silence on this one too.
But now I'm confused.
Maybe it was easy.
Or maybe it was vague.
So what do you guys think?
That is easy or difficult?
Well, that's a very,
you know.
Yeah.
So it depends it
depends upon a lot of factors.
What? Just tell me about the concepts.
Like all the concepts
that we have discussed.
Obviously it's not going to be like that.
You will not have to work on it.
You have to do the project,
you have to spend some time on it,
then you will be very comfortable. But
the concepts aren't the all clear to you.
Do you guys
okay, don't be nervous
before making a comment.
Even if you mess it up, you can always,
you know, the lead
up and going into
is it all about get
yeah that's all about that was is in full
that's
I think we have a lot of information
that we discuss
Oh well guys listen I remember one thing
I shared
with you.
I shared with you guys
the diagrams, remember,
in which we have all the basic steps
you guys have those diagrams with you.
Okay, So
let me just open them up.
So these diagrams
are going to have real life.
So just make sure that when you get lost,
you revisit them
and you know
your basics.
Just realize them apart from these basics,
I don't think you will be confused
about anything else.
Everything is going to be very much geared
to our Yeah, it's on canvas.
It's there.
I uploaded the slides
also the slides I'll for you
that to you.
So these are the slides
I go at each and every slide
only I think
this slide is left.
It's a little bit about centralized
weeks, distributed weeks and
local.
So is something that is your homework.
You guys are supposed to read it and
you'll get the idea of what it is actually
stashing. I have a slide for that.
Do branches a little bit life or death
password much and most conflict
and when does of it arrives.
These slides are also available for you
on the canvas.
You can have them go to them and read them
and the notes.
I will be uploading them too.
I think that
okay, class six and seven
notes are combined
taken out there.
I hope that
now you guys
will be showing me
good results in the good project there.
That's that's the one where I don't know
whether I have done a good job or not.
So I'm looking forward to that.
And the previous three batches, really,
they may be crowded.
No one had, you know, even a single posted
and the support chatter that I didn't get.
So I'm expecting the same from you.
We did a lot of practice.
We spend a lot of time
and I'm pretty much sure that you guys
will be able to do the project
on your own, at least a big part.
I trust you guys just make sure that you
are following the steps one by one.
And one of the more important thing in
whenever you are working on your project
is to work in a team as a team.
So if anyone is having trouble,
you guys have to help them out.
You leave them and,
you know, get the project,
tried to do the project,
just help that person out, use GitHub
platform to communicate with each other,
help out each other, try to
make others.
That's the opportunity there.
You will be learning
how you actually work together as team
and how you help each other
to reach the same level that you are.
No, I would never showing you that
because I highly describe that.
In fact, I don't like it.
I tough on lira, trust me.
Like the previous batches.
Few students figured that figured it
and I also showed them in one class.
But I strictly mentioned as good
not not to do that anymore.
Not to teach students
how to use intelligent to push
and do stuff like that.
So there is there's a reason behind that.
And that's that reason is that
most of work working might not be using
intelligent.
You might not be using that.
You might be working on
something different. I mean,
and one
other reason is that when you guys start
using automated
to like intelligent work with you,
you forget the come out of it.
You don't even bother to go over there.
And that's the biggest mistake.
You forget the workflows,
you start making mistakes
and everything is, you know, messed up.
Well, I don't I'm
pretty sure that once
you know how to use it in an intelligent
you will be using that because we all us
find a way to do it easily.
So I would love to comment
that it will disturb you.
It will disturbed your workflows.
And apart from that,
you can never actually, you know,
use that much power to debug your errors
and maintain a smooth workflow.
Using that is all you can do
is make a bit of an addict.
And you know, sometimes that's
that's all you can do.
So I don't want to do that.
That's a favor from my side to you.
You will get that in
maybe one or two years.
You'll know that was right about it.
Not right now,
but you will let us have enough
of it.
So anything else
before
looking
for someone to ask me
about the tab that we have.
So let's have a look at them to
think,
Well, these are issues.
You can open up a new issue
if you want to.
So most probably you will not
be using this even if you want to.
You can simply use tab in GitHub
that allows you to
post some kind of issues over here.
So let's have a look.
Let's try to create one.
There is a plug
in We
each branch
and the details.
You can assign this
issue to different people and
you can
label it also.
So whenever you
someone can click on this issue
and have that, okay,
there's a bug in the feature, but
okay, let me have a look at that.
So let's assume that one of your friend
is having some issue,
which is which he is unable to resolve,
so he can simply post issue
with the assign it
to one of his other friends.
Maybe you guys have time to address.
Maybe you guys are unable to communicate
via one chat
at the same time one is working at night
and one is working at day.
This kind of differences might be there,
so if you need someone helps,
you can simply use create an issue
to go and assign
that that particular person
which you think can help you out.
And he is going to just view the issue
and say, okay, how can I help that person?
Maybe I'll go to this going into my own
repository and I'll try to resolve it.
So this is
our issues is going to help you out
once that is the scenario,
then you guys can have a communication
on that issue.
I checked it.
The problem is in your semicolon,
let's say, and you can comment on
our try using this updated code
and you can post up here.
So whenever he was here, you have this
mark on his issue and I would see, okay,
so I need to make these changes,
something like that.
And you guys can basically, you know, I'm
going to get over here, will request
you all know what is that actions.
This is something that
we want we talking about.
This is the advanced features
that GitHub was has
with all the tools which we can integrate.
There are going to
be see, I see the pipeline,
but They are usually
paid they are not free most probably.
Yeah, they are pre
and then the projects
we won't be discussing anything
about project also
because we do not have any wiki
is again
going to do left like this security
this thing that is you know
will be under the team lead or the one
who is one of the representatives.
So I guess you will also
be not needing that inside.
So we have discussed that you only need
to know about net for other stuff
that's not that much needed,
but you can always
in the settings.
The important one was
how to invite collaborator and branches.
The next next ones are something
that I think that it's
okay even if we don't cover them.
So that's all about GitHub.
Thank you all for your time
and tomorrow is
not going to be any recap,
No review tomorrow.
Tomorrow is just going to be
a one hour session in which you guys
will be giving a brief overview of how
to do your project and that's it.
Nothing else.
So make sure I'm sure all of you out there
who are not there, they can
watch the video recording later on.
And best of luck,
everyone, for your projects.
I really appreciate that
you guys put in your best effort.
That's
everything that you have until this point.
You guys will be practicing that.
So make sure that you spend
a lot of time on it
and review everything that you have done.
And after that,
you will be having just two more topics.
Maybe you want us to add an API
and then you will be graduating
and you will be in the job market
pursuing your dream of a good, handsome
salary,
working in the fields in real time. And
that's what we can go there, right?
So that's your time to practice.
I know this assistant project
is just for the example
you will be working on Index MSW.
Not so surprising.
How did you put that project?
I don't know.
I think you guys did.
You guys
notified about that?
You need to make
jobs.
What you guys know decide about that
are you do you already have rooms.
I don't know that
you can have groups already
so you will be working on the same group.
So I think minimum is at least
three people at a maximum
was like 5 to 7 people,
nor less than three.
So that's that's the requirement.
Okay.
So best of luck, everyone.
I'll see you guys tomorrow in the morning.
Sorry. Evening, everyone in for me.
And we will have that session.
Okay. Take care.
Have a good
day at.