Hey, guys.
Can you guys hear me?
So, everyone there?
You guys did pretty good.
Can you guys hear me?
Hey, guys.
How's it going?
How's everyone doing?
How was your day?
What did you do today?
What was the highlight of your day?
It's the
lawyers.
Gerald.
How's it going?
Works a lot
or not.
How did your testing all remain right?
Tendra.
Angelica.
The bill.
How are you guys?
The minor
Abdoul.
Mariam.
Amelia.
Millie. Did you change your name?
Wasn't it Emily Jo or something like that?
Lobo.
What's up?
BlueBell?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Is that my father's way
you change your name to Don't.
Terrible.
It's just terrible.
Terrible, terrible.
All right, let's.
All right.
Are you guys ready or are you guys ready?
It's ready for you.
That's ready.
All right, guys, let's get started.
Today's a very good day.
You guys know why?
Today is a very good day.
There's no way to beat that.
Well, yes, that's true.
But today's a good day,
because today is our last class together.
How cool is that?
That's cool, right?
That is a very, very good day.
No, I mean in a good way, right?
Because if you think about it,
I think my first class with you guys,
I told you that, like, time flies, right?
Right. I told you that.
I said the next few weeks,
we're going to be together.
And now it's time for me to say time
did fly by,
and it's going to continue to fly by.
Right.
So that's how fast time flies
throughout, you know, throughout syntax.
You know.
Now, before we start the class,
I want to say
a lot of you guys,
every single one of you guys
that has done
a very good job in this class.
Every single one of you has done
a very good job.
There are students out there
who where English is not
their it's not their first language.
And you guys, English is not your first
language.
Right.
I'm not going to say names,
but you guys did a fantastic job.
I can tell even when you guys were writing
the cucumbers scenarios,
you guys really understood the concepts.
Okay.
So and that was that was very good.
That was that was really, really good.
And this is not an English class, right?
I wasn't criticizing
the way you write English.
I was looking for other things. Right.
If you understood the
concepts, if you understood
how to kind of
write a cucumber scenario,
that that was, you know, decent.
That's right.
That was my my main goal. Right.
And a lot of you guys have done a very,
very good job.
So I congratulate you
for being very good on that part.
For those of you
who are taking this class,
an English is not your first language.
And for the rest of
you guys that were English
is your first language.
You guys also did a very good job right?
You were able to understand the concepts
and that kind of thing.
So everyone here has done a very good job.
And some of you guys are have
on the assignments and late,
which is completely fine.
You guys reached out to me and you guys
said, Hey, I wasn't here for this class.
I still turn on the assignment and stuff.
But the fact that you took time
to build it to do it,
to did it,
the fact that you took the time to do it
shows that you care, right?
Shows
that you're willing to put that effort.
I had some students that missed out
because maybe they were sick or maybe,
you know, life happens, right?
Some of you guys have jobs.
Some of you guys have families
You guys need to do to attend to.
Right.
So you guys some of you guys
still wanted reached out
and stole some of the assignments.
Right.
And so I congratulate you for
for doing that for yourself.
So today's class is going to be
a little different.
Today's class is actually going
to be very proactive.
It's going to be
just a little bit of review here
and there, but we're going to just heavily
work on JIRA.
Yesterday was kind of rushed.
You know, I tried to respond to everybody.
Some students missed out on some things
because maybe
I went too fast or maybe I didn't explain
something too well.
So today will basically be
just like yesterday's class.
And we're going to all be proactive.
We're going to help each other out.
We're going to communicate with each other
and that kind of and that kind of thing.
Okay.
Does that sound like a
like a deal to everyone
and sound like a deal to everyone?
Okay.
All right.
So that's what we're going to to do.
And I also want to say
and that's a good question, Fatma.
I also want to say that
everything that we learned, right,
while it may have been the first time
you've heard these words, it may have been
the first time you touched something
like JIRA right throughout the class.
Some things are going to start,
make more sense.
And at the end of the class,
we are going to review all of this again.
Okay.
So you're going to hear all of this again.
Okay. Does that make sense for one?
Most likely.
Maybe I can do the interview
review sessions with these, but
with these classes or any anything,
any other topic
if you want to go home.
All right.
So let's get let's get started.
I have some questions for you first.
Is there a way
you can make your volume higher?
I have no idea. I'm speaking very loud.
I think you have to put the volume
higher on your end.
Can everyone hear me?
That.
Does it sound low, guys? Does
it sound low?
I don't know.
Like this microphone?
Maybe it's crystal clear. Does it?
Is it good?
Okay.
Mohamed says a bit low.
Okay, So.
Okay.
Got it.
Got it, Got it.
You are cause for us to beat bags of money
after fight.
You are a cause.
I am a cause.
It's fine.
It's school, all right?
So I'm a cause.
I'm a cause.
Like, cause and effect.
Okay. All right.
So are we ready, guys? Are we ready?
Are ready or are we ready?
Okay.
And again, I want to say what was
the number one thing we learned yesterday
about asking questions?
Right.
And I'll repeat what I said yesterday.
Again, just in short, basically,
if you have questions, right,
ask the questions.
Okay. Don't be shy. Don't be scared.
Don't be afraid.
There is no such thing
as a stupid question in my book.
You can no such thing.
Okay.
Does that make sense to everyone?
No such thing as a stupid question, right?
No such thing.
So why are you scared of me?
Guys, I'm possibly the nicest person
you'll probably ever meet here at Gitex.
Yeah.
So. All
right, so there is a
someone saying. Yeah, right.
Okay, now
you make us believe that there are no
there are no dumb questions, right?
I'm also not a drill sergeant.
Look, I just wanted to make it clear
yesterday to everyone,
right, that basically
if you have questions, ask the questions.
Okay.
Because, like,
I want you guys to be successful.
But there's a difference, right?
When I'm telling
you guys not to do something.
And then you guys go and do it
and you guys mess up
the whole JIRA board and stuff, Right?
And that's why I'll call you.
I'll call
you kids or something like that. Right.
But am I wrong or am I?
Am I not? What?
So, like, you put yourself
in the same situation, right?
You want to you want to carry
on a whole class yourself.
You want everyone to pay attention to you.
Most of the class is listening.
But then some students are just,
you know, in their own world.
Right? And you can't really
stop, right? You just got to
say you're willing.
Everyone else's module, that's it.
But I just like to keep it 100 with you.
Right.
So that's fine.
All right, so let's get started.
So let's talk a few things first. And.
And Yes, and it's. Excuse me. Pardon me.
It is my fault.
I did not share my notes
from the last two classes.
Okay, So I still have to share that
with you guys, but
I will still share that with you.
And, you know, keep them, review them.
We'll touch the materials again.
We're going to revisit that stuff again.
Okay.
This is not just a
you learn it in three weeks and that's it.
You never hear about it again.
We're going to revisit it again.
Yes. The point you're going
to get all the slides, everything good
1 to 2 and I'll make sure to
to message right now.
But it. Okay.
Yeah.
I think sometimes we
click the wrong button like today I did.
And that's okay. Right.
Let's just try to follow instructions.
Right. If you get lost. Right.
If you're not sure
if we should click something, then ask.
Right?
Ask and should we?
Good to go
or good?
Are we good? Right.
So I didn't play with Jared yesterday more
than we're supposed to, but it was it.
That's fine.
It's cool when you start your job
and you accidentally start
touching things,
let me know how that goes.
Okay, so.
But you know that
that's the whole point, right?
So if you have questions, ask
and that's fine.
Cool question.
The gamer players are going to be know
class will end before ten today
or 10 p.m. Eastern time,
10 p.m.
Eastern time.
So, again, a lot of you guys are saying,
you know,
you accept, you accidentally click
a button or something like that, right?
It goes, We all make mistakes.
That's fine.
We all make mistakes.
But at work, are you going to accidentally
click a button
or are you going to click a button
without knowing what it does right.
All right.
So and here's the thing, right?
We had another user story
here, right? In progress.
We had the one that I gave you
the task for homework and so moved it
for some reason.
That's beside the fact and I have to go
and look for it.
The homework assignment
was what this segment to work on.
What user story was, the homework on
what?
No, I changed it.
Was it one
had an employee, right.
An employee
and an
employee.
Okay.
See something
was amiss.
B 11 Right.
It must be 11 one.
But look, someone moved it back.
But perhaps, maybe the person
that moved it by accident.
Right. To the to do column.
Thank you very much for moving it back.
I see that it was also changed
from a story to a test.
So that's
cool. So.
All right, guys, let's get started.
Okay. I want to review some of these.
Someone changed the description
I sent, and we're tasked with directing
someone.
Change the description.
I said task.
Okay, so before we get into this
JIRA thing, I got, let's let's talk about
a few things. What is zero?
What is JIRA?
JIRA is a project management tool, right?
And is JIRA the only project management
tool that exists
now? Right.
There are other ones, other ones that
that you may end up working with, right?
There's HPL, there's different tools.
Rally is your DevOps.
There's there's so much, there's
so many other tools
that you'll probably work with it.
It all depends on the project.
Okay, but JIRA is the most popular one,
which is why we are showing you
how to work with Xero.
That now everything in JIRA, every ticket
that is created
in JIRA is known as what
as an issue, right?
So issues are also known as tickets.
Right?
And so far we've worked
with stories, right,
with user stories and we know what tasks.
All right.
So this is how a user story looks like
and this is how it test
looks like right here. Okay, Well,
okay, great.
Let's see, what else about JIRA?
Yesterday we had a ceremony.
What ceremony did we do together
yesterday?
What ceremony did we do?
What ceremony that we do?
Sprint, sprint planning.
There you go.
Sprint planning.
And if you remember yesterday's
class in the sprint planning meeting,
what did we end up
what happened in that meeting?
Like?
What happened at the sprint
planning meeting?
We assigned level of efforts, right?
We gave estimates. Okay.
And but what hours?
Like hours for what?
I was Hours for what?
The development hours and testing.
There you go.
That's what we did yesterday on
and just like that, what else
can you tell me about that sprint
planning meeting we were working with?
What artifacts?
Like we were here right?
And what were we working with?
You guys remember
the backlog. Right.
And once we gave the item a estimate,
what did we do?
We moved it right.
We moved it to the sprint, right?
We moved it to Sprint.
Call.
So we moved it to the sprint.
So segment
that sorry,
I see that some folks created
Sprint yesterday.
Clean this up
just so that we don't get confused. Oh,
and once you delete the sprint
all of its contents
so we have
Joseph we have Irina NASIR.
Not that me now,
but I'm Ron to all of these tickets.
Okay.
I'm going to move them to the backlog.
You linked it to the wrong sprint.
Okay, so let me ask you this.
Right?
When we don't link things properly,
what happens to them sometimes,
like what
Essentially what ends up happening?
Well,
they get lost, right?
It's kind of hard to look for them now.
They exist, right?
We just have to go and look for them.
So I'm doing this.
I'm moving
the service of that to the backlog.
I'm going to move this one
that doesn't have a name.
I'm going to move this one over
and then I'm going to meet
Sprint to.
All right.
Now at at work.
Okay. I'm at work
every not everybody has
the same rights to grow.
Okay.
Obviously, they will protect
they will control who can do what.
We can do certain things. Okay.
So here we have this t sprint
one created by.
No, no, I'm going to move your ticket
back to the backlog
because you get to the wrong sprint.
Okay.
So I'm going to go all
the way to the backlog.
All of this backlog
C scroll and there you go.
And I'm going to delete the sprint,
please.
No one else creates sprints
because I just made this
right.
So cool.
All right, so we're here.
All right. Let's see.
Do we have training your page
so we don't mess with real syntax page?
This is the training page to get.
This is the the training page.
You get cool.
So you just got to kind of follow
through with it.
We can think of something.
I can talk to them if you want to.
You know, We'll see.
All right.
So what else did we learn about JIRA?
We learn how to create a task.
We learn the linking, right.
When we're linking a ticket
to another ticket
or an issue to another issue,
what are we doing there
when we're linking?
Like, what are we doing?
What what what is that called?
Like when when we are linking
any issue to another issue, Right.
What are we doing there.
No, not, not copy name like we are.
What are we doing?
We're not assigning.
So when we are linking a ticket
to another ticket, any ticket,
any any of them, what are we doing
there with these tickets?
No, no, we're not us.
I'm not talking
about user starship testing.
I'm talking about any issue.
It can be any issue.
We're not comparing them
when we are linking
a ticket to another ticket,
guys,
when we are linking to tickets together.
What is that?
What are we doing there?
It means that we are establishing
a relationship with
with those issues, Right?
They somehow relate to each other right.
And somewhere. Right, guys,
we talk about that.
You guys remember, right.
For example, yesterday
we had the user stories.
Okay?
And the reason that we were linking
our tasks to the user stories is
so that when I come here to the user story
right, and I open it right,
if I open this, I can see
the links here.
I can see the links to to this one.
Okay.
I can see if we'll link that and it shows
like you see, I can see tested by right
and I can see all the tasks
that were created and they're linked here.
Okay.
So we are establishing this relationship,
all the tasks that you guys created
and if you linked it properly,
they would be linked here, right?
So I'm saying, you see
and this is what would tell you this h.r.
Must be to admin user log in
which was we worked on yesterday.
If i open this ticket in a new tab.
Okay.
And i opened the ticket
and if i go down to issue links.
Right, it says show 87 more links.
And this is this issue is tested by
and it's all of these right.
So that makes sense.
But there are some folks here
that when they did it,
they selected the option blocked by.
Okay.
Do you guys remember when I told you
what to select when you're linking?
Right.
I said to make sure that it says tests.
Because now those folks that select block
buy it doesn't make sense.
Right?
Like this issue is blocked by these tests.
It doesn't make sense.
You guys see this now
and some folks that I see that
had not created multiple tickets
for some reason,
I'm not sure why,
but we can see that you linked it
and it's not properly linked
because it's blocked by at work.
This would be a big deal
because this user story is not blocked.
Right.
We don't when we're saying is blocked by
this is a big issue.
This issue can
this user story
can probably be blocked by a bug.
But nothing else.
Okay.
This doesn't really make sense.
So we need to fix this. Okay.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to
Lenny also linked it
and this is blocked by this is why
whenever we do our linking, we need to pay
very close attention to that.
So I'm going to exit this.
I want to delete these links here
because they don't make sense.
Right.
And I want to see something else here.
So, okay, now it looks good, right?
So now when we open this issue. Right.
And let me first page it from as we to
I open the story,
I see the acceptance,
what can we call this interconnect?
You can call it anything you want,
as long as you understand
that there is a relationship
that you're establishing
within these tickets that you can get in
JIRA, we link it, right?
So we call it linking.
And here
now we see all
the issues that you guys created, right?
So it looks like a lot of
you guys did a very good job,
except someone who created this ad,
an employee is linked to this.
I have to figure out who linked this here.
It shouldn't be here.
So I'm actually going to delete this link.
Right.
And I'm going to refresh the page.
Okay. Amnesty. That's right.
So all of you guys, look, look, this
this looks so neat.
A lot of you guys followed instructions.
We have the name.
We have your
we have the Kua, we have the server.
He didn't add the hyphen here, but
you guys see how readable this is, right?
I can go here, I can see the tickets.
I can see that
this ticket was created by Ahmed. Right?
I can see that this is not does.
I can see that this is Luis Cabrera's.
I could see this is Jimi's
I can see saw bonds, right so forth.
This is admin user log in.
So this is all. Yes, yes.
We're talking about yesterday's work.
Yeah, we're talking about yesterday's
work.
Does that makes sense?
Mean We're talking about yesterday's
work, right?
So this is all the work that we did
yesterday.
It looks like this year
follow the naming convention,
but he created a story instead.
So you need to change it to a task.
I'm going to remove it from here
because when you created it's not a story.
Okay. So
and just to do it for you,
this here, I'll open this a new tab
and you'll come here
and you can easily go here
where it's a story and you can change.
It goes to task, right?
And that's it, man. Problem solved. Right.
There you go.
And then we refresh it. Right.
It will be changed to a task right now.
Really change it for this year,
which wasn't this year
with students, humans, humans here
were is this year.
This year right here we change it.
See, it's a test done.
Well, okay, so I change it, right?
So we need to be careful
with what we create at work.
So, for example, if you're creating a bug,
but you create a user story by mistake,
obviously you can fix it, but
you don't want to do that right
first time is okay, second time is okay.
But when you keep making the same mistakes
again and again and again,
they're going to start to think
that you're not paying attention
to the work that you are doing right?
Sharif
didn't follow the naming convention.
Okay.
So Sharif so Sharp didn't
follow the naming convention.
He just put his name there.
This is 41.
So if I open it, the scenarios gods,
it links it, right?
But for some reason,
he said, blocks this one.
I don't know why, but he didn't.
You didn't fix the naming convention,
so that needs to be fixed.
Okay. Okay.
And is to be fixed.
But look, everyone else very good.
We're here with in the Sierra.
It looks like this
here created another ticket.
For some reason and that's fine.
So, guys,
when you create a task or an issue
or a ticket in JIRA,
you don't have to create another one.
You can just added the same one. Okay?
You just have to be careful
with how you're creating it,
where you're linking it to
and that kind of thing.
Okay.
Oh, Danny, Alexis,
someone said just testing
whatever it was, and
I can see who created this
mark to life or to life.
Just testing who's smart to life
is underwater.
Life is right to life.
27 That you MLB.com. Right.
So yeah, that wasn't that wasn't
part of the test yesterday, right?
So we're supposed to do that.
Okay, so this makes sense, right?
Look, we're saying this user story,
right, is tested
by all of these, and it shows like this
because you guys linked it well, right?
You guys linked it very good.
This here needs to change Chances
68. Right.
But then some of you guys selected tests
and you see now it doesn't make sense
because that user story does not test
these tests is the other way around
these tasks test this user story.
Does that make sense?
Right.
Does that make sense, guys?
So that's the kind of tricky part
with zero, we need to know
we need to be careful with what wording
we choose, right and so forth.
Sports makes sense.
So Christine Amar, just testing
again, Kazeem
mean, you need to change the way
that you have linked this.
Well, all right.
So that was just released to us.
And a lot of things happened, though.
A lot of things happened yesterday.
A lot of people went in there.
It changed a lot of things.
And I don't know why.
William as see 0901
gmail.com assign this to himself, right?
So you're already doing things
that you were supposed to do.
Okay. Does that make sense?
So who was that and what?
All right,
so we're here back in the board game.
And your task,
your homework task was to do
HMS B one, Right?
So I'm going to open it.
I'm going to look at it again.
And this is B one.
It looks like someone changed this, right?
What what was it before?
Yeah, this is what was there.
This is what was there.
But someone changed it.
And I know I want to call it.
What else are they?
And this is
what was the acceptance criteria.
And I can tell that a lot of you guys
did a very good job at linking.
You created the task.
I haven't read the scenario yet. Okay.
If the old and if the old
acceptance criteria doesn't make sense,
does that mean that you have to change it?
No, you don't change the acceptance
criteria.
You don't change the acceptance criteria.
Or who changes the acceptance criteria
out of project?
Who changes the system
script to the VA right.
The IT.
Okay.
So for those of you who read this
and said, Oh, this acceptance criteria
doesn't make sense, you are right,
It doesn't make sense.
And we purposely did that to make sure
that you were actually
that you would actually be able
to point that out.
Right.
So acceptance criteria, that's it.
And it kind of looks like a
and this was different, right?
Because it kind of
looks like a cucumber scenario, right?
Kind of looks like it.
Well, the thing is that in some projects,
like in my project, my B.A.
actually writes the acceptance criteria
in Cucumber scenario style.
Okay.
You write it in cucumber scenario style.
So sometimes I don't even have to write
a different scenario.
I can just use that one that you wrote.
Does that make sense?
So you're saying, Yeah, just copy paste.
That's it.
If the acceptance granted
does not make sense,
should we point that out somewhere
in the queue?
It does, yes.
Yes, you can.
That's very good.
Alan, you commented on the test.
Okay.
So anyway,
does that make sense to everyone?
So this one says
when user failed, first name, middle name,
last name, employee I.D.
and user and a user by the say
a lot of things that are off here, right?
Doesn't make sense. Right.
So we can change this right?
When a user fails and a user enters,
you say
and a user enters
a first name, middle name,
last name and employee I.D., Right.
And the employee the and clicks
save button, right?
Yeah, clicks, save button.
Okay.
Then the user.
Then the user has a different first
and last name
and the user doesn't have a middle name.
So this one looks like
this is talking about.
So this right here, it doesn't make sense.
Right?
There's a lot of things that are off
that don't make sense or like what?
This doesn't make sense.
So what do you do in this case?
You get this for work.
You don't you don't understand.
What do you get it right?
You ask A, B, A, okay.
But there are times
where you the bay, let's say
the bay is busy
and the bay can't respond to your email
right now.
They can respond to your to your chat,
your to your message.
Right.
You are still required to create a test.
You still have to create a task on it.
So it can be on the JIRA board. Right?
There are two things that you can do.
Okay.
I'm going to tell you this right
now. Right.
So what you do is this, yes, you can ask
for documentation, but we're assuming
that the bay is busy, that you can get
the documentation for some reason.
Okay.
So listen,
there are a few things you can do.
Are you guys ready?
There are few things you can do.
This acceptance
granted doesn't make sense to me at all.
So we're going I'm
going to tell you what I'm going to do.
Come.
First thing you can do
is this is a ticket.
No one can
know.
You don't you
don't bring things to the product backlog.
That is not your responsibility.
Right? The VA does that.
You guys are never to move
anything to the backlog.
And you guys don't.
You guys don't manage the board like that?
No, Q8 does.
No developer does either. Okay.
This is just like what the VA does.
They manage this stuff.
Sometimes the project manager can try to,
you know, be in there and stuff like that
and they can move things. That's fine.
But if the VA can't respond to me,
I sent a message.
I'm getting no response.
I have to show some progress, right?
I need to document
what I'm experiencing at the moment.
So there are a few things you can do
or a couple of things
actually that I would do.
This is a ticket.
So what I would do is
I would go to the ticket and scroll
down to the comments section.
Okay.
And I'm going to add a comment.
Okay. And I'm going to say,
need more
clarification on acceptance
criteria. Right.
And you can say I
reached out to
and I'm going to tag whoever
and you can type people here.
You see this,
someone say reached out to a cell.
Okay.
On on ten yesterday was 19, right?
October 19
time, 1920 21.
Right.
And there you go.
And now what a and then bam.
There you go. I documented that. Right.
Does that make sense, guys?
Does that make sense?
And you can mention things
like this. Yes, absolutely.
But even though you can say it,
you still need to document it.
Right?
You still need to documented
because remember
when we talked about word of mouth
being so valuable, Right.
What are you going to trust?
More documentation or word of mouth?
Which one are you going to?
Which one are going to trust?
Documentation. Right.
So at the same time, to protect myself
and to show progress.
Right. I didn't understand it.
I need clarification because
without clarification, I can't test this.
Right.
So I am going to come here, comment on it.
Because this is what I did call
and then tomorrow's standard meeting,
I'll be like,
yeah, for a time as B 11 one.
I just, I reached out to ASL
because I need more clarification on this.
So would you happen to have some time
today to discuss this acceptance criteria
with me, or would anyone have had to have
some time to discuss it with me?
Please?
And I also commented
that on the ticket. Right.
And that would be your daily stand up,
your daily stand up status code.
Does that make sense?
Are we going to have access to this class
practice more?
Yeah, well.
Well, be always on state of meaning.
What does that mean?
Be always on stand up.
I'll be okay.
Yes. Everyone is in the stand up meeting
everybody.
Right.
Are the business hours,
the A's, the developers,
the test, the the.
I'll tell you,
my project was on the calls.
The clients are on the call.
The business hours on the call,
the federals on the call,
the developers on the call.
The rest of the team is on the call.
So everyone's on the call.
Yeah, I changed the AC.
Was there. Okay.
No, it wasn't okay.
You're not allowed
to change the acceptance criteria,
but as testers, as a Q
way, am I allowed to change the acceptance
criteria?
Am I allowed to know
who is allowed to do that?
No, not even a little bit.
We can't change it.
Right? The VA right
now, if this acceptance criteria
needs to be changed
and you talk to the VA and the VA
says something like, Oh yeah, I wasn't
so clear on the acceptance credits yet,
but this is what you have to do, right?
You can tell the VA, okay, can you please
update the ticket to reflect that?
Right.
Well,
does that make sense?
It is only it only VA.
It could be the business analyst
or the project manager.
One of those two.
Okay,
but not the developers, not the testers
unless they're specifically
asked to do so. You got
not the
lead, but usually doesn't change
acceptance criteria or nothing like that.
Oh, the product owner.
Okay.
Do you guys know who the product owner is?
An agile environment.
The product owner
is not a manager.
Be as the boss. The head.
The investor?
Yes, the investor.
The product owner is the client, right?
They are the owner of the product
because they are
the ones that are paying for the product.
Does that make sense?
So they are not the project manager, okay.
They are on the client side
or so think of it like that.
Think of it like this.
They are the product owner.
They own the product, right?
And maybe that person didn't pay for
the whole project by themselves, right?
Maybe their team did,
but they assigned him or her, the product
owner go.
And that's and that's, you know, and it's
always going to be the client's
always going to be the client.
That's why it's called product owner.
PEO Product owners are seen as managers.
Sometimes they don't necessarily manage,
but whatever
they say goes right
because they are the broker.
They're the ones that are paying
the contractors to do the work right.
They are the client side.
So whatever the client's idea
is, is whatever the client says is
what has to be
what as to what has to go to be done.
It's it's the client
all. Could
you briefly explain team communication
daily, weekly calls and so on.
That's a scrum environment
you're talking about.
What exactly is your question?
You'd be more specific than that.
Like you guys know the scrum by, right?
You have your ceremonies,
you have your daily standards,
you have your other meetings.
What what exactly do you like?
What exact questions do you have?
They said Paul is the one communicating
with the customer.
It's the other way around, some sort.
Okay.
So in some projects and some projects
and just what I said,
the manager
between the client and the team.
So the thing is that the client side,
let's say the client is Google, right?
Google is truly the one that's
where the money is coming from.
Google, right?
So and and Google has its own teams,
they have their own teams and stuff,
and then maybe they assign
a few team members to with your team.
Okay.
So they will assign one of those members
the product owner role.
Okay.
And they are the ones that are considered
the product owners, Right.
And then they have their own team, Right?
So I'm sure that's what he meant to say
at some point, product owner MBA
communicates with client.
So the product owner,
what they can do is
even though they're owning the product,
they don't fully 100%
on the product, right?
So what they have to do
is, let's say the PR, let's say
you'll give us the PR
you work for for Google, right?
Google makes your product owner
for the project that we're working on.
I am the contractor,
you're the product owner.
So you kind of already know
what is expected.
You know what
the project needs to be, right?
So you tell us what has to happen.
So I am the contractor side.
Let's say I'm the program manager
and I will I will talk to you.
You'll get it and I will say, hey,
our team is doing this right.
Our team is doing this.
Is this good, Right?
And we actually show what we do
to your Geeta and her team, right?
And now you'll get a
has to grab the product
and has to kind of showcase that product
to the more internal folks of Google.
Does that make sense?
Does that make sense, guys?
So at that point,
it's really all the client side.
So the product owner is the client.
I mean, they are part of the client side.
Okay.
That's that's what you need to
that's what you need to understand.
Okay.
Now they deal with their internal meetings
separately and lot of their meetings.
You won't be in a lot of their meetings.
Actually, they have their meetings
of their own kind.
Does that make sense
that they are the ones that will tell you
the requirements that will sit down
with the business analyst?
I will talk the requirements
out, everything like that.
But And then when they need like
maybe when they need authorization
or they need permission
or they need to have their work reviewed
by someone else, the product owner
will reach out to someone else
at that point.
Okay.
So as a tester, what can we do
and what can we not do under oath?
Okay, that is a good question.
So, Indira, you will just be responsible
for moving and reporting your own tasks.
You will be able to create test
cases, you will be able to create
tasks if you're asked to,
but you probably most
likely would never be required
to create a user story.
Okay, That's not that's not your
that's not your role, Right?
That's more of a of a test.
Okay.
You also won't be able to mess around
with any of the developers work
because that makes sense.
You're only responsible for your work.
So. So you also won't be
starting a sprint.
You won't be moving things
from the backlog to the sprint backlog.
That's actually all done
by the bay and stuff.
But yesterday's meeting, we had like a
an example of how that meeting would go.
Okay.
So yesterday's meeting
I played the VA role
reports
basically linking issue and commenting.
Yes, exactly.
I keep track of your progress, right?
Yes. So so basically, we are restricted
not to mess up like yesterday
in a lot of
places, guys, they won't really restrict
you so much.
You'll have the freedom
to go and move tickets all over the board.
But it's not going to look good, right?
Especially like in a real project.
I know this is like a project
that we're showing you here,
but you guys remember like when we were
creating a new task and saw that message
that said this will change
the scope of the sprint, Right?
Do you guys remember that
message yesterday?
So those kind of things
will impact the project.
And when they generate reports,
it doesn't look so good.
Okay.
It doesn't look that great.
Testers are saying test for themselves
or the VA.
It can go either way for us, maybe the bay
or the team says okay, four assigned out,
take it to yourself.
Right.
So you would go to the board
and you will assign it to yourself.
Okay.
All of a sudden, this one to myself,
someone changed this again
for some reason.
So. Right.
So you'll come here and you'll.
You'll assign it to yourself in JIRA.
Who's the reporter in the ticket?
When you see Reporter Who's the reporter?
You guys know?
No, no. Who is the reporter?
No, no, no, no, no.
Who is the reporter?
I'm objecting to the answer.
The person that created the ticket.
That is the reporter.
Okay.
Right, guys, You guys remember
who was right here?
Do you see this right here?
Who is the reporter?
The person that created the ticket?
Okay, The person that created ticket.
And here it looks like it can be changed,
but at most in most projects,
you won't be able to change this. Okay?
You won't be able to change the reporter.
Well, and who was the assigned me
was the assigning.
Yes. You guys,
whoever or whoever is working on it.
Right.
Whoever is working on
ticket is the assignment.
It could be the developer if it's assigned
to them, it could be the tester.
Right.
So that makes sense. So
who creates the tickets?
Now, guys, we already talked about this.
We already talked about this guy, right?
Who creates the tickets, guys?
The business analysts. Right. The bias.
Most of the time they will create
almost all the tickets, right?
They're the ones that are going to be
writing the acceptance criteria
and stuff like that.
Right now, they may ask you to create
a separate task.
In that case,
that's a different type of ticket
that you may have to create yourself.
Okay.
So you may like this task
that we're creating.
You may be asked to create some testing
task just to keep track of your project.
Do you guys
remember
like when you guys had to install job
intelligence or Eclipse
or whatever it is you guys are using?
Right?
So when you start a project, right,
these are that
you may have to do some things like that.
You may be
there may be a task for you on the board
just to keep track of track of that.
Like, okay, Marvin used to install JDK
and Intel.
AJ Okay,
that's a to do. Is it in progress?
And in most companies you won't be able
to just go on Google
and install it yourself.
Helpdesk may have to do it for you.
You got another department of the company
may actually have to do that for you.
Yeah, it does.
Does that make sense?
Okay, cool.
Yeah.
Okay, cool, cool.
Does anyone have any questions so far
you guys are asking very good questions.
And again,
if it doesn't make sense, that's okay.
It's going to start to make sense later.
Okay.
You have to keep, you know, doing it
and and so forth.
Okay.
So yeah, exactly.
So first things let's just talk about this
high level
JIRA is a project management tool, okay?
It's where we basically manage
the project, right?
We have the backlog, we have
the requirements, everything like that.
And we're able to keep track of our work
there right?
So we have to keep track of our work.
There we go.
And this is what we can do.
What?
Yeah, we keep track of our work
and we get to show what we're working on.
Okay?
This is how we show our work go by.
Does anyone have any questions?
So anyone have any questions?
Go. Yes,
it is.
Is your software Agile project?
So this, this, this?
Yeah,
that it is.
So do we select Tester
or it was by default.
What do you mean?
What can you clarify your question more
you select that you your
you have to select it.
You have to change it.
Right.
Okay. So
I'm going to create another sample task.
Okay.
Before we can
we before we test the rest of users
for the remaining of the class,
we're going to create,
I'm going to move these
to the In Progress column.
Okay?
We're going to work on all the tickets.
It was.
I want to. Please don't move anything.
Please don't move anything.
What was the other one? So there's a move.
Anything.
Sharif was assigning this to himself.
Okay, so please don't remove anything.
So here's what I'm going to do.
I'm going to open h.r. Ms..
Three, and i'm going to basically do
what i did yesterday again.
Okay.
And i hope that some of you guys
can follow along.
You got
all right, so i open the
ticket, and this is the
the search and employee, right?
Is everyone paying attention?
So it was you
that asked questions yesterday
or saying how do you link
how do we do this?
Stuff like that? Right.
So I'm doing it again.
I'm doing it again, guys.
I'm doing it again.
Yeah.
So my attention.
So we open links in a new tab
and someone already
added a ticket to this and
so, okay,
so this is the acceptance criteria
and it's here.
All right.
And as an admin user, I should be able to
to search for an employee
by specifying employee name.
For some less.
As an admin user,
I should be able to search
for an employee by specifying employee.
So we have two requirements
basically and one user story
and that's completely okay.
So for this one, we need to write to
I at least two different scenarios.
Okay.
So what I'm going to do
is I'm going to click on Create.
Okay. So first of all, I'm
going to copy the name, right, right.
Copy the ticket, name
and then
know that was the task.
So I'm going to click Create
and I'm going to make sure
that this is selected to task.
I'm going to make sure
that this is not selected.
The story that is not above
that is not epic.
I'm going to make sure
that this is selected to task.
Are you guys following instructions?
Right, That's following.
And then what am I going to do here?
Going to place the name,
but first I'm going to say Q8 space hyphen
at the end and say hyphen
and then my name.
Right?
Okay. There you go. So I did this.
And what is next?
What are we going to do next?
So I'm going to scroll down.
I'm going to scroll down
and you see this right here.
This is the important part right here.
So those two, those tickets that said
block by are tested by something.
You need to make sure that this linked
issues, guys
says tests
at the time of creating the ticket.
I'm going stop right there.
Does anyone have any questions on this
part? No,
No questions.
Okay.
This everyone, what are you going
to make sure that linked issue says
when you're creating the ticket?
Because this task that we are creating
is going to have our cucumbers in there.
All right.
That tests this ticket
right here from as B 1113.
Right.
Does that make sense?
No, no, no. You just choose test.
That's it, right?
It's just test.
And what am I going to enter here?
This task is testing what ticket?
What ticket is this? Test testing
HMS B 11 three.
Yes, Very good.
So let's say this.
B, 11, right three.
And it's right here.
And I'm going to select this. Right.
And again, let me ask you again, I already
asked you in the beginning of class,
but why don't you write
your commerce scenario first and see what
the rest of the options. You can do
that, too.
I'm just showing you like the linking part
and everything because that's really
what confused a lot of people.
Okay, well,
I know you're just listening right now.
You're just listening.
You're not following along.
You're just listening, guys.
You're not doing what I'm doing.
You're just listening. Please.
So when I'm linking an
issue with the other issue,
what am I doing?
What am I doing when I'm linking to issues
or when I'm linking issues with issues?
What is that?
I'm establishing what? Right.
I'm establishing a relationship right
between the issues right there.
I'm linking it right.
I'm establishing a connection. Right?
That's exactly as everyone makes that.
Does that make sense to everyone?
Yeah.
Well, all right.
Okay, so then I've linked this,
assigned me as myself,
So I'm so, like, the cell,
and you guys will select your name,
but don't do it
now. You're just watching this,
and then you don't select
anything for epic link, right?
We don't select anything for our link
and for Sprint.
What do we select for Sprint?
Sprint one what? Sprint one is
what?
Sprint one And why are you saying to
why would we select to
we're going to select a
term as B 11 sprint one.
Right guys, that is this current sprint
that we're working with.
So I'm going to select that
and there it is right?
So I'm going to delete this.
I'm going to hit cancel
and I'm going to do it again.
Okay.
So step number one,
what is step number one
now? Step number one is copy.
What? Copy the name. Right.
I'm going to come here and copy
the take a name.
Right.
You can't highlight right click copy.
You can highlight command C for copy.
Right.
Once I do that,
then what is the next step?
Create. Okay.
And then what I do in the summary
of exactly.
Make sure that what that the issue type is
what?
Make sure that the issue type is.
What story do I make sure
do I make sure that this does bug a bit?
What am I looking for?
The task. Right.
I want to make sure
that this is selected to task.
Okay.
And the summary.
To a space hyphen,
what am I going to do?
Paste the name that you copied,
which is search and employee right.
And then hyphen and then your name.
Exactly right. Okay, next.
What are you doing?
Oh, and by the way,
I want you to see this.
I am creating the target, right?
I am a cell. Right?
Do you guys see how by default
it says reporter me?
You guys see that
this is
because I am creating the ticket, right?
So whoever creates
the ticket is the reporter, okay?
Oh, so, okay, what do I do next?
I stop what I do.
I'm going to scroll down.
Okay?
And someone says, okay, tell me what,
what is the most important thing here
that I have to look out for
the link?
What? What?
What am I looking out here for?
Someone says tests.
I'm making sure that the field link
issues.
Says what test? Right.
So is this correct right here, Just about
okay.
Is this correct right here?
Nope. How about this?
Is this correct?
So what is it going to be?
Just tests.
Exactly. Right. Very good. Okay,
very good.
Good job as you guys are. Right on. Okay.
And then the issue type, what goes
what happens here?
What happens here, What I do here issue.
Okay.
But to clarify
this, a lot of you guys are saying h.r.
Must be level three.
You guys are correct,
but i'm linking the issue that i want
to establish the relationship with. Right?
And it's this one someone say h.r.
Mess. It already comes up.
It's the first one.
Okay, cool.
All right, guys, next.
What is next?
Sprint?
Someone said assigned.
Yes. Assigned to who?
Assigned to what I type.
You assigned to yourself. Right.
So in this case, it's a cell.
And then what is next?
Sprint.
Okay, someone say a sprint.
And what I do. What sprint do I select?
What sprint do I select someone says one.
We see multiple sprint ones
here. Which one do I select? Guys
HMS B 11 Sprint one.
Which is this one?
Right right here as we let this one.
Ladies and gentlemen, please take
a screenshot of this right now real quick.
Please take a screenshot of this
right now.
Take a screenshot of this.
Gerald, Take a screenshot.
Yeah.
So once you're done, I need you to take
a screenshot of the bottom part,
so let me know.
Give me guys thumbs up
when you guys start taking screenshots.
Not a picture. Right?
You guys are I.T. professionals, right?
So we're going to scroll down
and can I scroll down now?
Are we good.
Take a screenshot.
Yeah.
Okay.
So I'm going to scroll down,
take a screenshot of this,
take a screenshot of this.
When you when I click create,
my window is not like yours.
Can you send the screenshot please?
So I can see exactly
where you talk when you see
that.
Got it, sir. All right.
Okay, cool.
Are we good?
Guess what we're going to do now?
Guess what we are going to do now?
Guess what we're going to do now.
No, no, no, no, no,
no. Guys,
what we're going to do
is we're going to do this again
to make sure that everyone understands it.
Okay?
We're going to make sure
we're going to do this again.
Okay, cool.
That's exactly what we're going to do.
Right.
So step one, what is step one?
Guess what is step one?
And let's help
the rest of the class. Right?
So we can understand
everyone can understand this.
Copy. What?
Copy The the second name,
which is this one, Right.
How do you copy?
You can highlight right click copy. Right.
Or you can highlight right in the windows.
It's control C and Windows, it's
command C, right.
There you go. One, copy it.
And then what are we going to do?
We're going to click on Create.
Okay?
And then we're here.
What is the next step?
You really are immune to start again.
All right.
So that's exactly what we're going to do.
Let me cancel this
and let me start from the beginning. Okay?
and then we start from the beginning
because that's a very, very serious
so so what?
Take it we're working on as B level,
right?
Right. HMS B 11 three.
So we're on the zero board. Everyone
look at the screen.
Okay, look at the screen.
So first of all, the actual real step
one is going to be what we're working on.
HMS B 11 three, what is going to be
the first actual real step,
right click right
and open in new tab, right?
So we lose the mouse
and you right click your mouse
and then you click on Open
Link and new tab, right?
That's exactly what we're going to do.
And then once it opens in the tab,
you see it it open right here.
So we're going to navigate
here, we're going to click on it.
Okay.
And then what is step two?
What is copy?
Copy the ticket name right
When I come here and I'm going to say
I'm going to copy this.
Copy the name. Right.
Command C, control C, right click,
see, copy of that.
And then what am I going to do? That's
great.
Okay. Very, very good.
And then that was okay.
The next step, What do we do?
I think we're on step.
What is this? Step four?
Step three was click on create. Right?
So we're on step for it.
So step four,
task task.
Someone says task big task, right?
So I'm going to make sure
that the issue tab says task.
Is this correct here?
Is this correct?
Okay.
Now, for those of you
that did, is this correct?
Right. No. Right.
What should it be?
It's going to be a task, right?
Exactly.
All right.
Now what what is the next step?
What is the next step?
What Someone says paste
name to paste your name.
Okay. Go away. So we're going to type Q a
hyphen paste
right then. And then your name. Right.
Okay. Very good.
You guys are doing very, very, very good.
Okay, so next step, guys. What do we do?
What do we do?
We scroll down.
Okay, okay.
I'm scrolling down. And then what
length issues?
Gerald was the one that had questions
about this yesterday.
Today he's on fire.
So, Gerald issues what what do we make
sure that it this says that says test
so is this correct is this correct
right here now how about this?
Is this correct?
Right. Okay.
How about this? Is this correct? Right.
So it should say what tests?
Write tests.
So I can test. Very good.
What is next
issue?
What am I doing about the issue?
What what am I doing here?
Establishing a relation with the take
I'm linking, right?
I'm creating some sort of connection
relationship.
And what am I going to
link this issue to?
Like what?
HMS B 1113 right.
So H are and this B level
and it comes up, right?
You can either type the whole thing down
or you can select it from the list.
Okay, so then select it. All right.
Next step,
what assigned to yourself. Okay.
In this case, I'm using the sales account,
so I'm going to use like the sub.
Okay, Very good.
And then what else is next?
The sprint.
Okay, The sprint.
And what sprint am I going to select?
That's
a term as B to one is like right on it.
Like she had those answers ready. Right?
HMS B 1101 Right.
It's right here.
Am I going to click on HMS B ten
Sprint one
Why am I going to click
on the T sprint one?
I'm going to click on a sprint one
now, right?
I'm going to click on HMS B 11
Sprint one go.
So when I click on this right
and then right
and then what you can do, listen guys,
what you can do before clicking create,
you can go ahead and write your cucumber
scenario here.
Okay? Right.
Write your cucumber scenario here.
Okay, cool it.
Actually,
I am going to choose a name for this
so that it's easy for you guys to find
that I'm going to type sample ticket.
Okay, so that you guys can see it for
your review.
Cool. Does that make sense?
So this is going to be a sample ticket
that you guys can review.
Does this mean that you will include
the name
sample ticket in the name?
No, man, you guys are so smart, right?
I would hire me hire
all of you if I could.
Right.
So you're going to ride your cucumbers
and arrows here, right?
Very got.
So I'm going to go ahead and create this.
Okay.
Go ahead and create this equal
that's been created.
I will go back to the board
and I have to look for it right here
to read it.
Let's say it was for me.
So the one that I create is a sample
random ticket sample.
There you go.
So I want to move this to in progress.
All right.
That's a sample ticket
for you guys to review. All right.
Very good.
So now we are going to work on.
Oh, we did HMS.
We won, guys.
Let's work on HMS B three.
Okay, Let's work on HMS before.
And for those you who have issues
on the ones that you guys did yesterday,
let's go back and fix them. Okay?
Let's go back and fix them.
Cool.
Does that make sense?
We're going to work every one.
Everyone work on
HMS B three.
Hold on.
Let me see the first time
and make sure it makes sense for you guys.
Yes. Everyone work on HMS Beloved three.
I have a question for you guys.
I have a question.
I question
that everyone hands over your laptop.
Right.
Are you going to coming to JIRA and
are you going to change anything on HMS
B 11 three?
Are you going to open the ticket
and change?
Stop here
and change the acceptance criteria
for the whole class
to get confused and stuff?
Right?
If you are,
please show me a personal message
and we will have a discussion okay. So
to me, personal messages, that's fine.
We need to have a discussion thread, but
for the rest of you, please don't do it.
Go Vote.
All right, guys.
Ready
to my window covers HMS B 11,
but yours doesn't.
Okay, let's see.
What does that HMS Batch 11?
What do you mean?
You were when I was creating.
It's right here. The one.
So it's right here.
It's right here to
I mean, when you click Create,
I declare create.
This is what?
This is what I see.
I see the same thing you're seeing
someone.
Are you good?
Tomorrow? You're good.
You're right
about moving the window to the right.
What about moving the window to the right?
What did I move to the right?
You move the sample.
Want to be able to see the description?
That window, guys,
you guys are See your window
shows, left side search and employee.
You want to search right here.
Oh, are you asking why you can't see it in
your monitor?
Is that what you asking?
Is because my monitor
is actually larger than yours.
Yeah.
Yeah. Yep.
I you can.
You can open it.
Why not?
Why can you not open that up?
What is what is the situation?
It's was she said,
well guys, I'm
I, I have
no idea what you guys are talking about.
Sorry.
Can we move create,
can we move create issue window?
No, you can't.
If I create it, you can't move it.
Even I can't do it
that it's opening the same page for me.
Well, what are you trying to open.
I'll show us some screenshots.
Oh help us show.
I was like,
well what are you trying to do?
Wow, very good.
So far,
nobody has done anything to these tickets.
Like everyone has left it alone.
Very good.
Guys, I want to applaud you for that.
I applaud you for that.
That's what's what's
what's the problem, guys?
Yesterday,
you guys were not following instructions.
And today you guys are.
Now, is this hard?
If you even make a mistake, that's fine.
If you make a mistake, we'll fix it.
Mistakes
are good because we want to fix them.
I want to show you how to fix it
so you make a mistake.
That's okay.
We will fix it together,
but we will fix it
together.
Let's see.
Yeah,
we'll give you feedback. I'll actually.
I'll help you fix the issue.
That's the point of today's class today.
It's just going to be proactive. Okay?
We're just to fix mistakes.
Maybe a lot of
maybe you make the same mistake.
Other people do it,
and we can help everyone else.
Oh, it's not all.
Yes. So click on open link in new tab.
You have to know right there. Right.
You're
right. Clicking open linking the tab.
Click on that. So
if you guys make mistakes, that's okay.
We're going to fix it together.
Okay.
We're going to fix.
I know how to do it, but it's not opening.
It's just saying the same.
Oh, you have to right click on the ticket.
So no,
if you know, if you look at the screen
because we know
look,
you actually have to write click on a link
and then open the link in a new tab.
So maybe it's
maybe it's thinking something.
Maybe you're you're just do that
first, go directly to the link,
right, click it and open a new tab
to write your comments in there.
Should we always say click?
And actually
now you can make it high level.
That's okay.
You can make it high level.
That's fine.
I'm not sure how to write the cucumber
criteria when I don't know where
they are supposed to search,
but they're a bunch of click.
Okay, some other stuff on there map
too much of what they're up to.
Place them up in second time out.
Everyone.
All right. So
is everyone paying attention here?
I we're paying attention to.
So I'm going to explain
this acceptance criteria
because I expect your cucumbers and arrows
to be top notch.
First of all, I told you
from the beginning, how many cucumber
scenarios
are we going to right, at least for this
to get to?
You can write both of them in the same
task.
Okay.
You can write
both of them on the same task
if you want to create another test for it,
knock yourself out.
I'll have a go for it, Offer it, go crazy.
Get what I used Your only want to practice
Grade another test.
You go for it.
So for this one, as an admin user,
you already have admin credentials.
I should be able to search
for an employee by post
by specifying the employee name first.
The last name for this one.
I'm not going to be so specific,
but just go on the application
and see where you need
to search for the employee and that's it.
Okay.
The second one, as the admin user,
I should be able to search for an employee
by specifying the employee I.D..
So it looks like you're
just searching for an employee.
But the first one, you're
you're searching by first and last name,
and the second one
you're searching by I.D..
Okay, just go in there.
Look, an existing employee search
the employee search and employee ID,
you know, like, just go ahead and undo it
and write a cucumber scenario for it.
Okay?
Does that make sense?
Does that make sense, guys,
when I'm trying to fix my problem
from yesterday. So?
So. Okay.
Sheriff. Sheriff.
Sheriff. What sprint are we in
or what?
Sprint are we in?
What?
No, we're not in Sprint three.
What sprint are we in?
This is the ticket number of Sheriff.
This is not the sprint number, right?
If you look at the sprint
right here, it says, What sprint?
Are we unsure
if you see what sprint are in one.
Right.
So you should be looking for HMS
B 11, Sprint one, not three.
If you go back and edit
the cucumbers narrows and hit create,
why would you hit create?
If you go back and edit the cucumber
scenarios, why would you created
if you're editing the ticket
guys in order?
Okay, so in order to edit a ticket,
this is what you do.
Okay, let me show you
because everyone paying attention, right,
is their own fan attention.
Let's say you created a ticket
and you didn't write your scenario.
That's completely okay.
Yeah, I think it was.
Do you guys have the login info for
or the application?
See that somewhere
here?
Yeah. There you go. Tomorrow.
Thanks so much.
Those are the credentials.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
You got so let me go back to this.
If someone needs to write, okay,
If someone needs to edit
a ticket,
are you going to create a new one?
Now? You're not going to create a new one.
You can edit an existing one, right?
So I'm going to edit this one for a lot
less time is going to pictures.
I'm going
to just mess around with it. Okay.
But the you know what?
We're a lot this was a lot of nice
and we have a lot of
I want
said a lot of I'm going
to just play around with your ticket okay
So just
I'm just going to use just for example.
So here is the lottery ticket. Okay.
So let's say I forgot to edit it.
You guys see, if I hover over here,
I have the option to.
EDIT Right.
Okay, you can click on this
and you can edit, you can edit here,
you can delete stuff,
you can change stuff.
I am editing.
Okay, Does that make sense?
Just go and then hit save
and then it saves that ticket.
You don't need to create a new ticket.
Okay, we'll just edit the ticket.
Cool.
All right.
And guys.
Okay,
so I'm going to let's do a bonus here.
Okay.
Let's do a bonus.
Let's do a bonus. Okay.
Well, so here's going to do
first of all, this is task one.
Task two.
Listen, guys,
everyone tasked to send one listening
task to
listen.
And I'm going to see if you can figure out
is to create
first of all, go into the syntax h.r.
Mess application, guys.
And let's see who, can find a bug.
Okay.
And if you find a bug created in jira,
that's going to be,
first of all, a very big bonus for you.
Okay, guys, in our previous classes,
i just want to bring something.
What do you mean?
Where where else would you create the bug?
We're working. And you're right.
So here's the thing, right?
And let me just show you real quick.
Everyone just pay attention.
You're going to go to the gear board.
This is the gear board. I'm here.
And in order to create a bug,
instead of going to a ticket,
I'm going to click Create up here.
You guys see this?
Okay.
Do you guys see this? You guys?
So instead of opening a ticket,
I'm actually going to be
on the JIRA board and I'm going to click
the Create button right here.
Okay?
Does that make sense to everyone?
So in here, So I'm going to click Create.
And when you click create issue type,
if I'm creating a bug,
what do you think I'm going to select?
What if you want to select, right
of the hard question, right?
You're going to enter the summary, right?
And now, guys, hold on.
Listen, the summary doesn't
have to be the name we've been using.
You can name
and whatever I'm going to say this.
This is just a sample bug sample
bug ticket.
Okay.
The name is going to be I'm
just going to make something up.
Okay. Log in.
Button logging button, not working.
Okay, cool.
All right.
And then as everyone penitential,
everything else
almost will likely be the same.
Right?
For bugs.
We're not going to link anything.
Okay.
You're not going to link anything. Okay.
What was that?
I said for bugs,
you are not going to link anything.
Well,
you. Oh, yeah.
I'm sorry. You add your name. My bad.
I forgot about that.
You add your name so I know that it's you.
So have my name to the name.
You don't link anything with bugs.
Okay, guys, just
don't play anything
with bugs, okay?
All right, Now
what I'm going to do
is I'm going to assign it to myself,
and you're going to send it to yourself,
and you're going to assign it
to the current sprint.
What's the current sprint?
Is that AFGE Sprint one?
Is it Sprint one?
Is it four, has four one.
What is a current sprint
that's not inside the HMS B level guys?
I said not inside.
Right.
Okay guys, everyone pause
what you're doing.
Does everyone stop it, please?
Because I'm creating bug
and this is what the next step is.
Okay, I'm going to cancel
everything I was just doing.
Okay, everyone, attention on the screen,
please.
Attention on the screen.
Attention on the screen, guys.
A touch on the screen.
A touch on the screen. Right.
Is there one on the screen?
There was my screen, right, guys?
Did everyone stop working on it?
As everyone's on the screen, Right.
Everyone's on the screen, right?
Everyone is on the screen, right.
Okay, cool.
Where's General?
The general? You on the screen.
You on the screen.
You'll here, you'll step away
here.
Okay? Okay. Okay.
Joe. Anthony?
Luis. Dominic, are you there?
Alexis, you there?
Jimmy, You there?
Are you on the screen over here to Mana
was named Marja.
The Sierra's here.
Lobo, Right.
Okay, Go, go, go.
Oh, there's. There's the other movies.
I didn't know we had to lose.
The other is Castro. We have Cabrera.
Okay, cool.
So I'm to create a bug.
Okay, I'm going to create a bug. Cool.
So what I'm going to do
is I'm not going to open a ticket.
I'm going to be the springboard, okay?
I'm going to be on the springboard
right here.
Okay.
That is step number one to make sure
that you are on the springboard.
Okay, then I'm going to click on Create.
Okay.
And if I'm creating a bug,
what do you think this should say?
If I'm creating a bug,
what do you think they should say? Bug,
Right.
How? That's a that's a very hard question.
Right?
So that's a complicated question.
Right. Okay.
So for the summary,
I'm going to write this sample bug ticket
ticket and I'm going to say
and then these tickets, guys,
they don't need to have the same name
as the tickets that you're testing, Right?
I'm Going to name it something else.
I'm going to make something up. Okay.
I'm going to say login
button to our content
and then at the end
you're going to put your name on
and then I'm going to scroll down
and the description right
to see, are you sending pictures
or you're or is your are you on the screen
because I saw that like for your test.
They were kind of not right So
watch the screen this here right.
So here's the thing
right in the description
here you are going to list
write the steps to reproduce
okay we're really talked about the bug
lifecycle.
We talked in the previous classes
how to report a bug.
I'm not going to give you that answer.
I want to see how much you guys
remember that.
So cool.
And then I want to scroll down.
You are not going to link it
to any ticket.
Okay. Now you don't need to write it in
cucumber form.
We don't write our bugs and form.
You just write steps.
Can you write steps that
so we don't link anything?
That's a good thing.
So that's less there
and then you assign it to yourself, Okay?
And then you assign it to the current
sprint. Right?
And the current sprint is what
mess is
AFGE Sprint one is a disparate one
is it for said
Sprint one, it's HMS B 11, Sprint one.
Right. That is the sprint.
Okay, cool.
That is so you create a bug.
Let's do it again.
And this length issues here
doesn't matter because
we're not linking it so you don't have to.
This doesn't matter what it says
because we're not working in issue.
Okay, let's do it again.
Okay, Let's do it again.
Do it again.
All right, Ready?
So, step one, what is step one?
Where are we going to be?
Where are we going to be not step one,
What's it called
was the proper word for it.
What is the proper word, friend?
Where are we going to be?
No, that's not step one.
Step one
is we're going to be on the sprint board.
That's right, Mustafa.
We're going to be on the Sprint port.
So am I going to be here?
Am I going to be on the backlog
in the going to be in another ticket?
No, I'm going to be on the sprint
port Red.
Okay.
Step two, what is step 24814141.
And because I'm creating here's
the hardest part.
Here is the hardest part
because I'm creating a bug.
What should the issue type be?
Is there going to be a story?
Is it going to be epic?
Is it going to be a task?
If I'm creating a bug, it's
going to be a bug, right?
Very good. Okay.
And then here
is just me.
I'm is going to write
the name of the public,
so log in and not working.
Right.
And then your name is
what goes in the description.
What goes in the description
steps,
not acceptance criteria.
Don't don't give me that kind of hard
to type right now.
Steps to reproduce.
Right
Steps reproduce right steps to reproduce.
Go. Okay.
And you scroll down.
You will not link anything again.
You're going to
assign it to yourself,
this case of a cell,
and then you're going to pick the current
spread a term as B, please
pay attention
to what you're linking it to.
Okay, I'm going to go ahead and
okay.
And I'm going to move it here in progress
just so that you guys can see how
to create. Okay, simple book. Take it.
All right. Ready, guys? I got now
the real syntax application, the syntax
HMS application that you guys are using.
There are some real bugs there.
So see if you can go and find them. Okay.
See If you can go and find them
after you write your scenarios.
All right.
So go ahead. Go ahead.
Read the tickets.
If you find more than one, create
more than one ticket.
Right.
Create more than one public guys.
Go crazy.
Go for crazy.
All right.
If they an employee
if they file employee I.D.,
it's if anyone saw an employee I.D.
on a website, you can just
go to the website and just look up
whatever play these. Right.
So let's see.
Okay. Very good.
Someone created a bug already.
They're sick.
They see space,
not function or display correctly.
So this is interesting.
Let's see.
Let's see what Alan says.
All over this.
This is a beautiful bug, but
I like the way it's spread, right?
And I like the way it's spread.
And guys, if you create your bugs,
go ahead, move it to the in progress.
I actually don't move it to in progress.
Don't move anything too in progress
because the ones that are in progress
are for you guys to see for samples
and stuff by the way,
you guys are doing a very good job
at following directions today,
which is
something that historically another batch
has not been able to do.
But yes, on the syntax page,
does everyone have the syntax,
your URL that the page
we sent it up?
What is it?
I think I have it.
Give me a second.
Look it up.
Let me look
right here.
This is the this is the URL.
Okay.
And that's the URL and the credentials.
Can someone
please send the credentials again because
they're somewhere,
but I don't know where they were is.
Thanks to the one
I tell you, it's my
I would hire you if I could.
I would I seriously seriously what?
Log in name not working performance tab
now working my report the bug
Dominic created search employee
Nice Dominic.
I see the naming convention is good.
You created a task you in. Well
Dominic, you are
on fire.
You were on fire also the bugs.
Obviously the bugs.
Guys, I want to see the bugs go. See?
This is it.
I want to see who's a good tester.
Go and go and find any bugs.
Guys.
Find bugs started.
Oh, guys, I'm sorry.
So, by the way, let's just
let let's.
It's 837.
How about we take a break
and we come back?
Are you guys good with 10 minutes
today is?
Just you guys just working on zero.
So you're going
to come back in 10 minutes.
So it sounds like we're having
some performance issue.
Maybe that's bug.
I don't know. It's up to you to report it.
So. So let's come back in 10 minutes.
Let's come back at 850
and come back and finish the tasks.
Get well.
I'll be here, guys, if you have questions.
If you guys made mistakes, please
let me know so we can fix them together.
We actually have the time here
rather than yesterday being rushed
and, you know, all that stuff.
So to leave,
that's
yes, we're on break. Had
you had Listen to me you Yes.
You would know that we're on break the
we're on break until.
Why can't you move?
We're on break until 850.
Oh, come back.
Come back
whenever you want. It's up to you.
So they were just working on JIRA
and we're going to have that complete
by the end.
Entire pages of bugs.
I can't and.
Okay, let's see.
Let's see
the bug bug hunter Bug hunters.
Bug bounty hunters.
Let's see.
I want to see who I want to see
if you guys find some really good bugs.
You know, I want to see
Alexis.
Yeah. Let's just give me.
Let's just wait till
eight me.
Just give me a few minutes.
Alexis, I look into your stuff
boxes. You need to take a break.
Then you got to take Can run for
cocoa.
I will take a look at it. Okay.
We'll take a look at it.
See, that's
just.
Sorry.
Hey, that's a good question.
I don't know. Should you.
Should. You are.
Should you not?
Should you?
Or so you're not
out of the way.
We talked about this, right?
We talked about this before.
When you are putting a bug.
All right, guys. All right.
How it's going? Are we back?
Are we back or are we back?
I don't want
you don't have patience for it.
Yeah. Okay.
Okay.
Is it a bug?
Would you reported?
Would you not say anything?
What would you do?
Someone moved this.
Someone my bug got to in progress.
Come on, guys. We're doing so good.
We're doing so good.
Come.
All right.
Why would you move it back to in progress?
All right, guys, are we back
or are we back to one
there?
Alexis, you want me to look at your.
All right, guys, come on, let's go.
I want to see want to see some bugs here?
I want to see some bugs here.
All right, let's see
when we go to the bottom,
the mirror opens this bug,
and let's see if it's good. Let's see.
Let's see what the mirror did here.
It said the mirror or dimmer
is the mirror here?
Same class.
All right, let's see.
A bug steps to reproduce.
He says
you don't need to copy the sample bug test
part of the name
the mirror that's just made
so that you guys can see the ticket
in case
you want to know what it should have.
So go ahead and fix that. The
so it says
multiple search results
with incomplete information on directory
steps you reproduce
open a chance website,
log in with credentials.
Very Good.
Click on the directory,
click on job panel.
So as I'm going to actually test this
as see if it makes sense.
Right.
The second step is log
within the credentials username admin
and say
oh, what size don't
see. It's
because a lot of us are using it. Huh.
Is it a bug or is it not?
Okay.
So okay.
So set logging username
and then the password.
This he provided password. Very good.
He provided the password.
He he already has the exact steps
to reproduce which is awesome.
Right? I know what I'm doing.
So I'm logging in.
It's going to take a while
because you guys are using it
as it's
kind of stuck here.
So. Okay.
And the next step says Click
on the directory directory tab directory.
But oh, there's only one directory
here, so maybe it can be a little bit
more specific there.
The mirror right.
So I'm going to click on directory.
That's what it says.
And then here it says Click on job title.
Job title or job title field
and search directory.
So click on this.
I guess he gives you a choice,
a dropdown right?
And choose accountants
to choose accountants
and click Search.
So I click Search.
We're going to wait.
And he's saying that the actual result
multiple entries with the name
a billion on the top
for job title account and
missing information such as phone number,
extension, e-mail address.
It's better for each person
with the same job title and they want
only one entry name title Extension
fields are accurate.
Let's see.
So I see what he's saying.
Okay, So I see
what he's saying.
He's saying that okay, for the job
title accountant.
So he's saying that there's more
than one person
whose name the billion on a title, Right?
Is it possible
for people to have the same name?
Is it possible for people
to have the same name?
Yeah, it is. Right. We having
Christine Williams from Fairfax,
you know, there is another Christine
Fairfax, Christine Williams from Fairfax.
So maybe there are multiple people
with the same name that are accountants.
Okay.
The missing information such as full
number extensions that email addresses.
So this is this is interesting, right?
The mirror.
This is good
that you're thinking outside the box.
Now, but before we report this bug,
we need to make sure that the requirement
says that there should not be any of this
missing information.
Right.
What if the requirement
what if there's no requirement for it?
What if what if there's a requirement
that says it's fine
if there is no phone number
or email address?
Right.
So the expected results for each person
with the same title,
only one entry
there could be different employees
can use Gerken language.
No, not really.
I mean, not really use list of steps
you can try.
I mean, again, when using Gerken,
you just writing English, right?
So you can
you can try it as long as it makes sense.
So the whole point of cucumber
name title extension fields are accurate.
Okay. I see
so this is all right.
But before reporting this above,
I would have checked the requirements
to make sure that this is a bug.
Right.
So the MIRA, you did a very good job
at thinking outside
the box is a very good job.
And think outside.
That's really good.
That's very good.
That that is very good.
So, Damian, can you please move
your take your bug to 51.
Can you please move it to the Don
column only?
Dan There you go.
Let me see the next bug here.
Ahmed 254 to 54
When trying to use syntax HMS website,
it takes several minutes
to get so these aren't, these aren't steps
Ahmed is often they're
these aren't, these aren't really steps
right you're just giving
a description of the bug
so these aren't really steps to reproduce
a return to
the syntax. HMS
takes
on side with all the credentials.
All the sub pages are slow
to open website.
Totally should be checked for performance.
Okay, this is good.
The description is good.
But you didn't really list
steps to reproduce.
Yes, you just indicated what happens.
Yeah,
but I see that
you're thinking outside the box,
so I'll give you
eight out of ten for that.
Okay.
Often
you can move your ticket to the column
that the done column.
And so there should be
two people in there.
Don't call them what you want. So
let's see,
let's look at and
and are you are you in class two
so far?
So far so far.
I see no screenshots,
which is a big bummer
because I can't see the bug, right?
Can't see the bug.
I can't it can't see the bug.
I cannot see the bug.
So simple bug ticket's error. Finally.
And by the way, you don't need
to include this in the ticket.
I just put that in my ticket
because I wanted you guys to easily
find it in case you need to see
how I create the bug ticket.
The merry go crazy.
Go find bugs. That's fine.
So description
Application error
By finding an employee by employee name
application is unable to file
employee by employing name.
Okay.
Expect the results by typing an employee
name.
Admin should find an employee in a native
based
open h.r.
Mess log in to syntax hms.
Okay, i'm logged in
navigate to admin,
so maybe I have to go back
to the office and navigate to admin.
But a user guru to user management
admin user management and was the next of
users.
Okay.
And then username users.
Yeah.
And then it says
type in employee name
and the employee name field.
But she doesn't say what employee.
So this bug is not that descriptive.
And where are you that you didn't indicate
what name
to enter?
You see, I need those details to reproduce
this bug that you are reporting.
Okay, so go ahead and edit this ticket.
But so far everything was good.
I like it. It made sense.
I was I was running through this bug
really fast.
This is really good
and really, really, really good.
Okay, so I'll come back to okay, I know.
I'll come back to it. I'll come back it.
So let's see. I was picking bugs so
I saw some Anthony
of performance issue.
Okay, let's see. 261.
Let's see.
Anthony, Anthony, Anthony.
Okay,
so he wrote this bug in cucumber scenario
and he said it test this one.
We weren't supposed to link anything
with the bug.
Anthony Right.
We weren't supposed to link anything
with the
right.
Yeah.
So it says given the
you are given the user has the URL
when entering the URL in the URL text,
but then there is a slow load.
Okay.
Maybe we can change the steps, right?
To be like one, two, three, like steps
you produce.
This is okay.
I mean, I understand, but maybe
you could say like navigate to your URL.
What happens is that
the page takes a long time to load.
This is good.
Obviously you would report a performance
issue like this.
So good job.
Just fix the change wearing a little bit.
Anthony
Yeah, that's fine.
Just change a little wording.
It's fine.
You're like, one, two, three.
So far, so far it
I want to point this out.
I'm mean, I give some hints out.
I haven't seen a bug that shows me what
time, what browser, what you was used.
I don't see any of that. Okay.
I don't see any of that.
I don't see of that.
Go back.
Okay. So
let me.
Alexis,
did you want me to look up your ticket?
If so, what I did was that.
Alexis, are you there?
So, Daniel, how's it going?
Are you.
I didn't know you were in the class.
That's the school
which my Levins
is two likes.
231 or look for 231.
So 4231.
Okay.
Bug create by not working.
Let's take a look.
Let's take a look at this. Bug
user opens website zero
stuff surfaces.
Oh no.
We're working on the syntax website,
the actual syntax one page
and we're finding a bug
if you can link any bug there
and, you're trying to reproduce it. Got.
So go to the actual syntax website
like this website right here.
And everyone's trying to, to, to look up
lookup bugs. Okay
so let's see.
I'm just thinking I'm just going let's see
Christine, did I tell Christine
to move this over to the dump column or.
No, I don't think so. Right.
I don't think I did that.
I, I don't, I don't remember.
I don't, I don't remember.
Does this doesn't mean that
Christine possibly did something
she wasn't supposed to do,
right?
Maybe
they maybe so.
243. All right, let's take a look.
Let's take a look.
Just just move it back.
You can move the Take it back.
Move back.
Okay. Login button.
Not working.
Let's take a look.
But just Dexcom.
So this is a bug.
Then What we're trying to do
then is we're trying to.
We're trying to find the real bug.
So you actually going
to the syntax website,
you actually go in to the syntax website
and you're trying to see
if you can find the bug.
Okay, that's what you're doing.
So you have the URL right and everything.
We already shared it.
Can someone share the URL again
that we need?
You're going to go to the syntax website
and you're going to actually try to find
a real bug
to be a real, real bug.
Let's take a look to 42.
So look at what guys the sample
bug ticket
name should not be on the ticket name.
I just wrote that so that you guys
can find my ticket in case you needed help
writing the ticket. Thank.
So don't copy
the sample bug keywords, just
change it.
So in the build,
let's see what the bill says here.
I don't see a description of this,
so it says there's not a slow
in page loading navigate to syntax atrium
runs website.
Enter this click on logged by an accepted
result page opens immediately.
Page does not open the actual time
approximately
2 minutes browser Internet explorer
time 850 day 20 Right.
That's really good. That's a good stuff.
My question is going to be like,
did you test as in Chrome?
Did you test as in Firefox? Did you test?
Is it in Safari? If you have Safari,
did you or did you not?
Right.
So these questions will come up.
Okay. So there you go. This is good.
So once you are on the bill, go ahead
and move your ticket to the done column.
This is good.
Very good. Very good. Very good.
Just make the changes.
It's a done column
and then they will, Christine.
They move the ticket back as Christine
take it back.
Very good,
Christine Friday, I'm so proud of you.
So the thing is,
Sorbonne, let's see this.
This ticket looks interesting.
This bug was innocent.
We had a Chrome browser
navigate to E shop and mobile. Now.
So one safari there might
so run it.
Can I have everyone's attention, please?
Have everyone's attention, please.
Everyone's attention, please.
Can I have everyone's attention, please.
Can everyone's attention please.
Everyone's attention
is everyone's in the screen, right?
So we're actually
using the real Syntax website.
We're not going to another website, guys.
We are going to the syntax
a mess website, this application,
and we are trying to find real bugs.
We're trying to find real bugs.
Okay, So that's what we're doing.
All right, so you're going to
another website here, so
your bug looks nice.
Okay, I'll tell you that.
But it's not the syntax HMS application.
It's like you working at Google,
but you're reporting an Amazon bug.
You know, So, yeah, let's see.
Let's see.
Sahay Morano, 31.
Isaiah It's 31.
So where are you from? Ukraine.
Russia
is right here.
Okay, cool.
Let's see.
Ukraine.
This reminds me of
that boxer that just won the
was the
best heavyweight boxer in the world.
What's the name?
Alexandre used to is from Ukraine.
It's really good, right?
His I really, really like that guy
so this is above
and says the user is logged in
as an admin as an add user page.
So this is saying that I'm logged in
as an admin, which I am.
And on the add user page,
where is the add user page?
Where's the add user page?
I cannot find it.
So from here go not there.
Oh, did I just show you another bug of no.
That I show you another blog.
Those are supposed to happen
that going to show it again.
But that was about
so it says okay,
let me go back to the ticket.
So system user
open link in the tab.
Okay, so we provided a link
steps to fill out the necessary
information, start, interrupt
as is required,
password alerts will appear and disappear
correctly one by one.
That's great.
What does it mean?
What does it mean
that what is x?
What is
you mean actual results?
Like can I change this to actual results?
Are you okay with that
system changes to the actual results
because that's how he reported his bug.
So password alerts
will appear and disappear one by one.
Passwords are overlapping,
passwords are overlapping ones.
And so he said insert this employee name
some tests.
Why is it,
oh, did I just show you another bug?
But I think I showed you another bug.
Right.
You see this?
I enter testing tests, which can be
a real name, but it's saying invalid.
What is the problem with this? Right.
So employee name and
okay is still saying invalid
that I just find another bug.
Yes I did.
I just found another bug.
The password for a strong password.
Please use a hard just to combine.
Okay.
I'm going the sixth.
I'm getting error message when I should
and because it says
should have at least eight characters.
But there's more than eight here
that I just find another bug.
Probably.
Good job.
That's not bad, sir.
Hey, move your ticket
over to the dumb column.
But I did just find three other bugs
so you can report those if you need
to count.
Parts of you need right to.
I'm logged in here to close this.
The job. Sorry. Job.
So let's see.
Two 6102 62.
So it was.
Let's see
cancel button issue.
The user is logged in as add
user on service already.
So this
we are to 62 right here.
So users name and password
click navigate on welcome user
navigate.
Welcome user navigate on.
Welcome user where's welcome user was.
Oh you mean welcome admin.
Okay to
welcome admin.
So you may want to change that, right?
You will want to change that.
So is this welcome.
So welcome
admin user clicks change the password.
Okay, so user clicks change
password, but it's going to take a while.
User clicks on cancel bunch of close
cancel
one doesn't work to execute the process.
All right.
Let's see that to cancel.
Oh, so now this is not about this is not.
You're not
this is supposed to be disabled.
Oh, you mean after clicking?
Edit So we're trying to say
it looks like it's loading.
Oh, yeah, that is true.
Yeah, not bad. That is good.
Move your ticket to the rug
bug Pro hunter one.
That's funny.
So go ahead and
move your ticket to the dumb column.
Let's see.
We're 260. Three is ramen.
Here is ramen here.
All right, guys, you guys ready
to start this whole thing soon
or what?
Navigate the Chrome browser to
log in with.
Log in admin.
Okay with Chrome browser,
you specify Chrome browser.
That's a very good logging.
Good.
Good at the menu on the top left
tried to click on performance, but
start to click on the performance button.
I want to click on it
to performance change color to gray,
but it does not lead us to the specific
page.
Let's see. I clicked it
there.
Let's see.
It's taken a long time to load.
All right.
So let's I'm going to look at this later
because, yes, you guys are
is a good let me ask you this.
How do you guys feel creating bugs,
looking for bugs on the application?
Right.
A lot of these bugs are good.
I just wish I could go faster, but
this is not even loading for me anymore.
A lot of this, a lot of these are good.
A lot of you guys added screenshots, a
lot of information, everything like that.
How do you guys feel,
What do you guys think?
Was it was it good?
Was it?
You cannot open the page.
Neither can I.
But did you guys see how you guys reported
the bugs
and I was following
what you're saying Step by step.
Right.
So That is
something that everyone will do
in the projects at work.
This is why you have to be
as detailed as possible.
Okay. To edit.
Is it like the same?
Can you repeat the question?
Christine to edit isn't same like task
as I mean, let's
something happen to my idea
to edit bug what is the question.
Don't Christine I don't get to all to edit
the bug is the same like test yes
okay.
Yep so all right guys
how do you guys feel?
That was good, right?
We're hands on
everything right?
We're very good. Awesome.
Right?
HMS based, not even open.
Of course it's a bug.
If it doesn't open, of course
it's a bug, right?
Even though it's a performance
issue, it's a bug which is still reported.
So very, very good.
You guys, guys,
give yourselves a round of applause.
This was JIRA. You guys did great.
You guys does great.
And then later, throughout the course,
you will.
You guys will do much, much better.
We want to revisit this
and so forth. Okay.
You guys will do a project
at the end of class
and then you guys will do a big project
like every batch
and you guys will also just go for that.
So you guys will have your practice
and everything.
That cool. All right.
So that's to come later
in the class plot point
is that those topics will be revisited.
Okay, cool.
But we good? Are we got it.
All right.
We don't want to make tomorrow late
for class, so let's get this thing going
right.
You guys ready?
Are you ready?
Yikes.
Late for work.
I mean, late for work.
My bet.
Sorry.
Ten to
the dawn
month.
It's a
All right, guys.
Remember, the winner gets a real prize.
No, I'm not talking about a sticker.
I'm not talking about a sticker.
I'm not talking about Halloween
candy.
Talking about a real, real prize.
So just about whimsy.
All right, guys,
let's get this thing going.
So here's the crew game.
Okay? Here's where we get this.
Everyone, my screen,
everyone should be able to see it.
All right, Follow the instructions
on the screen
to. Okay, so let's go, guys.
Let's see what join.
So Fairfax, thanks for indicating that
these are
angelic 902 for all
who entered that as a name
no there is no link.
There's no link.
You see the instructions. Write
the instructions.
It tells you to join
that you can do it on your computer
or you can download the app.
The link is on the screen
that you have to type it in.
I can share it
with you.
9022423 ten.
What's even just this in here
was a Luis is here very good
Stephen Anthony
Let's see
where is
the Malaysia
which she's always like in class whenever
I don't see your name
What I've been to search
is a here Once you saw his name.
Sorry. Do any worse.
Are you
certain.
Oh, that's right.
That's why.
Only if it's a67 people.
The eight people.
Do you see Aleksander?
Yup, I see Aleksander.
Two minus two. One Here.
I see. Come
on. Two. Monocle speaks for Jose.
Speak like ten languages.
Four. What is an audio Punjabi?
What English and what else?
Hindi. Right.
So I don't even feel like playing of that.
That English.
Aisha
Okay, so Gerald There you go.
All the way for Gerald to join.
Sebastian Where are you?
I don't see Sebastian. You
Sebastian here?
Sebastian Especially when I hear
the question.
They were different deals.
Punjabi.
Nice, nice, nice, nice.
Anthony. Anthony, is this you?
902423.
Guys, I need you to play this game
like this is squid games, okay?
I need you to play this game
like this is with games.
All right?
Alan, are you.
Are you here?
Along with along the lines name
along
What's on here?
It's seven or not.
This right here
or will you hold that?
What was once in your will want
to see the
look and not the side to show up to class.
Hey, Homolka, are you
in Vermont Warriors
or not?
All right,
you watch them as here, Chavez, here.
Luis Castro, Are you in here?
Answer those questions.
Which Castro Which comes to lose Castro.
I see
the best.
Not you, Luis.
Okay, so looks like Luis
Castro is going to stick to Luis.
And who is going to be the last one?
Love will take a bite of money,
perhaps.
Maybe you see?
No, no.
How do we go from the world to No, no.
We'll give you that nickname.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
But I don't see no,
I see no resistance.
No, no.
You see.
Well, Irina decided to join Irina.
Who are you with?
We're missing Catalina here.
Okay, I'm going to do it.
Finally. Here
was. Catalina was telling
all your why.
Okay, that's my run is up.
Okay, I'm bronze.
Here is Alexis.
Here, Alexis here.
Irish was Irish.
Irish was here.
Jimmy, Jimmy Castro here.
Jimmy was Jimmy's name
in here.
Jimmy was
right here.
Marvin over here.
Make sure I want participants.
Someone let someone join. Someone left.
Was Marvin
went on to monitor.
Why would you join the team
more than Morgan.
Two people left, one person join.
People are leaving.
Alex, what is your name?
What is your name?
Alex. Alex. Alex. Alex. Alex.
Alex Alex.
Between us, there's
something wrong with our page.
To Mina.
Woe to Mina.
How are you doing? Over
thing that hurts me today
to. Are you here like your worst?
Amusing to me, not to me.
To me.
You can also find your phone, By the way.
You can also play on your phone.
Not to Mina, to me This to me.
This name You see to me.
Correct me if I'm incorrect.
Minutes
in which 2 minutes to see the mother
said to me To us often
words often
said a amore is that Oh, I see it here.
Got why, guys, are you ready?
We're going to start in exactly
one minute.
All right.
So let's start exactly one minute.
So make sure to join us.
Everything
You guys,
I need you guys to play this
like it's squid games.
All right, 20 seconds, 20 seconds.
All right, Ten.
Are we good, everyone?
Is there anyone that has enjoyed?
Is there anyone that hasn't joined them?
I give you 15 seconds to speak
or say something Now.
Are you going to join or what
is someone that casino
you're going to join?
Then we're waiting for you guys. Come on.
You want join guys, Join.
But it is okay.
Whoever is not in, tell me right now.
What is your name?
What did you enter as your name?
No, no, I don't see it.
Tried to enter the game again.
So leave it and enter to get.
All right. What are we waiting for?
Let's see.
No, no. Are you. Are you in or what?
We're waiting for you.
It seems in.
It thinks you enter are probably
okay. I'm going to start this.
If it is,
are we good now? All Are we good?
Are you there
waiting for.
No, no to say something.
Hello?
No, no rain for you
there.
No. Okay, you're in.
You're in. That's fine.
That's it.
Ready?
All right. Ready,
set and
easy.
So, guys, squad games.
Okay, Ready, set.
And you go
equal.
Pay attention.
Still. See?
Oh, guys, I think it's
a support testing life center.
That's what I think.
Actually, I would probably pick
the software testing life table.
That makes more sense.
I think. I think so.
So one of those two for sure.
So we chose the software test center,
so they show who answered those questions
incorrectly.
I was on their man.
All right.
Okay.
We have Merriam on top of the podium.
We have two winners.
Second place or my Dominic and Louis.
It's not it's not bad.
Not bad at all.
Okay, so Mariam,
who's married, by the way, is married.
Oh, marry him from Maryland. Wow.
That's. That's impressive.
Okay, whatever the rest.
I don't see Aisha here.
I don't see Alan.
What happened?
Everyone was scared of Alan.
Right.
Ready?
Here we go.
Testing hard.
You have environments, is
all this is.
I think we.
We about this a lot.
I think it's stage
four is right guys I think is like stage
acceptance royalty and then it goes to the
and then it goes to a
all my guys
7 seconds six, five, four, three
two, one.
Very good
very, very good.
For those of you guys, we don't start
testing on the stage environment.
Right. Where were those?
Right.
What is who does the testing first
and in what environment.
Right.
And who does the testing first.
Who does who does the testing first.
That's do right does do right and does
and what environment do they tested
right in the dev environment.
Right. Exactly.
And they do unit testing there. Right.
So why would they
why would stage come first?
That's All right.
So that's okay.
Let's see
how name is on top.
Louis, What happened?
Dominic happened.
Guys, we got to kind of Ellen's up.
He bumped up to second place, his second
in the podium to mine.
I Don't see your name.
I don't see your name. Yeah.
Okay, so the goal is to get rid of Mariam.
Okay, Ready?
So true.
Or False black box test requires
internals of the application.
I'm going to say yes, obviously.
Yes, I think I'm gonna say yes.
It's 8 seconds.
7 seconds, 6 seconds, five,
four, three, two.
I'm going to say no.
It's very, very good. Very good.
Black
box testing requires sense of what
type of testing requires
internal of the application.
White box testing right there. Good.
You guys ready?
Let's see. What do we have here?
Okay, Ellen moved up to first place,
ma'am, is by second by two points.
Sebas off I shot from Florida.
Why don't we see ice here from Fairfax?
Okay, Ready Sebas Whoa.
Who's the boss? Came out of nowhere.
Ready?
Here we go.
Said why box testing is done by joint
thrusters.
Absolutely, Yes, I'm going to say no.
I think.
I think it's. Yes, my guys.
You guys, help me out here.
So is that no or yes.
Guys, we just had this question last.
Right. Why? But I even told you why.
Box testing requires
internal knowledge of the application.
Who knows that the developers do it right?
So is it done by testers?
No. Right.
Oh My goodness, guys,
we can actually sell this.
No way.
Okay, Just keep this between us, okay?
Keep this between us.
We can't show some of this in red.
So let's see what we have here.
Oh, I ship from
Florida comes Alexis is of third place.
You get a Dominic
is up okay
Dominic made it back to the podium, guys.
All right.
By the way,
I forgot to mention the second, third,
second and third place Also got a gift.
All right
you got to do that,
I said don't tell them.
So the way it works is
you can still be in last place and.
You can catch up all the way to first.
That's how it works
and that's how it works this way.
It doesn't
mean you're going to be in last place.
So I shall. From Florida.
Very good.
Smoke testing and request
regression testing are the same.
Yes, I think so.
Actually, I remember this
maybe probably
8 seconds, seven, seven,
six, five, four, three.
Just.
But thank goodness
that.
Very good.
Okay, so Dominic is gone.
Alexa still in third
eye shut and Florida stays on top.
There's not anymore.
There's not a worse.
The question is supposed to be blank
ready
whenever they're ready.
True or false? Ad hoc testing.
It also known as exploratory test.
Who likes exploring?
I don't think that's true.
Maybe it is. No, I don't know.
What would you guys chance
if someone tells the answer
to very, very good
very, very, very, very good.
Okay.
Okay,
I'm ready.
So let's see what's up with this.
Joseph makes it.
We have yet to offer it.
I saw Joseph is there.
Joseph are.
Welcome to the podium, sir. Welcome.
Okay.
Ready, guys.
So, how many primitive
data types of Java are there?
Yeah, it's ten.
Ten. Right.
We have.
Is it seven?
If I'm wrong, please tell me, guys.
All right, I Don't want to let us know.
These are her pluses.
Very good for the 50 people.
What primitive data types
and boolean floats.
Bytes.
What else?
Char long
double Wonderful.
Very, very good.
Okay, Very good.
Very good.
Yeah.
All Alexa second place.
I'm not sure who NZ is, but NZ angelic.
Welcome to the podium.
It isn't third place now but
to get it isn't so and and
the third place.
Okay, this is interesting.
It's going to get interesting.
Okay, ready?
Small testing
is execution of lightweight test.
I don't think so,
but I'm keeping my opinions
to myself
right now.
I'm going to.
What would you guys choose
then?
This is. That's
what happened, guys.
The one Brian
And what if this was squid games
which click the wrong button on thing
So yikes, the whole podium
changed the whole of your gear doesn't
place Alexis.
You can still catch up.
Whoever was at that point,
you guys can still come back up.
We have Joseph Angelica's
in second our hottest now on the podium.
All of us are welcome to the podium.
Welcome, welcome, welcome, welcome.
Okay, nine players have reached
answers for.
Okay, Ready? True or false?
Compliance
testing is less important than smoking.
Testing,
I must say.
What am I going to say?
I'm going to say
compliance testing,
which is also known as five way testing.
Right.
This lesson for it. Very, very good.
It's just as important.
It's very, very, very important.
Okay, let's see what happened here.
The podium stays the same.
These guys, they know their stuff.
They're not messing around.
You eat Angelica
Joseph for order, not mess around.
Okay,
Positive
and negative testing are the same.
I'm going to go With what?
Yes, I think so.
Are they the same, if I'm mistaken?
Can someone correct me, please,
for two reasons.
I don't know why.
I really want to find out
who answered that question.
I really want to know who.
I just want to know who that was.
But I'm not going to be to do it.
All these guys are messing around,
but it's okay.
The next question is going to. Right.
We're not ready. Set. Let's go.
At most project
the testing hierarchy of environment is.
This is a great question, guys I think
and I think I really think
that we start the testing
in the stage environment.
Maybe I don't, but
very good.
And I think we had this question.
And so if you got it wrong again,
don't know what's up.
So. Oh, I delegate
Luis on the podium now Louis
welcome very much to welcome welcome,
welcome to the podium.
Louis Angelica, you're in first place.
You are the podium.
All right, let's see you guys ready?
12 of 13.
What's the proper way
to print out a console?
I think, guys, you're going to ask me
my professional opinion.
I'm going to go with the
with the
with the rectangular one.
So. All right.
Very, very good.
Right now, let's see to the podium.
Joseph is up in second place.
Marianne from Maryland made it back.
Welcome welcome welcome for how this is
is that mesmerized?
Is there
that's okay I said don't worry
you're answered these correctly.
That's okay.
That's right.
That last question.
What is syntax for main method?
Oh, I think you're going to ask me
for my professional opinion.
I really think it's going to be
the triangle.
I think so.
That's just what I would select.
But I don't know.
She does go
it said Square games.
All right, So
tricky.
Right?
All right.
Let's see, guys.
Ready in third place
we have Alexis just came of nowhere.
And Louis,
that's fun.
How Joseph, when all of this
I. Joseph.
What? All this I want
doesn't just came all the way.
All right.
All right, guys,
that wraps up today, class.
All right.
It was a pleasure teaching you guys.
You know,
keep doing well with with with the course.
You know, just ask questions.
We're here.
We're here to help you with everything.
You guys will get the slides.
You guys will get the notes.
You guys will get everything with it.
But don't stress things too much, okay?
You guys will. You guys will.
We're going to cover this everything again
at the end of the batch. So.
So you should be good to go.
Okay, I'll.
I'll reach out to the winners
in person. All right, guys,
can we have the.
Yeah, sure, you can have the questions.
Yeah,
I'll look at the tickets on the board.
Very good job, guys.
You guys did very, very, very good.
Okay. Very, very good.
And, you know,
keep up the good work again.
Have a wonderful night.
And every one of the night
that you have questions, please
ask me that.
All right, guys, take it easy. See?