I lost two classes, guys.
Well, technically,
today is the last class of selenium.
Tomorrow, we're going to be going over
some other design.
Okay, so design of the framework.
I'll start with page object model,
and then you guys going to continue with
with building up the test
engine framework and Cucumber
framework.
Okay.
All right.
So I hope everyone completed the homework
that I gave last time.
Right.
And everyone understood
about the last class, all the topics.
And I hope you guys are practicing right,
Especially the tables.
How to manipulate the tables, rows
and columns.
All right.
So today, it's not going to be
a really difficult class, but
just going to go over some last topics and
if we have time, I'm going to start with
page object model, and then
we'll end there.
Okay.
See? All right.
So let's let's do a quick recap, guys,
of what we've done so far or last class.
All right.
And then we can go ahead and start
with some new topics.
Okay.
All right.
So what did we do last class, guys?
Okay, so we worked with calendars, right?
What else?
And we have covered actions class
with covered screenshots.
Right?
So now we know how to
how to have screenshots, how to make
some other extra actions.
Right.
With Selenium.
Check. Check your settings.
Okay.
So it seems like
everybody else can hear me.
Okay, good.
All right, guys. So.
So now
let's start with calendars. Right.
So what do we know about calendars, guys?
How do we handle calendars?
Okay.
All right.
So calendars are similar to the table,
right, that we have on the Web pages.
So how to handle
with first click on the calendar.
Then we find the month and the date.
Okay.
Store date into a list.
Okay, So what do we do?
What do we do with what month, guys?
We get the text.
Okay.
And then what?
So we locate the month, we get the texts,
and then look through.
We find the next button.
Right.
Okay, good.
Okay.
I have my month. I have my next button.
What else?
We need a while. Right.
Because we don't really know
how many times
we need to click on the next button
to find the expected months.
Right.
So we're clicking on the next button.
So we found our month.
Now we stop there. Right.
So afterwards, we will go ahead and start
looking for the date.
Right. That we need.
And then we're going to go ahead and start
looking through the dates.
And we have a condition
when our matching the date
where we match the date
with our condition.
Only then we're going to click on it.
Right. Okay.
Nice.
What about the.
Before we move forward?
Any questions, guys, on the calendars?
How to handle the calendars?
Oh, good.
Right. Okay.
All right, So let's
let's go ahead and talk about
talk about the actions class.
Right.
If declared outside of the loop.
Okay. Yeah.
Then that means your page
is getting refreshed, right?
When you click on next or something is get
something is happening in the website.
Right.
If your next button wasn't working,
if you declaring it outside of the loop.
Right. So that happened
last time
when we were dealing with tables.
When you click on next,
the whole page is getting refreshed.
Right.
So that's probably why it wasn't working.
Okay, so what do we know about actions,
class guys?
What can we do with actions?
Class when we use actions, class.
So actions class is used
for keyboard and mouse actions, right?
Okay.
So what kind of actions do we know?
Okay, so we now drag and drop right?
We have mouse over or double click.
Right. We have right click. Okay.
So these are some extra actions
that we can perform with actions
class, Right.
Okay. So we've done drag and drop.
I think we've done moves to an element.
Right.
So today we will be going over the right
click and the double click actions.
Okay.
All right.
So but before we do that,
let's go over the screenshots. Right?
So why do we need screenshots? Guys
to report the bugs, Right.
To have approved or something. Right.
If our test case passed or failed
so that we can show to our developers
if it's de fact, we just
would just create a defect
and attach everything in there.
And so main point of having the screenshot
is to have a proof of our test case
has covered some functionality.
Right.
So what's difference between actions
class and action class?
I think we already had that question
last class.
I'm not sure what action class has.
Okay.
I've never looked into that.
So it probably has
some different methods in there.
So just take a look
what's going on in there?
Okay.
All right.
Any other questions
before we move forward,
guys?
Okay.
And one more thing, guys.
Today, since it's the last technically
last class of this millennium
and tomorrow we won't be doing
anything new with Selenium.
So I am going to give you
a very big homework
from the
from the very beginning,
what we've started so far.
Okay. To
up to date.
Okay.
So it's going to be
pretty good exercises for you
so that you can refresh your memory
from what we started from
right until today.
Right.
You're going to have to create a lot of
a lot of new steps and do more examples.
It's not going to be the Oracle now.
I have pretty good examples in here
so that you guys can go ahead and do that,
but I'll give them to you
at the end of the class.
But did you guys start with Test
and G already
or no.
Okay. Nice. Okay.
So you covered test in G,
Did you did you guys cover
assertions or. No.
Okay, you guys covered the session.
It's nice. Okay, good.
Because I have
this kind of examples as well,
so I'll give those to you
so that you can practice on those as well.
Okay.
Next.
All right.
So right now let's see.
What I am going to do is
on set then.
All right.
So today what we're going to be doing
will go over the rest
methods that we have in actions
class, like right click and double clicks.
Then what we're going to be doing
will will be
uploading some files
by writing some scripts.
And what we're going to go over
is JavaScript execute.
Okay, so not too much today.
And then if we have time, I'll just start
with page object model, and then
we'll continue tomorrow.
Okay.
So let me create the class, Right?
Let me create a new
package
to class 11 point
and create a new class.
And that's
right.
And double
what actions?
Oh, that's awesome.
That's
all right.
So let's see.
So let me just copy this
just here.
So if
let me see if we have
something that's
more all.
Okay. All right.
So what we're going to be doing in here,
we will be navigating to this website.
And then when we navigate, you can see
that these buttons
indicate some text in here.
And this one is asking us to right click.
This one is asking us to double click.
Okay, I'll share the links in a moment.
Okay.
So when we right
click on this, you will see there's a
what's called there's a menu popping up.
So I click on edit
We need to handle this in here
and I'm going to double click on this
and then we'll be handling
this alert as well.
Okay, so
let me just send this.
Okay.
And I need to update this in here.
Any questions, guys,
before we get started?
Now? Questions.
Okay.
Good.
So now, guys, first of all,
what do I need to do
in order for me to start this text?
So I already navigate.
I already navigated to that you out.
What is my next step in here?
We need to find this element, right?
That we need, that
we want to interact with.
So I'm going to inspect this page
in here and I have my Dom open.
So let's go ahead and try to
identify this element.
So how can we identify this element, guys?
So I have a class in here.
I also have some texts in here.
We could do an X path
and go by text, right?
So they open up.
What's the topic right now?
The topic is right click and double click
on actions.
Okay, so I open this.
Let me actually this
I open this selector box. Right.
So double slash.
I have a span
tag in here.
Okay, so what I am going to do, since I am
identifying this by text,
I'm going to mention text in here and
I will need to paste
a text that is on our button.
Right. Okay.
This is our x path and this is one of one
can use link text in here.
That's a question for you.
Can you?
Why not?
It's not a link, right?
So you can use a link text for links.
Because as in here we don't have any tag.
Right?
So that the tag that we have
is ten right now.
So if it had an eight only then
you can use the link text.
All right.
So what I am going to do
when a copy of this class go back here
and I will create a web
element in here and say that
right click
button is equal to
driver dot find element
by x path.
There we go.
So we have an element
that we want to interact with, right?
So what is our next step, guys?
We need to create an action class
object, right?
So in order perform some actions,
some extra actions
like move to an element of right
click, double click right.
What we need to do,
we need to have an object of action class
ready for us, right?
So actions action is equal to new
actions in here.
And what we need to do,
we need to import this class.
Okay, So inside
the constructor, what we need to specify,
we need to specify the execution
object, right?
Which is in this case, our driver. Okay.
So once we have this action
class object and we have an element
that we want to perform our action on,
then we can start performing our action.
Right?
So in this case, what we need to do,
we need to right click on that button.
Right.
So in action class, guys, right
click is called a little bit Different.
Okay, So when I try to access all the
methods from actions class,
what I need to select in here is context.
Click okay.
So contact's click is what it's going
to do is going to go ahead and click.
It's going to perform. I right
click, okay.
So I'm going to choose the first method
because what we need to do,
we need to perform an action
on the element, right?
So I'm going to copy this
and paste this in here.
What I need to do after I I'm doing
the contacts click and here guys,
I need to perform this action right?
And if I have
more than one action
on the same line, guys,
what do we need to do in that case?
We need to build all the actions
and then perform, right?
Okay, good.
All right, so let's run this.
Okay, So I'm going to run this
and let's see if we will be able to right
click
on that specific element
and we'll go there.
So we right click.
So now you can see that
this menu popped up.
So what we need to do now, we need to
click on this edit option, right?
So any questions before we move forward,
guys?
Okay. Pretty easy, right?
If you want to do a right click,
you just use
contact's click from Actions class.
All right, So click on this.
So now what I need to do,
I need to go ahead
and locate this element, Right?
How are we supposed to locate this one?
Guys,
any thoughts?
I have this element that I want to click
share.
Okay.
So simply, we have a we have a tag
and we have a text in here, right?
Why don't we go ahead
and do the same thing as we've done
for the button itself,
for the button of right click me.
Right.
So what I'm going to do in here,
double slash
span tag, right?
Again, I'm using the text option and here
and what I will do, I'll go ahead
and put the existing text in here
and you can see that
it's one of one
it located the element we need.
So what I'm going to do, I'm going to
copy this, go back
to my script and I will create another web
element in here.
All right?
Okay. So edit
option
is a driver, that font element
by X path and I will paste this
in here.
Okay.
So once we have done this,
so now what do I need to do in this case?
Guys, we can simply
go ahead
and perform a regular click, right?
But sometimes, guys,
sometimes this click will not work.
Okay?
So you will not know why it's not working.
And maybe
something is wrong with a website or just
selenium is not picking up something.
So in that case, guys,
if this click doesn't work,
there is an option to click on any element
on the web
page from the action class as well.
Okay.
So what you can do in here,
we will be using the action class object
and what we can perform
is this simple click in here,
but we need to specify what
what elements we need to click and then
perform our action.
Okay.
Is it always safer to use actions?
No, guys, it's not always safer
because most of the time,
like 90% of the time
your regular click will work.
Okay. But sometimes it's very rare.
I think in my project
I've only seen this once
that it didn't work and we
we use some different ways of clicking.
Okay. Yep.
So as I said, guys in coding
there is not only one option to perform
some actions or to have a solution, right?
So in coding there's a lot of different,
different solutions, right?
So this one is one of the alternatives
for the regular click.
Okay,
Well the regular click is going to work.
Okay guys,
in this case, in this example, but this is
an extra thing for you guys.
If sometimes this regular click
doesn't work,
you don't get lost
or you don't panic or anything.
You use a different way for this.
Okay, so let's run this and see
if we are able to click
on that edit option.
Okay, There you go. So we clicked.
We can clearly see in here
that we have a alert popping up in here.
Okay?
No one would look at us
weirdly for using actions.
First of all,
you need to use the regular click.
Okay.
So if that doesn't work,
only then you're using the actions.
Click okay.
So if if you have a reason to say that,
hey, okay, so the regular click
somehow not working when I'm performing
or trying to click on some elements
and that's why I'm using this action,
then it's fine.
No one is going to say anything.
Okay, sure.
Let's have it in the notes.
Okay, So
if let's
put it this way, if regular
click
not work
you can use and
turn the way off
having
access class
click method F from
in order to perform tense.
Well it's sometimes
okay, let's go ahead and take a look
what that method actually does.
Okay. So let's see if we have this.
Let's see here.
This form, it's building
and performing at the same time.
It's going to work without this, I think.
But sometimes it won't catch the action.
Okay.
So as I said before, guys,
if you have multiple
what's called multiple methods, right?
If you have a method chaining in here
and you just do it
without build, it will work. That is fine.
But you do build
so that it's a precaution for you, right?
In the future it might not work
so that you don't have to go ahead
and change that again.
Okay. So you take a little bit precaution.
Even if it's working, it's fine,
but you take it precaution
so that in the future,
if it doesn't work, you don't have to go
back and change the code.
Okay.
Any questions, guys?
All right.
So now I clicked on edit what I need to do
now, guys, I clicked on.
Edit I have this thingy over here.
We need to handle the alert. Right. Okay.
So what kind of alert
are we having right now in here?
Okay.
What kind of pop up?
It's a simple alert.
Okay, So is it a Windows based? Is it a
web page?
Is it a JavaScript alert?
What kind?
Okay, so there's a window,
there's JavaScript, there is web based.
Okay,
So I have different different answers.
Guys.
Okay.
Why do you guys think it's a web
based alert?
So people who said it's a web based alert,
why do you guys think it's a Web
based alert?
It's from the Web.
Okay.
We cannot inspected. Right.
So if you have a Web based alert,
what you can do
is you can go ahead and inspect that.
Okay.
So if you have a Windows based alert,
so that means you're
having a completely new window
popping up for you.
Right.
So since it's neither of those,
that means this is a JavaScript alert
and this is a simple alert, right?
What we can do, we can only click on.
Okay, right.
So how do I handle this
alert in my script?
Guys?
Okay, switch. Right.
So we need to switch to that alert.
Okay.
So okay, so driver
that switch to an alert.
Okay.
Do I need to somewhere?
I switch to an alert. What?
What is next, guys
assigned to a variable of an alert type.
Okay, that's very good.
So if you have a question in your
interview, guys, we went through this.
If you have a question,
how do you handle alert with selenium?
What would be the answer
using an alert interface, right?
Absolutely. Right. There we go.
So what we can
do, alert, alert is equal to this.
So import the alert
interface in here
and then we have alert dot, except.
Right.
Okay.
So we're going to accept that
alert in here.
All right.
So let's execute this.
That should be enough.
If you say you use alert interface
and you can ask them if you want to go
in details on how often, how many ways
or what can you do or how can you handle
you can just do.
Okay. Seems like it handled that alert.
Okay.
So you can just do here.
You could just do not accept that is fine.
But if you have in in your future,
if you have more alerts
you need to handle,
what do you want to do?
So let's say in our execution right now,
I need to.
Okay. So let's get back.
So I clicked on right click right.
This alert popped up.
I clicked.
Okay, so now I'm clicking on this one.
See, I have another alert.
So that means
I need to go ahead and switch to it again.
Right.
But let's go back.
If I assign this to a variable, if
I don't have to do this again,
that's why we're assigning this switch
to alert to a variable,
because we don't want to switch
to alert again and again in the future.
Okay.
All right. So let's go back in here.
So now what I need to do,
I handled that alert, right?
So now what I want to do,
I want to double click on this.
Okay?
And get this text print out in my console
and then handle this alert.
Okay.
So if I double click on this,
what kind of alert am I having in here
this time?
Again, a simple alert, right?
Okay, good.
All right.
So now let's
go ahead and identify this element.
Okay.
How do we want to identify this element?
Guys?
Okay, That's a good question, Blake.
Guys,
do we have to switch back when we are
when we handle an alert?
Where did we use to do this?
In frames, right?
So if you have a frame,
you switch to the frame manually
and you switch back manually, but
with alerts, you switch to an alert,
but it gets the focus back
automatically, Right?
Okay.
So since we have a pretty long
text in here, why don't we use a contains
method
right when we are having a x path in here?
Okay.
So I'm going to go ahead and do button
and do contains
right text
is equal to
double click.
Okay.
Why is this not working guys? See?
All right.
We should use a comma
instead of an equal sign.
Right?
So if you use this,
then we can see that it is one of one.
It's unique and I can copy this path.
Right.
So go back in here
and create another web element,
which is
double click
button is equal to driver add find element
X path, paste this and here.
Right.
So now guys, this is
I have my web element, right?
So I need to perform
a double click in here.
So since I already have an object
of the actions class in here,
I don't have to create a new one, right?
So I'm going to be using the object
that I created on line 19
and I'll go Action dot simple,
double click.
Okay, So a double click in here.
And what I need to do, I need to mention
what element I am double clicked
right?
And then what I want to do,
I need to perform right.
Okay.
So once I perform this,
what is my next step?
Guys?
Accept that alert.
Okay, so we need to switch it to switch
and get texts.
Right.
So do I. Do I need to switch again?
Guys in here.
I need to driver that switch
now. Right.
We don't really need to do this
because we already have an object
of an alert in here
which helps us to switch to an alert.
Right.
So what I will do, I'll directly
print out the alert dot, get text in here,
and after this what I need to do,
I will simply accept that left.
Okay, Now let's execute this
code and see
if everything runs smooth.
There we go.
So seems like
we double clicked on that as well.
And you can see that
we got the text from the alert
and we accept that that alert as well.
Right.
Okay.
Any questions, guys, on how to perform it?
Right
click and double clicks by using actions
class.
Very straightforward.
Everything good, right?
Double click.
The only thing that might be getting
a little bit
confused with actions class
is this context.
Click okay
because everything else is simple.
English drag and drop
move to element right?
Double click.
The only thing that is not
simple English in here is the contacts
click, which performs the right click.
Okay,
so you just need to remember this one.
If there's no questions,
then let's move to a different topic
in here.
Check one thing.
All right,
guess so. Now what we going to be doing?
We will be uploading some files
and I'm pretty sure you guys already know
how to do this manually.
Right?
Whenever you are uploading some pictures,
whenever you uploading some documents
and some website.
Right.
You go ahead
and let me actually pull that up in here
file upload.
Right.
So if you want to do this, you click
sorry,
you choose your file first, right?
So you click on this.
There is you need to choose a file
from your computer.
When you do that, you click
okay, It's going to pop up in here
and what you do,
you upload that file in here, right?
And you've done this in social media.
You've probably done this
for some documents, whatever you're
uploading for something, business licenses
or just to get any documentation.
Right.
So this is what we will be doing,
but we will be doing it through this.
Correct. Okay.
So it's going to be really easy
to upload any files
through this script
and I'll show you how to do this.
All right.
So let's go back
in our intelligent
and I'm going to create a new Java class.
Okay?
So what I'll do is do file
upload.
Okay,
of the list and
I have this in here
and I go, guys.
Okay.
All right.
So manually, guys, by uploading
when you want to upload anything,
what you want to do
is go ahead in here
and stuff this.
Okay.
So basically manually
whenever you are trying to
to upload any file, Right.
So you have to go click on this.
Then you have to go find your file in here
and let's say anything in here, right?
Okay.
There we go.
So we have this in here.
Okay. Am I going too fast, guys?
Is there a lot of people who are behind
right now?
Sometimes. Okay, guys.
So let me continue
and then I'll give you time to type.
Okay.
How did we get to the page that I'm on?
I sent you the link, guys.
I'll show you how how we got in here.
Okay, So.
Okay, I'll show you where to click.
Okay, guys.
So let's captured the logic right now.
Seems like
everyone is trying to get to the page
that I am on and trying to type in.
Right?
So I think it's better to catch up
with the logic first.
Okay, guys,
I'll show you how to get to any page.
It's easy, right?
But first of all, what we need to do,
we need to catch the logic
behind everything.
Okay.
All right.
So manually, guys, whenever you do this,
you have basically
you need to choose the file in here.
And what you need to do is
you need to click on upload.
Right?
Seems like it's not working,
but it's okay.
So let me choose a different from here.
Let's choose this one.
It should rest upload.
There we go. All right.
So when you upload,
you should be getting anything
like verification or success message,
right when you are doing it manually.
So in this case, we the file was uploaded,
we chose the file from our computer.
We on the upload and we have this name
and the success message in here.
Okay All right.
So now let's do it in the script.
Okay, so it's pretty easy.
So first of all, guys,
what I want you to pay attention in here,
so let's get that so simply, guys,
whenever
which type of file we can
try to upload guys like the
I think text file or Excel or word file,
it's in here.
So that's going to be better
because I don't think
this website accepts all type of files.
Okay.
You could try you could try pictures
as well.
Okay. Yeah, that's fine.
That's okay.
All right.
So before guys, before doing anything.
Okay.
Before writing your script, guys, what?
I want you to make sure guys,
So whenever we have a button, right?
Whenever we have a button
and you inspect that button, what do you.
What kind of tag do you see for that
button?
Guys?
No, no, not the tag name.
The tag name, not the attributes. Right.
So exactly.
So usually
when you're inspecting a button,
the tag name should be button, right?
Pretty straightforward.
But whenever you are uploading a file guys
through the script,
what you need to make sure, guys,
that this file, when you choose
this button, when you choose the file
guys, has the tag of input.
Okay, so here it's a little bit different.
So what you can do in here,
you can input something.
Okay.
And in this case,
what we will be doing in here,
we will be inputting that path
and the location of the file
that we want to upload.
Okay.
Is that clear, guys?
So basically, here's what we did.
So when I choose file,
I am choosing from my desktop, right?
And here if I click on this.
So basically what I'm doing,
I am giving this place,
I'm giving this place a path
or the location of my file, right?
So we will be doing the same thing.
So but first of all,
what we need to do, we need to
let me see in here, we need
to locate this choose file element.
Okay. So
before, before we get into the page.
Right. So we we are on this page, right?
So what we need to do,
we need to click on this file.
Upload. Okay, guys.
So let me inspect this in here.
All right.
So we have this.
What can we use in here, guys? I d
we can use a link text right there.
We go.
So let me copy this.
Get back in here and create a web element
and say that file
upload link is equal to driver
find element by
link, text
and paste this link text links here.
So what we simply need to do is
to click on that link.
All right, so let's get back in here.
So when I click on the file upload link
in here, then I'm going to
what's called land on this page
where I can actually upload the file.
Right?
So now before we upload the file,
we need to locate this element.
Okay.
And in here what we have, we have an ID
in here which I can use, right?
So I'm going to copy this ID
and I will create
another web element and name
it as choose file
is equal to the
driver.
Find element by I.D
and paste this into.
Okay.
Is that clear? So far guys?
What I'm doing in here.
Okay, cool.
All right.
So simply guys, now since
it's an input element, right?
That means we can send something.
We can send some text in there. Right.
And as I mentioned before,
what we need to specify
is our location of the file, right?
Or in other words,
we need to specify the path of the file.
Right. So
so what I have in my
desktop right now, so let me see
here.
Meet it is over here. Yes.
So there we go.
So I have this sample test data
in here on my desktop, Right.
So what I need, I need a
I need a whole pass for this
file. Right.
So in in Mac, what I need to do,
I'm going to do get info
and I think in Windows what you need to do
is you need to go ahead and get
you go to properties, right?
So get info in here.
I have it here. Right.
So in Mac guys, what you need to do,
you need to start with users, okay?
You don't need this Mac SSD or whatever.
Okay.
What you need to do,
you need to start with users.
Okay, so I'm going to copy that.
The one in here
and I will go to intelligent.
Okay, so open this back.
And what I am going
to do is going to copy this
file and simply
send keys in here
and not this one.
Okay, Choose file, send keys in here
and let me see.
And I'm going to get this
and paste this thing here.
Okay? Is that clear, guys?
Any questions?
Yeah, Yeah, I'll edit
guys. I'll edit guys.
So I'm just trying to I'm just trying
to see if everyone is on the same page.
Okay.
Seems like all good.
All right.
So now I only have here up
to my desktop, right?
So what I need to do,
I need to mention the actual file.
Right?
So my file name is simple tasks data.
Right.
And do not forget guys
to mention the extension as well.
Okay.
So it's going to be x
as x seems since it is an Excel file.
Right?
So after you locate the desktop
and then what you need
to do is you need to actually
mention the file
name as well.
Okay.
Any questions on this, guys? Yes.
You have to write the full name
of the file and its extension.
Okay.
I think you have to put.
Yes, I think you have to.
Guys, if it's PNG file.
Yes. Dot PNG.
All right, so let me execute this.
Okay, Let's execute this.
Okay. Running here.
Click on that. Okay.
So you can see that in here, guys.
You can see that
we uploaded the sample test
data in here.
Okay.
So that means the path that I gave
was correct.
Okay.
So when you run guys, as long as you see
your file name on the web page,
that means it is fine.
That means you were able
to provide the right path
for your file. Yes.
Without the extension, it will not work.
So you have to make sure
you put the extension as well.
Okay.
So we send the whole path of the
of our file.
So now the only thing that's left for us
is to go ahead, actually click on upload.
Right.
So it has an ID in here,
so I'm going to copy this ID
and I will go back and here create
another web element right.
Upload button is equal to driver
find element by
ID, paste that ID here
and I'll just simply click on upload.
Okay.
Tried different.
Okay. Yeah, that's fine.
That's okay. All right.
So let's run
this and see if we can get the
the success message
and the name of our file.
There we go.
So we clicked on upload as well.
So now we get the success message,
which is file upload it
and the the file name in here as well.
Right. Pretty straightforward and easy.
Right guys.
So sometimes guys, sometimes
what we need to do is
sometimes this send keys
will not work for us.
Okay? So sometimes it's not going to work.
That's why whenever it doesn't work, guys,
you will need to use
some different libraries.
So in this case, what you can use is
you can use a rollback class.
Okay, So it has it has different
different methods
and you can perform different, different
key actions as well.
So you can copy that file
and you can paste that file in your
in your web page. Okay.
So just you could just take a look
at that rollback class.
Just briefly, guys.
And but most of the time this send keys
will work perfectly fine.
Let me go in here
and let me say
upload files, not interact.
That's why we use correct? Yes.
So that's why we sending direct path
because we won't be able to interact
with a Windows based popups.
Right.
But if you want to interact with Windows
based pop ups, what you can
do, you can use a robot class,
as I just mentioned.
Okay, upload
documents in here.
So in order to upload
documents using
selenium, we can simply
do is right
and we can
pass a file path.
Right.
And if send keys
not work, use
robot.
Okay, so robot
class is basically coming from Java.
Okay. From Java Library.
So there's a lot of different combinations
that you can do with keyboard.
Okay.
So you can briefly take a look at that,
what kind of methods it has
and what else you can perform.
Okay, But it's a pretty good library.
I found some actions with that as well,
and it's pretty good.
Okay. All right.
I guess any questions on actions class
and how to upload the documents?
Yes. Okay.
It's 807.
Okay, guys.
So let's take a quick break
and let people type up the code in here.
So probably let's come back at 825.
Okay?
Come back at 825.
A ten minute break,
and then we'll continue with JavaScript.
Execute.
Okay.
All right.
Okay, guys, I'll see you at 825
next to the code for
why it's not it's
it's just.
All right, guys, let's get back
and let's continue
the class.
So I get to go.
Nice.
Okay, guys.
So now let's talk about the JavaScript
execute,
right?
Okay, so JavaScript execution,
guys, did anyone do a research?
First of all, guys, didn't
anyone to do a research
about the JavaScript executes
see things like not,
okay, okay,
that's fine.
All right.
So JavaScript executes, right?
So JavaScript execution is a library
that is present in Selene, Okay.
And it can be executed
in different programing languages
like Java, Python
and different differently.
So the JavaScript executable
is an interface, Okay?
And he has some methods
that you can perform on the web page.
Okay.
So these methods are a little bit
different than usual actions.
Okay,
So like there is one exact same method
for click which you can perform
with JavaScript, execute as well.
Okay.
So other methods you can,
you can highlight an element,
you can refresh the page,
you can scroll up and down and on the page
you can also open a new tab
and you can also scroll
to a specific element.
Okay So these kind of actions are given
inside our JavaScript
to execute our library.
Okay.
And we will be performing those actions
right now.
Okay.
So we should only be using JavaScript,
execute order
when we are not able to perform actions
such as click
on the elements or opening a new tab.
Okay guys, so
let's go over the notes first
and here.
Okay, So JavaScript
executes.
Okay, so it is a library,
is a library and selenium
which can be executed
different
languages.
Okay, So we can put those in here, Java,
C-sharp, Python and etc..
Okay.
And we can say that
JavaScript execute here
is an interface, right?
And methods or actions
which can be performed
by using execute.
So those are the actions in here.
Click on the element,
right scroll to the page
and refresh the page
and highlight
the the element.
We can also do scroll to a
specific
element and we can also open and use TAP.
Okay, So any questions guys,
before we move to an actual implementation
robot class,
it has different methods to
to interact with Windows
based platforms.
It comes from Java Library.
Okay. All right.
So JavaScript
executable here has two different methods.
Okay.
It has executed script and execute
async script.
Okay.
So it's going to help us to keep the
the extras
and now more interactive, right?
As we said in here, scrolling to the page,
highlighting an element,
scrolling to a specific element.
Right. Or opening and you tap
right again guys.
So we can click
on the element the now we can click
by regular selenium and click.
We're going to have an action
class click right.
And now there's another alternative
that we can use is
JavaScript execute or collect.
Okay, So sometimes, as I said,
it's not going to work.
So you have to use some different,
different ways
in order to achieve what you need to do.
Right.
Okay, so JavaScript executed guys.
It has a little bit of a different syntax.
Okay.
So what you need to do, you just need to
what's called you just need to
remember those that script
that I am going to write down right now,
it has its own built in script
that you need to follow
in order to perform this kind of actions.
Okay, So
What I am
going to do, I'm
going to create a new Java class in here
and I will name it as
JavaScript execute or demo.
Okay, So
now what I want to do in here
is, is this.
So let me get
the URL.
Might have this here.
I'm not here.
Okay, that's
my thing.
It was some thoughts project
right now.
What was that
scene
that guys what was the what was
the length for the
okay so I had it right okay
but it was system okay.
All right Yeah I had it right. Okay guys.
So what I want to do in here, guys,
I want to
navigate to this page
and what I want to do.
I want to
enter using name and password
and what I want to do.
I want to highlight the password
text box in here.
Okay, So let's go back
in here and let's see
where we use
to identify those.
Think we have it here now,
okay. Yes.
So I'm going to copy this
and place this in here.
Okay.
Log in, button in here. Okay, guys.
So everyone knows what this trip does,
right?
I think I need I might change the URL
in my script.
Okay, so this is the URL.
So what I need to do here, I'm passing
username and password.
Okay?
And what I am doing here,
I will be highlighting this password.
Okay.
All right.
So now what I need to do guys,
since I passed username
and password in here, what I need to do.
Okay, so let me comment this out.
Okay.
So first of all, if I want to use
a JavaScript executed in here,
I need a JavaScript execute or object.
Okay.
And since this is an interface, right,
we won't be able to create
a an object directly, right?
We either to create it indirectly
or we will be casting this down.
Right.
So when was the last time we were casting
something down?
Guys were what was the implementation
and the web driver?
We're creating an object indirectly,
right?
Any other times, guys?
Alerts No, we're not.
We're not down casting in there.
Right.
The question is, when was the last time
we were casting something down
or up
in our implementation?
Anyone remember
now? Okay, guys,
last class.
What did we do?
Guys, It was just last
class, right?
So what we did in the last class, guys,
we casted down,
take screenshots, interface, right?
So what we are going to be doing this
time,
we will be doing the same thing,
but we will be doing it.
The JavaScript executing.
Okay,
so what I will do in here, JavaScript
executable, right?
I'll put it as gas. Jess Right.
So I'll have a JavaScript execute
right here and we are passing this down
to the driver, right?
Because that's our actual execution
object, right?
So we have this in here,
we have a JavaScript execution
execute object in here.
So now as I said, guys,
it only gives us two different methods,
which is execute script and execute
async script, right?
So we are only going to be using
the execute script method.
Okay. So
what I will do in here,
I'll do just that execute script.
So in here this method is going to
expect us to different arguments.
Okay.
So the first argument is the action
we are performing.
The second one is
the object on the web page.
Okay, so in here, guys, what is that
object that we're performing an action
on, not on the web page?
What is the object
that we're performing an action on
the password TextBox.
Right.
So what I'm going to do in here,
I'll just copy this
and paste this in here, right?
So that's the element
we need to interact with.
So before this, write what I need to
do, I am going to perform an action.
Okay, So since I said, guys,
it has a little bit of different
script, so you just need to remember
how it works.
Okay, so this is a built in script
that I am going to put in here right now.
Okay, So what you need to do in here,
you need to start with
arguments, okay?
Arguments.
Open and close the square bracket.
Inside the square bracket,
you need to put the zero
and then that style.
Okay, So we are we are working right now.
We're trying to change some styles
in here.
Okay.
And in this style,
what are we trying to do?
We're trying to do
with trying to manipulate
with a background color.
Okay.
And what I need to do
is want to put the background color
and I'll put an equal sign
single code, and let's do it as red.
Okay. So
here, don't get confused yet.
Okay, guys.
So because this script that I just wrote,
this is a built in script
to a JavaScript, it okay,
So if I don't think you have to memorize
all the scripts
that that JavaScript execute or has,
you just need to know the logic
and the actions
that you can perform with JavaScript.
Execute.
Okay, So what I will do right now,
let me run this
so that you guys can visually see
what is going on.
There we go.
So what happened here, guys?
Whenever I, I entered my log in
and the password,
it highlighted my password.
TextBox Right, guys.
So when,
when can you actually use this guys
Yeah, this is just a visual change for us.
Exactly.
For screenshots.
Absolutely right.
So sometimes let's say
the text is not appearing correctly.
So what you can do, you can just
highlighted take screenshots and
create a defect and attach that in there.
Right.
There we go.
When you want to highlight important words
or any elements on the webpage, right?
So this is one of the actions
that you can perform with
with JavaScript to.
Okay.
Any questions on this?
The blogs are crazy right now.
You misspelled arguments zero
line 21 here.
This is down casting.
We have an interface.
We need an object of that interface.
So basically what we're doing in here
is down casting our object
to the execution point object
that we have.
Okay.
So in here, since the driver is our
execution object,
so we need to perform some different
actions as well, right?
So that's why we're doing this.
Since we can't create an object
of the JavaScript, execute or interface.
So I said your name. Right?
Okay.
Okay, no problem.
Can you highlight
any text on the webpage? Yes.
So if you go ahead and get
you need to have a web
element on hand, right?
So You need to locate that web element
and then you have to execute this.
Correct.
Okay.
You can try. Yeah, try.
Let's try.
I don't know if we're going to work
red or what.
What else can we do?
Purple
of blue.
Okay, Yeah, Let's do this. Fine.
There we go.
So let's execute this.
So now it's a different color in here,
right?
Okay.
All right.
Any questions, guys, on this?
What does zero mean?
I'm not really sure what this means,
but just know that this is how it's built.
Okay?
How can you use it without down casting?
I don't think you will be able to, but
there might be some other ways, of course.
But this is one of the way that I know of.
Yeah, you can use the same syntax
for the username.
You just need to change that element.
You interacting with.
Okay.
Any other questions?
Okay, so here what we're doing,
we're just down casting.
That means.
So when you try to convert one data type
to another data type,
that's when you want a down downcast.
Okay.
Line 20.
Yes, the line 21 will be the same.
You just need to use this object
on the username.
Sure.
Just you can have the same exact in here.
You just need to change the
the element that you're
trying to interact with right.
So let's do this right.
And the other one is blue.
So let's run this.
All right, there you go.
So you just need to change the
the objects that you want to interact
with on the web page.
So we use for other actions.
What what other actions
are you talking about?
Confuse on down casting.
Okay, guys.
Okay.
In order for us to use
to use JavaScript, execute our methods.
Okay,
how do I get access to those methods guys?
Okay. If I have a class. Okay.
And it has some methods like, let's say
action class, what do we do, guys?
So in order for me to get access to,
the actions class
methods, we create an object, right?
Because it's a class.
Okay, So we're creating an object
because we can do this with actions class
because it's a class and you can create
an object of the class, right?
So since this JavaScript
execution is an interface, right?
So it's an interface
and we just need to have access
to the, to the methods, okay.
To the methods that it has.
And in order to do this one,
what we need to do,
we need to have an object to
we need to be able to execute it.
Okay, So what we're doing right now,
we're basically
converting the data type in here by down
casting.
Okay, So don't go too much into details.
Went to down
Castle, went to up class in here.
Okay so whenever you're having
an interface and you trying to use it
from different libraries,
you either don't pass or you directly,
you can implement
most of the time as we did on alerts guys,
depending on
what kind of interfaces they are
and what kind of
actions you want to perform.
Okay, so but in JavaScript guys
in JavaScript execute or what
you need to do, since you're performing
some actions on the web page,
you need to cast it down
and change your data type to a web driver.
Okay?
No, you don't have to do that.
You don't have to.
Dom cast all the what's called
all the interfaces, okay,
Because here, guys, what we are doing,
we're actually
performing an action
on the web page, right.
And to perform action on the web page,
we are using the driver in here.
Right?
So, so in order for us to
to perform some actions
and use at the same time
the methods that are available
in the JavaScript executable,
we need to have this JavaScript execute
or casted down and change the data type.
Okay.
Yeah. I think I already did that.
It should highlight both.
Okay, check them.
Check the spell spelling on the
on your script.
Okay.
And check your elements
that you're trying to interact.
Okay, guys.
So now we change the background color
of the username and password
text boxes, right?
So what I want to do guys,
I want to click on the log in button,
but I don't want to use the regular click.
Okay.
So there is another alternative for you to
to click on any button
or on any web element, right?
If you want to click.
So again, guys, since we already have the
the JavaScript execute our
object in here, what I am going to do,
I am going to use that
and I will use the same exact method.
Okay, so now what is the element we will
be interacting with in this case, less
the login button, right?
So what I'm going to do,
I'm going to put the login button in here.
Okay.
And then what I need to do,
I need to write down this credit,
that action that we're going to be doing.
Right.
So again, arguments
with zero, Okay.
And what I simply want to do
is to click, okay,
So this is the script,
the built in script for JavaScript execute
or to click on the button or the element,
whichever you want to.
Okay. Yep.
We got all we got three
different click options right now.
Okay, So let's execute this.
I think this is going to be really fast.
So let's see.
There we go.
So it highlighted all to element's
username and password, right?
And, and it clicked on the login button
and we see that we are on the dashboard.
Okay. Now, excuse me.
Exactly.
No excuse for not being able to click.
Right. Exactly.
All right,
guys Any questions on this?
Any questions on how to highlight
or how to
click on the Web element?
Any preference on clicking?
Yes, regular
click is the first option for you.
Okay.
Regular click is the first option for you.
The second option, it depends on you.
You either want to go with JavaScript,
execute,
or actions class click
okay, it's up to you.
They both to alternative to the
to the regular click
on Insulate.
Okay.
Any questions guys, for now?
Okay, good. All right.
So now let me go ahead and create
one more class
and Skeeter demo two.
So let's go over different
different options
in JavaScript. Executed.
Okay, go.
So I am going to change the URL to
Amazon.com.
Okay.
So okay.
So now, yes,
when normal click doesn't work,
you will try the others.
Exactly.
Okay, guys.
So now when you navigate to the Amazon,
you can see that
the page is very long, right?
So there's a lot of stuff
going on in here.
There's a lot of links.
So in order to to find something,
you have to scroll down right?
So sometimes, guys,
sometimes it's not going to happen
very often guys,
but it's really rarely happening.
Thing
that if you want to click on some elements
in the middle of the website
and you are just
showing this, it's not going to work.
Sometimes selenium doesn't
catch some elements which are not
visible to them, to selenium.
Okay,
So in order to click on those Elements,
what you want to
do, you want to scroll down
or what
you want to do, you want to scroll up.
Okay, So
what we're going to be doing right now,
we're going to be scrolling up and down
and we will be scrolling
to the specific elements.
Okay, So let's go back in here
and start actually
implementing that. Okay.
So first of all, guys,
if you want to scroll up and down
what you need to do,
you will go ahead and use JavaScript,
execute.
Okay?
So for me to use a JavaScript,
execute or methods, what I need to do,
I need to create a
object of the JavaScript, execute it right
script, execute a driver in here.
So we cast it down.
So now what I need to do,
I need to execute some scripts, right?
So in here guys, since I want to scroll up
and down, I don't have anything right now
to scroll into, right?
So I will be scrolling by numbers.
What do we scroll by on the web page,
guys?
Just calling up and down.
Guys, we're not changing any pages, right?
So here we are on the same page,
but we're just scrolling down
right
For now.
We don't need an element, right?
Because we are just
scrolling down on The View, guys.
Okay,
what are we scrolling by
browsing?
Okay, lines.
Not really.
So we will be scrolling by pixels.
Okay,
so what we are having here,
we will be scrolling by pixels.
Okay,
so what I am going to do in here,
I am going to
I am going to put a script
that is built in for JavaScript.
Okay, so what I am going to do in here,
so I am scrolling on the window, right?
So I'll put window that
scroll by
and inside the parentheses what I will do,
I will start from the zero and.
I will go down by 500 pixels in here.
Okay, so let me run this
and see what we're going to have
for now.
Yes, we have to. Yes, Correct.
If you just want, scroll on the page.
So for now you have to.
Yes. Yes.
So we navigate to the Amazon right now.
So now you can see that
we are a little bit down in here.
Okay.
So you can see that
we are not at the very top.
We work a little bit.
Scroll down in here.
Okay.
Any questions, guys?
Scroll with actions.
I haven't tried that.
Okay.
So how to know after zero
what number to put for?
This is just an option to scroll down.
Okay, so you can guess any any number
of checks and
in the scrolling text.
I'm not. No, no guys.
So here I am just scrolling down
without knowing where I'm going to end up.
Okay,
so I'm just scrolling a little bit down
so I don't know where I'm going to end up,
but this is how you scroll
down on the page and I'm going to show you
how to scroll down
to this, to this specific element, and
that's going to make more sense to you.
Okay, You can scroll more.
Yeah.
If you if you edit this number,
you can scroll more.
Okay.
So now if I want to scroll back up, guys,
So how would you do this?
Okay. Or
just here,
what you want to do this same way, right?
What you can do,
you can go -500.
I'm not sure about a horizontal way
how to scroll on horizontal way
because here guys this JavaScript execute
or whenever you maximize your page,
most of the pages
they get,
you don't have to scroll horizontally
right?
Okay.
So this is going to be really fast.
So let's see if we can catch up on this.
Let's see.
Okay, there we go.
So we scroll down and we went back up.
Okay, Can you break in between?
What do you mean?
Oh, you want to see?
Yeah, yeah, sure. Yeah. Let's.
Let's do this.
Yeah, sure.
Let's put for 2 seconds. Okay?
And let's run this.
Okay.
There we go.
All right,
so we scroll down and we scroll back up
the second JavaScript executable.
I think it's a class
that's a different thing.
So the one you should be looking for
is JavaScript executable,
which is an interface.
Okay.
All right.
So now, guys, what I want to do in here,
since
it's a long way right
there, is it's a long page here.
What I want to do, I want to scroll.
Okay, beautiful.
I want to see
I want to scroll
right to this button over here.
Back to top.
Okay. So.
So since we don't know how many pixels
we need to scroll down.
Okay, What we can do?
We can directly scroll to this element.
Okay, so what I am going to do in here,
I am going to inspect this page
and I will need to identify this element
first.
Okay, So let's see,
what can we use in here, guys?
How can we identify this?
Let's
see if class name is available. Right.
So let me copy this class name
in here.
All right.
And let's create this web element
back to top, right?
Right.
Where
to find element.
I have a class name in here
and what I need to do now
since I have that element on hand
right now.
So I going to
execute this script.
Okay. So again,
I need to paste an element
that I need to interact first in here
and then I need to paste it.
Actual scripts.
Okay, So what I'm going to do
is zero arguments, and here, right.
And now what the action is,
I am basically scrolling into the view,
right Scroll
into view in here
and open and close parentheses
and I'll just paste to inside.
Okay,
So let me execute this
and let's see if we will be,
scrolling down to the exact same element
that we just mentioned here
or just go up and down.
And now you can see that we scroll
right to the bottom where you can see this
back to the top button in here,
right?
Pretty cool, right, guys?
It's just it's just a little bit confusing
scripts that Java's executed or has.
But other than that, there is a lot
of cool stuff that you can do with this.
All right.
Any questions, guys?
Let me close the session in here.
Good question, Michael.
Yeah, you could do that.
Try this.
Try this at work.
Let's see what happens.
So if you get fired,
don't come to me, though,
okay?
Okay.
If it comes to me,
then I'll probably laugh, but it's okay.
We'll see.
Okay.
Now questions.
Let's continue. Right. So let me create
a new Java class in here and say
class four
Oh, I'll probably won't be boss
for I won't be probably doing automation
in three months, guys.
Yes, I am going
full time back in development,
but probably in a month or so
we'll see.
Oh, no, no.
This not in my last batch, guys.
Probably not, but.
All right.
So let's continue.
So now
study
what to do
if if you if you study and it's fun,
but you absolutely not passionate
so if you're finding fun stuff in it.
So that means you already have
some passion, right?
We just
just think about money now,
okay.
All right, guys.
So let me copy this and let's go over
some more JavaScript
execute or actions.
So instead of Amazon,
I will be going to Google.
Okay.
So what I am going to do in here, guys,
I will be using a JavaScript
executed to open up a new tab.
Okay, So what I will do
and here again I am going to
create a JavaScript execute object
and casted down
to the driver. Right?
And then what I need to do,
I am going to execute this script.
Okay, so me to open a new tab, it's
going to be just one script
and I will be managing Windows again.
All right, So window dot open
right, and opening closed parentheses
here.
I need to insert the semicolon
and finish my
what's called
and finish my statement.
Okay, So let's actually
do this.
Okay. Okay.
Let's run this first. Okay.
And let's see what's going to happen.
I'm going to bias syntax poser.
I thought you going
to put my picture in there.
All right, So I'm executing this.
Oh, he already has mine. Okay.
Okay, good, good.
All right,
So I executed this script, right?
So what happened
is I navigate it to Google and
I opened up a new tab.
Right?
So right now, guys,
so let me close this.
Any questions on this line?
16 guys.
Now, this is just a built in scripts in.
Right? So I have a question for you guys.
So if I navigate to the URL
after I open up and New window guys
in the script this time
this is a built in script, okay?
That's
why we need to put the semicolon in here.
So okay, when I open up a browser,
I open up a new window.
Okay.
So if I navigate to Google, guys,
where is this going to open?
Is it going to open on the first tab
or the second one
second line?
Okay. Okay.
First
will.
First, second. Okay, cool.
Let's run this and see
what happened.
Guys.
It opened
that page and navigated to that page
on the first tab. Why?
Because even though we open
a new tab in here,
our focus is still on the first page.
Okay,
so if I locate this element, the search.
Okay, if I locate this element
and I send some cheese in here
right after this script,
is it going to send in there
or now?
Yes, right.
Because our focus is on the
Google in here.
So let's go ahead.
I think it was this one. All right.
So let's inspect that
Google.
So let's inspect this page.
And what I want to do here, let's see.
Okay, I have a name in here,
so let me use this thing.
Close this. Okay.
So what element search is equal to driver
dot find element by
where is the name
here and what I need to do.
Search, start and keys.
There's a lot of stuff in right.
Okay.
So let's execute this
so we open a new tab.
Tab in here.
Would navigate it to Google
on the first of all on and you can see
that we entered the text on the first tab
because our focus is still there.
But visually we on the same
we are on the second tab, right?
Any questions on this?
Any questions on JavaScript?
Execute any questions to what we've done
so far in Selenium.
Guys,
if you click on what
you don't have to click
to open a new tab, right?
So you just need to execute this script
and it will open
a new tab for you.
The text we sent, the text we sent
in here.
So you
need to click on the Google support.
I don't think
it's going to open a new tab.
If you click
the first one. Yes.
So if you want to do that, you
you open a new window.
You need to switch your focus
to the second right.
And only then you can navigate to the
to the different zero.
Actually, that's going to be
a good homework for you guys.
Let me add that.
Okay?
Because you already should know how it is.
Switch between windows
or is and it's
Michael.
That's not that's not good, man.
That's.
Am I falling in there?
Why are they holding me?
I'm like, I'm like,
fainting in there, man.
Come on.
They hold me back.
Okay.
All right,
So that's actually pathetic notes.
Let me see
the homework.
So open
new browser, right.
Open a new tab.
Navigate to a different URL
on a new tab.
Okay.
There you go
to syntax.
Okay. Nice.
At least here I have two guns.
Okay, that's good.
My mic is in team syntax. Why?
Who hired him?
First of all, he hired and so.
Well, probably he's working for free.
So that that works.
Okay.
All right, guys, any questions?
Any questions on.
Let's put the jokes aside. Right.
So we've got 30 more minutes, guys.
So any questions on
JavaScript, executable actions, classes,
anything guys
are, it's fresh.
That's a homework for you. Okay.
So that's what I have
in my notes. Okay.
Find out how to refresh with JavaScript.
Execute.
We go through the last homework.
What is what is confusing
guys for the last
for the last.
Yeah. I don't think you should.
You should worry too much about this.
Remembering the script. Exactly.
For use with this one.
What is the confusion?
Are we going to use Firefox in selenium?
No, but I'm not sure if you guys are going
to be doing this in test engine.
You should probably I think you will be
doing some parallel testing in testing.
G Okay.
So you will be using two different
browsers.
But again, guys, I'm not sure.
I think that was one of the topics
where you parallel testing.
You can ask the instructor, I don't even
know who's going to be teaching testing.
You guys.
Oh, okay.
Yeah, ask him because I'm pretty
sure testing G has Good,
good.
Where you guys can do parallel testings.
All right,
so let's go over the homework now.
Okay?
Okay.
Pretty good amount of things in here.
Like, there's no questions for me.
Yes, that's it for tonight.
I think I'll
I'll.
I'll start with I'll start with
page Object model right now,
just to give you
an idea of what is going on
and then we'll wrap it up.
But first, let's go
let's go over the homework.
Okay.
Okay, guys.
So the first homework, you open
a new browser, you open a new tab,
you navigate to the different URL
on a new.
Okay, So that's that should be clear.
And then here goes
one test case
where you need to use it in testing,
and I want you to use assertion.
Okay.
So what I you to do is
navigate to this
website and then you're to know it's
here.
All right,
So enter a valid username
and leave the password empty.
Okay,
So on log in button and verify the error.
The error message with the text
password cannot be empty.
Is this way. Okay.
And you guys are did this
okay.
That's fine.
You can do it one more time.
Right. But.
But do it.
Okay.
So don't do it in test
and you do it in selenium now.
Okay.
All right.
So the second one, did you probably you
guys probably did this as well
so navigating to the same website,
leave username and password empty
and click on the log in button.
Okay.
And verify this error message is
this way.
Okay. And here
the other one.
So you need to to the same website.
Enter valid
username and the wrong password.
Okay.
So click on log in and verify that
invalid credentials is this okay?
When is the due date?
There's no due date for this. Okay.
This is for your own practice, guys.
Okay.
So this one, do it on the selenium
project.
Okay.
So what I want you to do on this one
is to go here
and start
going through each and every tab in here.
Okay,
So first of all, what you need to do,
you need to drag and drop
here, double click in here,
switch to the frame, enter something here.
Okay.
I don't think
we have anything in here. Yes.
And then click on the next available.
So I think we're on the phone
right now. Yes.
Click on the next tab
for click on this link.
Wait for the element in here, verify
the whole text is displayed in here.
Then click on the next tab, guys.
Okay, Let's
see how you're going to handle this. So.
So basically
what I want you to do is navigate
through every tab that you have in here
and perform all the actions.
Okay, So this form, right,
you already know how to handle the
what's called radio buttons and checkbox
says you know how to handle the drop downs
and here we know how to input text
and click on submit and everything.
Right So when you're done with that
you go to controls.
I think you already we were already there.
So widgets in here. There we go.
We have another file upload, Right.
So try to upload any file in here
actions again, click me double click.
Okay drag and drop in here.
Move to an element.
Right. So switching.
So we've done this example.
Try to do it again.
Okay Exactly.
Do everything on the website
one by one on the tabs.
Okay. Yes.
They the YouTube channel
that I used to work is nivine.
Okay.
I think it was nivine
something.
But if you just Google not Google,
just let's go
Navy automation.
There we go. Okay,
So remember this
you guys
okay, you
So yeah, I think this is for the
Naveen Automation lab.
Okay. So go in here.
He's got pretty good
pretty good videos in here.
He explains a lot of good stuff
that.
All right.
Any other questions, guys?
Homework? Yes.
It's posted in the course.
Announcements.
Go. Okay.
I'll push the code right after we finish.
Okay.
All right, guys,
If there's no questions tomorrow,
we're going to go over the page model.
That's going to be a little confusing.
Okay, guys.
But because I will be jumping through
between a lot of different packages.
Okay.
So I'd suggest to just follow me
when I'm explaining
and not type
because you will get lost in there.
Okay.
So I'll be jumping
through different packages tomorrow.
So it would be best to follow me
what I'm doing in there.
I don't think I'm going to teach
cucumber guys.
Okay.
Yes. No typing tomorrow.
Just come to the class and enjoy the show.
Last class tomorrow.
All right? Okay, guys.
Have a good night, everyone.
Thanks, everybody.
But tomorrow's topic page object model.
Okay.
I'll see you guys tomorrow.
And please start
working on the homework
and please practice.
Okay.
Thanks, everybody,
and I'll see you tomorrow.
Okay.
Goodnight, everyone.