According to Smith,
all road students
last number
eight
according to canvas
last class of the timber
fire.
And we're almost on the verge to complete
their paperwork will deliver almost 90% of
the remaining 10%
desirable contribution metrics.
Let's pick Right.
So first, let's quickly go to
what are the links, the debates,
what are the things we covered in
yesterday's issue?
Edmunds?
What was the first thing
that we really asserted?
Scruggs.
What was the first topic
we learned in the studies class?
Got it. Got it.
The first thing was using
each object more of
the right
functions in in
respective classes.
Correct.
The very first thing, what we did
this one correct.
Now, according
to this particular function,
according to this particular function,
what we are doing here in this function
is related to one particular class.
Right.
If we have any function which we see
which is given for this particular screen
in the application.
So instead of writing that function
in our class,
according to three locators
there, we can write
this particular method in this class
or to set in the speech itself.
And then instead of calling to three
locators begin, simply call one method
correct. This
disconnect, and
then we can do these things
for polymorphism.
Yes. Yes.
Correct.
Now, after this, in common methods,
we came up with the requirement
of very common operations.
The operations
which we perform every now and then,
for example, say,
to give the operation Click operation.
And then we saw a couple of more scenarios
associated to this particular
operations. For example,
same gives method.
But every time when we are going
to send the data before that,
it might happen that there is some data
available in that particular suit.
Right.
In that case,
if I'm simply sending the new data,
it will come, it will add
with the previous data, existing data.
So for example, if it was this day
and I am sending one, two, three,
so my final value becomes
absolutely not going to be correct.
In that case, in that case, missing
that he was going to create.
So now, according to the minimum,
what we have to do
first, we have to clear the
and then we have to save the date.
These are the two things
we need to perform.
But if I'm using these operations,
it gives operation
every now and then in the application. C
15 times, 20 times are 2000 times, right?
Every time I have to call the near doors,
it gives me an
uneasy. Suddenly I'm coding same methods.
Two times I do methods this much of times
again and again.
It's not going to make any sense.
So what we did,
we created a class called Common Methods
in this Common methods.
In this common methods.
We added the function here,
and in that function
we provided no clear method,
but so this time
we are overwriting only element
and the data which we need to
parse in the form of string.
This is what we are doing
and it's
this is what we are doing.
Fine.
So next time I don't need to call out
Delimiter.
Dawson gives method. No.
What I will do simply is I will call this
particular method same text
file locator.
I already have great in mind pages
according to object model
designed by then.
Basically I'm using initialize
all those elements.
When I initialized all those elements,
I can call anything
from there
while creating the object object
I had created in big initialize
this class.
Next page initialize this class.
I extend it in my common methods. Right.
So the same object is working
throughout my project or not.
The same object is working
toward my project.
So now.
So now things are getting to be used.
Things are getting absolutely reduced
and you see object calling particular
data is coming from either Excel by right
or feature file or properties
file from anywhere,
and the method is performing
its operations.
That's how we wrap up every single thing
with the concepts of Java.
Now we are able to connect
every single point
a method connected to my classes.
Classes are connected via objects
we are calling constructor.
Initialize
all these objects using my script.
Pre feature
files are connected to the steps.
If steps are connected to my
This features are connected to my classes
and the classes are connected
to my politics that I have already.
Right?
So now my entire project becomes a big
this big becomes a complete big
and that's what we need
single execution point.
When we use Mavin project
in Mavin project,
we have a single execution point
going from Don extremely high and
due to
this reason we added this particular part
as a plug in.
We call it Mavin.
Sure.
Why is plugging now?
What does what display
plugging that specifically this plug in?
Mavin sure.
But like in generally
makes our project in the form of a bead.
Will a single unit connect
all the glasses, collect
all the packages, checks
all the functions, check all the code,
compile
this code, execute this code in a single
fully understood
always
remember
either you use this dandy
framework or you use Kimber framework.
You will use much better plug in
because this plug in
is related to your Mavin
notwithstanding the conversion rate.
So if we are working with the project,
we will always use
Mavin should be lucky is that everyone
All right.
So the very first method be completed
in the class was same method, right?
So put it in the notes.
Should note
the second operation in this song
was clear completion.
Right.
But we using this click operation
every time
without providing bit in my application.
It is loading
sometimes the selenium will not lead
unfortunately like this is will be right.
If it will be my best guesses then it will
affect my overall automation coverage.
So according to the standards, we have to
provide a sufficient amount of bead
so that my bead becomes loaded properly,
my element becomes visible on the screen
and it will becomes visible on the screen.
I can easily perform
whatever the operations
I want to perform
on the particular element, right?
So for that reason,
we learn to operate in selenium, right?
What are those tools?
Nice.
We have two types of works
implicit and explicit.
Click right between these.
What is the difference
between implicit and explicit?
Nice.
Christine Implicit.
Wade That relies on
time.
Implicit which relies on time and explicit
will relies on completion.
Explicit, which relies on condition.
Fine. Now,
when we talk about implicit,
we have a separate method for this
that were not managed
by most are implicit rate correct.
We have this method directly Selenium.
Unfortunately for explicit
we do not have an environment
manager timeout not explicitly.
We do not have a method.
So what we have to do,
we have to use a degree of explicit weight
and that a degree is web driver with
that driver beat
underscore.
I gave you one more explanation when we
were taking a selenium review fluently.
What is the difference?
Driver do what are explicit?
What is the difference
is before
explaining the topic of window
and as I gave you this explanation
that Luther
one, I'm just asking you a question
from that informative you today.
I didn't start anything yet.
We are just still revising.
My question is
right now.
So right now
we are talking about implicit weight
and explicit weight
in our function, right?
In selenium in framework.
So implicit work which relies on
which relies on implicit
and explicit, which is the one
which relies on condition setting.
But when I was taking, I was taking
your review sessions for selenium.
And that point of time
I explained one more type of make
implicit explicit in explicit
the driver and another one
was blue in the late right.
So when I ask what is the difference
in between the blue?
So how would you answer
that? And
we end.
We will also be relying on conditions
by the number of quotations
be provided in blue, incomplete.
So based on those number of liquidations
it removes its cycle rating.
Yeah, it correct or correct,
you just google it.
No, it just Google it.
Excellent.
The where do you see
appalling delinquency.
My I got this what is available there.
I know what frequency right.
So basically rate
basically when we talk about it
we simply for example you want to wait
for this particular condition.
For particular condition.
So you really wait for this condition
three times increments.
Then seconds one stands again is completed
again, the cycle
for insisting that it would again
to print the cycle audience.
It goes how many times? Three times. Why?
Because the Model three predictions
you provided is three
ways reputation
of you define the reputation of times,
reputation
of cycle in a
the final.
So right then
that's why I always anecdotes from here
and then illustrate
to do this
maximum time for the driver
to wait for the condition the other one
they expect of doing to make it to
the game is used for define
and what is the remaining definition.
This is how
maximum determines what the
what exam. But if you provide 10 seconds.
Right and you provide three depredations,
maybe the big once is three.
So how many times
I wish time it would make for
end plus ten plus ten, three times.
That is a constraint.
This is the maximum.
So it is just
for the interview question, Right.
So you should know.
You should know what is doing great.
What is the primary rate?
What is the difference between this Indian
and any other way to use whatever
documentation mode?
Everyone knows it.
You will use the same. But it's true.
Names are always using the same.
I know couple of students
who have been working in a different last
five six years in the industry.
They're still using technologies
sleep an implicit every bit.
That's what I'm explaining. So
as well
as the frequency rate is used to define,
you'll give me a Venetian
if my maximum length.
There's why I argue is the half of
the definition is what is the big one.
See with which we want to check
the condition before throwing in.
Great.
So this is the frequency
limit number of reputation.
Great.
So now here, here we are using
which one goes in click method.
When we provide the method
which which way we could see
when we are providing this big method,
wait for the community method.
So we are using explicit, oblique,
explicit way.
It means migrate is relying on the mission
to make the element becomes clickable
and you'll see this condition
employed in my function.
Right there is
is this correct or not?
Then we be 11..
One point.
I just remember
already based.
So now now here
I've been using this
particular
for two methods for applicability
click method same next to method.
Sometimes it's important.
Sometimes it's very important, right?
So that everyone, everyone can be
a part of this conversation right next.
So we learn Excel.
In my opinion, lecture should not be
a one week conversation
right
when I'm delivering the lecture point.
When it comes to topic,
then only I should explain.
Right?
And I never allow anyone to distort
their decorum of the class when I'm
something important.
But at the same time I have to make sure
that my superiors are not getting bored.
I need to involve them with
the communication, with the conversation.
You guys can open up great. Like this.
If you guys get an opportunity
to speak on this particular platform.
Right.
And if I ask you to play your part here.
Right, definitely.
It will boost up your confidence.
At the same time,
you will get more interest in my classes.
I got to
correct
this philosophy for kids
also came from this background, right?
From the business, from here.
Engagement is extremely important.
Business engagement rates plus liquidity,
and that level of engagement
is extremely important
the way they live.
And I'm saying engagement is important.
Everyone starts planning to get to get to
finance.
Just it's hard.
Congratulations.
And you didn't invite me very big.
I purchased new T-shirt for your function
and you didn't
wait with.
Excellent. Excellent.
You are very free now.
It is utilized Google go it completely.
Although you have people upset
or you're frustrated.
I think it
Excellent, excellent.
She is happy.
Nice.
We are not, you know
even thinking of the boss to
and you are ready for the second one also
excellent second inning
is going to start nice All the very best
and see
for me is thinking about when I'm
going to teach in base 12.
So cutting
exactly
the moment you'll see
there is a restriction
to your freedom, to your thought process,
where you are
not finding new things to block
better the need that please
immediately.
Sometimes, sometimes you have
to understand one thing liquidity.
At this point it's start.
What a question, Alex.
It's like how you can execute your script
without writing it.
If you need to build a failure report,
you need to write or commission
script first, like
by guys,
now click method,
send text button vibrant.
Let's talk about JavaScript,
execute the method.
Why do we need JavaScript?
Execute method 10 minutes
Students
Right.
Sometimes in our application
there are a couple of operations
on which my selenium normal command
doesn't work, such as completion.
So when interacting with the code,
if my nightly operation is not working
or any other operation is not working,
I should be having an alternative, right?
So we do one alternative here
for completion
by a JavaScript execute there. Great.
So what is the difference in between
JavaScript executing and normal take?
I told you
this normal still in complete command
always checks for two things
whether the element is available there
or not, what it is intractable or not
great in UI clean,
but at the same time with the same thing.
If we talk about JavaScript
bleep work here,
it works with the code,
it interacts with the code.
All right.
The good header give you have
within the next edit beneath there.
So that's the difference.
That's the difference
in between JavaScript, execute
and normal click method.
So far so good.
Everyone to this point.
Then after that after they
we downloaded something from someone.
Junior. Remember this particular plugin?
We downloaded this part great board
because we need,
we need the Google
Maven report right to do MAVEN report.
So we got one guy called Damian.
Great call Damian.
Let me show you once again
this guy,
this guy.
Great. Damian
So this guy wrote
one particular plugin for us.
So then with this plugin we can generate
very good report or graphical report
current and see how, how generous
this guy is.
Yet a jigsaw
once we are happy with by this number.
So much with brother even will this number
all right.
Excellent Alex What a beautiful quality
Everything he had.
I didn't understand that.
But now, now you see here
it says Maven move or that you can
by reporting put this into your politics
AML file right run this command.
But we had an ambient test command. Right.
And the reports are generating
in target folder in the combat
multiple supported fine.
So we added this particular plugin
yesterday in our class.
Right.
And we deleted some
of the optional code played
below Asia.
Great.
So now here we change the project name,
which is the input directly grade.
We changed this version, right?
If this project is not working for
someone, drive it 5.5.0.
Right. That right there.
It will work
if that region is also not working.
I me give you a couple of more words,
but majority of people
were able to solve this problem yesterday
joining the workshops.
Please do it.
All right, guys.
So we changed this particular part
execution point
so far in this part, right
after reading this particular plugin
from here.
B they do R and R class
and when we went to our class,
we and here would bring together
a part called GZ Target.
Could you, can you see this?
Can everyone see this
right now when we are executing, remember
to generate this report we have to
execute automatic simplify.
If you're executing only a smoke,
it will not generate this report.
Bomb not accessible
will generate this report grade.
So after executing from an excellent file,
we got this particular folder
he had collected.
You were a team of report and there we see
all these reports available
so you can see for tags,
related steps, related features,
related failures selected
indisputably What
screwed everyone
from. Yes.
Got it. Got it.
So I'm coming to that point. Nobody.
I'm coming to their point now.
Now, I gave you one task yesterday, right?
And Jimi, I should I must acknowledge
you did a great job.
This guy did a complete function
in the common methods, Right?
The task which I gave
and his code was working absolutely fine.
The best part is he applied within two,
3 hours after the completion of the class.
It shows his consistency.
It shows his particular,
you know, commitment towards the job,
towards his work, work to the study.
I must appreciate it.
Good job, Jimmy.
All right, fine.
Or if I need that kind of dedication
from your students.
So now, now that function, that function,
we are going to add in a common methods
played.
Common methods. Correct.
In this
common
methods, we are going to add a function.
Through that function we will select
any drop and we will select any drop down.
So now, before writing that function,
that idea
or drop drop down selection
or dropdown selection using
text, see now
tell me if I want to select any value
from there.
Drop down how many things I need.
Just think about the code for select
class 18.
How many things we need to automate.
One dropdown
greetings.
All right.
What are those two things the most is
all right.
All right.
Well, element is one thing.
What are remaining to value?
Second thing and select glass 35.
So variables think is very
first thing is all the geniuses
we need to write the function.
We need to write a function, select
the dropdown.
We need to write the function.
This is the very first thing
we have done it
for dropdown in choosing date and calendar
with this month.
Correct. I wrote the code.
It disturbs your whole mark,
but their task was to write
this function in common method.
Yeah, that's fine. That's fine.
You can copy this
because see what I'm saying?
Basically, next time
you don't have to use this function here
and then simply call this method, provide
the web element, provide the dataset.
Okay.
So first thing
first thing we need web element,
and second thing we need is text read
is this Critics
see not what I'm writing in the function.
I think select is is equals to nil select
and I'm passing this element
now again,
again, the concept of polymorphism
method overriding what will happen here.
I will override the element. Right?
And now I have this method in select
class selected by value, select by index.
Select my visibility text.
If I'm providing select by index
instead of providing here in the argument
is doing what I do plus
integer symbol,
then I can override the integer.
Right?
If I want to pass the value,
then again a string.
If I want to mask the text,
I can pass complete text from the string.
Does it make sense to everyone?
Does?
Is this clear to everyone based
what I'm doing.
So now, now, next time.
Let's see.
Did say in your inheritance.
Can someone please.
Okay,
get someone please share the code for that
particular one so I can copy and paste it.
Code is their task homework
and they can write
here.
No, no, not discord.
Yeah, that
is fine.
I just want. Okay, let's do it.
Let's do one thing. Let's do one thing.
What I'm going to do is post here.
Let me show you the application
right here.
This is the application we have.
If I click on an employee here,
I can. So
when I save it
after this,
I have to click on this every time
I used it. Which code?
But code four month,
which I gave you right.
Yesterday in the task,
did you complete the task.
Fine.
So now, now I'm
coming to this particular screen rate.
In this screen
I have a code, if you remember, but
ending the employee training.
So let me quickly read
once the menu. Right.
And then hit a button, click on it.
Option right.
I will try to select any one part
such as nationality.
Just one thing I'm going to show you using
this particular function, would they be
okay,
So let's do it in an employee feature.
If I'm adding one particular employee.
So this in already this one
clicks on, see a button and the employee,
if it successfully
let me go to this particular store
and here it is
the gear discord forced just to check.
So I'm seeing here,
instead of changing these
dropdown
and here I'm writing
first, I just want to check
whether my
this particular function is working
or not
working.
Click on Save Button
after clicking on Save button.
What it does,
it will take me to this particular page
right now here, I need to find this edit
option to place.
That is going to be my point.
What I'm doing here.
It will take me to this particular
edit option.
So let me take this edit option.
It says I did button. Steve
Let's take way of value.
This type
based export
rate.
Yeah, that's fine, but I'm just checking.
I'm just it just for this purpose.
Don't worry.
I mean, I'm not going to do this.
Follow this completely. Everything.
I can put it anywhere.
So there's a new employee page here.
I'm going to write this
particular function, but edit option it.
And then the second look
that I would need is
marital status post. See,
it says Here it is, this one
item.
So let me go for this idea
I'm putting in guys again.
I'm saying in an employee pay rate,
not employee detail speech
or employee less
because I didn't clear the pages of now.
Okay.
Just to show you
I'm doing this member status.
And then another thing is
don't don't get confused with the task
for your task
is you have to create a new page for this
and I will go
check with the nationality
first.
Names in combination,
find marital status
or nationality and adoption point.
So not if I go in my date Employee here,
Employee successfully going to declaration
employee here.
I'm going to write dashboard
Redemption
here I need to perform Click completion.
Right.
So let me put it into the click operation
post after this.
I'm talking about select dropdown for it,
so it is asking for two things.
So first one I'm going to take is stored
marital status, comma.
What would be the value
of the mental status?
Single married, other.
Let's talk about here other.
How can you say married?
Lot of people are planning
to get separated if you're not married?
It's either.
Then the another one is select dropdown.
Again, I'm taking an employee page
or nationality.
Right.
And here in the
nationality this time select.
Let's take the easy one.
British, British one.
And then here is going to click
on Save option.
So again, this particular word I can use
is this correct?
This just to show you
I'm putting this code
and putting up this putting up this code
just to show you.
So let me go ahead
and this time
execute this task.
Yeah,
I clicked on Steve option already, Jimmy
and I'm doing great.
See it selected British selected
other entities successfully saved like
right case
So now your global function
your global function is working
absolutely fine.
Which function working
absolutely fine or drop down automation
right now let's talk about
another important function here.
You'll get the finally,
your favorite part is into the picture.
Yes, Correct.
So we are going to work on
screenshot method.
Screenshot method.
Thanks for being patient with me.
Now I see what they want.
The reports we are providing doesn't
mean that how we have executing the code
and whatever the things we are doing
absolutely fine.
But we do not have any article is not.
We do not have any idea it is open now
that it
started.
So let's write a function.
Let's write a function for screenshot.
So here I'm going to write
this particular function.
This particular function will return
me, will return me
the screenshot of the scenario.
I am going to execute.
This function will return
with the scenario.
I'm going to execute. All right.
All right.
Great.
For every single execution
which we are going to make, this function
will then make a particular screenshot
and just put everyone
nowadays don't write anything right.
Focus here
what I'm trying to do very first thing
I remember, can we find this method in
which materials
dropdown selection?
Yes, obviously.
Why not?
I'm going to put it into the code.
Everything will been developed.
This is what I'm doing for you
when needed.
So you get it.
So now see the remember whenever we talk
about the grammar,
whenever we talk about Gutenberg.
So he can do always returns,
always returns
and able find
what it returns
life it returns and able byte.
So when we get when we get the data
multiple, multiple bytes,
multiple bytes existence
which means area of byte.
Understood.
So in part function we read the function
for taking the screenshot in the
could remember it will return one thing
that is area of byte.
So in the end.
In the end I have Eddie Obeid
also were writing the function button.
So what would be the return type
in this case for my function?
What would be the return date in this case
case?
Ariel Bait. Simple.
Let's go ahead and write.
One function was to be public
stating write public stating.
And I'm seeing my
name would be a
screenshot.
Now see
now see it is giving me right now
it is giving me this
right.
So here
it would be my edit of my understood
edit of Mike and here
I am going to write
so terminates in selenium
which might be used for screenshots.
We use a screenshot.
This is equals to
x screenshot
driver.
I hope everyone used this particular
method.
This particular part
in your selenium classes.
I hope everyone used it.
If someone didn't do
slide
this lately, we are going to change this
according to this particular framework.
That cucumber that we are using.
Yeah, that's what I am saying. So
here, here.
Right.
What we can do basically is simply
we can simply change it
according to the consumer functionality
that we are using.
All right.
So that's why I implemented any of byte.
Now see what we are going to change
in this function,
read this function and even most days
don't get screenshot s right.
So here we provide
what output takes, output based output.
Then what you generally
provide is still me.
You provide FYI.
Correct
here because it is returning me
any overbite.
So do we need to provide file
or do we need to provide something else?
You see three functions d function.
So which one we should provide
because it is written by it.
So we have to provide bytes.
We have to provide bytes.
Understood.
Since it is returning bytes.
So here I writing the object
that I'm going to store it as big bytes
picture of bytes
which is mine, which is my edit,
which is my body.
Understood.
Now, Now when it is returning,
it is returning.
I need to store this screenshot
somewhere in my framework.
I need to store this
the screenshots in my inbox
when I need to provide
one particular files.
Right So here I am writing five. Right.
It would be my list of source five,
maybe eight. So
I'm going to write it as dot
get screenshot as
so now here it will be my file.
This payment would be
split output.
They would be mine for free.
Whatever.
Okay, now see what I'm going to write you.
I'm going to write 10 minutes
to access the file, to access the file
and copy the code which file utility
we have to do with the file in Java,
which utility we use.
I knew this
and we use pilot in space
Dark copy fight is this method correct?
What I'm writing
it is asking source by so source fine.
Which one?
I've already provided Source my right.
It's his destination
by destination by now.
Right. The destination by now.
I am going to define like this
C needle fly.
And here in this new file
I'm going to provide the bottom
right arm location.
So do we have any location
for the screenshot as of now?
Do we have any location
for this screenshot?
As of no, we do not.
Right.
So let's go ahead and do it.
Let's go ahead and do it.
Open your constants class,
Open your constraints class
and provide a box
here in your constants class.
Provide a but
what would be under your package?
Enter your package. Great.
So now see in constants, I'm
going to provide a public
static final.
I'm going to provide the path is
a screenshot
screenshot file, but
great
in this point code would be C
and then here I am providing I'm
providing the path for the screenshot
is under the screenshot
folder under the screenshots folder.
Okay.
So now tell me if I say under screenshots
folder.
Maybe have to create this
particular volume
where we have to create this order.
It'd be
nice.
I'm not a Jardim is here, here, here.
So now.
Now let's do.
Let's do it here like this.
It should be more screen.
Can you see
I haven't already announced interest
Can everyone see
I have this folder A screenshots here now
right
now go into your common interests
so far any questions
how we provided this part
so for any question for this anyone
is that clear.
That clear.
Guys please don't die Please don't date
been responding
short.
Are you want me to show again?
Okay.
Now see, guys here.
We provided this part in the context
because this thought
is not going to change. Correct.
So we provided always those boxes
when these are binding in our constants.
Plus, what is your user idea?
What you in the class
When I explain this part of city
user data is always redundant.
It is a command,
right of operating system.
It's always written from Java,
the back of your project.
So whenever
whenever you are executing this command,
it returns
the part of the Project Builder project,
but it returns the command,
it returns output.
Okay, is the SO user territory.
Okay, so user directory students
for part of this particular
no issues, That's what I would say.
So now it becomes odd part global
because if I write this in your machine
it will return the part of your machine.
If I ran it in my machine,
included in the portal by machine.
Right.
So if I write this one,
it makes our base globally on
an inside this, this bot are constants.
This button constant dynamic,
these quantities and this could now be one
point.
So now let's go into the common method.
So here, here and with the right enemy.
No, my file location, I have a mark,
I have a file location.
Is it just a screenshot Facebook
extension Facebook group.
It is
giving me the error mode a chance to
I get.
Fine. Let's do it.
We take it to over. And now.
Now here
simply I'm going to say it returns
it returns my big box.
You see guys this function
you see guys this function is
clean screenshot.
Can you see it?
Everyone.
But but I can see one problem
in this function I'm seeing find
should be saved in this screenshot file,
but which need
which name right with what name
we need to provide.
And you see any name being provided.
The facebook? No.
We deployed. Right.
And can you predict
the name of the scenario?
With scenario we are going to execute
how many submenus
we are going execute can predict. No.
So if
we cannot predict something like this,
if we cannot predict what scenario
we are going to execute our minister,
we are going to execute
which one is going to be parsed,
which one is going to be fiend,
What is the name of the method?
We cannot see anything
because it completely depends
on the requirement of what execution
our required.
We we would change this, right?
So first first what we will do,
we will provide a global FYI,
we will provide a global file name.
And this we will hand in here
in our method in terms of kingdom.
So now you'll see
in terms of correct firstly
timestamp we will do the mission,
we will do that bundle.
So first thing you see, find nameplate
is correct
or not.
Now now here, now here. What is happening?
If I provide this tiny right,
you might provide this by name,
then what would happen here
after providing the file name, right?
If I'm executing one
just because it will generate the report,
take this feature if I provide second best
because then execute it.
What would happen?
What would enter?
It can override this one.
It will replace.
So will I get the previous one here?
Will I get the previous one? No,
I won't see.
So let's let me show you this here
what I'm seeing.
Let's see my screenshot name is ABC.
After first execution
after second execution again,
ABC report will be generated
so here I executed ten scenarios
and here I execute in five scenarios.
Right.
So tell me which one would be the last.
This one is the latest one.
So we will not be able to get this one.
We will be able to get only
this one right.
It means my this data is gone, right?
So I don't want that kind of setup here.
I want to set up
where I can find this one.
I can find this one. Got it.
Got it.
So what can I do?
I can see this file.
Instead of writing this ABC pilot, X,
Y, or Z byte,
I can save this fine with some parameters.
Those parameters which are unique.
So when it comes to unique, what is unique
design is unique.
Maybe did seem
maybe month the same, maybe even seen,
maybe our same in the same one hour.
We can execute multiple things
because this or not.
Instead we guys
maybe minutes also same guys.
In one minute
we can execute multiple or not.
Maybe state gives also same.
If it is a small execution.
In a small execution,
we can execute a mistake,
but milliseconds would not be seen.
Right.
So you'll see this much of time
we can provide right in the file name.
So if we get exact date,
execute the month, execute it,
execute our commitment sequence
and exit the milliseconds plus destiny.
If we provide a file name like this,
then everything, even
if it is executing up to 1 milliseconds C
one millisecond it takes one millisecond.
It always takes to open the browser,
to close the browser.
And this is the smallest scenario.
So now after every execution
we will get separate payload,
We will get separate by cutting
final.
So to do this, to do this,
do we have any parameter
right now to provide timestamp here?
Do we have any parameter?
No, we don't have, we don't have.
But in Java, in Java
we have a clause going deep
which class we have in Java date.
And this data class
basically returns, returns right.
The current date.
So let me write for the time it's
been writing yet
public static string.
I'm writing because I need something
in return of this method.
So I didn't get time stamps again.
Time stamp? Yes. Fine.
Now tell me guys, first first, let me show
you something and I will ask this.
Is it did
is it was do
you did this
now here,
right here by default, by default,
the better by default.
The python is here.
Great. Our
great state games and.
This is the default format which we get.
Great guys.
Correct.
Hello.
Right now,
maybe it returns something else for me.
I don't want this particular format.
I want something else. Great.
I want something
that is so what I can see.
Okay, In this particular bar,
I will define my own python.
I will define my own python. In which way?
Then I need you to return me that big.
I will define my own return in mass in
any that I want d I want minutes.
I want only milliseconds.
I want only is against whatever
the things.
I will define it on my own.
So now I'm going to write here C Simple
date for me
equals to new simple date for me.
And according to date,
which did better the python
which I will be providing
so it will return me.
Simple is the method for me
and it does this object we think
any question
in this function let me right here
I'm writing it is
for made B
according according
according to r choice.
We have to use this function
which function is d of simple date
for make function.
We have to use this function. Why?
Because Java is returning one particular
date in one particular for form.
I don't want that by another date.
I want my own back
and so I have to rearranged.
I have to form a statement.
And for me, that particular victim,
two things I need first function
through which I will form and second
by which I mean boss in that function.
Right.
So this is the function which I am
using simple date for me to formatted
according to the method.
And this back
then I will provide in my scenario
while providing the
name to my student industrial
and the school
disk is going to see it.
So now see what I'm doing, what I'm doing.
So far
when I provided this final nameplate
file name I can provide, but I might need
maybe to file names.
Can be seen as of now is off
now if I can was simply so let me.
Makes it different.
Even if the file name is seen, the
remaining parameters will be different.
Now let's see through label programing.
See, first
I will provide the space in the name.
Most I will provide is space in the mean
and output is this.
I will provide here this particular
method called big time step.
So it is asking for paper. Yes.
Guys, can you see
it is asking for pregnant.
I am providing the name dates.
I'm planning to provide the name
so it is asking for Baghdad.
Can everyone see it?
So then here I'm going to provide
which button I need.
I need. Let's see. Viva
in name.
You can
find this button on Google exhibit.
You can find this picture on Google is
what do you need?
Because month is in capital
hours is in also capital grade.
It is by default.
But then I'm not doing in
capital name use for months.
If people use but I would say small
D four days is more like one year.
And after this
small in 4 minutes
and the small is positive is
understood. I need 10% gain.
Sorry I don't want this
milliseconds in all is discussed
and that's what I'm saying.
Yes, but it
nasty guys now see
in this folder
but in this folder portrayed
it will save my file getting
this will save my file this file
having the fighting name with file name.
I will provide the reason for that.
You consist of this right?
For example, if my name is
if I name is ABC so it will save
ABC 2021 right.
2133 something like this
file would be like this and one
Why are the month what is kept?
Remember like I said, it is a pre
defined a format reading define it.
We are simply using it from Java eight.
So why we should ask this to the students
of Northeastern University.
Straight
or Sun Microsystems?
Basically?
No, no.
After this, the last thing which
we have to provide is in which for weight.
I want to see my file in this screenshot.
So what is the most common for me?
We have a flood to go
with being right, So fine, let's provide.
Don't be in default.
I need to save this point.
I want not be in default mode
to save this point.
So for any question in this function,
this store, for any question
in this function
and in this lecture did me
is there
anyone who has any question
in this particular function
experience,
please don't take the code
in answer to my question, please.
But it's perfect.
The only thing might line them,
but a bit fine.
So here, here.
I seen this line, right?
Because we need a unique
findings category.
We need unique findings.
Can we use project
name for device or expose?
No, no, no.
I will tell you that we can do that
because we didn't
call this method anywhere.
Okay, So what you need to understand
is why we're providing this timestamp.
Because seen if your tool file names
are similar, it will over your fight.
It will override your flight. Correct.
And it would overwrite you have been
you will know
you will lose your previous report.
So that's
why to make a pretty board unique
we need to provide
this is just a name of your flight.
Okay.
This would be the name of your flight
with your finally actually it
now I understood
almost would
find for example
let's say you are executing your test case
having the name log right
So first time if you create
and if you don't provide timestamp create
and file name by providing right, let's
say whatever the mind is to name is
that would be my Finally
for the screenshot
yet no one because milliseconds
we don't need fade.
Like I said, this is our own vector
so we are providing 10 seconds.
That is fine because we need,
even if there are 2 seconds
plus one, execute it in second one
and second one executing second.
Then obviously these are two things.
Now just consider one scenario.
You have a log in, test,
your scenario name is no name.
You execute your scenario.
Big APM, for example.
So what would be the name of
your scenario in screenshot if you don't
provide good gives stack loaded
because you
calling that and you want to save your way
with the name of the scenario.
So there is nothing it in being again
you executed those teams in any way
so against in would be generated
and this time we
the screenshot
next is what I am seeking
so it runs in seconds
also you see that's why 2 seconds.
So in my project in my project if you see
even if you consider the most fastest
isn't any
how much time it takes to open
the browser is to represent or not
those like. Right.
So if in executing do the forensic games
would be a different name or not,
even if it is in seconds.
So now just consider the situation
without get name.
Instead, what would happen
if you execute using that you would now
give me free and you provided
the fighting name is the scenario name.
So first it executed, then it got it.
Give you the name of
this creature does not indicate B
Now you'll again execute in this scenario
it might be
so this time again it will give you
the screenshot name as logging.
Right. So when do files are on same name?
The latest one
always replace your previous one.
It happens or not.
Great.
So again, I have to either rename it
or it will get replaced.
All right, fine.
I don't want the situation right everyone
to face the situation in my project.
So that's why I came on with.
I will provide some feedback on this
with my final name.
So now, even if my filing is same,
but this topics information
will not be the same.
It will change every name.
And then so I will get all of my points
right again.
Universal function, global function.
No dependency on hard hardcoded
loophole.
The date is coming right from the calendar
so we can do it.
Yes. Correct.
So what panel execution
has to do with this?
Even in the parallel execution,
you know, the concept of Multithreading
when you get tickets online at one time
for watching any movie,
like for example, Spiderman,
if anyone is trying,
everyone is trying to move that they could
implement is a way to access this screen.
But this application is providing
multiple threads
to multiple user one, 3 to 1 user.
For us,
we see it executions, best example rate
rates on providing to all the users
that one day.
But there is a delay even in nanoseconds,
milliseconds microseconds
because like it's correct, there is a
delay in every single trade rate.
So same thing be playing here.
So you should also include work rate.
Fine, fine.
Now what we are going to do see,
eliminate,
think be soon master
this part clear to everyone.
This particular part clear to everyone
then is just
just 5 minutes
the I'm completing this part
and then I will give you
when I'm completing this part just by.
Okay.
So far, so good.
Everyone.
Now, now I missed the part for the byte.
The mirrored
basically the area of by trade computer
always any of it in terms of screenshot.
Okay.
No, it's not required. It's up to you.
It's up to you. It's
why we provided this area of writing.
We are handling area of rate.
That's why we're not putting our name.
Don't buy we are putting out good.
But it's not.
Day is when we did a screenshot.
When we did a screenshot.
No, no we can not we can not use
you saw we got just three options.
Bye bye.
So see you see the 64 link
verify something when we're
not at the end of the disconnect
passing at the end of it.
What it is doesn't matter
whether it is past
or it is spilled or whatever, it is great.
Whatever it is, we need a screenshot
with every single report.
Correct.
But we need to ensure we use digital
domains to highlight the error.
Yes, JavaScript code is something else.
Great moment.
Don't get into that part of the register.
Get confused. Right.
So now we don't need listeners.
Tell me which part
of which part of article, but has that bar
it will always execute after my code
that we always execute
after my code into interview.
But we have the portion already.
Which portion is there?
Yes, yes, we have hooks.
We have hooks in hooks.
Remember precondition, post condition.
So precondition out of school
we don't need as of now,
we need post condition.
So it is my hooks and then of my esters.
You see this method.
I can
you see this method?
I have ratings.
So now here in this method I'm c
before closing the browser,
before closing the browser.
In the end, when my post condition
executes big the screenshot
and recover the screenshot,
that's what I'm seeing already.
Well, read.
No no.
Here, here.
See what I'm seeing.
Let's see.
This is my
the screenshots folder.
I executed five scenario
how many screenshots it will generate.
Hooks will execute many times
for five scenarios. Looks good.
Executed five things.
So how many screenshots we will get here
in the screenshot folder?
It's been short one.
This screenshot to exclude showed three
in short four screenshot from
after execution.
While looking into this folder here,
can you see with scenario
as Boston was to use the
can you select this there?
This is pass.
Does this pass?
Does this feel
this is failing
and this is big.
Can we say this
by looking into this menu for
no from the report?
That's what I'm asking. From here
we can see or more.
No, we can not,
because there is no distribution.
The distro distribution.
Now what we will
see under this situation,
this problem in this one,
what kind of problem behavior?
Everyone understood this part.
So now
that you understood the problem,
let me give you the solution.
We built article.
But to save this screenshot.
To save the screenshot.
How if they are fail,
put it in the fail folder in their Bosque.
Put it in the passport section.
Now if I execute five scenario
my and out of them
three passed and two are failed.
So my document will provide
two scenarios inside this folder
and three scenarios inside us.
For understood
understood
how how we will do it.
Let's see.
Isn't it interesting part
that we are going to do now?
See, guys,
I need your attention for just 5 minutes.
Just 5 minutes. Here.
Here.
We have to use one class from the number.
So maybe.
Maybe this is
sideways. So.
So now here, now here.
What I'm going to do
is I am going to use one particular class
from the computer,
and we call this class as in, you see,
I will talk to Jumbo or Java,
we will call this class is scenario.
So we will use
the object of this to let us
which class we are going to use based.
We are going to use scenario class.
Understood.
The is just just by for the next
really interesting part is going on
grade don't don't focus it
focusing right now I am going to see
all right
my convert is going to return what
the screenshot method is returning, what
based
big any of my trade
any off buying it is returning any of it.
So I'm seeing the object
first for this area of like
understand what is next.
Now I want to capture the screenshot,
find with this scenario method.
So remember this scenario.
Plus I'm going to right here.
Right. I'm going to right here.
This scenario class from from
December because the complete information,
the complete information
of your execution,
what it does, it pulls the complete
information of your execution,
what you have executed,
what is the status of your executed,
what is the name of the scenario
that you're executing?
It would a single thing that would
understood.
So now now what I'm going to write to see,
I am seeing see how distribution is done.
If if I'm using this object.
My scenario is feed.
If my scenario is three,
then what you have to do
in the area of byte,
if this object creates this big object
for the area of byte
I'm seeing in this object, call my method.
Take a screenshot point,
call my method, take a screenshot.
Now what is not filing?
It's providing my findings.
So I'm seeing a scenario
not get me scenario.
Don't get him would be my file.
Can you see? Okay.
Because I told you my scenario is holding
all the information, all the information
straight of my execution.
So now I'm providing scenario not get name
else and see else I'm seeing.
Save the screenshot
for big screenshot again.
Big scenario.
Don't get
No, wait, wait.
With the weather.
My scenario is
if my scenario is free, right?
If my scenario is filled,
it is going to take the screenshot,
find it otherwise
also it will going to take the screenshot.
So what the situations are saying,
can you see
if it is forced
taking the screenshot, taking the name
if it is taking the screenshot, taking the
screenshot of response, taking the name.
There is no distribution for feeling mask
still
because we are just checking the status
here.
If it is feel is going to seem like this.
If it is forced
screenshot saved like this.
We are
very to see
this screenshot of failing bus.
So one more thing we have to do is here
I'm going to write
create one folder called
Goal feed.
Right
only for those where my screenshot is big
and create one more folder here.
Say run for it here, go
paused right or buzzed so dag nasty nasty.
If my scenario is feed
it will take the screenshot
seaweed under the feed folder under
screenshot folder with my scenario name.
Right.
And here also
it will see under my scenario understood
and desperate.
Everyone.
So it will exist in India. Great.
Now see,
now see, one thing is done.
One thing done.
In my scenario
selected is screenshots will be captured
under is screenshots folder.
Right.
And then the screenshots folder.
But do we need food for them?
Why don't we need food for the utility?
Why don't we need this?
We are discussing the point.
Yes, we have to.
We have to.
We have to add this build and fast folder
we automatically
we generated because we are putting them
in this script.
Right.
So this folders will be generated.
Correct.
My take a screenshot whether we generate
the folder based on the
what we have provided in the common matrix
and they take screenshot function.
That function we have called here.
So it will create itself right? Yes.
Yes. Got it.
Got it.
So now see here with this method,
what I am seeing, this is storing mind.
This is storing and capturing
my screenshot and the screenshot spoiler.
But I don't want this.
These screenshots
only in domestic interest folder.
I want this.
The screenshots
will be attached with my report.
I want these screenshots
to be based with my report.
All right.
So next time I execute my scenario,
I want to see this
screenshot week
based in my reporting system.
All right.
So to do this just one command
I need to add.
This scenario will do everything.
So now you don't bug batch.
Can you see?
Can you see it is asking post by default.
It is asking any of my Do not tell me guys
Eddie of Berkeley do the asking.
So I am writing area of byte I have big
I have big.
This big is the object
that I've created for Eddie Obeid.
So it can be by asking for maybe a date.
So what would be the media of this image?
So I will provide image
sort of image, which image being image
feed.
And then the third thing
it is asking is string name.
So here the name of the string
that I would be provided release theme
name named
Keep it simple, Let's keep it simple.
Only the name of the video industry.
So what it will do it
will it will attach the pics
in the food
and putting these commands also so
that you can understand what we are doing,
so that you can understand
what we are doing.
Is this part to everyone?
Is this part clear to one
easy, just four lines, be easy and
now let me do one thing
to execute one very common scenario.
Take this batch 11 one plate.
It would take this bent elements in edu.
So I'm going to put it in my
things
and I'm
going to execute this scenario from mine.
But I'm not extremely fine guys from my
which any
bom not exemplify point.
No. See, I am going to execute this menu
from here from my to make fine.
So test
build success based
will success is just
can you see here
can you see here under the screenshots
folder generated called parsed can you see
folder generated parsed
and this and here
you'll see this is my scenario
name really and mini log in.
Great this is there for me
the burden which we passed I see
this is the format between must not be in
g now just match this
with this particular part see
is screenshot file
but the provided file name.
So finally we provided a scenario
don't get me
great scenario,
don't me scenario name. See?
But it
is based you see here this, this
and then here.
So here you see is month.
So you see January day 23 hours 22
See here 2226 minutes 25
just one minute ago and seconds
continue forward.
Don't be
eight days.
The same format what we provided
my code is working according to that.
Correct.
Is this correct?
Everyone, now,
now let's open this open report.
It's open adequate. How?
We open the report right
click open in any browser.
Open in any browser.
Can you see this report right.
Can you see this report?
We want
open it
going to looks can you see
now this time of hooks execute trade
this hooks it says that is an attachment.
Now click on it is this this screen
where I completed my execution.
Is this the script for the last display
when my execution stops?
This is right.
Correct.
Correct. See,
I got all the details straight.
I got all the details. Wait,
how many steps fast?
It it'sit's everything.
And here also
it is attaching my screenshot visible.
See this?
Is this part clear to everyone?
Right? Exactly.
Damian remembers idle.
So for any question in this part,
but they're taking them on.
For example, I didn't provide anything.
They mean bombarding similitude.
Where have you seen this that I provided
big name in
which take moment
which you are not involved
match 11.
No it's not going to take some insert
expander your small cricket
it is more enough
under small
point.
Let me come in this code
so for any question in this part strings
there
is any question so far
no question here
except
now you in a big it's
been almost 2 hours already 2 hours
code is
can we take to the repository right.
Let's take a break. This
at the middle Like I said the
like I said,
it does only any overbite.
That is the only thing that's big.
But yeah, you can read it and
then you will deprecate very easy part.
This remaining all the steps
are symptoms of selenium bar.
I totally understand.
Another important topic guys.
After the break we will discuss.
Let's see.
Sebastian is already got the screenshot.
Is this part working for everyone of
my screen?
So guys, let's take a break.
Let's take a break for 15 minutes.
And after 15 minutes we connect again.
Okay.
One store next.
So far, so good.
Everyone.
Nice,
nice place.
I produced it as everyone gets
so we can proceed for the please
of big screen quickly.
But fine.
So now.
Now ready to not do more things.
Very interesting thing.
I did not get that feature.
It would
Sir Richard McWhirter talking about
which feature
This one.
This one?
You mean
So I can clearly see, right?
I can clearly see it's already of liberty.
It was just you expanding this way.
The view is going.
It just you expand there just to,
you know, hold it
and then you will get that to put
or maybe execute it one more time
and then you will get the connectivity.
Look, in this part,
when you're talking about this
particular part, right,
You from here.
From here,
if you see you have to click on this,
it will get highlighted
and then can open this part or
right
now, do we have reviewed the model?
Yes, ma'am, we do have we do have
your welcome, sir.
All right.
So now see, guys, Aisha.
Yes, I will tell you that also,
I read in their notes
we don't have to do it
explicitly will have in function for them
one commander, we do everything okay.
Nice, nice, nice, nice.
Let's come here.
Just let me execute.
Let me execute this log in so you can
you see everyone?
Everyone. You see this log incident?
Sometimes what happens,
Sometimes what happens?
Basically,
if you execute hundreds in that you do
scenario,
maybe for this and then you wait,
you execute this mercenary.
Also, there's a out of hundred scenarios
in Evil boss and 20 will see
it happens.
Many names take these.
Remember the example
of parallel execution?
It happens multiple times, right?
When you execute scenarios,
some of them passed, some of them feel
they please, please join me. Now.
We have already done writing the code,
copying the code.
Everything now
makes it more than two conversation.
It's important discussion.
Now what happens is basically
if this premise scenarios
are failing,
these two scenarios are free raid.
So it's not necessary that these are
these scenarios are failed
because of issue in this script.
Because if you execute them one by one,
then this
you pass, right?
So maybe due to some unforeseen
circumstances such as application
not loaded doom was not available
station not created Selenium time out
because of some x, y, z issue,
because of these exceptions and issue.
Sometimes here disk is good big,
but sometimes you just get speed.
So now what we are doing as of now,
if my if I executing my request,
guess in the batch execution
I hope everyone knows
what is better execution
they expect already at the time of destiny
there
batch
execution.
Fine, fine.
So now, now, now see
what are doing
If we are executing raid by a batch.
So if hundreds
and that is I'm executing 23.
So again
I'm executing 100 scenarios to test.
That's what we are doing so far,
but that's what we are doing.
Correct.
Now, Now I do not want to do this.
I want if I'm executing hundred scenarios,
if 80 bars
and 20 fail,
I want my convert to execute
only destroying these scenarios again,
because
if my ID are already paused,
why should I execute?
Do it again?
I just want to execute this
20 scenarios fake.
So what make me do passes
make dumas's point fine.
What I will do
I will execute your scenarios.
If you're a designer, use paused.
I'm not bothering
that I'm more bothered about this 20
so I will give you the name of this
20 fields in areas,
name of this 24 scenarios
and then you can execute
only these 20 scenarios which are already
available in just one peak
in just one thing.
And just so we can rerun
only three scenarios.
First execution all the scenarios,
then return one more execution
only for privacy settings,
that kind of sector we need in our.
Now tell me, isn't it very effective that
if I'm executing 100 of these scenarios
out of them, 100 past four people, So
next time I don't need to execute those.
I just execute remaining to be
and then they will also be passed
and it is still the issue exist.
Then maybe we can go
and check our script, right?
So right away
on the script and changing it
and then it's not a good solution for us.
Give this scenario
speaking to one or two prior
and then come off with your script.
At this point.
So what it does to the overview,
the situation, the condition
which we are going to implement now,
everyone, let's
go ahead and do it and implement
this part.
To implement this part first,
what I'm going to do is
I am going to open my small guest.
If I'm going to open my smoke, relentless.
And here in this plugin,
in this plugin, I'm
going add under the blanket
and that plugin name is Reason.
What is the name of this plugin these
days?
Reading and in zero plugin issued
under target folder.
Under target folder create one
the XD file with the name feed.
So now what would happen?
What would happen here is C
this thing disappeared
or b XD by holds
all the scenarios, all the scenarios
which are which are feed
during execution plus two
industrial days.
And now.
Now when it comes to execute
only those scenarios
which are field during the execution,
what we have to do
we need this the file but
read this but we need fine
so when we need this
but how we can get it to see I'm
going to create
another another class go
read.
What I'm going to create
is an additional class going
children of right
and in this field, in this
take you let me create
this in the class now see
in this field and then what I need
let me copy this part
from here to read complete but from here
and I will pasted here.
Now tell me this
Do we need this dry rectangular
to check whether my steps implemented
or not?
Do we need this bag?
Also,
are we going to execute based on base?
No, we don't.
Do we need this written like any of
the we need this plugin?
No, because the employee is
generally used to generate the field,
not the XD and they should not be
well executed from here.
So when we're executing already
for the scenario.
So this time why do we need we don't need
the do we need this reports
guys, this reports
but we need this import once again we
know because
reports we are already generating from our
or not render classmate
a smaller regression analysis like
Eric.
Let's do it.
Let's do it. It's pretty.
We are keeping it because this pretty well
print all the execution steps in action
so we'll keeping now tell me,
is this the right but is this the right
path to get my finger to see
is this the correct one.
No. Right. So what is the right but
where where my the extreme
will be generated under
under target aid.
So to write target the folder
we have to provide but like this
not to get in under target under target.
What is the name of my clinic?
That's field.
Don't be
adherent or the normal field don't be.
This is the finding we have seen
here.
This is done by newbie applied.
Can you see?
Can you see that we want.
So now let me do one thing.
Let me execute
batch 11 mistake here also
and let me end this big here also.
So so now in burst
well it is this username
and password
intentionally.
I'm going to feed this one scenario.
I'm going to make three out of 384.
Let me just execute two scenario.
Otherwise it would take more time.
So these two scenarios,
these two I'm going to execute
and in this scenario intentionally,
I'm going to pass one
and I'm going to fill the second one
just to
right now.
Let me first change this batch.
1.11 is right.
And here.
Here. See what I'm going to do now?
I'm going to execute my bomberg exemplify.
So based double click on test,
double click on test to execute this one
for scenario, execute
not it is executing the second one
will feel played
beautifully.
No issues,
Nancy.
According to the setup
which I've made grade.
According to that setup,
I should be able to see their test case
name, which is field under me
and then
and then Target.
Can you see in the target
it generates one point call field
or the
can everyone see this point?
Now let's double click and open this blank
Can you see it
says FYI is is not to see test results
this features log in don't feature line
number seven do not see
log entered feature line
number seven being
it means this in any any valid
is this log in this one failed or more
this one thing point
No Now tell me
how many scenarios of have executed
two How many of you got here?
One late only failed when we got eight.
So next time, what do we do?
Let's go into the scenario
check already and find this.
And that is failing.
My vote is waiting.
Oh, there is an issue with the code.
I notice I'm going to change this part
with an I need to fix it.
And now.
Now I don't need to execute
the past scenario.
I will execute only the fields
in any right
to execute the field scenario.
Here.
What I will do,
I'm simply executing it from here on
right Click Return
just to show you.
So this time
how many scenario will get executed
just once in a grade C
spaced, just one scenario got executed.
Understood.
So this particular fight
now see can you see it is creating the do
folder
based on field also because
my one scenario of liquidity is this in
it gave me the name of the scenario
with the paper.
Also for the screenshots
you can see this things, right?
So my screenshots are also working
according to my condition,
the condition which I passed by
students, what can you see it
in here?
Here.
This part is also working fine.
What happens to the text file
after the world's biggest file?
It generates read.
It generates their data
for all the failure text case
and we provide this file.
But we provided this file
support from field or the field runner.
So next time, whatever their best guesses,
we get this best guesses
details inside this field running via
ready to not be fight.
So now you can run from momentum.
Your report.
Yes we can run from memory as well.
We need to change
this from the field on the
moment you can read that.
But also right you can go I had this
but also just wanted to show you.
That's why I execute from your point
nine guys.
Everyone, they
know.
Now let's do something interesting
first in case.
Tell me,
how many of you guys in the Startup
Moment Project?
Everyone got it right. Everyone got it.
Getting
now. Everyone.
So home environment right?
Okay, so they we're in that video.
In that video you can see now see
just open your terminal or command prompt.
Open your terminal
or command prompt and raid
when command called in the end
and be in space.
Watch it
when you running ambient space
hyphen virgin right
right.
So see when I when this come ambient space
hyphen virgin
it gives me the detail of my moment.
Can you see a bottom event?
3.8.3 which is installed in my machine.
Can you see this everyone.
Right,
right now.
See what I'm doing?
What is my project available?
It's in my machine. In my machine?
What is my project available to me?
And you see these?
See you obviously intelligible,
intelligent.
I'm using my project.
Getting my project is available.
And let's see users
Suhail Idea Projects BET 11.
H&M is vegetarian, Correct?
This is my project.
Good to always do is to into this part.
First click here.
Right click here
open in terminal right.
So you will get the part
or that party will get it.
This is the part.
So just copy this part reference from you.
Maybe this particular part, or
you can simply find this part
in your folder.
So you'll see this is the match element.
H&M is match element.
Can you see this folder for me
guys in my machine, each item is batch 11
and inside this is inside this.
I have all the files.
Can you see all the files
related to my project I have?
Everything is database.
Everyone
now know what we have to do is there.
My bonded assembly is available
where might This bonded
exhibit is available
inside this particular part.
I have to open my command
prompt from here.
What I have to.
I have to open my command prompt here.
So see,
it says open is windows done within point.
Click, click.
Can you see I'm under see users
Suhail idea
projects batch 11
which are in this batch deliver
can you see
it means I'm under
my project grid connect directly
one more way easy be easy be
you open your command from
Let's see you are in this one right now
right?
I have to go under my idea project.
So see the idea project?
So I am under my idea projects
Then see this
based, right?
I'm under my image element.
Great.
Then see the space.
Italian is my living.
So I am. And there might be H&M
especially.
Can you see this case?
So can we see the transport
change category then go inside
till the time you go to your project name
H&M as mentioned.
Even so, here
now I see all the fancy one get
not idea screenshots, no respond or text
can you see similar?
So I got it.
So now I got my one excellent fight.
I got this.
But always I showed
how to come to your project group.
Part of me simply click here.
I see me
pressing the You are already in the month.
Do you want me to show the Third world?
So once again, guys,
so do we see?
Click here, click here.
I see. Be
man I showed three.
These are all three fast.
It is just playing with the terminal.
I'm just playing with the terminal.
Playing
against this one.
See, again, I'm showing
this is your folder part right click here.
I see and the interesting to
you are in your particular CMT command
terminal part.
Yes correct. Correct.
Third place the best yet because
this is the shortest one the shortcut.
No, no.
Here first for see,
I'm not going to execute anything
from my intelligent line
because I can execute my bombarding
symbol flight from my command prompt
if it is available here,
if my method is available in my machine
and I am in the correct folder repository,
if I'm in the correct project group
with my ribbon so I can execute everything
from my command prompt,
I can execute everything so
my command prompt understood this point.
Remember I told you forced
execute everything from feature point.
Then you will execute
everything from remote
plus then you will execute everything from
textbook fine and.
Now without even in intelligible,
we will execute everything
correct?
Correct. Yeah. Correct.
So now see what I'm going
to write the first.
First, let me tell you how we can execute
simply right in the end
in the space clean.
Why we use clean the base to remove
and to delete target
for the right to clean up project.
If we get big sexist message here.
If we get sexist message here,
what do we do?
We simply executing.
If we get this message,
then we will execute our actual code.
All right. Alright
guys,
please
reply by you guys are always really busy.
Maybe can I ask your business?
This business is ask ask.
No, you don't need.
You don't
come.
So now, now
with this in being clean
with this inventory.
Right,
we are going to clean our target folder
cutting
inventory.
So now I am going to run this command.
And what I'm expecting that message,
I expect.
Right.
I should expect right to the bomb, right
symbol, same message, success.
Right.
So executing.
Can you see anything?
I got big success message here.
Great
boom success message.
We are cutting
inventory now now I'm to perform mine.
Second is what is this like this guy still
in this great
feature
feature?
We have to.
No, no, I'm doing this for you
because I want a genius.
We are going to execute great.
We are going to execute our exhibit
quite right in this command.
We used to execute bombed or similarly
in that complex you will find we provided
the bottom smoke in smoke.
We provided a couple of tapes,
customize missions,
we provided feature point,
but there's so many other things, right?
So the we are bombed
or ExxonMobil was executing
big failure to see the full strength
project to in-situ.
There is no bombing there.
That is the remnants.
What I am seeing again and again,
you have to be in the right repository.
You are executing it.
Another user is not in the project,
so radio project is available
right where your bomb external file
is available.
Open your terminal on that point
and then will execute.
Otherwise your operating symbol
is not available there.
How will pulling the courier
project? Right.
I showed this earlier as well.
No, that's fine. Let's wait. Fine.
We it's totally
all right.
So now, now, next thing,
what I'm going to do the moment
I have run this command in being clean
and being based
the way it was executing my small grammar
using exhibit
in the same way
it will execute even without intelligence.
So let me be in print
what an invalid now needs to be
compiling.
So it would be great for me, I think.
Very good resource.
So need to see the
maybe it is a double Olympic minus again.
Explain this point. Let me quickly fix it.
I can fix signatures.
Your works videos. Yeah, that's fine.
Despite being
not Nazi
Nazis. As if I'm doing it.
See, I'm doing it from my.
From mine.
Come on, from
now. See, it is working fine.
It is working fine.
Correct.
This is this like scenario
which I am executing.
Correct.
Getting
correct Nazi mine to test fast
even without touching my intelligence.
I got the result.
My two best
first grade don't test run to failure.
Zero errors zero zero.
Correct.
Is this correct?
Grade
some output
that is in console rate putting in console
in your command company auditing,
getting every single information.
Every single information in this command
appropriate.
Good. Correct. Correct. No.
We're directly dealing
with the data management tool, right.
Directly
dealing with the written management,
which
already correct
already industrial.
We should test we want to run from
city of the I'm coming to that point.
You get that for us to learn
what I'm teaching.
Right.
And then coming to the point
which I will teach later
is that any so far which I lived,
I didn't
leave any single point
covering one by one.
But the problem is
I am only one guy so I can cover 1.1.
But after some time
I will take another topic.
Okay,
so now, now here from that's
how developers work.
They never execute, right?
They do not execute from intended
or from a glimpse because the project
is available in some repository
somewhere right there
to the updated project in their folder.
They simply open the command prompt
in this input on this command
and it's working point there.
So they work in the studio
indisputably on how they work.
Is. Yeah, please knock, please.
Plus a
knock.
There's one time.
See, I will cover this point.
I will cover this point week.
I just explained this is one time.
Don't expect everything.
Can you repeat that one? Yes.
So how?
If we do not want to execute our best
guess from intelligent from anywhere?
What do you have this project?
Do you have any your good right?
What do you do?
Just take the updated code
from the gate in your machine.
Once you have this code in your machine,
open the folder.
You have vulgar ExxonMobil
in your local computer time command prompt
or open that particular folder
in your terminal or in command prompt.
Very apologetic symbolism
and then simply run this command.
Now you need an intelligent eclipse.
You don't need it. Got it.
You don't need it.
You don't
quite So now
coming to the last point, coming
to the last point of this particular path.
Right.
Got it.
Coming to the last line
of this particular work. See
if I want to run,
if I want to run both these things
together in being clean and being busy
right now, what we are doing,
we are cleaning
first in the existing best.
Now we are doing and being clean and test
both together.
Press enough,
see first it cleaned everything.
It deleted their target folder,
then it is started the execution.
When it started the execution, it executes
all of my best case
once and executing all of my best guess.
See, Aisha
is there answer to your question?
Do we need to execute clean
always before test?
So the answer is no one
command will work for both cleaning best
understood everyone
there is everyone understood
this.
Nice. Now last one.
Last one.
What if.
What if I am on to override my bag?
I don't want to execute
only smokes in animals.
I don't want to execute only integrations.
Usually I want to execute
scenarios based on their dates
I would be providing here on me.
Right here only.
So what is the resolution to that point?
How we can do that
and as to what I'm seeing.
So now.
Sorry, can you show the last command?
It's Ambient cleaning based together.
Ambient cleaning this together. Right.
So the one
what do you want to see them
the last command executed in
we end up next.
We already discussed this in being clean.
So your target folder,
if you guys
want to see which command
you executed last.
So simply simply place this over
the upper end, over.
See, I typed in your keyboard.
It gives me the command
which I executed last.
Before that I executed.
And we invest one more time.
If I click this upper, it'll
give me that command.
This would be my last third, last third.
So last again.
Last command.
Can you see this?
Right.
So now it's time.
It's time to override.
Let me go here.
And this time. Right.
Let's change this to change changes
to ambient.
Let's change is to me in back right now
see in my smoke which they use available
even if we ran
it from terminal would still go
Yes yes it will still be report
because to me
we are executing our protection and import
exam will be I to plug it in so intimately
it is creating report everything
paid rate.
So now
now guys, what I'm going to do here I'm
going to I'm going to
what am I to my big brain?
How to do that?
See here I will write ambient
test my normal command
and weirdest is my normal
command of delete.
That is
going after this.
I have to date minus B minus
B, then I have to write
here it go letter dot options
minus D into my dot options
without space minus d
to compare dog options is equals to
is equals to double
and the will cause minus minus
six, minus minus x.
And you see guys
minus maintenance bags
at the rate mean
whatever I think very ambient.
You see everyone this
so this time doesn't matter.
This time doesn't matter which particular
bag you have provided in your book.
Smoker enough right.
This Vonnegut exhibit
will take you to smoke or not,
but will replace this bag
from your ambient big so only scenario
which is I mean in being dead
will get executed afterwards.
That's this point everyone
wants to be one industrial designer.
What?
No, we don't need to change anywhere.
We don't need to change anything any bit.
Everything will be going from here.
No, see, no.
Didn't take it.
Didn't think there would be something
wrong happen
to a john and badge eliminate about target
port number
is this take a smoking bench 11 blade
so they take a look right
Let me change this
Let me change this command to
minus D to convert
or are free to talk.
X is equals two
is equals to this time.
And that in
you it won't see.
So now know which command
we have to use gate
See my ambient best is my normal command
rate.
Ambient best is my normal
command minus d controller dot filter
dot bags is equals to
and the rate in which did I want the bus.
So now
now if you see here it executed
it executed my wish take a direct ambient
is this the scenario be executed
so there is no match 11 now
can you see
and you see how we override
how we override this part C
B ambient best minus D could convert
not free dog because the ambient let me
put this command.
If we put this command in
in No you're not.
So it is the most
to execute from
from CMB or
in place.
One command
post is another command in being clean.
Is this under the command in its mind
as de
da to
don't fix is equals to iterate
whatever you want to provide
from the override already base
it a couple of more points
open, open the CMB or terminal,
open this DMV or
terminal in the project Root
beer on dark.
Examine is available
and then execute
it. Your commands
and just put this part
and dispute this part.
Let me take another one.
Let's take any scenario, for example here.
Go in in school here and take any of those
in any of
maybe from this book.
So let's finish facility grade point,
go here and instead of ambient
I want to execute dashboard,
let's execute.
See it executed one scenario
and which one it executed.
Number 33.
x is equal to the rate
in the fish board.
Wait, wait.
I want to show you the remote.
That's why
this should be visible correctly.
It opened the scenario
and it got executed now.
So see
here it executed for data main beam,
live time
recruitment performance dashboard
that both things in the message
all values or tables are equal in best
guess his past which best kids exist.
This board
ought to be overriding their next or not.
Nice Tell me here
are we overriding their tanks or not?
So if you want to execute your smoke,
just simply say no.
Come on, it will execute.
If you want to execute the ignition one,
come on,
it will execute the student.
They want the new member
to execute their test.
Because this idea that advantages
of not so many things
to compile your code to make your code
rate is a single boot.
Yeah I already coming to this command
right in your
in your code
but still see this is the command
ambient best minus
the jumper not filtered
or x is equal to the rig.
Whatever you want to pass on replace.
All right, guys.
So now now practically for code
writing part
minuses will probably I did typing wrong
correct.
Correct. Probably.
You're typing something wrong this way.
So now we are done with that.
The chamber framework portion.
We are done with the input crucial rate.
All the coding related part,
big part conceptual part.
Everything is done.
Just one thing is remaining there.
The explanation code moment that I will do
after the break or after the break
with see what member means.
Let's take a break guys, for 15 minutes
of the minutes before
10 minutes admin instead of a beep
note the text.
It's completely
code is committed pushed.
Right.
All right.
I see you attempting to escalate.
11 2332 2347 We meet once again
15 minute.
All right, base final
alright can you Napier ambient clean
can it be here
intended need I just want to check
what is the output really successful
for you
looking by now.
If it is really success with ambient bleed
it means the problem is with a big test.
See it says will success rate
now it is working fine now blink ambient
test simple in being pissed right
and we entered
late in ambient test sick and
I give you one by moment.
I didn't give you the complete
information of ambient test.
Minor could convert or not
baked in the plus short and we are just
then ambient clean ambient
clean this together
and then overwriting that take me do it
step by step so that you can check
whether your code is working
correctly or not.
Well, read
my source for Max.
Everyone is here now.
Right? So now this is the problem
with your another class.
I could totally see this in the error.
The problem is with yet
another class. And what class
this time problem is with your class.
Put it in the support.
They will help you Shiva, if your there
in the sample, please help on one read.
She is having some really basic
problem. Right?
These are committed
by good okay students.
So now. Now here
here.
See I'm looking about
Melbourne.
No segment
if you see
clean validate compile
this package ready by install side deploy.
Can you see all this like sake?
Can anyone see this
right now?
What is the meaning?
What is the meaning of this lifecycle?
Why we use let me tell you, higher grade
here,
here, here.
When we talk about clean grade,
when we talk about clean.
So the moment you run in being clean,
what it does
it briefly, it performs
three actions be clean,
clean,
forced, simple.
This clean.
If we talk about in the clean action,
it removes
and cleans my mine.
But a good friend of mine I did it for
industrial.
It bleeds my body food industry everyone.
Now this is the $7 billion
7 billion after clean.
What did this see after clean
what it does.
So here we have complied
we have test
we package
we have installed
we have deployed.
We have really by
grade we have been
put in a stored and there is some movement
the repository site available
break this part. Now
when you actually test
when you actually run the command call,
when you actually run a command record
and read a test.
So what it does,
what this command is first,
first
it combined your code, it can verify its
if if there
is something which we need to install.
Let's say you read a dependency rate
but operating the dependency
you reload your project.
So installation is yet to be done
if you run in your test.
So clean install those jobs
dependencies as well and then it converts
your entire project into a package
so that it can make a single build.
And after that
it will execute your test case.
So before execution
it combines your code capability,
but it's within your code is not
build, build your part installed.
If there is any dependency
or job widespread that needs to be added
and then convert your package
into convert your code project
into a package form
and then simply execute via test.
Come on.
I'm not talking about deploy
because this deployed it's
not that deploy the deployment.
It is something as diplomacy elements
relating to the server
to execute for execution
or discord.
Everyone
everyone understood
will lifecycle.
If we make it very clear
that we used
cannot be put there.
So it would be your
compiler test
package
for installing
deploy.
We deployed
clean.
So here
I served three actions three clean, clean
and paused clean.
And this is available.
You signed there.
So that's how
things work.
This is Europe.
This is your Melbourne.
This is your Melbourne Lifecycle.
Remember life cycle.
Everyone, everyone,
guys, come on.
Any questions?
Look, in this park,
what is movement lifecycle,
how we generally use it?
Is there anyone who has
any question about this park
currently
not correct, but that's what
we generally do rate many of the year.
It is doing everything on it,
so we don't need group
rate.
This is all the visitors information,
all the business of measurement.
That's why we use measurement
as a mood management tool to compare.
But with both
basics and framework
is done.
Correct? Correct. Right.
See, this is a part of lifecycle inventory
validate compile Best buy.
Get ready by installing deploy site.
Everything is a part of lifecycle trade
correctness.
Can you see this on my screen?
Come on students display
start typing days.
I'm going to commit the code in that.
Importantly.
Nice nice.
Fine. Fine.
So finally we are done with command.
So prior to 2 minutes, how is the journey?
How is the journey so far?
This is something you have to do
for the entire thing,
not just the last part, but Angelica.
I hope
that is no concentrate with and as food,
there is no concept we should get it.
You got every single concept.
What did we.
I'm talking.
I'm asking from understanding
perspective, explanation, perspective.
Was that anything?
Was there anything from my side
that you made a mistake?
Is there anything or is there any concept
that you guys didn't understand?
It was like a monster for you.
Concepts are clear.
It's great.
Seen for that right before that
once you are done with the course.
I read that you remember all of this
was totally in the stomach.
No, not one important point as I see many.
You got exhausted because of
not of information recovered to date.
Great greatness.
Students, come on.
Just a couple of more minutes with me
and then you will be to play.
I know you guys are exhausted because
we have learned a lot of information.
So now I'm going to give you some ease
rate and we do give you
some is what we are going to do today.
I was supposed to cover one more topic
related to testing, right?
So this is we can create a project
level project with best integration
work, best engineering related.
It's a because we've seen 90% see,
but because by looking at
your responses here and the
energy level rate for everyone,
I decided to postpone this
big group the models class.
So in tomorrow's review,
it's a must attend review for all of you
because in the first portion
of that particular review,
we will create this energy
based framework, right?
Based on the best framework
in just one hour.
What it will take, hardly
one hour will make just one or two test
is not more than just one or two gives us
have to be true during the review class.
Yeah, very important but important piece
because it doesn't make any sense
if I beat you right.
Not as the new framework also.
And you guys get confusion,
both of them. Right?
I totally understand that you guys need
practice that
already today.
So now
Yammer,
you might want to hear the standard
but then you this topic, right?
This topic is you can watch right?
You can watch this topic.
And in the recordings, basically it won't
take more than an hour for me to explain.
So I will do that.
And you guys would be comfortable
for that.
I know I'm pretty sure that
because the hardest part, the hardest part
you guys are going through already,
you guys are done
and you guys did really well
In the hardest part.
That was the framework.
If you understood the framework,
if you can, the framework, right.
If you understand this,
if you can explain this,
that the intention, the
of attending the asset class is achieved,
it's achievable.
If you can explain this framework part
according to the expectations,
if you can do it,
definitely everything is done.
Quick question.
I don't know if you're already answered
this, that that's what I'm saying.
We are going to create one thing
working out tomorrow.
Do you in the top that would be best
and you work with whomever
the correct.
I will.
I would be too late
already.
One more class with all of you and
then you guys will be free from mistake.
Okay, I think I'm done from my sailboat
race class.
If you guys have any question, please ask.