All right.
I guess I guess we have enough people
right now to get started.
And it's already 705.
Okay.
Hi, everyone.
My name is Allie.
So this is your first selenium class.
And welcome to the Selenium class.
This is where all the fun starts.
Okay?
And I'm going to be with you guys
for the whole
Selenium process class,
and we'll see how it goes.
Okay,
So I hope you guys are doing great in Java
because we are going to be integrating
Java with Selenium
and I hope everyone is
got the JAR files for selenium,
import it and create a new project already
inside there.
Intelligent.
I think that was the
prerequisite before this class.
Right.
Is there anyone who is having problems
with with installing
and setting up selenium
in your
intelligent guys?
No issues. Okay.
So it should be pretty simple, right?
If you if you are having issues,
please post it in syntax support.
We should be able to
to take a look at it and
and take a look at the videos in YouTube.
They should be really straightforward
and easy.
Everything goes step by step
and it's not that difficult to set it up.
Okay. All right.
So how the class are going to go?
So I'm going to go over
the theoretical part first.
Okay.
That's the boring part
where, um, not everybody.
Like,
so I'm going to go
over the theoretical part and then what
we're going to do, we're going to go over
the implementation,
we're going to dive into coding
and we're going to see what we can do
with Selenium, right?
So I promise you guys,
Selenium is more fun than Java.
So it's not
that it's not always seeing some
some output in console,
but what we're going to be doing
will be interacting with the browsers
and we will be writing a lot of
logic and building a lot of logic
to interact
with browsers and performing
a lot of actions in the browser.
Okay. All right.
So before we get started,
any questions, guys?
Like not So please,
please try to be active
in the chat glasses since I don't see you,
I don't see what's going on.
I don't even know what's going on
if you don't answer in the live chat.
Okay, so I'll be asking a lot of questions
who will be interacting with each other?
Okay, so please, please
pay attention
and try to answer and life questions
whenever there is a question
so that I know what is going on.
Okay.
All right, cool.
Okay. So
before we get started,
so let me actually create
one folder in here
so that we can keep our notes in here.
I've just created here,
so I'm going to put it as notes, right.
So I'll have notes in here so that
so that you
guys, I'll type in some notes for you.
Okay.
During the class guys
so that it's easier for you to recap
what we've done through the classes.
And I'm going to be pointing out
all the important stuff in here.
Okay.
So we're just seeing a little background.
So other instructors, they don't do this.
They put some background in there.
Okay.
Yeah. If you want to use Eclipse.
Yeah,
that's fine. It's not a big deal. Okay.
But we will be doing the same thing
anyway.
So as long as your selenium is working
and you have Java installed,
that's fine.
All right, so
let's put it here
and let's do
this.
I forgot how it was the other one.
Okay.
So the notes.
The notes are the notes
and code is going to be in GitHub, right?
The slides are going to be in canvas.
Okay, guys.
So that's why I'm
putting everything all the notes in here
inside the project that we're doing.
And then whenever I push the code, you
could just pull it to you, to your stuff.
Okay, I'll push the code
at the end of the of the class.
Okay.
Do I suggest to write everything with me
at the same time
if you can? Yes.
But sometimes I will really need you
to listen, but not to type.
Okay,
so this is the once we just starting.
It's easy stuff, but when we go forward,
we will be having some different,
different topics.
And that's we're going
to have some challenges in there
that I need to explain to you.
So it would be great to listen to me first
and then type the code in.
Okay,
But anyways, you're going to have the code
and at the end of the day
or after the class
so that you can pull it to yourself.
Okay, well, what are doing from scratch?
Okay, class 27 is for Java.
Okay, so this one is going to be class
first for selenium.
Okay, so you guys are going to be doing
two different things right now
at the same time.
But there is a little bit left
for you to finish Java, I guess.
I'm not sure where you are yet,
but I think you have a couple of classes
left, like, if I'm not mistaken, three
or four classes left for Java.
Okay, so we don't.
Yeah, six, 6 to 7 classes.
There you go. Yeah.
So we will be doing it simultaneously.
So we're adding more fun.
As I said, not just Java.
What's one? Okay.
I don't know
if everybody heard me in the beginning.
My name is Ali, guys.
Okay,
so I will be your instructor facility.
Okay.
Any other questions before
we get started, guys?
Separate pool.
Okay. Yes.
Drivers are going to be located
only in the folder.
Yes. For this project.
That is correct.
The project you guys created right.
Should you put drivers in other projects?
Yes. Will will be coming to those points.
Okay, guys.
So let's just go step by step.
Okay.
So we have drivers in in our project.
We have selenium libraries,
right in our project.
So let's finish the Selenium project
and then we will see how everything goes,
how we can manage all the drivers
and everything once we start
going into building the framework.
Okay, step by step, guys. One by one.
Okay.
All right.
Any other questions?
Okay, cool.
All right, so let's get started.
Right? As I said, boring time,
Boring time, theoretical time.
So from theoretical part, guys,
I like to interact with you guys
so that I can see how you guys think
and what you guys think about this topic.
Okay,
so since it's our first selenium class,
let's go ahead and get started
with this simple question.
What is this software testing, right?
Since we will be automation testers
after we finish this course.
So what is
software testing us?
What do we know about software testing,
how it works?
What are we doing
whenever we say it's testing right?
What are we trying to do?
What's the purpose?
Automatic monitor.
Okay, on my screen,
we'll see you guys will see.
Well, the the main part.
The main part
you need my screen to see. Okay.
The the notes and the code.
Okay.
So the software testing is we're checking
if the application that we're working on
is working or not.
Okay.
We're checking the requirements
impact right?
So basically what we're doing,
we're testing the software for making
sure the functionality
works properly, right?
So we basically what we're doing
is we're identifying the correctness
and the quality of the application.
Right. Checking for bugs.
Absolutely right.
So what we do,
what is software testing is to identify
correctness and
quality
of the application, right?
So basically you go inside the website,
whatever your project
is, wherever the application is,
you start clicking right
based on the requirements
you are given, right?
So, okay, so we identified
what's going on with software testing,
but how many ways
can we actually test guys?
Okay, two ways.
So there's two ways of testing, right?
One is manual
and one is automation, right?
I think you guys already done
the manual part where you
where you've done the test cases, right?
Where you did
the stats for the test cases, extracted
values, Um, actual values, Right.
So let's go ahead and put here manual
and automation.
All right, you guys a little bit
did that in the first classes, right?
I didn't I didn't think it was a
lot of classes in there. But
anyway, so
you're already familiar
with with manual testing.
So when, when do we go for automation now?
So we said there's two ways to test
the application manual in automation.
So we know about manual.
So in,
in automation, right?
So when do we actually go
and start our automation
when we want to find where is the bug?
Well,
you can find it manually as well, right?
You can find bugs manually as well.
The after manual testing is passed, right?
So once you you do you do all the tracks
for your manual, right?
So whenever you're given a task,
what you try to do, you go
try to log into the website
right to that project or application.
You're checking it manually first.
So once that is fine
and then what you can do,
you can start writing
your logic in your code, right?
So what we can do in here, we can put
after manual testing is passed, right?
So let's see,
perfect world when manual testing is done.
There is correct
when we have to test something repeatedly.
Okay.
That's a good point.
Right.
There are many similar projects and
we can write program to check them easily.
Okay.
We want to avoid human errors. Okay.
That is that is correct. Yes.
But the main point one,
another main point that we have in here
that I'm not sure if you guys
already talked about this
on manual testing classes.
Did you guys talk about environments
that you guys will be working?
Yes, right. Exactly. There we go.
So what environment
are you going to be testing,
guys?
Testing environment. Right.
So in order for you to start automation
or manual testing,
that environment has to be stable.
Okay?
Only then you can go ahead
and start your automation.
So I can put in here when
environment is stable.
Okay.
So there will be sometimes you will see
that you cannot reach some website, right?
Or you cannot go to some page
because you're getting some error.
So that way you won't be able to to
to go ahead and perform
any actions in there because you have
what's called
because you have something blocking you.
Right.
Okay.
All right.
Any questions so far, guys?
Okay. So another point, guys.
So when you just start the project, right,
when let's say
we just started the project,
we said that we we said that, hey, okay,
so this is our project we're going to be
doing manual and automation.
So what do you need to do
in order to start automation?
In that case, guys?
So what did you guys do today
before coming to class
in your intelligent, you need to prepare.
Prepare what?
Prerequisites. Okay, so
preparing your
requirements, automate
the code test case environment.
There we go.
You integrated selenium
with intelligent, right?
So what we've done, in other words,
we went ahead
and we downloaded selenium, right?
We, we just uploaded all the jar files
into our intelligent
and we check that it's working.
So what we did is we chose our app,
one of the automation tools, right?
Because we know that we will be automating
everything.
So Selenium is one of the automation tools
that we will be
using, Right?
Okay.
So what we've done here,
we chose was our automation tool.
So when we do, we go for automation,
when we analyze, right,
our test suite and
choose our
automation tools.
Okay.
So before you start any project,
you need to know whether you will be
going for automation or whether
you will be doing everything manually.
Okay, Any questions, guys?
Okay.
So since we talked about
automation tools, guys, what
what other automation tools do you know
except selenium guys?
Okay, So we said there is selenium, right?
There's you have to you
I think you have to
is pretty pretty outdated.
You have to is also I think it was cold
cuts or something like this
but I'm not sure.
There
we go. There is cucumber. Right. Cucumber.
Okay, that's good.
APM, APM is for mobile testing, guys.
Okay.
Okay. Test.
And you can include test engineer.
It's a framework,
but it's still it's a testing framework.
Okay.
Cucumber is another tool,
but we will be coming
to this a little bit later
during the during the classes.
Okay. Cucumber is a testing tool as well.
So there's one more tool, guys that is
getting popular a little bit nowadays,
but it's it's not that good.
I've used it a little bit.
It's not that really good
because it has a lot of bugs
inside that application itself.
It is called
Tatlong Studio.
So in order to use this
you have to pay for it,
but it still doesn't work properly.
Okay, guys.
So that's that's how it is right now.
So maybe it's a bit,
a little bit different,
different tool.
We we'll be using Maven as well.
All right.
Okay.
Moka I'm not familiar with Moka that much,
so I know it's a coffee,
but I, I don't, I don't really know
how, how it works in testing.
Okay.
All right.
So let's go through the levels of testing,
guys.
Okay?
Levels of testing.
We will be using Maven guys, not Kaplan.
Okay, So what do we know
about levels of testing?
Guys,
Anyone can guess Any guesses for this
small progression?
Those are those are the types. Right?
There we go.
So unit test, right?
This is one level of testing. Okay.
Who, who, who performed the unit test?
Guys?
Developers. Right. Exactly. There we go.
What else, guys?
Acceptance. Testing.
Okay, that's good.
Acceptance testing, system testing.
Absolutely right.
System testing.
And then there is one more. Exactly.
Integration testing where we are testing
how the application works from
the backend and front end, how
these two parts of the application
communicating with each other.
Okay.
So these will be
the levels of the testing.
So now what about the types of the testing
guys? So,
so on set small regression tests.
Right.
So those are the subtypes.
What is the parent of those subtypes guys.
Can anyone guess
it's a functional test.
Absolutely right.
So types of testing.
So there's two two types of testing.
One is functional,
one is nonfunctional testing, right?
So functional testing and then
nonfunctional testing.
Okay.
So what do we know
about nonfunctional testing?
What can we do in
nonfunctional testing guys?
So in functional,
it's pretty clear, right?
So small test regression, everything
that you perform on the on the web page.
Right.
Okay. Speed. Right.
Non nonfunctional speed.
What what In other words,
can we say that guys
there is some terminology for this
performance testing.
Absolutely right.
There we go, performance testing.
And then there's there should be one more
nonfunctional test guys.
So memory tests.
Okay.
That that's that's
part of the performance testing
reliability.
Okay.
In other words, guys, that
that's really close.
Low testing is very similar
to performance testing.
Okay.
What about your, um, what about the
how do we call when you
when you have passwords, strong passwords,
not strong password.
There we go. It's security testing, right?
So you need to make sure your
the security of the application
is good as well right
before you launch your application life.
Okay.
Secure the testing.
Okay. All right.
So we went through the level of testing,
types of testing.
Right.
Any questions so far, guys?
Okay, good.
All right.
So now what we are going to do is now
we will actually start
going over the selenium itself.
Okay, So did anyone did a research
What about selenium?
What is selenium glass
do automate web browser actions.
Okay.
It's testing tool.
So that we can automate our test cases.
Okay.
Any other guesses, guys?
It's a testing tool.
That is correct.
It's a library.
It's an open source automation tool.
Okay, that's very good.
Quick input.
Select navigate that everyone can use.
Yes, that is good.
Okay, so guys, selenium is a set of tools.
Okay,
so there are four different components
in selenium and we will be going over
those components one by one,
but we will be using only one component
from that Selenium.
Selenium set.
Okay.
So Selenium is,
is a set of tools.
Okay.
Which
helps us to
automate
lab applications.
It is mainly used, mainly used
to perform
functional testing.
Okay.
So selenium itself,
it has four different components.
Okay.
That's why it's a set of tools.
Okay? It's a set of testing tools
which
will help us to automate web application
and it is mainly used
for functional testing.
Okay, So now let's go over the selenium
components.
Okay.
So we sat
there are for anyone did research
about these components guys
okay ID what driver are see
and grid right.
So Selenium
ID right.
Selenium grid
Selenium lab driver and
Selenium bar see.
Right.
So there's four different components
Which one are we're going
to be using in our class cars.
Exactly.
We will be using selenium work driver
because this one is the most updated one.
Right.
So there are selenium I.D, grade and RC,
they are a little bit outdated.
I will go over them
like high level. Okay.
We're not going to be going into
details for the ID, RC and
GRID,
but mainly we will be
going over the selenium web driver.
Right.
So I.D. stands
for the Integrated
Integrated Development
Environment.
Right.
And then our grid is going to be
I think it was just the Firefox plug
in, if I'm not mistaken.
And then RC is just the
remote control.
Okay.
So I'll just put these high level
explanations on here, guys,
but we will be going a little bit
into details of what
the the other three
selenium components do.
Okay.
I'll show you
what's going on with those in a
in a chart and what is going on, how,
how they were developed
and everything like that.
But for now, let's focus on selenium.
What?
Driver Okay, so now what is
selenium
work?
Driver Guys, direct communication
with the browser.
Okay, So
some people said it's free, right?
So it's,
it's an open source automation tool
which allows us to perform actions
on a web application.
Right? Exactly.
It allows testing across various browsers.
Right.
It's an open source
and it's very popular right now.
So we can put in here that open source
automation tool, Right.
Which allows us
to perform
actions on a
web application.
Right.
And I'm pretty sure guys in Java,
you guys are already familiar
with interfaces, right?
I hope you are.
Did you guys go over the interfaces
in Java?
Not yet or yes.
Oh, you are talking about it.
Okay, that's fine.
So I could just put in here
that web driver.
Web driver is an interface, right?
So you will be seeing what I mean.
But after you guys
start going through the interfaces
and we will see what this interface
has in the future.
Okay. So right now
let's just put it in here.
That web driver is an interface.
Okay. All right.
So now before we dive into coding,
there is one more thing
that I want to go through.
In theory, its advantages
and disadvantages
of this selenium web driver.
Okay, So let's go here.
So then you
web driver
Okay, So what do you think guys,
are the advantages
of selenium web driver
Well,
first of all, it is free, right?
It's open source, right?
You don't have to pay for it.
You can just go ahead and download it
by itself.
Right?
So open source, what else, guys?
It's most popular. Okay.
And supports various programing languages.
Exactly.
So it works
with the different
languages.
Right. So what kind of languages do
we know, guys?
So one of them
that we will be working with is
Java, right?
So he also works with Ruby.
It also works with C-sharp
JavaScript, right?
So it works with different
and different languages.
I think it also worked with Python
it from that mistake.
What else guys
automate?
We can automate different browsers,
so that means it
supports multiple browsers, right?
That's one of the biggest advantages
of selenium web driver.
So we can see
we can put in here works with
multiple whole browsers and
supports
cross browser
testing.
Okay, anything else guys?
Is integration with ID?
Yes. Support.
Absolutely right.
So supports across various operating
systems, right.
So that means it is it doesn't care
what operating system you are using.
You can use selenium
in that operating system,
either its iOS or either
is Linux or Windows.
It doesn't really matter.
You can use Selenium in any case, right?
So we can put in here
that it is OS independent, right.
So you can use it in
BIOS, Linux
or Windows.
Okay.
So these are four really
main advantages of selenium web Driver.
Okay,
So now let's talk about disadvantages
of selenium web driver.
Any thoughts, guys, on this?
Open source means means no support.
That is correct.
And there is no technical support.
That is correct. So no
technical support, right?
Okay.
If you pay for it, that means that means
whenever you pay for it,
you can get anything is broken.
You can go ahead and call or email
their support team.
Right.
So since it's free,
there is no technical support for you.
Okay.
Anything else?
Exactly.
It only supports web based application.
That is correct.
That is very good point actually.
So that means this advantage for us is
we cannot automate the desktop
applications with selenium.
Right.
So cannot
automate desktop
applications.
Right.
Okay. Anything else guys.
So we can't automate,
not automate, let's not put automate,
let's put cannot test that.
So applications
with selenium, right, right.
Correct.
So there is no visibility on reporting.
Right.
So there is we can we can say no
the built in reports right.
In selenium web driver.
Okay. What else
new features might not always work.
What kind of features are we talking about
or we're talking about the selenium
features itself
or any web application features,
open source.
It can be developed by anyone.
Yeah, that is correct.
Depends.
Third party framework
like you can run test and G.
Okay.
There is one more thing that we cannot do
with selenium web driver.
Guys, is we cannot automate images
or test images.
We cannot test captures videos,
anything visual on the web page.
Okay, So you won't be able to verify
anything visually on the Web page.
Okay.
Is that clear?
Guys cannot
test captures.
I hope you guys know what capture
is, right?
Captures images, videos,
capture is when
when the website, when the web application
is trying to tell you that
are you robot or no.
Right.
It's asking for something for you to enter
any text or you need to choose
some or what's called some images
from that particular square.
Right?
There you go.
Yeah. So that is capture.
So that is we cannot test it
with selenium web driver
unless we do it manually.
Okay.
And there is one more thing that in here
we can put as a disadvantage,
but it's not really a disadvantage.
Maybe it is in, in some way
that it takes more time
for you to build the test cases
because you have to build the logic
in your code, right?
So to build to build
the test case is easy.
You just write the steps
you pasted in your Excel
or you pasted in your in your ticket.
Right.
But to finish that test case
inside, inside your code
or by using selenium web driver,
it's a bit challenging sometimes.
Okay. It takes
more time
to create
test cases.
Okay.
All right, guys,
any questions so far, guys, that
what we have done from the beginning
right.
It's more manual work
to actually start automating?
Well, sometimes it depends on a test case.
Right.
So MIT to to actually build
or to actually write a test case,
it's easy, right?
But after you write the test case,
you need to implement all those steps.
Right?
You need to
you need to build that logic in your code.
So sometimes that might get challenging.
So those technical test cases are
are taking more time to actually complete
that whole process.
Well, we'll be coming to screenshots
at the at the actually last
classes of the Selenium
parallel testing.
No, we will be actually using
a different tool to do a parallel testing.
Okay.
No built in reports.
What I mean by no built in reports
is whenever you whenever you,
you execute your test and your test is
finished, let's say it's passed, right?
You don't have any reports on hand
so that you can show your manager
or your test lead
or anyone that your test case has passed.
Okay.
So that that's
what I meant by no built in reports.
Exactly. No feedback on results. Yes.
So you can just get that
your test passed in your console,
but you won't be able to have any
like estimate of report
or any kind of reports on hand.
Okay.
All right.
Any other questions, guys?
Do we use per facto?
So I know I'm
not really sure what that is actually.
Any other questions, guys,
before we dive into coding?
All right.
Okay. If everything is good.
So let's go ahead and start the fun part,
okay?
So what I'm going to do, I'm
going to create a new package
in here
for class one.
Okay?
And then what I will do is
I will create a new job class, okay?
And I will name it as launch
browser, a
bigger for you
and what I'm going to do,
going to paste the main method in here.
Okay.
All right.
So I hope
everyone knows how to do this stuff right?
So this is pretty easy.
Creating a package and creating a class
for now, since it's our first class guys.
So we will be gone over new methods, over
new functionalities, and over new code.
So it would be better for
you guys to listen first
and then type in the code afterwards.
Okay.
All right.
So now, guys, so everyone has
the selenium project, right?
It doesn't really matter.
Yeah, I'll give you time, guys.
Okay.
It doesn't really matter what you call it,
right? It
is. Okay. Sounds good.
All right, guys.
So everyone has the Selenium
project set up.
You have drivers you have all
the libraries important, right?
So now we have our first class in here,
our main method.
So before we start
interacting with the browser
itself, right?
So inside our drivers, guys inside our
drivers will have two different drivers,
which is one of them is Gecko Driver,
one of them is Chrome Driver, Right.
So the chrome driver we know
is for the Chrome browser
Gecko driver is for the Firefox browser.
Okay, So what we will be doing,
we will be mostly working
with the Chrome driver, the
you don't have to have it right now,
but in the future
I think we might have some actions
with Firefox as well.
Okay.
If you don't have a gecko driver right
now, it is fine guys.
That's okay.
You have a
you have a question sign on drivers.
It's okay.
So seems like
you connected to the to the GitHub
but you didn't push your code yet
so that's why you have that sign. Yes.
I created a package
under source folder in here
and I created a class under the
that package as well.
Okay, guys,
if you have only chrome, that is fine.
We will be working with Chrome anyways.
Okay.
But if you don't have chrome, please
download Chrome.
Okay. All right.
So now, guys, so we have the drivers,
we have all the libraries in here.
So now before we interact
with our Chrome
or with our browser and we perform
any actions in there, what we need to do,
which is we need to set the properties
before we perform anything.
Okay, so how this is going to work?
It's pretty simple. English.
Okay, guys, so what I am going to do,
I will start typing in here.
System dot set property.
Okay, so let me actually do this.
So let's see that property.
Okay, so this is the first method
that I can see in here that popped up.
Okay.
So what you can see
in here, it's asking for us
for two different arguments.
Okay, So it accepts
two different arguments in here.
So both of them are as a string value.
Okay, so I'm going to choose this method.
So I have one string in here of comma,
the second string in here, and I'm going
to close my statement in here.
Right.
So for the first key, for the first value
that I need to enter in here,
I need to specify what driver
I am going to be using.
Okay?
In this case, I am going to be using
a chrome driver, right.
Which will interact with a Chrome browser.
So now the first the first value that I'm
going to enter, it's a built in value.
Okay. You just have to remember this.
Okay, so what I'm going
do in here,
I'll start typing web driver, dot,
chrome,
dot driver.
Okay.
And again, guys, this is them.
This is the built in what's called feature
that you just need to remember to interact
with the Chrome browser.
Okay.
So the second one,
the second value
that I need to pass in here
is to tell my intelligent,
where is my chrome driver is located.
Okay, so in this case, if you look in here
we have a drivers folder
and that chrome driver is located
inside this drivers folder.
Right.
So what I'm going to do simply
right in here,
I'll put drivers slash
chrome driver.
Okay.
It is case sensitive. Yes.
So since I'm having Mac in here guys,
I don't need any extensions.
Okay.
So I, I don't need any extensions in here.
But if you are using,
if you're using windows,
what you need to do is for windows,
you need to add an extension of that key.
Right.
And extension of that XY.
Okay.
So now here what we did on line six guys,
we told our intelligent that, okay,
so I'll be interacting with a Chrome
browser.
Yeah, with a Chrome browser and
this is my pass.
This is my path
for the contract Chrome driver
that I will be using right
where the ad is.
It's going to be here
just after your chrome driver dot xy.
Okay.
All right.
Any questions so far, guys?
I should be clear.
Right,
Because we didn't really perform anything
or if if that doesn't work for Windows
guys, you can also
you can also use
you can use the backslash.
Okay.
Sometimes it doesn't really work for
for for Windows users
so you can use back to
double backslash is so that it works
it not it's not always but
sometimes some might have that problem
for Mac.
Oh you mean the absolute path.
Okay yeah you can you can,
you can actually do
the absolute path in here.
But in this case I'm going to explain that
why this doesn't.
It's the why it's not necessary.
Because you are in this class, right?
You try to access the driver,
which is in that specific project.
Okay.
So your intelligent will figure it out.
What where your chrome driver
is because your intelligent
will be looking inside this Selenium
Basics batch ten project.
Okay.
That's why you don't have to put
an absolute path in here.
Drivers Chrome Driver.
Okay.
What if it's a different web
browser? Okay. Yeah.
Good questions.
Okay, so there are a couple of questions,
guys. I'm Greg.
I'm going to explain those one by one.
So first of all, this one,
this one, as I said, it's a built in
what's called
built in feature, right?
So this is unique, right?
So in order for you to interact
with a Chrome driver,
I mean, Chrome browser,
you have to write this one.
So this is always going to be unique.
This is the way it's
going to stay in here.
Okay.
The first argument that we passed in here.
Okay, So if you want to do something
else, then in here
what you can do Web driver
thing if you want to use the gecko driver,
it was Gecko dot driver.
Okay.
And since we're using Chrome,
then it's going to be chrome.
Okay, guys, depending on which
browser you want to interact with,
that's how you will be changing
the name in here in the middle.
Okay. Okay.
Coming to the second argument
that we passed in here.
Here you are.
Just specifying
here, you're just specifying the
the chrome driver where it is located.
Okay.
Because you need to tell you
tell me, Jay, where it's running from.
Okay.
So if you don't have your driver,
you won't be able to open up the Chrome
browser, Right?
So that Chrome driver will be helping us
to open the Chrome browser.
And we need to say in here,
we need to specify where
that Chrome driver is located.
Okay.
Or Yeah, you don't have to do that.
Yes, you don't have to do
you don't have to put that absolute path.
Okay.
But make sure, guys,
make sure you have a drivers
folder in your project
in side your project.
Okay.
And inside that folder
you have this chrome
driver.
Okay, guys.
So if your drivers, if your drivers
are in a different location,
then you have to put your absolute cap,
but you need to have this drivers
folder inside your project.
Okay?
If you don't have it, create
one folder in.
Copy that Chrome driver
from wherever it is and paste it in here.
Okay? And
where does the system come from?
System comes from Java.
Okay,
so it's a it's a final class, guys
said, okay, yeah, that's fine,
That's fine.
Guys, if you have that question
mark, it is fine
as long as you have those chrome drivers.
Chrome driver and gecko driver
inside your project, that is fine.
That's not a big deal.
That that question mark.
Okay. Any other questions, guys?
Is anyone confused?
What is going on?
Copying to intelligent?
Yeah, that is correct.
So you have to do it in the actual folder,
right.
Where you downloaded.
Okay.
All right, let's continue, you guys.
So what I will be doing next since
this one.
It's fine.
It's okay.
All right.
So the next thing that I will be doing
right now
so I mentioned here,
I told my intelligent, Hey, I'm
using the chrome driver
and here is the chrome driver,
the path where it is located.
So I will be using exactly this file
to to interact with my Chrome browser.
Okay.
So now the next line, what I will do,
I will need to launch my browser.
Okay, So what I will do in here,
I will simply start with saying
web driver driver
is equal to new chrome driver.
Okay, since we are interacting
with the Chrome browser,
we will be instantiating a new instance.
Right? And use of our chrome driver.
If it was for if we were using
if we were using the Firefox,
I think it should be
Firefox driver in here.
But since we're using the chrome driver,
we will be simply using
chrome driver in here.
Okay.
Any on this guys?
Any questions on like ten or 14?
Okay, cool.
So now what I will do in here,
I'm going to right click
and I will run this class.
Okay.
So when I run this class, let's see
what's going to happen.
There we go.
What happened, guys?
So right now, what we can see in here
that it launched
the Chrome browser in here, right?
So it didn't go
it didn't go to any to any website.
Why? Why?
It's all right.
Because probably you don't have the
I don't think
you have the libraries in here.
Yeah,
I don't think you have the important.
That's why you don't have this.
So it didn't go to any website. Why?
Because we didn't specify anything.
Right.
What is specify
where to go, where to navigate.
Right.
We didn't specify what website
we want to navigate.
Right.
Exactly.
We don't have the euro yet.
So what we just did, we just launched
our Chrome browser.
Look to this line 14.
What is it going to do?
It's going to launch the Chrome browser
or Firefox browser,
whichever you put it in here.
Okay, Any questions, guys in here?
Is there anything you guys are confused?
Shouldn't be right.
It's pretty
easy and straightforward right now.
Okay, so now it's time for us
to go ahead and navigate to
let's see if you
are having some issues in here. So
and then you see,
okay, Nick, you missed that.
Easy in there
in your path.
So make sure you put in here
at the end.
So that's why I don't think it's working.
Uh, let's see.
Yeah.
Guys, check if you if you're using Mac,
you don't need that easy
if you're using windows
only if you're using windows,
you need an extension of the.
Okay, guys.
And make sure if your folder,
if your folder name starts
with with a capital D,
then you have to mention it here as well.
Okay.
So it's all case sensitive.
So so please pay attention to that.
Okay guys here.
Yeah, you don't have to.
Okay, So you don't have that. Just put
don't do that.
Double double backslash is just do
what's called the regular slash.
Okay.
So it seems like you have double backslash
as in Mac.
So try to do just one slash
and it should work in your case.
Okay guys, after you have there's one
more thing guys.
After you
what's called after you have pasted
your drivers, you might get some
some notification when you run
your code, it's not possible to run.
Okay.
Because there's some warning
that it's not safe.
It's malicious and all that stuff. Right.
So what you want to do in that case,
you want to go to your system preferences.
Okay, System preferences
and just go to security and privacy.
And there should be here to allow anyway.
Okay, just click on that
and then urania code again,
that should work.
How to launch right click in here and run
right.
Okay guys, anyone else having issues?
I'll explain line 14 as well.
Okay.
If you're having issues, please post it.
Incentive support, guys.
We will be taking taking a look at those.
Okay.
All right.
Yeah. The messages in the console is fine.
Yeah, that's fine, guys.
As long as you have that Chrome
browser open,
that's fine.
All right,
So now let me explain in line 14 again
and then we will continue.
Okay.
Line 14, guys,
what we are doing in here I am
I am creating a new instance
of the Chrome browser again by using.
So basically what this line does,
it's going to read everything in here.
Okay, so we're using Chrome in here
and this chrome driver is under drivers.
So now what I'm to do,
I'm going to launch a new instance
of the Chrome browser.
So on line 14, what we're doing in here,
we are launching the browser.
Any questions, guys?
What preferences are we talking about?
So I can show the preferences? Yes.
If you if you have it with capital
starting with capital center,
then yes,
you have to mention the capital as well.
Oh, system preferences.
Okay, So system preferences in here
you go to system preferences,
you go to security and privacy,
and then there should be a button in here
to allow it anyway.
Okay, So click on that and then run.
Run your
what's called running a code again.
And that to work.
Yes, that's fine. That's fine.
The usual first day.
Yeah, that's okay.
I opened up empty page. That's fine.
That's okay.
So you said that if you have
if you have the
the Chrome browser open, that's fine.
Okay, guys, let's move on. Right.
So we opened up the we opened up
the chrome browser and now what
we need to do,
we need to navigate to, to some web page.
Okay?
So now it's pretty straightforward
and is easy.
Okay, so what I will do in here.
So now from now on,
I will be using that object
from the line 14.
Okay.
So what I will do in here
in order for me to navigate to some page
what I'm going to be
doing, I will be using this
object that I created and what I will do
when I hit Dot, it's going to give me
a lot of different methods
that the first method
in order to navigate to the page
is going to be driver dot get,
which accepts one string argument.
Okay,
so what I will do in here
inside the driver not get so
I am going to be doing here let's
let's see.
Okay let me take this here.
So let's say we're going to Google, right?
So this is the thing.
So what I am going to do
or what you just go,
Yeah, let's do Google right now.
So just copy and paste it in here.
Okay?
So driver dot get so get method
what it's going to do, it will go ahead
and navigate to the website that you just
mentioned inside the parentheses.
Okay.
So what I'm going to do
going to right click
and write my code right now and let's see
what's going to happen.
Okay?
Running now.
Okay, There you go.
So now what happened,
guys, is I am on Google page, right?
So hopefully everyone had the same outcome
that you guys landed on Google page,
right?
So pretty cool, right, guys?
So starting off launching the browser,
navigating the website.
So pretty good, right?
Yes. It's really it's
it's suggested
the best way to do it,
you have to have the whole weblink. Yes.
With the SGP and everything.
It's highly recommended to have that look
if you just do it.
Yeah. W ww google.com it should work.
But if you just, if you do this
I don't think it's going to work.
So if you just do this one,
I don't think it's going to work,
but I'm not sure it might work.
But let me run this again and see.
But it's highly recommended, guys,
that you put the whole web link.
Okay, So see you guys.
It didn't navigate to Google because
we don't have the whole thing in here.
Okay.
So you
can see you can even see in the here
that there are
there is some invalid argument exception.
Okay.
And we will be going over these exceptions
in the future classes.
Okay.
Work on.
Did you do you have,
do you have the Chrome
browser open or no.
Okay, then it's fine.
If you can't import anything,
please posted in syntax support
or go ahead and please watch the videos
from YouTube that we have.
That should be that should be pretty easy
and straightforward.
Guys. Okay,
so for now
it's 820.
So let's take a quick break, guys. Okay.
So people who are a little tried
to find out
and import everything, get ready
for the second part of the class.
Okay.
All right. Let's take a 15 minute break,
okay.
And then we will continue with that.
All right, guys, let's continue.
Uh, let's see.
All right, let's continue, guys.
I see there are some people having issues,
but I think
Please join the What's
Mohammed's zoom,
and he's going to help you guys.
He sent this he sent a Zoom link in
and the syntax support.
So please go ahead and do that.
Okay.
But I hope the majority of the people.
Right.
A majority of the people,
they everyone have
everyone has the oh,
let's call the jar files.
Everyone figured out
what's going on, right?
Everyone was able to launch the browser
and navigate to Google
right.
The video you download at six. Okay.
I think six is going to work,
but I don't know.
I have seven. That's fine.
If if you if it's working with six jars,
that's fine, guys.
Okay.
All right.
Okay. So
okay, so we navigate into Google
pretty good, right?
So now there are a couple more thing.
That's a couple more things
that we're going to be learning today.
So there are a couple more methods
that we will be learning from Selenium.
So one of them, right?
So when you navigate it to the euro, okay,
when you navigate it to the URL,
you want to, sometimes
you will navigate
to the to the right page.
But the URL itself, it's
not going to be the same.
Okay?
So it might be different
sometimes that that might cause
any defects and everything.
So what we can do actually
with help of selenium work,
Selenium libraries, what we can do,
we can capture that your
that we just navigated to.
Okay so what I can do in here
is can do driver that
get current your row.
Okay so I have this method
it's built in methods
in selenium
so I can use this method, right?
So if I get the cure you guys,
what am I getting in return?
What do you guys think
I am getting the whole,
the whole link that is in here, Right?
So The one I navigated.
I should be getting that.
But in that code, guys, what is the type
of the data I'm getting in return?
Guys?
There we go.
It is a string, right?
So what, what I can do in here,
I can simply assign this to this string,
right?
I can say string URL is equal to driver.
Get here in Europe. Right.
So I want to see this in my console.
So what I will do simply
and here
I will print it out in my console.
Okay, So what I'm going to do
is I'm going to run this code again
and let's see what's going to happen.
There we go.
So we opened it here, Google.
So let me go back in here.
So as you can see,
it printed out the right
your route for me.
Okay, So this is pretty easy.
This is straightforward.
Any questions on this, guys?
So you get the URL,
you you can print it out
or sometimes you need to verify
that the zero is correct
right after you navigate it to the page.
Okay.
All right.
So the other thing that we can do
after we get the new URL,
we can get the title of the page.
Okay.
So if I get the title of the page, where
do I see the title of the page in here?
Guys?
So let's say I navigate it to the Google.
This is my this is my.
You are right.
What is my title?
My title is going to be on that tab,
right?
So Google should be my title, right?
So what I can do in here again,
guys, I can do Driver dot
simply get title.
Okay, so get title.
It's going to return me
as string value as well.
So I'm just going to assign this
to a string in here.
And what I will do,
I'll just print this out.
Okay, So let's run this and see
if we can have this in our console,
okay, there we go.
So we navigate it to Google.
So if you look in our console,
there's one link that we have
and there is
the second one is the title of the page.
Right?
Pretty cool, right?
So we got the URL that we entered
and we got the title
from that tab that we have right?
And at the very end, guys,
whenever we did some actions,
we performed some actions, we got the URL,
we got the title right.
So what do we want to do
at the very end of our test
guys,
we need to close the browser
or to quit the session, right?
So simply what I will do driver that quit.
Okay, so when I run this code right
now, it's going to be really fast.
Okay,
so you might not see it in my browser
but you will see it in your screens, guys.
Okay, so this is going to be really fast.
So I'm not sure if you guys
will be able to see this
You should be able to see this.
Yeah. Okay.
We navigate it.
There we go.
Google
and it terminated that session right away.
Right.
So your code, whenever you write the code,
the selenium code is very fast, right?
So it's not going to be
waiting for anything.
So you navigate, it,
you got everything you need.
You quit the browser. Okay. There we go.
Okay.
Very good.
Right?
Yeah.
We will be going over the waits, guys.
We will be going over how to pause
anything, how to see anything.
I will be showing you
how to pause the execution
so that we can see everything visually,
because everything is really fast.
Okay,
So we can set a time
for quite a little bit later
in my next example.
Okay, guys.
So it is.
Yeah, this was just the simple
launching the browser,
navigating to one website,
getting the euro, getting the title
and quitting the browser.
Okay, so right now
we're not verifying anything, okay?
Because we are just starting.
Okay, So but we will be
we will be verifying some information
on the web page.
Okay. In the future, classes. Okay.
Right now, step by step class.
Okay.
All right.
So let me see.
Let me close these sessions
so quick.
Okay.
Any questions before we move forward,
guys?
Oh, right.
Pretty good.
Okay, so let me actually
do this.
It looks fun for right now.
Hopefully it's going to remain the same.
Well, we'll see. We'll see.
There will be some challenges, guys,
but they're not to too difficult for us.
Okay, Hamzah,
I need to see a project Explorer
right here that you
that you minimize need to see that
I need to see where that coming from.
Okay.
But for now,
let me give you a quick task, guys.
Okay. Uh,
see, let me give you a quick test
so that you guys can practice.
So let me actually
create a new class in here.
And to test one.
Okay, There we go.
So launch the browser, guys,
navigate to Amazon, print out the title
and the URL in the console
and close the browser
right?
So 5 minutes for this.
It should be really easy,
but try not to copy the
the properties how to set everything.
Okay.
Try to type in manually yourself.
Okay guys.
So that way you practice with that.
Okay.
So you can delete
that classic delete that.
Yes. You need a new class.
Open up a new class, guys.
Create a new class and complete this
and then we'll complete this together
real quick.
Okay?
And then we will be moving forward
to a different different
actions on the web page.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Your your driver folder is empty,
so that's why your code is not working.
Seems like you imported everything,
which is good, but you need to copy
and paste that drivers inside your drivers
folder
like you can send a screenshot here
or join the zoom link that Mohammed sent.
Seems like he sent like four zoom links
and no one is
joining.
Nice. Okay. Some people are done already.
That's good.
I hope you guys didn't copy and paste
everything they said.
Properties,
please scroll up in your memory.
Scroll up.
I need to see the
whole error in your console.
There is some list that you need to check
that I need to check at the very top
clause
and quit. They don't do the same thing.
I will go over those
at the end of the class.
Okay.
So we'll be going over the difference
between those.
Yeah, that's fine. Clause quit.
It's going to close
and I need to see the whole error.
You didn't set the properties.
You your instance, a new chrome driver,
but you didn't set the properties.
That's why it's not running for you.
Okay, good.
All right, so let's do this together,
okay, Quickly
in here.
Okay, So main method in here.
What do we need to do?
First class for this task?
We need to set the properties. Right.
So I'm going to start with system
dot set property.
So this is expecting me
to input two keys in here, right?
So one of them is telling that, hey, which
which driver I'm going to be using, right?
So here
work driver, chrome driver.
And the second key in here is the path
that we have the chrome drivers stored in.
Right?
It's going to be
drivers
Chrome driver.
Right. So we set the property.
So now it's time for us to have
a new instance of the chrome driver.
So what I will do in here, web driver.
Driver
is equal to new chrome driver.
Right?
So if I run this right
now, will this launch the browser
or now guys, it's
not going to launch the browser.
Is there anyone who says Yes,
Yes, it will. Right.
Because let's take a look
at the previous example.
I left a note in here, guys.
Our line 14 will launch the browser.
Okay,
so please pay attention to these details.
Okay.
So line 16 that I have
right now
in here will will launch the browser.
Okay,
So now after it launched the browser,
we need to tell our browser
where to navigate the.
Okay, so what I will do is driver get.
And here I think
is Amazon dot com.
Right.
And then what I need to do in here
I need to get
the would navigate it to the Amazon
right now I need to get the title
and I need to get the zero right
so both of them we can
we can store them in a string right
so title
is equal to driver the get title
and then the second one is zero.
Go to the driver
that get
a new URL.
Right?
And then we can simply print this out
title and concatenate here
the URL.
And at the very end
what we need to do is just
quit the browser
right?
All right.
To always stored this information.
If we just put it.
Oh, that's fine.
That's fine, guys.
I mean, if your best bet is to store it
inside the string or whatever
the return is,
but you can, you can simply store
this inside the the print line as well.
All right.
It's title something.
Yeah.
It's just the it's
just a naming convention, right?
You can name it.
Whatever you want to name it.
Right. So
the best practice
is to store them in a string
and then print them out or however.
I mean, if you want to verify those at the
and in the future,
then you need to store them inside
the inside the string.
So that's that's the best practice.
Okay. So now let's run.
Okay, Let's run
this and see what's going on.
Okay.
Amazon, there we go.
So now it it closed the browser, right?
And now we have the
the title and the title right here
and the euro right here.
Okay.
All right.
Let's see.
I need to see the error, guys.
What's the same? But not working?
Yeah, I need to see the whole error, guys.
Okay, so.
Okay,
so you have to
you need to follow the steps
that Amazon sent
in the course announcements.
But think
let me see if you did
go here. Yes.
So basically, as I explained before,
guys, you need to go to your system
preferences.
Chrome driver cannot be opened.
Okay, that's fine. Yeah.
Go go to go to system preferences
and then security and privacy
and here
and then there will be a button in here
allow anyway
so I'll click on that and rerun it.
Okay.
Okay guys, when you run your code,
are you running this from here
or you're
running by right clicking on here?
Because some people I see they're still
their code is going to
Google is navigating to Google
because I think
you guys are running from here
and you are running different
what's called different classes in here.
Okay.
So when you right click in here, run
task one.
It should be navigating to Amazon.com
and not Google.
Okay.
All right.
Any questions, guys, on the task?
No, the title is on the tab, right?
The title is what you have on the tab.
The URL is,
what you have in that text box.
Right.
It's all the way around.
Okay. Got it.
All right, guys, let's continue.
Right.
So we got this.
So now there is one more
thing that I want to show you
in here. So
let me create
a new class in here and name it is is
Navigate method.
Okay,
So, all right,
I'm not sure if yours is working
without that.
Maybe this is running.
What do you have in your previous class
in your launch browser?
What are where are you navigating in
launch browser class?
Send me this screenshot this. Okay.
Or it better send it to syntax support
guys.
Okay.
So we are a little behind,
so I need to finish some stuff in here,
but okay.
All right.
So I created, I created a new
a new class widget which I named Navigate.
Okay.
So I'm going to have
a new main method in here.
So what we're going to do in this
example is I'm going to show you
a different way to navigate to the
to some websites. Okay.
So before
what is it in the previous examples,
what are the
what's called?
What are the method
that we used to navigate to be
to the URL guys?
It's a get method, right?
So now in here, so let's go ahead
and set the properties in here
right.
The driver
driver
and then drivers.
Chrome driver.
Yes. Setting the property is a must guys.
Okay.
Setting the property is a must.
Okay. So we set the property.
So now what I will do, I'll go and create
a new object of the driver in here
which will help me to launch
Chrome Driver.
So now what we used to do, we used to
do Driver Right. Get.
So let's
navigate, let's navigate to Facebook.
Okay,
so let's do
so I'm just going to copy this URL.
Go back in here,
paste it in here. Okay.
So now, guys,
there is a different way to navigate
to the to any your okay.
And it's pretty simple.
It's really simple English.
So what I'm going to do in here is
I will do driver that,
navigate that too.
And then what I will do?
I will need to paste a euro in here.
So I'm just going to grab a URL
from Amazon
here and I will paste it in here.
Okay.
So there's two different methods
to navigate to the pages
that drive
and I get and navigate to, right?
So there is a slight difference in
navigate and get methods.
Okay.
So then the most important,
what's called difference between get
and navigate is navigate.
With navigate.
You can move back and forward
and you can also refresh your page.
Okay, So this is the very important thing
that you need to know about it.
Navigate. Okay.
So if I run this right now,
so if I run this code right now,
so what's going to happen?
Am I going to navigate to Facebook
and then open up
another browser
and navigate to the Amazon?
Or how is this going to work? Guys
on the same window?
Okay, first, first, first to Facebook
and then to the Amazon on the same window.
Okay.
Probably open both in separate windows.
Okay. To
same browser, different tabs.
Okay, first
Facebook, then Amazon in the same browser.
Okay, good.
All right, so this will navigate.
Okay, let me run this and it's better
if you see it, right.
So I'm going to run this right now.
So let's see what's
going to happen.
Okay.
There you go.
Facebook.
So now Amazon right?
So what happened is
we went to Facebook first
and then our next line of code overridden
that the previous one.
And we went to Amazon right
on the same tab on the same window.
Why? Because we have one
instance of the Chrome browser.
We only have we only launched one guys.
Okay, please keep in mind
if you have multiple,
if you want multiple different chrome
browsers,
you need to create more objects
off the web.
Okay.
So since we only have it on line ten,
that means we're launching
only one web browser.
Okay,
well, we'll be coming to creating new tabs
and going to the tab, then manipulating
with a tab in the future classes.
But right now, let's get this one
clear that we created one object.
That means we have only one Chrome
browser.
Okay?
And we will be performing actions on
one tab on one window only.
Okay.
So, so here
we went to Facebook,
we went to Amazon after that.
Right?
So now what I want to do,
I want to go back to Facebook page.
Okay, so what I'm going to do
and here it is really simple
I will do driver that navigate
that back simple English.
You don't have to complicate this right
Driver that navigate back
which should take me back to the Facebook
page.
Okay, So let me run this.
Let me run this and see
what's going to happen.
Okay. Running.
There we go.
Facebook page, guys.
Amazon.
And then it went back to Facebook.
We I hope all we all notice
that we went to Facebook Amazon
and then we went back to the Facebook
right.
No when you are navigating back
in this case we don't have to specify any
your route because we already specified
this one in here.
Okay. So pretty cool, right, guys?
So what if I want to go forward? It's
pretty easy driver
that navigate that forward.
Okay. Yes.
This is the main
like the main feature of navigate
method is to go back forward
and to refresh the page.
Okay.
Yes, it won't. So you're open.
You're opening
a completely new instance of the chrome
so it doesn't have any history.
So that's why it doesn't keep any history
before that.
Okay.
All right.
So let's run this.
If I run this right now, where am I?
Ended up in here, guys,
we need to.
Excuse me.
We need to end up in Amazon. Right.
So let me run this real quick.
So Facebook, Amazon, Right.
And then we need to go back again.
Facebook. And we went back
to Amazon again, right?
So pretty cool, right, guys?
Navigating back and forth
through the through the Web pages, right?
So now if I want to
let's say I navigated back and forth,
I ended up on Amazon.
So what I want to do now,
I want to refresh that page.
Okay, So easy as well guys
driver that navigate that refresh.
Okay.
Pretty straightforward
and easy methods in here.
So I'm not sure
if you going to be able to see this.
So but let's run this and see if
if we can spot that.
Okay, so I'm
running this again.
Okay.
Amazon,
we need to go back to Facebook right
from Amazon.
Okay, There we go.
And it refreshed the page one more time.
Right?
So going back and forth
through the Facebook and Amazon in here
and then at the very end
what we navigate to Amazon
it refreshed our page as well
right pretty pretty cool right guys
so manipulating with back and forth
and refreshing the pages
it's not going to refresh for Facebook.
No it will refresh at the very end
because at the very end on line 14,
we ending up on Amazon.
So that's the only page
it's going to refresh.
Okay.
No get get
method will not have this feature.
Okay.
Only navigate will have the feature
to go back and forth
and to refresh the page.
Okay.
I need to see a code comes up.
All right.
So there's one more thing
that I want to show you guys in here.
So since we saw in previous examples that
let's actually
put here as Google,
okay, because that's much
lighter, lighter website.
So it navigates really fast.
So if I run this right now,
so I think it should be faster
than running Amazon because Amazon
has lot of things on the website, right?
So that's why it's loading really
a little slower than usual.
Okay.
So if I go here Facebook, see it's
it's going really fast right now.
Okay.
So because Google is really light,
what's
website
and it doesn't have anything to load.
So what I want to do in this case, guys,
I want to do
I want to pause my execution
for a little bit, okay?
So that I can see visually
what is going on on my screen.
Okay.
Because right now,
when I run it, you saw that.
You saw that it was really fast.
It's going back and forth.
You don't really understand
what is going on. Right.
So what I want to do in this case
before I refresh,
I want to pause my execution
for a couple of seconds.
Okay.
So what I will do in here,
I will simply do thread
that's sleep, okay.
And this will accept
an argument in milliseconds.
Okay.
So what I will do,
I want to pause this for 2 seconds
so that means I will need to enter this
here 2000 milliseconds.
Okay. So
what I will need to do in here,
since it's not compiling.
Right.
So what I will need to do,
just hover over guys
and do add exception to method signature.
Okay.
And then you're going to have this
throw interrupted exception,
but don't really pay attention to that.
We will be coming to those exception
handling later on.
Okay.
Is this clear, guys?
Any questions on this?
Okay.
If you have €3, yes, it's
going to be the same.
That's that's fine, guys.
I mean, they're you need to you need to
manipulate with back and forth, right?
So if you do back, it's
going to go to your second URL.
And then if you do it forward, it's
going to go back
to the third one.
So you need to
you need to see the logic yourself.
So the last part was I explained
this thread asleep
to pause and just add this
insight on the method signature.
Okay, so this is an exception handling.
This is don't pay attention to this
right now
because you will be covering this
in the last class of Java.
Okay.
This is not an implicit or explicit way.
This is just that
I'm pausing my thread.
Okay.
So whatever you run your code in Java,
you you open up a thread.
Okay,
so you paused that thread for 2 seconds,
so your execution goes
top to the bottom, right?
So when it comes to line 15,
what you need to do, it's
going to wait for 2 seconds
and then it will go to the line 16.
Okay, So I'm going to run this right now.
So now let's see
whenever it goes to Google
before it refreshes the page,
it will wait for 2 seconds.
Okay, So I'm on Facebook.
Go to Google, back to Facebook.
Google now 2 seconds
and it needs to refresh
the page, did it not or it did already?
I'm not sure.
I probably missed this.
Yeah, it did. Right?
Yeah, I didn't see it. Okay, cool.
All right.
So see, guys, it waited for 2 seconds.
That that means you are
here. It waited for 2 seconds.
It paused our execution for 2 seconds,
and then it refreshed our page.
Okay.
Any questions so far, guys?
Any confusion?
Okay, cool.
All right, so now we were talking about
so once I refreshed the page,
so at the very end, what we need to do
we need to quit the browser.
Right?
So some of you guys in the previous
example, some of you guys did
did drive a dot clothes.
Right.
And I'm going to explain how
how that driver
dark and drove that quit work.
Okay so what I will do in here
driver that clause.
Okay so
and I will put driver
quit in here as well.
Okay so there is a slight difference
between close and quit.
Okay.
So if I go, let me open up this one.
So I have a chrome in here.
So how many times do I have right now?
Guys, the top
two tabs. Right.
So if I do quit, guys,
if I do driver that quit,
it will turn Nate the whole session
and it will close all the available tabs
on this particular crop.
Okay, But if I close guys,
it will only close this particular tab.
Okay, so this is the slight difference
between those,
but we will not be seeing that.
We will not be seeing this right now
because we only working on one tab right
now. Okay.
But when we come to the point where
we will be manipulating with different
and multiple tabs,
you will see that difference in there.
Okay.
So you basically get quit is just
if I if I
right click in here you can see quit
right guys.
So if I do quit
it will close all the tabs.
Right. It will.
But if I close one tab inside the chrome
is just going to terminate one tab.
Okay, So that's the difference
it is in here.
Closed. Closed.
The current page
quit closed the whole session.
Okay,
so what we can do
will close the current tab.
And here
I will
quit the whole
browser gap.
So I'm just going to
common this.
Okay.
Yeah. It's.
It's really useful
when you have multiple tabs.
Exactly.
All right.
Okay.
Any questions, guys?
Should be clear, Right.
Pretty straightforward.
Okay.
All right.
So there's one more thing
that want to show you,
but I want to guess what
we've missed so far.
Okay?
So I want you to guess what
we've missed today.
So We launch the browser.
We navigated to some websites, right?
So what we did,
we navigated back and forth.
We closed the browser,
we refreshed the browser.
Right.
What is one thing
that is remaining for us?
Not really.
I'm not talking about performing
any actions on the web page.
I'm talking about the whole browser
itself.
Guys,
Any guesses?
It's state running within inside.
Make it full. What?
What do you mean by that?
Making for what?
Full screen?
Absolutely right.
We didn't maximize our browser.
Right?
So there's only one thing left
is to maximize our window.
Right?
So we can do this with selenium as well.
What I'm going to do,
I'm going to create one more class in here
and name it as maximize
window
main method, right?
So what I'm going to do in here,
first and foremost, what we need to do,
we need to set our property
right.
So what I will do in here
with Driver, the Chrome
driver,
and then where my driver is located.
And then I'm going to have that instance
right of my driver,
my web driver.
Okay, So now we'll launch the browser.
So what I want to do in here
is let's use actually let's go to Google.
That's fine.
So what I'm going to do,
going to navigate to Google.
Okay,
Going to navigate to Google in here.
Let's see see.
So your exception is not correct some.
So you're you're doing IO exception.
That's not correct.
You do interrupted exception only.
Okay.
So yours is stating a no different.
So let's move on in here.
So I'm navigating to Google.
Okay guys, So what I need to do in here,
I just need to maximize my window.
Okay, So it's pretty easy as well, guys.
So what I need to do
is driver that navigate, okay?
And then what I need to do is
not navigate.
I'm sorry, guys.
What I need to do,
I need to manage my windows.
Right?
So What I will do.
Driver that Manage
What am I managing in here?
I'm managing my window. Right.
So manage the window.
What am I trying to do?
I'm trying to maximize my window.
Okay, so let's run this and see
what's going to happen.
I'm not sure
if you're going to see it on the screen.
I hope it doesn't.
It doesn't maximizes
that window on the other screen
that I have yet.
As I said, guys,
as I said, guys, it's it's
it maximized the screen,
but it maximized it on other screen.
So that's why you didn't see it here.
But I hope when you run it
on your local guys, you will see that
it's maximized.
Yes, I will go over the
what's called difference
between full screen and maximize guys.
Okay.
So give me a couple of minutes.
I hope everyone had their browsers
maximized.
Okay, cool. Nice.
All right.
So there's one more method
that some of you guys is to fullscreen.
Okay, so let me do Driver dot manage
window that fullscreen.
Okay.
So let me actually common this out.
Okay so let me run this and please
take a look at the difference guys
what can you notice in here?
I hope this is going
to a full screen in here, but let's see.
Okay. Launching this.
Okay. Nice.
So what did you notice on this screen,
guys?
What happened?
Full screen occupies the whole screen.
Absolutely right.
So you don't see the euro.
You don't see your bookmarks
you don't see the tabs.
Right.
So when you do maximize,
the browser only gets maximized
and not the the website.
Right.
When you do maximize, you can see a tabs,
you can see a euro,
you can see your bookmarks, you can see
everything for your window right.
So that's why you can just see
the difference between
full screen and maximize, right?
So this is the difference
between full screen and maximize.
Any questions on that, guys?
I hope that's clear.
Any Okay, sounds good.
So now let me go to the class
notes in here.
All right.
So now let's go over the get method
and navigate method.
Okay.
So what was the differences, guys?
What was the difference between get
how can we open a few tabs?
We will be going over those
in the next classes.
Okay.
So Navigate will let you go back
and forward and you can refresh, right?
So navigate can
move back
forward and refresh.
Right. So this is one.
So there is two more differences.
Get and navigate.
Okay, So get
method will be waiting for your page
to fully load.
Okay.
So get method will wait for for the page.
Like let's say if you
if you're navigating to Amazon you can see
that it's taking time to load all the
all the
the whole page right it's spinning it
spinning for a couple more seconds
until the whole page is loaded Right.
So get method will wait for that
automatically
until your page is fully loaded
and navigate will not do that.
Okay,
so let me put it here.
Get will wait for the page
to fully load
whereas
navigate
on that.
Okay.
So this is
this is another difference
between get and navigate.
Right.
And there is one more difference
between get and navigate
that get will not keep the history off
your browser and navigate well.
Okay, so get
will not keep the history
of the
browser
or not open date.
Well okay.
So that's why that's why
you can move back and forward
by using navigate.
Okay.
So if you don't have any history,
you won't be able to move back and forth.
That's why I get doesn't have it.
Is that clear? You guys?
Any questions on this?
Okay, cool.
All right.
And then we talked about clothes
versus
quiet.
So clothes
or clothes,
the current tab
and quit
will cook the whole
browser.
Okay.
All right, guys,
any questions that what we've done
so far
and ran will wait
until Yeah, we'll
we'll be getting some challenges, guys.
Okay.
It's not that hard it
you just need to study and they'll and
it's it's all straightforward
you can see it's simple English guys
navigate get right get the care
and you're all refreshed back and forward.
It's all
it's all it's all simple English
in comparison, in comparison to Java.
Right?
So when you look at Java,
you won't really understand
what is going on with hash sets and maps.
It's a bit confusing
until you get the logic.
But here it's simple English, so
selenium is not that difficult.
Okay. All right.
So there's one more thing
that I want to show you guys.
So whenever you running your test cases,
okay, guys,
so whenever you're running your test
cases, you
most of you guys are getting errors.
As I saw, there was a lot of errors today
where you
some of you guys can import anything
or some of you just give it a different
error path for your chrome driver.
Right.
So what I suggest to you guys is always
you run your automation whenever you run
your automated test cases.
If you get an error test,
please read that error.
Okay. It simple English as well.
So let me do one error.
Let me make an error in here.
Okay. And let's get something
in here.
So let me run this.
Okay.
So as you can see, this is not correct.
Right?
So I just I made a mistake, right?
I made a mistake knowingly.
So let me run this
Let me run this in here and see
what's going to happen.
Is it actually easy, Asghar is.
I don't know.
Well, it's always easy for me as well,
so it's probably
both.
Okay, now, guys,
let's take a look at the error.
It says exception in thread main.
Okay. Job blank. Illegal state exception.
That's fine. Okay.
We don't have to understand that.
But now let's take a look in here.
Driver executable doesn't exist
and it gives you the path, guys.
So it tells you that the driver
you just put in here, it doesn't exist.
Okay?
So that means that you put the wrong
the wrong name in here
or you specify the wrong folder at all.
Okay,
So you can actually click on this one.
It's going to it's going to get you
to the line number ten.
But the main error is right here.
Okay So, guys, whenever
you have any exceptions, any errors,
do not be afraid of those errors because
you will be getting a lot of those.
Okay.
So try to read what is going on.
Try to look at what line it's happening.
Okay, so this is simple English
and we know what is going on in here.
So you just need to do what's called
you just need to fix the
the path in here and.
It should be fine.
Okay.
And then
let's put the full screen
versus maximize maximize.
Okay.
So full screen, right.
Why? It's showing
all these are the lines Because
because here.
So it's not only
these errors are coming,
you see from the chrome driver,
from the chrome driver service.
So these errors are coming
from the libraries that you imported guys.
So these errors are coming from selenium
libraries.
Okay.
So in ideally so ideally.
So there is an hierarchy.
Okay, I'll show you the next class,
the hierarchy
of the chrome
driver and web driver and everything.
So that you can see
all the all the hierarchy, how it goes.
So whenever you import a library, it's
not that just one class, right?
One library may contain hundred
classes, one library may contain ten.
It's up to the
it depends on the library import.
Okay.
So in this case, we have an error
about the what's called about the path.
So it all all these are coming from chrome
driver driver service and all
other classes that
are inside the libraries
that you import it.
Okay.
All right. So screen versus maximize,
let's put it maximize
will maximize the
browser
and will not
and let's say
and you'll
still be able
to see your
tabs and bookmarks.
Okay.
Full screen
will maximize
the whole web
application.
Okay.
I hope this is clear, guys.
It's not working for me.
It just freezes
these is something we're probably I'm
not sure actually,
I haven't really seen that issue before.
So if you do full screen, it freezes
that.
That is weird.
It freezes your execution.
Josef, is that what's going on?
Oh, it freezes the execution.
Now, that is weird.
Okay, I haven't seen this.
Yeah, that's why
I forgot to mention
that full screen is not that used.
Okay, so maximize is the most used
method to maximize the screen to work on.
Okay.
All right.
I guess any other questions
on what we have covered
so far?
I hope you guys are having fun. It's
what selenium integrating with Java
right today.
So very cool. Okay.
Okay, that's good.
That's good, guys.
Um, we will be doing more fun tomorrow.
Okay.
So we will be actually
clicking on everything.
We will be typing on the web pages.
Okay.
So, so
we're going to have a lot of a lot of fun,
guys.
Okay. Yes.
I mean, we got it's
going to get harder and harder, guys.
Okay.
But the main thing for
you guys is to note Java.
Okay?
So if you know Java and you know
how to build the logic with Java,
Selenium is just easy.
Maximize.
Sure.
Okay.
Okay, guys, any other questions?
Any other questions
that you guys want to ask?
It doesn't have to be selenium guys,
since we have 15 minutes.
If not,
we can.
We can wrap it up.
Oh, do we have a homework?
That's a very good question.
Okay, let me see.
I forgot about that.
How do you hack Google?
We can't for now.
Okay, let me see.
Yeah, there's.
Okay, so I don't have any homework
for today's class,
but I will have homework for tomorrow.
Okay, so tomorrow
I'll give you two to homeworks,
which you will have
a lot of different practice.
Okay, so
you only need to have Jeff Bezos
his account.
Okay. Good luck.
Good luck with that. Uh,
yes, I will.
I'll push this code in GitHub, guys
but seems like I'm
not able to find the the password.
So I asked Samir for this,
so I'm waiting for the password.
So once I get that password,
I will be pushing everything to the
new repository and I will send it to you
in the course announcements.
Okay.
And for, for the slides guys,
I will be uploading slides in canvas,
but I don't have the password for canvas
as well, so I'm waiting for that.
Okay.
Once I get all that information,
I will upload everything, push the code
and I will
I will notify you guys and course
announcements.
I will be your instructor
for all the selenium classes. Yes.
Correct.
Okay.
If can we create a program
where we can purchase things?
Yeah, you can. You can.
But it's, it's going to be in the later
classes.
Okay.
So let us let us learn
how to perform actions on the web pages.
Then you should be able to do it yourself.
Okay, so that's easy.
That shouldn't be really big deal.
Class two type. Okay. To type.
Okay, sure.
If I give you.
Okay.
Sounds good. That's okay.
So let's do this guys thing.
So let's have 20 minute breaks.
Okay.
15 minute and actual break.
5 minutes for you guys to type.
How about that?
So that way
you guys can type in in 5 minutes.
It shouldn't be really big deal, right.
And one minute to send them.
Sounds good.
That's a very good plan.
I like that.
Okay.
On tomorrow's
agenda, guys, So please take a look at
what the web element
is and please take a look at the locators.
Okay.
Locators and the element
is, is your full screen area.
Okay?
Well, yeah,
this is the time out exception. So
this is really weird.
I've never seen this before.
I'll take a look at this issue.
Okay.
I'll take a look at this issue
and see if I can find anything on the.
Yeah, for now,
it doesn't seem like it is obvious
because I haven't seen this issue
before, so.
Okay, guys,
So seems like there's no questions.
So I'm giving you ten more minutes.
Oh, the next class is agenda. Sure.
Yeah, sure, sure, sure.
Yeah, we'll do that.
Okay.
After right after I finish the class
alkalosis and of course, announcements.
Okay.
All right, guys, I hope you had fun.
We'll have more fun tomorrow.
Okay.
And I'll give you a lot of homework
tomorrow.
So please take a look at the Web
elements and locators for tomorrow class.
Okay.
Great effort,
everyone, And I will see you tomorrow.
Okay.
Thanks, everybody, and have a good night.
Thanks. Bye.