All right, guys.
So today for us,
we will start with the recap
what we did in the last class.
So the very first thing
which we were discussing in the last
session was reading the data from Excel
by correct.
All right, guys,
what was the problem with data provider?
What was the problem with data provider?
Why have you switched on to the Excel?
Why are we passing their data?
Got it. Right.
So the volume of data
basically is the problem,
the volume of data.
If it is big,
if it is large, data provider
cannot handle this correct.
Good morning, Anna.
So in this case, when we have our data
in large volume,
we need some other source.
We can not proceed
further with data provider class.
In that case,
we always go with the Excel file.
So the setup is we keep our Excel pilot.
One place
and then to read this Excel file,
we write one dynamic universal function
irrespective of number of rows,
number of columns, number of keys
and values
in the Excel file, Correct.
So now whenever we talk about Excel file,
right, we write a universal function.
Doesn't matter how many keys and values
we have,
how many rows we have,
how many column we have.
Right?
We can read any kind of data from Excel
file with the help of just one function.
Hello, Jose.
Hello.
So if I open my utils
there.
You see,
this is the function we have written right
where we were opening the workbook.
Okay guys, I told you one more thing.
The two formal topics are
what are those two formats?
The extension. Yes.
Dot Excel
six is the one in dark excellence.
The second one.
So now if you guys are using Dog
Excel six,
which workbook
and which library you are pointing to?
If you are using Dog Excel as X workbook,
which library access F,
and if you're using dark excellence
extension,
then which one
are it at?
F right.
Not except it is
edge as F and X is separate.
These are the two libraries
you generally deal with, correct?
Yeah.
When you are dealing with dark x and six
extension x
and fighting and dark
Excellence Excel file extension,
it's already here.
It's already here.
If you see right now,
I already put it in the
this is the new what extension.
Right. We already discussed this
and I can see this.
All right.
Now to deal with the Excel file.
The function
we have written in that function,
are we relying on number of lines?
Are we the number of games
are be relying on number of values
or something
or my function will get every data.
I'm not relying on anything.
My function is a universal function.
It is not relying on the size of file,
on the size of data or on anything.
You just store
your values in your Excel file.
And my this function, my
this function will read all the data
from my Excel file and will provide
me who used in Java classes.
Correct.
So that's what we did in the last class.
And then we parsed we pass this data
from there from R method,
right from our test case.
And then we have read this data
when we have read this data,
we have used it to create new employee.
That's what we did in our previous class.
Is it correct?
Right?
Student Are you getting what I'm trying
to explain what we did.
It is just static get Right.
That's what we did in the last class.
Fine.
So now the task which I gave you, right,
Let me open.
Come on. Fine.
So what was their task?
When you go and when you try to add
some employ rate, let's say you're
trying to add any employee, but the first
name, they'd say, I'm writing
this and last name also
this.
And when I create any user name,
nobody is.
Nobody is going to do it. Now.
I will do it for you.
So let me create one user name.
So I'm saying user name is
now normally it was just a task
I gave you, Right?
Anyway, I'm going to cover this here.
I just told you. Right.
So it was not a profitable homework,
you can see, but it was just I just wanted
to check your coding ability.
That's the only thing.
We will do it.
We will do it now. Like the task.
All right,
So now I am going to give the name.
Let's see
this one and password is
well, fine.
So now, if you guys see
what I'm going to do here is
when I click on same option,
When I click on same option,
can you see this employee? Right.
This employee increased engagement.
Mike employee generated
I will captured this employ it
from personal details speech.
The fourth thing
let me add one employee right.
Which user name is not created already?
So let me take some user names
something and I know I'm going to use.
So let's see, I'm going to write one.
So when I create this,
it should clear Now you do that right now
from this page.
From this page, what we will do,
we will capture this employee, right?
This employee,
we will capture the first thing and then
and then we will go onto this name option
once again, right from Pim.
Option go to employee list.
In this employee list,
in this employee ID in this employee,
we will use the same employer ID,
which we have got from the right,
which we got from there. Why?
Because we need to capture the employee.
And then if I click on this search option,
see guys, I created an employee,
I captured that employee ID
which was generated here.
I copied it from runtime only.
Right.
I'm not passing anything in my script.
I mean, I'm not going to pass anything
in my script.
That employer I.D.
we captured, we put it here.
And when I click on Search option,
tell me how many pools it should written
against this employee ID it should return.
How many points? Just one.
Just one. Correct.
And and if you see here it is
getting it is giving me what employee
81st and middle name and last name
correct?
That is correct or not.
Now this data, what I can do basically is
I can get this data the first name
relevant, last name from where
we are already passing this first name,
middle name and last name in our script.
Right.
So when we are passing this data
in our script, what we can do is
we can get the data
from this particular row, right?
We can get the data
from this particular pool
after searching this, whatever
the data is available,
I will get this data from here
and then I will provide a solution.
I will put a solution that, hey,
from my Excel file,
the first name, middle name
and last name is this.
I am using this post
name with the name Last name
to create a new employee
against this employee.
And then when I'm searching,
when I'm searching with this name
employed, it should give me the same data
because it might happen
if there is a glitch in the software
that you are trying to add one employ.
But when you're adding the employee
right against one
employee ID,
it might give you some other user,
it might draw some exception,
it might draw some X, Y, or Z data.
Right?
So this is a clear verification
and validation, correct?
Correct. Correct.
So from Excel file,
you will get one entity
and the second entity we are taking from
here as a search, it isn't
got the concept.
What we are going to do now based
students, everyone got the concept.
What we are going to do. So.
So now let me go into our code.
Here we are, right?
So we want to tell this point
after clicking on Save button
right after clicking on Save button.
Now I'm going to change
just one thing in this code.
What one thing I'm going to do
is can somebody tell me
I have to get
I have to get the employer ID, right?
So if I go if I go on the page
right on this employee page,
where is my pages?
If I go in my own employee page
right here, here,
I can give one more thing
I can add one more thing.
Which will this
tell me the employee ID like employed
from the confirmation,
but it's not going to change.
You see here, that's what
I'm trying to explain when I try to add
employ by default
it is generating employee I.D..
Right?
Can you see on an employee page
only you are getting this employee.
Correct.
And this employee ID is not changing.
This is system generated employee.
So from here we can capture this data
and then and then on that page we will go
and we will search
after getting successful message
right.
Is getting my point.
Now tell me now, tell me one thing.
Yeah.
Sometimes you generate, but the actual
functionality of application stays right?
It should always generate
it should always create a unique employee.
Okay, so let me find it.
Can you guys didn't notice
the look that I can find from you?
Can somebody tell me what is the location?
I can buy it from you
I.t. But I have name as well.
I have value as well.
I have ideas.
Okay, you're seeing it.
So let me take it point
on which I should have based.
I should ID on which page
and employee page dashboard page
log in page
an employee page click.
Let me go ahead and do it.
So I'm going to see an employee page here.
This is the I am writing the element
and then I'm writing
employee
Correct.
Now, now, see,
now when I'm coming here on my test,
write on my test.
First,
let me check whether I'm able to access
this data in this page or not,
whether I am able to get this I.D.
here or not.
So to do this
right to do this, I'm going to write here
on my an
employed page, don't employ 80.
I'm getting I'm about to get this employee
correct.
Fine.
Now I want to store
I want to store this employee 88.
So let me create one variable.
So I'm going to write this string, right?
That is what we need.
What we need
from this particular location,
we need what
next?
What can you see here?
I have one more thing.
I have one more thing here.
Can I take the value also?
Yes, because if you remember
the attribute, right,
if you notice color coding part,
if you know the color coding.
But what does it brown color indicates?
What it indicates is brown color.
Is it attribute?
Is it tag?
Is it value?
Is it
what is what it is attribute? Correct.
The brown color.
So now when I can clearly see
that my employ ID is in numbers,
but it is available
as a value of one attribute.
So is there any method in selenium
which I can use
to get the attribute
of a particular element?
Do we have any method in selenium?
Right,
we have one don't get attribute y value.
Right.
So let me right here. Let me right here
employee I.D.
value I'm going to get
y are employed 80 dot
good attributes.
So what attribute I'm going to pass based
it is value correct.
So now from this line let me right here
let me right one
comment also, Mike, how many days
capturing
employee 80 from system right.
We are capturing it from system
only right.
We are not going to ID anything manually.
Fine.
Now after clicking on same button
after clicking one state
button dates again,
I have to go on to the option first.
Right. I have duplicate option.
Then I have to go where I have to go on
employee list page.
Right. Let me show you from team option.
I have to click this time
I have to click on employee list page
when I come in inside
employee list page right here.
I'm going to search this i.t. Addict
guys, is this correct or not?
So now tell me one thing.
This team option,
this employee list option are available
on which page
it is on dashboard page.
No, it is not on any employee pages here.
This right
this option and this employee list
option is available on dashboard
page only.
Yeah, that's that's completely fine.
We are learning. So it is fine. Right.
So now let me go ahead on dashboard
page and see, do I have the option here?
Yes, I have team option.
Do I have this option
and employee list option?
No, I do not have.
So I have to identify this right
employee list.
I'm getting this I.D.
from here right.
Let me copy this away from you
and I will go on dashboard page
here.
I will add this employee list
option here also.
So I'm going to write as
this part is ID fine.
So it is
employee
list option, correct.
So reduce.
Is everyone following me?
Everyone.
All right,
so now now
let me go on to an employee page.
All right.
Like I said, after clicking on after
clicking on same button,
right to enter the employee I.D.
first, what we have to do,
we have to navigate to
employee list page.
Correct.
And to do that to do that,
what I have to do
first, I have to click on where
again on
on the list
dashboard page start theme
option first, not Dashboard dashboard.
Right.
We have to click on Team Option Direct.
Well,
the first thing is
I have to click on team option
and then I have to
click on from dashboard page
employee list option.
This time right there
I was clicking on an employee button.
Now I'm clicking on employee list option
because my flow is different
after going on to this particular page,
I have to find another locator
that is I have to find another locators
on this page.
Employee list,
which tells me how many locators
I have to find from this page based.
The first is i.t Eugene.
Second is search option.
Also a correct
search option also.
And then the third one is the result
which I'm getting.
Yes. So let me go ahead and do it first.
I'm going to search it.
So it says search I.D..
Fine.
Tell me to do
I need to create new page one
employee list on what?
Okay,
so I'm going to create a new class called
employee List page.
Correct.
And then I'm going to excuse my
common methods. Now,
one by one, all the locators I will find,
but let me copy one from here first
so that I can use it as this index here.
This is my index.
So I'm going to write ID
employee first. Me.
Second
thing is for certain, written right?
So it is my search window.
Let me click here search option.
It gives me it again.
Let me take this ideal
correct
that is
Now why writing this specifically here,
tell me,
why do we need to write this three note
in the initialization of elements
to initialize
all the elements of this page
according to page object model design
by then
correct?
Is it correct? Grace
Now, now, let me ask you one thing
I'm seeing.
Let's consider a scenario
like a test, like a Q with correct.
You have entered this employee, right?
You have entered this employee now.
Now you are clearly
you're searching this data as a Q
If you have if you're thinking, yeah,
that's fine, you can do that also.
Now you see when I'm getting this data
while entering the I.D.,
it might be possible
that the same employee ID
can generate multiple data
if there is a glitch in the system.
Is it possible or not?
As a Q
when thinking of all the scenarios right
now. Now,
if I'm going to take if I'm going to take
just one rule, just one
or just one particular element, is it
just define my entire search criteria.
Tell me
that is getting my point.
What I'm trying to explain,
any one, any one field, for example,
this one or this or this.
But if I'm picking just one field
right after searching, is it
justify my entire criteria? No.
Right.
Maybe I can have two rows,
I can get three rows, I can enforce rules.
I can have five rules. Correct.
So I have to find this locator
in such a way that
even if there are multiple rows available,
my function should be able to identify
this, should be able to identify the data
from all the rules.
So if there is a glitch in the system,
my function will be able to verify that
before
getting my point, getting my points.
So let's try to identify
this locator first for this complete rule.
Let me check
when we are going
inside this fine.
Open it
again.
Opening
it is giving me this idea table, right?
This is the result table.
And from here, if I see right,
this is the body I'm getting.
This is the body body of duty.
But now here I'm getting draws.
Can you see this?
This is the row I'm getting.
That is.
This is the result table, right?
All the results are capturing here
inside this body.
Remember this drink duty.
How many of you guys
are aware of the duty?
Whenever
we try to get the locators of any table,
we use the odd instance law
that is dear state
the rules that actually got it right.
So this is what we are trying to do
with.
Might be we can have multiple beers, but
you see inside one row, inside one beer.
Can you see
multiple columns here? Can you see this
multiple data available?
Right. So do I need to take this?
No, I need to take this out only
so when I get this tier, it will give me
the complete data of all the rules.
All right, let's go ahead and search it.
So I'm going to write double slash start.
Tell me, guys, if I'm doing
something wrong or something correct.
I don't know how to find the data,
how to find the locators.
You guys knows better than me
inside this.
When I'm coming
slash, it says
where we were.
Body rate, right, Body and inside body.
We are getting clear. Is it correct?
One of what I'm getting right now is
just wonderful.
If there are multiple rules,
then what would happen
is if there are multiple rows,
then what would happen with this part?
With this locator?
We will get
will we get just in just a unique element
or we will get multiple elements for the.
Yes, correct. Correct.
Then it will identify the data
for all the rules.
Right.
So right now it is unique.
I'm getting my data.
It means my system is working fine or not
my system is working fine or not.
This working fine.
Let me go ahead.
But this is what we are
verifying right now manually.
Let's go ahead and do it. Wow. Automation.
So I'm going to write a list. Why?
I'm putting it into the list.
You guys tell me where many, many.
I'm seeing raw data, right?
Data from this particular rule.
So I'm saying try to find any make
by dot element.
Sorry, because I'm getting multiple data
from this particular portion.
Guys, how many of you guys got this
concept?
Why? I put it inside the list.
Tell me.
Mm hmm.
Correct.
See, you guys know Java better than me.
Fine.
Now. Now,
you know, through the data, right?
To get the data of this particular rule,
which I have to use,
while you should invite.
Look,
we have just one condition right here.
We have to pass the statement.
We have to pass the logic,
and then we have to pass a logic
we have to use for loop
because iteration requires.
Right.
So I'm going to write here in
I'm going to write in digit
I is equals to C2,
and then I is less than my raw data dart
sized builder time.
I am getting rules. Put it inside this.
Yes we can.
But right now
we don't need to because we are just
going to take the text from the array
and then I plus plus
ideally, guys, listen,
one more thing, right?
You have to send this locator here
first, right on this page,
particular page employee list.
And from there you have to call this.
Okay, guys, this locator idea
you should put there.
Remember this point,
I'm just putting it right now
because we are creating the logic
and then we will switch on
to the next part.
So I'm leaving it on you guys.
Now. The next thing is post.
I have to check
whether I'm inside the loop or not.
So I am writing.
I am inside the new
gate values for
the newly
generated
employee connect.
This loop will give me the data
of the newly
generated employee from the system.
All right, so I'm going to say
whatever that text is available
in this role,
I'm going to store it somewhere.
So guys, tell me, can I use it
a string global to do this part?
Can I use a string or not?
Right. So I will write here
My road8 are dark.
The gate of I.
It means index y is one by one.
I'm going dark.
Whatever the data you are getting,
just give it to me here.
Now my data is available
involved in road text.
I have my data correct in draw text.
So let's bring this data first.
Right.
I'm simply
printing this for my checking rate.
It has nothing to do
with the verification part as of now.
Now, now after this. Because
when I'm searching right
here,
first we click on employee list option.
Fine. We're done, guys.
We must do something.
Tell me what we missed. You
guys.
Can you see we missed something?
Can anyone verify?
The first thing is
I need to search in the employee.
Right.
So to start in the employee,
I have to create.
I have to create the object.
So let me create
the object of my employing
list page
is equals to new
employee list.
Correct. Now here,
if my right employee list
dart i.t employee.
Now tell me guys here
if I'm going to pass this employee
this employee from where I have to pass.
Can you see in our system
only we have captured this employee.
We have captured this data here.
Employee added value.
Can you see it, guys? Only one.
So my best guest is everything, right?
So I'm going to pass this data from here.
Only I'm not passing anything
hardcoded right?
Everything
I'm taking from runtime and I'm passing.
And after this, when I click,
click on this page for software.
Correct.
After such work done after such were done,
I'm getting this data correct.
And now.
Now when I'm getting this data right, I'm
going to right here is my history.
So I'm seeing my
expected data first.
So what would be my expected data
for this employee?
The value I'm getting it from my own time.
This data and talking about this, I'm
trying to generate this sequence now.
This sequence,
can you see everyone, this sequence?
So first
I'm getting my embroidery value, plus
I'm going to provide my 10 minutes
if I want to take my first name,
middle name, last name.
From there, I can take
guys from where I'm passing
my first name and last name.
No, no, no, no, no, no. Nobody is.
Nor we are getting this data.
No, no, no.
See, we are getting this data, raw data,
this road next
we are getting I'm
trying to provide this from my example.
This is for a solution. I'm
trying to get it right.
See this data?
I've already got it.
Yes. Employee information.
This data, whatever the data I got from
this rule, I already got this data here.
Can you see it?
Everyone?
We got this data here.
Now, I'm trying to create a generate.
I'm trying to generate a pattern
the way I'm getting the data
in this raw text, like this
I'm going to generate the data from.
I'm passing this data.
I'm passing this data from my Excel file.
Right?
So just think about it.
Just think about it.
You got this employee a revenue
from your time by your put it here
then then you are going to get
this data from MAP employee dog gate.
What is the first thing you're getting?
You're getting first name correct.
Guys, I'm just I'm
just trying to make this structure,
that structure
we're are getting this data from
because we are going
to compare the raw data.
So we have to make one raw
also because here in the road next,
we are getting one complete
through my complete process post
employ 80, then force, then middle name
and then last name.
So here I'm creating this post employee,
then my first name.
Now after first name,
what is the next entity?
Tell me guys
like me.
Right?
It's mad employee Dark Gate.
I'm going to get my
middle name from here.
And after this, again,
one space.
And the last thing
which I'm going to get is map.
Don't get.
The last thing would be my
last name from here.
Right, guys?
So now if you see my raw text,
give me employee ID,
false name, maiden name, last name.
My expected
data will give me employee I.D.
first name, middle name and last name.
Correct.
These four things,
I'm creating the data in the form
which I am receiving from my application.
Now to me to compare to data.
Now I have more this data
to compare these two data,
what I have in testing,
to enter this data, what I have
a session.
All right,
I want to execute my complete code.
So let me put one assertion There is
what kind of assertion I should pass.
If I want to execute my compute code
of is map
that is map twisting.
Map in is map.
This is the data
we are getting from Excel right?
See the same data we got here also?
Yes, that's what I'm saying.
This is the data we are getting from it.
Simply remember the function
we have written in the last class.
So from there, if I'm trying to get
the data from my Excel file,
the data which I'm passing right,
I have to use my that particular function.
So to do that function,
I have to store this
data.
This is this is the
these are the three details.
Right.
I have parsed from my excel file.
No, no, no.
I'm not going anywhere now
because I'm done with the code.
So now I'm going to explain everything.
Nobody.
Now I'm giving
you time to write everything.
So here, here,
if you see this is the expected data
we are hiding
why we are making these expected data.
Because in the same format,
in the same structure,
we are receiving
the data from application,
right?
We are receiving the data from application
in which for user username
first employ 80,
then first name, then middle name.
Then lastly,
if I'm getting this data in one row,
this RAW is returning me
the same data, right?
Yeah, just a moment.
So when this role is returning me,
this data, I have to create my data.
So in the same for me.
So this for me is giving me the same data.
This employee and first name, middle name,
and then lastly, right?
So that's how I have created this.
My expected data.
There you will
really add a whole new part of code,
right?
I'm just explaining that could only guys
everyone done with this employee list,
which is everyone done with this which
Andre
kind of
Now let me come here
See this is the code we have written.
This is the only code
we have written, right?
So what we are doing
after adding the employee again,
we are going on to employee list page.
I am clicking and entering the employee ID
which I took from the code
only from the system only.
And I'm searching for the employee
when I'm searching for the employee,
it is returning me
unique element in a row.
So when it is returning me in a row
here, right, I'm
getting it into the raw data
in this particular element.
When I got this data,
I'm trying to get every data one by one,
one by one, one by one.
So inside the loop I am putting
if my raw size is more than one,
it will go and capture all the data
and then it will give me invisible text.
So what I'm saying, hey, raw data, go.
If I is equal to zero, it means false
to get the text of this particular raw
submit here. Right.
And then I'm going to bring this data
here.
Correct? That is correct.
So when I'm going to print this data,
this raw text, when I'm going to print
it will print what?
It will print it is this first name,
this middle name, this last name.
This is the data and it will print correct
if you'll see there is no other data
available. Right.
So first name, last name, middle.
FYI, I got this data from raw text.
I got this for me. Great.
As you can see,
it is returning me Employee false name.
It says false name and middle name.
Both of them middle names, this last name.
Now, if I want to verify this data,
it is my responsibility
to create another string which will retain
the same structure of data.
Right.
So the same structure of data
since most employee fine.
Do I have any function?
Do I have any facility in my best
guess that can give me the employee idea
and remain so for every employee,
which we are generating?
Right. Right.
After generating that employee,
I will search the same employee last name,
employee value at the same time.
You'll see at the same time in
this iteration is still I am in radius
and this by loop
still we are working right.
We are adding the data at the same time
updating the data.
We are verifying the data also. Right?
So my employee
I am taking from brand name,
I am putting this posting
from my Excel file by
because this is the same data which
I've just passed to add the employee.
So now for verification
of the employee, also
I'm using my same data, correct?
Similarly, I'm putting my middle name,
I am passing my last name.
So this expected
data string is returning me
the structure
which I'm getting from my application now.
Raw text expected data.
Both are giving me
the same kind of structure, not tell me.
All right.
Actually, we will do that.
Also in Cucumber also will be having
the functionality. So there
there we will do that tomorrow.
We are starting with that,
but I'll keep that in mind.
Guys understood this functionality so far.
The logic which we have written here,
everyone
so far, any question in this part, anyone
know what the problem is?
The problem is there are multiple things
in the framework, right?
And when you try to memorize the things,
you will not be able
to memorize everything.
But I didn't write even a single thing.
And after that, right,
I didn't write even a single word.
I'm just explaining.
So how can you submit I'm going to pass.
No, I didn't write anything.
I didn't change anything anyway,
that's what I'm saying.
Oh, okay. All right, fine.
So what we did basically is
we just added these two fields.
First thing, what we did is we added this
is employ 80 search button first thing.
Second thing is second
thing is on dashboard page.
We added this employee list option, right?
This employee list option
because we need to search the employee
and to search in the employee.
We have to go on employee list, but then
and then in an
employee test, we added this data.
We added this data because on
clicking after clicking on employee
list option, we will add this employ ID,
we will search, we will click on search
button and then we will capture the data.
After searching. All right.
So we are capturing the data
after searching.
I think.
Yes, Yes. That's what I'm seeing.
We are finding this employee adoption rate
that is also on this page,
an employee page here.
This one because there is logic.
The reason of adding this employee ID
locator is
we need to get this locator from runtime.
We need to get the data,
the value of this particular field
from runtime, Right,
Because this is system generated part.
Okay.
So we need to get the value
of this particular portion.
All right.
All right, guys.
Yes. Correction. Correct.
Correct.
Exactly.
I think this is the last part, right.
Which is hard.
And I'll put this to three
very easy topics and then we are done.
It's like that, guys.
Now, tell me, is there anyone
who didn't understand this part?
Is there anyone who didn't
understand this part?
Why are we doing this?
How are we writing code like this?
What this code will work?
How this code will work?
Is there any question like
this from anyone?
Students
graduate.
I've got to
employ list
here in the employee list page.
So the on dashboard page here,
Stephanie The moment I execute this code,
I will commit everything
in the repository.
You guys can simply take the pull
of my code
and every single thing
will be available in your machine.
Right after execution.
I will commit this code in between
the class.
Don't worry about the code.
Okay? Yeah.
Yeah, I will.
I will do that. It is in my mind.
Do worry about it.
I will do that for sure.
I'm just trying to explain because still
this assertion part is yet to be done.
Right.
If you'll see,
I didn't put any assertion part here,
so we have to add a section, but also.
All right.
So there is now, shall we proceed
further the solutions here?
Fine. Okay.
Now tell me, guys, why do we need to add
soft positions and not hard positions?
Where do we need words of soft position?
Exactly? Because we are adding.
We are adding.
How many employs one employ to employ
three employ maybe four or five employees.
Right.
And when we are adding multiple employs,
if we put high distortion
and if error comes in,
the first iteration will allow our
execution to proceed for that
hard decision.
Allow no right.
But I want to add for all the three
employees and indeed I need to report.
Right.
So which one is the better approach
going with how the solutions are going
with softer solutions?
Soft one. Correct.
So let's define softer solution,
right?
I'm going to write before the attrition.
I'm going to write here
where I've created all the objects, right?
So I'm going to write soft
assert
is equals to new
soft percent, correct?
Correct.
Student's
on this line.
On this line.
I'm adding a soft position. Why?
Because I'm going to use this
soft assertion in my best guess.
Right?
So if someone is writing the code,
make sure we are this soft assertion by PR
to verify their data
for every single employee.
Right now, if I want to verify this for
every single employee, what I have to do,
I have to go in my best case here
and I have to write here
soft assert or dark assert, assert equals
so true.
Assert equals right.
And we are comparing what doing Page
two by two character long chart by what do
is string.
So let me write it strings. Okay.
Which one?
The first one draw data Root text
is what we are getting the raw text.
Shetty The raw data is the data
you are getting
and converting it into the text,
right? See
here you can you see it is
what every single row you are getting
and you are taking get extra method
and then you're putting it
your text, right?
So this is the final output
you are getting.
And then we are comparing
this raw text to home
based.
What is the second entity expected data?
Correct.
So let me write expected data.
Is it correct?
This is my for loop.
This is my iteration which I completed
and here after iteration here
I'm going to write.
Then media is to get collective report.
Who get the collective report which method
I have to use in soft position
as the last statement of my best guess.
So I'll start dark
aside on
is this correct?
Their data.
Their data,
which we have got is the actual data.
So the actual data is the raw text, right?
Yes. Outside the loop. Correct.
Because we got the collective.
We need to get the collective report
outside of the loop
right.
See, expecting it
actually means the one thing
the one thing you're expecting
from the application
to give you another thing,
you have something in your hand
right now when you compare
that this is what I'm expecting.
This is actually what I got
when this actual and expected
both are equals, then
I can see my verification and relation
check points are done
connect two entities.
You need the one entity you provide
another entity application provided.
Compare this to introduce
together. Got it.
This is what we call a solution.
What one type of solution?
Another solution is whether the field
is available there or not.
We call it a side
not assigned to true means.
We are checking the existence, whatever
we are seeing, if it is benign or not.
If it is denied, then a solution fine.
If it is not benign, a solution is passed.
If it is agreeing with our statement,
a solution is passed.
At the same time.
If it is giving me some value
and I'm expecting some value.
So this expecting value in actual value,
both are equal,
then we a solution is passed.
This is what we call assert equals.
Correct? Yes.
I did this full line in my code.
The first one is right
after starting the employee
got their data
and as the last statement I put aside all
that.
But now you got the concentration. If.
All right.
So now, guys, so far, everyone
clear?
Students Andre, Anna, Mike
Great.
Now what is the next thing
we have to do before proceed further?
What is the next thing we have to do
to update the data in Excel file?
Right.
This is what we have to do.
Okay,
let me check that.
The 19
guys, please don't use this data.
Okay? What data? I have changed.
Please don't use this data as of now.
Please. It's a request.
All right, let's try to run this code.
All right, Mike. Now you don't use it.
See, I'm just trying to execute this
data this time.
Now you'll see my system
performance is enhanced, right?
Everything is working smooth
because I got new system.
So the first thing is, guys, what?
The very first thing is to
add the employee, right now
after adding the employee
after hitting the employee,
maybe we have to provide some weight
because it is taking time.
It is searched with this particular I.D.
clicked on search option right,
right now see it give you this data right.
Then the second part.
The second part.
Yeah, correct.
Of because so many people are executing.
That's why
might be
the issue is with the application
file size exceeded.
All right.
Maybe we are using the file size
but still see it is starting their data.
Right. It is starting the i.t.
It when there click on start option
and give you just one line of eight.
Again the third data,
even if the assertion failed,
that is fine, but still
we are able to get the data in the room.
We are able to generate this
data and I will show you the log
also where we are getting this.
That's why we put that line system
down, out and in and passing
and printing the raw text
so that I can show you.
Fine.
No worries.
Let's see.
Can you see it is giving me this data.
You guys
see this is employee
first name, middle name, last name, right.
It says See all the assertions B
we parsed Anna surely Ricky
it says Anna Jack B were this system
got the data
from somebody explains the employee here
also see this I.D.
it says black Malia Olin
this is their data.
We passed the expected menu.
But what we found in terms of raw text,
we found this employed
if same John James Carter.
Right.
Similarly for the third one, also,
we send this data, but we got this data.
But but is this the logic correct
or not to verify the data
while getting the employee
ID at one time from the application?
I hope guys understood the logic.
The logic which I put.
Yeah, correct. Correct.
But how many of you guys
is still having any issue
when investigating
this particular piece of code?
Now ask me,
Jamal, is it clear?
Yeah. All right.
No, no, we cannot say this.
Anna Andre Olena Verdu.
Why you guys are so silent today.
All right, All right.
Million employee list page.
Okay.
All right.
Correct. But
I hope you guys are understanding, right?
The logic.
You're understanding
what you will get for sure.
Code is not a problem
almost matched
operate.
Yes, I can see that numbers are missing.
All right. Good. Correct.
Got it.
All right.
So now,
now everyone is done with this part.
Okay.
Is everyone done this?
Let me commit this content.
10232021.
This is the correct date.
No, we are creating the new project
from scratch tomorrow.
Don't worry, we will do that.
We will going to create a new project.
Don't worry about it.
All right, guys.
So code
has been pushed right into the repository.
Now the new code is available
in the repository.
Whatever the code we have written so far,
so far, whatever the code we have
written, it's already available.
Great and great.
So now,
now the next important point is here.
Now let's talk
about another important point.
What is that?
We are executing so many things right?
But what is the proof
that we are executing this?
What is the proof we have?
What is the best way to get the artifact?
What is the proof we have right now?
All right.
Where we have reports
in our framework, do we have any report
as of now?
Right. So that's what I am saying.
Mike, do we have any reports right now
in our framework?
No. So very, very.
That's what I am saying.
Émilie will report FEMA report extent.
They will report anything.
We do not have anything correct.
Because.
Yeah, because we know already how to add
listeners.
How many of you guys are still remember
I tested this interfaces,
we implemented that listener.
How many of you guys know that? Correct.
Everyone
knows it because we already did it in.
While when you are learning
testing as a tool,
we have gone through that particular
concept of listener from test.
And now let's go a step further
along with the listener, right
along with the listener.
I'm going to provide a screenshot as well.
What is the need of screenshot? This
now this time.
This time when my listener provides
everything grade with the test me,
whether it is parsed or their test name,
whether it is B
grade, because now
you are getting the updated data.
So it is saying it will be overwrite
your data so fine because you might
have changed something in your data.
Right.
And when you take the pull, it will take
the updated quote from the system.
So yeah, that is fine.
All right.
So now
as an artifact
to show trade, as an artifact to show,
if my best guess is passed,
at which place it passed,
when my best guess is based on
which point it failed.
Right?
These are the things these are the things
we need to implement in our project.
I want to show every single thing
in a sequence in an organized manner.
Right.
So similarly, I'm going to provide
one place in my framework
where I will keep all of my screenshots
this getting my point.
What I would say to my listener.
Hey, listener, go ahead.
If my best guess is parsed,
give me the best to me.
Along with the test name,
take the screenshot
after taking the screenshot
of the story, take one piece.
Getting my point
is getting the concept.
We know already
what the listener does inside this.
Thus we are seeing the screenshot
also whether test gives his boss
or my best guess is well,
you have to take the screenshot
and then you have to store it
at one place.
Correct.
To do this.
To do this,
what I have to do is force thing.
I have to write one function
to take this screenshot.
Correct? Correct.
I have to write one function
to take the screenshot,
which will take this screenshot
for all the all the best guesses.
Right.
So tell me if I need something
which I would be utilizing
throughout my project,
throughout my test cases.
If there is a need of a function
like this, where should I
read that kind of function?
Well-tolerated function based
students
in common methods.
Right?
So let me open my common methods.
Right.
All right. We have so many methods.
Let's write another one here
then we guys, What might this method be?
Static or not?
Let me take the name of Take
screenshot.
Right, guys.
So I'm seeing I'm seeing in my screenshot
right
guys, tell me when you are learning
this dominion,
right when you are learning this selenium.
Yeah. Correct.
What is the method
of taking the screenshot?
So the method is t is is equal to
y is. I am not using new keyword.
Tell me
why we are not using new keyword.
It's interface. Correct.
And to use the interface
we cannot create the object.
So I'm going to write here.
Fine.
Because I need this by the source file.
Right? Why?
Because I want to store it.
So I am saying take a screenshot dot. Get
get a screenshot as
as I'm going to take is output
type dart
file.
I will tell you write this code.
Let me imported first.
Now tell me is this two line says
take the screenshot first.
When you take the screenshot,
what kind of file you need, whether it is
a pdf file, right or it is jpg
file or it is jpg file
or it is something else.
Right?
So you need to define the file papers
or not.
Right.
I hope you are understanding this code.
The code what I've written so far.
Okay, let's proceed further
then I'm going to write file
your case indicates
why I'm going to write file.
What is the reason?
File Utilities value
this dummy is you are already is.
You have already done this part
right in your selenium.
Why do we need to write this file
and then dart copy fight.
What is the reason to write this?
Come on. Yeah.
No copy, Firebird.
All right.
Yes. Correct. Correct.
To storage at one particular point.
So let me write source file. Right.
I'm going to put it a new place
to my new file would be would be.
Now I have to Define the place
now tell me whatever the screenshot,
whatever the screenshot I'm going to take,
I need to define it.
One particular place.
So my place would be final or not.
My place would be constant throughout
my project, throughout my framework.
Whatever the test gives this
I'm going to execute, whatever the results
I'm going to get, I will keep
all the screenshots at one place,
not using it, not depending.
It's my framework, right?
So it's your framework.
So you are going to decide, right,
whether it will be at one place
or multiple place.
But when we talk about framework,
it gives us an organized structure.
So what organized structure says,
it says you need to keep
all of your screenshot at one place.
Correct.
So now what we are going to do
is we are going
to define that one particular place.
Yeah, that is another point
we going to discuss there.
Don't worry about it.
We will discuss the other solution
for that also.
So now to define
such parts, to define such parts right.
Tell me which class we're
in. Constants.
So let's say I want to create one folder
here, right?
I'm going to create another directory
because I want to stored it
at one particular place in my project,
all of my screenshot.
So to define all of this, a screenshot at
one place I need to define one directory.
Right.
So let's create a one directory call
the screen shots.
Correct.
This is in my project or not. There is.
Is this in my framework or not?
This is screenshot solution.
It is now.
If I go in my constant right let me right
another point here.
I'm saying
public static final
I'd say stream and then
screenshot, right?
Correct.
Because because it is already
in my project
so system dot great property returns me.
What is this?
The standard gauge
property returns me. What
because
all the values which are final right?
We already discussed this point
earlier. Right?
This is your part, right?
So these are the values
which are already fine.
And you kept them.
You kept them in capital C Now tell me,
why is this system not good?
Property returns me.
What my project. Right?
Where is my current project?
The path of my current project.
So now inside of my current project,
inside my current project,
I have folder.
Do I need to go inside this RC y?
Correct.
I have to write it as
screenshots.
Right.
Why this slash?
Because in screenshots
I'm going to define everything.
Right?
So it will be in this screenshot
of the example being this slash.
Correct.
Let's go ahead.
Yeah, let's
go ahead and use this screenshot file.
But in our methods. Now
back to the discussion.
Again, we were using this new file
to define the file, but now
from where I can get this file. But
constants DART,
it gives me a screenshot file, but connect
can aggregate
of it.
Now I'm going to say
I'm going to say right.
That saved my finally write my final name.
So what would be my file name? Tell me
what would be my file Name it with my find
it would be different every time or not
nice if I don't give my file name unique.
If I don't give my file
name unique. Right.
What would happen?
It will overwrite, right?
It will. All right. Correct.
So let me boss one parameter here
called string.
Finally correct.
This parameter.
This parameter will give me all the times
my file name as unique.
How did I originally
write
plus plus
dark Be in
my file name plus start paginated.
So I'm going to provide s
dorky and g point.
Is it correct?
It is giving me one at us.
Why strike it exception?
Fine.
So let me write Inside Bycatch BLOCK.
So here
I'm going to catch one exception
flying E
and it says Here
E brings to class
this one.
This one, I'll tell you this.
Yes, yes, I'll tell you this.
I tell you just just just a moment.
I will this.
No, now I need
I need one of facility here.
Right? I need one facility here.
That's why I kept it intentionally.
The next point is related to this part.
Yeah, we are doing this.
We didn't get any file name Oxana so far.
We didn't get any.
Finally. Now tell me De is
what you think.
Let's say you are going to validate
for test cases
five test cases then best guess is it
one time, right?
If you're executing
ten test cases at one time,
how many you screenshot
your system will take
in one execution.
If your exec, for example,
let's take a very common scenario right
in your logic test.
If you see here you are providing this
data validation rate, error validation.
How many iterations are there?
Andrey?
How many times
my this test has been executed
four times
now when I'm seeing big defined
name rate of my screenshot, take the fine
name of it for the screenshots
would be having
the same name or not.
So do we need do we need something?
Do we need something that can define
my everybody
screenshot name as a different one
as the unique one.
Right.
We need something like this or not me
right now.
Now things are making sense.
What I'm trying to explain now
things are making sense.
All right, now see, now
see what we are going to do here.
There is a function trait
that is a function
of taking current date and time in Java.
That is a function of taking correct
to date in time in Java.
All right.
If you execute that function,
it returns current day.
It means current year,
current month, current day,
current hours, current minute
current seconds, current milliseconds.
Now, now, tell me one thing.
If I'm going to execute four times
single test case,
are these disk is going to execute it
same time or different times,
even if there is a difference
of milliseconds in the execution time.
Right.
Cannot gone by const IGA.
Is it possible that I saved my function?
They take back the screenshot
when it executed
the exact time included in the fine name.
Can I say this or not?
Create a fine name
in such a way that it executes, let's say
it, 23rd of October 2021 857
8 hours, 57 minutes, 21 seconds.
The second execution, 8 hours,
58 minutes, 23 seconds.
Then the third one 8 hours, 58
minutes, 25 seconds.
It means for every execution, right.
And for every execution,
it will give us a different screenshot
with different name.
Unique screenshots we can pick or not.
Tell me is it possible or not?
Yes, correct. Seconds.
Only seconds.
Let let me show you how
we can do that. See?
So another function I'm to write.
It is public
static.
This function will return me.
Want to get timestamp right?
I'm going to return timestamp from here.
Right.
And the pattern. The pattern
which I will pass.
I will tell you this pattern is you need
you need your time in which pattern
you need your time in which python.
You will pass this python from here.
Once I implement
it will give you so much sense.
It makes so much sense
or date I'm going to write is equals to
new date.
See it says Java u till date. Correct.
So from Java you are taking it. And then.
And then I'm going to formatted it
when I'm returning.
When I'm getting this date, I'm
going to for my day.
Remember, I'm going to write here to
for make that date
according to our choice.
According to our choice,
we have a function which function we have
and even know which function we have.
We have here simple bit forming
SDF is equals to new
simple date.
What is the format that you're
passing it a paper fine.
So it returns.
This function will return your SDF dart
format big.
Now see now see what I'm going to say
here.
This three liner function.
What will it do?
You will pass one python for example.
You are passing the python here.
See here
month date
our minute segments
Milicic is correct.
Let's add
this is the pattern you're passing.
Let's say this is your python.
So once you get after getting the date
what this pattern
does, this template format
will change your date in this format.
It will change your date
in this particular format and it returns
this date in this particular form.
Correct.
So now, now, after when I'm
going to save the break,
when I'm going to save my screenshot,
when I'm going to save my screenshot here
after finally what I'm saying is see
here, I'm seeing
my file name.
You're taking take it. No worries.
After this.
After this, add one prefix and one suffix.
So what is the fixed good time spent?
Now it is asking for python.
So in this method you can pass the python.
So what I can do like with it here first.
Then we need month, then we need date,
then we need hours.
Then we need minutes,
then we need seconds.
Right?
Correct. Correct.
Now this would be your filing space,
your time spent
after this dot being image.
Now tell me when you save your screenshot
in this format.
Menu status screenshot.
What is this going? Yes.
When you save your screenshot
in this particular format,
will it give you unique a screenshot
all the times or not?
Now forced, forced forced.
You guys should write this part.
Now go ahead and write this part.
I know many of
you guys have already written
it will return all the times unique name.
So first guys, please write this to
and do let me know.
I know the code is still small, but still.
Please write it
after 2 minutes we'll be having a break
so you have time to 3 minutes.
You can write it after 2 minutes.
Can you see it now?
All you have to do is set your P.S.
20. Can everyone see the code now?
Complete code
students.
Can everyone see the complete code?
Yeah, sure, sure, sure. No issues.
I will of
should if you see right.
I put the command here.
Let me put the command here
also because it is I think
you guys are already done.
So that's why I didn't
want to take screenshot.
Let me find it to take a screenshot.
Fine.
I come in for both this
and this is.
These are the only two methods
I have written.
There is every one done with this code
writing for.
Is there anyone who has a still
Andrei, Jamal,
Sergey, Mike nor
Anna?
Yeah.
Then that's what I told you already.
Right after 2 minutes
we'll be having break.
So let me confirm with everyone
and then we'll proceed further.
All right, fine.
So now, now, the rest
rest of the part is very easy, right?
Which we are going to do now, the rest
of the part, it is obviously easy.
Yeah, right.
Okay, guys.
So if everyone is done.
Oh, okay.
Or in the north, you are saying?
Oh, okay, fine.
Okay.
Alright, guys.
So now let's take a break for 15 minutes.
Let's connect after 15 minutes. Right.
So Break will take me right here.
Break build 21.21
connect 2121
So before going onto the break,
before going on a break, we were here.
We wrote this two methods, right?
First is for taking the screenshot.
Second,
say okay, we got this time is ten.
Why? Because.
Because.
Correct.
So because we need to generate every time
unique
screenshot name right now let's go ahead.
Right now
we have just defined the methods.
We are not using these methods anywhere.
Correct?
We are not using this method anywhere.
So let's go ahead and try to use this
method enemy, guys,
because I want to get that report
straight.
So which part of my framework works
for my reporting structure?
Giving me the results? Name
every other thing.
Which part of my framework
reporting structure.
We we are missing
one thing here in our framework right now.
What is that, Miss Nuts, guys.
Right.
The first thing is listen,
this correct? Yes.
So let's go ahead and do this
next part first, okay?
Now tell me how
we can create a list. Notice
first if I am creating a list.
Next class, right.
Listener's class.
The way we created.
Remember, I exist in this net interface.
We have created.
Remember everyone
I just list, not interface.
We had implemented that
and when we implemented
we put we call all of the methods
and provided the body to our requirement.
The same thing,
the same thing we are going to do here,
but with very less amount of code
within this amount of code,
let me show you
now, tell me inside you didn't
have to create list nurse or not
which which part suits the best pages,
best guesses utils.
Which parts?
What's the most odd.
No, no, no. No test cases?
No. Make see in your test
gives us your writing
only your test cases
which you are executing. Right?
These are the utilities of your framework.
You will use this list in your test
and do not make symbol.
It means what?
For all the test cases
you will use this listener Correct.
So it will be a part of your utility.
Let me
create one Java class for listeners.
Correct.
Recognize I have created a class
for listeners in my utility.
Now when I see I'm going to use my
I test the listener interface.
So which you and I have to use here
for my listener.
If it is interface
extension,
implements, implements, correct,
it implements it.
Since I
test listeners
correct?
Correct. Yes.
Now see
just two methods.
I am taking just two methods.
I'm seeing if my best guest success
and if my best guess fails escape.
Skip a start and I don't all this
method just two methods
on test success and on test failure.
Right guys?
Can somebody please
bring that code of honor
based on test failure method
from a previous class?
Okay, let me write it
on test
success.
Correct.
Guys, this was the name
of my maternal mortality.
You can check you have already this things
in your framework.
Public void on test
failure.
Now, Now I'm missing one point here.
What is that point?
What is missing in method?
What is missing here? And
Anna,
any idea?
Andre Oliver.
Mike Sherry Bourdieu.
It's about which parameter should index
what I'm asking.
Now you will remember
how many of you guys
did not tell me, right?
We were not adding the result.
How would we get the result?
Guys, are you revising or not?
The previous concepts.
When we were learning this test
as a tool there, we used this, correct?
Everyone We used it or not.
And this result,
this result will give me want
see, this result will give me
the name of my test and every single thing
it will give me correct?
Correct.
So now I'm seeing I'm seeing
if my test success
then give me this screenshot.
So my a screenshot
method is available where tell me
guys on my best access.
I need a screenshot on my test failure.
Also I need a screenshot common methods
so common method start to get
dark.
Take a screenshot correct.
In a screenshot I'm seeing.
I am seeing. Right.
It is asking for final name.
So I am seeing it is.
I don't get name simple this time.
This time
if you see in my fine name. Right.
I'm passing this get name.
After this get name I will get here.
They must be hours minute, second week
finally right with test name
I will get this much timestamp dot being.
Got it. I will show you this same thing.
Same thing I will put for my failure
says events of common method start
take a screenshot in reserved
dark get name simple
now now if you see now if you observe
this to me there are just two methods.
I'm taking dates.
First of all, I tested is
not is the interface.
I implement this interface just for
my test to success and for test failure.
It means if my test is pass,
I'm concerned.
If my test is failing, I am concerned.
I need the result in this case.
Only now, when I'm implementing this
this don't get me
this got get name returns
you the name of your test
which you are executing.
Remember when we were learning
testing is a tool.
We use the reserved door to get name
because you are passing
this eye test in this.
No you're not passing
I tested is that is the problem.
Andrey.
You'll see it is I tested is time passing.
That's fine.
That's what I'm saying.
This is a test listener.
This is I tested is eight different
things raised
and can you please check it in
your machine Also
is this If you correct it right,
you will get that.
Remember guys, when we were learning
that best in as a tool there,
we used this listener's part
and to get the name of the test
are executing the result don't get memory
does the name of your test case
How many of you guys remember this point?
It is I don't get name
it returns the name of your best
guess which you're executing.
Let me open that
that project or
I will show you that project later
that test and you framework
you actually I might have left.
They might be and it might be that's why.
But we have already done this by right.
We have already done this,
but it's not new.
This result don't get name.
The only new thing is this time.
This time along with this name.
I'm taking a screenshot.
Right?
And this name
I'm passing is the name of my screenshot.
Correct.
So now if you go in your common methods
guys, this court understood everyone.
It takes a screenshot and it will give
the name of your file name.
Is this correct?
Now if you go in your common
method, you said here
the name of your file would be file name.
So this is a result. Don't get name right.
Result dot
gig name is giving you this by name.
Correct.
Plus the
space
you book and then you're putting year
month date our minutes against ending dot
BMG now makes sense.
Nothing makes sense guys
when we are creating file
name and then timestamp and then not being
someone was asking why we are putting this
a space in between.
Right. Right.
Just to just to verify.
Just to identify the things.
Correct.
That is now things make sense or not.
Tell me now.
Now tell me what is this
in this method when I'm passing this?
What is this, Andre?
Sheriff, surely.
What is this here under date?
Hours. Minutes.
What is this?
This is the back end, Right?
I want my time in this then.
Because this date, right when I see this
date, return something fine.
Then with simple date for make method
right from this part simple date for me.
I can.
I can edit and I can customize the way
I want to see it.
I can customize it here.
That's what I'm doing. Fine.
So now this method will work
where in my class, this list.
This class is working?
Kind of.
Yes, because it will store all of my
the screenshot method.
Now see now
see everything. How things work.
Right.
It takes the screenshot file
name from here in terms of great wizard.
It will go here and create one file.
This file will go and stored it
here in the screenshot file
and this is on file,
but we have defined it in constants.
Can you see
this is the path available here?
Correct.
Guys understood.
The hierarchy which we did.
All right. Superb.
Now tell me now tell me
from where I can pass listeners
what is the place from where
I can pass my listener Well,
I can pass my listeners from
extremely fine.
Let me open.
Excellent
right where I recklessness inside best on.
I would say this
I would say test
let me write it to your listeners
and then I'm going to write
listener
in is where
my listeners are available.
Is this the correct part
you can start listeners is correct.
Fine, let's execute.
Let's execute
this one log this right, this one.
Why? I'm going to execute this one
less time
consuming, less preparation here.
Correct Notice?
Correct or not
less time consuming plus four.
Now here I have to write groups
smoke
break because I'm going to execute smokes.
I'll make sure that there is no other.
It is because belong to smoke.
I'm going to change for all the smoke.
I'm changing this. A smoke
just for a moment. Right?
Just for a moment.
I'm changing the smoke because I want to
execute just a one smoke here.
Now, see,
package wise, I'm executing my inside.
My best guess.
This package
before and after method.
It should be part of the group are not.
It should not be a part of the group
because we are writing always run
is equal to to
correct
When you say always run.
Yeah, correct.
Then you run
whether on based on the group priority,
whatever it is, as always run,
it means it will always run.
It doesn't matter that your test case
is running or not.
This condition
conditions will always execute.
All right,
So now, now let me execute this days.
So far everyone understood the point
in this point,
everyone understood what we are doing.
How are we doing
what we have written so far?
Great.
Let me implement it and admit I it.
First operation done, second
iteration done,
third iteration done
for preparation, then
best guest post.
Alright, everyone can see it or not.
Destiny Now.
Now let me open a screenshot.
How many of you guys can see this
screenshot here?
How many screenshots
I've got here? Tell me
for right.
See invalid log in error
message validation.
Fine.
Did the same for me.
This is the python guys.
Can you see this face?
This is because we were talking about.
Now you'll see this is the year month,
date hours, minute seconds.
Can you see the difference?
39, 44, 49 people difference.
I came straight.
That is easy to understand
why we have put this time stamp
easier not
students.
Please update your status
whether you got it or not.
Is there anyone who's
still writing the code?
We didn't add
any screenshots to their test.
We edit the screenshot,
we added the screenshot in common methods
is screenshot in common methods
and from there.
Yeah, sure, sure.
See in common method. See?
And I said right.
Can you see this is screenshot file but
static log binder.
No, I'm not getting looks
and I will tell you don't worry about it
all. 21 beam not Benji
are no issues
talking about error
I'm getting warning was the break
all right obscenities
is warning for your unlock for you so
it is nothing to do with your execution.
Don't worry, there is a difference
in between error in warning rate
error means you can not.
Yeah, sure.
This is your business.
This is my business class again.
You Are you calling them all
these big screenshot material
in your listeners?
Are you calling it here?
All right, let's do one thing.
Let's do one thing.
Let me push my code right.
Take the updated code from my repository
and then check
whether it is taking the screenshot on
because it should take
the screenshot.
Right?
Okay. Yeah.
It's just just one more point.
Just one more point. Conceptual
it. See,
I don't have access to my console, right.
I do not have access to my console
and I'm not concerned about my console.
I'm going to verify whether my test gives
this don't feed
this for the screenshots I'm getting here.
This one is screenshot.
Fine.
This to a screenshot is also point.
Right? Similarly
I have for the screenshot.
Now tell me where did the screenshot
to see which one is faster?
Which one is fake? Out of this one?
If I want to identify
which one belongs to pass test,
guess which one belongs to test case.
How can I verify that?
Just let me do one thing.
Let me do one thing.
Tell me.
Tell me here how many?
How many data and validation we are doing?
No, we do not need to work.
We do not need to take a screenshot
method.
We are adding already this right?
In listeners and listeners we are passing
in our testing do not simplify.
So maybe you are not executing
the same test in you.
You have best in your take symbol file
from where you're passing.
This listener might be You're not passing,
you're not executing that one.
Now show me here, Show me
you're passing the listener.
Kirkpatrick Then you're passing this group
also, correct?
Let's check them all.
Let's take a look, check notice.
Tell me. NASIR, one thing.
I'm going to intentionally fail
one best guess, right?
This one, I'm going to fail.
So instead of empty, I'm writing empty.
Simple.
Now Tell me how many test cases will pass
and how many test cases will fail
intentionally.
I changed it.
Three pass. One, three. Correct.
Let's execute.
Let's see
what are saying is correct or not.
by right.
You'll see one fail, three pass fixes.
Correct
Here I can see.
But let's say
I do not have any access to my console.
I'm going into my screenshot
now here it says
for this one, this for
am I able to verify out of this for
write out of this for write in 945.
This one which one belongs to fail?
Which one belongs to pass?
Can I see this?
No. Right.
I can't see
in this case.
What is the what is B Are
output for this.
I mean what is the root
cause of this thing?
What is the solution for this?
B If I'm getting this problem
in my folder,
then what kind of segregation I have
to put so that I can have all the filters
because it passed this test,
because this identify in screenshots.
Can I do that?
Any idea?
No, let me tell you
there is no condition.
I can say one thing, right?
Because see, when we say
my framework is flexible, what does mean?
It means I can tell my playing framework.
Whatever the test gives are passed.
Whatever the test scores are passed,
you can keep all this test
case inside a screenshot
what under past folder
and whatever the
test cases are free,
you can keep all the screenshots
of relative success
under screenshot in free folder.
Correct.
Now you got segregation point
all the past test cases been going to past
folder all the fake test cases.
The screenshots will going to fail.
You're seeing because you did.
Yeah because you didn't provide this.
But that's the reason
did you.
Jesus, did you write this
Because let me show you
in your content.
Did you provide this screenshot
like this here?
Because I'm not sure
whether you provided it or not.
I'm really not sure about it.
If you provided it like this.
Right.
He had.
But actually, if you are providing
like this, this returns, right?
This returns your project current root
right root path and slash.
It means you have a folder with this need.
Yeah.
Correct.
Maybe have put small or capitals
for screenshots.
That's why That's why.
All right.
So now what I'm saying is I don't want
to save everything in a screenshot here.
Instead, all the bars, the test cases
will be available should be available
inside us and all the very best guesses
should be in field.
All right.
How can I do this?
You don't have to do anything in nothing.
Just do one thing.
Just put it here.
Make this fast
right.
What?
Come on, fast.
And similarly, here, be.
That's it.
Right?
No, it's correct.
Don't get afraid of saying anything.
If some idea comes to your mind,
don't get afraid of that.
Just explain. Just tell them.
If we make mistakes,
we will learn more things.
Now, guys, tell me,
does it make sense or not?
This time?
Does it make sense or not?
Should we execute?
Not the only thing
I changed in my existing part now.
Yeah, correct. Correct.
Because I'm sitting here, you just go
it and get a screenshot.
Not all the test.
Guess what? We're inside.
So it will create.
Now see, let me show you guys.
Let me execute it first.
Let me show you this time
the configurations,
the configuration we make this time.
Let me show you.
Fine.
Now, now,
how many of you guys see these two folders
guys?
Can you see these two folders? Now?
Students, where are you?
Now? If I open if I open this one,
it gives me three.
If I open this one, it gives me one.
It means my face just gives goes here.
My positive disk gives goes here.
Correct.
Jamal
Andrej, Anna,
Olena Bourdieu, are you guys.
Yes, yes, yes. I'm reading.
I'm reading.
Nice. How many?
How many of you
how many of you are able to get this?
Yeah, because all of your test cases
are positive.
That's why Anna, if you intentionally fail
the way I fail to one best guess
intentionally, then you will get failed
folder is well, for me,
no screenshot here, so only one find.
All right. So
yeah so
in your
in your list nurse In your list nurse.
What you're doing basically
is you're simply posting this part,
this particular part in your file.
That's it.
Right?
This part and this part just
so that you're seeing with the result,
get an employee.
Go ahead.
If it is bars then created a post.
If it is near, you can safely correct
it. We committed this code again
so that in a timely manner
everyone will get
this code.
Gordon has been posted to the repository
now available of digit code is available.
This case
fine.
So adding this test rate
according to the screenshot popping
into the listener's
posting this list Nurse in your small
Nordic single file
and employed test
fine.
Sure.
Which by this one
the last one for verification.
What rate of you must be?
You must be by something you know
I see this an employee paying
and you're passing this things right?
I need to check on this.
I need to check them
because for sure there is
there is some problem
with passing their data for sure.
So we have to check that.
All right, guys.
So far, so far,
everything is clear or not any
null parsed well
that we have to check that
instead of Melbourne's rate
it should be only paused.
You're posting something else from there.
That's right. Is taking Melbourne.
But we will figure it out.
Don't worry, we'll figure it out.
All right, guys.
Now, now the most important point right?
Let me show you this
So far.
So far, what are the things they are doing
right?
We are executing
right.
We are executing every single thing now.
No more coding.
There's no more coding at all.
Don't about it
now. See
here.
Can you see this symbol point, everyone.
Right on.
Let me take this screenshot of symbol
that could make more sense.
Yes. Now, if you see here
we are
using this bomb Arabic symbol fight.
So we are adding this dependencies, right?
This dependency, this.
Why are we building this
dependencies? This
to use jobs.
Right.
Because we don't want to add
jar files manually.
We have to take dependencies
that will get every single data
from the central repository, correct?
Correct.
That's what we are doing now
instead of me.
One thing when I go here,
when I go actually on my application,
right on my maven central repository
in when right here,
Melbourne
Repository, right
when I write this Maven repository
and I open it,
let's say I'm going to read Selenium
for example, I'm
trying to search selenium John files.
Now tell me, am I the only one,
Am I the only one on this planet
who can access digital files?
Am I the only one who can access this?
No. Right.
You can be. You can also access this.
Someone else can also access
based on what?
X, Y, and Z can also access this. Right?
Everyone can access this or not
static.
Now tell me one thing.
Hackers can access this or not, right
now, people, people
who are elderly, people
who are dealing with sensitive data.
Right.
And who wants to cut up
or who wants to make someone application
can David can access this jar files A lot.
Right.
People who want to harm your application
can also access this repository.
Now, can they inject
can they inject some viruses,
some spyware,
something in your application
by using this job points or more?
If you are using the form,
they're using the simplest forms
and their intentions are not correct,
their intentions are not ethical.
Is it
possible that they can harm
your application easily from you?
They can or not, right?
They can.
So let me let me show you one scenario.
In this case
when I see and then I assume, Evan.
Right.
Remember the concept we discussed? Right.
This is your
this is your central repository, correct?
This is your central repository
and this is your local.
When you need this dingy,
when you need this stingy,
when you need selenium, right.
You just provide the dependency here.
It goes here and it makes it here.
Correct.
Now here, here, the things
which you guys are using here,
the things are dependencies
that jobs in the everything
which you guys are using here,
the Problem is, if there is something
if there is some problematic file
which is coming,
which is coming from this repository
in your machine
and simply you're using this job finds
in your application directly, If you are
using this, then in your application
it will affect it again.
Affect or it might affect
on your system's performance
in your application, security,
on performance and every single thing
of your application.
Correct?
That is the reason why That is the reason
why in many organizations
which are highly secured
in dealing with highly secured application
in data, for example, Jp
morgan Chase, for example,
your Department of Homeland Security,
DHS or Department of Defense, D.O.D.
or Wells Fargo Bank or liable Bank
or any other bank, Great.
When they are dealing right,
when they are developing application,
when they give access
of their applications to their developers
and their testers, their testers
and developers are not allowed
to use this central repository
directly to download
all the data files and dependencies
from here
into their local.
Getting my point
these developers and testers
cannot add any dependencies directly from.
The central repository. Why?
Why? They can they can not add anything
from there directly.
What is the reason behind this?
Because it is a threat.
It is a severe threat to their security
guys.
Getting my point.
So what they do in this case, yes,
doing is already one step ahead.
So what they do in this case,
when they don't,
then they can't add anything
from the repository, right?
No, they have their own repository.
For example,
this is for, let's say, Wells Fargo.
Right.
One client, Wells Fargo,
what you generally do is
the you if you want to add some
you request, you add this dependencies
from Wells Fargo repository.
This Wells Fargo repositories border
connected to the central repository.
Right.
So they take this jar, files this,
get everything and put it here,
make it right free from all the spyware,
from all the, you know, corrupt files
and it will,
you know, this particular repository
will make all these dependencies directly.
And then when you do a request,
they will allow you to add your jobs here,
in your dependencies, here in your diet,
and the admins in your local park.
Got it.
So this is a central layer.
This is the central layer.
Let me show you this part in our
framework also, right.
You see one local repository,
three types of memory repository.
Second, this central repository,
third is remote repository.
Can you see this in the in the slides,
these local repositories,
which one is tell me
which is this local repository
dot in two folder.
Correct.
This is your local repository.
Which one is the central one
right on the web, on the Google.
And then every single thing is available.
This remote one is the repository
that manages by the company's
owned the software. Right.
Who owned the software.
So organization based company builds
repository.
The third one, correct.
Got it.
The students.
I hope you are understanding my point.
What I am trying to explain here.
Great. Let's go ahead
now. Now, So far.
So far.
Tell me, how are we executing our
to get this?
We are making them in a groups right
batch execution.
Okay.
You're not then you will share soon.
You will do it.
Now let me show you right now
what you guys are doing.
This is your Java class, correct?
Let's see
where you're writing your test cases.
So what you are providing,
you are providing your groups correct?
This is what you are doing.
The second thing is your test.
And do not assemble class
in this configuration file.
You are passing your package name
here, write
all the package name inside package.
You are passing this groups here. Correct.
So what it says
in this particular package,
it means this package
based on these groups, for example, smoke.
So based on this group in this class,
this whatever
the test get, those are available,
go ahead and execute them.
Correct.
But we are focusing
we are focusing on one execution point.
I have this MongoDB exhibit here, right?
I have a regression dot exam in here.
Let's see it tomorrow.
I will be having a regression
to smoke to so many exam invites.
So is it one stop execution,
one point execution from where I'm
executing all the things that I'm having,
multiple points of execution.
Tell me
anyways,
is it one point execution
or so many points of execution?
We have
we can execute on in
once the smoke integration?
How how how should integration detect
some of the smoke detector?
How we going to execute
all of them in a single shot.
No group why is is packages
I am seeing integration
the text images are different by the smoke
dot examiners are different file right
now. Let me tell you one important point
we are talking about.
We are talking about all the possible
combinations which we can have
only when only when my this framework
is available in my intelligent ADC.
Correct?
Correct.
You are going back.
I am talking about this.
Regression or submitted is not acceptable.
Let's say you have a smoke.
One smoke to smoke. Three
not acceptable. Fine.
I want to execute all of these three.
So is it one point execution
or multiple point execution?
Multiple points.
I have to execute. Right.
And that too, you can execute
when you have this intelligent ID open.
All right.
Let's say
you are traveling somewhere, right?
And you cannot access this intelligent ID,
but you have to execute
you have to execute all of your script
without.
Even having this particular I.D.,
what is the way to execute your best
guess without even having this I.D.?
What is the way to do that?
This is my question.
Correct.
We have to use now,
but I'm not accessible.
FYI, before going into one segment,
let me just fix my error.
My error was this Instead of empty,
I am putting empty once again.
Correct?
Right.
I put it empty
once again here
just to make my best guess.
Buzzed. Fine.
Now let's go in, run
exam and fight right in this form.
Vertex email fight.
Tell me when we talk about memory.
What is memory?
Let me put it in the notes
we were writing.
The moment someone is what
students
memory is a way
automation tool.
Memories work as a note automation tool.
It is a build automation tool.
It makes your project is a building.
If you want to make your complete project
in a single unit, go build right
This Moment project
will help you to do that.
Right now,
when I say my one project is a whole,
I'm not able to achieve that point,
right?
I'm not able to achieve that point because
I'm having a regression vertex symbol.
I'm smug, not accessible.
I'm having so many other things,
but not a single build
that will I will make from bomb, vertex
and then fight.
Right.
So here, here we have to add one base
what we have to add one build
and then to add it to make that base
we have to add one
in the name of this plugin
to make my complete project as a build.
Right?
And then I can execute everything,
everything from my the next email file.
I have to add one plugin
and the name of this plugin is Maven.
Sure.
Fire plugin.
What is this going to repeat with me?
We are going to add mixing thing. What
is maven?
Sure. Fire plugin cutting. Sure.
If you are a sure fire plugin.
Alright, so let's go ahead.
Let's go ahead and add this surefire
plugin here.
So from where?
From where we can get this guys,
everyone is on the same page
with here.
Please upgrade produced it as fast
so that we will proceed further together.
Everyone can.
Yes. Yes. Everyone.
Everyone.
All right, let's go ahead.
What we have to do, we to open
we have to write here Maven.
Sure.
Fire plugin search
maven should find a plugin, right?
Search everyone. Maven Sure.
Fire plugin
and you will get this sherpa plugin.
Everyone.
Everyone should get this.
You remember that Apache?
Not all are sure. Fire slash maven. Sure.
Fire plugin.
Is everyone able to get this?
This particular screen? Everyone
did now know what it says.
See if you go down.
If you go down. Right.
It says the following examples show
how to use my sure
Fire plugin in more Edmonds.
The used cases,
the first one says using test engine.
Is this the one we are using these
you'll see here there's ten
GJ unit five doing it for order test
skipping, test skip after failure.
Which one we are using
using this DNG simple.
So just click on it
and when you click on it
right, it will give you this spark.
Can you see the spark?
Everyone is just not from this plugin,
right?
From this plugin to this plug ins.
Just copy this.
Right.
Just copy this from
this plugins to this plugin.
Just copy
that is getting it using selectable files.
Just copy this from plugins to plugins
right now.
Go into your symbol pomodoro symbol find
everyone is yet in one great example
after your dependencies stick
Once you're done
with all of your dependencies.
After your dependencies tag, just add
one tag. Go
build, add one bag,
go build a right.
All right
then this part done everyone
now based this plugin inside
the way it is
giving is the error.
What happened?
Just a moment.
Let me go here once again.
At this point,
let me just take it once again
and open Wikipedia first.
I will right here.
And they begin on the
line.
Fine.
Now, now it is not giving me.
And yet it
let me just keep it.
What you guys need to do is just add
this build plugin rate
built in this starting
and in the ending and inside the build.
Put this plugins.
Yeah. Yeah.
We had this dart files.
You have to delete this dot,
you have to delete every one. Yes.
Do we have to do it?
We have to do it
all the time so
I mean if you are going to upgrade
something in your project right,
you have to add the dependencies.
If you are going to integrate
some new feature in your project,
you have to add new dependencies
if you want to do so many other things
right for every single thing,
you have to do it now.
Now see this, guys?
What we are doing here, Right here.
When I'm using this part,
if you guys see right,
it is giving me this read
why it is giving me
the right
how to break from that boundary.
Guys, tell me how to upgrade this example.
Let me go to the project right
where it says
return or click and not reconnect
is till I reopen my.
Yeah, it is working. It is working.
It wouldn't work.
You can try one more thing
instead of in five.
You can try it in four.
Yeah. This highlights remove.
But Jamal, if it is not taking four
and five, begin driving the M for this
3.0.0 slash.
No, it says not found 3.0. 0m5.
That's what I saying, Eugene.
I'm just trying to explain this. Right.
If you guys are not able to see this
M5 right,
just take the M4,
just change it to M4. Right.
And see the moment I took M4.
It is no errors. No.
Right.
So maybe compatibility issue. Yeah.
Four for home in five is working.
You can keep the M5 or who M4 is working.
You can keep M4
are not working in this. Why
M5 is working for you guys?
20 so you can take M5 and
then you're putting this 3.0.0
and hash M4.
Yeah. Find M5 is working then take the M5.
No issues.
All right.
Can you guys try reload the project
from this from here.
All right.
Now just right after putting this M4
here, right.
Just go into Melbourne
and then reload the project.
Can you do it.
If you reload the project right,
it will give you
this dependency part here.
All right.
Because if you are taking this
from here, right, this part
3.0.0 M5 is the latest one
and 3.0.0 M4 is the previous one.
These two things right?
Just M4 M5. It should work.
Are you taking this lead part
inside the plugins and then plugin
take?
All right. So for those
yet this one, it's working now
because you need to refresh,
you need to refresh rate
even M5 is also fine. Correct.
That's what I'm saying.
What you need to do is write
like on your thumb vertex single file.
First going to
this maven reload your project.
It will add dependencies, right?
Reload the project.
It will takes time.
It will take time to add requirements.
It now guys see now I see one thing
it says you install excellent
file, right?
Yeah, we'll figure it out.
We'll figure it out.
That screenshot issue. Don't worry.
So now you'll see here in your mail
it says if you want to execute something,
just add the name of your test in.
Do not single file.
Right.
If you want to execute,
then it says just execute trunk
based in g dot next email like.
So tell me
what is the name of my test in your logic
symbol file?
It surely will will will resolve
this problem. Don't worry
today.
So can I put here?
Can I put here the smoke dot symbol?
Can I do this?
Guys, please reload your project.
Reload the project. Right.
And then reloaded from disk again.
It will work. It should work actually.
Or do one thing. What I am doing.
The one thing what I'm doing.
Maybe it will work.
Could be showing you right now.
Sometimes it
even if it also happens sometimes.
Yeah. Correct.
That's what I'm saying.
Sometimes you get replaced everything.
But it still it shows at a
So my new problem
doesn't exist anymore, but still it shows
and it's like that.
Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
Will see.
Hold on for a moment.
Now if you guys see
if you guys see what I did, I'm passing.
This is not not exemplified here.
How many of you guys can see
this is MongoDB, single party
dry file reload on Andre.
Is it working for you or not?
Great guys. Can you do it?
Going to your file and it says reload
all this one reload all from that is
can you do it?
Click on file and reload all from this one
great strategy.
So I told you
it was just a refreshing issue.
Right?
Do doing
already to that.
We'll look into this, but don't worry
because it says you have to pass your test
in your door.
Take single file. Correct.
Do we have any file with the name?
And you do take symbol here.
Now, we do not have any test testing.
Do not actually we have the smoke,
not somebody or the ignition, not X
and we've got it.
So we had to pass according to our find.
So our file is
is moderate. Extremely correct.
I Bosniak
correct. Not
on M5
is not on M5 means he had a smoker
take civilians to examine files.
You're changing.
Yes for everything.
Yet Virgin has nothing to do
with the fight. Right?
That is virgin.
And this is the file name.
These are two different entities guys.
Remember if M5 is not working.
That's why I said use input.
But still we had to change this
because there is no file
called test
and did not exclude in our project
guys so far.
So everyone reached this point or not
everyone has reached this point.
Great notion so we can change that.
Yes, you have to you have to Oxana
according to your smoke integration
or take similar
you have to change this binding.
Otherwise what would you execute?
Now let me show you how it works
this time.
This time when you say smoke,
not single file.
So your your form not accessible by great
having this
the smoke dot examined
it will go and check.
Do we have any smoke not examined
it says yes I have a smoke protection
well inside this exists.
All right.
Do we have any group
you say? Yes. Small group.
Fine. Which package? User.
Best guess.
Package it will go and check inside.
This gives the gauge how many classes
we have so inside best gives us.
We have an employee does not exist.
How many best guesses
I have belong to smoke?
It's just for point.
It will return.
Therefore it will execute it from here.
It's a one bomb or and file can execute.
Smoke can execute regression can execute
smoke to an executive regression
to and so many other
should it.
That is a part of later discussion.
We'll go on to that part also let's
try to solve one it went right so you see
this would exemplify the smoke detector
symbol we are passing your right one
right
guys, can you see what we are doing
So yes, correct.
We pass the smoke in our Sure. Fire
plug in. Correct.
Now it is making my complete made Why?
It is making my complete build.
Tell me,
what is the advantage of having this?
Remember
when we talk about deployment,
right, when we are talking
about deploying our code
to one environmental exit from best
environmental protection environment
or even from development environment
to pest environment,
who deploy this good
students who deploy the good
developers,
correct developers deploy the code.
Now when they the code before
deploying any code on any environment,
are there any prerequisite?
Are there some prerequisites
that they need to follow
or are checkpoints or their check boxes
they need to check before
deploying the code on any production?
Can they blindly deploy the
code on any environment?
No. Right.
They cannot deploy any code on any mine
without checking.
Right. I'm billion
unless you have to check.
So what what are the parameters? Right.
What are the parameters to check?
So The parameter is
when you make your project as a build.
This build has to be parsed
this way.
There has to be.
Tell me, why is this bill to be parsed?
If the bill is failing,
if the bill is failing,
they cannot deploy their called on to any
and might need
to deploy.
If they're caught on to
any other environment,
they have to make the bait right now.
Let me show you
when we're talking about Maven.
So you see this memory tag.
Everyone can see this memory bag here
on the
right corner.
Students How about others?
Just three or four play.
Just click on it.
Just click on it and you will see here
in lifecycle, in lifecycle, it gives you
clean validate compile, test
package, verify, install, site and deploy.
These are the lifecycles of MAVEN.
These are the lifecycles of memory.
All right
now now
we can test by this builder to exemplify.
We can clean our entire project from here.
We can validate it compile,
we can install, we can verify,
we can deploy every single thing
we can do via
using this simple basic tool and to make a
we have to use this plug in.
That's why we have added this plugin.
Got it, Got it.
Not everyone.
Now let me show you something.
Let me show you something here.
Can you see this target folder?
Can everyone see this target for this
right now? See,
I'm not using my intelligent ID anymore.
I'm not using.
I will use my terminal. Remember
two things.
The first thing is you can execute
everything from your intelligent ID.
Now the state guarantees
you execute everything
without your intelligent,
without your I.D..
How c
I have to go in my project
where these my project exist,
so my project is in it
says new folder testing D framework best.
Fine.
So let me open my command prompt.
Right.
Let me open my command prompt. Once again,
I'm going inside my case directly.
Idea projects.
Then again change directly from new folder
and again change directly
test in deep framework.
So now I am inside my project.
I'm inside my project
using command from you guys.
Mac users can also use this part
terminal, right?
You guys have to use terminal part.
You go going to your terminal
and go inside.
Video project is available,
for example in this location on.
This location, my project is available.
Are you
guys here?
Everyone is here will do wherever
your project is available,
wherever your project available,
open your command prompt.
From there,
let me show you another way
how you can open it.
That's fine. That's fine.
You will get it shrink. Don't worry.
I will show you next point.
Now let me show you another way
how you can open
open your project. Right.
Let's say this is my project, right?
This is my project in my folder.
Just select it and. Right.
See M.B. here.
What You need to see me for Windows users.
I'm seeing interest in there by default.
Your inside your this folder.
Can you see shortcut
by default your inside this folder
should if open your project,
the wherever you project is straight
open your project
on this line just right.
See me on this line.
Just read see and be interesting that
it will open your terminal from here.
So you are already in the repo
directly not
nobody
BLEEP.
Now here the first thing. The first thing.
Remember I have to clean
my project leaks this my project.
When I say clean,
it means all the previous repositories,
all the previous this database
which is generating generated resources
maven status.
Sure.
Fire reports, test classes, everything
I want to clean before execution.
I want to clean all these things.
So I will simply write and we and clean
what I will need.
I will simply write an MBA in clean
and it would successfully clean
my project right.
I will get bin to pass message
right before dark.
Before that to make sure Before
that make sure
Maven is installed in your system.
Before doing this, remember
MAVEN should be installed in your system.
I hope everyone that already everyone
has installed memory in your machines.
Everyone
there is
everyone is having memory
in your machine or not.
All right, let's do it then.
First, let me show you this part.
Open your browser, everyone
open your browser.
Everyone
read and write.
Download Maven, open everyone and right.
Download Maven. Right.
Are you doing it, guys?
Everyone with me.
Oksana. You're doing it. Everyone with me.
Now what I'm doing is doing now, right?
Just go here and download this Bach bin.
Zip, right
for all the users for Windows use.
This means if
everyone
in cities, everyone this builds it
all right for Mac users
or Mac users, I'm writing for
Mac, right?
So installing a bi chain movement
for Mac users, right?
You guys will use this part VR dot
GZ This one, right?
This one. See,
I'm giving you the options also.
Don't worry about it, just target
targeted.
GZ Now you open it, it will automatically
gets downloaded, right?
So when it's downloaded,
it would be like this,
it would be like this.
You will get one zipper there.
How many of you guys
got the zip folder here
after downloading?
It's a small file, right?
Just just right click on this.
Right click on this right
and extract on select extract all
and then select extract
marks.
Just wait wait for a second kind of stuff.
Correct.
So what? Don't open it first. Go back
first.
Go back on this
deep folder and step and right click
and then extract it.
Yeah, just
fine.
If you're using
if you are having this already, fine.
So now when you extracted after extraction
you will get this folder
like this unzipped folder.
How Many
of you guys got this unzipping folder.
Now everyone.
Helena, if it is not unexpected,
I'm afraid whether when we are
when we are going to edit in advance
to system variables,
it might provide some problem.
But yeah,
if it is like this only for you,
if it is already like this, then is fine.
Now open it everyone open it.
You will see another folder here. This
guys are you opening it in this point
when you are getting this bin,
how many of you guys got this bin folder?
Tell me
now in this open
this bin folder also and copy this, but
open bin folder and copy this. But
copying it.
Everyone
now go now going your advance
system variables there is that just right
click on this piece here my computer
going to properties
going to
properties and B
and you see it wants the system settings.
Everyone knows how to create
Java home environment.
Everyone knows it, right?
But we are not going to add
Java environment, right?
We will simply add just click on this
advanced to system settings
Environment Variables.
How many of you was reached in this point
and one system settings
and one main media ones?
And you will get this screen system
variables?
Fine.
Let me do it once again.
Go on to this PC right click
Melia de nada and the
properties
inside properties
going to advance the system settings
in advance to system settings.
Click on environment with humans.
When you click on Environment
Media was here, you will see this plot.
So just select system variables
so far.
Did you guys reaching this point or not?
Tell me, Oksana, what what
what is the problem variables
Don't tell me.
Melia Oxana, you guys got stuck at ABC.
Fine.
Did you was created
this home environment for Java.
Yeah.
Eugene They don't don't don't give the
spoilers You wait for some time, please.
All right.
So advance the system settings.
Click on it. One system settings.
Oxana, click here
can you see
is in one variables days now everyone
people who by people who date these
till this point
I'm telling to them
correct Andre
correct.
Now click on environment variables
and now when you click on environment
variables,
you will see the system variables
here unique to select.
But now everyone reached in this point.
Oxana, please update
nearly a piece of data.
No. Great.
Oksana, what's your status?
You have Russian interface
even I don't know she
my path looks different than yours.
That's fine. That's fine.
So now the point is,
did you reach this point on the variable
here till this point
you guys reached in this point or not?
Tell me.
Fine.
Now click any.
Just select this spot and click
edit, click, edit.
All right.
So this
guys on this screen, everyone
now select this new
select this new and based on the party,
select this new.
My edit is disable.
I'm not sure why it is actually made
with some system issue or something.
Now, just based on this
ended up part of your click on new
and paste the part of your Apache
maven bin folder here.
Everyone did it.
Select this going to edit,
select the new and paste the party
has everyone pasted
the but it will look like this.
Then click okay
click.
Okay.
Once again click.
Once again click. Okay.
And closing.
Then everyone.
Great.
Now now let's open.
Let's open again. Command prompt.
Now let's open command prompt once again.
Now, guys, see in this command bump
this time you have to write in the end
space hyphen virgin
yammer smart time.
Okay, let me give you the link.
Meanwhile,
what you guys have to do basically
see this bin zip again,
you have to download
right into the environment,
but right into the environment pop.
And then here you have to provide these
two women and women
who to provide this bin
falling apart from the terminal.
You have to do.
Let me share this link for me.
Marvin,
where is Mac?
This is Mac.
We open the terminal
switched to the directory
where file is extracted
and use this particular part.
So let me give you this one.
By the way, just to make users rights,
I will give you a base just already.
Let me first finish it for this base
for all the Windows users.
Okay.
Anna, this is your project.
We are verifying Olena.
We are verifying that amendment
is installed or not. Correct entry.
You got the moment now, see,
And your project is available here, right?
This Is your framework available here
just to select here and biopsy
and be just right
CMB here and press into this.
You just need to open
guy's command prompt.
There's the simplest thing
you have to do, right?
Just open the command prompt
and then right.
And we end in the in space hyphen version.
This is the command
to verify whether MAVEN is available
or installed in your machine or not.
So what we have to do, we have to open
command attempt inside the command room.
Doesn't matter where you're opening
the command from, from just open command
prompt and right
and we in space hyphen Virgin three
when you enter it
it will give you this maven virgin
correct.
Well then we are verifying
whether Apache is available or not. But
all right.
So now it means you didn't add
the port correctly.
Means you didn't add the port correctly.
You just need to copy
the port of your Maven radial
bin folder and then you have to edit.
This is the you are available, right?
You can go through that,
you want it and you can simply use that.
You want to build the bin folder, but
yeah, for that.
Eugene For that
what we have to do is we have to
provide this being home also, right?
Without Maven whole,
if you want to simply verify this maven
right slash kill bin trade,
then simply provide the path will be
and then you will get without
creating the home in we full maven.
Okay, this is the difference.
But right now when I'm when I'm assisting
you guys right so similarly
with something right I will but right now
when I'm doing this with you.
So what is the problem
in downloading this things with me?
So you guys in your downloads again,
I'm repeating guys again.
I'm repeating even though you guys
have added Java underscore home right?
In the same way. Right.
Okay, Sheriff, that's why I'm
repeating this is the third time behnam
repeating the same process right?
You focus just for one time.
It'll be more than enough
because this is the thing
you guys have done already for four months
back, right?
When you were editing
the Java Java Underscore home.
If you didn't edit that, I'm assuming
and I'm thinking how your Java is working.
C you have downloaded Apache.
Everyone.
Everyone has downloaded Apache, correct
this Maven zip folder.
Everyone.
Yeah, I know, I know, I know.
I'm talking about understanding
what Jenna
So this is that this time I'm going.
Let's see.
Nancy So now tell me
why is everyone got this zip
folder or not?
The people who didn't get this.
But I'm explaining these things
for you guys.
Once again,
you are getting this the folder.
Not everyone.
Please update the status guys.
No, I'm talking about others.
When you guys got it
just right click on it and extracted.
First we have to extract it.
And when you extract it
right after extracting it, we ask you.
That's fine.
In the end, after extracting,
you will get this folder right.
You will get folders like this.
We just unzip, open it,
go inside the folder.
Yeah, correct. Correct.
And then open this bin in your Apache.
Open this bin folder.
When you open this bin folder,
you have to copy this.
But just copy this part from here Right
now, when you copy this part,
everyone is so far
understood how we can copy the portal bin
folder, every one
to just move this
how we reached this point.
Now, now, when you copied this thought,
you have to paste it somewhere.
Then go on to your this PC,
click on properties
or my computer and click on properties.
You will get this option
advance the system settings.
If you are not getting this option here.
If you're using Windows 11,
we can search it here.
Also, advance the system settings
and when you open it warns
the system settings,
it will ask you for environment variables,
right?
When you click on environment variables,
it will give you this system variables.
Getting this system variable.
We want to
click on environment variables
and then click on system variables.
Inside this system variables.
If you see
inside
this system variables,
if you see you will get this fourth
variable right, this part variable
getting it guys, everyone
this part variable
students
that is till this point,
everyone got it or not.
Now you have to simply edit
here, click, edit
and because why are we editing the things?
Because we have so many parts
already available, right?
So inside editing, right?
The but we have to select this new
and then we have to select the new.
Then we have to select the new here.
Here we have to paste the part
we copied for Maven.
All right. Right.
We have to just based the path like this
I posted on already here.
You see,
I pasted this part already.
Yes. When you do it,
when you do it, just select.
Okay. Okay.
And then we'll find
right now
now simply open command prompt.
Right. Simply open command from anywhere.
Not in your framework.
Just open the command prompt in right here
and we and bash the space
hyphen word in
now everyone got it or not
this opportune moment
experience is everyone got it or not and
all right
okay so now it is working for you.
Great for
is there anyone still inside the class
who is still didn't
get this a patch amendment.
Mark, if you want, I can do it once again.
If it is a language issue, right,
then maybe
I can not.
And when is not a command right?
Because you didn't install it properly
or it looks.
And let's connect after the session
and I will install it in your machine.
Okay, I will do that.
Rest all of you based on able
to do whatever
to do it.
There
is this update the status.
Is there any other one
who still have an issue?
All good.
Correct.
All right, fine.
Now, now let's open
let's open
your framework in common with them.
Right.
So I already told you how we can open it.
You'll see here it gives you this
where your framework is available
right in your terminal.
You can open this part, right?
I told you already how you can open
simply just open command or terminal.
The city
I'm using inside my idea projects
my project available in new folder.
Inside this my project is available
in Destiny framework.
This is my framework available.
So I came in my framework.
Has everyone opened this point?
Everyone
All right, guys in your here
step here to serve.
If you see this option, just write CMB,
raid CMB
and it will open your command or right.
For Mac users, it is terminal
Now go where your framework is available.
So how you can go in your framework
just to see
what is the path available there right.
Or or the second way.
The second way to go there is open
your framework Video framework
is available in your folder structure.
For example
my framework is available here.
Right?
So I open to my framework in my folder
and on this block on this.
But I will type symbol.
See M.B., I will see them dictating.
Now just click
here, press enter
and you will come inside this.
You will come inside this.
Now everyone is here.
Great.
Now let me show you one thing and
yeah, so I gave you just a shortcut.
This one right now. See
if I go in my
project you will see this target folder.
Right Generated resources maven status.
Sure. Fire reports, best classes.
Remember the point?
I told you that I have to.
I have to clean my project.
So can I clean my project from here?
Someone says yes.
You can clean everything now.
See, I just raised one command
envy and clean
is the command I'm going to write.
If I get build success message
If I get builder success midget message,
it simply means my command executed
my project is clean
so I'm typing here and being clean.
It says what I see, what it is seen
is what it is doing.
Work the same. Cool.
It means build success.
Make for everyone.
Your project is cleared cleaned.
Now if you see here
your target folder is gone.
There is no target folder.
Can you see guys?
There is no target folder
in your framework anymore.
Then we have to check why
it shows builder failure.
Ideally they should see later pass
right build success rate guys.
So what we did,
we just clean our project right now.
This is the time to execute our project.
Now tell me if I'm going to is Yeah.
The last thing
which we are going to do now.
See, this is the last thing that we are
going to do now, Trace, here
the last thing which we are going to do.
Shady Last thing is a stupid thing
which we had you to do.
All right, so now now see, here
I am passing my smoke dot example here.
Correct.
If I execute my smoke notice symbol.
Yeah, I know.
I know this
maven installation part two time now here
this part will execute my smoke,
not examine
my smoke dot
someone will execute all their test gives
in these packages
belong to smoke category correct.
But I'm not going to execute anything
anything from here.
I'm going to execute everything from here.
Only right from my command prompt.
So I will right here m v and
test.
Just read this ambient test
and see the moment I press.
Enter
and you see execution starts
now. See
now see it says build success.
Can you see guys what it says?
Guys, It says build success right.
You'll see your parsed
this one with this credential
with this credential with this credential.
With this credential.
Correct.
All right.
It will see that and see errors
out of point.
Errors are okay, right?
Mail is failure.
It means there is something
which is not are downloaded completely.
An area will see that.
Why will this mean you will see?
Can you please posted a screenshot of that
now now if you guys see
we do not have to go
and check our console in our ADC.
Right.
We are executing everything smoothly from
Jamal.
It is too small.
I mean I can't even read what is this can.
Okay, so you have to close
all of your Excel file.
If your Excel file is available
and opened everywhere.
Right? Just close your
Excel point from implement.
It is
start talking, talking about your accent.
So just close it.
All right.
So now it worked the correct.
Great.
All right.
So now if you guys see
right when I'm executing
it is giving me this result right now.
Let me show you one thing.
Let me show you one thing intentionally.
I'm going to fail my guess.
Yes. Yes, correct.
I'm going to fail.
My best guess intentionally.
One best guess. I'm going to fail.
Let's go ahead
and then execute it Once again.
I'm going to write in the end test
again.
It starts execution here
right?
Fine.
Now see, it is saying run
one bus around to boss,
run three field in run for this
boss, can you see?
But it is name build of failure.
It means what I'm saying
unless you get hundred percent result
right
it will say bring the failure So before
until unless developers
get the boss message
they cannot deploy the things on
to any in mind.
Mean what does it mean?
It means their goal should 100%
getting my point
right.
Their code should work 100%.
Now you'll see it is very easy to identify
if you go here right?
If you go here,
it gives you the address. Right?
You see it says assertion
error message does not match.
It says password cannot be found.
The password cannot be empty.
You got this message, right?
It says failure. Fine in this test too.
So that is also funny.
It is giving me for logging based invalid
log in message validation, line number 41.
And you see it is giving me completely
does inside log in test.
Fine let me go inside logging test open
this is my logging this
it says invalid log in message validation
line number 41.
It means here right?
It means here.
So my fail point is here only because are
providing a solution here only correct.
Now Now let me fix it.
I just fix it.
And again, if I'm going here,
I will write in the end test.
I am simply executing everything
from here.
You see, this time
false test gives executed.
Second one executed,
third one executed
and fourth one also executed.
Correct.
Now see, it says build success
in this case, it says build success.
So this time when you're done
with your coding part,
when you are completely done
and even if you want to
execute your script,
you don't need to go in your ID,
You can execute everything from
just one simple command wire command
from the wire terminal.
All right.
So there is a formal step of this.
What is this for this step
right now you are seeing that
browser is opening, Browser is closing.
Hegel's browser, if you use
it means everything will execute, right?
Nothing can be.
And we don't need to start intelligent,
no strategy.
That's what I am saying.
So even your Chrome browser will not open.
You will not see Chrome browser.
It will execute all of your script
you will get.
There is a
this is what we call chrome headless
if you
use headless browsers when witnessed.
You know what so many of us
do business in automation, we use headless
browser network, 10,000 scripts,
12,000 scripts.
So it executes everything.
It doesn't open any browser,
it doesn't close any browser,
it just everything
it gives you that isn't there.
So Things work. I'm
getting my point based
guys, so far.
Any question in this explanation?
Yeah. Right now it is using Dex.
What I am saying it is a for better step
further, if we implement that
step, then even Chrome
browser will not open.
That is Chrome headless browser.
It is an advanced part.
We will see that right now it is because
we didn't provide headless browser.
Correct.
So this was the last point.
Right when we started our conversation,
I told you that we will reach
till the point where we will not meet it.
We will not use any of the file
for execution.
So right now we are not using any file
for the execution.
We are passing
just one command in our command prompt
and my entire test gives entire framework
based on my customization,
based on my configuration.
Executing is it correct or not?
That is getting my point.
All right.
So this is all from the test and you park.
That's all we learn.
Your testing as a tool, correct?
Correct.
So now from tomorrow onwards, guys,
we are going to
start cucumber part, right?
We are going to start our cucumber part
from tomorrow.
The new framework,
completely new framework, less complicated
very easy to understand, very easy to use
as compared to test injection,
but is much easier.
All right.
Obviously, things are seen so many
things are seen in that framework, too.
Like, yes, it would be much easier.
So still still if you guys,
you know, lost a grip on best India
framework.
Right.
If you guys think, no, I didn't
get everything from this framework.
Right.
Not all the things fine.
Cucumber is another chance.
Go ahead, grab cucumber.
All right.
Yeah.
Are going to connect
shortly.
Sure.
Definitely.
I will take care of that.
All right, guys.
So like I said, right,
I will leave you early today.
So we are going to end the class now.
See you guys tomorrow, everyone.