All right.
So from today,
we are going to start first Indy.
Now, what is thingy?
What are the advantages of this
and why we generally use just energy.
Right.
Why we can not Why we should not use
other tools and we should use test.
What are the limitations
we had in our previous tools?
Right.
So that we have to adapt this new tool.
All these things.
First we are going to discuss.
We will see the overview
of this particular tool.
We will see all the practical applications
of this tool.
And then we'll go ahead
and setup this tool
in our intelligent idea.
All right, fine.
So far.
Let me ask you one thing.
This is your application, right?
Let's say this is a project.
Let's say you all got a job
and you have a project.
You you're working on this
particular project.
You go to one web application.
On this web
application, you have to perform testing.
You have to verify whether this
application is strictly working or not.
When I say verify,
it means you have to test this
applications, complete functionality,
whatever the beautiful logo
and the symbols and the fields
you are seeing here onto this
screen, Right.
This is what
this global this complete screen.
What is this? This is UI, right?
We also call it 20 days user interface,
front end.
So here to try to interact with this
UI to automate something on the frontend
which is available on the website.
We have one tool, which tool is this?
Selenium, right?
We are using selenium
to automate out of application.
Right now when I say yes, I mean
I never thought of this word.
I will implement it in my coming batches.
So on this UI part,
on this UI part where we can interact,
where we can interact
with the web elements, with the web
application, we also collect them.
Benedict as the UI has the right user
interface frontend testing.
Now tell me one thing
when I'm entering this data here, right?
This data I'm entering
when I'm entering the password here
and when I click on log in,
it will redirect me to the homepage
to their dashboard page.
Right.
So when I see I'm passing username
and password and I click on log in button.
So how this website knows that yes,
this is their time to redirect
this particular user to dashboard page.
So from
where this admin credentials are coming,
this username, this password is coming
and with the information
which is linked to this username is coming
and visible onto the screen
from where we are getting the event,
what we are writing.
That is also code from where
I'm seeing from where it is coming.
Yes, exactly.
From backend.
Right. From database.
We have stored this information
in the database right now.
How we claim your database is connected to
where UI your UI is nothing.
Your UI is just a user interface.
What does it mean? Interface.
We've already discussed this interface
gave game definition according to you.
Give the body according to your own
requirement according to your own needs.
Right.
So you provide
admin username and password.
When you provide
It will give you the data which is linked
to the admin username and password.
At the same time, instead of admin,
if you enter with this form,
this is available here,
this user, then it will give you the data
which is linked to this file.
Right. So the data is coming from making
this video, performing this operation.
It is fronting right now.
You need one platform
where you can perform all of this
operations together, right?
Where you can perform
all of this operations together.
You can verify and validate that data
which is coming from the database.
Right.
So obviously,
the data which is coming from the database
will be available on the application.
Right.
So you have to verify and validate
this data from the application
first requirement, the verification
and validation of the fields and the data.
Second thing,
you need proper artifacts, proper proof.
When I say proper proof, proper artifacts,
it means when you execute something,
you must have something to show
that something is nothing but your report
right now.
Right now you are using selenium.
Tell me which report
you are getting for the execution.
No, the
screenshot is not the report surgery.
If the report says this, my test
says you have executed
this much discusses us
this much just because this big this much
just to get this.
Yes. Which console should right
but console is not the report.
Let's say I am your client, right?
I'm your client and I'm asking here,
should go ahead and send me the report.
You said it's well,
I've executed 1000 scenarios yesterday.
I'm asking for artifact
and you're sending me the console output.
Would it work?
No. Right.
So at that point of time, if not, what
if you send me 1000 console screenshot?
It will not work
because this is not a proper artifact.
I need consolidated report which say, Hey,
on this execution
out of 1000 scenarios, 500 pass
fail.
Or do you speak?
Sure, sure.
So that should definitely.
So what I'm saying basically is yes.
And if right.
So that's what I'm trying to explain.
This is just an overview I'm giving.
So if you send one report,
it should say out of 1000 scenarios
you have executed 500 past
to 50 fail proof of this.
Get this this consolidated report.
This is artifact that we need, right?
Currently,
we do not have anything like this.
So this is one
loophole in our current system.
There are so many other loopholes
we have in our current system, right,
in our current setup.
And we have to throw but
we have to overcome all of those loopholes
so that we have to adapt this
particular tool which we call test engine
so far is
this player.
Great.
Now, let's go for the let's
start with the very first thing
and just light.
Yep. Yeah, indeed.
What is this?
And now my question is for new ways.
What is testing?
Have you gone through some documentation,
some length or something?
What is testing
next generation and distance for
that is playing.
Okay.
Thumbs is it is a framework
then it says it is
an annotation based tool or framework.
All right.
Let me tell you one thing, guys here.
Whoever is saying whoever is saying
it is a framework.
Whoever is saying it is a tool
because it is
a tool as well is it is upstream, but
first, we will learn best and soon
we will learn its advantages.
We will learn its method.
We will learn its functions.
Right.
And the features of this particular tool.
Once we are done with learning
of all this features of testing,
then we will implement the
actual framework of testing.
Getting my point.
So the process right.
First, we will learn testing as a tool
again, I'm repeating myself.
First we will learn and as a tool
we will learn all the features
of this engine once we are done
with learning and understanding
all the features, how we can use them.
I'll be right then in the code.
Then we will go
and we'll start creating a framework
from scratch for testing you
right
by now.
The process right now, what you are doing,
you mix it.
You have one selenium class, right?
If you want to execute
this particular class, I'm giving you
this overview, Right.
What would you get
once you're done with this test in Dubai?
Right.
So let me give you a first,
your current scenario and the scenario
you will be having after learning testing
not only tool, but also a framework.
Let's say you have one selenium class.
What is.
Next-Generation Basically,
this tool is developed, right?
This tool has been developed
based on the concept of daily
unit and in unit.
When we talk about testing,
we have created this tool
developer, developed this tool
which is having all the properties
of the unit as well as having new features
right in test index, five year
old properly next generation tool, right?
Because it is an advanced it
all which overcome all the previous issues
of selenium and other stuff.
They give it name as a test engine.
So test next generation right now
why they give the next generation.
I think I should take a meeting
with those developers,
but this is a need.
What I think basically next generation is
I will elevate you also.
So basically,
according to my understanding,
why they give it acceleration,
because it is a latest one, right?
If it is a Lakers tool, definitely
it is a next generation.
That's why they give this name.
All right.
So now what I was asking basically is
you have once an Indian class, right?
And in this in Indian class,
you guys have written
some piece of code.
All right.
But when you guys have written
one piece of code, if I
if I asked you to execute
this particular code.
Right.
Which you have written inside one class,
how would you execute it
will do anything when?
All right.
So now
you have hundred classes, right?
Selenium ones do.
Selenium. Selenium.
For If I asked you to execute
all of these classes,
what do you have to do in this case?
Right.
You have to run 100 classes, Right.
Selenium one, right click one by one.
Is it a good idea to execute this?
To get this, you have to click one by one.
Let's say you have a big application right
there.
You have 10,000 just to get this.
Your client says, I need execution
report by tomorrow morning
and it's already 4 p.m.
in the evening.
Where do you plan to sit In the office
for the whole night
and execute every class one by one,
and then take this screenshot
from the console
and send it by tomorrow morning.
Right. Big time. Do this.
So when we see all of these things.
Right.
And we see all of these things,
we need one tool
from where we can overcome
all of these problems.
Right?
This is the scenario
you are having right now.
Another thing,
what if esi write your entire code,
launching the application, maybe
get to the you are launching the browser,
navigate to the you are in perform
logging admins enter username
inter password, click on log in perform
all of this operation,
but don't write amendment
I getting that question.
What if I write your complete code
but don't write main method?
Will it work? Yes.
How did you write this?
Then you can execute it.
Java doesn't sound
practical.
Okay, fine.
Right.
I won't execute right?
Correct. In Loza. Correct.
So here first thing
which we will be working on is
we will not use men
method anymore for execution.
You don't need a main method on first
thing.
You don't need to run your classes via right click this and this and this based on
I am talking
once you are done with destiny
learning right?
No method.
You need.
You don't need to click on any other
class, right?
Every single class right click
and then execute this.
No, we will create executables.
We will do some customizations.
Right?
If you say it is executable,
yes, then it's
like I said,
it is a fresh beginning right.
Third thing, I think
let's say
you have 50 test cases, right?
50 selenium classes you have
I want you to execute just 25
and keep those 25 as it is.
How would you do that?
Yeah.
Incorrect.
No, no, no.
Anybody disable nothing, Right?
We don't need to do any enable
disable yet.
We'll keep all of these classes.
Like I said, hold
your horses one by one we will enable
disable is an advanced concept.
Priority annotation is advanced concept.
I'm just talking about
simple customization part.
Right?
Currently what we have,
we do not have any setup
in which we can perform
this kind of operations.
Right.
But if we really
want to perform this type of operations,
which is quite practical, right?
Let's say you have 1000 to get this
and I want you to execute on this.
Look, this, this
which is having partnership of 18 or 20,
this gives us
what would you do in that case?
This is another thing, right?
We need to look
from the practical perspective.
All right.
So all of these things,
all of this things, whatever I'm
explaining right now, all of these things,
we will be implementing in our test
engine portion
already
now here, see it.
Since this is a testing tool,
it is a unique test framework.
See, first it is a tool, then
it is a framework designed for testing.
This system is designed to cover
all categories of test that is unit
test functioning test integration test
and doing test every single thing.
Fine.
Now, let me ask one thing.
All users, this tool,
when I say testing is a tool and test
and it is also a framework
fine board developer and testers
can use this.
Both developers and testers can use this
to know why developers can use this tool.
Can somebody answer
yes because they perform unique
testing correctly.
Mom can.
I told the Yeah.
So that's what we called unit
testing. Right?
They always perform unique testing.
Once they are done with the unit testing,
then they only deploy the bid
on to the other environment. Right.
So to perform this unique testing,
they can also use this test in due
to it, Right.
Because testing is all about
customization.
Testing is all about providing
the new features and the facility.
Right?
So both developers
and testers can use this particular tool.
So far clear everyone.
Now why why we developed this tool.
It is inspired from unit
and you need to know what is Janee Tool
they really discuss.
We will study this unit also.
Don't worry about it.
But just remember inheritance.
We are learning right now
from G Unit and unique, right?
We have inspired from these two
and we created Test and Orchestra Test
and we inherited the properties of G unit
and unit and also test and D has its own
specific features as well.
Right.
By adding new functionalities
which made this engine
more powerful than other unit test
frameworks.
Right now.
After this, like I said,
it gives ability to write your more
your code, more flexible,
your test gives this more flexible rate
and it gives you more features
to execute the things right.
For example, annotations,
grouping, sequencing,
parameter sizing,
all of this things we will see one by one.
One more guys.
You have used Excel file
to pass the data, right?
Everyone uses
right?
Everyone uses Excel Point.
Have you gone through that bulkier code
Excel file
your Excel file to pass the data?
Right.
Have you gone through that bulkier code
inside
one for know your rating number of rules?
The number of columns
then converting all the list.
Right.
All the maps into list
and you're adding into the list
and they're calling the list. Right?
Everything.
I don't know how to read that code.
I'm just explaining. All
right.
You know, all the bulkier correct list in
this is
you don't need to parse any data
from your Excel file
or you don't need to write
that much of code anywhere.
I have my own personal feature.
If you can use a personal feature,
your parameterization testing
will be done inside this to excel.
We don't have to use Excel.
We don't have to use any of that file,
right?
We just
say we just need
to provide our user name
and password inside test
and it will take it as a parameter
and it will perform
all of my testing.
Another feature of testing, right?
I'm just giving you one by one
and when we will implement,
you will like it more, right?
You will definitely like
it when we proceed for the
now after this.
After this one more exam.
One more interesting points.
Let's say you have been test cases.
Right now, I'm just giving you
a very basic example, Right?
You have test cases
and I asked you to execute this dentist.
This as of now
with your current selenium classes.
Right.
I'm talking about those current classes.
If I ask you should
if Abdul Oksana, Jameel.
So one step, everyone. Jamal
to execute this test, get this
how much time
you guys need to execute them
and what is the standard procedure
to execute
which you will follow, right
One by one.
Exactly.
Right click contain times
rate on ten different classes.
That's all you need to run.
Now, consider the same scenario for 100.
Consider the same situation
for 100 scenario.
What would happen?
Yes, everyone's
everyone's thing that will hurt
us thing.
It takes more time.
Second thing you will die. Correct?
Third thing.
Third thing is
you might miss some of the best.
This right there you are more likely
to miss some of the test cases.
If you are rigorously working on 100 test
cases, you're trying to execute them.
One by one.
There are high chances that you may meet
some of them.
Correct.
School test indices.
Even if you have 100 test cases,
don't let me just run my one
class and I will execute your hybrid test
guesses at one point of time.
It means if your two test cases
are executing in one minute,
your 100 test cases will also be executing
just one minute.
Getting my point.
This is what we call
parallel execution, right?
It means what on multiple instances,
your test,
you will execute
all of your test cases in a single shot.
If you have five test cases,
it will execute in 5 seconds
because it will execute them
firmly, not sequentially, one by one.
Right.
Or because better execution.
Really?
I wasn't aware of it.
It seems like my MBA is working here.
No, Jamal. No, never.
That's what I'm seeing. Right.
It is in Spence's, right?
This is not a browser browser instances.
Okay.
What is this?
When you said the chrome driver dot,
it's the right.
This is web browser.
This is the driver.
The web driver.
But what the driver does
Web driver gives you web browser.
Have you ever noticed this point, guys?
When you provide driver dot right
is equal to new chrome driver.
Before that you provide chrome
driver, web driver or driver
and then the part of driver
not exit. Right.
This isn't executable
file of work of chrome driver,
but when you launch this fight,
it gives you Chrome browser.
So what is this Chrome browser?
This is the instance, right?
This is the image where you can see
whatever the operations you're performing.
Remember, one more thing.
Whenever you enter
any username, you enter any password.
Whenever you try to click on
any of the button, you're always dealing,
you always interacting with the Google
document object model, right?
You're not dealing with this frame
or with this images.
You are dealing with the document
object model.
You're interacting with the web elements
which are available in the dome, correct?
But on the instance on the image,
you can see
what is going on in the picture.
Getting my point
right.
So similarly.
Yes, right.
That is to make also one vaccination.
Those
along with this.
All right.
So what I was explaining
basically is when we talk about this
type of scenarios, parallel
execution, it creates multiple instances.
Right.
So multiple instances of this need
I mean, if it is ten or 20 instance
instances,
it will affect on your processor, fine.
But as far as four or five cases
are concerned, in one shot,
it will execute, right?
It will execute.
That's why developers always need
this kind of high
configurations system, right?
Ryzen seven processor or Intel i7
or I9 process or i5 11th generation
processor OCTA core processor
with 16 traits.
Why we need all of these things.
We need SSD now, not HD 64 GB, RAM nor 16.
Jimmy is more than enough
A and 16 GB RAM is more than enough
as long as you have a very good processor
OCTA core processor basically
already.
So kernel execution.
Now after this, let's say
you have to test this.
You want to execute
all of them in a single shot, but you want
to prioritize them.
For example, the test
which you have written on number nine,
you have to execute it first
because you have written it number seven.
You have to
you want to execute it on the second,
the 10th one
you want to execute in on third.
Is it possible in testing?
So the answer is yes, it is possible.
In testing you can prioritize your test
because this you can define the sequence
of your test guesses
and according to the sequence
which you have defined your test
and you will execute
all of your test kits. It's
right.
Got to to
right now the most important point I
yeah, what I'm trying to detect also
yeah really verify this.
Yes correct sequential testing
so you're performing right now already.
Right.
So sequential testing.
Also we will see here parallel testing
also we will see get both
this things are possible in testing.
All right.
Now, let's talk about the most important
point here
with testing.
Right?
You can have a very good colored HTML
report for all the test
execution, right?
It means now you will get this effect.
The FDA will report,
you will get it right this time.
When I said before,
you will see how many cases fast,
how many test cases fail,
how many test cases,
even if you want to see where it failed
right.
So you're not get
those kind of exceptions. Right.
Line number
Java 32 element not found exception,
not if you will get the actual detail
or rate.
Hey, this verification validation
point said go and check
invite is great
because we got this particular value.
We were expecting something else.
We got something else right there.
Also, you will see here,
correct?
Right. Mean correct.
Correct. For smoke testing.
You said some annotations
to one particular one. Right.
And they didn't execute only that one.
Not for the whole test.
Fine. Let's proceed further.
The not too much explanation,
but it is important.
All right.
Now, if you see here a number of benefits
which we are going to check, we haven't
talked about here in that session.
Great.
Thank you.
Was the right.
So now let's proceed for that.
What are the benefits
we are going to get? Right.
We already discussed about the features.
Fine.
That these are the functionalities and
these are the functions test in defense.
And when we implemented,
we will utilize all of those features
because of those features, right.
Because of those functions,
because of those facilities,
what all of the benefits we can get,
that's what we will going to see now.
Right.
The first one is this ability to produce
reports of execution.
Earlier, we did not have any default rate,
which we can show to our client.
Remember, guys, when you're working
in that industry, they're your client.
Always need artifact.
Your client always needs artifact, right?
When I say artifacts,
it simply means proof.
If Mike says, Hey, let's say I'm
your client
and Mike
is still working on my project, Great.
And if I'm asking him,
tell me how many test cases
executed yesterday, What is the status?
And Mike's is well,
I have executed 75 out of 75
to 17:01 period seven escape.
I'm not going to rely
on this information. Why?
Because this is not documented anywhere.
If I'm a client, even
I have to report to senior management.
Right. For that
I need consolidated report.
Everything should be documented
is the first rule
of being a professional person
in the industry.
Right? Everything should be documented.
So when I say documentation right there,
we need report for all the execution part.
The same thing.
If I ask Mike Mike what you did yesterday,
Mike's is all right.
I'm sending you the report. Fine.
In that report, time is mentioned
that is mention number of test
cases, mention name of test cases, mention
which one positive.
Which one of these are not being paid.
All of these things mentioned.
So does he need to explain anything?
He don't.
He doesn't need to explain
anything. Right.
The report says every single thing.
So it gives you the ability
to produce this
report, get it,
get it right,
then annotations make Esther's life easy.
Give this point aside right now,
what is annotations and how it makes
our life easy? Events. This
test cases can be grouped and prioritized.
Right?
I already told you
we can prioritize this things.
We can say all over on execution order.
We can state in order to execute
all of our test cases.
Right?
We can do all of this things.
Fine.
Now let's.
I'm not good at it.
You know, there's medicine in all Summit.
I'm sorry for that.
Even I'm having a bad headache
I can take anyway
by now.
Batch execution is also possible.
Now, Vanessa, back to execution.
What does it mean?
Guys, Remember,
there is a difference in between parallel
execution and batch execution, right?
Batch execution means executing 15
or 20 scenarios together,
but in sequential form.
Getting my point dates.
If you have multiple scenarios,
let me just show you
this example here.
Let's say you have test one,
test two, test three.
You have three test, right?
If you want to execute
all these three test together,
right together
means on instance one browser, instance
one this is executing
browser, instance two this is executing
and on browser instance three
this one is executing, right.
They all are executing at one
point of time.
What example what time is it is 830.
So it is executing at 813.
It is also executing at 813. Right.
And this one is also executing at 830.
Right.
In a single shot when you're executing
all of your test cases
at same point of time
against multiple instances of the browser,
we call it
an execution, right?
This is better than execution.
Now, see,
we have test one,
test to
test two, three.
We're executing this test
right in a single shot.
It means what?
I have one file
right?
This is my digital pen. Actually,
on my digital board,
I'm writing all of this thing
so you guys can see.
Right. Let me change it.
So here, this is my test class,
right from where
I'm having this three different test.
When I'm executing that,
this one will execute first,
let's see this one, execute second,
this one execute third.
Right.
This is this is in
this is in sequential form, right?
This is in sequential form
with executing one one.
But because we're passing
them as a batch we call eight
batch executions and
say it's timing, it's 814,
this one would be 815.
Let's in this one would be 816,
eight, 18 lives at different times.
Right?
But just one execution one
and it will execute
all of this things
guys understood the difference
in between batch
execution and execution.
Take now
next thing here, assertions is possible.
Thank you us thank you very much.
Aspersions is possible.
What is assertion?
Assertion is nothing
but the verification check points.
Right?
When I say verification checkpoints,
what does it mean?
Let me show you.
I hope you guys have done this part.
Also see you have your application
where are having your
username
password
log in?
Right?
When I say verification,
it means I will check
whether this username field is available
or my first thing.
Even if this field is available.
Right.
Even if this field is definitely available
here, I have to check whether their text
which is available is username
or something else.
Negative.
Well, is available
by text. Is username one.
Is it correct
then negates?
No, it's not correct
because I'm verifying only not only field
but also the text
which is available on this link.
See, this is my username
so message should display as a username.
Right?
If field is available
like a message is username one.
Is it correct?
It is not correct. Right.
So when I say assumptions
solutions, always make sure assertions
always make sure that whatever the things
we want to verify,
the things are actually present
in its actual expected form.
Correct.
So this then also provide facility
of using assumptions. Yet
this assertion was present in June.
It also because it inherited
some properties of unique test
and has its own assumptions as well.
The next thing is data transfer.
Data parameterization is also possible.
What is this data pattern?
Because basically
I just gave you one example right?
Couple of minutes back,
I give you one example about using this
Excel file, right?
That bulkier piece of code
which you which you have written earlier,
this tendency is you don't need to write
that piece of code.
Instead, you can execute
and you can utilize
my inbuilt function by using my feature.
By using my function, you can perform
the data parameterization testing.
You can force the parameters in my invoke
function.
That's what we see.
Data acquisition is possible. Indistinct.
Now the best
part is whatever the selenium
we have, right?
The existing selenium
we have right now with this
we can integrate, we can add,
we can make this test engine
without selenium, without a cucumber,
without a maven, and so many other tools.
Right?
So testing this highly flexible,
adaptable tool currently in Selenium,
we are facing so many issues that we are
not able to execute in a sequence.
We do not have groupings,
we cannot get any,
we are not getting into the force
or something. Right?
So to overcome all of these issues,
what simply we can do
is we can simply integrate this tool,
the test into tool with that same book,
with that selenium, right?
So in our selenium, but we will be having
our programing language
are the best automation tools.
Selenium are extended all together.
Then we will get perfect combo right
then we will get perfect combo
to get all that depends
to get all the artifacts here.
Great. So far in this complete explanation
of so
far in this explanation,
whatever the things I've explained so far,
do you guys have any question or anything
which you guys take?
No, I'm not getting it.
All right.
Yes, definitely. All in. Definitely.
But first explanation is important.
Place assertion one more time short.
So assertion
basically to verify the feeds,
verify all the elements we have in
its original stage
array might be possible.
Sometimes it is available. Right.
But this thing should show something else
and it is showing something else.
If it is happening.
Do we have anything protest? No.
That's
why we need a solution to test, to verify
the things in its actual form.
Right. Exactly.
Based on j unit and units getting.
All right.
Giving you this overall
overview was very important. Why?
Because right now
you should have this understanding.
Great.
Why are we going to use this
particular tool
Now when you have a complete understanding
what this tool is,
what are the features?
What are the benefits we can use, why
we are not going to use everything?
Shall we proceed further
to create this DNG tool
along with Selenium
and integrate in download everything
so that we can run at least some test to
get this Putting
in cells call.
We never discussed disadvantages of the
right
we can try known as will not try
it will implement for sure.
All right guys
first thing
great we all need
the very first thing is
selenium just like
So to do that right, we need selenium
just as well as we need to study
just these two jobs.
We need correct.
From there we need to download this job
files, go on to the MAVEN repository.
Guys, this is the best place
to download everything right
related to your job and everything.
Going to have a repository here.
You have to simply write,
test and g and click.
You will see on the first portion
on the first.
Read the false links.
This just indicates click. You
and it gives you so many options.
7.42.0.
7.3.07.1.0.
Which one you want to use?
Let's say I'm going to use 7.4.0.
All right.
Let me quickly take once again
the great American depository, everyone,
and search for one repository
for thing,
guys, do what I am doing right now here.
Are you guys done with this?
What I'm doing, you
in this point.
Let me not if I'm going too fast
now, write, test engineer
and search for this just in
everyone got this option as opposed to
link is s on
good day.
Now let's click on this test and
you will see
all of these different versions of
and you can everyone see this
great click on this first 17.4.0
and here you'll see it says jar 907.
Can we
click on it?
It will download everything.
It will download your job, click on it.
Once you download, it will show
you just like this test.
Indeed.
7.4.0.
This chart
is downloaded.
Everyone.
Abdul
Great
shirt and show.
This is the job unit.
Go down download
now guys,
tell me how many of you bought is
still
do not have selenium jars in your machine.
Is there anyone?
The last step is simply you need to
click here and it will download.
Just click here
and it will download already.
No, no, no, no, no.
We don't need to call credence
and the name jars folder.
Just download it.
All right.
Is there anyone who is still left
with downloading test and digest
or everyone has downloaded
or it?
I want to make sure that everyone
is on the same page with me.
Right.
So the class is for everyone.
I know some of you guys up very fast.
Some of you guys are intermediate,
some of you guys are slow.
That is fine.
But we are here to take everyone
on the same page, Right?
That's why I'm going slow now.
That's great.
All right.
Now the next point is tell me, guys,
do you guys have
is showing this files
which one you have downloaded QWERTY.
This one, if you just simply click on Jar
File.
Right.
We do not need to open anything.
Just download and keep it like this.
It can be a single file only right?
Okay. That's what I'm showing. Right.
This is the jar file dates.
Can you see it simply says jar 907.
Give you this, just click on it
and it will download
this one really good download.
See simply click here.
See it is giving me
why is why it's not
letting you download.
If there is an option coming right
there is an option.
Keep it right.
Just click on this option.
Unidentified Developer
Can you please post the screenshot of this
which error?
I just want to check that
advances after download my behavior.
This should not happen.
Actually.
All right.
So just should events even mirror
has this equal rate and everyone
that is good.
All right, fine.
Now let's talk about selenium.
Just fine, as do you guys have already
downloaded selenium, your files
in your system, or do you want me to go
download this in the game just for you?
You do great.
Already downloaded, great.
No black? No.
There is no new jobs.
Don't worry about it.
Fine.
So what I'm going to do here is see,
I'm going to create
a completely new project for testing.
Already this
a whole new project
and I have just created already.
But I will show you
how to create a new project as well.
Don't worry about receipt.
Click on file.
I hope you know this already,
but still I am showing you
keep click on keep
seems here have already downloaded one job
because that's going to indicate a one.
Yeah it is.
It cannot be opened right.
It must be downloaded already.
So if I downloaded this file to the right
from this report
so it is already downloaded.
So in your machine it cannot be opened.
You don't need to open it.
Just keep it where it is already.
It's already downloaded.
All right. Please confirm.
Very similar.
Please confirm
so that we can proceed further.
Imam Sayed Imam, just click on
Keep.
Great.
Said he has done
Yeah Imam, great.
I'm waiting
I'm waiting for your response to these.
So Mira,
when you're getting this error, it simply
means you're trying to open it, right?
You don't need to open it.
Correct?
Yeah. Everyone has just one Java.
Everyone has just one
Guru.
Correct.
But I
there is no next step after download.
We are still waiting for everyone
to complete download process
so that we can proceed for the
correct.
Now guys, if everyone is okay,
shall we proceed further?
Put your status in the check.
Great.
So now what are we going to do
is we are going to create
a new Java project.
Like I said, right in the end, even
having problems this post you equityzen
the support right was I'm correct
these guys work and like I said, right.
We are taking baby steps
when I set my project.
First we need to understand
what is testing right and after that
we have to understand why
we use dependency and not use jar files.
And then we will see the big tool.
When we talk about the tool,
then we will implement the method.
Like I said, we will learn for
testing as a tool and then we will create
framework.
So we will use this tool
to create a framework.
That's
why right now we do not have dependency
because we are not using mapping tool,
we are simply using Java project.
So we are using checkpoints, we
now to create nice.
Tell me,
I don't know how to create a project.
Where should I click
click new?
Thank you.
All right then
let me go ahead
and do it.
Fine,
because it is my Java project.
I don't need to select anything else.
Simply I will click next
right
then next
my project and then would be you can write
as dict
best team and test and
correct.
Simply click finish
new window.
You'll see
again the steps shorter
click on file
Click on file
Click on new iPhone file
on Click on project
after project Simply click next
again Click next.
Give the name of your project, the name
which I gave you as date back then.
Test energy right.
Once you give this name, simply click
finish.
Once you finished,
you will see folder structure like this.
Here.
Now earlier Imam.
Great.
Now if you guys see one thing Java is by
default available in my project.
Since I selected Java project,
it gives me Java 1.8,
which is already pointing to my JDK.
So my is available here right now.
Let me give you the overview.
Read the layout
which I'm going to implement here.
So now we need what we need one
programing language right?
Which programing language
we are using here, Java.
We already have a place.
We need automation tool,
which tool we using.
I Selenium,
right.
We need one more tool, right?
We also call it integrated tool.
Why we need this particular tool
to overcome the issues
which I am having no pulse
I'm having in Selenium and Java.
We need the third thing,
which is this integrator today days
testing, obviously, right now
the project which I have created,
I already have Java
tool things.
I have to take selenium and test
and right.
Two things I have to selenium
and test in terms of what
in terms of Java, it's like
I have to a Java
so that I can utilize all the features
of this selenium as that is existing
in my complete project.
Java have already Selenium in testing
you are going to AG
now, so let's go ahead and do it.
How to add,
how to see,
click on find
Project structure.
Yeah, right, right.
There's project structure.
I've got to go into modules.
Okay.
Yes. If you guys are very intelligent,
sometimes
I think I don't need to teach you.
Great.
Now here,
here we have to add our selenium
as well as our test integers.
Right.
So get your test in D jar first.
Simply click on this plus sign.
It says jar directly.
It will ask your detectors
so that it is available
on my desktop.
And the things that's and that syntax.
This is my test. G Right.
So I am simply clicking. Okay,
You see my testing is available here
now I have to aid what I have to add
to my selenium.
Also, I will go here again.
Don't worry
guys, if you're not able to follow, right.
If someone is facing their difficulty
how to add files?
I will guide you.
Don't worry yet.
I will go.
Testing think takes
selenium
select to click.
Okay again go
your files
inside lives.
Whatever the jobs I have available
these four five jar files
I selected click okay.
Right.
We have to check.
All of them are compiling
it are in compilation stage.
Right.
Simple take.
Okay.
Right.
I again project structure
go here
you see all of these jobs how
to add these jobs again I'm showing you.
Let's sign.
Sure. So
click on jobs
go here
going to the top
ready.
You have your jobs available, right?
For example, mycelium dataset
available here.
So two jobs are this.
And by jobs inside this, right.
We need these five job files
as well as these two data points.
Right?
You have to select them.
Click.
Okay.
Okay, fine.
Got it.
Now I have testing jobs
as well as I have selenium jobs
clear
so far.
How many of
you guys have already downloaded this job?
Find it? Yes.
All break even.
If you try to correct connect,
try to select it.
It will get just one from the selenium
combines one source one so that is fine.
I'm not it. I am lost.
All right.
I'm like,
Would you please tell me where you lost?
Fine. This is mine.
External liability. No
adding jar
files right.
Got to correct.
So let me show you once again,
click on file
Project structure
whoever wants to 85 bit job
so you guys will be just I have
you can see here
you can check this jobs with me
that six jobs we are taking from selenium.
Where do I find all these jobs.
So one job I have already downloaded
right in front of you.
So contextual.
So Nick,
you have this just integers with you.
I just showed right how to
download this to do you have this job
right now?
The remaining jobs
we are taking from your selenium.
Have you downloaded them earlier?
Joining right now?
Fine.
So inside selenium jobs A right now
we are why we are not eating drivers
because we are not actually
executing the test case.
Right.
We are just implementing the test
and just setup
driver is a part of your script
not for testing this.
Right.
So we will add drivers also don't
worry about it, we will add everything.
Just don't worry about it.
Now, after this, the next thing
what we have to do basically
is, okay,
where do I find iPhone selenium,
just which files to add?
So if you go into your selenium,
let me show you
right.
Just click on selenium.
You'll see two files out here, right?
These two files and inside lives
you will find five find see it.
So these five files, plus
these two files
you have to egg in your project
here is clear.
So far
on the
please check once again
right in your download folder
because it should be there
in your download
folder.
How are you using Mac or windows?
Which one you are using
windows.
Right.
So just go and take in your downloads
folder.
It must be this
if we check
by waiting 4 minutes.
Bravo
file from this.
Got it
then in module perfect.
All right, so guys, so far so good.
Everyone clear
in there?
Anyone who has a still any by.
We don't have video to make it
Andrej because I personally feel
that it is always good
to give you a support.
If I asked you to download everything
with me here, it would be more easy
than watching any other thing.
It is just for reference right?
The already you have, right?
You have already added
all these things here.
The makeup is just somebody
that is operating.
Just one jar for you, right.
And just to I'm also telling you here
that you have to download with me.
So if you have any problem,
it is just a matter of adding one jar.
If you can do it here.
Yes, yes. No. Right.
These are selenium jobs. Correct.
And as far as selenium jobs are concerned.
Right.
You guys should have this video machine
because you guys have been
working on selenium from last two months.
So what I'm asking is.
Right. Exactly.
So adding the jobs, whether you are adding
selenium or you're adding testing
or your writing any other day.
So job files, the process,
the installation process is always seen.
It's not going to change anything
up on any after 11 minutes.
What do you think
by the time everyone will be okay
with this?
Yeah, that.
That's what I'm just making sure.
Yeah.
Andre, we will help you with the video,
then write it.
But again, saying
it is just a matter of one five and.
Right. You have to add
just one job fighting for that.
If you need video, then definitely great
to work on your installation
process and everything.
Right guys.
So I think students are asking for break
right?
So let's take a break for 15 minutes.
Maybe it's 15 minutes.
Okay.
So by the time others can also catch
of the things, right.
And connect you after 15 minutes.
So my time it's 12
and so the 850 here next connect nine five
after 15
minutes.
All right, guys.
So now what we have to do
basically is class wise,
we have to use them everything.
We have to understand all the features
one by one.
Right? So first, let's create a package.
So you'll see here it's our system
that I have right in my project.
And I'm going to create one package.
So simply right click,
go on to the package
right now, guys,
get me how we can create the package,
how we provide the of the packages
type.
I'm going to wait on dot syntax
simple back where do you it right.
And inside this package
I'm going to create
my new class for example,
let me put this name
box expert
plus one
right
inside package.
We have to create our classes right.
So I'm going to
write my first class called
simply First in class.
Right?
Normally class
without amendment. There. I see.
I'm not using any method inside
this class.
Correct.
That is so far clear.
What I did
Now, like I said, right.
Like I said, I'm going to write
my test in annotated methods.
Right.
So I'm going to use what here?
I'm going to use my first test
in annotation, which annotation.
Let me go here onto the slide.
They exist to execute test industry.
We don't have to write this separate
class.
We can use simple Java class, right?
We have used a simple Java class, but here
we will not write main method public
static white main because we are not going
to execute this from GB.
Fine.
So we are not using main method
we didn't implement.
It works best in it works with annotations
and annotation.
Can be represented by edit symbol.
All right.
So right now we have to take one
by beginner an octave method, right?
How we will write.
Let me show you this.
Annotation is a tag or a meta data
that provides additional information
about class interface,
automated interest in the member,
whether I'm going to use class
or interface or
meeting test in this annotation
indirect annotation for everything.
Right with this edit annotation
what all are the limitations they can use.
We will see that
like the insert
annotation based tool or annotation
based framework.
This is tested correct?
We have already discussed this case.
This is an annotation based tool or test
and is annotation
framework.
Right.
So annotations in both the methods
according to the invocation type.
Fine. What is this invocation?
Now see the request annotation in testing
did the most important annotation of this
and best annotation this the request.
This annotation mocks a method
or class as destined to test the member.
Now we are not using men method.
So what is the alternative to Metro?
We need something to execute, right?
We need one execution point from where
we can execute all of our piece of code.
So to execute our piece of code
we need one annotation.
Which annotation
is this annotation at best.
This is the bit we will write
all of our scenarios,
all of our test cases on our methods.
Clear.
Right.
And when I say request,
it always correspond to your one method.
Remember it always correspond to your one
method, right?
It means your menu test
next to your best guess.
So you will write at the request
and then the method
which will represent it
correspond to your one menu request.
Guess then at the request again it will
again go to second guess and so on.
Right.
So one by one we will see this parameter.
Also one by one we will see this kind of
customization, also implementation.
Also right now
we are going to use at the request
just for one method just to show you.
All right,
let me write here inside my main method,
I'm going to write edit
this.
It is giving me an error,
so I'm going to write public,
right?
Let's say my method name is
just the method.
Okay,
so I'm going to write a simple statement.
This is my first method.
Clear.
Right now I do not have main method,
so I'm using my at the request annotation.
You'll see it import from or do test
annotations
Don't test right so from India annotations
give an important test annotation
and this method.
So now this method will be considered
as one manual test scenario.
One manual test case. Right.
Whatever the logic I want to use,
I want to write.
I will write inside this particular
piece of code and can be
and then I test a notation, right?
It will be considered
as my single test case.
In your case
can be executed.
This.
Is there anyone who has missed anything
in this point
and read them?
All of them.
Are you guys here with me?
Sure.
So at the request annotation we are using
so it will be considered
as your one test case.
Right.
Whatever the test case
you are using that test case.
Right. You have to write inside your test.
So this time when you execute,
you do not have main method.
It will execute it
as far as per your request.
Annotation part.
Yeah, sure, sure.
No. So we can have
my simple test cases in one class, right?
We will go and we will look into part.
And so it's not an issue, right?
We will go and see how many test cases
we can have,
how this people behave inside one class.
We will see all of this.
I'm just trying to explain one thing here.
When I'm writing this one method
along with the right test.
So this one method will
be considered as one scenario
of No, not actually.
You have
to write and direct test three times
if you'll see the way I am writing here.
Right. You have to import it.
So import or gene test in annotation
start test would be in your import
and then you have to write a request here.
Let's go ahead and try to execute it
right now.
How many of you guys got this error
tell we
everyone got this right?
Intentionally. Intentionally.
I executed it because I knew everyone.
This error gone biased
did come under parameter exception.
Right?
That's the main advantage
of working together.
If we come across any error,
we'll go with the resolution part also.
Great.
Congratulations your test
and just so smart.
Your DNA is also fine.
Great.
Now guys who have got this error,
what we have to do, simple resolution.
If you go if you get this error
when you're practicing alone,
maybe you will spend hours and hours.
One thing we have to do is
we have to download one job here, right?
Which are we have to download.
We have to download. Take my job.
Let me
go and show you where you can find this
information.
Copy this.
And you
is going to stick overflow, right?
Just pasted and you will see four answers.
It says if you're using seven project.
So we are not using seven project. Right?
If you use a project without the map,
then you need to add this job
which it says Jake on my net 1.48. job.
No, as long as it is working fine,
you don't need two people
who have got this issue great.
Simple. Yeah, sure.
Jake.
Commander,
let me get this straight in the track.
The right.
So the error is this.
This is your end of gear.
It's this can be used, Jake.
Commander parameter exception.
No class definition found error
fixes exception in trade. Me.
Now people might be thinking
that we are not using men method
how it is saying exception in thread mean
right
because you guys might have
got this kind of error.
Somebody people straight.
Exactly exactly.
So when you got this added,
what is the resolution to this error.
This is the main question. Right?
So the resolution is once
we find this error,
once we try to search for this edit here,
we will
see for my project this dependency
we are not using right now.
Any moment. Project instance.
If you use project without amendment,
you have to add this job.
Fine.
So we are getting this job.
We will start with this job here.
It says go ahead and use this Java. Right.
So again, where we should go,
we should go into our MAVEN repository.
Then again,
just download this job file from here.
Okay?
When you download this java, right?
Sure.
I think it
is. Everyone got this
in the check.
The name of the job is a Japanese.
So now when you download the Java,
when you download
this job file yogurt, you will get this.
You are fine here like this
git commander 1.48
right.
This is your job by you.
Did you get it now?
Sure.
Why not show now again
the same procedure to add the java right
click on Project structure.
After clicking on the project structure,
right click on plus sign
jobs are directly
click on back Stop
right for me for you guys to get over
you have put
paid your job files
go to your git commander
select your
Jacob mine desktop and click
okay simple apply.
Fine.
Now how to git Commander
Java is everyone is working now.
This time if I try to run this
working by now.
Correct.
Should
everyone for everyone.
It is working now.
Great.
This is the benefit of working together
guys.
We are able to resolve issues right
in a fraction of a minute.
Please go ahead.
Yeah, it's on piecework
in work environment.
We will set up the PC.
All depends.
It depends. Right.
First thing,
if you are working right
and if you joined your organization
as a new employee and they're giving you
a new machine, completely new machine,
then you have to set your complete
we collect estimate
right in the professional environment.
We collect estimate.
So you have to set up their test
from scratch
sometimes, sometimes not all the time.
Sometimes you would be getting the system
where
all the softwares are already installed.
You just need to use them
or you just need to configure
the installation
and configuration different things.
Right?
Sometimes due to some security
firewalls issues or some
networking issues or something like that,
you just ask the networking team
and they will download everything
on your behalf, right?
They will give you the system ready.
You just need to configure them.
Okay, So it depends completely
correct.
Am I correct?
Now, if you'll see here the first thing is
it is totally test run,
one process, one failure, zero
zero rate
any if you want, I can
I can give you the complete
overview once again, don't worry,
we will repeat everything.
Okay.
So now, guys,
if you see here one thing for most is
you're getting very consolidated
output, right?
Nothing additional, nothing less,
Nothing more.
Right. It says defaults weak.
So test run.
Why it is giving you total test run one
because it will count
this at the request annotation.
All right.
When I say
it will count at the request annotation
it means one test at the rate
one at the request.
One annotation means one test,
one notations meant to test
right now on this pen and on this.
And if you see it says in this project,
this class will be executed
inside this class, this test
we have executed
correct.
Is this correct?
I hope you guys are understanding
what I am trying to explain here.
So that is still I am going to fast.
So it is fine. Now.
All right, fine.
Let's proceed further than now.
What I'm going to do
is I'm going to write another.
So I'm writing
oblique like
another matter.
So this is
another method in
this engine.
Now, tell me, guys,
if I execute this particular class right,
how many methods will be executed now
and what would be the result?
How many test cases will I get?
Only test method.
Why not this method
static?
Because you see here one thing, right?
Let me show you this first,
let me try to execute this class
because just one method this
it executes just one method.
Now you'll see here
this same right,
this one is execution for class.
This one is the execution
for a particular test rate.
Again, if I want to execute this one,
what I have to do,
I have to write a direct test
annotation here as well.
Now see, it is giving me this run
option here. Also
run option here also and here
also it means I can execute
particular test from my class
I can execute complete class here also.
Right.
Both these options are available this time
if I execute
this class.
Output changed right
guys, can you see output change now?
Totally test runs.
How much do
you guys can use it to do this?
How much do classes to
write?
And it is giving you both.
This method executes.
Let me do one more thing.
I want to show you something else
here. Now
I'm going to write Public void
last The method
and the last.
And that's empty
class
right now.
Understood that if I had run this
three outputs I will get
I total test run would be three.
Right.
If I execute this particular class
now if I could see it since to test run
three passes three failure zero
and it skips zero.
Correct bug.
But if I see here
first I wrote
this is my first method, right?
Best method.
Then I wrote another method
and then I wrote last method.
But if you see the order of execution
is supposed to be executed,
another method,
then it executed last method.
Then it executed test
method for the overall output.
If you see right here under default,
I'm getting this output opposed to
this one is okay
and this one is tied
right?
That's what my question, remember
by default
is to execute everything all the test
does is not
remember setup.
Parallel means it executes another method.
Last method method
all three equal one by the end
if you see it is executing one by one.
So this is sequential execution,
but here by default, test
indeed executes
multiple test cases in alphabetical order.
Okay. Right.
So if I write this, it
instead of being in last
method, I'm writing as being asked method.
And this one I'm writing is speed
estimate.
Now. See, or let me do one thing,
let me write e, b,
c, and this one is
intentionally
I'm just editing one word ab and see now
see how would execute.
I executed that method only.
I'm going to execute the complete class
now, see
A, B and C because it took alphabetically
right?
Guys can use your total test
run three passes, three. Yes.
We won't be want,
but this is the first class, right?
For that you have to wait for some time.
We will go proceed further
and then we will see
that we should not perform the right
click in execution.
Everything. Don't worry about it.
I will tell you that also.
All right,
Line 17,
You didn't put.
Yeah, that's fine.
That's fine.
Even if I remove this from here.
Also why we're using this parentheses,
I will tell you that also.
Don't worry.
The next topic is that one there
we will use.
That is what we did here.
No, no, this is not parallel execution.
This is batch execution. Right.
This is batch execution
right now.
I'm telling you why it is happening.
So you guys, if I'm clicking here,
see if I'm clicking here on my class name
and if I execute this class, see,
I'll show you different outputs here.
It indicates all the three methods. Right.
You see, if this to take this from three
boxes, three failures, zero gives.
Correct.
But if I run from here let's see,
I right click here
and then I'm performing.
I'm trying to execute
from here in the class.
You'll see it execute just one test.
It's not all the three, right?
Because I didn't execute my entire class.
I to one particular test.
Right.
How will you will identify this
when you click here right click
it gives you the class test in the class
but if you call here right click
and you try to run another method
just one method, it is fine to execute.
Right.
The same thing you can see here
on different execution points, right?
For the execution points, I can see
three for pretest
and one for entire class.
Right guys?
Got it
right.
So now see, so far
we have seen how to write at the request
annotated method,
which will be considered
as your one test case.
They can think how they can execute
knowing sign this is not a disadvantage.
But definitely if I don't want to execute
in the alphabetical order,
can I put my own order?
So the answer is yes,
I can put my own order is but
we will try to run that.
We will try to implement this also.
Right.
So far, answer to one of the students
question, right.
Someone was asking
how many tests we can write.
So you'll see here, so far
we have written three test
inside one class, right?
We have written three test inside
one class.
If you want to write a test inside
one class, you can write a test inside
one class.
Also, there is no issue at all clear
thing to by default.
If I have multiple test cases
by default, if I have multiple test cases,
I can execute all of this test.
Get this in alphabetical order
because test in D
by default executes all of your test cases
in alphabetical order.
Correct.
So that is so far in this part.
In this part, whatever
the things we have implemented, executed,
explained, and defined,
do you guys have any kind of question?
All right, let's proceed further then.
If we are done with this part,
we'll proceed
further.
Do we always have to write my test?
Yes. Correct. Correct.
Because we are using the tool
which is a notation business tool.
Right.
So Always.
We have to write numeric values
to our work with the order.
Right. Right. Numerical values.
This is what we call priority. So
we will see that.
Why don't we find
so now
at the request
a notation we can see now this is the task
created test with the unique test
method names and execute
all test methods.
Yeah, I can understand. I can understand.
Sometimes the terminology is different.
Annotations is something new,
A session is something new,
priority is something new that you guys
are listening this 31st time.
So I can totally the standing,
but it's not that confusing
when it comes to implementation.
It is very easy. Don't worry about it.
So now if you see guys it says
executing test using, iterate, test.
All right
create three test with unique method name
and execute all test metrics.
After the class, you will be having time.
You can go ahead and simply
utilize time rate in implementing
this piece of code here.
Now let's proceed further.
Now, tell me one thing.
Let me just keep it
simple.
Fine.
Let me ask you
one thing, guys.
Yes, you will get it.
You will go to sleep.
Don't worry.
Now, I see you have one test, right?
And then a test for, let's say, log in
verification.
Right.
You have another test
for next day
verification, right.
And you have another page.
Another test you have.
Right. See, this is right over here.
My very good.
I think you're my name.
So one is log in, one is homepage page.
The third one
I am thinking is, let's say an employee.
You want to execute
all of this three, right?
You want to execute all of these three.
But these three are of each other.
This one log in is not depending
on homepage and homepage is not depending
on employee and employers,
not depending on log in verification.
Correct.
These three are separate test this.
What can you think of something?
Can you think of something which is common
among these three test cases?
Can you think of that?
No, Blake, that's what I'm saying.
In order to be employed,
we have to follow these two.
That is fine.
Like the one best guess.
Only you have to follow
not only of the log in.
This means your test,
because it's very simple.
What is your test?
Guest Enter username.
Enter a password,
click on log in and verify.
Right.
This is one thing, right?
The same class.
So many questions, so many outputs. Great.
Now let me tell you one thing, right?
You need to go to the web page here
and maybe
I should get it.
So now, see, this is your first guest is
enter the
username, then
enter password, and then
click log in.
Right.
This is your verification of log in
and then verify
some X, y, z page
and employee.
See interlocking
and then an employee.
Simple.
Right?
But for this test one and four
this does to what is common.
That common is
non to browser
and navigate to you it right
well then you want to verify the log
in all.
You want to add the employee
the very first thing.
What you need to do is which is common
in between these two test kits
is all in between
all the test cases, right?
Is launching the browser
and navigating to the
you are correct.
Similarly similarly,
if I if I completed this test case
called verification of log
in, if I completed this test case,
I have to
I have to close my browser as well
right here.
Also, if I'm done with the employee,
I have to close
my browser as well.
Getting web one days.
So because this test case is independent,
so I have to launch the browser,
I have to navigate to are.
I have to perform this operation
and then I have to close the browser.
Then I can only see my test case.
B one is independent of this
player.
Similarly, if I want to execute
only this test case in in a case,
if I want to execute only people,
then it should also launch the browser,
navigate to you all, enter all the details
at the employee and close the browser.
Right.
It means we are getting one thing.
What this steps.
It could be any of that a step.
Guys, I'm
just giving one example from our project.
It could be any of that example.
Launching the browser, navigating to
you are a This is your precondition
for both the test cases
and close the browser.
Right.
Close the browser is your post condition.
So precondition
first condition for all the test.
Get this right
now test and this is
if you have three tests
and see if you have three test here
and you want to execute something
which is having a same precondition
for all that the same post condition
for all the three,
you don't need to write them multiple
times, three times, post three times
three times,
write post condition and precondition.
You have to use annotation, right?
You have to use annotation here.
So which annotation we have to use.
Let me tell you
first for defined pre and post condition,
I'm creating a class called
precondition and post condition.
Right?
So first I'm going to write my normal
annotated method.
So I'm going to write the public
void.
Let's see, was the method
right?
So this is my
first
method and then I'm writing here again.
One more my third call it that test
public void.
Second method.
This is my
second.
Correct.
Two things.
Now see?
Okay, let's take it one by one.
Right.
I'm going to write
one thing here called iterate
before method, right? Is
what I'm writing here
and direct before method point.
So in the before method, I am writing.
Enter it before method
public void
before automatic
and before method and
will execute before
every test.
This is my precondition.
This is my precondition. Now,
now. After this
I'm going to write my post condition.
So the post condition would be a direct
after method
public void
and after method
and will execute after
every test.
Right guys.
So now if you see I have written iterate
before method for my precondition
and added it
after method for my post condition.
Now if I try to execute this particular
class, see if I'm trying to execute
this particular class,
what I'm getting,
I just want to show you this.
So let's tell me
how many test cases once. So
right.
Why two when I'm having one, two, three,
four methods,
then why just two?
Correct.
Because like I said, the test
is your most important annotation, right?
Your best guess will be considered
based on your test annotation.
When I say iterate before method
after method, these are the conditions
in post condition and these conditions
not be considered as your test case.
Correct.
So test and you and just do a direct
consolidation here.
When we say just to request a notation,
it simply means
that it will execute just to test case.
And that's why we are getting now,
if I see the output here,
it says posted execute.
I am before method.
It means which method.
It executed this before my type,
then It says this is my false
two method means my first method
executing this method.
Then it says I am better method.
It means
before method executed before this test
after method executed
after this test again
executed before the method once again
by because I have another test.
If no,
no, there is no problem.
Now if you see in the second
method. Right.
Because I have to test the
my before method will execute.
How many times?
Two times. Right?
By two times.
Because my precondition
is for all the test cases.
My precondition is for all the test cases.
The test cases
I'm having examining five test case
and I am writing one precondition
before method.
So when I the data
before the method, this editor
before method will execute
before every single at the request gifts,
and then it ultimately will execute
after every single case.
All right, fine.
So here the order is first executed,
then my actual test,
then after method is my first condition,
then again precondition executed,
then my test case,
and then my 20.
Right.
So so that we generally use
this precondition imposed condition
to mention the pains,
for example, the situation, the condition
that requirement
which is same across all the test cases
right
next to you obtain test guess to execute
so you will not write, log in, log in, log
in, log in multiple times
for launching the browser,
launching the browser,
launching the browser everything test.
Guess this is what you guys are doing,
even if you are creating a single class,
what you're doing basically is
you are writing your this driver
or driver is equal to new chrome driver
all the time.
You don't need to do it.
You just write it at one place
and this one place is nothing.
But your precondition will execute
for all of your test cases.
So the code reusability concept
we are implementing here
with the help of before
method after method, also
Now, even if you have let's see,
I'm going to add I'm
going to add another method here.
So after second method,
I'm going to add here
automatic
and then I'm writing method.
Now, what would happen in this case
if I execute this particular class
where having three test cases
right, it executes total three test cases.
How many past three failures escape deal.
But if you see my before my third execute
one time to time
creating my after method, execute
the one time to time three time
and then my actual test gives executing.
So what does it mean?
I wrote it
one time but did execute it three times.
Code reusability. Correct.
So for example,
if you want to verify dashboard page,
you want to verify an employee page,
you want to verify login page, fine.
These are different scenarios.
For all of these scenarios,
you have to launch the browser
and maybe you are these four
things are common,
so you can put these two things
in your precondition or before method.
Right before every single test case, your
this same method will execute at the rate
before method will execute,
and you will be getting
the same piece of code
across all the methods clear.
Similarly, closing the browser.
Then you can put it in the post condition.
So after completion of all the test,
guess what you have to do basically is
you have to close your browser.
So this enter it after method,
but particular annotation
will help you to close your browser.
So right once use everywhere
go to usability
concept with the help of these annotations
and the read before method and direct
after method.
Is it clear to everyone guys,
why responses are getting slower?
What happened is
how can we document this test and
I didn't get your question.
Should
All right,
Mike, great.
All right.
Shall we proceed further now
let's create actual script, right.
With the help of a direct test
annotations.
So test and we are going to use.
So for example, let's say you go to one of
make more sites of your
inside these notes.
Let me write it right.
So first thing, let's say you're
working on one particular string, right?
You all right?
You all know what is this strange?
You all know what is a product?
The backlog, testing backlog.
If you need any clarification from my side
on this point, I can give you also.
But right now I am asking this thing
so you all know what is user story,
right, guys,
You have to kind of make locks, right?
What are these?
What are they?
What are the backlog?
Discrete backlog. Fine.
All right.
Which one is the bigger one product,
the one or the sprint one?
Yeah, we will look
at the backlog is the bigger one.
So let's say
you're working in your fifties
sprint trade, in your fifties,
you got one user story.
So this is illustrative story
when you're getting in this sprint fight
from where
you will be getting this user story,
you will be getting this
from your product backlog or
you'll be getting this
from your sprint backlog
of the sprint backlog right?
So let's go ahead and see if you get
a user story from the Sprint backlog.
Right.
So your user experiences, let's say user
number will be five,
four, three, two, one.
This would be your user study and it says
as in
admin user, you
should be able to you should be able to
log in with
valid credentials.
Right?
This is your results.
The race
now will try to implement this part here.
So I'm going to write new class by
logging test.
Simple.
Now, inside this class,
inside of this class,
I'm going to use my first thing.
This is a direct test
to write my actual test case.
Correct, because I do not have any method,
so I have to use my request.
Fine.
Let me write my request here.
So I'm going to write public void
by any log
database.
Now, tell me one thing
someone already had
someone was already working in this spring
and it's trained for in this particular
write in particular project.
So if he had added
up right now, if you want to use,
you can use no issues, right?
Why did you use.
Because we will use when you are going
to add a couple of features here
of parenthesis
we have to use, we must use
when we will use these features.
Right now, even if you don't use
it will not give you any error.
Now you got this 50 sprint,
but in the remaining for the sprint,
the previous sprint,
someone was also working on one task
right at the request
and he added one user story here.
Right.
That is, for example, public light system
as the user story.
I'm not adding anything yet.
I'm just writing this.
If you are going to add
this video, log in now
for both these things.
You guys are working on
single application, right?
So precondition and post condition,
let's say for both of you,
for both of these, just get this
both of these stories are seen right.
And what is that this is nothing
but you're launching the application
or launching the browser
and navigating the UI
or simply launching browser.
Not even you are in let's say
you guys are working on different
application, but launching
the browser is simple, both of you, Right?
So to do that, to do that, there is a,
there is an annotation we generally used
which annotation we use for precondition.
Those.
I'm going to write it
before my third DFA for public
void before my third.
This is the precondition.
So I'm going to write here
open the browser
simple. This
Now inside this for the browser
I have to write system dark
state property.
There's always the database
system to our state property.
I don't know how to read this quote.
You have to tell me
then here I think driver dark
chrome type
that.
And here, here
I have to provide the path of my chrome
driver dot xy
right.
So now let's do one thing.
When I'm creating this project
inside this project only
I will create one driver right
for the name drivers.
Right inside
this just right click on to see right
And inside this RC
you can create one directory for work.
You can create a directory
for your drivers, right?
And inside drivers
you can put your chrome driver dirty. It's
since I already had here with me,
I'm going to copy
simply from this project.
This is my driver state
or let me just copy my chrome driver
or to exit from here
and I will add it here.
So how I'm going to right click
right on my SLC
new package.
My package name would be drivers,
right guys,
what I'm doing, right
click on this RC new package.
My package name is Drivers
and inside these drivers
I'm going to post my chrome driver
dirty exit by
so here if you see this is my driver
got the exit
guide.
Is everyone on the same page with me
what I'm doing here.
Yes right.
It's RC right click new package.
Then you can edit these drivers
and their drivers.
You simply copy
paste your chrome driver to see.
I didn't provide any right
click, I'm just clicking here
and then this deep state.
So and you will get this option
for the moment.
You click paste,
it will give you this chrome driver
you see here
is everyone.
Until this point.
Okay, so now I'm going to provide
the party of support
would be my SRT
drivers.
Chrome Driver. It's correct.
This is my path
inside of my RC.
I'm getting these drivers of my drivers.
I'm getting chrome driver to exit
again.
So if I'm correct or not, let's
go ahead now.
I'm going to right here.
Web driver.
Driver is equal to nil
chrome driver.
All right.
The loser.
So for Chrome driver 30,
you see what you have to do.
Go here and write.
Download
Chrome Driver exit.
All right.
Simply click here
and you will get this option
if you're using Chrome was a 95 download
this.
Chrome was a 94 download this.
How would you get your chrome
driver virgin double
click here right? Help
this hamburger option click here
Going to hell about Google Chrome.
You will get this.
I'm using 94.
All right.
So the one which is compatible with 94,
it says if you're using 94,
download this one.
So similarly,
you can download this one from here,
correct.
Guys,
if you are having compatibility issue,
then do let me know because you might
be getting compatibility issues.
Some of you guys.
Right? Exactly.
It is for Windows only for your Mac.
I think it's simply
the part of Chrome driver not to up.
So shall we proceed further now then?
Those are all good.
Great.
Now what I'm going to do here
is to perform this value log in right.
Fine.
Let me right here Web driver.
Driver.
Because I'm going to use here
also my driver.
So I'm saying here, I'm going to use my
open browser.
So let's say
I'm going to write Driver Dark Gate
and then the you are not my application.
So that is that you are in there you go.
This is the you are I'm getting
I'm going to copy this.
You are only here first thing
all drivers chrome but I will see
I will tell you this
let me deleted from your for now okay.
Someone said I misspelled their driver
with.
Okay fine
now I'm going to write driver dot
when they start
bringing those
out maximize so maximize my window
and then let's put some quick right
to launch browser
and open this application
so driver dot manage start
I most out implicit wait
I am putting for 10 seconds right?
So it can be my time with it in
seconds.
I'm going to pull it guys.
This could clear to everyone.
You guys have written it
multiple times, right?
But still I'm asking.
Fine.
So now let's go ahead.
We are on after performing this
we are on application page.
I still can't paste their driver,
many of which
which one you're using.
Is it Windows or it is Mac
windows.
Okay.
By you are not able to get the driver
first.
You must be getting it in your folder.
You have to extract your zip folder.
Once you extracted after extraction
you will get one file dirty xy.
Then you have to copy this
if after the extraction
and then you will be able to press the
guys.
Make sure when you're sending this chrome
driver dirty exit to everyone.
Right.
Make sure these dirty zip
are compatible to their browsers
because it is not mandatory
that you're also using the same browser
they guys are using.
My you are using 94 or they're using 89.
Right?
So you're wrong.
Driver 47 not work for them. Okay.
So let them download everyone
according to their good browsers.
Otherwise then it will further
lead to an issue that we have to resolve.
You All right,
guys?
All, all.
Okay, everyone, are you correct?
Correct.
The browsers compatibility
in Melbourne, also in Melbourne
also you will get that issue.
But we have another way to overcome that.
Then we will not use
this compared to the event.
We will not use this drivers for you.
But after some time, don't worry with our
drivers we will execute everything.
We will not use these drivers,
we will not use this
main method, We will not use this system
because it property nothing we will use.
But still we will be able to execute
all of our test guesses.
That would be the final output.
Right of learning this towards
entering book.
All right.
So naturally, project for the race
and let's go ahead.
By the way, crucial precondition
class quotes can be quick
precondition.
Yeah. There you go.
This is a precondition.
You'll see
the previous one.
This one.
This is just a normal method, right?
Alright.
So that then.
Okay, so now we have to verify already.
Someone has already sent me this.
Thank you. All of us
for quickly printing 20
main.
Why it is not taking
the driver. They send me
guys it is not taking my driver by
no instance video will wait
and if I have to write across my test
then let me define this driver.
Right liquid.
Define this driver here.
Now tell me this.
What is this?
If I'm defining it, is it local
or it is instance?
Within instance,
what is the specialty of instance
video with
I can use it inside
throughout the my class
in all the metrics.
Right.
So again, I will define it at one place
so that I can use everywhere.
If I am defining it as a local variable,
then every time I have to define
because the scope of visibility will been
limited to my method only, right?
That's why I'm defining it here
on a class level as an instance variable
so that I can utilize
this particular instance
throughout my all methods.
Let's go ahead.
I'm going to write driver
defined element by default.
You shared this good one.
I point what is the idea?
So it is
the user name
point.
Then the second element
I'm getting would be mine.
So it is equal to driver dog.
I got I-80 and here on
so I'm getting the is
the it's the CoSport
the third element would be my dog
in Vietnam.
Right.
It would be mine.
Right now I have to parse their data.
So to parse their data,
we have a component called user
named person because
right,
this is my user name
and then I'm passing my password
dot send keys.
This is my password.
And then simple click right next.
This is my very log in.
Now, after this, tell me one thing.
Right
when I'm entering, I say, Well log it.
So is verification done?
I say to verify that the log user is able
to log in with valid credentials.
So is my verification done from here?
Yeah, that's fine.
Any I'm. I'll give you a time.
Don't worry about it, guys.
If I write into the username, enter
password and click on log in.
Right. So this is our first guest.
This is fine, but my verification done
audit is still pending.
No, we have to check.
But did we implement everything?
That's what I'm asking.
The answer is no,
we didn't implemented. Why?
Because let me show you again
the user story.
It says you should be able to log in
with valid credentials.
Right?
You should be able to log in
with political initials.
Fine.
So should be able.
It means we have to verify something.
Right. Some verification check points.
We need write how we do this
verification checkpoint.
Let me show you
that actually.
So let me write it in here.
Now, you'll see here
we can verify as many things
as you know, things which we see here.
These are unique.
We can verify all of them. Right.
But the most common thing, the most
common thing, which we can see here is
the most common thing Is this welcome text
correctly using cutting, right?
This welcome text.
So I'm going to get this
welcome text by PR,
how to identify,
how to inspect the element.
Right.
Still, I don't know
the status
is giving me one ID here.
Right.
So the best part is taking the I.D.
I'm taking the ID from here.
I can also take the text here right?
I can take the text here.
I can take the ID here.
I can take the link here
also by because anchor tag link
and the text
which is available as link text.
So three things I can take class also,
but for class I have to parse the index
and so many things.
So how many things we can get link
text I.D.
class, partial link text.
We can make export.
We can make the selector also. Right.
Remember the short
form of the selector for I.D.
it is hash
and then the value of class or hash.
Welcome would be a selector.
Then I'm just trying to brush
up your concept.
Okay, Final
now. So many options, right?
Let's go ahead and do it now.
Here.
I'm going to write this one more
Web element.
Very limited would be my
welcome attribute.
Right? So it would be my driver dog.
Find the element by dot export
and my spot would be double slave start.
And that ID I.D.
is equals to
welcome.
Right. If you want to cross check
copy, come here.
Let's take see.
It is just one right?
It is just one.
So now I'm writing here.
One thing I'm writing is if
if my welcome attribute is displayed, then
print one status coin
best guess is valid and USSD
otherwise
print else.
This case is
invalid.
Anything is.
This is my actual test
now precondition if you see here,
this is my precondition.
This is my actual test.
Now it's time to write my post condition.
Right?
So my post condition would be a detect
after method,
right
I'm going to write public void
here.
Don't buy it
because I'm going to write my driver
dog going.
I hope you guys know what is driver.
Sorry.
What is the difference in between?
Driver Great and Driver Not close.
Everyone knows it.
Great.
Got it.
All right, so now see
if I execute my test tickets here.
This is my first test.
Closed. Closes.
Dammit quick with the complete pros,
the content and all the instances.
This is a different point now. Liquidity.
This test is also I'm going to take
just one at the request
precondition and post condition.
Shall we execute this days?
Okay,
let's
see this.
It just open the browser.
Fine.
But it gave you an error.
Errors is null pointer exception.
All right.
Let me just complete this
and then I will help with that.
So guys see
it is giving me null point that exception
right inside my log in test accessible
need log in and down both are feed
right Sergio this works why yours works.
I think they do that
it is null point that exception
now let me give you one
point that exception see
we we have defined web driver
driver to you.
Right.
That is can you see on line number 15,
I have defined one instance
variable, right?
This is my driver. Driver
inside my method on line number 20.
Also, I have driver. Driver
guides here.
This is my local one there instance one.
Now selenium get confused
why you are calling the same thing
on an instance label
and then you are calling it
in a third level as well.
Right.
So do Driver.
We have defined on two different places.
This driver is coming from here.
You'll see that. That's
why we always have color.
Can you see all of this driver right
there?
Driver instance where we have used
this is in purple,
this one also in purple.
But this driver, when I'm using
this driver, are not purple.
This driver, white, white.
Because my instance variable, it should be
applicable throughout all the methods.
But this method
is calling for this local one.
So what I have to do,
I have to remove this driver from here.
Now see it
colors changed to purple, right?
So intentionally.
Remember, if you are asking
why I'm writing on line number
ten with Driver Driver.
That was the reason I was writing.
But then I decided show you
this error first and then write it.
Now I remove this red driver.
Driver right this time.
This time
let's go ahead and try to run this
yet. And I will.
I will share the complete code.
Don't worry.
I will give you the code.
Can you see if this case is valid?
Advised to take test one plus one.
All right.
Andre already sent the code.
Thank you so much entry.
So. So, guys,
everyone sees this code
working fine, but we want
experience.
Where are you
working for everyone or not?
Guys?
Okay. Any. Any.
You got the code in Detroit, right?
So what you can simply do is
you can take this code.
Just take this code.
Right? Use it. And No, that's fine.
That's fine.
I really appreciate that you don't
want to copy just for your difference.
You can take this code.
All right, I'll be fine.
So we don't need web driver.
So that part
we have not reached that point yet.
Great.
And next, what I am seeing.
You don't need to copy paste the code.
Just copy this code for your difference.
Right.
Whenever you read the code,
you can simply see this code.
All right. This is the code I am writing.
And in this code,
if I'm having any mistake,
I can check this as a difference
from that code.
That's it.
I'm not asking you to copy
paste it and never, ever advise
anyone to do this thing.
Okay, so Edwin, there
we will not use this web driver.
That part will come later in our later
sessions.
Not now.
All right, fine.
So, guys, so far, so good.
Task one,
what we did here is correct or not
for everyone
right now,
if we saw test
case is invalid, it will show
that we passed.
That part will come later strategy
when we will discuss about solutions.
This is the reason why
we will use our session
after method code this point.
So there you can see
this is the code for automatic.
You can simply write
it is just one nine in the automatic.
You can write it from here.
I think we have written so much code.
So this prudence I'm not able to follow
it seems right.
But still it ought to be going
with a gentle pace, guys,
so everyone can cope up with this.
The pace is fine, right? But
All right,
let me do one thing here.
Right.
I'm going to create a new repository here.
Fine.
I'm going to push this code. Right? Right.
So whatever the code we have written here,
this would be good for all of you.
Okay, You can get this code
from the repository.
Yeah, Yeah, sure.
And so that's why
I'm committing the code, right?
So once I committed, I mentioned this link
with all of you guys, so you
can use this
to you guys.
Code is available here right
inside this you go.
You will find this code right
now let me give you this URL
with all of you
guys.
Got it.
We have committed this code so far.
Whatever the code we have written,
it has been committed.
This link has been shared with all of you.
Get this code in your machine try to run.
All right.
Any for your reference.
Also the code is available.
We can use the same code.
All right, guys,
do you need a break from the public?
Because there the weather
is completely different for all.
So she might be feeling sleepy today.
All right, guys, Fine.
So let's take a break and
then we'll meet again after 20 minutes.
20 minutes would be okay.
Yeah.
If lunch break, I can totally understand.
It's lunchtime.
Any You don't need to. Don't worry, I.
Can we take my code in the repository?
Still, if you facing the issue
we are available in this intake support.
Right.
We give you support over there also.
Still, if you're not able to find anything
right after this, we'll do a quick zoom
in on that. Zoom
with all all of your credits.
One for you.
Okay.
All right.
So let's connect.
It's 20 to 36 here. 20 to 36.
Let's connect after 20 minutes.
Fine.
So before break,
we have seen log in test, right?
We have executed it all.
We have used annotations at the request.
That is obviously the main one
through which we execute our test case
and then iterated before test
and that
it before test it at the rate of greatest.
All right
so the enter it before method and edit
after method which executes as a pre
and post condition.
Correct.
We have executed this thing.
Now let's move further and let's talk
about the another annotation.
Right the another annotation
which we will be using here.
Fine.
So now now we have seen
this is our main
before method
Optimizer.
Right?
I'm going to write another one called
Before class
and After class
right
now. Tell me guys,
this is my execution flow rate.
At the request we have executed
before, method after method.
We are done
before class and after class.
We are going to focus on this part
before class and upper class.
Why this do annotations guys,
Can you think of
any practical example
or any practical explanation
why we should use
before class in upper class?
So this
can you give me.
All right, fine.
Let me give you one example.
Right.
You have, let's say, 20 or 30 test cases
and they
you want to use
some properties,
You want to use some data.
Right.
And you put the data inside one file.
It could be your file,
your JSON file, your Excel fight.
It could be anything
or even if it is,
your third property is fine.
Also Fine to date some properties
in your all that test.
Get this.
Yeah, it's been great to clear JVM,
but this is not a part of our testing,
right?
We can use it in a precondition. Now
thinking a think of this part, right?
What I see in your test case
or your 20 test case
or in your 30 test cases, right.
You have to redo data from one fight,
correct.
You are going to read the data.
So are you going to read this file again
and again?
All of your test gives us
no what you would do.
You will read it at one time, right?
That one will be executed.
It will be utilized
throughout your classes for all the test,
and then you will close it
in your after class situation.
So the situation, the requirement
which you need
just one time in your class
for all the test cases
before even starting the execution
of the test cases of your class,
you put that requirement in your
before class
and then you close
that requirement in your upper class.
Here.
Now let me
show you here the example of this.
If I come here
in my pre and post condition, I'm
going to write here at the rate
before class point
probably right
before class,
I'm going to write I am
before class.
And then another one I am using
is the rate
after class.
The public void
I am optiplex.
Now guys, tell me this before class
and after class,
how many time it will be executed
before, after method, before every test
and after every test it executed
one each.
All right.
Why one each?
Because we are executing it.
We are executing it on a class level.
And then it before class means before
starting the execution of actual class
and after class means after completion
of the execution of all test.
Because it's available inside that class,
it will execute.
Now, let me run this particular
code.
Fine.
It gives us three test cases.
Why? Because I have
one, two and three.
That is fine.
But if you see here
now, if you'll see here,
it says first execute I before class,
then I'm before my
then first class
first two method means my first test,
then after my third, then again
before method.
Right then second method.
So the after method before method,
second method and then after method.
Right.
If if we have to see this, the execution
flow.
Right.
Let me give you this execution
flow from here.
First one.
This will execute,
then this will execute.
Then you'll actually test execute. Right.
So one, two three
after this, After days
for one after method, we execute, then
fifth one again before, method execute
six the one, this one execute
7 to 1 after method execute,
then add the one again before method.
Execute mind one this test execute
end one this after method execute
and as the last statement
after class will execute
as the 11th is technique.
All right,
now let me show you all these elements.
Take me to
the first one before class
second one before method, third
one first method,
then fourth one again after method.
Yes. Correct.
Correct.
Order doesn't matter
because the annotation defines
the annotation states before class.
It is but obvious that will execute
before the class
if another patient sees it after class.
It is but obvious that yes,
it will execute after the class.
So you'll see three, three, three and two.
It means total 11 strict lengths.
Wait for three days
to get this three preconditions
for the red before three can be generated.
Right after method
33391 time ready for class one time.
I didn't get how to after class methods
after class method where
after class there is nothing like
as you're saying,
I didn't get how to after class method
so there is nothing after class
method right.
Guys, are you understanding this before
closing did
after class everyone
there are two after class method
two after class method just one.
I have an output also I have just one.
I am after class.
Very second one.
Can you see that?
I have two after class method
I don't see anywhere.
It's just after method,
before method, after class
and before class.
There is no two methods.
Is there any confusion on
where where you're getting confused? Tell
sure this is your console.
Yes it is thing I am after method
and second is I am after class.
These are two different things.
Right?
Sure. And
there you go.
This is the code
that I can
make. So
is it clear to everyone? No.
Great Lakes proceed further than fine.
So don't think about before testing
before switched as of now.
Right.
We will discuss this later.
Execution order we have already discussed.
Right.
This execution.
I already defined all those 11
where which method will print
the witness statement before class,
after class, before method after method
and the request annotations.
Right
all the 11 statements we have gone through
along with the execution order.
Now, here
it says this class based
on a class label
we see before class, after class nine,
before group after group.
We are not going to use this right now
because there is one more part
which we need to learn it first and then
we will be able to implement this toolbar.
So I'm not going to you anything right now
about this
before method after method
we have implemented at the request.
We are done with.
Now there's this test
and symbol based annotation.
So before we week after week before test
after test, when we will create this test
and do not take file,
then I will tell you how we used before.
So we end up this week quite okay.
Task is executing different instability
test and annotations.
Create class
that we'll have before and after class.
Annotation
before, after
method, before after class
and to my textbook test annotation,
let me give you
this task and the homework.
Now it's just best guess, but I think
from testing include the following steps.
So this is what we did guys.
What we did.
We took one user story
from the sprint backlog.
XS Right. The business logic of test.
So we written the business logic
of the test as an admin user.
User should be able to log in to the HRA
application with valid credentials.
Right.
This is the business logic insert
test in the annotations in your test.
We have used this annotation as well.
Added annotation information
like classes, methods and modify it.
This is not we are going to do right now
and execute test
and have executed it.
This is what we did right.
Your first tangible driver test case here.
This is what we did.
This is the part
you guys have to work upon.
So let me give you their task.
Also.
And I guess
I'll write like, fine.
So now
let's talk about a new topic, right?
The topic is test and attributes.
Now we are going deep dive, right?
We are going deep
dive into the concepts of this synergy.
We are working point two attributes now.
Fine.
So the first one, the first one
which I want to take is priority, right?
This is my first aggregate.
I want to take you
so many attributes we have,
but we will be taking them one by one.
Right?
So the first one
which I would be taking here is,
like I said, it is priority basis.
Okay.
So I'm going to start on priority.
Let me create one class.
My class would be its priority based.
So I'm going to create a
new class, existing priority
or simple priority
attribute.
Fine.
I'm going to use the priority one.
Now, we have seen.
Okay, this is my best guess.
Let's say I am writing public void.
My log
in method of
I am not getting method.
I'm going to create
another method called the request.
This method name would be public void
launch browser my third.
So I am writing. I am
launch browser.
Right?
And then I'm writing again and the request
public void
get you wanted and take
and maybe
get your ID.
Another method
I I'm writing is public void
Jones browser
right?
Right.
These are the metrics I have written.
All right.
Now if you see
Wall Street says log in,
then it says launch browser.
Then it says navigate.
You are then exist closed browser.
If I look the flow,
I don't think that this flow is cutting,
right?
I'm not able to log in first.
First,
I have to launch my browser and then it
goes, Hello.
Right.
I see here
something is wrong with the flow.
I have to first launch my browser.
This should be my first one.
So if I say this should be my first one,
what I have to write DFC.
I have to right now.
People were asking right?
Why we need this parentheses earlier
because we were not passing any attribute.
We didn't use parentheses.
That is fine here.
I have to use parentheses.
I'm going to provide one executed
and attributes is priority.
So let's say I want to do one by
because I want to execute that enforced.
Fine.
Then navigate the URL is the second one.
So I'm going to write
priority is equals to do
or launching the
you are in I'm going to write
priority is equals to three.
And then for closing the browser,
I'm going to write priorities
equals to for
now, see your alphabetical order.
Yes. Benji doesn't care
if it comes to your priority part
by default,
the priority of every single method
is zero
by default, every single
the request annotation rate,
annotated method.
Every single method has, by default
zero priority.
It means what it executes
not based on the priority,
based on the alphabetical order.
Right.
If every single one has the same priority,
then how fast and you will decide
which one we should execute first,
which one we should execute later.
Write it based on only alphabetical order.
Now, alphabetic order is gone.
No other order is gone, right?
Not that order exist anymore. Why?
Doesn't matter whether you write
your script or your method.
Victim place If you want to execute it.
Good. First place simply prioritize it.
Right.
If I'm going to prioritize
and then I am going to run this code,
see what would happen then right
now. See
it execute first launch browser method.
Right.
So the priority is for launch browser.
Then it executes navigate you on
priority to its navigate.
You want it,
then it executes log in method.
You'll see priority
three is log in method.
Now it's this close browser,
so you'll see closed
browser is the priority for correct
there.
So we defined the flow and we execute it
according to our own priority.
All metrics
we can arrange, we can customize, right?
We can prioritize them
according to our priority
and in the same format,
in the same sequence, in the same order
testing will execute of all our methods
so far clear everything
they provide
just for five days are responding via.
Those are not simple.
Right.
Okay.
I know the class is the bigger one.
I can totally understand that.
And it's a weekend.
But again, guys, like I said,
this is a fresh beginning.
So many things we have to learn,
so we should spend time.
It's up to you guys either
spend five months on your learning
and then enjoy your entire
or five months of enjoying
and then learning your entire life.
It's up to you.
Great.
Just trying to figure out why I can't
import my common methods from selenium.
Which common method you're
talking about German
is close browser.
That's fine, but these eight months
will give you a lifetime joy.
We created common mistakes in selenium
so we don't have to manually each time.
Right now we are not extending
any common methods right?
Because I'm not using any extents.
You have to use extents, common methods.
Then only you would be able
to use them. Right?
Concept of inheritance.
Here we are not using that.
So here
I'm simply writing simple methods. Right?
These methods are not common
methods of something.
I am writing this method on my own
because the logic behind this is
I want to write these methods
just to show the priority.
I'm not extending any methods
or cutting any methods
from selling right.
If you are doing it, I'm not sure
which project you're following,
but right now I'm not doing it right.
So that's why I'm just keeping it simple.
We will definitely do it.
We will extend our common methods
in an upcoming part.
Great.
All right, guys.
So now let me give you one practical
example of priority bytes rate.
For example, see
here, let's Lexy.
Someone came, right?
Someone came and someone right.
One more party.
Great.
What is that? One more part.
Someone has written one more description.
Yeah.
And of course, short.
So what are we going to do now?
Let's say you have written
this particular class.
You have written all the metrics.
Someone came and someone has written
another method before your method.
So he has written Let's the Public Boy
validate
basic board page.
Fine.
Whatever the code, let's say
it would be anything
verifying the
Facebook page.
Now, if you see here
right
alphabetically, alphabetically, you'll see
this method will execute later.
This method will execute first, right?
Intimately. According to the standard.
According to my understanding,
what should happen is
first, because the before method will work
for what this test gives us.
So it will launch the browser,
it will launch the browser,
navigate the on, but then before log
in, it will ask for validate dashboard.
Right. This should not happen.
I want to execute my this test first
and then this test gets taken.
So what I would say I will see. All right.
Hey developer, do one thing in this test.
Guess is
whatever that is because you
are writing,
give them as a priority to level test.
Guess in the test case,
which we already have,
keep that test as a priority
one test gets.
All right
in this way, even if you are editing
or someone else is editing the test case
according to the priority
and the importance and the functionality
you can better take your test
because this in your DNA project this but
clear
grade.
So what it will do, it will again execute
your test cases based on the importance,
based on the criticality,
and based on the priority point.
Now, let's go ahead and let me create
another one, because another attribute
we are going to learn, I'm
going to write here is
another attribute
which I'm going to do
is enable and disable attribute.
Right
now, what is this
enable and disable attribute,
we need to understand this,
guys. See,
let's see, can we take this logging
this right.
Let me copy
the code from my log in test here.
I am writing this code here
by correct?
Correct.
So now see, I have
I don't have any priority as of now,
I'm simply writing my test.
And so it says fine.
Validation to validate
they support is also fine.
Let me take the third one third one since
validate
global right.
So we define
then another one I'm getting is let's see
this time validate
log out
verifying log.
But then me
from this part, right
You have four five days to get this right.
How many test kits this
you think as a part of small
you can execute
you have this discuses right now with you.
Okay.
You want to execute
only two or three from them
radius.
What is a smoke? Testing, basically.
Can somebody tell me
what is the smoke?
Testing
everyday routine Critical test.
Not on the top of my head.
Right.
Everyday routine.
So tell me one thing.
If I have tested something today,
why would I need to test
the same thing to model?
I hope you all are getting my questions
right.
If you think I am going fast,
do let me know.
If you are not understanding anything,
Otherwise, please respond.
It is just you know
to revise your concept, to brush up
your concepts.
Fine.
So guys, you don't need to write anything
from here, right?
From this code.
You don't need to write
whatever the code I am writing.
I've already committed in the repository
and still,
after completion of this, I will again
commit the same code in the repository.
All right.
So you don't need to be worried
about the code right?
Just listen. Everything like a story.
Just observe everything here you will get
in the end all the code, right?
As long as you understood the concept.
This is important.
We use a smoke testing to develop
the new functionality of smoke testing.
Correct.
Mike knows that basically, see
if your application is working
fine, You need to check every day.
You never know what tomorrow
brings, right?
You never know what tomorrow brings.
Get application.
So every day we need to check that.
Yes, my application is up
and it is running.
And the critical functionality,
for example, log in functionality,
low load functionality
or some other important test cases.
Right.
We need to perform
those test execution there.
Just to check
whether my application is up to the server
and it is working extremely fine.
So other users when come
and when they want to use this website,
they are able to use it.
They should be able to use my website
to do all of these things.
We perform smoke testing.
So obviously if you have 15, 20, 20
or 30 test cases in your one class,
you will not execute
all of them in your smoke,
right?
You will not use that is for sure
what you will do.
In that case,
you will execute some of them.
You will need some of them.
Right?
So when I say you will leave
some of them one be.
Exactly, exactly correct.
So one way to do this is
obviously you
you're not going to delete, right.
If I say we don't need it for now.
So you cannot believe that
you have to keep them as it is in there.
Also, we have to disable them.
One way to do
this is to make them disable.
Yeah, if we come out, then again
it is a big 80, right?
So we don't need to
execute all of them
but we need to keep them inside our code.
So what we can do is just in this case,
go ahead, enable whatever
that is because you want to execute
and disable remaining ones.
So for example from this for validate
they support local
null golden logging for validation
set here.
I think valid logging logo.
These two are the crucial one. Right?
Even if Noah is not available,
I can consider
and this is a dashboard page.
Also I can consider. Right.
So coming out fine.
So I will use another great day.
Tag is see how can I write this date?
I'm going to write here as
enabled equals to do
it means I want to execute this
enabled so
enable equals through right
by default By default every single method
which is I mean at the request annotation
every single method
at the request annotation by default
every single one is true.
You'll see again, I'm writing here
enabled
see by default
what it enabled is equal to two.
It means by default everything is true.
If I want to make it disable, I will write
enable is equals to false right?
And then I will write again to enable
is equals to false
let me put this one on
so as enabled is equal to false.
So now it's
the opposite of boolean default.
Correct.
So now you see these three
I have made false this one.
I made it to just one. I made it two.
So this before my third
and after my third will execute.
How many times guys, the actually this is
the next thing which we are going to do.
Don't worry. This is the next
thing which we are going to
didn't I just enable is equal to false.
I wrote it here,
but still I have four test.
So my editor before my edit after method,
my precondition
and post condition will execute
how many bytes
only once by
based going to correct?
Correct.
Because my enable test case is just one.
Even though I have 1000 test scores
as if I made nine 999 in a disabled
fine mind before my after
method will not work with those nine nine.
It will work only with the one
which is enabled, right?
Correct. Correct.
So let me go ahead and execute this part
first, enable it to say, look, see
how many test it's going to execute.
It works fine.
All right.
How many test kits is executed? Just one.
Why one?
Because only one was enabled.
You'll see. Right?
You'll see here out of all this.
Now I'm going to make this one also to
this one also to find.
Right? This one also true.
Now, tell me, guys,
if I have to test this here.
Right.
Obviously, my precondition and post
condition will work for both the test.
Right now it's up to me
which one I want to execute first.
Which one I want to execute second. Right.
So shrimp
answer to your question, generate
priority and enable disable
these two attributes together.
So the answer is yes, I can do it. How
the right priority is equal to next to
for this one
and comma separated
priority is equal to one for this one.
So first this will execute very log in.
Second
this will execute validate, log out,
go ahead and execute this once again.
Now see the difference in the output.
My browser will close two times,
Web browser
will open two times my true test
because this will execute.
It will open the browser
to lose the browser two times
because my post condition and precondition
will work for both the test cases.
Correct?
Yeah.
And I sure
now see again
it will open the browser the second time.
Also it will open the browser. Right.
It opened the browser a second time. Also
it closed it a second time also.
Now see
it is giving you valid log
in invalid logout right.
Thank you Francisco
you'll see enable disable very valid.
Now see
my value log out having the priority two.
So that's right. Executed on second time.
It is priority
when it log into it executed it forced
it gets.
I hope your understanding of the thing
great
and I hope it's not hectic at all for you.
All know it doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter even if you put priority
second, no issues at all.
See, not giving you
any elevate
by default.
I just said right.
By default the priority is zero
for all the methods, right?
By default is.
So if it is by default zero,
then obviously we have to start from
one. Right?
And it
similarly,
when it comes to enable and disable
by default everyone is enabled
is equal to two by default.
Everything you don't need to write
to specifically if you want to mention
you have to mention
enable is equal to false.
See, let me show you this once again.
Right.
I'm going to delete it from here and.
I'm writing enabling right?
The moment that it enabled you to default.
Right? Enable is equal to false.
Is this one? Can you see
after now we use two of the attributes.
We have a couple more. Correct.
And it's going to we have a couple
of more women then will use all of them.
Don't worry.
I hope whatever
the things you have implemented so far,
you guys are learning them.
You guys are understanding them.
This is more important.
Doesn't matter
how many of attributes we are learning.
If you are not getting all of them,
it is of no use.
But instead of ten,
if you are learning five in a session
and you are understanding all five,
this is important.
I want you to do well.
So look
right.
If we leave one at the rate test
without priority indication, okay,
then it will execute. In the last
like this is this is what?
This is what see,
when it comes to priority,
when it comes to provide the priority.
Right.
So let's say you have 500 test this.
Do you have that much of time
to provide the priority one,
two, three, four, 562513.
Do you have that much of time
or do we have that much of time?
When you work on 18 projects,
no one has this much of time, right?
So again, this is a problem
since this is the feature
that is the attribute of test.
Indeed, we are learning.
But in future, in the longer term,
we have some more better ways
to execute, customize
our overall execution process
right now.
Just to just to refresh every one of you,
every one of your eight days.
Attention.
What I'm saying now, what I'm saying is
earlier you use
to execute your test
gives us work with men method.
You're not using men method right now.
Correct.
I'm giving you one very good
you know booster. Yes.
We are not using men method.
In future we will not use Java project
in future we will not use your data files
in future We will not use your chrome
driver or the XY file.
All right.
Java Project.
The Java project will be there.
I'm not going to teach your new language.
Java language will be there.
We will not use Java project.
There will be some other project
we will use.
So in future we will not write
this program word or the portion.
Also right after completion
of both test cases,
right after completion of both
the frameworks test engine cucumber,
you will learn
how you can execute your test cases
even without this intelligent.
It is very important. Why?
Because if we give you the end product,
then we will not give you the cons
of all these things,
the pros of all these things.
How would you understand?
Why are we implementing
those things in the project?
So getting my point,
if we give you the solution
and we will not give you the problem,
how would you know
this is the solution of what?
So first we will learn this
when we come across the program.
When we come across the
problems
right then we will prepare
proposed a good solution for them.
Okay.
There's is the flow of learning
it, right?
So after some time we will teach you
and you will be executing your test
without using your intelligent idea.
All right.
You will not use this idea
after some time.
After some time you,
even if you do not have
your system with you, is still
you will be able to execute.
Your test gives us
your code, will do everything for you.
It will execute your test cases.
It will give you the reports.
Reports will come to your email.
It will identify
all the loopholes in your system.
It will give you how many test cases
you have executed, how much time
it has taken in every single thing
you will be learning.
All of this things in this classic clear.
Was it a booster for all of you
that to my every single
there's not much jokes today not much fun
more focus on explanation part.
All right
please proceed for the guys
If it is a booster for you
for next 45 minutes.
All right.
Bye. Octet, enable and disable.
Let's go ahead for the other tests. Right.
What I'm going to do
is now see, I'm going to create my.
Well, let me open this.
So here priority,
the priority for this test
method enabled and disables.
We have seen this
also this attribute right?
This gives prioritization, right?
We are done
there.
So we generally define the priority.
We are done with this
enable disable.
We are done with this.
This is what we are going to work
upon, not a solution part right now.
Let me show you one thing
I'm going to
right here.
Fine.
This is my another class,
which I'm writing,
the associate class.
And here
I'm going to copy this score
right from my log in class.
That is my log in disk.
I'm going to copy my log latest
now I see in my log
right?
No, no, we are not done yet.
All right,
So now what I am going to do is
this is my log in the first one priority.
Right?
Another one I'm going to add here.
Another one. I'm going to add the request.
I'm going to add public void
validation
of title, Right?
I'm going to validate
the title of this application.
This is what I'm going to do.
So to validate the title,
validate the title,
what I have to do first.
First,
I have to pass the value
first.
I have to pass the value right,
which will I have to pass
the value which I want, right?
So I'm getting this value,
the actual value.
So the actual value would be
what is the title of my page guys?
If since the human
management system
is there, take this data,
let me go and show you this title
here.
This is what we call title,
the Human Management System.
Right?
The human management system.
This is their title.
Now, why do you guys think that
I have to take the locator
to get the title?
Do you really think
that we need to get the data?
We have a method,
right, Diverter to get title,
so we don't need any locator.
In that case,
what I'm going to write is here,
I'm going to write another string. My
expected text is equal to
driver or to get title right.
This is my text.
Is this correct or not?
Tell me now
that right.
So I'm going to write what if condition my
if conditions sees if my
if my this the actual value right is
equal to
expected value
then go ahead and write my
end right.
It is not like
let me put this this
priority is equal to two
comma
enable is equals good.
This one is priority is equals to one
and enable is equals to again
this to find to test
gives it's intentionally.
I'm going to make this one fail
intentionally.
I'm going to make this one fail.
So I am writing human management.
This.
I just want to show you something.
Now let me execute this particular
piece of code here. See?
Right.
Remember intentionally, I'm making it okay
because I have four different IDs, right?
And so many test cases working fine.
I mean, multiple classes,
multiple methods by them.
I have Visual Studio code for JavaScript,
I have for Java, I have Eclipse, Java,
having Village Idea,
all these things I have, that's
a problem
by now.
If you see guys here right,
it is giving me it is not correct.
Right.
What it gives it is not correct.
Why it is not correct
because you see it is not correct.
Fine.
So my condition called filter plus
students.
It is big.
Now see one interesting point
here it is the idea.
Right.
But validation of title, if you see
here it is saying pass.
Can you see this
is indeed a problem
if I'm using this,
if it's condition, don't you see that
this is the problem?
Correct.
Then what is the resolution
of this problem?
That's why
we should not use this defense condition.
I'm building this one more method.
We should not use this else condition.
Fine.
Then you will ask if we are not using a
false condition, then what we have to do?
There is a solution.
We have a solution.
We have from this thing.
Right?
You'll It says a solution
from testing sucks, right?
So just use this assert doc,
there are plenty of methods, right?
I'm not going to use this
method right now.
First let me go to slide
so I can show you this part
why it didn't work at all.
Because I intentionally made it fade
right?
You'll see.
I'm writing human management system
here at this point of time.
If you're looking into the things
that I'm writing,
this human management system is fail
human management system, human management.
Since I have paused,
that's why it is fake.
I made it intentionally just to show you
that we are getting this problem
and we are getting this problem.
Yeah, right.
So this is the problem
with the false condition in testing.
If even the condition
is a positive test case, Why?
Because it says testing.
This is I have my own verification
and validation check points.
And for that
you have to use my own defined methods.
Right? Predefined methods.
So this features predefined attributes
we have to use in order to verify
this this stuff right.
So if I see I'm not going to use this one,
then you might ask
then which one we have to use.
So let me show you this one we have to use
right.
Right? Exactly.
We have to use a solution.
So what is the solution?
The sun is shining.
Test energy means trust, but verify
is trust, but verify.
We are trusting that already
it is working.
But we are going to verify also
whether it is working correctly or not.
Remember, I give you an example.
Presents of an element is fine
after presence, the text is visible
according to our requirement or not.
That is verification.
And that's what test and assertion does.
We verify the text
according to our own requirement
if username field is available.
At this point, I don't have any concern
that I get it right.
I trust you. What? I need your password.
It's like that.
Okay.
All right.
So now you see what it says.
Trust but verify.
Assertion is for the form to compare
the actual result with expected result.
We are signing one value.
We are going to get one value.
So one which we are signing.
This is the expected one.
The one which we getting
that is the actual one
which we are getting from the program.
Remember I wrote Driver to get title and
then storing this title into one string.
This is the actual one which is coming
the program from the application.
At the same time, I am putting
one more value as expected value, right?
So these are expected
when you will be compared
by test and assertions with actual value.
If both is expected and actual values
are equal, then my assumption is passed.
Otherwise my assumption is fake.
Clear
students clear
in as best
an assertion is performed
with the help of a third class.
I just showed you that a third class
will this asset class once again.
This also
helps
us to verify the conditions of the test
and decide
whether their case has been or passed.
Right.
It is most popular
and frequently used methods in testing.
Creating selenium is obviously
without verification and validation.
There is no point of writing this
and in the script
we need this verification
validation check points earlier
before using this a false condition.
But this events condition is of
no use for us.
So we are using a set of transponder test
and this is very important.
Let's suppose in selenium
there will be the situation in the test,
but you need to check
the presence of an element.
All you need to do
is to put in a statement on to it
to verify its existence. Right.
This is very simple use.
It is easy to show you how.
And the next is was this assertion
in the title position asserts
helps us to verify
the conditions of the test and decide
whether test is very low cost
fine test is considered successful
only if it is completed
without any exception.
There are two types of assertions
we are going to study guides.
How many types of assertion?
Yes, if
we are already in the second class.
Correct.
Because the slides has been slowed
or designed according to the
three hour sessions. Right.
But right now
we are having five hour session.
So obviously we have to take
some data from six plus two.
Okay.
So I will try to complete your entire test
individually, take minimum four classes.
I will try to completed in three
or three and a half so I can give you
some extra time before starting
with their test and do framework like
I'm taking care of it. I'm on it.
Don't worry about it.
Fine.
So now, now you'll see here
there are two types of assertions
we are going to use.
The first one is hard assertion
and the second one is soft assertion.
Now what is hard assertion?
What is soft assertion?
We will discuss this after something,
right?
First, we will see one type of assertion.
So currently,
currently we are going to verify
hard assertion by
we call it hard assertion.
I will then you that also why we need soft
assertion.
I will tell you that false right.
First we will implement harder solution.
We try to implement our test case and then
I will give you the difference in just a
Now if you see here, there are several
methods,
many, many methods
we will be having inner effect, right?
This assumption of testing a third class
from testing has all of these metrics.
So for example, if we have to compare
two things, assert once,
if you have to check
whether things are there not then assert
true or assert false, right?
These are the conditions we can check.
Let me show you all of this method.
See if I'm going to write is also dark
dark.
A third dot assert equals can you see
assert equals four following feature
values to by to get it third to long note
then any of integer short byte of bite
of a separate editable long object
everything assert equals right.
All of these metrics
see this much not equals.
Again, if you want to check to say to map
to flow to the way to object
right over your data methods
assert
throws assert to assert equal state.
All of these things
we want to use assert equals.
Right.
So I am having a string
and expected
to string it actually string to string.
So I need to check for the string
where in the spring I will check.
This is my string. Right? I can write.
It is giving me first
the actual value comma.
The expected text.
Right is
just one line of assertion.
And then I'm bringing one method here.
I'm going to write.
I'm writing so much python code nowadays.
So since everything is in Python minority,
I am executing after a session now.
See this time.
This time,
if I'm executing, what would happen?
You will see the difference.
Let me running all.
It's like a monkey and humans.
No monkey
got to
do much
in is today's.
Now see here
it is giving you the validation of faith
and is paid right in the actual part.
It is the now see it is thing.
The expected you're expecting
is human management system,
but you are getting human management since
it is giving you this type of solution
where you are getting the value right.
This is coming from the wrong time.
This is the one you are passing in.
You see everyone, students
Good morning, everyone.
All the geniuses
already.
Wait just ten more minutes in the class.
Please be just ten more minutes.
Not going to push you for entire 5 hours.
I leave you 10 minutes.
Only just ten more minutes.
Are you guys ready for ten more minutes
for your complete engagement? You
think? No.
It's like is not slow.
I mean, I barely get the message.
It's next line.
Fine.
So now you see here
this expect didn't actual value.
Also it is giving you here
you have to click to see the difference
the difference between simplicity and also
you will see the complete information
it is giving you test in a feel
right solution is speed bias.
Action is fail because intentionally I'm
rejecting because I just wanted to show
you human management system
and human management system.
It is also giving you
not only giving you the error
but also giving you their differences.
Earlier,
the same implementation we were using
with the offensive statement,
it was giving you the pass
for validation of data
and now it is giving you the field.
Can you see
it is giving you the feel this time
why it is giving you fail
because you are using one of the test
and stick is harder and.
Harder Session sees what is hard session.
Basically high definition means job.
I should do that for the exceptions
and errors a lot.
Right?
So basically what is hard session?
It means when error comes.
First of all, execution starts.
How hard assertion
the one which we have implemented here.
This is hard session.
If error came here,
it means the execution stops
because execution is stop the we didn't.
This line I'm executing after the session.
It didn't execute anything here right
inside this block of good first thing
so they can think it will give the result
at the same time right at the same time.
So we can write this
only in a single name.
This is what we see.
Hard decision now.
Psychosocial, slightly different than this
hard decision.
All right.
We will implement that later.
Now, let me write it intentionally.
Correct.
Come on, take me
here.
One more thing. One more thing.
Let me execute.
Once I going to edit.
One more thing you can put here.
You can put one more comma
and then you can write message.
Also, you can see by default
it took message.
What values are not seen?
This message will be printed only
if there is an error in the assertion.
See, this message will be printed
only if the assertion exist.
Right.
If there is an error in the assertion,
then it will give you the difference.
And with the difference
it will also give you this.
Give it a message. Now.
Now, if you go back below it,
you see it says
Java Lang assertion
Error values are not seen
right.
It is not only giving you the difference,
but also it is giving you
the message which you are mentioning here
in your assertion.
So the moment you provide this message,
it will give you
some additional information, right?
I hope everyone can see this
and let's go
ahead and implement it correctly.
So I'm going to write this system.
You will find it like this
that after some time
your cell
goes to spend one month with us
from this. Now.
Now we bought this to get this past.
Right.
But we didn't get anything.
Just one message I got which message.
It says this when I'm executing
after a session
by if you're a session is passed.
Right.
If you're not passing anything,
anything which is problematic, it means
your assertions, values are correct,
then there will be no message.
There will be no warning, there will be
nothing, no comparison analysis, Right.
It will allow you to execute.
It will allow your program
to execute further piece of code.
It will give you the complete report.
All right.
This is the function of hard assertion.
Again, I'm the only thing harder solution.
We have used the
what is the definition of hard assertion?
Hard assertion simply means the moment
it gives the error,
it will stop the execution first.
It will give you the message
if you have provided one,
or it will give you the difference
in between your expected value
and the actual value.
Correct?
Correct. Case
file Right.
Now, tell me, guys,
indirect tributes
from the installation explanation
while creating the first test
and the driver class.
Everything. Yes, yes, yes. And I know
we have created so many classes.
We have written too much code.
These attributes and everything is there
is there anything is there anything
you guys didn't understand?
But is there anything
you guys have any problem?
If yes, I'm giving you
three to ask the questions and everything.
I'm here to resolve your problem
for the next 15 minutes.
Also, I don't have any problem in that.
Please ask the questions.
I want resolve all of your ideas inside
the session.
Pixel
is related to
your implementation
is related to your sighting
of the environment, downloading the jobs,
writing the code, anything
short, I will send this
code to you.
All we are creating for every single topic
new class.
Like we are just taking the code
from log in so that it will save our time.
You'll see what enable disable.
We have different class
for logging as different solution,
different precondition priority different.
Right.
So I'm using different class
for different concept.
I'm just taking the code to log in
this one
it is public unit.
There's two classes.
It is a public one.
That's why it is open unit test
class. Yep.
So first I'm going to commit this code.
Yeah, the slides I will share you
maybe in the canvas.
Okay, Sure, sure.
I will definitely take care
of all this things.
Take it. S right.
You'll see.
System
with small lesson system with capital S
Definitely like I try
to do that.
Yes, we will add comment also.
I think that gives us additions for sure.
Definitely.
How can I see the method?
We know the classes,
we're below the classes.
I didn't get that here.
You just need to click on this one.
The expansion
pink one, right?
So you just need to click here on
you have to click on this part.
I'm not sure then why?
Maybe I have to check that already, guys.
So no one has any question.
A social part for a second. Sure.
There you go.
This is the assumption part, right?
So that that's what I'm saying.
We will take it as a suggestion
and I will put the commands also there.
Right.
Whenever I write new code,
I should if I have already committed
the code right just now I can.
We did this already did.
Let me show you in the repository.
So I just completed work.
Can you see?
3 minutes ago I committed this code.
All right,
so homework you guys have got, right?
I gave you the homework.
I'm going to give you the slides
also from here, right?
For class two and three,
You just need to read the slides.
Fine.
So you can go through this slides
before our next lecture
that we will having the model slide
in canvas for sure.
Definitely. I may give you this.
Anything else that you need from my site?
Great. All right, guys, Then.