Protesters.
Can you hear me
as goes on this honeymoon?
That's right.
Sup, guys?
How are you?
Yes, you. It's
to test us.
Guys, thanks for waiting.
I had some issues
setting up.
Let's see.
First of all, is this Jenkins class at my.
In the right class.
Okay, cool.
So, what's up, guys?
How are you?
What's going on?
How's everyone?
So, who is here today?
Ekaterina or Mont
and Lenny? 100.
Some dominate I.
That's right.
I think I don't know where asker is.
Maybe he's on his honeymoon.
I know he got married.
Omran Mohammed Zuma lna.
Guys,
this is
your last classes.
That's it.
This is the right thing.
Was, like, four months ago.
I kind of told you
that syntax was going to have to.
What was it, five months ago?
I told you that sentence
was going to be really intense,
but try to tell you not to quit.
The time was going to fly by so quick.
And now we are. That's it.
This is the end.
We are at the finish line.
That's it.
This is it.
So how about this?
We have a topic to discuss,
which is Jenkins.
Okay.
Can you guys see my screen?
Really?
I was just writing some notes down here
for you guys.
Just.
And I'll send all this information to you.
Okay, sir.
Hey, how are you?
Nikolai. Elena.
Amar.
It's really good to see you
on your last day.
Yeah, well, tomorrow.
But tomorrow is going to be easy.
Last.
This is a short.
Congratulations.
You are just two weeks away
from discovering your true potential.
Who's excited?
I was excited for the market.
Was. Was motivated.
And who needs motivation?
Who's who's motivated
and who needs motivation?
Both.
I don't know your personal reasons, but
try to remember
why you started this whole thing.
All right.
If that's not enough motivation, then
all I can tell you is that
that the I.T.
field is a wonderful, beautiful
field,
big field with endless opportunities.
And these type of opportunities,
you don't find them in many places.
You know.
Consider yourself
lucky to be in the industry.
Got endless opportunities.
Always room for growth.
You know, you can make a name for yourself
and be who you want, you know, And.
And you go from there.
And that should already be motivating.
You know, that that's not it.
And I hope the money motivates
you at least,
you know, to go this year.
How are you?
It's been a it's been a while, but
it's good to see you at the finish line.
All right.
So first of all, you know,
your interviews are coming up, right?
It's you know, it's time to study.
It's time to really, really study.
You'll find your own creative
ways to study.
You'll start with
I recommend a lot of reading,
you know, flashcards,
index cards, work on being able to,
you know, to properly
answer some questions
because I feel like a lot of you guys
do know the material,
but you guys probably don't know
how to answer some questions, right?
So that part is going to take time.
It takes time.
Right.
For example, if I asked you right now
in an interview, we're sitting right
across from each other and ask you in your
own words, what is in a room?
Can you answer that or not?
Right.
And if you can't, well,
you know what an array is.
You've worked with that. You used it.
But can you put it in your own words?
Can you talk about it?
Can you can
you answer the question? Right.
What is an ArrayList? Right.
What is it all?
Can you answer these questions?
So this this ladies and gentlemen,
it takes practice.
Does that make sense?
But it takes practice.
But most importantly,
you need to follow one.
One thing.
You know, you need to follow something.
And that's called
patients.
Okay.
Be patient with yourself.
Okay, Cool.
You know, understand yourself.
Respect yourself.
You know, be patient with yourself.
You're going to achieve
what you want to achieve with patients.
Yeah. Cool.
Tomorrow. Welcome to class.
Is that a show up?
Very good.
All right, questions or not,
before we start
this class, are you guys ready
or you guys ready?
You guys already know things.
I expect you to take your own notes down.
Okay, That's.
That's kind of, you know, standard by now.
Take your own notes, ask questions,
and we'll go from there.
Okay, So, Jenkins.
Okay. What is Jenkins?
Maybe you may have Googled it.
You may have watched YouTube videos on it
and stuff like that.
I want to say something about Jenkins.
Jenkins is very, very easy
topic and it's very easy to talk about,
but it's actually considered a buzzword
in in the industry
because of many reasons like
women,
you guys, we only have 49 participants,
but I've been to like
the rest of the class
is this is this is is the attendance here?
That is not what it is.
I thought at some point we had like.
So you guys made the cut, right?
You guys made the cut.
So, all right, you guys made it.
So congratulations.
Right. More doubts for you.
Right? So, anyway,
Jenkins is a is is a buzzword.
A buzzword.
When I use when I say buzzword,
I mean like a word that
just goes
and spreads around that people talk about.
Other people say,
but they don't understand what what it is
or what it means.
Okay.
I've interviewed a lot of people
when it comes to the topic of Jenkins.
They they freeze,
they kind of stop, you know,
and they don't know what to say
even though it's on the resume.
So, you know, it's very easy.
And that's the whole point of today's
class.
And tomorrow's class promised promise
to go easy because it's the finish line.
But here we go.
So Jenkins is considered a CIA tool.
Jenkins is a CIA tool.
This means continuous.
Continuous integration.
But what does continuous integration.
Meaning?
Okay, so
what does it mean?
So first of all, a lot of companies
use Jenkins.
And Jenkins is not the only CI tool.
I was going to organize some military you
there are other tools out there
that you can look like bamboo build bot
Travis CI GitLab and that kind of stuff.
Right.
But the thing is
that with continuous integration,
it means to continuously integrate
your code.
Okay.
But the reason it
became so popular was because
a long time ago and I don't
think you will experience this at work,
but before you could be like
in a development team,
let's say a team of of five developers
and let's say every developer
is, you know, committing code.
And when I commit code,
I mean pushing code to like GitHub or
whatever, what, whatever their source code
management tool is, right?
Like you guys are using GitHub, right? So
you guys imagine you're working with like
five of your teammates
and you're continuously pushing code.
But the thing is that with that team,
a lot of this organization, a lot of,
you know, let's say
Mohammed Mohammed pushes this code
and then 3 hours later, Alana
pushes her code and then 3 hours
later, Allen pushes his code.
But when it came time to run the project,
maybe something felt
right and they don't know what failed.
Okay, I'm not blaming you, Allen,
So I'm just saying, does that make sense?
Like Mohammed works, He pushes his code,
then Alana pushes are called.
2 hours later,
Allen pushes this code 2 hours later.
And then when it's time
to run the project, it sells.
It felt So then Mohanad, who
was the first person to commit his code,
he kind of starts to feel like,
What happened?
I pushed this code
like 6 hours ago and now you're telling me
that it's failing, right?
So to continuously integrate your code
and let me just add some words, you know,
continuous integration and continuous
continuous
use development.
So that's why they call it a C. ICB
is a CI
KB tool.
This means this read.
As soon as Mohammed pushes
this code, the project will run.
Okay.
And if it runs good,
then Alana can push her code
and then when she pushes her code,
the project will run
and then if it fails,
then she is notified immediately.
Does that make sense?
That means that she can fix her stuff
right off the bat.
She can. She'll get the results.
Maybe it could have been an issue
with with Mohammed.
But the whole point of that was that
when Mohammed pushes this code,
the project will we call it build?
Okay. That's what I mean by running.
When it when the project builds,
everything is good,
Then that's good, right?
But when there is an error,
you can be notified immediately
and you don't have to wait
for everyone to push their code.
So this is where the idea of Jenkins came
came,
you know, came about.
Does this make sense so far?
I know that it's kind of a little tricky
to talk about, but
all of these things get created,
for one thing.
Efficiency, right?
For efficiency.
That's that's why these tools get created.
So then they took it to a next level.
For example,
let's say you have a team with five
developers and Allen to mine on this here.
They're all working,
They're all developers,
they're pushing their code,
everything is working right.
But now they can design,
they can design their Jenkins jobs
to like for if they're
when their project builds and everything.
So when the project successfully builds,
then guess what?
Then they can trigger
your selenium test automation right away.
You don't have to.
Allen doesn't have to.
Do you know, the development team
doesn't have to test tonight and then wait
till tomorrow morning to message the queue
and say, Hey, testing is ready, right?
What can happen is
if you have your test automation,
which is your which are your cucumber
selenium test kit test cases,
as soon as they push their code
and everything works,
then they can trigger your automated tests
without you having to do anything.
Which is really cool right?
And then will your test automation pass?
Well, hopefully.
Right.
And if it all passes, then that's good.
If something fails, then you and your team
get notified of any failures.
And so the developers, because developers
want to know if anything
had felt like this, Does that make sense?
Guys?
Why does that make sense?
So that is the whole point of this idea
of of CI CD the right Lumos.
Okay, if I'm a developer,
I want to push my code.
If my code is good,
then execute Lumos test cases right?
Another thing is that we're going to talk
about is scheduling, scheduling jobs.
Right? Scheduling jobs.
There's an interview question
that I'm going to ask you right now.
And maybe you know the answer to this.
Maybe you don't.
But what do you do in your project
to ensure the stability
of the application?
Go? What do you do in your project,
in your project,
to ensure the stability, stability of
the competition?
What do you do?
Go ahead. Take a shot sensor.
You don't know. That's okay.
Take a shot.
Someone. So check requirements.
Very good.
That's right.
Muhammad Smoke tests.
You run your smoke tests, right?
There's smoke test.
Remember when we talk about
the different type of testing, right.
We said that smoke tests
are can be run every day.
And this is just to check the stability
of the application, because just because
your test case is passive, it doesn't mean
they're going to pass tomorrow.
Right.
Does that make sense?
For example, let's say you have a scenario
that's logging in,
everything is working,
the logging button's working,
but then all of a sudden tomorrow
the logging button doesn't work.
Okay?
So as long as you understand that,
then we're good
questions.
Questions are not right.
So you run your smoke test.
So another cool thing about Jenkins
is that you can schedule your smoke tests.
You can't and you can schedule it to
maybe your project wants you
to schedule them at midnight, right?
Maybe your schedule.
Maybe you want to schedule them at 7 a.m.
The whole point is that you actually
don't have to be working.
You don't have to be on your laptop
at all.
You can just live your life,
go to sleep, wake up tomorrow,
and then wake up to see reports,
to see what happened.
Okay.
Does that make sense?
But you don't have to wait.
You don't have to wait.
Now, it sounds too good to be true, right?
But you can do it now.
One of the most common problems about
running your or, you know, running
your test automation on Jenkins
is that you get random failures
all the time.
Okay.
Different failures, like maybe
the server was down or maybe
your automation failed
because the execution time was too fast.
Right?
And you'll get like a you'll get like,
you know, such elements, right?
Or element not interactive
or some exception from the web driver.
Right.
But the thing is that
when you run it on your local machine,
when you run these test
cases on your local, they pass
this.
Does that make sense?
So there are some things
that some workarounds that you may have to
to do in your test cases
so that your test cases can pass
when you run them on.
JENKINS For example,
if you're getting a not
so you're running your test case
and everything is passing
in your local machine.
But when you run it on Jenkins,
it's failing.
You're getting a no such element exception
somewhere.
Okay, what would you do?
Like you're running that same test
case on your laptop right now.
It runs. Everything passes.
But on Jenkins, it's failing
because of this. So what?
What would you do?
Okay, cool.
Explicit. Wait, wait.
I you that gets passes that's 20.
Exactly.
So the idea is that you would add
some sort of weight, right?
You add some sort of weight.
Cool.
All right, perfect.
All right.
So that's pretty much Jenkins.
And if you understand Jenkins,
then that's cool. So,
look, you can monitor when you guys want
to interview them and ask you, do you use.
JENKINS Yes.
You can say no if you don't feel
comfortable with it, but you can say yes.
What do you do with Jenkins
Well, I monitor,
monitor and schedule jobs
and just get the jobs right.
What jobs?
You schedule world, you schedule
or smoke tests
or smoke test and regression
regression tests.
However, for regression like
and I'll tell you this, we actually don't
have a scheduled job for regression,
but we have a job for regression.
Why is that?
How often do we execute regression?
Do you remember?
That's
another interview question
that you should be able to answer.
So the question is right.
How often right did you
execute your
regression tests?
Yeah, when updates are made.
Well, not really.
When updates are made,
every spin at the end of each sprint.
Yeah, sure.
At the end of every sprint.
Right At the end of every sprint.
Like for example, if
the developer is working on a user story
and they develop that user story,
but they have like
ten more user stories to work
on, are you going to execute your whole
regression test because of that,
or is it a better idea for them to finish
what they're doing completely?
And then you can run your regression tests
this way?
Exactly.
So your regression test
aren't run every day.
Okay.
They're probably run every sprint
or every two sprints
or you know what the best answer is?
They are executed prior to a release.
Okay.
Regression so or executes
either or at least the work prior rates
before. So.
And what is it? Release.
Oh, man.
What is a release?
And by the way, you're probably asking
yourself, how is this related to Jenkins?
Right.
And I'm going to explain why,
because later on
we're going to have to talk
about what DevOps is. Okay.
And this is all part of DevOps,
by the way.
DevOps stands for Development Operations.
Okay.
But we are going to discuss that at the
after we cover this stuff, right?
So what is a release? Does anyone know?
Does anyone want to take a shot of
what is a release?
A release is a deployment, Yes, a
release is a deployment to what?
To what guys?
To production.
Right. You are like you've paid attention.
Wait to go right
alone. I'm. I'm proud of you. I'm.
I told you five months ago
I believe in you.
Right.
So a release is a deployment
to production.
Let's talk more about what is a release
and how often is deployment to production.
Okay.
How often
stage deployments
are production?
And ladies and gentlemen,
I just want to say something to you. US.
It's very important
that you are paying attention
to these questions
because these questions that I'm literally
telling you right now that I'm asking
you right here, these are the questions
where students get stuck.
Do you know why they get stuck?
Because they didn't care to pay attention
or they didn't care to learn this.
They thought it was important. Okay.
So if I were you and you're
in front of the laptop right now,
write these questions down on your
on your notebook.
Okay.
These questions are incredibly important.
All right.
I had a student that got a six figure job
just by answering these questions. No.
So then it was just, by the way,
most of the questions.
No job, no questions,
just questions like this
is gone, which are very easy.
Questions, concerns, comments.
Guys, are you guys they're less excited.
Are you guys mentally checked out?
What's going on? Guys?
You guys need more energy.
We need we need energy.
Guys, I'm not I'm not
feeling the energy of this class
now. So what's going on, guys?
What? Talk to me. What? What is the issue?
And by the way,
if you need me to repeat something, ask.
Say it. I'll repeat it.
Okay, I repeat it.
All right. Came from work.
Tired and hungry. It's okay. I understand.
Take your time, you know, get some food.
Do what you got to do.
Writing things down. Cool.
And again, if you need me to repeat
something, don't be shy. Ask.
There's a lot of there's
a lot of students here
that probably have the same questions
that you do.
I've heard Jenkins is for developers.
No gen testers are using Jenkins.
My team uses Jenkins.
I use Jenkins all the time.
So it's not for developers.
Okay,
This is not going to be on canvas.
I'm going to share the notes
with you though.
But as you can tell, I'm
not going to write so many detailed notes.
I really want you guys
to listen and understand
and ask your questions.
Okay, So let's kind of recap
everything that we talked about
from the beginning of the class.
Okay.
So we talked about congratulations, right?
Because you guys made it.
You guys are gratitude,
this business right?
So you guys are you guys sorry.
This is your last classes.
I told you to be patient with yourself,
okay?
You have to be patient.
We said that Jenkins is a CI
CD tool for continuous
integration and continuous development.
We talked about what
continuous integration was, basically
to continuously integrate your code
with someone else's work.
Right?
So if Nas was a developer
and if he pushes his code
to his source code management tool
like GitHub,
he wants the test cases
to automatically run as soon as he pushes.
Well, first of all, his
his code needs to build code.
Once this code builds, then
then you can
design Jenkins to automatically trigger
his test cases.
Okay.
We talked about the idea of tools
like these being created, right?
And every tool is being created for one
purpose, for one purpose to make your life
difficult, to make your life harder
to use, to make it easier, right.
To help to see if they can find a way
to help your efficiency.
Right.
And then what can you do with Jenkins?
There's a future
where you can schedule jobs.
And there's a question here for you
What do you do in your project
to ensure the stability
of your application?
You run your small tests.
Does this mean that you have to run it
through automation?
And now
when you run your smoke test,
you can do it manually.
I was in a project once
where we were running our small test,
and by running I mean executing.
Okay, By running, I mean executing.
I'm going to put that here.
We're running.
I mean, execute
executing a smoke test manually, right?
It was just done over the top,
maybe like about 20 minutes, 20,
20, 30 minutes every day.
And with automation,
it took like 2 minutes
right?
So we talked about
random failures
and grand failures
with Jenkins, right?
We talked about this
with Jenkins, for example.
What do we say your Jenkins jobs
could fail because of what?
Like it could pass on your local.
You're running it on your laptop
server outage.
Maybe it went too fast. Right?
So you have to add some weight,
right? Different things like this.
This comes to show you. Right.
And this comes to show you.
Is Jenkins perfect?
No, it's it's actually not good.
It's like the idea of Jenkins
is fantastic, Right?
But a lot of things can get in the way.
Uh, yesterday,
which was Monday, and on
Friday, all of my Jenkins jobs at work
found all of them.
We had, like
27 Jenkins jobs.
They all felt
because of wait times.
Because of wait times.
We were curious.
We were like, Well, this is executed.
This is passing on our local machines.
Why is it failing?
Because of wait times in some areas.
Okay, so there it is.
Okay.
And when the developers
get the notification,
they're like, Hey, what happened?
Well, it's okay to say, Oh, our test cases
fell because we just it went too fast.
And they're like, okay, cool. Right?
So these are the issues that you will
most likely experience at work.
Yeah.
So we said that you can use Jenkins
to monitor and schedule jobs.
Monitor meaning like, you know,
check the status of your smoke test
or whatever tests
you're running, scheduled jobs.
You scheduled jobs to run your small test
and regression test.
Actually,
we don't schedule jobs.
You could you could
I haven't been on a project
where they schedule a job
for a regression.
Well, Lubo.
That is a fantastic question.
Right?
The question is,
why didn't you implement implicit
and explicit weights to begin with?
Well, here's the thing,
and that's a very good question.
An explicit weight
you have to explicitly specify
somewhere in your code
where you want that extra weight.
Right.
But what if everything's
passing in your local?
You don't know what step needs
that extra weight, right?
Does that make sense?
So you actually have to run your test
cases to find out where it's felling?
Yeah, that's thing number one.
Thing number two is,
is the implicit weights,
the first of which are good idea.
But they here's the thing,
there's something called
the Selenium.
Selenium JSON wire protocol, right?
I didn't want to teach it to you, but so
I would talk about it. Okay.
So if you go on Google
and you type in Google
Glass, type in, do you saw
wire protocol, selenium?
Okay.
This right here actually discusses
the architecture of the Web tracker.
Okay.
And how the Web Java actually works.
Right.
So this is the concept of
you writing your code with Java Selenium.
Okay.
And you can write it
anywhere.
You can write it using anything, right?
You can use Python,
you can use JavaScript,
you can use Ruby,
you can use different programing languages
with Selenium to
to perform your test automation.
However,
your the browser,
the Chrome browser is not designed to read
Java code, it's not designed
to read Python or JavaScript.
It's not designed to
to read any of these languages.
So how does this really work
on the architectural level?
Okay.
Does anyone know
when you write your code
in Java and Selenium?
Okay, you guys all you guys know, as do
you guys just hit this play button, right?
Or you guys run your runners.
It's like just click,
not play, but. Right.
How do you think how do you think
this request gets made to the browser?
And now I can talk about this
because you guys did.
I heard you guys had the most amazing
API testing classes.
Web Java interface takes care of it.
No, not really.
What what what do you guys think?
I'll tell you this.
You guys had the most amazing Web services
classes, right?
So when you guys make this request,
okay, your Java
will have this open.
See your Java and Selenium code
actually get converted into the request,
gets converted into it.
JSON object.
Exactly. Very good.
And it needs the help of a web
service to help transmit that code.
What is the name of that web service?
What is it?
I mean, it's it's a rest API,
but what is the name of the what?
The rest assured it's not a web service.
Rest assure as a Java library.
Okay.
That's that's not a web service.
What is a
it's a restful web service.
Yeah, we already said it.
Russ API RESTful Web service.
You don't rest. Webster.
It's all the same thing.
Except rest assured us is, first of all,
are we clear with it?
Guys, rest assured is not a web service
register.
Sure, it is just a Java library.
That's just the name of it.
It's not Rest API.
Okay, But there is a web.
There's an API that is going to be used
to transmit that request.
You guys know what it is?
Yeah.
Unit is also library.
No, those are those are methods guys.
I'm talking about a web service.
There's an API.
It's called the Chrome driver.
It's called the Gecko driver
or whatever browser
you are communicating with.
Right. That is the web service.
That is what's going to transmit
that request to the browser.
Okay.
And when the browser,
the browser will understand
the JSON object.
Right. And they will execute
whatever it's going to execute.
Well, guess what?
When you make a request to a server,
expect
a what?
When you make a request
to a server, expect a response.
Right?
So the server is going to
the browser is going to respond.
Okay with
you know what
the JSON bar protocol says
that it's going to respond with.
Right.
And it tells you
here is a very really so resource
to understand, you know
selenium web driver a period right.
Look at this.
It tells you if this response
responds with code
seven, throw a no such element exception.
Right.
If if it throws code eight,
that means that there is no such frame.
Right. Look at that.
You guys have seen these exceptions
before. Right.
Still element reference exception element
not visible element is not selectable.
No such window.
Have you guys seen these exceptions
before?
It looks very familiar. Right.
I hope that you guys have seen
these exceptions before right.
So but the thing is that it's responding
with these codes and then the web service
is just converting, you know, printing out
whatever has to be printed out right.
You guys probably didn't know that,
but now you do and you see
response status codes
and go ahead, read this.
If you want to learn
more about how all of this works, good.
You don't
have to talk about this during interviews.
Right.
But back to what's his name,
the question that he asked Lubo.
Right. But this was your question.
Right.
Back to how that works.
And let me tell you, I think I ran
the automation here on this project.
I want to show you
there's something where the your reports
get stored
when you reports in the target folder.
I hope you know that. Right.
And then it gets stored in a cucumber
about JSON files.
So this is the report that gets generated.
Okay, This is the report.
Now, this is a JSON object.
You guys know how JSON object looks like.
My question is and look, it's
a very small test case.
You can kind of see here
the timestamp, the time it was wrong,
the duration, the location, basically.
What did you run that
name of the scenario?
B Now the stat is red.
Here's the thing. This is a report right?
Is this the report
you want to give to your team?
Like I'm going to give this to you
and say, hey, here's my report for today.
They're probably going to read it.
And if you give it to if you give it to
to your project manager,
they're going to be like, what is this?
I don't understand this. Right.
I don't get it.
And if you remember in class,
have you guys generated cucumber
reports?
Exactly.
So this is the first report to get
generated, which is something that is
specified in your pump that X And now,
ladies and gentlemen.
Right.
Let's let's go down here and let's see
what the situation is with our plug ins.
And this you can do this with any project,
by the way you go to them,
maybe a project it uses the help of.
Sure.
Plug in that's used to generate that
JSON report and is used to execute
your test cases using maybe
command statements in the terminal.
Okay.
That's what your favorite plug in is.
The one that gets generated.
We use another plug in called the Maven
Cucumber reporting provided by net
dot Master Thought
and this is what converts that JSON file
to that nice, beautiful cucumber
HTML report that you guys generate.
Does that make sense?
This is a MAVEN report.
So if you want to execute a MAVEN report,
you must specify that
in the heart of the MAVEN project,
which is the palm dot X amount.
Cool.
Does that make sense?
I feel like I gave you so much information
there, like in like a minute,
like you guys have questions
or what's what's the
you guys good
questions concerns and you can do this.
Open your framework.
Take a look take a look. Right.
That is how these reports are generated.
So actually, I don't know if I have
a report.
I don't have a full report to show you.
Okay.
But if when we run it later,
I'll show you and stuff.
Cool.
So and here's a thing.
Now that we've talked about these reports
and how JSON
protocol works and everything like that,
there's a question that Lobo asked.
He said, when you said this before,
Well, here's the thing.
The Jason protocol of the web,
Java is unreliable.
Okay?
And what does that mean?
Okay, That means that Lobo can
explicitly specify in his code.
Wait up to 15 seconds to do whatever he's
going to do with that Elemental element is
present or element is visible
and that kind of thing.
Right?
But the thing is
that sometimes execution happened so fast,
especially when you run
your test automation in headless mode,
which is what we're going to do as well,
to the point where it actually doesn't
wait 15 seconds, you know what I mean?
Like, it'll probably just wait
like 6 seconds and process it as it waited
15 seconds because of the execution time
being so fast.
Okay.
Some ways to get around
this is by increasing
the explicit wait time by a lot longer.
Okay.
The thing is, with that problem
is when you specify a very long
wait like that,
like a minute or like 2 minutes,
and if the Jason protocol
is being reliable in that execution,
it's going to take a long time
to find that element.
Okay.
Now, I know one
minute it's not a long time, but still,
does that make sense?
So everyone
and you kind of need to be careful
because if you have very, very long test
automation case,
long test cases,
let's say it takes 15 minutes to execute.
We have at work a single test case
that takes about 30 minutes to execute.
So if I'm going to go in there,
implement like explicit
weights everywhere, you know,
you could easily prolong that 30 minutes
to maybe 45 minutes
sometimes, you know, So
you kind of have to decide where you want.
Now, you may need to say this
in the interviews, Right.
This is this concept is important
to at least be able to explain
what these weights are, but also, it's
okay to use the hard sleeps.
It's fine, right?
You guys know that this lead method
from the thread class at Java Red
thread, that's deep
and you specify the time, right?
I was going to say time, right?
It's okay to put this. It's
okay to use this.
It's fine.
Just wait 2 seconds. Right.
Wait 3 seconds. That's okay.
Right.
And that's actually
what we do in our project, actually.
Yeah, you can say it. An interview.
I say an interview. Right.
But you're going to say, listen,
we tried to use the implicit
and explicit weights from the web Java
as much as we can,
but when that's not working, sometimes
we end up using hard sleeps, You know?
It's okay.
Say it.
So in your example right now,
you are running your test
from the palm that XML
or you were showing a dependency for it.
I was just showing the dependencies for
if I show like
how the reports get generated
and the architecture behind that
because look, you can run it,
you can run your
you can run your test cases
from your runner's classes, right?
You can just open your runners
right click run or whatever.
But that's not
in most cases, depending on
how you configure your your automation.
If you want to generate a MAVEN report,
then you need to run it from the Palm
or you need to run it in the Maven way.
Okay, do me a favor.
I don't have your project, okay?
You guys do me one favor, please.
Okay.
Can you guys run?
Just test case from your framework.
Just a single one. And,
like, just go to your runners, run it,
and then tell me
if a report gets stored in the first.
Do a maven clean.
You guys know how to do it?
Maven Clean.
Maven Clean does what?
Maven Clean does what
It cleans.
It cleans the target folder.
So when you run your when you're
when you run your runners
after Maven clean, then the reports
get stored in the in the target folder.
Right.
Okay.
And are they the beautiful pie charts,
Are they the
you know what some of the question marks
is it
under description to decide
what really part of my smoke does?
I want to know
what is the scope of my decision making?
Mohammad
You can talk to your team about it.
You can say, Hey, like
what do you consider like the most top
ten important test cases, right?
The most, like, so I can put them on here.
I can, you know, add them to my smoke test
and they will tell you
the question.
Yeah, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
No, I got confused.
Are you asking me a question
or do you want me to ask you a question?
I don't understand.
You said. Yeah.
And the question mark
we have
an X is the cucumber reports
like the pie charts?
Oh, that was a question.
So no,
let me
know.
Is it okay with you if I can ask you to
please repeat your question?
I just want to know.
I may have missed your question.
Last one. What do you mean, last one?
There's like a lot of comments here.
You saying question Mark
cleaned previous reports.
So I don't see a
sorry, I was asking your last question.
Okay.
My question is, can you.
Worries can you run your runners
first, do a maven clean
and then run your run?
Any runners just run a test case
and see if a report gets generated.
And if it does, can
you send me a screenshot of the report,
please?
Can you send me
a screenshot of the report?
Hope it's not a question.
Okay.
Go ahead and send me
a screenshot of the report.
No, no. The the pie chart report.
I think it's a start on that.
Is it
cucumber that html?
I'll do this, do this.
Is that how awesome I seem? See?
Okay. You're using intelligence.
Can you right click on cucumber
dot html can you right click on that
and when you right click on that
you should see something
like copy full path or something.
Right.
And when you copy that full path,
can you just open your Chrome browser
and paste it in the URL
search box and hit enter?
You should be able to see it.
Yeah. Open.
Aisha, what is this you're seeing?
There you go. Very good.
Nice.
Is it possible to view like this?
What do you mean, like this?
Oh, it doesn't look good like that.
I think. I don't.
I don't see.
Like,
I think you didn't copy the right one.
Maybe I saw.
That's interesting that it looks at.
This is what happens when you copy.
Okay,
cool.
Let's see.
All right. That's okay.
No worries.
Right.
But I need you to guys
to understand something.
When we generate what we call
MAVEN reports,
we can go to the renders and right
click and run the test.
We have to specify that.
And the pom that XML file.
I don't know if you guys ever installed
Maven.
Right.
I don't know if you guys ever installed.
Did you get.
No, but like did you guys, you did.
Okay, so can you open your terminal.
Are you guys
using the built in terminal and
you can use the terminal on
your laptop doesn't matter.
You can run it on the terminal.
Okay. Okay.
So now let me ask you this.
Let me do amazing clean.
Okay on my project.
Okay, cool.
Target folder is gone.
Now let me run a test.
Let me see something.
Okay.
So do you guys know how to run from your
terminal, or would you like to learn that
we know?
Tell me how to do it.
Maven test. Okay,
so that's all I have to do.
Maven test nothing else.
Maven clean test does that it
press enter? No.
All right, So of course I'll show you.
So open the pom and where you have
your Sure fire plug in here.
Can you guys go here.
You see.
I see we're configured.
You guys have configuration or. No.
The configuration tag.
You guys have this here.
Okay.
And the US have the includes tag like I do
and then here you're specifying
it. Runners.
Let me comment this out so that you guys
can see better,
which is how you commit an X amount
because this is an X and Y file.
And the reason I want to show you this
and if you understand it,
you're going to understand
everything much better.
So go ahead and save it.
Here.
You have to specify
the name of your runners.
Okay?
Your name of your runners. Cool.
So go ahead and do this, guys in these.
Sure.
Fire, plug in, Specify
the name of your runners class,
the one that you want to run
and is to be spelled the exact same way.
Then that Java. Okay.
Do you guys go ahead and do that
right now?
Please?
You guys can go ahead and do that
right now
are greatly appreciated.
I'm going to try to generate a report
for you
And guys, I'm here to help
you have questions.
Ask like, you know,
I want you guys to be able to
to to do this
includes dot, dot, dot small.
Okay. So you know what that means?
That means that you want to execute
any runners class that ends what?
Smoke.
You can do that as well if you want.
Yeah, you can do that.
That's fine.
As long as you specify something there
that's going to work.
That's okay. Right?
So I'm going to go to the terminal.
If you go ahead and open the terminal, do
Maven clean from the terminal
to clean the target folder.
Okay.
And see, this was the one that I want.
Both Right.
Can you please go back to your palm?
Yes, sir.
Or let's see
right here.
Absolutely right here.
This is what you need. Okay.
The configuration tags, right?
Or Madam? I'm sorry.
It was just a habit. Yes, madam.
But do you guys see this
right here?
You guys need this, this.
This whole thing.
If you guys don't have it.
But it looks like you do, because
I've often said that it's included it
in his
in his.
Perfect. And you've specified something
here, right?
I think you guys have that dot, dot star.
Whatever.
The star star slash star does start smoke,
right.
And see Mohammed's.
All right, cool.
Right.
So open your terminal.
Do even clean
the end
and get clean.
And then make sure you get to build
success.
Just clean your target folder. Got.
And then we can simply do ambient test.
Okay, like MAVEN test,
let's see what happens.
So if I do MAVEN test, it's
going to start compiling.
Once the code, once a project compiles,
then it's
going to start to build and the build
is going to happen right here.
As you see,
as I'm running a completely different test
case, ignore what I'm running.
Just run.
Whatever you're running.
Okay, so I'm doing this.
This is just application.
Let's going to be automated.
Execute it.
It's just a form, right?
We see it here.
Go ahead and run yours. Please
go ahead and run yours.
And let me know when you guys
have finished running your work code
right. So.
All right, slow.
You said slow.
What is your slow?
Are you saying that you are slow
service website?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Build success.
Nice.
It's all right.
Go. Nice job.
The same. Very good.
Very good. Very good.
All right, then. Well, all right.
Test case done. You guys ran yours.
Beautiful, Right?
And then the target folder
will now have the cucumber HTML reports.
Okay, cool.
You see how you can have the.
Do you guys have something similar
to what I have is called
the overview hyphen features
or feature or something like that.
Can you take
can you take a screenshot of your target
folder and short show to replace?
Took a screenshot of your target. See?
Yeah. There you go. Perfect. Beautiful.
All right, so let's
rank.
How do you guys open this in the browser?
Right click.
Was it copy relative pass?
Let's see
here.
Yes. Nope.
Wasn't this one copy
on? Okay.
There you go.
See, I just copied the path of the report
and bam.
Well, all right, so you can open it.
You can see what's there.
And it looks like it looks like
there are no screenshots.
Which is
which. I don't know why they're not there.
We have to take a look.
Okay.
So you can see that
this whole scenario read.
You can see the hooks,
you can see the tags, right?
You can see all of that stuff go.
You can see the steps and so forth.
All right.
But now that you understand this, okay,
and you see, here's the email file
that got generated, which is in the form
all the jigsaw objects.
Well,
that's actually an additional document
that then gets converted to just an object
to generate that reports.
Okay.
Or I'm sorry, it got generated
from a JSON object to generate this page
HTML report, but because of the plugins
that you guys have,
that's why we see the beautiful HTML
pie charts kind of thing.
All right.
So the idea was that
we ran this from the Palms X amount.
Okay?
And this is exactly
what we have to do with Jenkins
code.
We have screenshots.
I mean, so the real questions
that screenshots questions,
any questions, guys,
any at all.
Anything.
So let's talk about one more thing, right?
Because
and this is all related to Jenkins,
by the way, everything we're talking about
is related to Jenkins.
Let me ask you this, though, okay?
And I want you to think about this.
You're the test automation engineer
in your project.
You got hired as a Q engineer.
You're doing automation.
And then okay, let's say
you don't have Jenkins set up,
you don't have Jenkins set up.
And they say, okay,
can you run the automation?
And then the most important
thing for management is what
the most important thing
for management is what
reports are reporting, right?
You don't just say,
I ran the automation, We're good, right?
You need to show a report.
So let's say you have Jenkins,
you ran this on your local
and then all of a sudden they say,
hey, has seen
can you share a report with us?
How would you share the report
with your team?
How would how would you share the report?
Does anyone know how you will
share the report with your team?
So you're saying that you would take.
No, not me.
Yours does take screenshot.
My task is didn't take screenshots.
Okay.
You'll get a says over email.
Okay, cool.
No, there's no get say.
There is no get
this is just your local machine
but okay you'll get over email.
Interesting.
How are you going to send it over email.
What are you going to do?
Send a link,
Send the link to the report and email.
Okay.
Mohammed.
Mohammed, you're saying
send the link to the report in the email.
What link are you talking about?
Alan We'll talk about that in just a bit.
You guys are saying the report link.
Okay, cool.
Share me the report link right now.
Show me the link to the report.
Any report
someone says attach it to my file.
It's very good.
You're going in the right direction.
This ATP report.
How did you get it?
Mohammed?
Why is it failing?
Okay,
it's failing, though.
I enter, I answer what you gave me,
but it's failing.
So What? Why?
It's like, Hmm.
That's right.
Yes. Nikola.
Very good, right?
Because that link that you share with me
will only work on your local machine.
Okay? Someone else sent me the some.
Someone else sent me the.
The path to your to your
to come report.
It's html email, email, double report.
Okay.
How would you do that?
By meeting.
Send presentation representation.
Now you need to send it to them.
So one, you can't send a pass, right?
Because the path is just going to be
the path to your local machine.
Does that make sense?
And like if you're using your local
and then I use it on
mine, it's not going to work.
We learn that we have reports of cucumber,
but no one actually told us
how to send those reports. Exactly.
Well, that's why I'm here with you
on the last day on the finish line.
Right.
I'm giving you everything you need to go
and be successful.
Right? That's it.
That was the whole point of this, right?
Because the whole point of this.
Okay, cool.
Let me tell you something.
This is going to be a fun fact.
You tell me
you guys said kind of the correct answer.
You're saying that you would email
the report.
Okay. How would you do it?
Right.
Well, let me
and you can try this on your own.
Right.
We have the the project here.
Let me minimize this.
So everything looks normal.
So we have the
the like everything here, right?
And if I go to the target folder
like you guys have and I open this,
I want you guys to get this overview,
steal
my report and upload it here on Slack.
I think you can do that.
So you're going to have to
button your target.
We said it's in the Cucumber HMO report
and it just when you see this,
I want you guys to send this to me.
I want you guys to do this
file right here.
If you can just go to your directory.
I want you guys to send me this file.
Oh, look at that.
Why is it pasting like that? Hmm.
Interesting.
Anyone else want to try?
Okay, now I want you to do this.
I want you to do this.
I wanted to get this to your mail report
and send it to yourself in an email.
Can you do that?
Send it to yourself in an email,
and then tell me what you see.
So tell me what you see.
Go ahead and do it.
So you see how it's sending it.
Sending
in a very weird email format, way. So
I just want
you guys to send it to yourself to see
you will see the report,
but you won't see the pie chart report.
Let me click on what Alex just sent
you. Just download, okay?
He downloaded this.
Okay, There it is.
Watch this.
So this is what he sent, right?
It looks like he was able to upload it,
but is this what you want? It?
Where are the pie charts?
Where's the pie chart?
By the way, this is what you will get
if you send it through email.
I mean, it says that the rotation,
it says the runtime,
the operating system that was used,
but where the pie charts, where is it?
Like the screenshots are here.
Okay, well, there's only one screenshot,
so click the link.
Which one?
This one
will link.
Okay, there's no pie chart,
but there's no pie chart.
All right. So the answer is this.
And I want you guys to understand
the structure of this,
because this will also apply to Jenkins.
Okay.
Again, everything that we are learning
and we're talking about right now,
all is related to Jenkins.
So I'm going to close this. Okay.
So back here,
if you want to send a report to your team
and if you want them to be able to see
the beautiful pie charts like the way
you're sending them, you actually have
to send the whole cucumber HTML report
folder and all of the contents in it.
Okay.
So again, if you want to send the report
this asiamah file
this report,
you need to send this whole folder
with all of the contents in it.
Only then will
you be able to see the report.
So someone, if you can,
please send me this folder here,
this one on Slack, please send me the
the some one of you guys
who read the text.
Send it
to me please.
Do we have any volunteers?
Any volunteers class.
You guys there?
That's just a pass.
I need to.
I need you to actually
upload the folder here
on Slack.
See it uploaded here.
That's not supported. It says on Slack.
Why is that?
Because it's probably too big, Right.
Added in. Is it added in. Is it.
It's failing every time.
Can you zip the file.
Too big, Too big for slack.
Zip it. How do you zip it?
Just copy the you can copy the folder.
We can go to desktop.
I pasted here.
Where is it?
Okay, I'm going to zip it, zip
it, compress it,
and then you can send this.
Can you guys send the zip file Too
big for Slack.
Even zip is too big.
We give it a try.
A type of file not supported in slack.
Okay, there it is.
Thank you very much.
The same. Let me open the zip file.
He was able to do it
so I'm opening the zip file,
which is right here
and now.
If I if I come this, I open the zip file,
I'm going to do the overview of futures.
We see
a copy.
There you go. Look at that. I can see it.
You see?
That makes sense.
So I'm able to see the report
that has team generated.
Okay, Now, he sent me the whole folder.
Okay, Does that make sense?
Cool.
Do we have questions?
Okay, so your email is is right.
So your answer was right.
You can email the zip file
and then the email just type in team.
Just click on the file.
That's called overview features
and then you will see the the report.
There must be an easier way for this.
Ahmed Yes, sir.
On the local machine
there is an unfortunately
there is not.
I mean you can always take a screenshot
of this and send it to them, right?
You can take a screenshot
of the report, right.
But you want to be that
QA engineer, right.
For right now
I showed you how to do it manually.
All right.
We have questions and thank you very much
for sharing the report.
See, thank you very much.
Does that make sense to guys?
Learn something?
Do you guys feel good about life?
Okay, cool.
So the question is,
now, let me ask you this again.
If you only had your local machine kind of
if you only had your local machine
and you had to share a report,
how would you do it?
Give me the answer.
Now that you guys know,
how would you do it?
I would.
How would you how would you do it?
Okay. Zip. What?
Zip. And him?
Zip. What exactly were you going to say
in an interview?
He is going to say zip
file, zip the cucumber folder.
The question was,
now that you know how to do this, I'm
going to ask the same question
I asked before
we showed you how to do all of this.
I said, How would you send your report
if you only had your local machine?
How would you send your Capcom report
zip and tie, cucumber folder,
cucumber, report folder and send it
via email.
Very good.
Go. Does that make sense?
All right. Very good. Very good, class.
So go ahead and take a Let's do
10 minutes.
So call. Come back. 825.
How do you
how often is it deployment to production?
That depends on how often your cut
your project has releases
and we're going to talk about that
if you want.
We're going to talk about this
because it's different for every project.
Okay.
So go ahead, guys,
and let's come back at 825.
All right.
Break down. That's right.
So you kavalan you want taking our review
on Asia, It's up to you.
We're going to start at 825.
You want me to take it?
You didn't take two days off
Going to do it. It's
all right. I will wait for you.
No worries.
All right.
And if you guys are here
and you guys have any questions,
please ask away.
Do you prefer your idea
better than until the day?
Absolutely.
The Visual Studio is amazing.
Yeah, it's very powerful as well.
Any questions?
Concerns?
Lots of guys.
As usual.
I thought I'd give you some extra time,
you know,
because you guys don't come back on
time for your break.
So it's all good.
And some of you guys are still on your
break.
So let's just wait.
Let's wait and let's wait. So
Lubo, Luba, Luba, Lupo.
It's okay.
Just let let's just wait for them
then take your 15, 20 minutes.
Whatever it's for. Lubo
What are the phases of
the software development lifecycle?
You just say next,
if you want to go to the next question.
Okay.
Write maintenance.
All right.
When the when does user acceptance
testing happen?
When does user acceptance testing happen?
Why would it be after deployment?
A Well, when you guys say deployment, like
what do you guys talking about deployment?
Where
final stage of development
not the final stage of development
because development is done.
What environments that
Oh man, don't
tell me you guys forgot these concepts.
These are concepts
that could get you a job that just
looks like we have to revisit them, right?
Looks like we have to revisit them.
That's all right.
Take a deep breath.
Yes, I know.
We're going to have to study.
It's all right.
Delivered to the customer.
What do you mean?
What is what do you say or what?
What's what does that mean?
Delivery to the deployment of the product,
to the customer.
We're going to talk about this.
Will you take some interview prep classes?
I actually I don't think I will.
I'm not sure.
Abdoul You're kind of right. Right.
But you need to think of it
in terms of to use the appropriate words
like, you know, when deployment is done
to the stage environment.
That's where they do their testing, right?
That's where the client tests.
Right. And
but the question is, when does it happen?
Right.
When when in your project does it happen?
And that's what we have to revisit
that we will revisit on that.
But I'm glad that you were able
to remember some of it.
So that's good
questions.
Anybody, when the test
when the test process theory, what is
are you asking me a question?
Oh, it does not start in the requirement
space.
Nope.
All right. Are we back? We are back.
So that's it.
I give you guys some time
and let's get this party started.
So listen to what I'm going to sing.
Okay? We are going to start with Jenkins.
We're just going to we kind of talked
about what Jenkins is, right?
We're going to go in there
and I'm going to tell you what to do.
Listen,
please follow instructions.
Please follow instructions
and please follow instructions so that
code, just like
if I tell you not to do something,
don't do it.
Remember, does those good old days
where we found out
that there were some kids in this class?
Do you guys remember?
Right, Exactly.
So this is I hope that you have.
If you were once a kid,
I hope that you have grown up
at this point in class.
Okay, So.
Well, let's hope for the best.
All right.
Remember, let's see how good you are
at following instructions.
Here is the
you out that I want you guys to use.
Okay, Take it, open it.
And I'm going to give you
your credentials.
Here is your username
and here is your password.
Okay.
This is yours
right here. Where is this super admin?
This is right here.
Your credentials right here.
Okay, Go ahead and log in these.
Okay, these.
And I want to see if this
based is here.
Okay.
This is for instructor.
All right,
so you guys have the credentials.
It's just simple.
It's admin.
Admin. Can
we have a non grown spirit?
Okay, I logged in to instructor
one at the beginning of class,
So Lumo log out.
And by the way, who told you to log in?
Who told you to log in?
I see it. I do it.
We'll her log.
We'll see how far that takes you.
Lumo do.
You should not have shown the instructor
only part.
I trust you guys.
You guys can follow instructions, right?
You guys can follow instructions.
We're a team here, right?
I don't
need to be hiding anything from you.
So, first of all,
do we have anyone from support here
to help us out today in case
we hit the wall
or we hit a wall?
And you want for support?
Am I the only one here today?
Anybody support online?
Yeah.
Go ahead and log in with your credentials,
which is admin.
Admin
all on me.
Goodness.
All right, well, let's get started.
All right, So log in.
And I'm going to log in
with my credentials.
The ones that say instructor only.
Okay, so this is yours.
Log on, please.
And I'm already logged in by the list.
When you guys log in, let me know.
Nice, nice, nice.
Very good.
It wasn't so hard, was it?
So this is Jenkins.
Let's talk about a few things here.
This is the what we see right here,
at least what most of us
are seeing right here.
And ignore all of this on top.
All these things that say pipeline,
everything like that.
I'll explain what a pipeline is.
If we have time tomorrow,
we will create a pipeline
just so that you can have an idea
on what it is.
It's not necessary.
And this is stuff that you
most likely will not be doing at work.
There's only so much a tester
does at work, at least from experience.
And I've been on multiple projects
where we've just Jenkins
If the developers are using Jenkins,
then they actually take responsibility
for a lot of the tasks
that happen on Jenkins.
So at most Okay.
And listen to this at most.
Jenkins You will use Jenkins
just to monitor it, schedules
your job, sets it
and what we're going to do
is we are going to create jobs.
We're just going to mess around with it.
We're going to play with it,
we're going to
do something and that's it.
Okay.
Does that make sense?
Now, the creating jobs
part, for example,
and I just kind of want to say this right?
When I create a smoke job,
you only
have to create it once
and you can just use that same smoke job.
I have using the same Jenkins job
as my project
for the last year and a half.
So it's actually been a year and a half
since I've created a new job.
Actually, no, I created one last month,
but aside from that,
it's really been a year and a half
since I created a job.
So you're not going to be required
to create jobs all the time.
Does that make sense?
Like, this is just the thing
that is pretty much done.
Like maybe once you just keep using it,
kind of like when you develop
your framework, you don't develop
your framework every right.
It's already developed.
Like if I were to ask
you exactly everything
that's in your Common methods class,
then you probably know what's in there.
But it's not like you're going to remember
the exact code of it
because you don't do it every day.
It's already been developed.
Does that make sense? That does.
Okay, so just keep that in mind.
But so this is what we're going to do.
So let's talk about this.
This a
Jenkins
UI, these pipelines ignore them here.
What we see is we see a status
and we see the weather
report.
Basically, depending on your build result,
Jenkins
likes to use
what they call weather reports,
which is kind of funny.
Okay,
because like if it passes, it's sunny.
If it felt there's like this
thunderstorm, scary
thunderstorm kind of thing they just knew
we had kids in this class, right?
So they were like,
hey, let's throw pictures in here.
Right.
And that that's that's what happened.
So To make this more interactive for you.
This was this was added here. Right.
And they say, hey,
I think picture with the sun
and some clouds just to show them
that their bills are inconsistent.
Maybe they will understand like this.
But anyway, you can see all the sun's
all the here
a little cute little sun's here, right?
And this means that it's good
everything passed.
Okay?
And here this means.
What do you think this means? Like fell?
I mean, do you think this means pass?
I mean, spell catastrophic? Exactly.
And you can see here
on the side, it's
also there's also a little circle.
And it just Right.
And then these say success.
Okay, when this one is like this color,
it just means it wasn't built.
Okay, cool.
All right. Okay.
So here these are all all of these, by
the way, are Jenkins jobs, each of them.
So I'm not sure how many we have here.
We have a lot.
Okay.
But just ignore all of these here.
Okay?
Does that make sense?
When we create a Jenkins job,
I'm going to tell you
to follow a naming convention
so that you can easily look up your dog.
Please don't touch anybody else's job.
Okay?
This is again, for your learning purposes,
you know, for you and stuff at work,
there may be some access limited to you.
So you may not, you know,
just don't don't,
don't just don't touch anyone else's job.
So let's click on new item on the left.
And as your naming convention, enter
first job.
Okay.
And put your name here.
Your name.
Okay. I'm going to let you do this first.
And by the way, don't type
your name, type in your actual name.
So for example, type in instructor
and instructor code.
You guys will put your name.
Let me know if you have any issues
following instructions.
Okay. Very good.
Very good.
Very good. Very good.
Okay.
You guys will also use we're going to use.
Okay, let's take this step by step.
So click on MAVEN project
because that's what we want to do.
And by the way,
you can create different types of jobs.
We can create pipelines
here, folders and stuff like that,
but click on me, then project
and then once this is done, as everyone
done, like you guys entered this,
you clicked on MAVEN project.
Okay, okay.
Does anyone need me to wait for them?
Anybody
know you're good?
Five, four, three, two, one.
All right, so you're going to scroll down
and you're going to click okay
when you click okay, your Jenkins job.
Hold on. Wait for it. It's loading.
Go ahead and click. Okay. By the way.
Go ahead and just click. Okay.
It's a little slow because so many people
are accessing the same server.
So just let it do
its thing.
Okay, cool.
Now listen to what I'm going to say,
what I'm going to show you.
All right.
Still loading.
Okay. I will wait for you.
Shows me Harry shows a screenshot
wait.
Job already exists
with the executive name.
First name
Jenkins joke.
You know have you ever created a name?
Let me see. Mario.
What's going on here?
Mario
Abedi.
Oh, let me ask you this, Marieme.
How many times did you click okay?
You probably clicked it a few times.
And you know what? Nice.
Because yeah, if you click that.
Okay, so first of all, wait for me.
Yeah, exactly.
So it already created a job, but because
it's so slow and you create, you click.
But again, it was too slow to show you
that the job actually got created.
So go back and look for it.
It's going to be there.
Okay, But wait for me. Hold on.
Wait, wait, hold on, Wait.
Before you look for it, please wait.
I'm waiting for everyone
to reach this page.
Okay, I'll show you.
I'll show you what to look for It.
Just wait for me.
If you couldn't find your.
If it didn't work, just wait for me, okay?
I'll show you where it is
okay for the rest of you.
If you're here, that's good.
Okay.
Yeah. So are we good?
All right, now let's go back and look for
the jobs were created.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going
to click on Jenkins right here this link.
So go ahead and click on Jenkins
and let's look for your your job.
You can do search or you can do control F
on your keyboard type in your name.
So I was an instructor.
Let's see what comes up.
Okay.
If that doesn't come up,
then I need you guys to do this.
Control F or command F if you're
using a mac and, look for what you have.
Instructor You see, minus there.
So, Mary, on this,
if you did yours, what is your name?
Mariam or Yo Guido.
You see, your
name is there, You'll get it,
you see it, it's there.
Okay.
So if you find it,
go ahead and click on it.
Mariam.
Mariam, your name is there.
You see it? It's there.
Is there anyone else that's looking it
on? Mac?
It's command F on your keyboard,
command F,
and then this little search bar
will come up here
and then like if you want to
look for your name, type in a Lenny.
Hello, Lenny.
And there is a Lenny Jenkins job,
which, by the way, shows me you didn't
the naming convention, right,
Lenny?
Okay.
Are we good for the rest of you?
All right.
Can I move forward?
Let's open Lenny, I guess.
What's the situation, Commander?
And then when you type in commander,
you can search up
or you can just look for it.
But looking for it's
going to take a while.
But it also looks like you didn't
follow the naming conventions.
So, like your name is I think I found it.
And it's this one.
It's right here. A Lenny.
Lenny. Okay. Right, right here.
This is your job,
the one that you created.
This. You
know.
Very good.
Very good. Very good.
Now don't do anything.
Just wait
and wait for the class.
You either can be impatient right away.
We're a team.
Can I change? Don't worry about it.
You already didn't
follow the instructions,
So just click on it and open it
and then let me know when you're there.
Just try to follow instructions
as we go.
We good, Lenny?
We're good.
We're waiting for you.
I'm going to find mine.
I'm going to click on it.
Bam, Right there.
Thumbs up.
If we're here.
All right. Very good.
Okay, Awesome.
Right
now, let's take a look.
This is our first Jenkins
job. Congratulations.
Give yourself a round of applause.
You created your first Jenkins
job. That wasn't so hard, right?
Good stuff.
Yes. All right, so let's configure this.
Let's go to configure
and let's do some really cool stuff.
So everyone click on
configure to the last.
Okay?
Let's just in the description, say
this is my this is my first day at school.
This is my first Jenkins job right here.
Okay.
This is my first Jenkins job.
Go ahead and write it down.
Go ahead. In that your name?
So I'm going to put instructor
Add your name.
Christine. Oh, it's floating away.
So a lot of us are using this.
Yes, sir.
I mean, yes, ma'am.
That we will slow down or slow down.
It's okay. We're all using it.
That's fine.
That's why it's a little slow.
That's okay.
Batch 11 touch of this
or something like that.
Right?
It's still loading.
All right, we're going to wait.
I need you guys to press.
No one said why? Why?
Why would you go to work?
When did I say anything about workspace?
Confused.
What?
What did you miss?
Yeah, you click on configure on the left,
click on configure
and it'll bring you here.
Mustafa, click on configure.
I think that's what you're talking about.
Remote stuff.
Like what do you click on on the left
click on configure
error.
What do you mean?
Are? Alanna
That's a very good question, right?
So think about it.
If you need a small job done
and you have a test,
you have a team of testers,
how many jobs should you create for smoke?
Just one.
So maybe only one person
gets to create it, right?
You all use the same one
when I click on configure.
Okay. Can you refresh the page please?
Can you refresh the page
and see if it works
for the rest of you over here?
So let's type in.
This is my first Jenkins job, okay?
And then once you've done that,
then do the following.
This is how we properly say what Jenkins
You want to click, play
and save,
and then it'll bring you back here? Yes.
Put your names there like I had.
This is my first, you know. That's fine.
Go ahead and do it.
Click Save and then click apply.
Well, this is what I'm going to show you.
I'm going to show you again.
All I did was like, click on configure.
And then here in the description
I just opened, this is my first Jenkins
job, Okay?
And then once you type and enter your
name, don't have instructor, by the way.
And then I just clicked on the proper way
to save us.
Click on Apply
and then saved and Saved takes you back
here. Yup.
Appliance saved.
Cool, cool cool cool
cool cool. Cool.
Class. Are we here?
You guys still there?
Are we.
Is it loading?
Is are we good or what's the
what's the situation. 200
good.
All right, so now let's go back
here, Let's click on configure
and let's continue to make some changes
to to the job.
And of course we have to wait
because it takes forever to load.
Okay, We're here.
All right, you ready?
Here we go.
So we're going to do
is I'm going to scroll down.
I'm going to say JDK, don't do anything.
Just leave it like this system. Okay,
So you can select GitHub project here,
but just uncheck it.
Don't do this. This project,
this parameter.
Okay, let's do something here.
Click on this.
This project parameter tries.
Oh, and by the way.
Okay, don't do anything.
Don't. Don't do anything. It's okay.
Just watch my screen. Okay?
Just watch my screen.
Please don't do anything.
I'm going to go back. Go,
going to leave this space.
I'm going to go back to here and you see
how I have build Now it's just a button.
If I click on it,
there's nothing is going to happen
because there's really nothing.
Well, there's two bills are filling and.
They're failing
because there's not enough.
There's nothing to happen.
Like there's nothing there, Right?
There's nothing to build done.
I clicked it twice and it's well, it's
going to come again.
It's the third time or failure. Right.
But you see how it's just a button
that says build now.
Okay. And don't do anything.
But now we want to make this job
dynamic as well.
Okay.
And actually,
we'll do this after you guys do this.
But the thing is it's taking so long
to load that far enough, we should do
it right now.
All right.
So how about this? Let's do this.
You see where it says
source code management
right here.
You see that?
Click on get.
Okay, click on Get.
Now, everyone pass for just a second.
Everyone pause for just a second.
Let's understand
some things first before we just start
clicking buttons and doing that
and then just building.
We need to understand
what is going on right?
So you guys have the framework
on your local machine, right?
In your ontology,
You know some of them, right?
We all have our projects
in our local machine,
but we, our projects are also where
in GitHub, right?
Exactly. Our projects are there.
So we have to tell Jenkins
that our project is on GitHub.
Okay.
We cannot tell Jenkins
that our project is on our local machine
because if we wanted to run it
from our local machine,
that means we have to install.
Jenkins On your computers,
you have to connect these ports,
you have to do all this crazy
installation part.
Whereas here we just logged into Jenkins
because it's being hosted
on the different server.
It's being hosted somewhere. Okay.
But the thing is here,
we need to tell Jenkins
that our project is on GitHub.
Okay, does that make sense?
And it's going to use that project
and build it.
So let's go to get Hub.
You have to go to get Hub.
Let me know if you're on GitHub
and what is the
what is the name of your batch
guys like,
what is the name of the repository?
Is that Cucumber framework Batch 11?
Is that yours?
Okay, so let's click on this.
Let's get the code,
click on code and copy
this, the project URL.
Okay, copy the project and we can do this
question, this website, what we use, it's
not real.
Jenkins No, this is real.
This is why would not be real?
Jenkins This is real. JENKINS
But obviously we're just practicing there.
That's why. Because we're just practicing,
you know,
that's why it's not secure.
Obviously, at work.
It will be secure.
Okay, Okay.
Does that answer your question? Alex
Right, Yeah. So,
okay, no, don't,
don't get your own project.
Get, get a copy.
This one, the main project.
The reason for that is because I feel like
some of you guys have code in your project
that are going to fail.
Okay, so just use this one.
Okay?
Just use this one for now.
And then later we will create more jobs
and you can do
as you please.
Cool.
All right.
Very good.
So now what I'm going to do is copy
this URL
and I'm going to go back to Jenkins
and I'm going to place the repository
URL here.
Go ahead and do that.
Did it go?
And for your credentials,
please choose the following
on that. Hmm.
Think about this.
Hold on, hold on, guys.
Hold on.
Okay.
I want to see which one of these
we're going to use.
I can't see the password. So
can we use
to think about this?
Can we just use this one?
The one that's a syntax technology
slash star.
Star, star, star, star. Diego
Jenkins token.
You select that one to
go ahead and selected.
Okay.
All right.
Now let's
let's click, apply and save.
Oh, and one more thing before you do that,
you see how it says
the branches
to build the branch specify to
this is going to run the project
on Master branch.
But if you had other branches right,
you would just create them here.
It looks like there's only one branch,
but if you have different branches
like you know your own branch
and you want to run just your branch,
only then you would change the name
of that branch here. Okay,
cool.
Okay, let's, let's scroll down.
Let's just quickly do an apply and save.
We're going to come back here.
Okay? Very good.
And then let me know once we're back here.
Done.
Okay,
so now we have a what do we do there?
We basically told Jenkins
where our GitHub project is, right?
We told it we had to tell it
where our GitHub project is
and we had to give it its credentials
so that it can clone the project.
Okay.
Jenkins Pretend as as a person
who has their computer
and they want to run their project
on their computer,
okay, Can we think of it that way?
Right?
Pretend that Jenkins is a person
that has a laptop
and you're telling that person
to run your automation at any time,
and he needs your GitHub credentials
to clone the project
and to do whatever
it is that you want. Okay,
That's what the situation is here. Go
now. We talk now.
Let's play build now. Just click it once.
Let's see what.
Let's see what's going to happen.
Just let it click.
Just Let it, let it click at once.
Let's see what what's happens
Don't go and click Get so many times
right here.
There's a button here that says build.
Now just click that. What?
Just click it once got my permalink.
It doesn't show any history.
What do you mean? Permalink links?
Doesn't show any history.
Okay, let me
refresh it.
Okay.
And if when I refreshed it,
you can see that the project is building,
something is happening.
That's a good. Yes.
That's what we want to see.
Now, it's going to fail
because it's just going to fail.
Right?
But it's building. That's what we wanted.
Okay.
Because Diego tried build.
We didn't.
What what's I mean.
Yeah.
So I'm going to refresh this page,
try to refresh it.
So we see a build status.
So it's it's running, right?
It's running and it looks like very good.
Just let's just wait
on actually
go ahead and click on the little circle.
Okay. The little ball right here.
Go ahead and click on it.
And when we click on it, it's
going to take some time to to load.
But you can see a console output
that it's supposed to show you
what's going on.
But I guess because
we're using this so much, there's here
the progress shows
a screenshot of you
see something here, the console output
minus still mine is still building
wonderful.
That's exactly what you should be seeing.
But for some reason
miners are still loading.
Oh, there it is. Okay, so
you see, let's read the console.
Right?
It says right here cloning
the get the remote repository.
What repository? This one.
You see what I mean?
It's cloning it, right?
Because Jenkins is a person
that has a laptop
that needs to clone their
their
you know, the project
we really talked about this all.
But then look at this.
Get in it. Right.
So it looks like there it looks like
Jenkins is trying to initialize
a git directory and Jenkins, that's
what get in.
It does.
And then here it's just getting
the versions is verifying some things.
And there's a lot of stuff here
that you don't need to understand at
the last Oh, look at this.
The last commit
message says API class date.
You see, this is why you need to be
very careful with your messages at work
because everyone will be able
to see those messages.
So It was not going to look good
if you just entering
stuff that you don't care about.
Let's see what's going on.
It's running. Oh, so you see this? What?
What is it?
Saying that the project is building
and that's downloading
the dependencies from
the repo.
The centralized maven, a bunch of dot org.
Right. That's what's happening as well.
So don't put silly
quotes with them in silico.
What is cool.
Oh like don't put a silly message.
Yeah.
Wait, that's okay.
Don't worry about it
Lenny. It's just about it.
That's because I have my the wall
that I clicked on was red
because the previous bills have found
yours was just
why you don't have a history yet
which is white.
But if this one fails,
then it's going to fail.
Well, let's just.
Let's just see what what's the issue here?
Let's let's let it build
the dependencies, download it, and let's
see what's what's going on.
Is it working for you guys, by the way?
Like, do you guys see what I'm saying?
Good. Let's see.
Is there any one to anyone here
that's struggling
and it's guidance that's low?
Yup. Same with mine.
Slow.
Still building
code.
It's got to wait.
No console yet.
I think it's coming.
It has to come.
Will we be testing on phone browser
environments?
Yes, maybe.
Depends on your project?
Depends on your project.
If they want to do mobile testing,
then they will do it.
What do you mean?
Same concept.
So they don't have access to.
To what exactly?
To phone browsers
to automate from browsers.
You can use APM,
which is basically a wrapper
over Selenium libraries.
So the question is yes, the answer is yes.
We'll talk about that later, though.
So building right.
Let's go.
Let's go, Let's go back.
Well, it finishes building,
so let's click on this right here.
I'm going to click on this.
This is go back
and see if we can talk about other things.
One, this building,
you don't have to be here, by the way.
Like you don't have to be on this page
just to wait for it to build.
Okay.
But anyway, we're going
to let that one builds.
And let's see.
You guys should see the little status bar
here on the bottom left.
Yeah, this has taken a very long time,
but what was it that we did?
We basically just told Jenkins
what our project was
and we provided the credentials. Right.
And I think it's working
because it cloned.
I think it would have felt by now
if the credentials didn't work.
Okay. But we'll see.
We will see.
Okay, I'm going to click on configure.
You guys can do so as well.
Okay.
So here, let's see, we have a lot of
different topics to discuss.
Okay.
But I need this.
I need this.
I need this job to finish first.
So let's just wait for it,
okay?
All right. Questions.
And you want questions?
Questions, questions, questions.
Shows
the wrong time is not the wrong time.
The server is just another country.
It tells us it's at a different time.
By the way.
So it's not it's not our time.
It's it's another time
someone says, Tell us a cool story.
Yeah, sure
cool story is that you are very close
at getting a nice I.T. job.
That's cool, right?
So cool story.
Okay, let's see.
I'm going to give it 30 seconds.
If not, then
we're going to have to do something else
so that we don't waste time.
Okay? It's still building.
Okay.
All right.
So I need that to build
again.
We just created our
why we need so much.
I'm sorry, What's your question?
Why we need so much?
Are you seeing Maven?
Maven as a building management tool?
Yeah, that's where all dependencies are.
Okay,
let's see what situation is here
as it tinker right now.
It doesn't take that long.
It's just really slow,
which is playing a big role in our
success
here.
Okay, It started it started running.
What runner's classes did running here?
Can you guys see
your finish shows?
A screenshot?
There is a scenario called frontend
and backend testing.
Did you guys do anything with that?
You guys probably
found pretty
nice.
Nice, nice, nice
cocoa called
sequel.
Good, good stuff.
Okay,
so I'm just going to wait for my to fell.
I'm glad that yours finished
and is there anyone else finish
your night yet.
Your crazy testers are testing everywhere.
Interesting.
Oh okay.
So let me see what happens
if I refresh this.
Oh, look at that.
Look at that.
Better refresh.
Jenkins is letting us down.
It is letting us down.
This is not good.
Let me complain about this
because it is taking
our time.
Okay? Do
you guys need something else than what
I see?
Mine just gave up. It's still loading.
Give it some time.
Kind of quit.
All right, So lecture time,
Lecture time, lecture time.
Let's
go back to what we were talking about.
So now you guys know what Jenkins
is, and I wish I could show you more.
I'm just going to wait for it to finish.
But let's talk about more things.
So if I were to ask you a
what do you use Jenkins for, like
in your project, you as a tester,
what are you using Jenkins for?
What should your answer be?
Monitor and schedule jobs.
Very, very good.
See right there. Perfect.
Okay.
What do you what,
what what jobs are you like monitoring?
A lot with which test cases?
Smoak Okay,
very good.
Okay, very, very good. Very good.
You see, that's it. Was that hard?
It wasn't right.
Let's see.
What do you do in your project to ensure
the stability of your application?
What do you do in your project
to ensure the stability
of your application?
You run your smoke tests. Okay.
Very good.
Very, very, very, very good.
Okay, Very, very good.
I'm so proud of you guys.
I am so proud of you.
Do all of your Jenkins jobs pass
every day?
No. Sometimes
we will catch real bugs,
however, every time you are.
So here's the thing.
I forgot to mention this.
If you.
If you experience a failure with Jenkins.
Right.
You'll obviously have to risk you have to
do some research to see why it failed.
The best practice is to see if you can run
that same test case again.
And then the second
practice, the next best thing to do is.
And I actually told the testers
in my team this,
If a Jenkins job feels like if a test case
feels like we're having, like,
let's say like 90% or 80%
a test cases are passing,
I ask them to execute the other test
cases
manually to see if there actually are
no bugs.
Okay, Does that make sense?
I actually tell them like, you know what?
Just to make sense,
let's just execute this test manually.
Let's see,
let's see if there's actually a bug guy.
And that that's that's really
that's our process
here.
If it's fast, it doesn't throw exceptions
it'll throw it'll throw the exceptions
that the that that the test through
it will show you where it failed.
Let's hear this.
Oh, there it is. Okay.
It's still in the same place.
So it got stuck executing this front,
then testing.
All right.
I'm going to go back to the job
here.
Still own thing. Okay.
But that's pretty much
now we're able to do a lot of this.
But in Jenkins,
for most projects, yes, you'll you know,
it's used for smoke and regression
testing purposes
at work.
You know, again, you really only create
a job once every now and then.
You know, you smell a you create
your smoke jobs every single day.
Right.
That's that's how this kind of works.
Come still loading.
Not such a complicated topic, right?
Not such a complicated topic.
Also,
keep in mind that you may not be able
to do a lot of stuff
and get on with Jenkins at work.
They may limit your access.
This is just to
be safe, to be careful.
Okay.
In terms of speed,
Jenkins is tied to Jenkins.
Well, it's just this is this server.
It's where we are hosting this
this Jenkins
instance that that's where
that's, that's what's slow.
Because if like, for example my job are
Jenkins likes is is really fast.
Right. But
keep in mind that these companies pay
a lot for that
even though Jenkins is open source.
But you need to host it somewhere, right?
It needs to be secure.
You pay for the hosting services.
For example, on most of our applications,
we are only allowed to test
between the hours of 7 a.m.
and 7 p.m..
After that,
the service gets shut down. Why?
Well, save money
some time.
Sometimes what we've had to do
when we have to do a lot of extra testing,
they will leave. They will leave them up
just to give us more time.
But then they you know,
if they can save money, why not?
All right.
Questions. Nice
at this point.
Anything I'm doing, I can. You do.
Sorry about the delay, guys.
Let's see.
I'm even clicking on this.
Nothing is working.
All right, Thanks. Huh?
Yeah.
At least we have a picture deck, because
I wanted you guys to do a lot more.
You know, I don't know why it's so slow.
This hasn't happened before,
and it's not like.
It's not like we have so many students
either.
Are you? Yes.
We're using MWC.
Yeah, I don't.
I don't know what's going on.
But the good news is
that we were almost done with the class
tomorrow.
Wanted to focus
on showing you how to schedule a job.
I actually want to do that today,
but knowing how slow it's going, I'm
so sure that we're going to have
oh, that's
just what the company decided to use
we have now.
We'll look at that loaded.
Oh, see, that's
just what the company decide to use.
They can use whatever they want.
They can use us, Microsoft
Azure, whatever they want to pay for.
Right.
That's that's done.
Okay.
So I don't want to click on that anymore
because I'm afraid that something
is going to happen.
Let's click on configure.
Can you guys get back here?
Is it still loading for you guys?
Still loading.
All right.
You know what we're going to do?
We're just going to have
a small interview review while this loads
are you guys go with that,
maybe some interview questions here
and there until we do some progress here.
All right. So
give me a topic.
What topic do you guys want to talk about?
Any topic.
And this is actually taking a very long
time.
Oh, okay.
All right.
So how many how big is your team? Six.
Can you please answer that question
when they user test applications?
No, I'm so confused with your question.
You mean like
how big is your team?
Can you please answer that question
with the user test?
I don't understand the question.
No, sorry, you please rephrase it.
Okay. Thank you.
Yup. Around 5 to 6
you can see around 5 to 6 guys.
You can say any number.
The whole point is that whatever you say,
you stick to it.
Okay?
Does that make sense?
You stick to it.
You can say five, you can say six.
I'm right now
I'm on a team that has only four people.
I mean five folks.
And I'm on another team
that has like 15 people you just got out
of, you know,
whatever the story is, just stick to it.
Yeah.
So you're saying around 5 to 9, that's
kind of like a big gap.
You want to say like 5 to 6 sounds better.
It sounds better
when you have an exact number.
Actually, we say, Oh,
we actually were a team of eight.
It shows that, you know, your team know.
I mean, so you can say
we're actually a team of
of eight, eight, eight people.
It is.
And then you make stuff up right
you can say,
okay, my my current team sighs,
The one that I'm currently working on.
We have two developers,
one business analyst, one project manager,
two cookies and
a product owner, and that's a car
put on the other team.
There is like five developers.
We have only two key ways.
We have a Scrum master in that team.
We don't have a Scrum master at this other
smaller team that I told you about.
So the business analyst
actually runs the Scrum meetings.
So do you need to have a Scrum master
in your team?
No, you do not.
Okay.
So you can have many teams
at the same time.
It depends.
If you get hired for a project
where you're only working on one project
at a time.
I work for a client where work on over 30
different applications, so I'm pretty much
in over 30 different teams
and they're all different.
They're all different.
How many times do we do a day?
That was one interview.
That was one of the two.
But you already went on the market.
Is that
how many tests do you execute a day?
Well, it depends on what you're testing.
There are some days where you actually
don't executing the test cases.
You're
maybe you're writing your test cases.
You know,
that means we need a close to true
stories.
No. Remember, guys, I told you, right?
I Told you guys.
And I'll tell you,
I always tell you guys this.
You either finesse the system
or the system will last. You
and you pick your poison.
That's my advice to you.
And that's all I'm going to say. Go.
That's all I'm going to say.
Well,
to choose your character,
that's free to choose.
Choose your character.
Well,
how do you decide which stays
to what test to automate
and which ones to manually perfect?
Good question.
So in in general, it's
good practice to automate test cases
that are repetitive
test cases that are long or test cases
that require to be executed
multiple times
with different sets of data.
Write a test case that you wouldn't
automate
as a test case that can be automated
by the tool that you're using.
Like selenium has limitations.
You also don't want to automate
a test case
where the requirements
keep changing, right?
Because you're going in there,
you're writing your code, you're
inspecting all these elements.
But then that requirement
changed. Tomorrow.
Then that means that the code is going
to change, that you're going to go back
and inspect everything again.
And at that point,
you're wasting a lot of time.
You know what I mean? You're wasting
a lot of time just trying to
to automate something that keeps changing.
Very good question.
Next question.
Come on, guys, interview me.
I am a really bad liar.
When they asked me to tell day to day
job activity based on for Oh, it's easy.
Lying has been very easy.
I'll show you how to lie spread
so it's
very easy.
You know what's funny?
Like whether you guys want to go
with the fake resume or not or fake.
I don't say fake recipe.
I want to say experience.
You know, people that are honest
and the resumes, you know,
they're also lying
because they're also overexaggerating
the work
they did at their in their job right.
Right.
And again, I'll say this.
You either finesse the system
or you let the system finesse you.
The resume is not going to get you a job.
Okay?
The resume is just going to get you
the interview.
Does that make sense?
Cool. That's it. Plain and simple.
If your resume says that you know this
and that, well, then prove it.
At the time of interview, go prove it.
At the time of interview, obviously,
some people are like,
Oh, what if I get hired?
And then they fire me later because
they realize I don't know anything.
Well, to be honest, that doesn't happen
because they actually interview you
before you joined the company, Right?
So that's not going to happen now.
They could get fired if you just are like
showing up late to work,
if for some reason
you're not responding to messages or,
you know, that kind of thing,
does that make sense
that that's pretty much it?
There was a question
I assume was a challenge
you experience where you work
in your current company.
I don't want
you guys think about current company.
I want you guys
to think about current project
because your company can support
so many different projects.
Your Company can support
Like if you work for a government
contractor like Right,
or Deloitte or Booz Allen or ICA
or anything, like they have contracts.
Like what?
That, you know, Department of Homeland
Security, IRS,
you know, some schools systems,
you know, here and there.
So I don't want you guys to think of it
like it.
JOHNS Your experience when you worked
in your current company, it should be
as they change your experience,
you worked in your current project or at.
Johns
You experience in your current project,
right?
Oh, cool.
Well, we'll learn how to answer those
project.
So a challenge is I mean, one of
the biggest challenges here is that,
you know,
we like requirements change a lot,
so we have to be very good at up to date
with the changes.
As a testing team,
we have to continuously update
our test cases and so forth.
Right?
So that's one challenge.
Have I.T. experience.
I have certifications.
Want to know what my honest resumé
got me in a year and a half,
two interviews, not job.
I'm willing to try something new.
Alan How about we do this?
We get your experience,
we get your certifications,
we make a wonderful resumé,
throw some salt and pepper in there
and bam, we get you a good job.
It sounds good, right?
Yup. That. That's the plan.
Very good.
There was a question
who makes that decision of what task
is to automate versus manual?
You do
and you
can actually discuss with your team.
If you're working with the team,
I'm sure you discuss with a team and say,
Hey, I think we should automate this.
You know,
you discuss this as a team and that's it.
And if you're the only way, then you're
the one it.
Does that make sense?
I sure.
Would you prefer to develop your framework
from scratch or work on an existing one?
I've worked on multiple projects
where I had to do one or the other.
When you work, when you develop
a framework, you develop it based on
the testing needs that you will,
the testing that you have to do.
So I know that you guys here
Selenium Java cucumber, but to be honest,
all of these frameworks are very different
than many different projects
and they are designed to test
their specific application.
Okay.
It it is,
it's, it's really up to you.
But what the most difficult thing
to testing already talked to
you guys about this.
What is the most difficult
part to testing?
Is it creating a framework?
Is it grabbing any tool
and starting automating?
What is the most difficult part to testing
the most difficult part?
This is still loading, but there.
Sorry for the delay guys
trying to do some value in here
to you guys too,
because you guys are patiently waiting.
I'm sorry, what was the question
that I ask the question?
Understanding requirements
minus loading forever.
How can we imagine ideal work environment?
I'll Show you a Catarina.
That's easy, but the most difficult part.
Look, right now
I'm a I'm a test architect, right?
And I've been to a of different projects.
People think that the
hardest part is to just get a tool
and start automating.
They think that it's, that
they think that that's the hardest part
to develop the framework.
That's nice and all right.
And obviously the challenges are there.
You can start automating
your first five test
cases, your first ten,
your first 15, your first 20,
but then what happens
when you have 300 test cases?
What happens when you have 1000?
What happens when you have so many?
Then what happens?
The truth is that the most difficult part
to testing in general,
both and test automation
is maintenance.
Maintenance is the most difficult
part to testing in general.
Okay, that's what it is.
But just if you don't believe
that, you will see
with with time,
you will see the experienced tester.
Well well can agree
with that the same thing
can you a little more explain.
Yeah.
Maintenance for example
you have a dozen test
cases, right and then requirements change.
First of all, it's
the way you design your framework.
How about I take you through my framework
just a little bit
to show you how different it is?
This is a real time project, by the way.
And, and we actually have everything
like we actually have two big documents
here.
Like what we told the new testers
is to come to our documents.
We have a code review checklist.
This is a checklist that the code
these are the standards
that you have to follow in order to pass
code reviews in our projects.
Right.
One of the code
reviews say that in our project,
like in every pages classes
that you have, okay,
and every page is classes that you have,
you need to have I'm
going to show you.
You see, this is the pages class, right?
You need to have commented lines up
in every single element.
Okay.
Right here with every single element
that you want with proper
naming conventions
so that we know what that element is for.
Right. Does that make sense?
Because the day of tomorrow,
if another tester joins a team
and they clone the project that does
or should be able to easily
find all of the inspect that.
Okay, so we comment all of the stuff
here as well.
You see all of the elements.
We divide them, we organize our elements,
we use comments, right.
And stuff like that.
Does that make sense? Right.
This is just one of the code review
checklists and stuff like that, right?
Because if you don't have this,
you're going to sell code review.
You're going to at least in
my project and I've been in other projects
where they do the same thing.
So this practice isn't new.
Okay. Yep.
And you notice
that that was a good call, right?
Someone looked at it.
Let me see.
Let's go here.
What are we using?
A lot of expert.
Expert. Expert, Expert. Expert.
Expert and expert experts.
Right.
We only use experts
in this project. Why?
Because let's compare this one.
We can make
we can locate very dynamic elements.
That's thing number one.
The difference between success and expert
really is that you're able
to customize the experts more.
You can really customize access, select
so much.
Okay?
And that is a big disadvantage,
of course, of using CSS selector.
Okay.
So that that there goes that
and that
is that is one that is a big
that's a big deal.
Okay.
So M has four new locators.
That's interesting.
Why there's no like I d I just,
I just told you we just expense.
That's fine.
You know, like, that's what we use.
Every project will have like it's it's
standards, right?
Like they'll say we use ides,
we use this, we that you know
like they wanted to use something for us
because we're working
with an angular application
and some service apps.
We are using this.
But that's just to give you an idea,
it's still loading.
All right.
Do you guys have questions?
Is it a project requirement?
What do you mean, project requirement?
One more time?
What was the advantage of success?
The only advantages, of course,
is that you can write them very fast.
They're very easy to write,
right?
They're very, very easy to write.
Write this stuff.
You can also Google as well difference,
which can see us as an expert.
And you will find that
who say that expert is is better
because it's more customizable.
You know, what do you prefer to work
as it tests or test lead
whatever pays more, we're based more.
It's the same.
I don't know like it's
where pace
you know, that's
that's that's fine.
That's okay.
You know let's start with to
not lead one.
Yeah. Okay.
Why did you decide to switch a job?
Well,
what will you do if you don't agree
with one of your colleagues?
You're going to fight them
in the parking lot.
You're going to we're going to call them,
and you're going to just start going
crazy.
Did you actually start a Q?
Is it a manual?
No, I was actually automation
with a lot of manual work.
What will we say,
which company we're working for this
that will be covered in the interview
preparation, guys.
All of that will be covered
in the preparation.
Okay.
But, you know, the questions
that we kind of went over today
are some questions
that you were going to get
and some of you guys
already have questions.
You know, they asked you
why did you decide to switch projects
or something like, Well,
I always pursued newer opportunities
when I felt like I could grow more,
you know, make it sound good.
You don't say, Oh, I was bored
and I decided to leave, you know.
It's it's about how you talk, guys.
It's about how you talk.
What if they ask where you graduate from?
Will say, Say
I went to this university or, this school.
You know, Did you go to
what did you go to?
I may learn JavaScript
after a couple of months, start working.
What do you think is a good choice?
I see.
Are you working already or what's
what's the deal?
They will ask.
It will be okay to start Manual
nine that we have for
it is how to agree but not sorry.
The question is they will ask it.
We will be okay to start manual
nine that we have
five years experience How to agree
but not sound desperate.
I don't understand the question
I sure you asking.
If you guys get a job that requires you
to learn a new set of tools, then do it.
It just adds more to your resume.
It makes you more of a lucrative tester.
Right?
How many testers are going to go out
in the market knowing, selling a job?
Right.
Imagine, you know, you having a different
tool under your belt,
right
Now they go, I graduated in business
studies in the fall.
So then say that, Yeah, see,
I got my degree from you know,
I got my degree in the fall,
but so so I'll go with that.
If they say
would you be fine to start doing
manual test a lot, say yeah, absolutely.
No, you know, testing is a challenge
itself and I love testing.
You know, I'll be up for the challenges.
Okay.
All right, guys, listen, Jenkins
let us down.
So let's just call it a night, okay?
Let's get 50 minutes early
tomorrow.
Let's see what we can come up with.
If tomorrow just not working,
then I'm just going to have to show you
how to do stuff without you
having to do it, which I wouldn't like,
because I want you guys to get hands
on, you know?
But we can go from there.
All right, cool.
All right, guys, have a very good night.
And I'll see you tomorrow.
All right? Okay. No worries.
I'll take a look later.
Thank you.