Orchestra.
And so last number six, so far, we own
some of the marks of framework,
complete parts of Mr.
D as a tool, complete part of the timber.
It is a two day in some part of the field,
but it provides a lot of room.
But right now we are using that.
And so if I take a look
of all the structure that we have here,
we have deepest functionality
in our teamwork or not
in our framework supports
multi
or non behavioral driven development.
We are writing scenarios
based on the behavior
and we are executing this values.
So we have very deep framework.
At the same time, my groups are working
across multiple sets of data gathering,
so their definition of data driven
testing is in my one script,
execute across multiple source of data
recorder directly when visiting
this or
do we have a digital testing
approach was in our playbook.
We have the exact opposite it.
So when when we talk about any framework
that supports more than one behavior,
for example, we did integer
they this deep boot inventory
look and we call this type of playing
but it is hybrid finger, what we call
it was
recorded hybrid finger because we have
many pieces to try, many features to play.
Right.
We can pause the data
either from the proper display,
we can pass the data from the table,
we can position it from examples table.
We can pass the data from exit by correct.
We have all these functionalities
implemented
in our framework or not, and
so now this
is a good
framework, supports
ambiguity and internally.
But this now yesterday
we learned one very important topic
that was busting their data
from Excel fine rate, right,
is passing their data from Excel by
unsolvable
of students rate to join me
after the class.
Then I was resolved.
What is a majority of the students
were having a very small problem.
What was their problem was the
data is are not using
my code is the difference one
second thing
they guys are waiting some melt keys
in their data in that exploit
and that's why you're getting
what is called it is should not be getting
to sequence date.
I've seen this in five six students.
Why is it so?
Because we are not passing the data
and we are just keep cheating
in the exam reading code
that there is a problem with the code.
Not there is not a problem with the code.
Right.
The problem is with Billington
detailed because of by
education.
So please provide the data and the keys
which we must return, the keys
which we must accept.
Find it open minus
these keys which we are passing.
First name, middle name,
last name for do grab
these keys should match with the keys
which you are providing in
which you are providing key and right.
If these keys are not matching,
they're definitely yaml as delivered.
So these keys,
if they're matching, definitely
you will get an edge
that someone was passing last name.
There but without space.
And here someone passing
data like the asked this need
how can it be match you're providing
different keys it's for possible rate
so make sure when you're passing the data
it should be matched
what the change should
be rate causing.
Yep, because we provided the name
as the employee data to the sheet name
someone had already sheet one new sheet.
Something like this.
Just because I paused
the name of the student
is employed
in a improvement positive employee blank.
I explained to time that we are passing
employee data here
because we had this cheat
name already available in Excel workbook.
If you have that name
stored, must
write basic,
so please take care when you are writing
the call rate from starting to end us
to observe how I am writing,
What are the points I'm explaining?
What are the points
we need to focus on more rate.
These are the things we need to take.
You know, and then when you are done
with your writing that would
and you come across any errors
or what you have to do, in that case,
you have to simply match your code
with my good.
The very first approach
should be against it and never believe in
copying best, but combine good
which is available in the repository.
Right in the repository.
This code is for your friends
so that you can have to copy
what is working, what is not working.
Now you can compare
both the copies that which one is working.
This one already.
And what is missing here,
why this one is not working.
And then you can predict
the student
along the wall.
Where were you in the last class?
You were not there.
Yes. Here we have to change the sheet name
and then whatever the key is to be
at a passing the desk,
we have to change the pseudonym here.
For example, you're going to pass
this time new immigrants, right?
So that the sheet name is new employee.
So lost new employee,
then you're accelerating what it will do.
It will read
here and it will read
which file from here
because the workbook is
it will read a new employee
spot, exemplar plate.
And here, whatever the guidance
you're providing, just provide those keys
instead of this keys.
And this gives us another one
independently.
You can work on that and you can simply
use those because Xerox was a good work.
So now there so I told
this one is a global function, right?
You just need to change.
The name of the sheet
tells the only thing you have to
bring on.
You get that.
But why does it get I didn't just
want.
All right, so now
should we start this
knowing?
No, no, no sheet
is a part of your workbook? Yes.
What are we are we are going property.
We are going for associates.
I know, I know.
This question. Was there.
We will go to that.
So Arena, if we are changing
the complete workbook,
then we have to change the back.
If we are just changing the sheet inside
same book, then
why do we need to change the constancy?
This constant
is returning the same workbook.
See, this is the same workbook.
Inside this workbook
I can have multiple sheet.
They just delete the source history.
The source system.
So we don't need to change the source.
We have to change only the sheet here.
There's
I hope you're not getting confused.
It would be sheet minimal workbook.
No need to shoot for a new one.
Note that is workbook.
In workbook we have multiple sheet
o key one.
Right?
No reason the most one
posting post
was think that someone was asking
to check the code for employing straight.
I'll be right for the verification part.
Let's do it
now. You'll see.
I give you the hand in the same scenario.
Can I write the code
in the same scenario with it?
But it will be efficient. Word
nights.
You keep open the application, you
you see,
when I'm trying to add a new employee
by default, it is giving me one employee
could.
Is this correct?
Five So before adding the new employee.
Right.
What I will do when I'm filling the data.
When I'm filling the data,
I will capture this employee
so that one's night and the employee
I will simply search employee
by the member of the scenario
we can start employed by do is one is bet
81 is by me and this put everyone
remember to search by 80, search by name.
And this idea is generating by default.
Correct.
So let's see how we can grab this.
I let me show you.
Let me show this bird
you see here
in this particular one,
it says I text name value and 80.
Can you see in value
it is providing with the employee Everyone
and everyone see this
now I'm not I'm negative selenium.
You tell me this
now. Tell me
when it comes to your beautiful selenium.
In selenium, that is a command.
It is a command called
good.
It is indeed a command and selenium.
This.
So what we can do,
we can get the end of what
we can get the attribute on really simple
first put first
let's do it and stored it somewhere. Okay.
Distorted some of it
but story after adding the employee,
we can search it
using this particular string
of this particular value, cut it
and then whatever that data will be there
we can simply be defined ending the
with the data passing
from what exactly right.
So the force
super example we are getting after
searching the employee that explains the
so we can check whether we're passing
the implement understood
understood what we are going to implement.
So let's
go ahead and do so very first thing
when posting
when I'm adding the employee here.
So after ending was name, middle
name and last name
right here only operating post name,
middle name and ask me,
I'm going to get the attribute,
I'm going to get the attributes.
So what will be
the entry and writing element
employed?
I need this request to do.
I don't
find it linked.
Right.
And this employee may be part one.
I. What is the id it will keep?
I id its employer.
It is simple.
We can take my own name is this.
We can take one name and
personal
P60 employee.
Now what I'm doing
See I'm working employed.
I don't
date attribute based on work
value and this value This value.
I'm going to struggle with this value.
I'm going to store, let's say one string.
I don't know whether it is one, two,
three years, one,
two, three, four, five, whatever.
So it could be spring,
it could be anything. Right.
So I'm writing here employee I.D..
Well,
which I'm going to store in this history.
So first, when
I'm going to actually add one employee,
it will store my employer identity
getting from here
for dignity, getting.
Is this correct?
And now, after this.
After this, what I'm going to do see here
when I go to this particular bar trade
see button after clicking on
still the assertion,
what we have to do, right?
So what assertion? You see,
when I added the employee
after adding the employee
coming on to this particular beach,
let me take some random
first
see employee I.D.
insist
firm.
So now I'm coming out to this beach.
Correct.
It is taking me to this particular beach,
but I have to really find it.
My employee is available on
in the list of the employees are not.
This is the page. I see the
this puts their details.
Beach.
I'm not going to work on this person
who didn't speak.
I am going to work on employee list.
So first,
after coming on to this particular screen,
after clicking on
See It button that I have to click
nice first I have to click on
employee list.
So let's go to the employee list
and approximately
want employees
to create what I have to do.
I have to take the I.D.
So this ID we are getting from this
this I.D.
we're getting from where we have
already decided we get should this I.D.
while adding the new connect
categories.
So now in a framework,
we are entering one I.D.
any using Bank 81 or further location,
but it's not passing anything.
We are just
capturing something from the application
and using it for further operations.
That's what we are going to
let me do it.
So first
posting first,
when what I need to do is post,
I need to search this employee
list, right?
This one menu I look at.
So 10 minutes of it
should I need obviously.
But I think what we need
of obviously.
So let me write that element
and this is equals to private or
by non I.D.
and this is the embassy
after
the address input everything on here
and what I'm going to do see, I'm
going to write first check here.
I am concerned in this 80 part
so it would take to look for this 80
because this search employee,
even though we have already contributed
one time, if you remember
remember here also we have used this boxy
individual, this name, last name
clicked on separately trade such 80.
We have done it earlier as well,
but now it will do it once again.
So what I'm doing here first
I'm going to click on this employee list.
And then the second thing is
employee I.D.
So free
right?
Is the first person for
the right employee to
search for student delegates
in this state used in this.
And key is what we have to do,
which data we have to pass
from where
the screen right from this particular is.
This is an independent
winning the bus current
cook.
So let me pass you
because this thing I'm doing is
tell me if I'm going.
Thank you, sir. Thank you, sir.
After clicking on Employee 88 employee
and entering
the data is what I have to do next.
You I bench duty? Yes, sir. Correct.
I i i It means
I have to click on this with the
click button
so it will do it.
So here
also I'm going to search on this part
and here in the search
button I'm getting this 80
just getting gates
basically
search.
Let them speak to us to try to
find out I.D.
And this is I'm crossing
and then I'm trying to search.
But people don't speak
one syllable.
Just watch, don't break.
Just understand.
All of them did
a request
just what I have, what I'm doing.
Don't tape anything.
In the end,
if nothing, you will get the complete
working quote.
Yeah, it's my humble request.
I can't keep them. Why?
Why? See,
but it's good that you write late.
But for us to note understanding
if you write it would be a problem
it after the last the next class
you have 21 hours.
No I want us to just see because
even if you miss a small point
during makes Venetian and after,
sometimes you guys lost
a completely
because of that particular one.
Okay. Yes.
Yes. Correct.
Now the main part starts here
and you let us
know before starting what today They
this book
must never sit by anything.
Never, ever.
I always did just watch it.
So next time, if you guys
have to do anything, then I will see it.
Just.
I could have been his.
You are like Zima
already, guys.
Shall we proceed for that?
Now compare them.
Okay, sir.
Thank you.
I'm. I'm in, sir.
I will
now see what I'm going to do here.
Let's search for any employee.
Looks at this employee.
I searched for this input.
Can you see this employee's
coming under this particular table?
Right. And this table should read them.
How many employees against the employee
and how many employees are true?
That one.
This is the exploded there.
I got stuck and now that's my I'm
sorry so nasty in this particular people
if I berating one employee
and then the data against the employee
and should be unique
and if one employee I'm passing
it should return
how many employees against there Just one.
If I'm getting one or more, the two
or more they do.
It means there is a problem
with the system
that it is providing a multiple employee
rate against just one employee.
This should be great.
So first we will break this part.
First, we will check how many details I'm
getting from this particular one
and if it is returning,
just one point rate.
So we take all of these in the list
one by one, one by one.
Okay, let's do it.
So I'm going to take first
I'm showing you one thing.
I'm seeing the list.
And in this list,
I'm going to take the above element.
Right?
The element I'm taking the raw data
which loaded this little.
And you see these are 2333 to double zero.
The data of this rule.
I need to be in my list.
How come here
in inspect.
Yes, yes. It's between.
Let me explain this to everyone.
Now. Here you see, what I'm going to do is
this is my table, right?
So here
this is my table
with search results three.
And inside this table, if I go
open this particular part
inside this table, if I go
in, I am taking
you. There you go.
Here. You see, this is the dessert table.
I can't right now.
If I go under this table.
Under this table.
Right.
You'll see.
This is the first one for the trade.
So we don't need it.
We need this particular one.
If we open this part, can you see this?
It is giving me one by one all the data
and everyone's need under
this is equal respectively.
I got this tea body
and inside this tea body I got this diet,
which is a stressful room.
Inside this row.
I'm getting this data one by one.
So this is my table.
Which table
is this case?
This is able.
So how to interact with the table?
Let me show you right here
the presentation start this time.
I'm going to make one simple painting.
Right?
So this is my table.
Let me be more specific here.
I'm is equal to.
But is it stable one on one regard?
If you want to be more specific
than the dialogs so you can use from here,
that bag is table
big fight inside this deck.
What we need next case.
We need the body
right inside before leaving India.
Now you see,
we go to this to this students
when I see this particular rule.
So it should retain the rules
according to the number of employees.
Since I have just one employee, it is
returning me ₹1 by multiple employees.
It will return me multiple rules. Right?
So the ideal
functionality is working
when I observe it manually.
When I need to take this functionality,
my permission is correct.
So how we do it?
Let me simply copy this particular part
and let me go here
and I'm will do right here.
Driver door
nice find elemental find elements
list of element.
This kind of elements by dark
this time not already expert
and this is the value.
First thing I have to do
first thing I have to do here
is this correct?
Is this correct.
Now see using for for a reason.
So to get one by one, insert this dear.
How many do I have? I don't know.
I don't know how many data
I Let's take this data one by one integer
is equal to zero.
I is less than your true
detect our size
and then I plus plus
my I'm using follow any question
during the experiment.
The result for loop is
please take me is pigment number one.
It initiates the volume integral.
Just one second. Is that technician.
I want to check my block of code
which I am writing in
my loop
will be executed in the third statement.
I will always execute
after the execution of my code is done.
So three statements we have, right?
One is already done
because I'm going to initialize the I
by zero and now in the second one,
the second statement which I provided.
Right.
This part will be executed
based on the block of code
which I'm going
to read under this for loop.
How many students?
Three, three grade.
So based on the science, we will take
all required, so not let me do it.
So first I'm going to check whether I am
inside this group or not
if there is any problem or not.
So it kind of small statements unquote
inside my loop
because I'm inside of my loop
rate in this loop.
What I'm going to do see, I'm
going to do the data so rotate.
I want to get off
I it means based on everything,
I'm reading the data
and then capturing the big stuff like
and just food raw data don't get off by.
If I his first one, second one
I want third one, I have the fourth one,
I have three.
And then again next one,
every single cent from the rule.
Now, whatever the text I am receiving,
I need to storage.
So we're getting so little stored it going
is visual text that is obedient.
What I'm going to define to control next.
It will contain my data.
Understood
and to support everyone.
I simply force simply force
to let me put this data,
bring this data, read
whatever the data I'm
getting from this particular
rule after I'm reading this rule,
one moment, one by one,
whatever the data, I'm getting, I'm
going to put that
in this text.
Is this clear to everyone?
So now, now what I'm going to do is see
I'm going to provide associates
grade.
I'm going to provide a solutions
in order to
I need associates.
So fine to use assertions.
What I'm going to do
is first, I'm going to capture their data
from my cellphone and their data,
which is coming from my application.
And then I will compare
both this data, correct.
So their data, which is coming from my application, is available here in your text,
available here in your text or not me
Okay, So now let's do it.
Let's do it. First.
Let's understand
in which automation we're getting this
data first,
let me explain you something important.
So let me open this part here.
I'm going to work with this
just one embroidery
because I don't want to waste much time.
One, two, three.
One, two, three, five.
I'm going to see just one employee.
I'm thinking as of now.
Okay, now let me go to one of application.
So this time, this time, if I go into
my first, I'm just checking these again.
I'm saying I'm just checking read logic
what kind of automate we are getting
for the data from the room,
from the from the people of the employee.
So first let me open it.
It came here
it right here,
click on beam.
Click on an employee.
I've been clicking on third employee
in the data compatibility
in here.
Go to employee list.
It can order this
search option, go to their data,
get me to this particular point
and then closed.
Fine, fine.
Now you see here I got there
did not in this one.
Can you see
they scanned everyone's need
first
post Let me copy this data.
Right.
Whatever the data I got here,
it means what it is giving me
first is what
post is what employee
Space Force to me is based.
Middle name is based.
Last name, right?
Yeah, because it shows already.
It shows us already this
and against this employed.
The data already exist.
Okay.
It shows us already or not.
That's why
this is a sustainability of the system.
Great.
So now. Now what I'm.
What I'm saying is basically
we are getting first employee
I.D., then first name, then really?
And then lastly, right now
let's see how I'm going to work with it,
how I'm going to do it, which is
in this part in the root text.
I got this due date from the application.
Now the same font
I need to make from the data
which I'm getting from my Excel, like
from my Excel
based on within the data. Why?
Because we need to provide a solutions
to match the values
and to provide a solutions we need.
We need some data from Excel Fight
so let's make a string in the same quantum
leap.
In this to implement,
we need to make a string.
So how could we see?
First, we need to employ
any relevant contact.
Is this correct?
Case was to
add two values together in this print
which operator we use
to add to. We're losing the string we use
in condemnation rate.
So let me use concatenation here plus sign
and I'm using this space as required
because you see there is a space
in between this particular park.
Can you see it?
You see there is a space in between
your employ and enforce them with a name.
Last name. Right.
So now I'm going to let you do this
to get the value from my map.
Can I use this dart get?
And here it would be mine on both days
and then again this time one more space,
less time left.
So this time I'm asking my
site space to sign my
own date.
I'm getting the value for my
bottom line.
Must be whatever the string I'm depending.
I'm going to see
if there's a string in my expect the data.
Now see this
in this particular part.
Any question
students?
Does it make sense?
What I'm doing
now first
first, let's simply simply create
this expected it also.
So here not
one is from here, one is from here.
Silva
What are our noisy two values we got?
The one is from application, one is from
excellent find. Great.
First, let's bring both these values
and then see how things work.
Okay, so let me run it again.
This doesn't make sense
what we are doing here.
Let's.
Yeah.
We have a company already to this point.
See, that is the problem.
It says user exist.
We need to change the user name,
but that's fine.
First let me check.
No records on against this.
What?
Notice
Now here, you see, it
gave me no records found.
It means from application.
From application.
We are not getting any data in here.
We got this data from which part?
This data from what? Excel.
Right.
Because user name already exist.
So let me do one thing.
If we change the user,
we make a unique user name this time.
So my username would be you would see
my name
with the mirror.
So me
four, three, two, one,
five.
Let's see.
Look to see
in now.
Now this time. So you got a date? What?
I'm trying to explain this particular part
we got from Excel file.
Similar part
we were getting from my application.
Right now, simply what I can do is
I can do a decision in G unit.
We have lots of assumptions. Correct.
So let's provide the assertion, assert,
assert door
assert, do y because we are dealing with
two particular element
or simply assert assert equals.
I'm providing what is my expected data
and another one is
my next
radius
bit written output.
The finding is pretty far
from where I shot.
Like I said, right here. Here.
If I'm trying to find something right
which is not available in the application,
that's why it is giving non.
Well who said from exam.
Who said from Excel. From Excel
we got this.
Did you see posted once.
We got the later words from this one
we got from the application.
Read this one we got from application.
So this is from operating the employee.
It says user name already exist.
I'll read.
All right
now this time we told
you can be excluded from here.
I hope this time it will take my username
because I don't know how many users
that we needed so far in the application
we have to delete
every week.
When I hope you understood to the concept
which you are implementing
but not.
It worked this time.
It worked with this time correctly
now. So it is asking for the employee.
Record this data, find
it's going to close now.
My best guess is past
now. So here
guys, can you see this
data came from application.
This data came from Exxon,
right.
Can you see both things are equal or not?
Many Bangladesh
students going
assertion work, right?
Yes, ma'am.
On logic one basically
right.
This is the logic
which we implemented here.
This logic worked
in this race.
This one part is just everyone.
Shall we proceed further now
just try to break the complete
piece of code in smaller
pieces to get it understood
first to the employee.
Fine.
Then observe
where my application is going.
Go this fine, then add another employee
before adding the employee.
We need to verify
the entry current.
See? See? I've used objects listed there.
It is also
when you can compare to this together
grade.
But we need to go over it again.
Find them one point.
So what I did after adding the employee
so far this part is done
in the time
we are getting adding the employee three
now a master here, I'm
taking an employee list option
but doesn't
because there is a comma in between.
Can you see a look of someone with here
to prevent this?
So instead of providing on this
this in double course you have to provide
commencement column space.
And then we look
now here,
this is the employee, by the way,
creating the employee,
a captured the employer based on
not getting digital value.
So whatever the value we have recorded
value now we can simply use this value
to search the employee because
against that employee ID, we got it in
the system right
now would be attitude into the system
based on this employee 88 click on such.
But when I clicked on search button
in the table,
it gave me all the results
of the employee's right
when it gave me all the results
of the employee in the search.
But then what I did, I am going
to take the data for every single tool.
I am assuming that every employee
should return.
How many employees?
Just one employee. Correct.
So I'm going to put this raw data
into the list in case if I get multiple,
I can.
Then when people think as if
I did just one, I can get just one thing.
But in this rule
I had multiple said getting in this rule.
I should under this drag.
We have so many TDD data.
So one by one, one by one.
I have to look through everyone
to look through every everyone.
I have to use one loop and
that loop is for look, which I'm using.
Right?
So in this look what I said builder time.
My rule is not completing just a date.
Every single loop
through every single zero the
but we look through every single rule
of the set of the rule.
I got what I got text from there
for every single
if by a zero first set find what we need
to get their next second segment said
get that expert said point in there time
you got them dusted right again
their data structure every single set
and then provide this fixed to me here
in this dream industrial.
Now after this, I need to get
the same kind of data from my excel by.
So now when I observe this, that will get
my application is returning data
in the employer becomes
forced, the enforcement
then will name then last I understood
the concept great when printing this data,
then I prepared
one more string to compare from the data
which I'm receiving
from my excel point in the scene,
or make the format
I had received from my application.
Because to compare two things together,
we need to provide them
in the same format.
One I already got from the application.
Another one I'm going to take from it.
So that's what I'm doing here.
Now you see in this particular point,
I'm going to get the data
from my excellent and the employee
and they captured what they did,
the employee, those two things together.
I made this particular string
now when I printed
I support these two strings are same.
And then I'm going to simply provide
assertions here.
Now in assumptions I'm seeing
compare these two strings in this instance
are true minus two because this passed.
And that is the reason
I got you to use, must also
our dollars.
The idea
is this things come straight,
things
come basically with time, with practice.
So hopefully it won't happen overnight.
Right?
Things take time,
but you will get a job for sure.
The gold has been pushed.
The hedging me. That's what I'm saying.
The court has been pushed
and it's updated already
in the repository
already. You can take the code.
It's already been in the repository.
I did get of this things,
especially with batch 11
every day, every time played a computer
that could write up the value.
It is a new slide yesterday
I would predict today will
find days.
No, no.
Let me open up some really good avenues
but you show it isn't new employee from
this particular one
that is
well this is the one we got from here.
We created this map employee.
Remember their data
which we are getting from yesterday.
We need to enter the employee.
Right.
So here we got this data one by one,
we got the value from the Excel point
and we captured all this by using
our new employee object of the map.
And there we are using this particular
object to get the value from,
okay.
All right.
Now, once in this,
just see this was to name break
this positive look at time passing here
correct?
Correct.
First was let's let's complete
with your code
the code which you are writing
or doing anything right
I'm giving you a minute for us to complete
because I need your complete attention
on this topic.
The topic which I'm going to spend
take one minute of time
and complete your the store.
And when everyone is free of Olympic
do that, we'll begin
prosecuting.
I hope you guys are understanding
what I'm expanding. Great
students, geniuses.
Come on.
When I students.
No one blinked when I said geniuses,
I see a lot of people
typing each.
You better addicted to good titles.
So now I got the key outward receivers
next time by roll call had the head
generally
next time I was called
but it is like one it's too it
it isn't.
Let's do it
Einstein. Let's do it like this.
I will call everyone now
seem Yes, it's
not for you because you're a genius.
All genius is common, though.
You did a little bit more
soon.
Got cinema.
Got it
Right now
I would intended you as a man in theory.
On the radio break
days,
our science was about in science
and technology.
Watson and Crick.
Minutes of same ferocity
sort of on the wall.
And in the end, Adelakun seems ingenious.
Nice.
About months when.
Okay, good.
It isn't a great
great.
What is the difference in the organic
and inorganic component
electrolytic cooling point.
What is remotely the reaction?
What is Heisenberg Uncertainty Principle?
It is
what is the formula?
Operation Magnet
Just getting
amazing year
amazing
in the periodic table.
I still remember from my school time.
Hydrogen, helium, lithium,
boron, carbon, nitrogen, oxygen building
like this,
like illegal human extinction show.
See the legal argument exception
the words is easy to say.
Should not be are not get a sequence
straight explain this problem.
Do what if you are presenting the key
right?
Either there is a problem
with the key that you're passing
so it is not matching with your exit
and the key you're passing in the script
or you are passing
many values from the exit by the
It is not taking any value from the
that is the problem
you push to good this
is working.
It's working. But this is just a warning.
It's a starting chrome driver,
not just because
you are using this username this way,
but it is working.
It's not reading.
This is just a warning.
This is not the edit.
Okay, fine.
Chilling prospect for the not so warnings.
Now see what I'm going to explain.
You see here, right?
You see here, it's so many places.
It's so many places.
We have provided this web element.
First name.
Look, in this particular script,
we provided this
in this particular script,
we provided this in this particular script
in multiple steps.
I have provided three days
to know what is the issue here to see.
I have provided the username.
Look it, and also multiple places.
Read this false name,
middle name and last name.
Look, there's also multiple places.
People write keys and so on.
Lot of lot of things
that multiple places the model.
What if something changes
in the application?
What if they change this user name
locator, first name William
Nostrum Locator Tell me it how many places
I need to make this changes
all of them right?
I need to change.
Took a lot of maintenance work
that did a lot of maintenance work
we have to do
because we have to fix our existing script
in this case and to be able to fix that
existing script.
In this case, it's not going to work
because we have to spend unnecessarily
too much time on this type of things.
We should not do this.
The definition of framework
is to simplify your work
and organized it.
And if I'm talking about organizing
the work, this is not going to work.
So let's see how we can simplify,
how we can simplify this particular part.
When we talk about simplify,
there is a concept
called
garbage object model.
What we are going to introduce know this,
we are going to introduce speed,
object model
and what exists page object model
this remember some of you guys great
because you later genius three
So some of you guys might think this
form is famous in politics.
No, that
bonded exemplars of configuration by M7
in this form with capital B capital
all capital AME is built for beach
object model.
This is designed by them.
So these are two different things.
Again, everybody being geniuses,
this bomb and bomb ratings and many
these are two different things.
Don't
get confused in between these two part.
Okay.
All right, guys.
Nice.
Next time, if I come across any question,
who is asking why you're talking about
and not bomb rate exhibit?
It is more than that.
Remember
what great bomb is?
Big object model design.
Pretend like this dandy.
Yes. Got it.
Getting so
little did I already gave you create
about which object built in the steps.
Right.
So what page object model isn't
bridenstine's simply it says if you have
log in screen on the application,
if you have dashboard screen
on the application,
if you have embroiled missed screen
on onto the application and so on.
Right now, any one thing when looking at
the current report, the code we have can
then in which classes
we have entered this username and password
inherited employs tens dashboard
steps employs dips employee just steps
log in the steps where we have date
a lot of plastic Ameritrade.
We don't know where we were in
which are all those classes.
We are past this post them look
at the last we didn't even look at us.
We may be multiple classes,
maybe been hundreds of classes.
So when we actually work
with our bulkier core in the industry
right there,
we have to handle multiple classes,
hundreds of classes,
multiple packages, right?
Ends of packages and classes.
And then if even
a single nucleotide change.
And if we go with this existing approach,
then we have to change
because of changing in one indicator,
we have to change it.
1000, please, which is not a good idea.
So in this case, to override this
or to get rid of this problem,
we have a concept
called speed object model design method.
So when you talk about beach object model,
what you see is what ever did you get.
That's you have to take the largest beach
people in the lagoon beach
make a key of it
any use this key everywhere
in log in beach in dashboard
Beach in employee
is beach in an employee beach.
So now you are using the same everywhere.
And next time when you are located team,
you don't need to change it.
Hundreds of places
just change it in one place in the log
beach
and everything will be fixed automatically
in dispute.
So now in one place we need to change
and then things will automatically
get completed every minute because
now we are not passing the locator.
We are passing the key of the locator
between based on the basis
and it will link
all the GIS link to the same locator
which is available at one place
in my class right now.
Let's do it. Let's see one by one.
Similarly for all of them,
force them with a name.
Last name. Right. Go on to Employee beach.
We want to add employee Beach in this bid
just for this post name
we didn't name last name locator.
Make a key of this
look at this and the provided indentation
for beach employee list
beach log in beach every minute.
Correct
understood functions
related to what
Beach locators related to one beach
should be available
inside that beach only.
And from there we can call these locators.
We can call this functions, right?
So that's how we can simplify the code
using beach
object model design in the studio.
In the studio or not,
let's first implement
most beach great that I would show you
and then you will get more idea about see,
I'm going to perform right here
on the Java page because the beach is also
part of my class.
In class is nothing but my Java.
So here I'm going to create in my Java
new package.
In the package
name is Page's package name is Page's.
Right?
And inside this pages,
the first one I will create and is
login page Beach
is what is the first screen
You can You can consider this screen
from the steps.
Also can you see log in two steps
for log in page.
So here I'm going to prevent
logging beach.
This is my plus and I'll see the advantage
of using log in page.
You see what I'm going to do
first?
First I see in my log in two steps
in my log
in, can you see and providing username
and password here like this.
Yes, yes, yes, please watch this.
Watch. You will get everything days
after the class.
You can track these guys.
This is something very important.
Please.
Trying to understand what I'm explaining.
Can you see here?
I'm passing the username. Right.
Is someone here also passing the username?
Right?
Multiple places.
I'm passing this username here also.
So even if there is a change
in the use of new rule,
I need to change in this small
piece of coded for places.
Right.
And this is not appropriate approach.
So what is the alternate?
Don't let me show you
in this nugget beach right in this log in.
Did you play Google?
I will write you delete
link like everyone knows
why the user did it find my
everyone knows you don't want me.
We used way to define the locator.
So my locator is available
for one with I.D..
I might look for the ids D
deeds, the user name.
Right.
And here I'm
going to provide my group element as the
user group.
And then I provided it very limited user
name group.
I made it public.
Why I made it public.
Supposed to
Why I made it public
because I want to use this particular
key user name across the
my entire project.
Right?
So to access it across my entire project,
I have to use this key as a public,
as a public key.
So this user name is available
as a publicly everywhere,
correct? Correct.
Grace Now let me take the same thing
for password also.
So he is listed as
password field
and this should be my
it should be my t
password.
Similarly, this one should be my VPN
login. So I'm writing here.
This should be my log.
In this
case.
Ah, this nugget is going to tell me
is that any of the look that we got from
the logging feature, is it
any of the look at the record
from the log page
error message?
Correct.
Cannibalism
with the idea of the data message based
it, we put it here
for the error message. So
I had a message
and someone please provide me
the end of the message.
I think this was sent such
please correct me if I'm wrong.
Is this correct?
Screams
guys, please don't type again.
I'm saying please don't be because here
for you
then we can not answer.
Yes, Nicole.
That's what I'm saying. Don't they?
Don't I just see what I'm going to try
and respond to it.
Try to be in the communication with the
the conversation.
Can we use any locator here?
City These are the locators.
Can you see these are the locators.
We are to use this locators
wherever we need them.
Okay?
Whenever we need them, we will use them.
Fine. So first things first.
Remember when we talk about Beach
object more do get better, right?
We have to initialize all the elements
straight.
All the elements
which we have in this particular beach,
in this particular class.
And to do this
whenever we want to do this, I mean,
instead of maybe use textbook,
if we use it, we can use a lot of things.
Yes, we can use a lot
of things that don't really
we can use a lot of things already.
You can use export.
You can use class name I.D., name,
trade, text, anything you can use
because everyone is comfortable
with this part.
That's why
I'm thinking from students perspective.
So now, guys, remember first
to use all these elements, grade first,
we have to initialize this elements.
What we have to do.
First, we have to initialize this element.
So now I know.
Just remember
the definition of constructor. Why?
Because constructor we generally use
when initialize the object right?
When we actually create the object
constructor
is directly called
automatically Constructor call.
We need constructor
to pass all of these things.
Great days.
Remember, if there is no default
constructor we are going to write user
defined constructor.
Got it.
And what is the definition of constructor?
Constructor is its
theme is constructed having the same name
as the class name,
but it looks like a method.
Then this is a definition of constructor.
Not so.
Let me later one constructor.
I don't know. This
constructor I'm asking you
is naming a statement
as the last but looks like a method.
This is a definition of constructor.
It's going to.
This is correct constructor or not.
So now I'm going to make this constructor
also public
and I'm making this public
by making this because I would use it
everywhere again, right?
If I make it private.
That is one of the question they ask.
Where did you used
constructor in your project?
So we apply the same thing
we do. Grid Yes.
Yes. Correct.
So this is the constructor
we are using to initialize
the objects to initialize
all the elements of the beachfront.
So Beach complete names for Logic Beach
we have one beach.
Great.
For this
would be a one beach for an employee.
The one beach for employees
that we have one beach.
So when we have multiple pages
in multiple classes.
We call this beach country
and a repeat of the beach
and we have multiple elements
to initialize this elements.
We need constructor.
In that constructor, we're using.
Understood.
Now see now see.
Very simple code.
I'm going to write for State.
Tell me the is where we have my drivers.
We need a lot of things
for our common methods.
So states are common
methods supposed to have
common methods.
And now I'm going to write inside this
inside this page again.
You see the first one which tree
I'm seeing dark
initialize element's initialize elements.
It is asking for two things here.
See it is asking for web driver. First,
it is asking for web drivers based to me.
Do we need to define another web here?
Or we can simply take the instance
of that web driver.
What we have from the common methods.
We can take the driver
from my commonwealth.
It's good to see it is connected and then
and then it is asking for not multiclass
objects.
So I'm defining it. Do this. Why?
Because I'm going to provide
which page this particular page.
So I'm going to initialize the elements,
this page.
That's why I brought this keyword
here, read this keyword here
and the driver I'm taking from
with the driver I'm taking from Common.
Understood.
If you don't want to take this common
methods from here, don't make it directly.
You have to write from here the code
for your common methods for driver.
This is also you can do.
Can you see things here?
Can you see?
There it is also you can do directly.
But then you will not be able
to use the properties of common methods
throughout your class.
So it is always good to follow the concept
of the concept of inheritance
and instead of this,
to simply call the driver
using extrinsic key
word in common methods.
So for any question in this
new question,
everyone, shall
you proceed further?
This is the first speech
we have created right now.
See what I'm going to do.
Very simple thing.
What I'm going to do now,
I will go in with this.
So in my log, in two steps, I will go.
I saw here I'm using username password
here, I'm using this username.
Let me do one thing this time.
See, I'm going to create the
object of my logging, which
at the
moment
I create the object of my login page.
My constructor is called automatically
or not the me
any days.
My constructor
is called automatically or not.
So now using this object
when I provide daughter,
it is giving me username and password.
We log important error message everything.
Can you see?
Can you see this crazy
right now?
Provide this username read
this username to dark circles
and here provide your send key straight.
So whatever the data you have
for the username. Right.
So data we are providing,
we are providing from
configurator.
Don't forget property
value in the vendor is providing a user.
Now tell me guys,
do we need these two lines then?
Do we need this web element?
Do we need this code?
We don't need it.
Not anymore.
Read the same thing
we can do with the password.
So this line on with the log in,
not the password field not is.
So again,
we don't need this code as we can now
see my code restricted to just two steps.
Can you see
my code is restricted to just two steps.
Similarly here, see here
what I'm going to do.
Take this log in breach again.
Great.
Because I defined this object
inside this particular step.
So it is not applicable to business.
Great.
I have to create another object here.
And this time I'm writing again.
Don't log in and simply click on this one.
And again,
we don't need this web element from here.
Correct? Is this correct?
Guys?
Similarly, I want to use.
Right. For example,
take this logging page from here.
Go to this a step.
Also find in this step.
Also use this log in word
change everywhere.
Whenever you are getting this user name
and provide this
similarly here also go right logging
password, field and incentives trade
Similarly
go for your logging door on door.
Don't click great days.
So now see, we don't need this amendment.
We don't need this element.
We don't family.
And just in make what is working
can be a function by and replace in
we use the function find
we can do that
but just to show everyone right.
It is a quick quick one.
It is a quick one.
But if I do this,
people will not understand.
That's fine. I'm going.
This is step by step approach.
Similarly here
raid for a solutions right this time.
See, I'm getting this error message
from here from this web element.
I don't want this web element anymore
because I have this part in my
in my login page.
So let's take it from logging based
error message.
I got this from there.
So this time same locator works
for my particular class.
Now see how the linking to get check
right click on this username
to go do declaration.
It is taking you to this place,
right?
It is linked with this particular key
that you avoided
here in the store.
Indisputably one.
So now you see
because of using this particular log in
if I go in, my log in is steps right
in my log in, two steps.
If I go and let me change this
to one more place here
and providing logging page
instead of these logging door
username rates or don't need this part.
Similarly, we don't need this,
but we can simply log in
password field, find
and it work right now.
See it is asking for dashboard.
So tell me nice to do something on
dashboard which class we need to create.
I don't want this locator here no more.
Look in any of the class,
no more looking down the steps.
Your locators, your functions.
We have to clear dashboard
which so unlock does on functions
when reading enough classes in our pages.
Fine.
So let me right
click in, Create another class bottom line
bottom on baseboard page.
When my Facebook page
tried again, Extents
extends to common methods
release
right to extend common methods
we all normally would
then enter it find.
But again
here we need to provide the value.
Fine. So let's provide the value.
So what?
All are
the things I see on my dashboard page?
The first thing is the welcome message,
which we would have like.
So let me take this as I the equals
value of this I can find here.
It says Welcome one.
So let's take this welcome here
and then I'm going to write public
places.
Welcome message
function.
What is the constructor Public
Dashboard page.
Public dashboard page.
Then Beechwood did not initialize
and the means driver
command this
hardware guys
students. Now
see if I go in my log instance.
I don't need this look at.
I will simply need to my dashboard page
but I'm
spending
dashboard page.
Create the object for this one.
Right
and simply instead of using this part.
Right,
this park web element simply right here
called dash
dot welcome message,
welcome message is displayed
and we don't need this element anymore.
So now what is big is to extend
or to call from to extend to extend.
I will explain you why.
BLITZER
Because when you put it in the constructor
right, you're making the scope
limited, right?
You're making the scope limited.
I will tell you,
if we extend that throughout the class,
how can you use those properties?
You will understand that part
one actually explained
because in common metrics,
we are going to add a lot of things,
right,
So that you will understand this concept.
Fine, guys.
So now, now, whatever
the things we did for this small book,
which is just one log in step three,
we create a dashboard page in log in which
no next time,
next time when your user make changes,
when your password changes,
when you log in,
look at our changes dashboard changes.
It should extend common methods. Class,
correct?
Correct. Correct. Exactly.
I will.
I will tell you why.
Rate in this legacy rate
in this next to classes on weekends
and this class, it will make more
clear for you,
why do we need to do this one?
So now you see this.
If if this time my user name
look bigger change password.
Look it again. 2200.
This is
how many place has been in the change Now
just going to one place
Jason located here.
Right. Just one place. Change it here.
And this key is applicable to every base
and no one look at it is going to work
for all the classes.
So no more maintenance.
No more maintenance.
Date You'll come across an issue
with the look at the prime Go ahead
candidate
one place and will fix all of your screwed
in dispute.
This part everyone
so for any questions Student
So now in Dashboard
Beach in Dashboard page,
we have a couple of more indicators
virtually obtained.
First, let's complete the speech.
Now, if you seen the dashboard steps read
here, we got
we got this data in the list of relevant
support for this.
We got this date also correct.
So now first, take this look at here.
Right. So I'm going to write this bar
list of elements of our list,
what I have to write,
public public
list of verbatim.
So I need this for
dashboard steps.
And what is the locator?
So the locator I can take from here only
it is via explanatory.
So let me take this export
and put it here.
So this would be my city
if I know that I'm using
x button instead of your I
is this one.
Nice.
See going to dashboard page here.
Create the object to find next object for
dashboard page is equals to the new
ish for beach and this time
we don't need this particular one.
They should perhaps read
okay one.
So we were taking this from here.
So this painting Dash done this book
kind, we provided this.
We don't need this.
Looking at the stored
industrial we want
we don't need this locator anymore.
We directly prevented this
from our dashboard based. It's
now Now, if I go to the application
you see on this dashboard page,
we have the option employee list.
Option right.
And employee button, all these options
I want page or not
then me this option employee list,
everything is available in my baseboard.
So let's take this three also because
we know we will be using employee list
and we are using actually an employee
employee list and option point.
Do we have the locators for this
three B option employee list?
And this
days,
do we have to look for option?
Or if we were to
invoke
this term?
Yes, we do have.
So let's take those locators from it.
Employee steps.
If I go, let me check.
We have BIM option, right?
So let's take this 80 for the option here.
If I copied this 80 and if I come here
BIM option, fine.
There you go.
Similarly for an employee.
So for an employee, this is the ID
copy this party and and paste it here.
Fine. And the last one is employee list.
So this employee list option
we got here in the verification part.
Right. Let's see the employee list.
We just clicked on this employee list
in employment
and find
employee list.
There you go.
This is the employee list option. Fine.
So copy this employee list.
Now come to Dashboard
Beach and simply add this employee list is
now again what we need to do.
Go wherever we are.
Finding this particular part right
Whenever we are calling rate and,
we will change them.
So after the break, right after the break,
we will change all this.
Locators in this class, this yellow.
I knew, I knew it.
All right.
So just thermometers, right?
And then we will be on break.
But so far, whatever the things we are
doing, you guys understood it or not?
Tell me this is the page
object model design concept design
in which we are using.
It's cool.
It's actually good and a lot of cool
things on the we like, guys are great.
We're going to reduce the concept now.
We are going to reduce
the number of lines of code, right?
We will use less number of lines
and we utilized and called
reusability concepts to the fullest.
We are going to implement in the
framework.
All right, guys,
so far, any questions?
I'm not going to push the code as of now
because code is in between.
Right. It's not a complete code.
So that's why I'm not going to push it
right after the class.
I will push the code. So don't ask
the code, which was supposed to be pushed.
I already pushed.
This code is incomplete.
That's why I'm not pushing.
It is because we need to fix
all the biggest one.
Okay.
Already so needed to take a break
and you push, push, push, push.
You pushed four times.
No, no, no, no.
We should start with this concept
that if someone got it correct,
we should start with the concept
from the scratch.
I will tell you.
I will tell you how to identify
the two technologies.
Would you like to change?
I will change.
I would change the.
Oh, break for 15 minutes, guys.
Classic. 15 minutes looking for 10 minutes
would be
okay, let's take a break for 15 minutes
and we'll connect up on that.
Let me start the recording just fine.
So now this is my dashboard page.
If I click on bim right,
then BIM is not going to let me anywhere.
It is still on their dashboard page.
So I got all this locators in it,
put them in their dashboard.
So there you go.
This is what I have it.
Should it open a different window?
So yes, correct.
I mean, it means more simply that
the screen is going to be application.
We consider them as a pages.
If you don't have any screen,
the application will not consider
this is a page.
Alright.
All right.
So now, now let's do one thing. Great.
Let's quickly change.
We click change all of this options
that it would we have used.
So first let's go to employee search rate.
In employee search, we got employee list
in module rate.
This is the first one more option,
so we need to change it.
So PIM option is available
in which particular based in which class
we have option
students
in they should be trained.
So let me clear our dashboard
beach. Right.
So let me just take this new
dashboard page and here
this dash dark
emotion I need to click
so I don't need this particular looking.
Do I have employee list also in addition,
which
let's just
employee list
also we have on the page or not.
Yes we do have
So now see just one object creation.
Right.
And both
the elements are coming from that.
They should be similarly
come here train for search 80.
So now tell me, guys, for searching the ID
grade for getting this particular value.
Do I need to create another page
or dashboard? We just point
is, do I need
to create another page of this dashboard?
Biggest point
for this search employer to look again?
New page. Right.
Christine,
How is it possible they're doing?
They should be.
They can read the data for an employee.
We can't do this right.
We need to create a new page.
So my new page would be
used according to the screen.
So what is the name of my page?
New employee.
Page A new employee page not eliminated.
Then whenever we create a new page,
what is the first thing we do?
It stinks.
Common methods.
And then we provide all the locators.
So let me go to an employee page post.
Tell me, what are the locators we need?
First name, middle name,
last name, employee
photograph create log in user confirm
password.
Say button. We need all these.
We need all.
These are not.
Tell me
so let's add them quickly.
Expand them quickly.
Guys, this is not something
which is rocket science.
It really is a thing I'm doing.
We already have this.
No, because I'm
just putting it in my page.
So the name would be my first.
I will take a look at
and this would be mine
to name
last name.
This would be my employee already
made locator and the employer did.
This would be mine
checkbox right
then this would be mine.
Okay.
After photograph I need for
to create the user name.
Is it user name after create username.
I need your password
and then my new book password.
And another one I need is perseverance.
So this would be mine.
See, that is correct.
Let's change. Let's change this. Keys.
So this keys I can find here.
I can find this keys of
the first name is this one.
We take this post to.
Actually, I'm on the same page.
Right?
Why we are not creating
the bin would be more option.
That's what human nature
later said.
Be this related to the screen
in the application.
Do we have any screen bin?
This is just an option
or it is a complete script.
Didn't
vet video.
See, this is a different page.
That's what I'm asking.
You see, when I click on beam,
when I click on beam,
it is just an option which is me.
This option here,
can you see just Mozilla on the beam?
When you click on beam, it is providing
you see
it is providing your employee information
which is employee list can you see so
begins again redirecting you to employee
list and not on speech.
If I click on employee see number
two is taking you to an employee page,
but you are clicking one beam.
It is taking you to employees to page.
That is no page for
industrial nation.
That is
no father.
No, we can't do this
because we have to initialize all of them
and to initialize
after that we have to cleared the object.
So I have this optional. Absolutely.
I will give you the solutions, but let
first, once we are done,
once we are done with this thing,
then I give you the solution.
How we can get rid of this
creating multiple objects there.
Okay, so it is in my book.
Hopefully the minimum sort of a beat
would just be
just like config.
That's what I'm saying.
Aisha Why?
You're not going to spend me
when we click on beam.
Can you see this
employee list is highlighted?
What does it mean
when you click on payment is taking you
to employee list page?
This is employee list page on me.
What is this?
This is an employee list page.
Raise.
Let me show you.
Let me show you the floor again.
Let me show you the floor.
You are on dashboard page.
So this is their dashboard, right?
You'll see everything on dashboard
when you click on beam, bitch.
When you click on Beam page,
it is taking you to employees to page.
This is employees to page.
Well, it's been page to me.
You need to
based on page.
And when you're talking about this,
what options you're getting the support
options only dashboard which see,
when I go in this work page,
I simply do this mouse over on
you see, I'm getting this for options.
So this what options doesn't
we don't be a beach.
And now when you click on beam,
it is taking you to employee list page.
See, employee needs to be
read.
You'll get understood
cutting
cutting currently
do not have any page such just beam.
That's way.
All right so now let me quickly add
all of their data from your boss to me
and then put they just for
last to name
and put as
many.
This is for button.
So let me change your privacy.
Also,
this is for many.
This is going we
now we need for employee ideas, but
I will point out here
for employee I.D.
this is the employee. A client is fine.
Just take it
for duty and then for checkbox.
So this is for checkbox
and I will put this checkbox
here and photograph.
So this is 34 books, but I you put
complete and
pasted here then for username.
So this would be the key for my username
and then for password.
So this would be the key for my
password.
Create password first
and then for password.
So this is the key for my password.
Now I got all this looking there. See it?
Can you see guys?
I got all this.
Look, here's
after this one step remaining.
What is that?
There is one step too many
instructor blades of public
and new employee page.
This is the construct that was deployed
called page three
or initialize element Driver.
Come on.
This. Right,
Right.
Guys, I'm done with this page.
Find the only beach,
the only page remaining.
Now see the only player remaining now
is this employee list beach.
Can you see the only pages
remaining now is this employee list page.
Here we are using three locator.
See, the first one
is searching by adding using
today's bid using search by 88.
We are using this search option and
we are taking their data from this list.
Right. This. So we got three locators.
Do we have already these
three locators and
right.
So now you get to and Aisha answer
to your question when we talk this page,
because this is a proper page
in the application,
we will create a separate class
for this one.
Go employee.
It's employee used page
since we have a proper plus,
since we have a proper screen
and then we have a proper
screen are using this particular page.
Understood now.
Now understood.
The concept of page object order design.
We should not go with just one option
or something
built in unless we have the complete
screen in the application.
We may not be in the beach
already.
Everyone understood these are not the
everything we need new Plus,
this is what we call
beach object model design.
But you need to create the object
of the beach in this design.
Then this is the model
that's explain.
There's nobody understood now, right?
I should.
So not on this beach. On this beach road.
We need certain locators on employee list
Beach
like we had locator for employees today
for the beach.
You get up and let me go,
and this would be once again
build me in this option.
When I saw this motion, this options
only the employee list an employee.
If if I do not write
this initial board page,
then what is the best place to make that
bet is another beach where we can do this.
I'm getting this option in.
This would be really great
credit scoring.
Someone is obliged, Steve.
We are.
We are getting this employee list
and they options
in which beach
in this footbridge
only that's why we need to keep on
of this thing Barefoot Beach.
If these things are visible
at any of the beach and definitely will
a new class
we add this be just this locators there
since again
they think this in their dispute building
why way to create any of the replacement
necessary for this could not
now let me take the locator
one by one here.
The first one is we need to open by any
employee
for searching the employee search.
So for that
this data
I need again from search employee.
So this is the only I will get from here
and I will keep it in my
employee list page that you.
And after this I need search button
so me as search button on this beach
and this search done I'm departing
from this search but
this also search for the new
guys.
Am I going bust or despite
because we already have this
locator straight,
I'm just copying and resort from here.
And there's the only thing I'm doing
is fine
and only is always agree
everything is okay.
Go ahead and do.
Employees are just tips now after this.
After this.
What we have to do this one.
Great
employee
search by name or something, right?
We can do this
for maybe we have some other look.
Sector will change for every value that
might need three Looking right now again,
the same stage public
beach name is employed is two page
will find
page 50 dot initialize elements
driver comment this find
nasty goes
now see we have all the locators read
all the locators in the respective pages
you see next time all need to do
is we just need to fix
all of these things.
How? Let's see
here we need force name locator to add
the employee every single thing find.
So in the beginning of this step,
in the beginning of the step,
I will create I will create the object
for this particular class,
for this particular class.
And now see,
do I need this web element from you
guys?
Do I need this very element from here? No.
We can write this and not force name
that is already here.
We don't need this line.
Similarly, and don't last name
look that is here.
So we don't need this line.
Similarly, ID don't
really
look at it is here.
So we don't need this line as we
connect.
Employee Fine.
So here also we can write simple.
This part is not employed.
We look at it.
We don't need this line
for to find no issues in this photo.
So here it don't photograph.
So now we don't need this line.
If there is any rule. Best practice.
We're naming the object.
Yes, just connect.
So by the by the name date by default.
What should added, for example,
is this employee beach.
So the name of the object
should be like this small one employee.
Okay,
this is the best practice by default.
You're intelligent.
Give you this addition.
All right.
So nasty.
But just to give you the know, high level
information, I did the shorter one.
But yes, if you want to change,
you can change like this.
Okay.
Reading is
now here.
Also, we need these eight employed
beach rate is employed based on checkbox.
We need point
and here also we need this employee page.
Don't checkbox.
Got it.
Now for these three
also we don't need them.
Not anymore.
So just comment this nasty.
Your best guess is reduced.
Choose here.
You need this very employee beach object.
Don't use it.
You don't need this.
You're Also you need an employee page
object.
Start It must work so you don't need this.
You're also you need this object.
Start the password so you don't need this.
It also just come in this part
and then an employee page
or see important.
So we're going to make this part.
Now see, your code looks clean.
Very simple code to read this and build
this based this employee list option
we are getting from where
this employee list option
we are getting from it.
Come on this board page.
So we need this dashboard beach file
is dashboard feature
to stick the look into the object is easy
as of now.
Fine.
So here I'm writing for a dish
or simply needs to work.
Fine.
So this location is normal in use
employee search fruit available
on which please goes
to me.
Employee search field is available
on which feature.
Again, sorry this employee search
with available employee search for you
know.
This employee search field is available on
employee list page.
All right.
So employing this to beach
is equal scrutiny
employee list page
being from here,
I will call this employee list.
Which board
employee list
which store I the employee search
base.
And then the search within
is also available on the same page.
So dark search button.
I need now.
We don't need this element
we don't need disturb element as well.
Correct.
In this data I can keep again as of now
because using it for just work.
So that is completely fine.
This employee button I'm getting from here
again are they should page it in bulletins
or take it from there
and then we don't need
this particular proportion.
All right.
So we've fixed this particular
step, right?
You can fixed all of these steps here
also.
Or do you want me to fix every step
you send me
there is
Do you want me to fix them listed?
Do it.
Thank you, sir.
Who? Let me do it.
Liquidity trouble here. So first.
Yep. I have to follow the order from Mr.
Local. It's very important.
Click the new dashboard page.
So from here I will trade
Base Dark
shop team option.
You got it.
After this. We need.
We don't need this particular one,
so let's do it.
I see how busy you guys are.
When I asked who is going to do any one,
it will follow.
Let me stop right now.
Let me ask where you lost my
business
and your get that you lost, All right?
You lost.
It means you're writing something,
correct?
I'm watching. Which understand. Right.
So why you're typing, ma'am,
when I'm saying don't date, well,
you're lost in the end.
I give you this code, right?
I will give you this code.
So please watch.
Otherwise we'll end up with confusion.
I'm typing this for you.
It is not for me.
I know how to create the framework.
I'm typing all of this things for you,
so please follow it.
Just look what I'm doing.
So. So that you don't get confused.
That is the only intention I have
so that you guys don't lost.
It would be great to see.
Everyone is watching
and you're typing in there.
If you have any questions, read that.
It is pretty much.
Yeah. Gutting.
So I quit trying forward and it's
just.
Yes, yes, yes. That's what I'm saying.
No, Abe, if you are typing,
then what would you do after the class
date time?
You have time right after the class.
You have time to type
to practice everything.
This is the time to get
the things understood right.
So please watch what I'm doing right.
This is not rocket
science. It's a simple thing.
We get our locators from multiple places.
We collected them,
and then we put all of them in one place.
Right now, we are calling all these
locators one by one from that place.
So earlier we had a different could not
get a listing that could be advanced one.
There's the only thing I'm doing
that is this is the only thing I will not.
So please follow me.
Please follow me.
Now, here
we got this fixed dashboard.
But first name, last name, First time,
Last name.
We one which begins to mean on
it and blank page
is equal to new
page.
Fine.
So here
at the start, enforcement
Roadster, the key is below this book.
Similarly here
employee page don't
last name,
so we don't need this locator either.
This is good all the way. Really.
I'm just removing one by one
so that it will be really easy for you to
in this date.
Similarly, let me take this particular one
right and book it here
so that this time
when I'm picking this new employ
object, don't
post names.
Forgot to put
line four before.
Yes, ma'am.
Thank you so much.
You got it.
So we don't need this now.
We don't need this as well. Right.
Because we are going to write an
employee beach dot last name.
We don't need it.
So don't need this either.
Like an employee page or dark middle name.
So we don't need it.
Find again, see how many times
we are using this post name last name
every time we were passing the data.
We are having a hard time now.
We don't need to do all of this stuff.
Simple thing At the end, the object called
this object called the locator.
Again,
call the object.
Call the locator.
Save the data
for the same thing we are doing.
Forward looking name as it was
fine.
We are close guys.
We are close now
that I believe we have written this much.
Of course of
life and don't
go past a really simplified
Yes is I read all of this
things for you
so that you guys don't have to write it
just to use this code red as a reference.
So again,
the object,
all the locators.
Fine. Same thing.
Use this object,
call the locator so that we don't need
this element either.
Thank you so much.
And employee peach again,
we need layer bash food.
Peach is the you dish food peach go here
managed on an employee to
Finally
we fixed all the code
in this particular class
we fit the complete code in this class.
We fixed it in their neighborhood pages
I believe.
Yes, we fixed it in employee search.
Step or dashboard We fixed.
But here we're doing fixed,
so let's do it.
Satiety is on employee list.
Peach equals to new employee list.
Peach
in district that we will be getting from
my employee list, which on
your front search button
finally shows
I do have search button on this page only,
so let
me copy and clear the object here
on my employee list page Search button.
Fine.
So now we don't need this element.
We don't need this element.
I'm just coming thing.
I'm not deleting
so that you guys can understand.
Great what we did earlier
and what we are doing now.
Great
here.
Also state here also.
Yes please to yes.
And I'm not deleting this word
I'm missing.
I'm not deleting
this to preach employees of the state.
My name was imposter data
so we don't need this again is
going to log in steps
we see log in page right.
Every tree object
we have created so far here.
This one.
So now, now we are fixed.
We are fixed. See?
No more locators available. See?
Not in this page. No more locators.
Not in this page.
There is no located in this page.
Norton Dashboard Dashboard steps.
Right. And not employee steps.
It is no longer available Base.
So my every local that is passing
from my employee Beige dashboard
page employee list logging
which is this correct?
Is this correct discordance
so first was let's try to run very basic.
So now you read lipstick.
Anyone scenario for example one smoke.
I'm going to take this right
I'll let me take this one is this easy?
Okay.
So to check whether might look like
they're sort of working or not, click
just to check
whether my locators are working or not.
Let's execute this scenario first
days of working
there is good working or not.
Still.
So what?
It is working,
it means my locators mapping
object initialization constructor calling.
Everything is working. Absolutely. Getting
correct
or unrelated right now.
Now let me simplify it more.
Right. Let's go ahead.
One more step further.
One step further.
We will go to right. Okay.
Ready, everyone
wants to taste.
I need your energy.
I am running out of my battery.
I need your energy. Then
are you guys ready to learn
one more important thing
here?
Months?
Yes. Look what we are going to do.
So now you'll see if.
I go in my eight employee steps.
You see,
I created a lot of object
dashboard page here.
Then this work page here, then employee
new bigger than new employee page book.
I missed you save button better
again, I have to create the new page
for this page.
New page eight new
employees
includes two new in employee page
and then I
am going don't see important
here.
We do it in one installing page. Right?
So now see I'm taking note of objects
read every
and these objects are such a been for me
read a lot of objects.
I don't want to create this object
so many places.
See here what I am doing right now
I have my logging page for example.
This is my class logging page.
If I am having dashboard four steps,
I'm creating the object for this one.
If I'm having an employee steps,
I'm creating the object
for those same one.
Even if I have any steps
I have to create in
different objects,
I want to get rid of this part.
I don't want invitation anymore. Fine.
If I don't want reputation any more,
what we can do
is we can create under the steps.
We can create one class which will
initialize all the objects at one time.
So next time
we don't need to create any object.
We will create
one class there to be initialized
all the object at one time.
So next time
we don't have to create any other object.
Only that object we can call everywhere.
Everybody be at. How did we show you?
So the name of this class
we are going to make?
No, this is not talks again.
I'm telling you what is hooks
is different.
This is object oriented programing.
So everything is object.
I'm going to do page in me.
She aligns
what is the name of my class is
the name of
my class is bead initialization.
Bead initialize a very simple class.
Very simple class.
Let me show you what
we need to write in this class.
You will definitely like this
particular part.
What I'm trying to show
you don't see in this bit.
Initialize it. I am with the right symbol.
All the objects read
so I'm making my objects my object.
This public
static make
public this big
log in page. Right.
And the object name
I will use this log in simple.
Similarly, I have public
static
dashboard page.
This object is dash simple extinguish.
I am having an employee beach. Great.
So this would be my object.
I am Royalist Peach.
So one
impressionist beach.
So this would be my object.
Three things We make them public
static.
This one also only make them public.
Let's take
now see what I'm doing.
Simply, simply, I'm writing one method.
And the method name is
this method
I'm going to call public estate White ID,
I'm calling it a neat shin Lies
Beach
Object.
This is my method.
All right, guys, guys, this is my method.
Now, what I'm going to do here in this
method, I'm writing first,
This is the log
in which is equal to the new log image.
I initialized
trade.
Then dashboard is equal
to new dashboard, which initialized.
Then add new employee pages equals
to new employee page initialized.
Then employee list it is equals
for me.
Employee that's initialized.
Now see,
all of my objects are initialized.
Next, next time, if you come across
if you come across and explain
any other for example,
new page, you create new class,
you create what you need to do.
Just create the object of the class here
and initialize that object.
In this particular class, a student
understood this.
Know how this will work?
I'm showing you so far.
Take me this part clear to everyone.
This page initialize
that part is geared to implement
newborn
nines.
Now see what I'm doing now
see what I'm doing.
This first piece of your deal status,
everyone, whether you're doing it or not.
Come on.
Very interesting thing we are going to do
quickly update your status.
All the geniuses still are like
nice, nice.
When you are exhausted,
learn how to take the list.
Not to quit, not to last in between.
I think it's quite
clear that this bacteria human right.
We are still geniuses right now
going to your common methods
see in your common method straightforward.
Let me show you
which is the initial point.
Which is the initial point.
The initial point. We have hooks.
The initial point could be a hook,
say from here might in
that execution is a starting correct,
but it is precondition.
I have been in the hooks in precondition.
I put which particular step,
which particular
method open
browser and launch application ladies
open blue closed blue fine.
So here you'll see right
this one particular one right in the
before this precondition.
In this precondition we are calling open
browser and launch application method
and this method is available.
This method is available
in my common methods. Right.
So let's come to my common
method and extend extends here
beach Initialize the class VI
because then I want to initialize
all the objects.
I want to initialize objects
of all the classes when I actually start
my execution.
So I'm actually starting my execution
here.
So I am seeing the
the moment I'm going to call my browser,
the moment I'm going to launch my
until initialize all the objects.
So now here I'm going to write this
method called initialize page objects
in my open
browser launch application method.
Can you see those?
Can you see
what I'm doing?
I extend this page, initialize
a class in my common methods.
When I got this in my common methods
I call this particular
method from my page initialization class.
Is this clear to everyone
now what it will do?
What it will do? What I do This
the moment.
The moment I am going to initialize the
I'm going to start my execution.
So in the very beginning of my execution,
the very beginning of my execution,
my hooks will call this method open
browser launch application,
and this method will initialize
all the object to all the classes
because initialized based object
method is meant called here.
Understood.
Now see now see the difference.
Now see the difference.
We extended this common
methods everywhere.
We extended this common.
But they're simply buildings.
Yes. Correct.
So now now let's go to log in to see.
I have common methods here.
In log instance,
I have common methods right?
It means the object we have already
initialized for log in page.
I don't need to
create this object anymore.
Why? It is giving me the error.
Because the object name is logging page.
The object name is log in page red case.
I don't need this object here
because the object name is login page,
which we created.
I don't need this object also.
Right.
Because the object name is logging peach.
You know.
So it is log in page
is also login page,
which is also log in page.
I don't need this
also because object name is
this log in.
I just need to correct the log
posting mixed
more.
Think thinking
now next time.
Could we also put this initialized
method insert hook.
No, no, no, no, no.
There's we're going to see
see in your hooks.
In your hooks.
So you have this open browser, correct.
You are extending common methods in hooks.
Understood.
So you are getting this common
methods technique.
So we need to call it
we need to call in common methods.
So the time when you call, when you extend
the properties of common methods
by default, you will get the properties
of your page initializes.
And you don't need to be initialized here
because you are calling this
particular method in hooks and this method
is already having been initialized.
Object. Okay, this.
All right, fine.
Now let's go to base footsteps first.
Let me fix it.
Also, you'll see this dashboard page.
But I don't need this time.
So it converts again in purple
because see, what it says is steps
be it initialized from initialized
or this object is coming in.
You see public static basswood peach.
It is coming
from the just also where to log in page.
It says step start page.
Initialize the public static log in beach.
We created this object in page.
Initialize that part one.
Now you see your code, now
you see your code
you unit to click on log in bottom. Right.
Nobody's gone the object
to perform click call the object.
Call to perform in the case.
Call the object.
Call the allocator.
Performance indicators one very Easy.
Right.
Let's do this for the remaining part
as we see.
Do we need this dashboard plate
object case?
Then we here we need this object.
No Coming.
Let's see.
It started giving me any errors.
It's not giving me any.
Is going to employ such.
Do we need this employee list
for the object? No.
See it converts.
Do we need this dashboard? No.
See, it converts.
Just play with the code employee list
page.
No, it converts
employee list page not converted. So
in this case we are just commenting.
We're reducing the code
now one by one. See?
Now let's go to an employee steps
commenting this part.
Fine.
It's working.
Amending this part fine.
Still it is working.
Great, great.
Yeah,
we would play if we know how to play that.
They're sort of teaching you.
That's what I'm teaching you, right
now. Just a command.
Whenever you initialized all the objects.
We don't need objects anymore.
Multiple times.
One place we defined for the objects.
That one place
is calling all of my objects.
Right, guys?
This one place
is calling all of my objects.
So we don't make objects
any more externally.
So now, see all the objects I fixed here,
I fixed all the objects here as well.
I don't need this object. Find it fixed.
It is also fixed.
This one also fixed. Fine.
We don't need this part.
This one also fixed.
And this one also fixed.
Fine.
Correct. Got it. Got it.
First I gave you the linear solution
and then give you the quick one.
Right.
So therefore you understand the importance
of this quick or quicker ones.
Okay.
So now you see the this baseboard
stability segregated world, right
employee suggested very segregated
log in is steps very segregated train
everything is segregated
no separate state
organized easy to read correct
that days
should would title once again
so that whatever the things we have added
just we want to make sure the rendered
things are working or not
so next running
initialized
all the objects getting the data
from log in page, building it here,
verify their dashboard page and it's gone.
Is this clear to everyone screams
this one
because this one of the points
I need to add and
that's why you see all this would
also bring the pages in this page
initializing.
Once I know all of these things
in the grid, then it becomes blue.
There's one.
It's stored in the repository
it's one local.
Yeah. No, I will.
I will for sure
will replace
so far.
Any questions?
Anyone
over?
None.
This is the actual framework
that we are making now.
Yes. Tomorrow is a review
on every property
in same things on the we now guys.
See now see one more thing.
Can we go to a little more logic
one more time.
Sure. And so this is the logic.
Logic is page object model design.
We right
according to this page object
moderate design button, right.
What we need, we need to basically
define all the objects, all the functions
related to one particular screen
in one separate class.
So the model,
if you have to fix that particular part,
you don't need to fix it in
multiple places.
You just go in one place, right?
Just click one place,
fix it with this, implement
the rest of all the places
it will get fixed automatically.
First thing.
Second thing to do this,
what I have to do, I have to create
be just according to the classes
and then I need to put
all the new characters
belong to the particular class.
That's what we did.
I know when we created all Look,
there's the functions, everything,
how to use them, how to use them.
So first we had one web driver, which
is already available in common methods.
So we extend the properties
of common matters.
Once we extended the properties
of common methods.
Here we use constructor to initialize
all these objects by be as constructor.
When we create the object constructor
it's been called automatically initialize
the object.
We need to construct the constructor.
Now here we have to initialize
all the elements of the beach,
so we are using beach
to initialize elements in it anyways.
Right.
And the driver
we are taking from our common methods.
And this is strings for, this keyword
which is pointing to my current class.
The pointer one.
Right. Current plus.
That's
what we did for all the separate pages.
Whatever the screens
we do not application we created.
We just for this
instrument.
Yes, we
have to forget all the previous systems.
Just focus on this particular event
and create projects with this will be way
I'm telling you,
I know it's all about mindset.
If you think I can do it, you can.
Do we believe you can do it?
It's very easy.
All right.
Okay.
But you guys did me.
So, Aleks, is this clear?
Is this clear what I said?
And then we will create this object
and the bridge initializes
right from that object.
We can call on the locators.
It's correct.
So this is the part of your page object.
Model your design, Pretend through
which you don't need to create
so many objects or group projects
in creating such frameworks.
Yes, I got it.
You need to create frameworks like this.
Then it's like we are digital or risky.
It is not
that we just wanted to to go with.
No, we have to create this right?
Gazi, whatever I said is it's is late
under of that
which I already
super in this part.
Any question
just in beginning
change note what we can change
there it is just a table we can do it
let me go ahead
and need to rename.
I like.
Well right now it got changed every bit
automatically
not omit.
One important announcement is still there.
Is it the final step?
No. Subtle one sort of planning step.
We are going towards
the final step in two classes.
I need many months.
Do we need more hours?
Maybe 10 hours straight.
Good things now. See you guys.
Another important thing
that will catch your attention.
Then we How many times we performed Click
Method Doors and Kismet.
How many things?
How many times?
Hundred times, right? Hundreds of times.
You're calling this dark click
methods go dark.
Same keys. But so, so many things. Right.
And also one more thing.
If you observed,
we are not waiting for elements.
So if you are not waiting for the elements
that are simply using trader sleep,
which is not a good option right?
Right.
Guys, if you're using trader
sleep, it's not a good approach.
We need to fix all of this because
remember, in our framework
we are not supposed to call this dart
click method from stadium everything.
What we will do,
we will write this click method one place
and we will simply automated concept
of polymorphic method overwriting We will
create saved is method in one place
and then we will simply override.
So next time the same circles.
But they're going to change the
negative quality, diluting the quality,
the look in the same method
we want implicit
we find call implicit wake method.
If you want to change that name right,
just change the name in one place
integrated to your project.
Whenever you call this implicit method,
then we will come up.
No, no copy paste, no copy paste, nothing.
We are going to write those dynamic
functions, right?
We are going to write those
two dynamic function. So
got it.
And after they will call are screenshots
method straight.
So the screenshot we take with them,
the execution,
it will give us the results.
Then we need all the screenshots
in one place.
We put all of them in one place.
These all are the things we will create
then when we execute our project.
Right?
Right now
we are executing our project from here.
I will tell you how to execute
your project even when you don't.
During DTG, we will execute your project
with our intelligent an entire project.
With our intelligent,
we can override the parameters.
Without intelligent
they're not. So we will see.
All right.
So the starting point was
you were executing every single class
nowadays,
including from one point in intelligent.
After some time you will execute from one
find in intelligent.
After that you will execute
without engaging in the next two stages.
Whenever you do that, your system,
your code automatically
get executed there. Also, we show you.
All right,
a note that is bit initialize
that is right related to the object.
That's why it is under the steps
nozzle. No.
Do you
think that I will be able to complete
all this explanation in just 10 minutes?
Today? Yes.
Yes. Correct. Correct.
So I'm
not sure I believe
it's already raised any questions for me.
I know it's part
nice.
It's Linda. I know it's confusing. I know.
But I hope you guys understood everything.
Whatever the things I explained.
And it's not something
which is going beyond the above.
It's not something like that.
I this is what I have been doing
for the last eight years, Right?
So even if you ask me, even I'm sleepy.
And if you ask me every day,
little step by step, Lenny Kravitz.
Who is this?
No more.
Okay, now
who's listening?
It's for the nice.
If I want an answer that are going to
not to be honest.
They are all gorgeous.
They might be.
I don't know.
I never find alternates.
So this is all from my side
or to this class.
I think I'm done from my side
if you guys have.