Great.
All right, guys.
So let me take one more flight here
as a note
so that we can start with the recap.
All right, students,
so we had started
with this dandy framework
in the last session, correct?
Those who guys didn't attend last class,
but them.
I'm telling you what we did
in the last session,
we started with the testing framework.
Earlier, we learned testing as a tool.
Now we are learning
test in G as a framework.
Should I commit this code
and it is already available
in the revenue repository.
All right.
So guys, tell me what is framework.
We discuss that part.
What is framework?
Yeah, yeah, I know.
I already committed it.
I will give a key set of rules.
Correct
structure and rules to follow.
It gives us
an organized
folder structure to follow.
Why? I'm writing the code.
Correct.
Is an organized folder structure, right?
A set of rules to follow
when we write the code.
Now, the question is,
it is giving us so many instructions,
the rules and the guidelines.
So what are we getting in the end
from the framework?
What are the benefits of using frameworks?
So benefits of
teamwork,
guys, why do we need framework?
Basically,
what are the benefits of using a framework
we can write code without framework.
Also, we already have a tool.
We know programing language,
we know everything
that we need, framework.
Yes, exactly.
It increases
all the usability.
The first thing
is the ability, say, content
and easy to maintain
maintainability, correct?
Yes. Right.
So in framework
you have a reporting, Right.
But without framework.
Also you can have reports.
I remember when we were learning
testing as a tool, we used that
listener and there
we were able to generate a stable report.
Yeah. Script less representation, right?
So this is what we call readability,
fine representation.
It simply means from just one click
you are able
to execute your entire report.
Doesn't matter how many classes you have,
how many text you have,
from how many classes you're passing,
the data,
every single thing, testing as a tool
and as a framework.
Both we use, right?
So right now,
when we are using right as a framework
there also
we will use a request annotation, right?
So this at the request, annotation
this test and you will find
this is a part of what
this is a part of a standard sent rate.
These things are already
there as a tool, right?
So now when we are creating
a framework in the framework,
we'll be using this thingy, then this test
and you will it not only as a framework
but also as a tool.
Getting that point you will
see when I say framework, it
is an organized structure,
correct organized folder structure.
But still to execute my script, right,
I need one tool and that is distantly
correct
one right.
So that was the first thing.
Great. The benefits of framework.
Correct.
Now, now,
when we are creating this framework, when
we are making this framework from scratch,
we are using one very important tool,
which tool is back
and correct.
So what does this mean?
Even when we are saying
we're using to create
our project framework from scratch,
we are using MAVEN.
What is embedded.
It is
build automation tool, correct
knowledge.
And this is not a word in control.
The virgin control is what? Yes.
Got virgin control this gate.
This is our build automation tool.
So basically why we use MAVEN?
I told you already, right?
I like I explained in the last session,
when we talk about MAVEN,
it gives us a completely readymade
structure, right?
Whatever the things we need beforehand,
start writing the test cases.
It gives us that structure.
Right now in this structure
because we have the things
from a diversified environment
where we can write our code at one place
and we can execute it at all the places.
This is our primary focus
when we create a framework.
I give an example also, right
when Mike, Anna or Nina and Blake,
if I'm not wrong, these four days
are working in one thing, right?
And the remaining three
wants to utilize the code, which is
in the Earth's core, right,
which has been written by the mike.
So how?
No, no, Elizabeth, I didn't say that.
I'm saying Maven is a build automation
tool and your gig is your virgin control.
These are two different things.
Right now we are using Maven on the right.
Whatever the things we are writing,
whatever the code
we are writing in one framework,
we are making it as a project.
And when it comes to saying this code,
to commit this code
into the repository, there
we use one virgin control tool that is
great is basically you consider transport
us, right?
Our code.
It transfers our quote from our local
machine, from our computer to cloud.
Correct.
This is great, but Maven is a tool
which allows us to create this project.
These are two different things
because so whatever
the code Mike has written, right,
he has written in his machine.
If the other people wants to utilize
this code, what they have to do
is they have to take the pull of this code
from the virgin control, from the cloud.
Right.
And the same code
should work in their machine
without even adding further Java files
or any other system.
Correct.
Maven allows you to do that.
How many of you guys remember
I told you talk to folder
Maven generally creates by default
the central repository of Maven.
I give you the concept. Correct.
So from the Maven central repository,
you can take the code, right?
You can take all the jar files
and it will create
its folder
dot m2 folder by default in your machine.
So this time you don't have to add
any jobs manually.
Institute Maven will take care
of all these things on your behalf
where we add all these things.
We have one file called
bombarding.
Similarly,
whatever tools we need when we identify
these are
the tools we need,
we will keep all of them inside.
Similar point in terms of dependency.
That's what we did.
Now after this, the another point
which we have seen, which we discussed
last time was because we are writing
the framework, we need two separations.
The first one based on technical stuff
that's current,
based on non-technical stuff before that
I told you we will not use main,
we will use only test.
The reason behind this is
we write the code related
to the development of application
in the main and related
to the testing of application in test.
So that's why we will use only test, not
correct inside test.
Also, we have to separations.
The first one is technical,
then we will write all the Java stuff
and the second one is non-technical
that we will read all non java stuff.
So we created resources
for non-technical stuff,
for technical stuff we have already Java,
right guys,
these are the things we did
in the last class, correct?
Okay, now now for the concept of order
usability, right.
For the concept of coder usability,
we used one part that was common metrics
and we added just two positions,
just two methods.
The first one was open browser
and the second one was closed browser.
That is,
it means precondition and post condition.
Just two things we added right?
And we were reading all the properties,
all the properties,
right for my project,
which I would need from 100 or properties.
Right.
We have mentioned this things
in our properties file
and we are reading everything in one class
corporate configuration view that right
in this fight
I already explained this concept how
we can load this slide, how we can pause
this data, every single thing
and another thing,
the values which are constants
which are final
throughout our project,
we will pass all those parts
and the values
from another class called Constants.
So far we have created this for two right.
As we will proceed further,
we will identify more school, right?
We will see more scope
of putting more final values here,
and then we will provide those spots
and values in our project
from this constraints class toolbar.
These are the things that we did
in this version so far.
What really do you guys have?
Any question?
Right.
Great. Now,
now let me ask you one question, right?
This is our previous project,
our previous project, right,
where we were learning best
and as a tool, correct
Testing is a tool when we were learning.
So this was my project.
Now tell me one thing, guys,
in how many places, how many places
we have used this locator
driver do not find element by road
user name it,
how many places we have used it?
A lot of places
in this small application,
in this small piece of code.
Only if I count makes minimum ten times
username.
Ten times plus what?
Ten times log in button. Correct.
I mentioned at least ten times right
now. Now here.
Right now. Here.
One challenge, One challenge
and one problem I can see.
Let me show is working
is a developer issue.
These are developer of this application.
It takes each item application
and she is doing some changes
in the application code.
Correct.
So now when she is changing some code
in the application and these four guys
are dedicatedly working right,
so many things working on this for guys
like Mike or Lena and I
are working on writing the automation.
So many places
collectively,
these four guys have written
15 different modules,
write code for 50 different screens
and so many test cases.
Let's test cases.
They guys have written on an average.
They're using this username a 50 times,
right on an every day using this password
and they make the three times
and this long important
also for three times because everything
is must include log in functionality rate
grade.
Understanding my point
what I am trying to explain now
now what shoulder basically is
yes in a correct
so now what she did basically
is she changed
this username to just one thing
she added text username.
She changed the it like this.
I'm just giving you one example
now I got changed
or not
I changed it this time.
You four guys are trying
to execute your script
with your script work.
No, you did this
to get this will fail correct
this because of this
small change because of this minor change
at one place right now, your work.
Your work is much higher, right?
Your work increases. Why?
Because you have to change this activity
places minimal.
This is the problem
we have been very using.
Simply do not.
But now when I come inside the framework,
right inside the framework, right
frameworks is even if you're using this
particular username,
particular password, or particular log
in with an 8 to 1000 places, it
1000 places in your framework
in multiple classes.
Fine.
I will give you a sector in such a way
that if you change this value in
one place, if you change this one place,
it will be changed automatically.
It 1000 places.
I think my point, you just need
to change it one place, right?
You don't need to change it 1000 place
and then it will work everywhere.
How we can do that? Let me show you
what we will do.
It has an app, correct? I know, right?
But at least let me explain
first to all of them.
Right.
So guys, here, here, what we have to do
basically is write
we have to follow one design
pattern, right?
What is this design python?
We call it page object model people.
And well, this is not feeling bummed out.
Symbol is different from right.
I'm talking about B or embedded
object model design Python.
What does it mean?
What page object model Design vacancies.
Well page object model design
can see specifically
if you have a log in page
in your application
dashboard page application
logout page in your application settings
page in our application,
create separate classes for every page.
What you need to do Create
separate classes for every single page,
and keep all the locaters
belong
to that particular page inside that class.
It means board.
Now it becomes very easy
for you to understand, right?
It becomes too easy for you to understand
and identify
that if my script is failing on page
full page, right.
And if there is a locator issue there,
so where you should find it,
you have 1000 classes.
What do you find in 1000 classes? No.
This time, within a fraction of a moment
you will identify.
All right.
Which one is
did this one go to dashboard page?
You will find the error.
Correct.
Isn't it really easy to simplify?
Isn't it very easy to identify
and fix the error rate?
That's why we call this this time
saving part.
Now. Now we are going to create
the concept of page
object model design in a framework.
Let me go ahead and start it
now. Tell me when I see every single page.
Right.
Every single page
will be having its own class.
So this is Java stuff
or this is non Java stuff.
This is Java part, right?
So let me create another package
inside Java
because like I said,
we need organized structure, right?
So this is our organized structure
in Java.
I'm going to create page
53 page classes or simple.
I can create one predicate calling
pages
the easiest one, right?
I'm not giving very fancy names
and very attractive name.
These are very simple to understand,
very simple to read these type of names
I'm giving, right?
Like I said, your project,
your framework doesn't fix things.
It should be easily
understandable and readable.
So whatever the things we are writing
or whatever the
things we are writing here,
we are mentioning here,
these things are highly easily
readable and easily understandable.
Next time you are writing like this.
So now tell me to find the locator
for the log in page.
I have to create one page here. Right.
So let me create one class based on the
concept of page three page object model.
I'm going to create one class called
log in page
Naming conventions Categories Camel Case.
We are following click logging
right?
If we create this particular
can everyone
see this?
I think
now, now here, here
we are going to use this particular class
to define all the locators here.
We call it object repository,
what we call this concept
object repository by because we keep
all the objects inside one class.
And from this class using this class,
we will use this objects
throughout our project
and extending the floor.
We will keep all the all the locators
at one place and volume
using the object of this particular class.
We will call all of this locators
throughout our project.
That's why
we also call it object repository.
Every single class has all the locators
belong
to that particular screen
inside via object.
You can access all of them.
So to do that, what we have to write it.
For example,
if I'm going to write for my first one,
so enter it, find my class, I have to use
which class entry to find by.
And then this is the syntax.
For example, I need to use it.
So what would be the idea of my user name?
I will keep the right here
and then I will keep my web element.
Right?
My web element is public.
Why public?
Because I want to use them everywhere.
Therefore, I'm keeping it public.
And this is the key.
This is the key.
I'm going to use
instead of using direct locator.
Now, I will tell you how we use it.
Right?
Can somebody tell me what is the idea
of that so that I can copy it from here?
Can I copy it from you?
Let me copy.
I'm simply copying
this idea from my previous project.
Right.
I'm not doing anything else.
Same thing.
Same thing we can do for our password.
So I'm going to write the the key for my
password box. Correct.
This is the key we need to change.
You guys remember?
And then I am copying this
from my previous project,
so let me copy it from my previous
project.
The idea for password and I'm passing it
here.
Similarly, the last thing which I have to
do is which is the next button gave
the next locator for
log in return.
So let me take the only plug in button
from here.
Now, see the advantage of doing this thing
everywhere, everywhere
in all the other classes,
in all the other methods,
in every single point,
you will be using this key.
This key can be used at 1000 places
because this key is linked
with this locator.
So next time,
even if you have used it 1000
places, this username, password
and logging button,
if there is any change happens here
or here or here
now, tell me how many places are very
any framework
where you need to make this changes?
Just this one place, right.
So that's
how you can save your time, right?
You don't have to spend much time
on fixing your existing automation script
or existing automation.
Best cases,
right?
You can simply place it at one point.
You can simply make the things
changes at one place and it will work
for throughout your project, correct? No.
Another thing.
Tell me another thing, because
this is the concept of page 50 rate.
I have to call my constructor.
So to write constructor,
what should I take?
What is the definition of constructor?
Class name of a constructor
is having the same name as class name.
So let me write
the class name right.
But it looks like a method, correct?
So it looks like a method.
Find this constructor and
now these are the elements.
These are the elements.
If I want to use, these are the elements.
If I want to use,
I have to initialize them.
Right?
I have to initialize them. Why?
Because without initializing
these elements I can.
I can't use any right these elements
so I can initialize
all these elements using page 50.
So I'm going to write inside my client.
Tell me that is why I am writing inside
constructor this page 50
When constructor will call
when constructor has been called
to the time of creation of object.
Right?
So the right moment
when I'm creating the object
of this class constructor has been called
in this theme time.
It will initialize all the elements.
All right.
That's why I'm writing here.
Page three
dot Initialize elements.
Now it is asking for web driver
first thing
and second thing is pointer,
which is pointing to my page.
So let me do one thing I'm telling you to
as guys, we have already defined
one web driver where we have
defined the web driver in that framework
in common methods, Right.
If I want to use that web driver here,
what should I do
if I'm writing like this driver or this?
Right?
So this is my current page,
but it is still giving me the error
if right.
I have to extend.
So let me extend what my
common methods.
Now, if you see when I extend my common
method, it my driver
error is gone. Oh,
you can write like this.
Also, I'm giving you another B,
I'm giving you another way
because we are using
the static driver, right?
We can simply call it
because this is not the only place.
This is not the only reason, right?
This this one,
the way I am showing you this one
by because in common methods,
in common methods right now
we have very little amount of things.
We will be having so many more common
methods that.
Right.
And when we are inheriting
the property of common methods
inside this particular page.
So it's not only the web driver,
which we will take from there,
but also many other metrics.
We will use it here.
So now is specifically curated
for common methods.
Driver Would you be able to take
all of those methods in your project,
in your this class? No. Right.
But if you write like this,
when you inherit
all the properties of common methods
inside this particular class,
you would be able to use
not only the driver
but also all the methods
you're defining in your common methods.
So we will need it.
We will need it
in the progressive part of our framework.
We will need that.
Now, another way I'm telling you guys,
another way is you can define another web
driver here, right?
You can define you to separate the driver
or class level here.
Right.
And then you can call this driver
for that.
You need to do this.
And then simply called enter.
This is another way
to define your web driver.
Correct.
But this will be only on class level,
right.
For this particular constructor,
you're using it,
but if you want to use it for
yes. Yes.
Correct. Correct.
This is another
that's what I'm showing you.
This is another way to do it here.
If you're passing like this, then in your
in your actual test case
where you will be using this, there
will be one issue you will be facing.
What would be that issue
and what would be the further extended
coding of two rate I would show you.
So for now,
for now I am writing like this.
The best one, the easiest one.
I hope everyone understood in this point
this code has everyone
understood this code so far?
All right, now tell me one thing.
This log in page is inside
this particular package, correct?
This log in pages
available inside this particular package,
if I want to use this
particular constructor
here or here or in any other package,
can I use can I access this constructor
with this current access modifier?
So what is the best way
if I want to use it, if I want to use it
throughout my project,
which access modifier is the best one?
Correct.
I have to use it in public.
Okay. Why is static?
It is my constructor.
Street prediction.
Anyway,
I'm going to use the object of this.
Right.
The object creation is important,
not only constructor.
I want to use this things also
already is one more important point here.
Remember we are using keys like this.
That's why
we are making this very limited supply.
If you want to increase a more security,
if you want to put
another patch of security here,
what you can do it.
You can make this public
instead of public.
You can make them private,
and then you can create gates in sectors.
Remember
the concept of encapsulation, right?
You create gateways
and and you hide this functionality.
So why are you using gated
sensitive field?
So you can use this then? Right.
But this is work.
Yes, but we are not using that.
We are using simply these keys.
These are the locators.
Because anyway, my implementation is right
here.
Right.
I will use only the keys everywhere.
Okay, so this is the code
I have done right for my log in page.
Correct.
But still is still what I did so far
I have identified all the locators.
I have made my constructor
public.
Yeah, I know.
All right.
So in this code, in understanding
this code, do you guys have any question,
any confusion in this
right.
You want me to write like this?
Let me do that.
No issue, this tool.
How you are getting angry or in its place.
Change it.
Fine.
User name is a single word. Right?
So user name can't be like this.
Ideally, user name should be like this
and you can make the capital beatbox
according to
industry.
Industry standards is a common case.
The right industry
standard is a camel case, but
even if you're writing password,
these are the simple keys, right?
Basically, what we generally follow is
we always write the user name box,
get password box, or in some projects.
What we did basically is
if this is your text, we write,
if this is, for example, this is not
a button video entering the username
so you can write user
name, fixed the password,
fixed the log in button, clickable
like this you provide the key.
So keys are self explanatory.
So every project has
its own set of standards.
Right.
But this is just for your better
understanding and writing.
User name
box password, box and log in button.
Okay, you can write, get user name,
get password
fixed, will get log in potentially cable
or user name fixed with password text will
log in button clickable like this also.
So it's completely up to you.
These are the different standards
according to different
clients and requirements.
All right.
Shall we proceed further now?
Okay.
Now, one more thing here.
I'm thinking Right, one more thing here.
I'm thinking what is there?
I'm going to write one user story.
Right? And what is my user story?
A user should let me write it in my notes.
I'm going to write one user story.
So let's say my
user stories.
It would be number one,
two, three, four, five.
It says
user should be able
to log in via
value
credentials, correct?
User should be able to log in via valid
credentials.
This is my users to look.
I have to automate
this particular user story.
When I look at this particular user story,
I know I knew the username
that should be valid
password that should also be valid
and I need log in button
but I need to click right.
But then if I think from my
but if I think from my framework
perspective, right,
one thing comes in my mind
what that thing comes
in my mind
it is
if I have to send their data
I have to use which
command from selenium.
Same because if I have to click on log
in button
which command dot click.
Right.
But, but I know
one more thing in my application
because if you're working
as an automation tester, then you will
not only automate your log in the screen,
you will automate the application, right?
So there there
you have to use this click button.
You have to use this button 1000
times minimum in your application, right?
So why can't we create one method
for sending the data, one method
for clicking the operation,
one method,
or wait for this particular element
and this method
we will use everywhere in that project.
I think
we will simply do one thing.
We will pass this key
I need to this spring.
I need to pass this element point.
This element to the string
method will work.
I want to click on button which will
to log in with the log in button.
This time submit button pass.
And we put on this time
dashboard button Pause Dashboard button.
This method will work.
We will make such an arrangement
where before clicking on every element,
your method will be builder time
your element becomes with
every time we will make such arrangement.
All right.
Getting up on days.
These are the things we can do
so now without wasting further time.
Let's start this implementation.
All right, So tell me, guys,
because these are the methods
which I will be using
throughout my project, Right?
So which is the best place
to put all of this things together
in a common method is correct.
Let me go ahead and try it in common
methods. Now,
since I want to use this
method everywhere, everywhere.
Right when I everywhere,
it was in all the different packages
throughout my project.
So what is the best access?
Modify it.
Actually, it starts with See, you guys are
more intelligent than the public,
right?
I don't want to create any object right.
Of these metrics.
Right?
I don't want to create any object.
So make it static directly.
We can use. Right.
Since this is my my method. Right.
Just for sending the data,
I'm not expecting anything in return.
I will make it void and then I will write.
This method name would be my standard
things, right?
My method name would be same next.
Now I see two things.
Two things here I need.
What are these two things?
The first one is element, right?
And the second one is data on
which element I want to send, which data.
These are the two things I need.
So I'll make it dynamic.
I will write web element
and I'm placing simple
element right come on stream.
So let's see, next to
this is my stream, correct
index case
right now.
Let me show you something here
in my application,
if I go, when you try to add employee,
it, it will throw you
out of the application.
Now, if you see
if I try to add any employee.
Right, right.
No, by default
it is giving me this data right by default
is giving me some data in my text.
If I want
to add some data, I want to provide
new employee ID for example, 1 to 3
and I want to add it.
Then what would happen?
It will add my data
after this existing data.
Briefly the data.
So first I have to clear this data,
getting my point
from every from every method.
I have to clear this data in when I this
data, then I will be able to add new data.
Right. Let's do it
here because I will do what I will do is
I will write element dot
player.
The very first thing
which I will do element dot clear
and then I will do element dot time keys.
So it will ask point on this element.
What do you want
to pass something extra say
now see
how this method will work,
how this method will work.
Basically
if you call this method anyway,
it will ask for two things element string
whenever you pass any element,
it will first identify that element right
via passing the key player.
And then second thing it will ask.
I want to string data on this element.
Data.
You will pass the string,
it will build the data, right?
So every time we don't need
to write driver to find element
by the textbook, right.
And then doors in the keys
and then double quotes and then data,
not just plus element esthetic.
Isn't it simple this is right.
Now. Similarly, I'm
going to add another method
public static void.
I'm saying
click method.
Correct.
Another method
which I'm going to write is click method
Springs.
So to click on the element,
how many arguments I need to pass yet?
How many parameters I should pass.
Just one.
And what is that element?
Web element?
It's simple element once again
and I will write here
element dot click method next time,
just call this particular method
and then it will pass the element.
It will perform.
Click now.
Now in our application,
in our application,
I can see one issue.
What is that issue
for login page?
It is fine.
Let me open
for login page.
It is fine, but when I'm
clicking on this particular employee
it is taking some time right
to load the application
and come on to this particular page.
Or let me do one more thing.
So here.
Yes, yes.
We have to add,
we have to wait for the time.
That is fine,
but I'm trying to show you something.
If I'm writing here like this,
if I try to open you see,
it is taking time, right?
It is taking time to load the data.
Even if my element is available here.
Right.
I should wait.
I should wait. I'm
just giving you one scenario.
It could happen to all the all
the elements, right in the application.
You never know.
So I don't want to face that situation
while executing my code.
So what I need basically is
I need to have one condition in my script
before even clicking on any element.
What you should do is
you should first check
whether my element is clickable or not,
even if element is there,
but it is not loaded properly.
Wait till the time it becomes clickable.
And then how much time we should wait?
We will tell that this much of time
you should wait for correct.
That's what we need to do.
So again, again, that kind of trick
that we will going to put here.
Right.
So I'm going to write another method
here to see what is that method.
I'm going to write public
static and I'm writing
a very private.
So this is my web table,
which I'm going to use the what would be
my method me get wait,
this method will return my weight?
Yes. Correct. Correct.
So when I would wait to get the wake
method, I'm going to get the weight
from this particular method.
Now we'll see what I'm writing here.
I'm going to write
wave driver
weight, new
baby driver weight
driver.
We have already passed.
Now it is asking for how much time.
So it is asking for how much time.
So is it a good idea to pass directly
10 seconds or 20 seconds
or 30 seconds here
hardcoded the entertainer 20?
No. Hardcoded, Correct.
So from there we can pass this integer
values and 2030 something like that.
From here we can pass this. Then this can
on things.
Correct.
So let me go to my constants,
which is my points
to let me go to my constraints.
And here I will write here like this
this time, not my implicitly,
but this is the way I'm going to write
is my
explicit weight.
And I'm putting, let's see, 22nd maximum
20 seconds.
You have to wait. Okay.
So this time explicit, which I'm
going to use for my constants class.
So here I can vertically write constant
start explicitly
fine.
Is this correct?
Because I'm having one return type
of this method.
I'm expecting something in return.
So what I'm expecting I'm expecting it
because I'm saying this method return.
Wait, think not Aunt Kate.
It should be only one.
You can now
see how I'm going to use this weight,
which I'm getting from this gateway
method, how I'm going to use.
I'm going to write
another method that is public static
void.
I'm saying wait for
flexibility
for one particular element.
I'm saying from this
method that you have to wait.
So which element,
whatever the elements I'm passing
so I can pass this element like this.
Yes. Yes.
Correct. Correct.
No, you don't need to remember
the method name.
I will give you a very small solution
for that.
So now I will simply pass one element
and I will say, Hey,
this method will wait till the time.
Till the time.
Like I said, so expected condition,
right?
I will write gateway to method. Fine.
Now this method is returning me.
Always tell me
get work
method is returning me
wait for explicit wait for 20 seconds.
Right.
So I will wait here
for 20 seconds Dark build condition.
So until which condition?
I'm saying until
expected conditions.
What is the expected conditions?
Till the time?
My element is
expected.
Conditions element will be clickable.
It says which element.
I'm saying my element
whatever the element time plus.
Now see here
in my click able method, in my click
method I will wait for click ability
for this particular element.
Now you just write this method at once
and then you call this method in click
option.
That's it, That's it.
You call this method inside, click option.
This method will work in the time
your element becomes clickable
and then it will perform.
Click option
Guys.
These two methods, clear or not,
just two lines of code.
I've written any, but it's a clear or not
everyone
students
did. Now.
Now when I'm having this method
that is fine right inside of my students.
This is my log in page bit.
I'm having this part Also,
there is also point
in configured properties everything.
I cannot still execute my first guest.
Can I have this up here in this project
right now?
Do I have this setup through
which I can execute my guest?
Do I have the exit
if I want to execute?
Like I said, right, this is my
this is my user story.
User should be able to log
in my credentials.
Do I have this method from where
I can perform my log in option?
Still, my best guess is missing.
No, I'm not talking about
username and password.
Where is that method From where I am
passing the username,
I'm passing the password
and clicking on the log in button.
Yes. My best guess is missing.
Which framework we are working
upon is tell me which framework is this
stingy framework.
Right.
So we have to use the direct test
annotation as a test case.
So there we have to create another package
in Java.
That package need is your
test case,
is all of the test cases
you will write here.
Since we are following
we are following page
object model for logging operation
which test because we have to use case.
Tell me I have to use it as logging test.
All write this class right.
This class I will use as my nug test.
Correct or not.
And now
whatever the things of Google now tell me,
does it make sense
if I extend common methods here
and extends common methods
in every single class because I have my
50% of my opinion inside common methods?
Correct.
So I want to use that method.
I have to use actually in my framework
to utilize those things every bit.
So to get those things here again,
I will use my expense,
common methods.
Right.
And now.
And now I will write my false test.
If I'm going to write that test
public void, I will see
and I will log in
right now. See?
Now, see?
How easy would it be
to write the test cases.
Now you will see how easy
it is. Where where is my look?
There are my locators
for username and password, which place
I have my username and password locators
in login page.
How can I take those log in pages?
Locators which are available there?
The objects
I have there? How I take those things
I have to call my constructor.
Is that the member? Yes. Correct.
We have to create the object
of this class.
So I'm going to write log in Page Log
in is equal to nil log in speech right?
Correct.
That it is.
Now see here.
First I have to enter a username. Right.
So see, I am calling this
method simply it's a same text file.
It is asking
how can I call web element
logging dot username box.
This is my web element comma.
It is asking for the string. Right?
So which is my string from my
config reader gate property value.
What is the property?
When I say the username?
Right. Let's see.
This is my web element.
I'm calling it by a key.
This is my value
and passing it on to the reader.
Right.
This is my method which I'm using.
Correct
it Similarly,
I can write the same method, same text
this time log in dart password box, comma,
configurator, dot good property value.
What is the password?
So this is my keeper password.
I think what I have to do
is think what I have to do.
I have to click on log in button.
Very simple click
rate going to log in page dark.
It says log in button.
Isn't it easy
to write the code in this video?
Tell me now.
Now, just think of a situation
when you go in the industry.
You got a job of hundred thousand dollars,
$125,000, Right.
And you joined a company?
Yes, exactly. Exactly.
So if you join the organization
and they say, hey, we're already working
framework creating a framework with us,
you just need to understand the framework
and you have to write your commission
scripts.
There.
Isn't it very easy for you
once you understand what how things work?
Actually
getting
through
This is what you need to understand.
That's why people that needs the most
who know
how to create a framework from scratch,
because this is the most difficult part.
They are making everyone's life easy.
That's why architects are yet
then it will do.
That also will do.
We do that?
All right.
A step by step.
Like I'm saying, hold your horses.
You're going too fast.
Get getting
right now.
Let's try to execute.
Let's try to do this.
Why right now?
What is the reason?
Figure into username password.
Okay.
Can you guys tell me?
See, it is working fine here it to click
also you guys might have missed rate.
Yes you guys might have missed
the value that you are taking from here
and there.
And you're calling the methods.
You're calling the locators.
Since so many things,
so many things to be logged together fake.
So there are high chances,
cannot find the part, correct?
Correct.
Why is it so?
See, this one is positive, right?
If it's called working,
come to complete key point.
Now you guys can do one thing right?
What I am going to do is let me post
on this call
is going be it October.
Yeah, I'm going there.
So guys, everything is available now.
Let me open my common method.
See, this is my common method.
Everything is available in the repository,
Correct?
Stickney I opened this here as well.
You guys can take the updated code
from the repository
I paste best in building, right?
And that you can use that link
and you can get double digit code
from there
already.
So everyone got that?
Okay, fine.
Coconspirators.
So shall we proceed further now
that even
I didn't get anything?
Andre, these are basically
we are not using log forger.
That's why it is giving you this warning.
This is not the error.
Basically, this is just a warning.
So let it be.
And as long as you are able to execute
your code, that is fine, right?
So it is just a warning, not an edit.
And it's it doesn't affect your execution.
The main part is that
if you observe even
I am having this part as a warning.
All right.
Okay. So, guys, we need break a lot.
We can proceed further.
Okay, great.
All right.
I hope you guys are understanding
the things now, right?
Things are making sense
to everyone or not.
If there is any point
which you guys didn't understand,
please, please let me know.
I will repeat that point.
I will go through the topic once again.
I don't have any problem.
Please ask
the logging artist this one
fitting.
All right.
So basically, basically what we did,
this is the final product
of all the efforts
we put so far in the framework, right?
This is great at strategy.
We try this is the same text method
we kept inside our common methods.
We return everything correct.
This is the key associated
domain locator
which I have written in my log in page.
Correct.
This is the key of my value,
which I have paused from my country.
Retreat or property site. Correct.
These are the things.
I have three things in different places.
Similarly,
I have created a framework in such a way
this structure in such a way
that even if I have 1000 classes,
1000 properties, 1000 methods,
I will simply call the similar method,
similar property for similar classes,
and I can have multiple functionalities
together.
Just I'm just a click of A
to implement this structure.
Now I'm not writing driver
dot find element by dot dot saying begins
and then passing the data.
No, just call this method in the locator
where you put it right saved it
and then call the data whatever the data
you have in whatever the fight.
Right.
And it will work for you, correct?
Correct. Exactly.
This is the framework for you.
So far, so good guys.
Already black. Nice poetry.
Fine.
So now
now the next thing is still here.
Validation.
But it is missing, correct
is getting
my point is still
the validation point is missing.
And without validation
if you are writing the automations script,
it is of no use
because there is no validation.
Correct. How would you verify?
How would you validate that whatever
the automation script you have written
and if you're testing some application,
it is parsed or you don't know, right?
So you have to put one validation
point here.
I'm leaving it on you if you want, right?
We will put that point also.
But I'm giving you one clue.
Yes, yes, correctly.
So let's do it quickly. Let's do it
quickly.
No issues.
Do it quickly on this page.
I am right now. Right.
This is the page
so I can verify any of the thing.
We already have
this verification point as well with us.
But but let me show you one thing
to put verification point here.
I have to create another page.
I have to create another page case.
Tell me.
Okay.
I have to create another page.
Right.
Because.
No, because the verification point is yes.
The verification point
is on different page
and every single page has its own class.
So when my verification point
is on dashboard page,
I have to create Facebook page point
I will create.
I am writing this
board
page simply
by default.
I will do one thing. Excuse me
common metrics, because the same method
I will use here as well in my dashboard.
So fine now.
As of now, as of now, I'm going to add
just one look at that, right?
So I will copy this
index from my log in page.
Right.
And I will go in my dashboard page here.
I have to use what
welcome message.
Fine.
So to do this welcome message, I can see
when you click there, it saves the ideas.
Welcome. Fine.
So I will take this idea as
well. Come
then.
The second thing is, guys, what
I have to do again for dashboard page.
If I want to use again,
I have to initialize
the elements of this page and to do that
I have to make my constructor as public
and then construct a name, Find.
Then I have to write my page 50
elements and then driver comma.
This I
is this code correct?
Don't always tell me.
Now again,
let me go back to my logging test.
And here, here
I'm going to write in my logging test.
I'm going to put
a simple assertion point that
first I have to create the object, right?
So I'm going to write Facebook
page is equals to new Facebook page.
Fine.
And then
a third start
assert true. Right.
I'm just putting one simple check whether
my welcome message is available or not.
This is the only thing I'm going to check.
So I am writing here
right on my baseboard page dot
welcome message right
door is displayed or not.
If it returns true,
it is just a project unsupported straight.
It will be correct.
Is it correct now?
Now my solution point
because available validation point
is available on this particular piece.
So I'm going to write it is.
Okay, fine.
No, I need to execute this once again
or be proceed
further.
Students So
this is your dashboard page
then?
Everyone.
I just added this
a welcome message located here.
The way I read the user name
password added here also,
and then I initialized my constructor.
I called my constructor
by activating the object of this page.
So defined by constructor here.
Correct. Two things I did.
I didn't add any other things so far.
Everyone with me
on code.
This is initialize elements we are going
to initialize all the elements
we are putting inside this page,
all the elements which we are mentioning.
Great, great. Mike.
We will work in the same organization
together.
Our class Cross.
So all right, so
here if you see this initialize elements
is the concept of page three, right
correct?
Correct. Note Correct.
In this initialize element,
we are going to use all of these elements
in any other page to get projects.
Or to do that you have to initialize
your elementary correct.
I hope you got that. Now
you're most welcome.
Let's execute it once again.
Guys like Insert are asking for execution.
Let me execute it again.
Guys.
My voice, my video, everything is clear.
I'm not great.
Why is it so black?
Which speed?
Internet speed are my explanations Ignore
explanation.
All right, so now looking fine. Correct.
My assertion is also passed
control test run process one
point
exam.
You were there in this class or not.
All you need to check whether you're
calling this assert with capital error
small E
on Sunday because on Sunday also
I was doing the same thing.
Then why it is not saying
because it should come
right from the auditor testing D
so it shouldn't be available here.
You can write like this post import
or do the test and you wrote assert.
Just try it that way.
And then if you
write a certain assert group,
all and
then you talk
and I can
you please tell me what is the problem
that you're facing.
Yes, he is. He is correct. Correct.
When I was thinking that
is this one
or jitter test
and you don't assert this one,
then why it is not giving you.
Okay,
you can I don't discriminate
given that we have to call
for today.
Go ahead, Mike. Don't be late.
All right. Okay, guys.
So let's take a break
for 15 minutes, okay?
And then we'll meet up in this case,
when you actually
when you actually work in the company.
When we actually work in the company,
Right.
Even if you're working
as an automation tester.
Right.
As our test automation,
you always have to go
first manually
to explore the application it.
And if there is no one
to perform the things manually,
then what do you have to do?
You have to write your test cases
and scenarios and stories
sometimes, right?
As manual tester as well.
These things also you have to do
correct?
So now I'm writing these
just to read the way you generally write
or we generally write in the industry
when we work on body departments manual
as well as automation.
Correct.
Take me go ahead and write that.
So I'm going to write admin user
should be able to add and
employ
to the IT chart.
And this
post user story it first
and then second users exec
and we will see it.
Right now
I'm just talking about the first one.
Now we all know, right?
This is the functionality
of our application
that only admin add users.
I remember
we have seen this functionality earlier.
If we try to log in from a normal user,
we will not be able to add any employee.
So to add any employee,
what we have to do is we have to go
in the application and then we have to
log in as an admin user only.
Correct.
That's my users to this is a meaning user
should be able to add
an employee to the h.r.
Application
that is
fine.
Now if i go in my application.
Right.
Some people gave me the feedback, right?
So when they were trying to execute
something, the click was not working
right.
They tried click somewhere,
but the click was not working.
It means what normal method of click
was not working.
I understand.
Even I know in this application
sometimes when you go
and you try to click on this same option,
when you click, try to click employee list
or an employee options,
some time click option, not work, right?
It's not working the normal click method
and this it happens in your application.
Also in selenium.
What happens
if it's this element not applicable?
What element is not able
to click on this point?
But actually when you try to do it
manually, it is clickable what you do.
In that case, what is the alternative
to click action, click another way?
Yes. Correct.
Correct.
We have JavaScript executed.
Right Actions class.
You always have to call.
What we will do basically
is in these cases, in these cases,
when we come across the situation in a
like is in my application on this
this this is normal click
method is not working.
In that case, I need use JavaScript
execution method the way I'm using
click matic.
So how I'm using click
method, I have defined this method.
I have written this method in my common
methods.
Right?
Similarly, I will another method for
JavaScript executed in my common method.
Let's go ahead and do it.
I will open my common method right.
It is my common method because
here you go.
So this is my common method
right now.
Here I will write
public
static, right?
I'm going to say that I'm going to get
JavaScript
executed first
from one method and then the same thing
I will use in another method.
So I'm writing
JavaScript executor is equals to
I am writing here, JavaScript executing
guys.
Quick question why I'm not using new
keyword here
in JavaScript executor.
Why am not using new keyword?
Yes, JavaScript executed is an interface
and we can create the object
of the interface right?
When we use this new keyword,
it means we are trying
to create the object of the class.
When there is no class, we are using
JavaScript executed as an interface.
Then there is no need of using
new keyword.
Correct, and then this method
will return my JavaScript execute client.
So it says Why?
Because it is expecting some return
type my routine type would be
yeah, let's execute a final now.
This method will return
JS to correct func.
Now I'm going to write method
for clicking my JavaScript executable,
so I'm going to write as public
static void
J is click.
All right, point on which.
Anyway, so I'm going to write and
web element
right on this particular element,
how great JavaScript
fine good JavaScript
executed dart execute script
and we guys what is the syntax argument.
So what should I put inside this
argument? So
zero dart
comma
element ready? Plus
is this the correct method
which generally used to write JavaScript
execute it or not?
Correct.
So we have written this method here
to write JavaScript execute portion
right now.
Now we are going to write
for adding employee is kidding.
Don't you need a semicolon after
fucking work
here like this?
That's what you see
like this.
Okay, final.
All right, so now,
now we have these two methods here.
Correct?
But we're using these two methods
because we have to be
have to use these methods
throughout our project.
Right.
Throughout our framework.
That's why we are defining them
in our common methods.
Three Now, what is our target?
The target is to add the employee.
Now let me ask
on this page, on this page
how many elements
I need from this page
in order to add the employee?
How many elements I need from this page?
Two elements
which are which two elements we need
in an employee.
Correct
this and this. An employee.
Right.
So in my disclaimer,
if you see an on which page
I have to define
these two elements, log in or they
obviously they should be.
So let me go ahead and then I'm going
to write it on my Facebook page.
I will write these two.
So this wish to
the first one would be my
B option
and the second one would be mine.
And so
employee better.
All right.
And then on which page you are right
now, common method.
This is a common method, right?
These two lines, Just two lines.
The encrypted book API.
First,
can someone please send me other locators?
All right.
Zeynep already send me
this Locators think is in it.
Please let us know.
And when you're done.
So now
I'm just going to take this.
Locators
from here.
And this idea
because these you can read right
according to your choice.
I am writing these according to my choice.
Okay.
Baidu object model.
You mean Hilal or bomb Vertex
You which one you're talking about
here?
Design pattern
is according to the project, right?
If you do not have baseboard page,
you directly have all the log in page,
then your next class would be homepage.
Correct.
This one is according
to our projects functionality,
because in our project after log in page,
we can see Facebook page.
That's why we are writing all these things
in dashboard page.
Okay.
All right.
So now, now on this page,
on this particular page,
I have this thing.
Great.
I have written all these things,
but still, still
after clicking on them and an employee.
Right.
Come on.
Concerning the things
it is sending me on an employee page. See?
So even if I just enter
name middle name, right?
Last name and I click on
same option rate
still it will save my look at that.
I am able to solve the aid of my employee.
I'm able to do that. For
example, if I'm writing test
or test 2021 middle name
two zero 2002 023 right.
I didn't do anything else right.
I'm just going to click on save option.
It will save my employee
initiate.
It generates.
A data
You see your first name with the name.
Last name also
guys, can you see it?
Right.
So first first,
what we will do basically is
we will identify all the locators from an
whatever the locators we need.
So we will identify this locator first
and then bingo and proceed for the right.
And then you another method, how we can
add the employee in a different world
so that also you don't play.
All right, so first, let's do this.
Let's do this first post
name, middle name and last name.
Right?
These are the things that we need
basically to execute our test guest post,
right?
Just two three things made both middle
and last name point.
So let's go ahead and
write this data
so from where we can start
because these are the main attributes.
So let's really look at this list.
I'm going to really look at the name.
It is giving me ideas posted. Fine.
So guys, do
I need to create another page or not yet?
This one is not technically dashboard.
This is an employee page. You see here.
It says an employee.
This is not Facebook page.
So we need another page. Great.
So let me create another page.
This page would be mine and
employee
page.
Right?
And simply
common method to be able
to put this on this particular page
and then
integrate find by
it is equal to this.
And then you would define your public
element as this one, your first
one very basic this would be you
Come on, bring it.
How many things?
First name with the name,
last name and state button.
As of now, just four things.
So I'm going to write it as a name.
And this would be my
last name.
It would be my Save
connect or short form
saved.
What an easy
in somebody.
Give me this.
I think it would be like this.
Lastly, guys, please check the locators
whether they are correct or not.
This ticket,
these or locators are correct or not.
And then it says last name, first name
user name explains it with the name
looking forward
within as a point right now.
The next thing again, public
and employee page,
then page 53 dot
you guys can copy also, right.
I'm typing so that everyone who is typing
right can get the idea.
Yes. So we have this.
We didn't even want to write it.
You'll see. Correct.
So now whatever the locators I need,
I have those locators also, whatever the
constructors I need,
I have those constructors.
Also everything I have, this is their time
to design their test case.
The test case to add employee. Right.
So I'm just going to right
click on test case.
Tell me guys
if I'm going to create this test.
Is right.
Sure, sure. Why not?
Now I'm just asking one question.
If I'm going to define new test case,
if I'm going to write new test case,
which test case name should I give here?
This obviously,
this should not be your logic straight.
This would be
an employee test, correct?
Right.
Because we are going to add employee.
But please let me know when you're done
this all
already.
There's respect for other than this
new Java class
and employee test that I
post are rituals, common methods.
All right.
And then and then I'm going to write it is
and then it test
our public void
and employee.
Now I see
I have my log in method.
Right?
But where is this?
This is available here in my logging test.
Can you see this is the log in method
I have available here.
I don't want to write this log in method
all the time.
Failed because to add the employee.
Also I have to use this log
in method faith everywhere.
I don't want to use this
three lines every bit.
So yes, what I can do
is basically I can go in my login page
right after defining my constructor.
I will write your public like
I will say, log in here.
Simple, right?
And then I'm going to write this part.
Which part
my same text
on this page.
User name, box, comma,
I'm going to pass my say username,
fate or simple.
Or let me do one thing.
Let me do one thing.
I'm because I'm going to read this
property directly.
So I would write the string here
username
because I have already their data, right?
So I can use this data.
Here is string password.
So now instead of passing this by it here,
when I will parse this data,
I will write a username here
and a string password.
And after this simply click on
logging button here.
Now see,
if I want to use this log in functionality
right, I will go in my employee test
the very first object
which I will create, the very first object
which I will create.
So I will create this object for my
log in function.
So I will write
log in page
log in is equal to
new log in page
space.
Let me know
once you're done with this part
any please, please speed up.
So many things are going on.
Right?
This is log in page.
This is log in only 300.
I opened already. This is the log in page.
You want log test or log in page.
All right.
Shall we proceed further?
Now, this.
Okay, so now, here, here in my ADD
employee, try to add the employee.
What we have to do was be able to log in.
Right?
So to perform this log in, create
a complete page
object.
Me, I instead of writing this three steps
again, I will simply call that method.
So log in be taught which method is this?
Log in username and password.
This is the method
I've defined in my logging page.
Simply I will call, but here it is
asking to pass is string username.
So now tell me guys
if I want to pass that username
from there I can pass the username
from my
guest.
Come on,
get property value.
Right. And this would my username.
And then the second thing,
what they're looking for is
the correct or get property one.
The second one would be mine
password.
So in just one line.
In just one line, your log in is complete.
Which one? The username and password.
This one wouldn't pass that right
because we are simply creating the state
and the rules states where you're defining
the test, you pass everything
this way.
You're passing just two parameters.
They're quite exempt.
If you directly pass their data there,
then every time, whenever you call your to
change this in your log in method,
but this time you're simply
calling methods with two parameters.
Now this two parameter
could be any parameter, right?
So the final output getting from the log
in method in terms of know
it is not in constants.
How can it be in constancy law?
Yeah.
And we will be having
we will be having long lines
that there will be more
and more parameters. I will show you that
not admin password is not constants.
Right.
You can change at any point of time
if you work in the industry
every after every two months
or after every one month
to change your password
every time you have to change that.
So how can it be constants
for security reasons, you have to do it
if you keep your password
same all the times.
I mean in constant.
No, this is not constrained by it.
This is in configuration or properties.
All right.
So now after log in completion, right,
you will be on dashboard.
So on dashboard page,
you have to click on which were ten guys.
Tell me
on Dashboard page
the first word I needed to click on
Grace. Yes.
So you have to right click on
Dashboard page start
option your on this particular button.
And then after this you're clicking on
another button that is ADD employee button
and then you are on beer
and employee page.
So on an employee page,
what you are doing again,
just create object for this page,
an employee page
and employee is equal to new.
So here if you're writing rate,
you have to stand there data.
So first thing text
where you're passing
on first name, right?
It says
so what they pay you a question.
Do you have this data
in your configuration properties?
Find dates, guys, do you have this data?
First name we didn't name last name.
It's customary.
Now. Now let's say I'm passing this data
right now.
First 90905 as a first name.
Then I'm passing same text.
Add employee page dark middle name
pants 9090 Text.
This is my maiden name
and then an employee page dark
last name I am plus thing is it
could be anything.
Let's see test 9090
or its name middle name, last name
and then simply
I am clicking on. See,
this is the entire flow of my best
guess or not.
Paste.
Tell me, is this correct or not?
First I am log in, then I'm clicking on
promotion and an employee button.
Then I'm entering
first name, maiden name, last name.
I'm clicking on stupid.
Is it correct?
Has everyone done this?
Is everyone ended with this scenario
or not?
Guys, please don't use this data.
Use any other data, please. Yes.
Yes. I'm.
I'm still not executing anything.
Don't we all we should
we should get basically make
the if you guys are using
if you're not post your last bulb either
I will use this open
mind version of names.
Great great.
You guys are so intelligent
you are telling them like indirectly
that use description six.
Everyone will use this to predict. Now
they guys did the same thing to me
last time.
When I say don't use my data
and everyone used my data.
All right,
so can we go ahead and execute it?
This is a
we weren't done with writing the code
or you still need time for the any.
Yes, yes, yes.
You again.
Great.
Can we change the. And now?
Now I will execute
love.
I know
someone must have got hit by the last one.
We change the data
last time.
I trust everyone
Email correct.
And somewhere on my machine.
I mean,
it's working more than me.
That's why
you can see the performance lag.
Then I can't send that case
or put spoke.
Working here on my machine is working.
Okay.
Maybe because of username.
Maybe because of course. Name
and last name.
Yes he is. Server crashed.
Might be not sure
what happened to the application,
but see it's working an employee, right?
Yes, it's work.
It works here.
If you see an test and an employee works
here, I think.
Now, let me tell you one thing, guys.
Again, no verification right
now, no validation.
So I just want to tell you what
verification you need to put in this case.
When you try to add employee, right.
Just click here
and you add some latency. ABC,
X, Y and Z stable,
right? For
okay, detect type
when you look at something different
than. Huh?
Yes, that's what I'm thinking.
So let's say I'm taking a unique is ready
for this part this is the user I.D.
I'm picking it up
doing something like this
people to the media when I click
it says state it creates a new employee.
Or do you have to do
is just copy this employee from here.
They copy this employee.
This is the another way of verification.
I'm telling you how you can do that
when you come on
this screen,
copy this employee I.D., click
employee list from here,
click on employee list from here.
And when you click on employee list, this
type, this employee already here, fine,
but exemplary for any employee.
So let's add,
this is the one you copied from there.
And then simply search for this and
you will get the data for that particular
employee
available here in this part. Right.
And that's how you can verify.
I will tell you
how to verify that part as well.
But Right now, I'm telling you like this,
if there is any data available,
right, you can simply search from here.
So this is the another verification part,
right?
The last one I implemented this one.
I'm leaving it to you guys.
You have to do it right.
I will tell you how to do that.
But as of now,
I'm saying you have to do it
now. Now, the most important point,
the most important point.
Still
no one asks this question.
Also, what I am pretty much you know,
I was shocked when you didn't ask
this question when it comes to assertion
part, right. See,
this is the part of our honor
that is a story.
So let me write first that user story,
and then I will tell you
what was the one I was talking about.
What is an X?
This is my another user story
number is like three,
four, three, four, two, one.
So in this is a story,
what I'm going to write is here,
I'm going to write
system
should display
error messages
when invalid
log in is performed right now
if you'll see
when I say invalid log in this performed
how many combinations we can have here.
It did
is something we need to understand
how many combinations we can have here.
Okay.
Let me show you.
The first one is your entire
username,
right?
Not many, actually.
I'm telling you lost your username,
right? And you.
And there's some invalid password point
and you're
trying to click on log in option.
It gives you invalid credentials.
Right.
The second one is you'll see
invalid username but valid password.
Great. So I'm going to write this
this one.
Then again it says
Sorry,
if again, invalid credentials,
two combinations.
Right?
One valid username, invalid password
embedded is an embedded password.
Hard one
valid username but no password.
It's this password can not be empty.
And then the last one is last one is
blank.
Using me by
valid password.
It says username cannot be
going to see those four combinations here.
Only got the fourth one.
Also correct.
Yeah. Great race two.
So let's go ahead and write.
This is a story here.
The first one is the first point is when
user interface
with valid username and
invalid password,
valid username invalid password,
then display
invalid
credentials.
Correct the first one or
you can write like this valid invalid
username and
or valid invalid password ID.
Then it should display
the invalid credentials.
Right.
This is the two combinations
we are covering here.
Now. The second one is
when the user needs
password Field MP.
Then display
password
cannot be empty.
Similarly, the third combination is
when user needs
user name ID and the then display
username
in order to be empty.
Correct.
Then again
it will say username cannot be empty.
Like in that case.
Also it will say username cannot be empty
because first
it will verify the user.
All right, this is correct.
Let's go ahead.
Now tell me if I want to implement
user story as an automation test engineer,
which is the best place to define
correct on log in page.
So let's go ahead and do it.
So here because
because I have a combination, right,
with every username and password.
Remember, guys, listen what
I'm saying carefully with every username
and password, I have different of Spanish.
I have four combinations,
I have four errors which I need to verify.
What is the best way to do this?
What what setup you think or
what do you think we can do that you
can do it, guys.
Our data provider
can be duplicated
by a data provider.
Can anyone think of readability?
Let me show you how we can do that. Right.
And the answer to your question
you were asking, right,
Why you are not defining the data provider
in advance.
Do we have eight?
So now let's do it first.
Let's create data for that.
So I am seeing my data provider
right, and I am writing
which parent class
makes quality for data provider,
which very classical
experience
object class.
Correct.
So I'm going to call it sorry,
why it is void.
It should be public
object, right?
I'm saying invalid
data.
Correct.
So here I'm going to define my object
as data
is equals to.
Again, inside
this I'm going to pass my data.
Correct.
So my first value, right.
My first value would be my username.
So let's say I'm going to write my first
name is James, which is my valid username.
All right.
And then I am writing
invalid password.
So my invalid password is this.
I will tell you.
Right,
I will tell you how I would testing this.
So when I say our values are valid
password, what is the error case?
Tell me, is this the character which I get
when I say username password?
I know.
Is it there?
Then if this is for just one combination.
Wait,
just hold your horses again and again.
I'm saying
we have to add four combinations
and after that
we can have return type, right?
We are just done with one only.
Fine.
Now guys, again,
the second thing is invalid username.
So this is mine. This is my
invalid username and
password.
So what would be the password
in this case?
Let's see, this is the valid password.
Now when I say invalid username
and password in that is very invalid.
Is there an embedded
password in this case?
Also it says invalid credentials.
Correct.
This is a second combination.
Then I'm saying the third one,
which is I am keeping only username,
but leaving the password field empty.
So it should say
password
cannot be empty.
Correct.
And then leaving the username
empty and passing
the password is
so it should see the username
in order to be
and be.
Is this correct?
And then I'm going to return this data
from here.
Guys.
So far in this data provider, any
confusion we can leave both empty as well.
Wait. Yeah.
In that case
also it will give you username
cannot be empty because the first one
it will fight like this.
Right?
So these are the four possible
combinations.
We have some more data later plus
three So far, so far in this distribution
and in this definition of data provided,
do you guys have any question?
Remember, comma separated means
this will be the first,
right?
This will be the second set,
this will be the third.
This will be the fourth set.
Correct.
In the it is returning the all this data
correct.
Andre, Anna and everyone.
Olena, Jamal,
Sherif,
we are all the guys.
Why and why you are not following me.
Oh, okay.
All right.
Point naught is
all right.
Once you guys are done with typing this
to let me know,
then we will proceed further up the that
as long as you guys are done,
please update your status here
so that we can proceed for today's
done.
All right, Anna
Andre, all
you guys done
so today I'm
out the remaining ones.
All right, let them complete
initiative, basically
because you see here every single right,
every single rule
against a specific set of data.
Correct.
Every single rule returns
a specific set of data.
Now, when it is returning this data
along with this.
See it one time.
I'm expecting username,
password, error message.
Right.
So this my one line is giving me username
password
in error message
having a unique combination.
Right.
Similarly for this also I'm getting this
this little time getting this.
But if I defined all of this things
in my considered properties,
then I have to define
two very different keys
and then I have to call 12 different keys
in one method.
So tell me when I say data driven test,
what is what does it mean
data driven test?
My one test children across my one test,
children across multiple sets of data.
Correct.
If I am defining this
in configured properties,
my one test case will not run across
multiple test of data here.
If I define my data provider
for one class,
my one test case will run across this
four sorts of data.
That's why I implemented
this logic. But it
you're Elizabeth correct.
So you're getting the error
been learning running before task
taking sources of it invalid source
release and dependency is is on zero over
11 was used to complete finishing saving.
It is
amazing that it read
with one out of zero and in which you
which is the error.
You need to identify the error rate.
It is pre compilation tasks.
Yes, correct. I will do that.
So now let's let's quickly
write this test here.
Right.
So I'm going to write
another test called a static test.
Now, if I want to utilize this data
later in my test,
what should I idea?
Because then it is always, always ready.
Right, with hybrid data.
Okay, invalid then if you were there
in the previous batch.
Also.
All right,
so now I'm going to write it.
It's public.
My best guess, right?
Invalid log in
error message
validation.
Correct.
All right.
I thought you were there
in my previous batch. Also in base nine.
Then I was dating test and it took over
as long as I remember one.
It was there with the same name.
That's why I'm thinking of that.
All right, so now tell me
when I'm calling this data provider
right from there,
how many how many strings and parameters?
I should expect here in my method,
in my test, actually.
How many days
getting my question
are no for actually just three rate
four are the states should be 468
you see first parameter setting
and the third one right so just three
and all three are my string.
So I'm going to write a string user name
comma is screen
password, comma, string message.
Right.
Whatever the message, I'm
getting these three things.
I'm getting.
See, every single set of data
is returning username and password
and message username.
Password, message. Right.
So it means it is getting three things
at one time.
Three string said one thing,
three parameters at one time.
Right now, again will write for
login page
equals to new login page.
I'm going to write login page.
Don't log in.
Right
that recordings.
I have a method to access
username here
comma password.
Is it correct?
All right, fine.
After this.
After this I have to write
one thing is stream
the actual error
rate the actual error from the machine.
Right.
So I need I actual error from the system.
It means this located. I'm
getting my point.
This locator also I need.
I will perform one method from selenium
through which I can get the text right.
So get fixed method I can use.
So let me do it from here.
In the logging feature I will go
and I will find this particular one.
It says it is equal to send message point.
So let's copy this.
Right.
This this idea I'm taking the one
which is showing the error.
So I'm taking this rate.
Let me go in my log in peach.
So it is my log in before they cool.
Why am I doing this in my log in page?
Why is this error message
is yeah, because it is on my log in page.
Correct.
So I am writing it is my error message.
Please note don't
watered down this path.
Nor should it
because it's not complicated.
Every single thing is on different page.
That's what we are doing right?
You just need to remember if it is for log
in page, it will be in the log in page.
If it is for dashboard page.
Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
I'm trying to clarify you.
I'm trying to make it very easy
for you. Right.
You put this for dashboard page,
it will be on dashboard page.
And then in the end,
when you write the complete test,
you have to collect all things
from all the classes.
You make your best guess
and you executrix simply.
That's what we need to getting my point.
So has everyone added this locator? This
is not
correct.
Okay, now let's go back again here.
So I was taking this locator.
So how can I take this locator?
Not in minutes.
I have to write my login page.
Dart error message dart.
The text method.
What this line will do.
This line, right will give me whatever
the text available on this error
message locator
and it will store in my actual errors
because I'm going to verify the errors.
I will write my assertion.
I will write a certain assert
when I have two things to check.
Right.
I will use a side note assert
to assert equals case telling me which one
I should use
if I have two things to cross check verify
comparison equals right.
So in the equals I am writing,
this is the actual one
which I'm getting,
the actual one I'm getting.
And then this is the message
I'm getting from my data provided.
It means here, correct.
And in case In case if it doesn't work.
If in case if it doesn't,
if these are not equal,
I will write
messages are not matching
or I should write at
message
does not match
error message does not match.
Correct.
There is no sheriff if you see
without framework,
if you have to write the same test
case, you have to write so much of code.
Now, when you have to write that
just because you are writing
within this amount of put,
how many just one line to line.
Just one line, right
to call the log in method
and then the second line to verify
that things in just two lines
you're able to write your complete code,
correct.
Okay.
So now now let me execute this particular
test, guys.
I hope so far you guys are in dispute.
Everything, right?
You guys have understood it all.
You guys have any question for that? So.
Okay, from here,
this is the message, right?
Can you see the third parameter
that we are passing?
We are taking it from data point,
but only state.
See, that third parameter is our message.
We are handling it.
This message from data pointer plus
and this we are actually comparing the
this one we are getting from application
directly
executed.
There is everyone in the tool.
All right.
So now if you see it, open the browser
execution script
and it close the browser first
for first test of data
for first set of this data.
Now for second one.
This time it is doing for the third one.
Similarly,
it will do for the fourth one as well.
So what it is doing,
it is verifying the things right.
It is verifying your error messages,
logging in, performing operations,
entering username and password
and every other thing.
Yes, Correct.
Because we took the locator, right?
We didn't.
We are getting the message.
The message is changing,
but the position is seen right.
So you see here it says
this one.
It executes across James 1 to 3 invalid
credentials, this one admin one
and possibly
this one admin and password MP
this one invalid and password Correct.
Sheriff,
can you see the four execution rate
four iterations of execution everywhere?
Yes. Locator locator is same.
See, the position is same.
Only The data is changing.
That is dynamic.
So you can take the locator
and every time when data is changing,
you can take the data on one thing.
Correct.
All right.
There is so password.
Yeah.
The next next topic is this one only
I was about to start this topic.
No, so far not so hard.
So far, so good.
Don't worry.
I'm not going to start
any new topic. Right.
I'm just giving you the overview
of the topic and we'll tomorrow.
Don't worry about it.
All right.
So now now, if you see here, because
this audience are having issues, right?
If you is there anyone who didn't complete
is there anyone who didn't complete
with the code writing for the incomplete
everything?
Is there anyone who is still left
or right?
You have like left join mind, Zoom
link right up to half an hour.
I'll start with my calls in 15 minutes.
I will start with my call.
Still time your class tomorrow
again.
I wish I could.
Yes, yes, yes. Correct.
If you want me,
I will execute it once again.
Do you want me to execute?
Sure. Don't worry.
I will resolve your queries
right after the session.
So let me execute this code once again.
So this piece of code will be executed
across this.
Right? For this four sets of data.
Now you'll see the four iterations
of execution
here.
All right.
So now if you see here, write
all the four combinations
that we have mentioned in the data way
that class it will execute across
all those four combinations.
The first one already execute it because
some issue with the browser, I'm not sure
a replay
bought you for what you're expecting.
The replay
obviously will do a recap for sure,
but there will be new functionalities
as well, right.
Which we need to learn.
So we will be working
on the new functionalities as but
you need something else.
Okay.
Now if you see here Noelia right.
When I told you
I learned this post, I would think
I'm taking classes in America.
All right.
So if you see here right, this is invalid
log in error message, right?
Forced taking third and fourth.
You'll see here
this is for the first data.
And one, two, three.
This is for the second data.
Right mind.
But only three tests of five.
Now we have just four.
We have just four
ranked with the market fight,
not the third one is this enemy
and then empty password.
And then the fourth
one is empty username and.
So you password
connect the four sets of data we have.
This admin log is a different test.
Guess if you'll see it.
Is this we're talking about this one
because I'm not executing this just
because I've executed the entire class.
That's why you'll see this
quite might be might be nearby
because you need to check
whether in these two which one.
You must've made some mistakes here in
this part password can not be important.
Username cannot compete.
You must have made some mistake
or you have missed
some of the point in business.
That's why you are getting the error.
But the was.
There is no edit of the code.
I hope everyone is able to execute
this code.
Is your code working?
Everyone's for working, correct?
Correct. Correct.
That's what I was saying. Then break now.
If you try to execute it,
we definitely work
here.
I think I should change my profile
pic now.
All right, now, now let's
talk about something interesting.
I don't want data provided in my project.
I don't want data
provided in my framework, but
I know your.
All right.
So right now
let's try to talk something more advanced,
something more professional,
something more.
Good thing, right?
I don't want data provider.
Yeah, that's why I started.
It all began, so I changed it.
Now let's.
Your manager comes to your base
and your manager sees.
All right, fine.
This time, go ahead and execute
this functionality across.
200 users. All right.
It could be any combination, right?
200 users in one user.
You're
passing the length of the user name.
Ideally according to the application.
What happens is right
when it defines the criteria.
So your user name should expect
25 characters.
30 characters, 35 characters
like that, right?
So if you're passing 15 characters
in one another iteration,
you're passing 20 characters
as a username in third one.
25 characters is a username every time.
It should give you some error
message, right?
So now data becomes increased,
username, increased
password, increased rate error messages
increase this time.
This time, is it possible
for you to maintain all of this data
in data provider plus the
if you have this much of data
right, we can't do that.
So in this case, I need some structure,
I need some kind of
of a format in my framework
through which yeah, it is practical.
It is practical how we can do that so.
We have to keep all of our important data
at one place, right?
And then we will write
a completely separate function,
which read the data
from this particular file.
And then from that function
we will use the data in our test cases.
Right?
So now, no,
we do not need to make any other config.
Great. No more configurations, nothing.
We will write all of our data
in Excel file.
In one Excel file,
you can have multiple sheets in one sheet,
you can have multiple data, you can keep
all these things in one place.
You can keep it inside
your one place in your frame.
But now, after this. After this.
Because this is your non
java stuff, right?
You kept all of your data
in your Excel file.
The next thing, the very next thing,
what you do is
you will create one function.
You will write one separate function
which will read complete data
from your Excel file.
Right?
Which will read.
Doesn't matter how many keys
you're passing, how many values
you're passing, how many sheets you have,
that one function will read
your complete Excel
and it will give you every single data
which is available
in every single sale of your Excel point.
That kind of function we will write,
we will use data structure,
we will use the concept of collection,
we will use the learnings
which you guys did in your Java.
All right, So these all things right,
these are all the things
we will write in one function
that will read our data from Excel file
and we will use that particular function
in our test cases
to execute our best estimates.
Why are using the data from this function,
which we had mentioned in our excellent
guys understood?
The explanation which I gave just now
in our testing script, in our test cases,
we will use that function,
the function which is reading the data
from your ex-employee.
Right?
We actually the executive team. Exactly.
So it's all about the number of classes,
number of test cases that will increase,
number of files will be increased.
But here's the structure.
You see, that's why I told you
this is the most important part.
You should understand, right?
What we are doing, how we are doing.
This is the backbone
of your entire learning.
You guys need to understand this.
This is extremely important, right?
All right, great.
So now I just gave you the overview right
now, Right?
I told you, how are we going to implement
how these things work?
So next time, what would happen?
You have 1000 or 100 or 200
or 300 username.
Fine.
Right.
You had this much? Fine.
Go ahead.
Put it into the Excel file. Right.
Your function will say, All right.
How many data?
1000 posts.
I will predict
within a fraction of a moment.
Point how many kids you have.
I said I'm going to use just five out
of those hundred data or 1000 data.
Your function will say point.
I'm expecting five kids.
Send me the five kids.
I will give you the data which is made
with this five keys from your Excel file.
You can use it simple.
Got it.
Correct.
Exactly.
But again, I'm saying right.
This things are like one time learning.
If you learn this,
if you know how things work,
you can utilize this things
throughout your professional journey.
Believe me,
just to give me two more weeks
and you will find all of these things
right in a very short former
so you will be able
to understand these things. So
don't worry about it.
I'm working on it.
Yes, yes, I'm working on it.
All right, guys.
So this was the overview, right?
Right.
This was the working
which I just gave you.
Is there anyone who didn't understand
anything in this
so far
that it kind of
we are using?
All right, guys.
So I think I am
done from my side for today.