She's
an everyone.
Good morning.
I am on or you go.
Hello.
So now then, we are going to start.
First we'll go forward, Recap
what we did in the last two classes.
What we did in the last
two classes is correct.
So let me open this.
Let me go to nodes and open here.
Class number seven.
We should be good enough to get part.
Anyways,
what were the things we did
in the last class?
What was the first topic
we completed in the last class?
What was that?
Three operations from Greg.
Right.
So first
we understood what this Rest assured,
Java does to short and how it worked.
Right.
How it worked.
We understood this part.
Cutting
good. And then.
Then the understood. One more thing.
We had seen this part.
How we can create request
all different operations.
So when we talk about creating
the record in the database,
meaning the record from the
database, updating the record
in the database, right.
These three operations
we provided widget, right?
So then we decided in order what order?
We decided first we created the employee.
After creating the employee visit
with the same employee.
Because it forced what we were doing,
we were creating a one employee
and we were expecting some other employee
updating some other employees.
Right.
So that was not the exact with the actual
way of performing the operation.
Then the gimmick would be approach
where we first created the employee
with took the same employee
which we created,
and then we update the data
against that particular employee.
Right.
How we did it.
We made one variable employee I.D.
instance. Right.
And the same variable
we used in different request.
Right.
And then we retrieved the information
just to cross-check it.
Or even if I updating the details
across this particular user,
whether I'm getting the exact data
or not from the API part.
So to maintain, to maintain
the order of the execution,
we used one particular part.
What is there?
Things.
Remember, we changed the order
of execution by default.
It follows which one
assuming order.
We provided the order.
Yes. Correct.
Fix method order.
So there be use mental disorders
from the unique part, from unit part.
Okay.
So we changed the execution order
because by default it follows.
Talk to what the.
But you don't want that demon
to be executed
in alphabetical order
or in ascending order music.
Right. So we followed this particular one.
You see here,
this one is coming from this.
And this particular part of method order
start ascending.
It comes from my unit. And this option.
Right.
So how we can execute our discuses
using the you need for that.
We have to use this method sort of.
So according to this approach,
what we are doing is to
we are creating the employee.
Then we are retrieving the information
of the particular employee,
then we are updating the same employee.
And after updating again,
we are improving the information
database.
That is the cycle we are following.
Correct?
Is this correct on or to extend
and really push
this code? Yes.
Code is already available in that class
only output.
Now, if I go into the notes again
right here, guys,
we have already discussed one part,
this one.
And just what is the difference
in between these two based
and why we use this part
decent.
But that is why we use this
JSON.
But it is a class.
It is a class side.
You get a correct.
But why?
Why we use this particular this book.
What is the reason behind this
and this JSON method
to be able to use the methods object?
All right.
Because by default in Java, rest
assured, allows data
to be sent in, which for me, in just one.
Right.
So to Z to cover everything,
to retrieve everything in JSON,
we have to use the JSON.
Right. We have to use this.
Just not correct.
From here,
we can collect the data monitor.
We can collect the data.
Whatever the body we are getting, whatever
the response we are getting, whatever
the other things we are getting in order
to fetch the values either
complete value or from one one value
from all these things.
Right. So we can do all of these things.
You can do this using this particular JSON
class or JSON, but method
is that you?
Morning Ziva.
So now I told you one more thing
while creating the request here in Java,
just a short API base.
You are right. It is this.
You are right means this you are
equivalent to what base you wanted, right?
Basically what it simply means is
you are correct.
And when we use given given.
What is the reason why we use
given key words, why
we use given key word
to prepare the request rate.
So to prepare the request, we need to have
this particular particular base.
You are
right.
Right. Next
file simply then keyword we can use.
So we use this when given to fit
the and pointed to the end point.
We need one keyword
and then the another keyword we use.
Then for
response or validation.
Responsible validation, correct.
Now let's do another thing here.
Let's to another thing,
just one operation here, and then we'll
proceed further to integrate.
Are this particular part to integrate our
Java session API with our framework,
because right now
we are doing these hardcoded
exemplars, right?
We should not do hardcoded examples.
Instead we will go and we will use
all these things in our actual operation.
Replace
b c e with B would be fine,
A, B, c,
and D after this
I'm going to write another method.
So in this method,
what I'm going to do is I'm going to
I'm going to get all employees
and all employees
after adding the employee,
getting one data, and then I'm going
to get all the employees.
So they
tell me
one thing in
order to get all the employees, in order
to get all the employees,
do I have any end point
in my swagger?
We have it.
We have it right.
And also,
I want to just see the total number
of employees, the employee count and
the ideas of the employee, what all are
the ideas of these two things.
I need data.
So now, now to do this, we need to write
one particular test, right?
We need to write one particular test
to perform this operation.
How we can do it.
First, I'm going to write public void
E because D we don't get
all employees,
get all employees.
So here first we have to make one
vice versa.
What we have to make
request.
Tell me this particular token.
This particular token, what we are using
is it good
or we have to change this token.
No good. We have to change it. Fine.
Nobody's in school here.
Page 11 API General token bar.
Send it
generate new token.
Simply update this
simply
we have to upgrade the token.
This is the token I got right.
So now, now here.
First I'm going to meet that exist.
So based on me which part we use
to make the request,
what is the first thing?
In order to prepare the request,
we have to call one particular class.
What is this
request?
Specification.
Right.
So let me create the object.
But it would be the variable prepared
like is it was for which giveaways
even start
in order to get all the employees.
Do we need a body?
Do we need body bodies? Nobody. Right.
But we need header.
So first let's take the data.
What should be the header
should be mine or to write zation
authorization, comma.
You can really
start another header.
What is the database
content type I'm going to provide?
The value is
application slash json
database application slash JSON.
So that's how I prepared to request.
After preparing the request,
I'm going to say
write this so I will get the response.
And for that response
I have to create one variable.
So prepared request dot
which give advice to hit don't
when keyword don't reach method
to get all the employees which method
get method don't get
simply provide the end point here.
So where can I get the end point from?
I can get my end point
from my swagger document.
So this should be the end point.
This should be the end point for
no. Now, here's what I'm saying.
It says Response not pretty Print
guide Why redistribute
students?
Why we use preprint
instead of the standard?
Let divided response
start with the printed.
We print everything in the console.
Fine.
Now tell me one thing.
Easy.
So. So let's here.
When I'm talking about this
particular request to get all the employed
right when I say get all the employees
so this particular body
will tell me what
it will do,
then we want this particular response
for all the embroider to done something.
What does that
list of employees.
Right.
Misspoke employees in the body of the work
body.
Right.
It returns all the employees.
So I'm going to get a string
called a string on
all employees
where I'm going to see this response.
I'm going to store this response.
Right. Right.
Because I will tell you
how I can use this particular response.
Fine.
Great.
Now, easy
decision, but class,
decent part class
I'm going to use here. Why?
Because it always allows us
data to be sent in this environment.
My data is also going to come in
JSON for me.
So first I'm going to do
one thing is creating the object,
the object of Jason for the class.
No. See,
what I'm going to do is I'm going to write
JSON, but
it is is equals the new JSON button.
And here I'm going to provide
this particular variable.
So this part, whatever the data is coming
in, JSON part or class object,
I'm going to use this data
to perform further operation
to perform further operation.
Now the point is, what is that operation?
So I can change,
I can customize my output, which I want to
bring in my console for API automation,
but I don't want every single thing.
First of all,
I don't want every single thing.
I need a couple of things.
So what are these couple of things?
So first, I have to take care of this
couple of things, right?
First thing I need over on account
of the employee's
what I would be based
is what I would need
the overall count of the employee.
Right.
So here I'm going to write it is start.
It says get the string
count is a string or what is
this object is going to return me
the count.
So count as a string or what
count doesn't.
Right?
So simply write gig and to get into work.
So now see I'm going to you this
here.
If you go right here,
if you go use this token
to your get on employee's demand.
Right.
And send it.
When you see this employee big
time, fine.
So now if you see this employee's
this employee's object, right.
This is the distant object, Right.
And inside this employee object,
I'm going to get all the bodies.
Correct.
So it is returning what these employees
object is returning to the overall list
of all the employees.
Getting my point.
Capital E place employees with capital E
right here.
You see this employee in one employee.
So these employees with small E,
that's their difference.
If you get their detail of one particular
employee in returns and private small E
and here it returns
employee with capital E, Right
So this employee bit capital
is returning the list of all the employees
where I'm having the information of all
the employees available in the database
and that's from
the concept
what employee is employee's with capital.
He is going to return the list of all the
employee's available in their database.
So now if I come here and we want think
what is the matter to be
generally used to get the size of the list
employees
not sons, isn't it?
That is or not
not size matter
we don't really use for work.
And then here simply
I'm going to print one part.
What is that I'm going to say
integer count is equals to this.
So whatever the count,
whatever the size it
going to return, I'm
going to bring that size here.
Say come.
Is that clear?
With 800 leaving
three B
the number of
employees in
on spawn in response. What
is this place?
So to execute this part, I have to add.
Now tell me one thing.
Do I need to run all of this?
Do I need to learn all of this
just to get all the employee?
This is my this particular test relying
on previous test.
No district is not relying
on any other display.
So let's run this one just to check
is it getting better listed another list?
It is list set.
It is a list
now you'll see
because we provided predicted.
We got all the data
we got already tied.
And after that, after that, in the end,
if you'll go,
you'll see here 1113.
Got it
like this 1113 is coming from
where is 1113 is coming from.
This particular account.
Correct.
Is this correct? This brings
let's read some
let's clear some
copy.
No, but you did not use it in this case.
Even we use pretty print
to get all the response
or to get a stable code so that good
because we use a pretty print part
rated pretty pretty good.
Print it every single thing
what we got in the body.
So every single thing printed by print
when you get this.
There you go, sir.
One one, one three.
If you see here eight days don't get
we got this data
I the looks like
we did this Jason but glass object
using this object
we got the total number of integers
right to the number of employees
in digital form.
So integer count
this is the size it is returning.
I'm going to print distance
one. I forgot to put this.
No, is not.
What is it now?
Another thing Now another thing.
We are going to do.
What is that thing? If we show you,
I'm going to write for No to
bring
all the employee ideas
from response only employee I.D..
I would need to. I'm going to print that.
Is there a way to get one particular part
from the body
employee or token
member?
Body token?
Something like this we got earlier also.
So in order to get one particular value
from the body,
we can use one particular part.
What is the conclusion?
First, because I'm going to get the
details right, I'm going to use for loop.
Why do I read the values one by one,
one by one, one by one, All the things
so very simple integer is equal to zero.
I is less than my total count.
Right.
The count I'm already getting here. I
carried a
statement which will execute
after my loop executes right here.
I'm going to write again
the same object json part
plus object is done.
Now, earlier we were talking about
total number of count,
total number of columns.
It was integer.
Now, if I talk about employing IDs,
the IDs actually these are the integers,
but these are ambiguous
or they are three to name
e see something
We can consider it as a string
variable characters write string.
So let me write here to get the strength
gain is great.
So from where I'm going to get this string
my employs with capital E object
and here I'm going to see here
I'm going to see in this particular one
go and
what I hear first, what I hear first. So I
don't employ
underscore i.t.
What is the meaning of this days, guys?
What is the meaning of it?
It means employee's
first like first of the employee object
you got
in the employee
printed second, the employee reprinted.
So how I'm going to print it first
time to put it somewhere
so I'm going to write the employee
I these is equals to this.
So simply
go here and bring them liabilities
into my employees.
Right.
Using for loop integer
I is equals to zero.
I is then then don't I plus plus
using the decent part class object.
I'm going and I'm getting the string
because my employee ID is the string.
Right?
I'm reading employee 81
by to all the employees.
The stores, All of this employer is in
one variable and printing that variable.
All these things are
happening inside for my
because one look complete, one look.
It went to work like this is that here
is that dear to everyone
that's
let's execute
this part first execute this part
and then if you guys have any question
you can ask
so that we can proceed further.
Yeah.
So this, this is employee
I is the counter, right.
I is the that you see everybody
one by running this
printing printing and printing
can you see this
now. You'll see every single.
Well you are just printing everything.
It is printing. Go down, go down, go down.
And from here it gets employ 80,
so it starts ticking.
Where is the employer?
There you go.
This is the employee, 88
total employees, 1108.
When we started the API classes
for the number of employees were just 43.
We all are difficult place
to make this count this large.
We have created 1000 employees here
is still
if you say we don't know IBA shame on us.
Believe me, we have created 1000 employees
and we didn't learn anything,
so they missed this part.
But you want me to explain it?
It is a little bit
by no
more and as good
would it be possible to understand?
Yes, why not not console? Okay.
Do you mean by why not by all?
For you see, this is the only thing
we have written today.
So if you want
to look for the previous class,
I can do that
also, it
will be possible to understand
your biggest possible
aim From today onwards the will noisy
not use ordinance because rescheduling in
some users.
Can we go over this method?
Yeah, sure.
This is the method.
You mean
this is the method to get all employees?
So basically the intention is to print
all the employees, print
all the IDs of the employees.
Correct.
So first of all, to print all
the employees, we need to get the response
to get the response,
they need to send the request.
To send the request.
We need to prepare the request.
To prepare the request.
We need some components.
What are those components?
We need this. You want it?
We need headers.
We need end points. Right.
So we created a request
to provide a request
using when key word here using proper
method point.
We hit the end point also.
So we got the response
using this particular response.
First we got all the employees
here, their data for all the employees
available
here, read the data for all the employees.
It was it is not for it is under the
for loop where you're actually
passing the perimeter.
So you are passing this writing is
it is simply employee's comp, right.
Maybe ever seen that we are passing
the part
like this embroidered size
we are passing that also.
So now here
when you've got all the employee's details
in this particular string,
we are going to use this class object line
because we have already seen what
this particular object does.
If you have any question in this part,
you go in here, you see the details.
What I like, we use this and by the class
and we already discuss
in the class number six, right from here.
From here, when we created the object
of the decent part
class here
we are calling this particular variable,
having all the employee's data, right,
having all the employee's data.
And then from here, I'm trying to retrieve
the total number of employees
available in the database,
which is returning this particular list.
So when I go there and object
that this capital
E employs with capital E is returning
the list of all the employees.
So when it is actually returning the list
of all the employees, I'm going
to get the count of the particular list.
You get the size to get the overall size
of the particular list.
I have to use one particular
method from the concept of collection,
that is Darden Sites.
It returns the size of the list.
So here I use this employees object,
which is returning the list.
So my list is under employees dot sizes.
The method I'm using using
which particular class object.
Jason Park Class object.
So just unpack.
Class object is having this particular
method get integer
when it is expecting it integer.
We are providing this particular data
now when it is returning one
particular integer.
What is that integer?
This is the overall count
of all the employees, right?
Overall count of the employees.
So I am going to see this particular count
in this particular variable
and this variable
I'm going to print for this thing done
first thing. Then
I printed the count of all the employees.
Fine. Now I don't want to print the count.
I want to print every single employee ID
If there are 1000
employees,
I want to print 1000 employee IDs.
Fine.
Do we have anything?
Yes, we have one thing from column loops.
What is that for? Look. For look is to.
I tried to traverse the values
one by one from the list.
Fine. So we go to the for an envelope.
I'm seeing.
Yes, the Bastian.
Right. Right.
Because someone named someone
might be in some other class
someone is taking the database classes.
Right. And they are hitting the employee.
Someone is working in, let's say
my sequel class,
someone is working in data science class.
A lot of things are going on and everyone
is just projecting to the same database.
So that's why data keeps changing.
Tomorrow, maybe you'll see
just 200 employees, 800 deleted.
Something like this happens, right?
So despite
at least you are getting accused,
you are getting this particular one,
the success message, right.
The correct message with your API
part is working point
right.
So now now here here.
If you see this particular version
using for the what I'm seeing, I'm saying
this time I want to print employee IDs,
not account of all employees.
Right.
So here is the employee is the object.
And notice there is a guy called employee
underscore ID
it is returning employee every time
so you get one
against an employee's employer
so it will return one employee.
This is what we did in mind.
This particular part
here you see employee DOT employee ID
because it is returning one.
Is it possible that some of those contents
can be viewed on the employee?
So we didn't get a complete list.
Don't do Nicole, don't do this
implicit.
We should not get empty list from here.
This would be very difficult.
I see. But everything is possible.
So we we need this, right?
It is possible.
Actually, it is possible.
But generally, this kind of operation,
even for the admin people, are restricted.
This type of operations are restricted
even for those roles.
So now for one employee
against simply provide employees
don't employ ID,
it will return one particular employee
readiness.
Yeah, correctly.
That's what I'm seeing.
See, I'm coming to that point also. Right.
I got it partly
because I explained partly knowing key.
So for one employee I complete employee's
dot employee it will return one employee.
But to get all the employees one by one.
Okay closed employee,
get the 82nd and get the 80.
So internally, internally,
when I'm seeing the entire list
one by one, I'm providing the index
of the employee,
I'm providing the index position.
Third employee.
Fine.
Get the employee printed for the employee.
If I get the employee printed, fifth
employee fine.
Get the employee printed like this.
We are doing So this is coming from where?
From my no informant.
I provided condition builder time.
My counter is less
than the overall size of the list.
You should print everything
one by one, one by one.
Traverse all the employee,
get all the employees in.
Pretty simple
now understood such
here.
One more thing.
It's completely a blue instead
of providing the employee ID,
if you want to retrieve hostname,
you can do that.
If you want to retrieve
last name, do that.
If you want to retrieve the gender
of all the employees, do that
right?
Yes, I got it.
Okay, let's.
So data retrieval.
Data retrieval can we've been in multiple
ways, right.
It's not a come by rule
that you have to retrieve
only the employee
you can retrieve all the first name.
You can retrieve all the middle name.
You can retrieve all the last name.
Right.
Not lot of things,
not of things are there.
Correct.
Funny. Now.
So now let's proceed further
and this time we will integrate
are particular API but integrate our
Java A API. But
can you remember understood
both it.
So first things
you perform in the operation.
Right now what we're doing,
we're manually creating a token.
We are generating the token manually
and then we are using it
because we know that okay,
it is valid for us
since we are learning right now.
It is a good approach going into it.
But when you actually work
in the realtime industry,
when you work in the industry,
it means at this point of time
in the airline
industry, is it the right approach?
Is it the right approach to go
and create token
manually generate the token?
And you know,
we should come up with the approach
that can generate the token automatically.
Any user token automatically voltage
generation
and use of the token
automatically should be our priority.
This should be our priority.
Current. Correct. Good.
I was thinking the second thing
we are passing the end point.
For example,
get all employees or get one employee
or generate token
something like this.
Right?
Or do your job provide you with token
Jimmy.
They will not provide you the token.
They will provide you just one thing
that is that credentials
to generate the token.
And then we have to make this collection
in most of it, or we have to put it
in the script to generate this token
every time for every coin.
Okay Fine.
So now if I'm anytime soon,
if I'm providing this data hard
coded, the way I'm creating it
here, here is the right
approach.
Is this right? Get passing
the body like this.
We are providing their data like this.
No, no. Right.
So again, again,
we have already put enough cream in there.
We know everything is.
Every single thing is that I'm increased.
But it it doesn't look professional.
Everything should be parameterized, right?
So then we use GIs everywhere
and we provide a value at one place.
So every time
if there is a change in the vendor,
we have to change it one place
and you should always
get updated every bit.
But it
similarly similarly.
Couple of things we need to check.
What are those things?
In a framework
we were using constants using constants.
Part of this constants values are fine.
That was values are fine.
And these are constants.
Current values are not going to change.
So we provide constants.
So similarly, some of the gods games,
some of the constants
we will point in the agents
whose values are not going to change.
We are going to work with
all of these things correct in our plane.
So we have this functionality
available in our framework.
We are just going to integrate
this existing functionality with an API.
But here, Student Square
Now, now tell me what is the first stage?
What is the first step
to integrate API with Key?
But what is the first thing we
Yes, we create.
First of all
feature correct?
First of all, we will create the feature.
Fine.
So now, now here I'm going
to create a feature right here, right?
So I am writing in this feature like
let me go
and create my
days.
Everyone knows how to create feature
file, right?
But still, is there any Einstein
who doesn't know how to create objects?
If he is there, do let me API
workflow dot feature
correct?
Correct.
This is my API workflow feature
which I'm going to create.
So first thing,
what we need to write in feature pages,
what is the first thing
that I can feature based
first thing that I do feature?
So I'm going to write the same dates API
workflow for
each item.
And under this feature,
under this feature,
I'm going to write forced
scenario.
So scenario I'm going to write.
Simple is let's see, generating
the first thing I'm going to write
is generating the token, correct.
So here I'm writing given given
which type of you can use guys, guys,
what type of token we use
is it
JWT token is
generated.
I'm going to write JWT Beer
token is a generated fine.
What is the next thing?
Now this is
what is the next thing
when forced
to generate the token
and then we will use it.
Right?
I started generating the token
as scenario need.
So after generating the token,
is there anything else we need to do
as of now,
we don't have to do anything else, right?
So first I will go in my donor class
and I will use a
new remote class here called
API and
call it bottom.
Right.
And in this API and I am going
to use the options from my smoke.
One only
from my smoke, one only.
I hope everyone remembers this part guys.
A direct run with the class.
Given our options,
everyone knows it or not.
Tell me
I'm seeing API workflow
that features will be b.
I like flow featured.
Fine. Okay.
Brian, we need this.
We need tags, we need plugins, we need.
We don't need this part.
What is that reason?
It is no option for reader Now.
We are not using this.
Find the rest of the things are working.
List of the things are okay.
So now now guys, tell me one thing
who generate this particular part,
this particular step from here.
First, I have to provide here one tag.
So I'm writing here. Tag is work
workflow,
and I'm going to provide
this particular tag here.
Fine,
fine.
Now tell me to is to generate this,
get what I should do
another class.
Okay.
I have to use try.
It is equal to to
the moment I need.
Triton is equals to draw
and I am going to run this particular
class and another class.
See what would happen.
It gave me this particular step is it
gave me this particular step.
Correct?
Correct.
Let's copy this.
When should I keep it? Was
this the step?
But should I keep it
under steps?
Okay, Now tell me one thing.
In a sense. Great.
I was just taking your knowledge.
That's what I was expecting from you.
In these steps.
We have rules.
What is rules?
Before? After?
It means opening the browser.
Closing the browser precondition.
Most condition. Do we need hooks here?
An API?
Do we need to open the browser?
Do we need to close the browser?
So if I provide
if I provide this particular steps
under my steps package, what would happen?
It will automatically take the hooks.
Correct.
And I don't want this part.
So what should I do?
We will not bother
about these steps anymore.
We will not bother about these steps
anymore.
Indeed, in Java
we are going to create a new package
called API.
API steps one
create another package, API steps.
And inside these I'm going to create now
class go
generate
token
generate token steps, generic steps.
Is that clear?
Is this clear
now? Here provide this particular
way, this particular import
so fine.
Clear. Everyone So far so good.
Everyone
Now now here I'm going to write this part.
First element is in this in this part
in this part.
What are the things I should write?
I would want
distance under the regular steps
because there is I just explained, right.
If I create this particular
steps class under my steps package,
then my steps back.
It has already hooks. Right?
This hooks is one precondition
in most condition, right?
So precondition condition generally opens
the browser, close the browser,
reading the report everything that we need
to open the browser.
We need to close the browser.
So we need to generate those reports
for the execution of that.
No, we don't need them. Right.
So unnecessarily,
if I put there, it will not work.
Great. It'll create problem for us.
So I have to.
I have to be
I have to be in the another package.
Right.
That's why I created API instance package
that is not clear.
But let's go to the so guys must be
first thing things here.
We are going to prepare the
request right so I'm going to write you
for generating the token guys.
Generating the token what you need
first we need here, if everyone
remember is clean
this you is equals to
rest assured door.
This is equals
to the value of my business.
You want
what is the value of my
Because you are engaged.
This is the value of my base you have.
I can provide this value here with base
to be a support
editable slash right.
Got it. GDP.
So now, now here I'm going to write given
given dot dot.
I'm seeing here
what I request is specification
generate
token
object request is equals to see
given dot
now where it is not taking
the given part.
Fine.
Now look,
so here I'm going to provide
first base then me
what is the header
base.
What is there that I should provide here?
Content.
Right.
And the value should be
it should be application slash
Jason Dot dot.
What is the next thing I is, guys?
What is the next thing?
I should go here
again.
Here to my authorization.
No, there is we are going
to generate the token this time the member
so for generating the token we need body
collect, we need body.
So here, here
we will going to provide the body.
Right.
Which body
now which body we are talking about here.
This is the body which we provided
for generating the token.
So this is the body we need.
Well we have imminent password.
Right. Dead body we need. Yes. Correct.
So we provided this dead body here.
Everyone understood this
one had to be provided one
dead body state.
Is this clear why we provided this
perfect
guys?
Yeah.
It is not the same as yours.
Your piece.
This code is called Relations.
Based on if.
If there is some internet
connectivity issue, do let me know.
Right.
Because above
what is going on as you can see here.
Got it.
And it's raining crazy, obscene.
I don't know where it started.
It is raining.
Please
put the correct amount of
this is not my problem.
This is my U.P. is right because of that.
I'm getting this temporary power
right now.
So for some time it works.
Yeah. One month cutting works.
Now, congratulations to this.
Our API knows that it should go to a text
rather than instead the end.
We are coming to that point.
We are coming to that point and we
so far this part correct.
This is how we are preparing the request.
So now, now what I'm going to do
is to send this particular bar.
I have to write generate,
generate, token request dog, then
dog post
post.
And here I have to provide
I have to provide this particular part
for generating the token and point post
I have to
provide is main point for us to select.
We provide within 20. Correct.
But it is going to generate the token
the final point of my token
should be something like this.
Viera Space plus this token
BNA is based plus this particular token.
Correct.
So this token, this token,
I'm going to see it somewhere.
This particular already exist.
We have, you know,
this is the email already.
This is the email ADB had, right?
Retirement It is this.
This is a mini milady.
I think. So
we have to use this particular email.
I need to generate the token.
Alright.
All right.
Understood.
Fine.
So now, now here
what I'm going to do is see.
I am going
to write here first my token rate.
I need this string as token. Correct.
Now tell me this.
I'm going to use this token
only at one place
ordered all the other places
where I will use this token.
All this is So can I make it public?
Can I make it public now?
I don't want to create the object
of this class.
Also, I want to use this token directly.
So can I use this to you?
Start you thinking, Great.
So here, Nancy, whatever the venue
you're taking, just save these values.
In this token, you would save this venue
in this token even right?
Right.
Thank you, guys.
So first first here was to see
what we are going to do.
This part.
This part when we're dating. Right.
Sorry. My right.
First we have to use our response.
Response I'm going to use
from my generate token part
like not when forced
first thing we are going to get it
like this. See?
And from this response from this response.
Sorry I should change this
from this particular response.
I'm going to get this token,
this token using JSON.
But is it isn't post
So the citizens of this should be my most
decent part object, right?
Because every time for retrieving
the value from the response body.
Yeah, right.
Just because I was just taking my control
is to put inside of wasp final.
So guys when I got this
response complete response.
So from the response body,
if I want to retrieve something,
I have to use this JSON,
but plus JSON part the method.
So I'm going to use
don't get string, get a stream of what
it's doing of my of my token.
So this token is available.
Well, if you see here in the body
you get a string
called token which might be remember this
this gives sensitive.
Right.
So whatever the value is available
against this key token,
it will be stored in this particular token
part.
It'll be stored in this particular
token part.
And here
I can simply print this tokenized.
There is any question in this part,
in this part,
any question is
here.
So firstly, everyone
now know what is broken
inside that gated string.
This token is coming under the body.
See, this is the body inside body.
This token is returning, right?
My request is returning, that is bonds.
So having the key token.
So that way we were using employee
not employ
a B to get one particular employed here.
We don't have anything like that.
We have simple tokens.
I'm providing token with good string
because in return it is returning.
Even if it was integer,
I should have gone get integer right.
And then we are storing it here.
So why Vienna?
Because my final value of token
is Vienna Space.
The value of token.
Can you copy? Best 18 to 23 for me.
18 to 23.
This particular part, this part.
So can someone please
copy and paste it here in the check?
But my dear friend Lou
offered.
Come on.
Yeah. Again, you just.
You just can't.
You just count this?
Fine.
Now, see, guys, if I go in my remote
class, if I go in my render class
here, instead of providing
this is dipped in glue.
Because why we provide glue.
Glue always provide
the part of the package we are here.
Define all the steps. Right.
So in our runner class,
instead of providing glue, it states
we are going to provide
this particular bar as
as API steps.
API steps.
So now, now instead of targeting
two steps folder,
it will target two API scripts
for API steps.
Package
video not working for you.
How about others?
See now?
Fine.
Now this time.
This time this time going to execute.
It will go to my API steps package.
My favorite one by the way
positions because I don't go
out so there is nothing up is eight
based on good for me.
Now when I go out it's
what is correct.
So now this time being executed right?
It will execute my API steps package
under this EPA steps package.
Whatever the class
we have provided with this bag,
it will create
and it will make each event from this.
Right.
So let's run
this particular run of API, run from here.
This time
I hope everyone understood this point.
Let's run this.
See it says generating their token, right?
It says generating the token,
but it's not printing the token.
Oh, come on, I see your need.
You have to do.
You should have told me earlier.
You should have
informed me earlier. Right?
You're not.
You're not of any fastest pulling.
Just kidding.
Let me read it again.
Got it, guys.
Got this token or not,
we are able to generate the token.
No, I hope everybody's getting my point.
We are able to generate the token. No.
Any questions of our students?
Any confusion, anything?
This is our feature right.
Make sure the steps, please. For sure.
Why not?
This is the steps.
First, we simply create a request.
We hit the end point.
We got the response.
That is the only thing we and we have been
doing the same thing since now.
Correct.
Let me commit the code.
Meanwhile,
this code is committed to
whatever the things we doing so far.
It is committed already in the deposit
to get everyone.
Please check confirm this
so far.
Is this clear to everyone?
There is any question.
Please ask any question.
I know you guys busy in writing the code,
but please ask.
I'm giving your time. No issues.
I'll give you 40 minutes
to write everything.
Nobody
got it.
So the small chunk of code Benham writing
rate and developing this team code.
First, I'm committing to the repository
so that you can get the object code
from there,
and then we will proceed further.
There is a strategy of following them to
a legal target was
does not really provide this part.
Rest assured, this part redeployed.
Then why is this not
They should not be the
because there are just two things that
only just one thing actually we wrote.
One is that in feature
and we wrote this particular code
against that particular feature,
the exec window, and we didn't do anything
and we are not posting
anything from anywhere.
So why the most is that
can you please check this particular part?
Are you using a strip
club slash along with this
HTP colon double slash and
then the complete part used is complete,
but that would work.
That should work actually
is not so correct.
Now we have the formula, right?
We have the method.
This method generate token every time
before making any point rate.
So then we don't have to take care
of this thing, right?
It will generate token automatically.
It will use this token automatically.
Every regulator
or human
to set this peg workflow.
Yes. Correct.
Detect
who gender token
any what to do with that with this case.
Normally I was going to do that.
We should not provide this any tag
or anything between to automatically
use the feature of Kimber.
Remember the feature of Google,
but that always executes
two things in Kimber.
That always executes.
The first is big down under.
When these hooks hooks we will not use
because we don't have the condition.
What's the condition?
Big company does in background.
We can provide this just before token.
So before making any request posted
will generate the token,
then it will prepare the request
and then it will call rate.
Because in preparing the request
also we need token.
So first
we will generate the token in every become
one. But
can you open your console by anything?
This is my console one.
Check your off top question. No,
please ask if you have.
Yeah if you have is ask
a one that Please check
your Triton is equal to true or false.
If it is true, make it false
and then it will break.
You can always ask.
Please ask.
It depends. It completely depends.
There is always huge requirement
for that huge request.
We've always rate up,
but it depends how you can contribute it.
How much you know, because there is
it can never be a straightforward.
You could
al-Fadhli I'm talking about this guy
but one that yes.
Are you brothers?
Are you would brothers
even you you're not going to see
my given is right.
It's an import problem.
Just think the import raid rate like this.
Yeah,
just rate like this even could convert.
Or Java. Not this one. Sorry,
not this one.
See, this is the import problem.
Just this import to give a rate.
So rest assured, given this one.
All right
it would are brothers
you'll get it is the same repository.
It is the same repository
the Kimber 11 from Bahrain Elementary.
What we have it's the only
nice and then why are you asking one
can ask the question
and another
will automatically get answer say
but output is different.
No virus.
Are you printing this
because I don't see you provided us
with not well what did they jumpstarted?
It was this the host is none.
I just answer to this question.
I just answer to
this question is check your base.
You are right.
It is correct or not. Now.
Good. Please check your train.
And then is it to do first
or second thing?
Provide this part?
So the standard order
print, you know, if you go on a break
to meet owners, all their queries
boost their produce first rate
I was expecting from
you also to resolve this queries
on your intelligent
rate.
You should be the leader now.
You should be adhere to the class
is trained base.
You are as equal to this
this particular part it right?
Oh, it is what I'm going to write.
Not for me then you'll either perfect
or release
any question in this
business contract.
And is it cost control for omron.
Check your with your I
but anyone was still not able to do
libraries. None
Are you providing this token spin
incorrect?
Doesn't matter. Don't get this free token
right then take the object
quote from the repository.
It will work.
Take the ability
quote from the repository.
It will definitely work.
Check your blue. Oh,
it's just this is Boston.
So white blue
is what I'm saying.
You should have know.
I knew if you don't provide this token
for print
it will not work
already.
So let's take a break.
Let's take a break.
Think for 15 minutes
that be in after 15 minutes.
We've got it once.
Okay.
So now, guys, to get all the values
for all the end points, right?
We Are going to create constants
because these values are seen
in same values.
We should not. Plus hardcoded.
We have to parse these values.
Using are constants plus.
So in constants
I'm going to write public static
public static final public stating final.
So we write them with global variable.
Correct.
So all we need public is data final
and then is clean.
Because my BS you are
I is going to provide me this value.
So I'm going to write
this assured dot
base.
You are I is equals to my value my event.
Right.
So where is the value
that you
this is the host.
I'm going to provide the API constraints
which we going to use.
Then the next thing is next
thing is renewed want.
So guys remember complete complete base
you are
I see
when I need to call complete base
you are right
it is the combination of you
are plus end point or not
guys it is a combination of your illness
and or not.
Right.
So here when I provide this key gold base
you are I
if I add here, if I add here this endpoint
so it becomes my it becomes my final.
You are right. Right.
So it means at this point of time,
I don't need to create two parts.
Remember, I don't need to create two paths
given and went back to different parts.
So how I'm going to write
is let me show you in my constants.
I'm going to write public
static, public static final.
The string
I'm going to write for first create
employ underscore you on
I and here I'm to write this as base.
You are right
plus plus the endpoint of create employee.
So the end point of create employee is
let me check
create employment use this great.
So let me take this and I will start
now this particular part create
employ you are
I will return
my complete part will to my complete
pattern not based on me.
Similarly, I'm going to write a public
static find and string.
This time I'm going to write for the get
one. Okay,
you are again because you are a plus
for data.
One employee is this one.
So let me copy this.
And recitative.
Is this clear to everyone what I'm doing
right
then create employee,
get employee
then we will do for public static
final string
a B employee.
You are
you want a plus
is update employee
right this update employee and then public
static binder screen upgrade employee
get employee
you all employees
right then
public static
final screen
beat employee
you are
and then
generate to replace
days these all are
B these on are the main calls we have
right if you want to use you can add
badge can also get status
also lot of other things you can add
right now I'm going to use only the ones
which we will be using in our script.
Right?
Because rest are simple, normal.
Get once again take in Bachchan.
Also in our current operations,
either we create, we update right
with retrieve the data.
These all are the things we do. Fine.
Now this let's talk about another point
that these content type is means header
so that also I can provide
from here on the right.
So I'm going to right here stream.
The next is drink is I'm seeing the header
to contain.
I is equals to
the value of my header should be
contain.
So now we're not going to provide content
I we will simply provide this key.
So the model if things get changed
everything that I don't need
to change content type in the value
I will change it one place
and this will get a bit everywhere
right in here.
Public static final string.
And I'm seeing here right
content type of value.
So what is the value?
It is application
slash
slash, JSON.
Everyone getting my point
right
now, there is another header,
there is another headers
called authorization.
Remember that?
Another difficult authorization.
So I'm going to use bank header here
find and screen.
I'm seen
header and underscore or
authorization.
So what is the value of this?
The value is on to raise the
this is the new rate, right?
Everyone
everyone
got it.
Same thing. We're doing great.
Now tell me why I'm not going
to provide the value authorization here.
Why is it so
okay?
What is the value of authorization?
Yes. Correct.
Because every time every time
my token is changing paid, I will generate
new token for every single execution for,
every request I will generate new token
for that we already have that
functionalities integrate with us now.
Now, when we are done with this part,
when we are done with this part.
We proceed further.
What is the next thing we have to do?
So let's see
now, after this
I am going to write a simple scenario,
right?
I'm going to write a simple scenario.
So what is that scenario? See
here?
I will in my
feature by this is my feature first.
Now guys, there is a
do we have to declare it
final because the value gets changed.
Everything
final for what?
For token, not authorization.
Key is final.
Right?
See yet if you go
this authorization is the key.
This header authorization we believe so
this is final threaded.
This final authorization value
which we will going to provide
that is keys find final
when it was changing bait.
So we are making the key.
Find this key we are making find it
understood for us now.
So now here
I'm going to write once to evaluate
maybe having multiple scenarios for sure.
So no, not
when it comes to multiple employee rate.
When it comes to multiple employee,
if I need something that should execute
on always before execution of my scenario,
this particular feature find
what is the functionality here?
It is simple as before method.
Interestingly, we have something
perfect.
They count me here
background we have so
we can put this part in background,
maybe put this part in the grounds
because I'm going to execute this part
every everywhere.
So this is my background.
And this one,
the first one I'm going to work
is create an employee
via API.
The first thing I'm going to do
is I am going to create an employee
behavior
rate, clear student
Everyone.
So now here I am going to write
given
a request is prepared,
a request is prepared for
the acting employees
I'm seeing.
First we are going to prepare
the request replaced.
Remember one thing
when you are going to prepare request,
right?
So for preparing the request.
For preparing the request, we need a token
for token.
We already provided or JWT is generated.
So this particular step will return
the token
token really use in preparing the request
district and we will use implementing
the request that what we put JWT
token is generated on the upper site.
Okay.
All right, students,
let's
after this, we have to right here.
When I was going
to create the employee, we have to go.
We have to use
British method, also method, right?
So when a bold call is made to create,
create an employee to create an employee
in a post
call is made to create an employee,
then what would happen?
Then what would happen based
employee created,
then then the status, then the status code
for creating an employee is
what is the status quo. Today's
201 correct.
Their status code is 2012010.
Nice.
You created an employee.
They lose it.
No, this is not a string.
This is integer
moment.
This is a deja.
This is not interesting.
If it was a string,
we would have provided a value like this
Guinea for constants for us.
I can also
I will not show it for second time.
It should for I'm going to see
why my undefined steps
are not highlighted in my beta flight.
How would I know
this is something unusual, right?
Ideally they should highlight.
They should highlight
when we get a note.
We have already figured out great.
So many issues.
We figured it out.
This issue already
maybe need to go to sleep before
strange time.
Nice. See
I thought the United States
but good can misquoting the method as well
it's beautiful part coding it
expected it can be stored in the method
as well instead of hardcoded no one.
But I will tell you right Like I said,
hold your horses first.
We'll go with the basic one,
then we'll go with the advanced one.
Right. And then so
and so on and so on. Like this.
Okay, fine.
So now after this things creating
an employee is fine,
but anything that we have to get
a different call,
we have to use a different code
to retrieve the information
or one scenario.
I should do everything.
What do you think?
I am creating the employee and
then I'm getting the date of the employee
right in my automation script.
The standard sees
the moment you create the employee
trained, the moment
you create the employee, same employee
take and check whether the same employee
is reflecting in the database or not.
Using date method
or simply you have to provide
a verification validation point.
Right?
So let's forget about get method check
whether you are getting employee
created message in the response body
or not.
Verification point.
Remember testing in days
remember testing Postman Right.
So we have to check
whether this particular message
employing created available in response
body or not.
Okay fine
it is available fine now give me employ 80
because this particular isn't
it better to make that
then condition for generic
like status code should be to zero one
so that we can use
it is to make then condition more generic.
The status quo should be two zero ones.
Great, we can do the same and we doing
will do it.
Seven Nobody will do. Don't care.
You get it now we are just
we should have it.
201 and 201 maybe.
Yes, we should put like this 2011
like this.
As of now, let me just read this step
and then we'll see this.
Good.
Okay, So remember is here
as we write it just we wrote in the post,
women were validating the message,
validating the value right,
and then the in hard coded exemplars
for Java, just a short API.
Also, we used we created an employee
and used that employee ID
for updating their data,
for deleting their data,
for partially operating
and getting their return.
So the same idea.
So what does it mean?
It Means the employee in which
we are going to get after creating
an employee will make it global variable,
will store it in the global variable,
and then we will use this particular
employ and write.
The one which we are generating
using this particular scenario
will use this employee
for further operations.
So everything we are going to automate now
automatically generating the token
fine automatically, creating an employee
fine,
automatically getting the bot,
getting the employee
80 of the created employee
and use it for further operations.
Every single thing we are doing
where automation, we just need
to click on one command
and everything will be done automatically.
The is
this clears clearance
lines so here I'm going to write and
and the employee
data contains key.
What is the key?
Key should be my message.
I will show you this and value should be
the value should be.
And before
we get this value and this key message
or not, see, when you create the employee,
it gives you this particular part
message is the key, right?
And employee created is the value
we get you.
Not everything received it date
every time we received
one student's
now we generated the employee.
We modified history to school.
We go to the message employee created.
Now main point.
What is that point?
We will use this particular part.
Which part?
This particular part of employee I.D.,
which we have generated here,
which we have created here.
We will use this particular employee
for the further operations.
Right.
So that I'm going to write and be in the
employee I.D.
delegates.
How can we get the employee I.D.?
I give you a
we have already got this employee.
How we generally define the employee
that is be used in hard coded example
from the entire body.
If I need one particular value,
how we do it, how we get one
particular relief from the internally.
Exactly.
Employment capital you your small e guys
capital one small one
go and take here
this employee for create an employee right
Creating the body in the response
we are getting this employee with
this employee with
in Istanbul we call it small
in any in New York so we got it small
not it's like capital train
so right you just getting this getting
docked
employee underscore i.t.
Great employer
and employee underscore it correct
is stored
as a global
variable.
Variable
to be used for
those calls to be used for.
Of course
pays.
Is this clear?
Super.
When you look from standard
everything is small by
you look at it at this much height
you should be grounded and everything
right?
It's a sign up arrogance.
They should not be arrogant as a Neumann.
We think
if a location is like hired
or if they did you sustain a bet against
because everything looks a smile from
the see are India.
Come here we are 1.5 billion
everyone is of
same size is here also yet on
right
the people call
this is the university of religion
Some say this is a city of legends.
We said this is a country of religious
1.5 billion indigenous.
We have
the greatness of this stuff
or don't talk about greatness
and don't talk about greatness.
Here the greatness is blowing
in the river, in bones, in fountains.
Every greatness is you
engaged.
So now what is the next thing?
Be built from
the bottom. Wants to see the heavens.
What are the top
mice? But
when I came to the Empire State Building,
everyone looks like someone.
Why did you
claim That part? Why?
What was the reason?
Beings
better suited your
for it to go here and it
all relates.
So now.
Now we have to generate steps
and part is providing from then
see and why we use these empty word
case, why we use engagement
supporting degree.
So after then when Angular is coming,
what does it mean?
What does it mean?
It means multiple verification
validation points.
Are there rate, multiple verification,
whether should points.
So one it first.
I'm really fine Mike 201 status good
API status good.
In second one I am ready.
Find one message and value
both and in third one
I'm not only redefining
but also storing the embroidery
which we are getting from the response
so that we can use this
particular employ as the global variable
every bit.
Correct these three validation points,
verification check points be synthetic for
if you want to dispute this
final
now let's generate the steps.
So again, I would go in my iPad and
I will make it true.
Right.
And then I'm going to run it.
We copy all these steps
and here in my iPad steps,
I have to create another class.
What is the name of the class base?
I'm going to write it.
API workflows.
It's simple
API, but across all the APIs
I'm going to put here
because there is no module as right,
there is no module as such.
That's why I'm going to write
this particular part here.
So see,
this is something I've written over here
while we were discussing
something important or you were discussing
about Russia Ukraine by then, Sebastian
is busy editing the pics.
So now, now you'll see here, right?
I provided Andrei,
I provided and in my scenario
remember too, and I provided in mercenary
based
after
then I provided to end in my scenario.
But here it took all three.
Then how intelligent making Uber is.
Campbell knows
the combined knows that will find
this is the part in continuation of then
so I should put
then only adding
content.
Now guys see one thing.
Let's check your java knowledge.
Also very basic.
I'm going to write here
request specification.
What about if we just this everywhere
use everywhere no issues are does
no issues are not relatively which
I we have already discussed
this particular tool.
Again it will generate the steps
with the keywords.
One keyword will be everywhere that
simple. You
guys guys did me
for preparing the request
for preparing the request.
What is the keyword I should use here?
Given keyword
dart, I would need header or not race.
I would need header rate.
Make sure make sure what we are doing.
Keep your mind open now we are going
to work on something critical.
See header.
So in header, what is the first thing
that we are going to use?
Contain take rate
students?
We content type is the first header.
Now should that providing
double code content they know
what should happen. Wade
I have to call my
my API constants
API constants not your DO strategy
constant simple API constants dog
I need header content.
I will see header content data.
It says the value is content type.
Fine.
Let's take this content and correct.
Is this correct based
first you need to extend are.
No, we don't need to extend them
simply with using the class reference.
I can use it right
then the value I'm going to provide.
So again,
what is the value of my content type? This
is a static metrics
frame, so
we can directly call these metrics guys.
What is the value of my content? They
again, API constants
DART Dart
content, correct.
Is this correct
application slashed just
and we've already provided
100 API constant.
So from there we are calling this
particular percolate and just every one
by DART.
Another header.
What is the annotated another header
these on transition so again
API constants
dart, I need header authorization.
Is this correct, is this correct header
authorization is
now what is the value?
What is the value of this?
What is the value of token authorization
when your token value rate
or token is coming from here?
And what do we have
any token here in this page?
No, we have to go and
generate token steps.
DART token
dart token right.
We are preparing this request for what?
Creating the employee.
So do we need body or not?
No, we need moderate an X, we need body.
So don't
worry, don't put
now holy point
renewed body rate
in me.
Is this the right approach
that we always provide body
in our main method, in our function
or record this body
from one particular place
we can call the body
from one particular place, right?
So for that
another constraints I'm going to create
and the name of these constants is API
be constants.
Another is a pay below the constants clear
variable one
in constant rate, API preload constant.
So just to make it clear that okay, this
particular constraint classes for payload
constraint and this particular constraint
this for all the variables inability.
Right
right.
That is going to be my point.
Duty one
to constants
class this one for specific node
and one for every single other part. If I
So now now here I'm
going to write a method called public data
and this method will return my string
because I'm going to provide to my body
in the string form and I'm going
to provide my body in the spring form
or so I'm going to create
employ, be,
create, employ, build based
in this method,
I'm going to write the string.
My with
a loop is equals to
the value of my payload, right?
So let me just take the value
of the payload from here.
The body.
So for creating the employee,
I have this particular body.
Can I use this? What is
this?
One more place is there from where
I can get this data,
from where I can get this one place?
Is this one more?
Either I can take it from was to an
or I can take it from
my EPA Bible called swagger
from there.
Also I can do it right.
So our favorite activity go to me.
Christine in Nas Google
gives Google
by now
the money and you'll get back to
and then the middle name is here.
New well in Z model.
No, Mom,
I don't know what is the Genghis Khan
giving it me
by? This should be 1988
radiation with 28 of BAB
is status is employee cloud note
because with this name
a person can only be a google fi
I provided about you guys clear
students.
I provided the moderate
point.
No. Now here
this method is going to return a string.
So what is this string?
It is going to return
create employee preload.
Create employee beta.
Is this clear?
Is this player
everyone first pardon or not?
Any question in this
Anyone?
Any question in this part?
Then simple.
Why did we create a method
instead of a variable?
So if you create variable rate,
you have to call all the variables
one by one, all the variables
you have to call.
But if you create matter,
you call just one method.
The matter will automatically call
all the variables of anyone inside
to great
state.
It's simply like you're asking
why I am writing 1000 lines of code
in one method and can't write thousand
lines of code in a separate part through.
But it is one variable.
Which variable
which we have.
See employ me first name
we didn't name last name date of birth.
We have a job title.
We have employee.
Everything from parameters of our method
for other
is the next step,
which is to me it is coming.
This is the first feature.
Find also the scenario operating state.
This is not the end of this scenario.
This is just the beginning. Great.
And one more thing.
If you're gonna solve
for the explain next point,
you can run your horse and you name them.
You should run
because now you are in the market.
In just one month
you'll be in the market, right?
Your horses are not running
even at this point.
Your horses are baked.
Believe me, you have dead horses.
I see what you mean.
I created employee
build as a single variable.
No, no, no.
I'm talking about the method.
So extend the framework estate. Right.
You're calling the same method,
but in that material, changing the values,
just that.
So that's the only thing.
We are doing it from here. And
now. Now
let's go to our API workflows dead.
And here I'm dead body.
I'm going to provide the data.
So my data is API
workflow, API
build constraints,
dog start employee pay loop,
create employee field, correct.
My heart is converted to it.
That's fine.
It's totally fine.
It would help if you explain
what you are about to do all the way
so that we understand
that you are going to add more code
after we have already defined this part
here, that field.
First, we are going to make a request
creating the employee.
Then we are going to make a Borst call
to create the employee.
Then we are going to get the status quo.
Then we define it,
then we going to get the message and menu
key value to verify and then we will going
to redefine the employee.
So the scope is very clear to everyone.
The scope is very clear
to everyone or not.
So now after this,
we created the service inside this board.
We created steps
inside this particular part in steps.
I am writing the code.
So while writing the code,
when we came across this particular body
here,
I tried to explain that instead of passing
the body as a hard coded,
we get pass the body from somewhere else.
If I provided this particular
API below the constraints
class even before writing the scenario,
you got confused.
Why are we creating this particular class?
Right?
So the moment you are a crossing,
you are coming across the problem
solving the problem.
I am extending the things
which is important,
which is not important Character.
Right?
So when you say it would be helpful
to explain what you are about to do before
doing the things I am telling you
and then I'm doing it.
Guys,
is there any question about the scope,
the vision, the product, the approach
we are going to do, if you please ask?
That's a good question. Simon.
If I mean the question
that if other people
also have this question
correct, Jimi.
Correct.
Do we have to do
because we have seen this part,
if you are rely only on your API
status code, it is not a complete
verification invalidation, right?
Getting my point, Jimi,
because we have seen you,
you got to zero one
but the value was not operating correctly.
You got to double zero,
but value was not operating correctly.
Right.
So if we rely only on the status quo,
the validation, my verification validation
check points, I'm not completed.
My testing is not good grade.
We have to verify that.
Okay, we got this particular point. Fine.
In this body.
Are we getting this piece? Yes.
Against this is are we getting this?
Did the venue? Yes.
Then only I can see it.
My API is populating
correct the data with great response.
Right, Simon, Not clear
what we are going to do.
My intention is to make the things
crystal clear for every
line.
That's why I'm asking, is it clear now?
Otherwise, if I'm teaching and you guys
are not understanding, it is of no use,
it is of no use, There.
So I'm asking guys, please speak up.
It's for me.
Please take
your limit.
Limit. Right.
Intentionally we provide this database
like the Israeli private APIs
like this also so that you will see bugs.
Right.
And if you don't come across these things,
if you don't check this things
indefinitely just to join and things
will come back. Man,
where were you?
My other.
Wow. I've been using my show.
Your horse running do fast.
Multiple classes on weekends.
Amazing
Here, people.
Horses are dying in the class.
And you're taking two classes.
Could you do what you like to do that?
I'm going to
send the picture of your horses to.
All of this is training
so that they can practice the same horses
because they know it's
if third day in this one class
which Brigadier using tell them see
Maria was the first
one was going to buy binaries so now
what other classes.
The post is not good
since that's like in this nuclear weapon.
The third is hyperloop
and the fourth one is it's
import classes
by all
railways.
This this one we created a request rate.
We are preparing the request.
So this is my request.
Is this correct?
Is this correct? PACE
So now now to hit this request,
to hit this request, this time
I have to go in another method.
In another method.
But my this variable is a local variable
or instance.
But can I use this particular request
yet in this method
guys, can I use. No.
So what should I do?
I have to define it on a class level.
Right?
On a class given like this. Correct.
Then.
Now can I use this request here
when dark.
Which color
guys which calls
to create
an employ in the database
which call we need to make
get on put call
when calling amazing
or to call it Come on guys
post one thing forced one find.
So now see related to the API.
Related to the API endpoints.
Do we have any constants
for endpoints?
Do we have anything?
Yes, we do have
API constants. DOT
which one goes
create employ.
You are correct.
Correct.
And from here again
I will use the response.
So this response
I have to be clear on a class level.
On a class level,
I have to use this particular response.
Right?
Because in the next method, in mixed
method, I have to use this response.
So my response I'm going to get in this
particular variable and this variable
now I'm going to use here,
I'm going to use here.
So now guys, don't be forced.
The first thing, if you see
if you see guys, everyone,
when I provide it to zero one,
there it is coming integer
as a parameter or not,
it comes here as a parameter.
It doesn't
it didn't come as an hardcoded value.
One note
Walmart allegedly
now understood.
I knew.
Fine.
So now here I'm going to avoid status.
Could you both get share one system?
You also need to make a response and
request a request and response to stating
why is it so?
And we are using only one class
then by static
to use class level.
I think it should work.
I think this should work.
What do you think it is?
Will it work or not?
This will work nice. Come on.
This will work in the same class.
It will work in same class, right?
It will work definitely. Fine.
So now, see, guys, here, here.
I'm going to change this
name as the status school.
Right.
This value
particular part is a status court.
If you want, you can use the small
one integer as an status code
and then
to verify the status code, what we can do
response Dark
and dark Assert
their status code is your status.
If not, then we can enter static with it.
Nobody.
Yes, but I think this should work.
It will work in this particular part.
Clear everyone. How are we verifying?
So we are not passing the data.
We are not passing the data.
Anything hardcoded. Right.
The data is coming from my scenario
in terms of parameter only.
Next time you just change the parameter,
it will come here and it will change
the parameter automatically.
You just change for double zero.
It will come for double zero.
If you try to do double zero,
it will come to the right.
All right, guys.
So far, so good. Everyone
or any
question, no questions.
Perfect.
If anybody has any questions,
stop me in between also interrupting me.
I want you guys to interrupt me.
No issues.
All all good.
Both.
Now, here we have to really fight
another point that my response body
should contain key
and value should and Randy.
So now you'll see.
Here you'll see here
it says force the string.
First is what is
what is my force to string
T right for the message
basically in the second is
message created that
message created something like this.
Calvin Great.
So now to verify this Bach again,
we will use a response variable
because it contains my older
the value then keyword
for verification assert that
don't assert that DA
Right.
So now here after this assert
what I'm going to write is body right
and the body in the body
I'm seeing the first thing is my message.
Now see, remember this point
hardcoded examples
go here and check this part.
We have already verified this.
Can you see this type of situation
is equal to we are using from which class
guys equal to we are
using from here.
Students
from JD Hand Christa matures
handles dimensions right?
We are using hand Christian matter.
So from there we will use
this particular part called JSON.
So notice of code equal
to equal to
and then the values of values
message
created message communicate.
Why does it import even?
I don't know.
Even I thank you so much and
thank you so much.
I was about to tell this one.
Next point.
I was also trying to check
whether it was in that class or not,
so I was about to tell him that, hey,
please share this.
The menus
it is show given this is very bad.
This doesn't work
automatically by mistake and this is fine.
I need to check everyone's business
rate in the class.
That's
why on this call people here have this
nasty nasty.
The last point I'm the employ and whatever
the parameter is coming,
I'm providing this parameter here.
Right?
So I'm going to write the MP IED. Right.
So this IED is going to be retrieved.
So first I'm going to write
from my response,
not my decent part,
remember, is to retrieve the value.
We will use this apartment
that from this class object right dug
in, which for me am getting my employee.
Remember that they get all employees.
So we were getting all the employees
from their range.
So in which for me there
dream jetstream right.
And here this highly variable rate
I'm going to take.
Fine So now it's this data stream.
So this employed is good,
this is the value employee not employing.
But in this particular spring
we are passing from our speech high
and then we will going to store this part
in one variable.
So we will make we will make this variable
as as global one.
So I'm to write a public spending
spree
like the score by D.
So now this variable,
this variable employ underscore I.D.
is going to store this one, right?
So now this variable becomes global.
One read this variable
becomes the global variable everywhere.
I can use this particular variable
is that clear?
Everywhere I can use this particular
player to everyone
based.
First, have a look at these three points,
these three verification.
Is there any question please
us this school, this is the whole code.
See if there is any question.
Please ask
all clear
of it.
It's good to able to make it performance
right Make it for us.
And first let me print this employer also
so that you guys can see what we got
from final.
So now
I'm going to run this quick.
Now just compare
just compare this particular part guides
with your Selenium execution.
In the Selenium execution, consider
if you have to execute your scenario.
So to execute your scenario first,
you have to open the application.
You have to go to register user
to create user page.
In that page of the calendar data,
really find all the fields, click
on some button, really make the message
how much time it takes.
It does seem time.
If you do the same operation by an API,
how much time it is taking.
This is the employee we got right there.
Token was automatically generated.
So we use the automatically generated
token, right?
We get all these methods positive, right?
You see everything is passed.
Everything is passed.
Case messages this message
and this is employee created
we got correct
mine gives errors.
Okay so
a solution error
to zero one but was for double zero.
Something is a problem
with this particular part
when you are trying
to get this part of boost call method
because it says audibles
you know values generated.
So please check your code.
Same for me.
I haven't got an issue status code.
I got issue with status code.
Right.
Why is it a squad issue?
You got everyone,
my boss.
But it didn't get deployed in the console.
Zimmer, can you please.
Did you write this last line
system got out of print
and an employee? Yes.
Please write it
and then it will get printed.
Whoever got this problem clear,
this is great as you guys.
If this one is not correct,
please check this all our or
check this part create employee.
You are right.
Whether you are using
the correct part or not. Yes.
Then take the barcodes
for what you provided.
The end point there. Right.
This is something you need to check.
Also check this particular part in
and right below it
if you provide something right,
it is not correct because here we are
passing all the majority of time
we are passing get parameterized value.
Right?
So when we are passing, really
we get some mistakes.
Right.
And because of that mistake,
we are having the problem.
How many of you guys
are having the same error?
It works for our next grade.
It works for Zoom also, right?
Lupita, what you do means good one
and what can you share your API
constants, please?
My API constants.
These here. You see this
Zima, you have it start on the end.
But if it works fine, great.
Let me just commit this
so that everyone can go
to the code. Yes.
Good. Has been pushed to the repository.
Please check
while you're suspending
three times the same employee divide.
1920.
Yes, everyone is spending one
in my current mine.
One is also printing one employee
and this is the correct functionality.
It should be just one employee.
I rate three times minus
the negative three times for sure.
Easy to find
and you are making a that confused.
You're confusing what that is,
but that's not thinking like my
is getting one and he is getting three
Einstein rise
and we
so in our jobs
will be forced to execute objectives
To write this one you have to see
and what happens basically is
whenever we work in the application area
right so this API is great
when we talk about API,
this is the most easy part
for developing the API
and the most difficult challenge is there.
The challenging part is to create your UI
because this is a user interface for
training.
So when it comes to user interface,
they always go for changes,
they always change the feeds.
The colors are in so many selections
and using so many scrappy methods, right?
So many technologies.
And then the export database is fine.
You just put the database, you some,
you just dump some building over there
and then you create established link
from database to API.
So now here,
by the time developers are working on
the UI part, right,
it is someone's responsibility.
Check whether their data is that
it is coming from their database or not.
If their data is coming from the database
correctly.
In the end, once you write by visiting,
I will simply integrate these APIs
with my white bar
because it is going to convert this API.
So why can't I check API? As of now?
And then we can integrate it later
with the white, right?
So from UI to API to database,
every single thing is connected.
That's why we call API.
Testing is a really stage test
and it is the
the fastest mode of the city
was developers
with your naked eye is only
you guys can compare data
when we talk about creating an employ.
So here when we are creating an employee
basically
so for creating the employee,
how much time it takes just to say okay,
rate in one to boost
it gives hardly any gender.
It created the token rate, It brings
all the data into the database
and it gives us everything big validation,
basically doing the point with validation.
It provides us everything.
We didn't know time but did the same thing
to talk about using this because it's
how much time it takes for the same thing,
at least more than this.
At least more time than this
particular list.
Character. Not
emit.
What happens.
I'm explaining to you.
All right,
so there is any question, super,
any question, any issue, any confusion,
anything we did
and you didn't understand anything.
I think everyone is busy
fighting the good fight.
Let me give you some time.
You guys can compete
from a spirit standpoint.
Yeah, you can see.
So from Speedtest.net standpoint, great
API is the faster one, right?
To get the details and everything
on UI. Obviously you take time.
It takes, you know,
it gives a lot of upload on to the server.
API is a bit late.
This could lead to an estimate response
for some bytes.
Did you see the size of the body
we were going getting?
It is just in some bites.
It is just in some bytes.
We need to write code for both of them.
And when you write code
then famous for both of them,
it would just a few seconds for more.
8.6 and whenever we write the code,
this is the only time picking activity.
But when you will work
in the actual industry data, you will see
regression, best guesses.
The five were 6 hours, 7 hours.
But execution, they say we go
and we perform night job execution.
What does it mean?
My job execution simply means
when you go out of your office, right?
When you move. All right.
You schedule a job in Jenkins,
You should a job in Dockers
or in some cloud such as DevOps.
So at night from 11:11
p.m., let's say from 11 to morning
six, your test executes
every single test because
when you come
next day to the morning, right, you see
the reports will get out of this 800
cases, 500 feeds, 300 plus something
like this.
No, obviously the API testing
is for checking the connection of data
within the data
is coming from the database or not.
Any other testing is to verify the fields,
the visibility
and visibility user interface.
So these are two different forms of this
data.
We are verifying the data
that we are sending the data fine.
But the is also here and it is it is not.
You wait this thing.
So both are equally important,
but this is administration testing.
So by the time developers
are working on the white whiteboard,
you guys can start working on it.
That is the normal approach
that companies on our is
just produced.
Is this clear to everyone?
That was my question.
One of you. Just two months.
Yeah. Yeah.
I'm afraid we have to
if required, we have to go for database
testing as well every way if needed.
We have to go for that also.
Mostly.
Mostly we perform database
testing like a menu, right?
We go to give their names, dates,
what I have seen in my career.
So let's see what kind of opportunity
you guys will get in future
hundred based.
Now it's time to take completely.
Someone was about to ask before that.
I'm telling you.
Let's take a break.
So now what we are going to do
is we are going to create another example
in which we are going
to define the complete flow.
So the employer we created,
we will use that created
employed for our future purposes, Right?
So first what we will do, we will see how
we retrieve the information
from the database, right.
For the same employee which we created.
And then it's not only will verify
that the employer is correct,
but also the data, right?
The data which we are sending in the body.
We will verify that the data which we have
saved the same data is being populated
into the body
of the created employee using gate client.
And this is what we are going to do now.
Plus we will create the employee.
So we use one particular payload.
Now we are going to perform
a green operation
and here we will verify that the data
which we are getting is the same data
we provided by adding the employee and
let's go ahead and do it now.
So I'm going to write another scenario
here.
Scenario
retrieving
is simply
created, provide the same
on what?
Right.
So now I'm going to write here
this scenario as
in base,
even for data retrieval back
get operation for forget operation
the same background will work on month,
the same background admin, same
particular step will generate the token
and that will be used
in this particular part.
Retrieving recently created in
the same
token, it will work.
Right?
So they're trying and given
a request
is prepared.
Get the client
to use the API upon
using it.
All right.
So then what type of call guys
we are going to make it now,
which is stupid request.
We are going to make get.
So when a gate God is made to
retrieve
the employee,
then first thing what we really find is
what is the first thing we believe?
Then then
the best deepness.
Good for this
created employee For this employee
is 200.
Correct.
That this is the API is just code
we should expect, right?
We should expect this
particular statistical fire.
And like I said, the scope already aims
very right.
So first we will see when I'm
actually getting this data right,
then I'm actually providing
that quality parameter where we are going
to provide this employee ID.
So the body which I'm getting for one
particular employee
in this body,
also I should go to the same employee.
So first thing is, data is populated
against the same employee.
Secondly, the value of data should be same
as what we provided
earlier in the payload, right?
So now I'm going to write here and
the employee
data will be
heavy
saving IED.
So very nasty.
If I go here,
forget one employee
can to see this time
it is returning the object but small.
We employ the object with small.
You can see this.
It does returning this small object
employee object.
So I'm going to write here Employee dot.
Now you see I'm there.
This I'm getting this employee ID
So employee
DOD Employee Correct, Correct.
I mean, this employee
this should match with the
global food
Store Employee
So far, so good.
Everyone
nice.
Fine.
It is just part dignity trade.
And you shall should must do well.
Remember gave you that example
but I didn't give an example of it.
I already get I believe me,
everyone is busy in
writing the code store names
and here, right?
Yes. Mustard
is stronger than short. Right?
And then we embedded
we and there is no point of error
rate.
I will tell you one day like this.
Okay.
But I didn't electric
today I with also
so now here after this
I am going to write in another point and
then the data
victim data and this object
which object employee with small E Right.
This particular object
your second feature please.
Now let me complete my second feature
then only I will bring, then I will.
Then I can write.
Let me completely demonstrate.
I be.
Yeah.
Why you not typing by the end
without my completion?
How would you know that you are having an
I just to get back from break?
No issues so I will give you time.
Could they they would post
employee object. Yes.
Employee object
matches their data
used to create
employee
with employee IED.
Now see what I'm doing here.
I provided that.
Okay, this data should match.
So which data?
Which. Correct. I'm talking about here.
So remember there was a concept called
data table.
How many of you guys
remember this concept of data table?
Right.
Let's take the keys from here
one by one for anybody.
So now see what I will do.
I will go in payload constants right
in this being or the constants from here.
I would first rate this E and B force me
and be forced to.
Then I would need
this in last.
So let's create the new data.
I'm going to end this time.
I shall and
am. And this is the force to me.
I will provide here first name
and then last name.
So let me go here. I will.
Last name is only.
So this would be my doctor
and then I would need
to delete trade.
So this would be my meaning.
And this
I'm going to update here this name or
and this
then gender.
This should be to
the impact to the company.
DC as part of Victims Services
is one of the largest guy of this.
On this planning.
He owns that angel.
Well,
now he owns JC where he owns Landrover.
He owns Ford Motors.
Even now, he now he owns the in India.
Also he is having Tata Consultancy
Services in saving technologies.
Saving Tata Steel needs.
I mean, so many the things
I know
is a big, big company baseball's
largest I.T company entity
in terms of employs the most of employees
if any company has
and it is DC is
and then employee status.
So this is employee
and employee
job title.
They should be to.
If you are doing them regularly created
then why are people different data
are we are going
to get the mode calls together
so next time I'm going to generate
the employee
is I'm going to generate the employee
after completing I will verify.
So to generate new employee,
I'm going to use new data and that's good.
Now I will run both of them together
and the plan is to run both them together.
Understood.
So, Christine, what is the scenario?
What's to be told one scenario right now
in a longer run.
So what would we do?
Do would first clear the employer same.
Then we will retrieve their data
from their database are ready.
But whether the things are working
together or not, quick
scenario
outline means you use example statement.
This is not the examples table.
This is detective was
guys guys.
What is the difference in between examples
dividend deductible
detectable works only for one night.
However,
the examples were for the entire scenario.
Right?
And in data table
we never used the net you examples.
They will be used in any case.
That's
why I'm not writing scenario. Right.
I'm writing synergy.
Is this okay?
All right, let's make some time in grade
because I know
some experiments were delayed,
so let's take time to write this.
Write this in any.
I'm giving you time
That is done
so that anyone was left
with this.
Everyone completed sprints.
Nice. Five minute ago.
You don't need
buttons
right?
So now, now
see what we are going to do up to this.
Simply, we are going to create
first steps for all of this.
Great.
So create the
steps, boss, to let me just change one
and I will go here
and I'll make it just simple.
Brian is equal to
Brian is equal to two.
And then if I run by run
it, it generates all the step,
so don't change a thing.
So I already created the steps.
I changed their data to one place
because I want to clear the steps for one
particular scenario. Right?
So here, if you see
I changed the date for this one,
this one was same already, correct?
No, no, that's fine.
It's totally fine.
So I'm glad
that you are paying attention to this.
So now.
No, here, here we are going to add
the data for this particular.
Right.
So let's determine
what is the first thing?
What is the first thing we have to do
is, for instance, what is the first thing?
We have to prepare the request
so that we can send this request
and hit the end point.
So let's do it.
If request specification do is done
to make us.
But universal
is also running to pass to error.
Nice. Right.
So now let's do this request
is equals to given.
Give me some that I shares on fire.
Jimmy is very cool
given dark
header.
All right.
Now we are writing a request to retrieve
created employee from the array
to protect what we have
produced predates.
Right.
So now here we are going to add
store name.
So what we are going to add here API
not we are going to
you are your ability correct front.
So now here I'm going to add things
from my API constant class.
So the first thing is mine
to be discontinued.
So I've already provided my quantity
in the value.
Also, I'm going to go
from here only so it is mine.
Go content, correct?
Correct.
And there is another header I'm
going to provide
that is another that I'm going to provide.
What is the next database
Authorization API Constant start
header authorization,
comma,
the value of the authorization header.
This what is the value?
It's token.
What whatever
token rate.
And then
since we are going to identify
specific entry into the database,
we said anything
we have to make an API call with
get requests or develop call judgment.
It's query barometer.
It's I'm going to a dot dot query better.
That is what we need equilibrium
with.
First we have to pass the key.
So these employ
now remember this provider,
we talk about employee object
with capital E or we talk about an object
with small E under be just an object.
We are getting this employee i.t
with small E, right?
So when it comes to comparison,
when it comes to edification validation
part with whether we are retrieving
their data or we are creating their data
or we're updating the data,
make sure the key should always be same.
That is small E for employee
and then we have globally stored employee.
For the employee we are creating,
we have normally stored employee activity
variable that
what happened Noel
I'm a non
you'll be to Zima in all cases
Christina's golden is better you lose
oblique starting
spring employee here he had
he had nice so when you guys are here
why you're not speaking I'm going
to commit this code in that it wasn't
doing something right
the focus here on the good
it is in same class right exactly.
So I'm going to write a simple embroidery.
This is the pattern.
We're going to be hit.
We are done with the request
making, linguistic completion.
So now in this particular
variable request,
we had this particular request
which we prepared.
And when
in any environment
which environment you're talking about
utilitarian and
nice, now that's fine, that's fine.
The good elements.
So now the next thing is
we have to have the employee.
Great.
So to hit the endpoint,
we have another variable.
After hitting the end point
for the request we are making,
we get one thing.
What is that
response?
Correct
response equals to request
dart dart which call
get called
and better get going.
We will try it here.
API calls things dart
due to one employee you want to
do methods clear.
There is steps clear to everyone.
I would not say do things get clear.
I mean everyone's is nice.
Is there anyone who has type of confusion
what we are going to do or any scope
related problem, region related issue
that I don't know what we are
doing anything like this
scope is clear, sir.
Great.
Nice.
If anybody has any problem with the scope,
let me know.
I will check. You do person.
I will send you that.
What is the scope
like?
Okay, now, now here.
The next thing is the status code
for these employees.
Again, it sees in DG radio.
See again, it passed the argument so I'm
going to provide it is also status good
status Court Right.
So guys,
we know how to write this response.
Dart Then we use plug verification
and validation point
DART, a third date.
DART status code.
What is the value?
This is the betterment that we can pass
this particular
status.
Is this correct?
Students
Fine.
Now the next thing after status code
is what we are going to evaluate.
Then we
we are checking
the content, including the employee.
Whatever the employee we created,
we got one employee so that employee
and should match with the employee
with the dream from the database.
Right.
So for both the user site
for the same user in one,
the operations one is for creating,
one is for retrieving.
So for creation,
it will be driven by the idea
should we see expected
data versus actual data.
Right. What should be seen point
these type of associates
guys, we did 1 billion times right
in case you were in testing D
so many times we test India session.
We did it between sessions and people.
We did it.
Now we're doing the same thing in API
also is did you guys have any issue?
There is barely begun
right?
Where
is Dennis?
Dennis is typing.
All right.
I again
I'm you gradient enough
nice Dennis I like your attitude.
Great by
the Zuma is just lapping Z by estimates
but you know
very garnishing food and well-maintained
kitchen and everything.
Zuma is famous for that.
A Lexus trying to have a Lexus trying
to get the position of business right.
So the industry comp competition
is going on in the glass
case, taking for by glasses.
Nobody's focusing only on knowledge.
Right.
Alex is trying to capture the disposition.
Yeah. No.
And you're also here. You're smiling.
I know
your job.
You're doing very good.
I'm sorry.
I'm not talking about school nozzle.
First we created employee or not, then
then after creating the employee,
what is the best thing?
The standard that is, is once we are done
with employed the and we have to test.
Yes, the scope is simple logic.
The the strategy.
What we are going to do in the scope,
what we are going to do in this scenario
that is a scope requesting scope.
So first, if we create any employee
knows what we have to do,
we have to retrieve the data, okay,
this is what we have created.
And now after retrieving this particular
data from the database, we have to match
whether this is the same data,
what we lost when creating the employee.
So now, when retrieving the employee
after creating it,
it should reflect the same data.
Isn't it
the correct approach of verification?
Right.
So enforce two scenario in first thing
that what we did, we created the employee.
Now in second scenario, what we are doing
we are simply retrieving the information
from the database for the employee
we created for the employee we created.
So once we are done
with writing this particular scenario here
for three, create the employee
and then we will retrieve the information
and then we provide some verification,
validation, check points trained
right
now. Understood.
Now, scope clearance
of fact.
You're welcome.
Now here today, see what I'm going to do
in order to get one particular
being from the entire responsibility
change
drink.
Are you writing this next
to make me confused?
Two words you type and in both words
you put spelling mistakes
and it's drunk yet and it's know late.
We don't know is testing.
You left the item spelling Alex.
I don't know.
I was thinking each to be honest
even his lap.
Is that all
the right But I'm going to
correct
he is lumping in Ukrainian language
you know this
beat what we know we know nothing.
He knows everything.
Okay, fine.
So now all the Einsteins.
Let's get back to work here.
We have to verify the employ 80.
So the member from the entire object
what we get from the response body.
If we get the body there,
we have multiple entries.
So from those entries,
if I want to retrieve one particular
information, we have to use one
Jason bot method, the member
that is Jason but method
not to get in Deja to get string
get get it right.
Yes got it later
you'll get that capability once
so let me right because it is going
to return one particular employ ID
so my employer is the string type
and writing temporary employee
be here like this and then from my rest
thought I'm seeing using JSON
but I could get string.
What is this pre.
So here let me use this one C,
E and B ied
employ temporary and beat IED.
This one I'm going to use here. Fine.
Now guys, to me,
one is the globally created
employer, globally stored employee
being employed here.
This one
and one is the employee
we are getting in this one right
So do verify
do employee eighties together what we use
assertions
assertions basically not assertions.
So assert doored
assert equals based.
Tell me this assert not assert equals.
You're taking from it
from deed assertions.
Right.
Because the main point
of creating our framework
and integrating API with that framework
is to use the facilities of our framework.
That's what we're doing.
So assert assert equals I'm seeing first
is my temporary employee I.D.
and then my globally created employee.
Right,
right.
This part will be one
scrutinize
despite clear will be or not.
Now now here you see
here you see it sees this particular part.
We need to generate data tables.
We need to generate data table. Right.
So here we are going to provide that data
in the detectible form.
So let's do this.
Let's do this.
How we are going to look initially?
First see, it is asking for how many
barometers, how many arguments the index
raised three arguments.
They forced its
employee object,
employee object.
Which employee object gets
this employee object?
Forgetting one employee.
This employee object is the first one,
then the second one I'm getting
is I'm getting this
response employee I.D.
response, employer.
And the third one is obviously detectible.
So you can provide this data table
like this one.
We simply import this party of data
tables like this,
Right? Like this, guys.
Data tables, simple.
These three things, please.
Straight
is right. District six, Get it.
So now you can understand it, Is it?
Let me remove this part
because we already discussed
these particular things multiple times.
So this
this part
clear to everyone.
If anybody has any question
in these three,
go to your feature file, you'll see
this is the
first employee object
we are talking about.
This is the employee ID we're
talking about, and this is their data.
People talking about.
This is their detective
that we are talking about right.
So one thing is this,
second thing is this.
And third thing is this.
Now, if you go here,
this is the object with small
E, this is the employee ADP are getting
and this is their data table.
We have generically right.
Is this clear?
No enemy from their data table.
By looking at this particular data table
in which form it is returning the value.
What type is this
maps conflict Eleanor
kind of data table gives error rate.
How soon do you change
it to this part? What I said,
did you change it
to like this?
I see.
Yes I did. I need to give that. All right.
And please check this particular part.
Are you using this input?
Can you please this input?
I ordered Googlebot not detected.
We don't get to be detected, but
please check this.
Also can x
someone will see give me some fire.
I would see Alexa is on fire
too much.
It it would be nice to get it
all right.
I think everyone now
wait for the leash.
Look, key item ultimately
are you guys are going to get this
Is it
is it?
Let me stop the recording for a moment.
Or is the. No,
no here.
See guys, at this point of time
when we are seeing the detected burn rate,
it is returning the maps, my maps
because firstname is the key
and the value we are pointing associated
to this particular key.
Right.
So whenever we talk about the requirement
that is returning key
and value bear,
we always consider these as
best maps, right?
And our detective will always ask that
this being our detective
will always ask what it ask it to ask.
You want this detective
to convert the values as mysteries.
Remember this case
we Bosner data from Excel file
so they're generating their data
the function right
converted maps right away
all the maps
one by one into the list rate.
But to compare by default
provide this parking meter.
But so here I'm going to write
my detective a dot
as it says list or maps on the IS maps
is maps
where my first value would be string.
It means my key would be history
and my value would also be street.
And this part, this part
I'm going to add in the list of maps,
so I'm going to write first
under the list.
That is a map and in this map
I'm going to provide a three
comma spring.
This is my
instability data
map of list with key.
And then now tell me,
guys, district is coming from where
this particular data is coming from here.
This line expected data
from a feature available right.
From what we find
now see what we are doing.
Expect predictability great feature.
But to compare this data,
we have to get another day.
It is coming from
what input should be used for list.
It is jolly good. It's simple.
This one would be great for map w would be
why we are doing a list of maps.
Find.
So right now
we are passing
the data like this in data table.
Right. This is my first name.
This is my middle name.
This is my last name.
This is my blood up.
So many things. Right?
And these are the values I getting
correct assignment.
What is this first name or the level last?
Then what is this
key and what is this here?
What are the value?
So when it returns together,
key and value,
what it makes, map.
So when you are getting the map,
it is having your key and value.
But if you have another value in future
to five legacy,
you're getting two employees.
Then one is returning one map,
another is returning another map,
another is returning, another maps.
Right?
So you have convert your data table first
as maps because it is returning the maps
and the one one draw
will returning one map.
Multiple rows
will be returning multiple maps.
So you have created a list of maps.
You have to create a list of maps.
But since it is an online,
you can only have one set of data.
So it could always be a map. No, no.
So right now,
the requirement defining the requirement,
which we are using
it is the smallest in any,
but we are talking
about the global scenario. Right?
So are getting from a bigger perspective
in real life examples,
when you go there,
you have to come up with an approach where
you can do this things in a batch right?
For the batch
kind of scenarios I'm going to put.
All right,
this is for one.
Since if we
do for multiple employees here,
we won't be having enough time to do that.
But that's why we are doing this.
We'll give you high level scenarios
that are low level information
will always be covered inside this.
Okay.
No, no, guys. Next thing.
Next thing,
I hope that this will break
What I'm seeing.
Noble Are you
know, was not yet in the class
gates Come on here
but right findable
so now it is
it is just kind of wakeup call
for all the alerts so they must know okay
you can call me on So
nuance is how it means
no one wants me to control.
It's great.
After 2 minutes, I'll check with it.
What is it in the class and not
I'm feeding my baby.
All right, all the best.
No, no, but.
All right,
so now, now for the actual data.
For the actual data,
what I'm going to do is see
in actually, like, here, make
I'm going to write from my response.
Dark body
in the body I will go in JSON.
But and from here I see get
simply get the object so which object
I'm going to employ object and this object
does this particular object
I'm here till the end of the session.
What is all right?
But my responsibility is to check
whether everyone is here or not.
Read them or not.
But see, it was a quick check.
I All right.
If you saw it getting out one
now, everyone
must be relieved
by being great great response them they
bindings.
So now see this particular employee object
grade this particular employee object.
If you see this is the employee object,
it is returning.
What goes in the body
of this employee object we are getting.
What?
Tell me
It's true.
This employee object is returning meet
all these keys and values are not
on. Read all this.
It is a map.
It is just a map.
This is not a list of maps
you guys remember.
This is one object. Come on.
This is one particular object. Right?
So these are keys and values.
These are keys and values.
That's not just with my bad guys, my back.
No issues. There is.
I understood
if multiple object, then list of maps.
Yes, I share one object.
Remember what we rate.
Map streaming is free and it is equal
to new hash or link dash with.
Great.
So how many object
which going to have just one for map?
And then we use map
and then we can provide any number of keys
and values together.
Jordan is I'm glad I'm glad you are here.
You're covered in nice I will come to you
is a great partner in crimes
so we can have multiple keys
and values in one object.
Right.
But if we have multiple objects, then
we can see only one object is returning.
One meant to object.
So returning to maps there,
we need to use documents.
Here it is getting just one as of now
according to the requirements.
But forget all employs in that community
list of maps right here.
We don't need just one.
So I'm going to get a map here.
So let me write a map.
In both keys and values
voters string on our index
keys, and then there's border string.
So I'm going to write here, This is mine.
I data.
This is my actually current
wrong place
or my
focus is gradient
focus.
Yeah, I got that.
I got Lukas studying school.
Fine.
So now, now see expected data.
Actually data.
But in actual data, remember
this particular part of map, right.
It really does key.
But when you add the one thing,
what is this one given value
means one being and one pair
means one set of values going to
that is one D, one value.
It means one belt, one permits
one set of building.
Right.
So how we read c
e and I'm going to write what
I am going to write
here for loop advanced for loop actually.
Right.
These are the ones for loop,
but it's a single class.
Again, please.
This one, this one,
because that's the default format
we use in data table.
Indestructible.
Now, I think I should,
I should explain to these particles to see
in math
if we write my break and value
add water is great
and is equal to the new
hash map, write something like evenly.
So here we write, for example,
and the output
we provide one key and one value, right?
Similarly And don't
put so many other things right now.
Who triggers these values?
What would happen here
in my detected Well, first,
because returning name in the value
it is not returning all the things
one by one,
but employ object
is having all these values together.
So I have to retrieve one key,
one value into one thing.
So to retrieve from five values
one by one, what I have to do,
I have to use for each loop even,
but advanced for loop.
So what these are the ones for loop
does from these multiple values.
It returns one value here
will compare this one value it is passed
will go to the counter and so on.
And let's put this
underscore
this.
I understood this method.
Nice.
So now here I'm going to write for my math
on my math,
which is having supreme comma string.
I'm going to use one key at one time.
We call it singular math.
And the value is coming
from my expected data.
From my expected data.
Right.
So they tell me one thing.
If I write this method,
he said, Why we use this key search
method, why
we use search method
once this year to get the key in value
as a sake.
Both candidates value out others
who a set of keys.
Right?
So I am seeing I am saying,
hey, I'm going to provide a set here
and in this scene
going to provide this name is the key
is name is key
important as a suit
anyone knows why embroider said
there is
any idea why I am providing said
because every single key
should provide a unique value.
If I provide a list, list
allows duplicates
but state never allows duplicate.
Right?
So we need set here
so we can avoid all the duplication.
We always get unique keys.
Amazing it or not.
Good job.
Good job. It was a minor one.
Good one.
No one was welcome.
Fine.
So we proceed for this.
Williams
Now from these keys not emigres
here here in this part
I should say keys from this map keys.
They're great.
I'm getting all the keys
here in the form of set.
So I'm having false
name with the name last name.
Every single thing available.
Every single thing available. Right.
I'm Going to right.
I am going to play this. I need 42
again, 42 bananas.
The string
key will be getting from the keys.
From the keys.
Now why is this to place
another for each loop?
What is the reason behind this?
Why another for each loops
tremendous. Why?
And then for each loop.
Who gave each key to blue
to look through the keys.
To traverse the key.
To isolate the key one by one.
To look through the key player.
So one key we will get one time.
Let's go ahead.
So I'm going to read first
Exit data value is equal to unseen map.
Don't get
map, don't get the key.
I'm going to
this clear
this part.
Clear.
This one is returning me
the map from that map, whatever the key
I'm getting and providing it here
from your Java concept
and string, I would see here
for my
bottom line actual value.
I'm going to write it
to do the right door and
expected value in actual value.
Looping all the keys
and finding my data. Yes.
Yes. Correct.
So now here there is when I'm having
expected value in actual value board.
So from here,
if I want to compare two things together
from J, you need what we have to use.
Again, assert, not
assert equals.
It should say expected value.
Gamma actually
expected comma actually value player
here this part of
outside the loop I'm going to write here
my another string
I notice frame called e and B ideas
equals to I'm going to provide my response
dark body
and from the body
I can get decent but dark from the
I get string in this string I'm
seeing from the response employ 80
response employ 80,
which is again, I'm going to provide a
equals to this employ 80
which I'm getting from here
to my global employer,
even though we have completed
this particular part earlier also.
Right.
We are again,
we defined it just for satisfaction
flagging any question in this podcast.
The main question is this expansion.
Clearly we want
it's possible for you
to give somehow to play with it.
Yeah, definitely.
I will give you the task today.
I will give you the task. Everyone.
Yes. I mean, is there, like you
said, the columns
column.
No. First
rendering the again values together.
Right.
And from that map only,
can you show your code for one second?
Sure. As they will.
This is the code.
And see this.
You see this is the code
on rank.
It is going to means
identical questions.
I want to be honest.
You mean to see this particular piece?
This one You are meaning?
Simon, Remember one thing
when we talk about this key
like language and only use this part
when you get a map.
Right?
See, we cannot change the structure
for us to.
Right. So we are getting a map.
So in map
we have find a way through region.
You can get one specific entity.
So what does the second we're using this
classic method,
we are using this to set out
one particular element.
Right.
Which is already having in the map. Right.
So which contains Indian hash map
or any other map.
If I want to get only one particular part
from there, we have to use key set.
Correct.
So that is the actual approach
we have to follow when we come across
any map since we are passing their data
in a key and the loop here
and we're getting the grid also performing
that is map.
So there we have to use keys to be
played.
And you say there's not
the column is it is basically a matter
which we generally use
to create a stick place.
If you if you go to the job,
if you revise the Java
you would see a key segment
that is used to identify
one particular component
from your complete the map,
right?
Fine. So let's run in this park.
Let's run this.
Let's see. Fine.
So now you see it says expected
and it got a unit mail.
Nice.
Can you see this?
It says expected aim.
And it got actually me right.
So remember here, if you see
if you see here when you provide here
when you provide here
something in your create employee bar.
Right.
Is an F it provides here as in female.
You see it
provides yet as female. Correct.
Okay.
Correct.
So when you go here, when you go here
in your claim, what do you have to do
anyways?
What do you have to do
in order to make it possible?
Do you have to provide the
in studio and be able to place me
right.
It's been changed to me.
I already changed.
And then
let's run an API now.
This time it's running.
So now again,
it is going to generate a new token again,
it is going to generate a new employee
and again
it is going to get the new employee
only right
and it will compare their data against
with the employee.
So now see it is past
now, so it is positive.
Now let's read this console closely.
Let's read the console closely.
You'll see this is the employee
ID generated during the first date.
We generated this particular token
after reading the token added the employee
right after adding the employee,
we got this particular employee
and we have to put different
you know, we don't have the same data.
We look for one
simply to work measures.
So now here this employee,
it is stored as a global variable.
Now if you go here,
it says your status could be 200.
You got every single thing right
and it compares the values correct.
So see both values
equal make keys are equals.
You're getting the data are
equal is status code is 200.
Everything is fine.
That's why I would ask,
is this a lost associates are clear.
Is this clear to everyone?
Now the first thing I should do is
I should come with this code.
Gold has been pushed to the repository
now was to me.
How was the session? To me?
Wasn't clear.
Yes, I'm in.
Please ask another question.
Should a soft assert.
Oh, soft assert We use in testing due date
in the unit.
I never used.
We never used a sample despite
we never said so.
We are using the unique part. Right?
So here we don't use officer
for use on the assert.
It falls to them first.
And what go to second that is hard assert
soft assert
allows you to execute your code.
The last line right in the last line
that is the hard soft assert.
So here what we are using this is not
supposed to be this hard assert since.
It is a two different places. Right?
I must get 400 of these.
Check your point rate.
The one you expected is clear. Does good.
Check your get check.
You'll get called.
Then you will find the mistake
and you'll get Alex.
Whatever the endpoint
you're passing, check that you will find
the mistake there on. All
right on
grade checker API constant.
If we add more than one employee,
should we add that imprint constant again
to yes for more than one employee
of the multiple concentrate
if he had more than one employee.
Yes. Correct. In AP workflow steps.
No. Alex, in your constant
supposed to check the bot from here.
This particular part right?
Then whether you're calling this same key
in your call or not,
then going to your methods in your steps
right inside systems,
check this particular portion
because you're getting the added
here, 400 400 means bad request, right?
It means it is not identifying
the material on it.
So check this part.
Take your this part and check this mistake
is here in this truly is check this to
show your features.
I'll be sure my day.
This is my feature.
Alex understood what I'm saying.
Mistake is in the status. Good.
It means you're not getting 200.
You're waiting for night.
So 400 is more than 400
is the bad request.
Bad request
means you're trying to access something
which is not the industry
is not understanding your mistake.
So you request so good there. Jake.
What is the problem is with your request
and there you will find the error.
Yeah.
Still, if you if there's any problem,
then do let me know.
Okay.
All right, guys.
So I think I'm done from my side
for today's class.
If you guys are done
with your questions, then
when we begin decomposition. No.
Thank you so much, everyone.
Guys,
thank you so much. Thank you, everyone.