Going.
Welcome to another day, another class.
What's going on, everyone
that started it. Yes.
Yeah.
I don't know why your badge comes
a little bit late to collect it.
Who is missing?
A lot of people.
See, I am doing well, guys.
Um, we've been working all day.
Absolutely.
I'm sure it's, you know, people who are
who are managing this course
after getting a 9 to 5 hour jobs.
You know, props to you.
Just hang in there, okay?
There's going to be time.
We'll go by very fast.
So you all, we all know what you look.
You're only on your second week,
so just hang in there.
And for some of you,
I know our international students.
I don't know how you're doing it,
but keep going.
I know it's.
It's a struggle at this point, though,
but it will pay off. I know.
It's probably
I know we have some students here.
They agree one in 4 a.m..
Okay.
You have to change your thing.
But remember, short time,
just a very short time and then
you'll be good to go with this once
everything is over.
2 a.m. for you.
I like sit here. Shoot.
Muhammed class has started.
You films?
Yes, I am right there.
I'm just waiting for everyone
to jump on us because I have a few things
since today is Will.
Technically,
yesterday was my last class with you guys.
I don't know if I told you
I didn't have a chance to shoot
because there were some issues
with some things.
But anyway, we'll get to that.
By the way,
how was how was how is the project?
I see a lot of you guys
did did the videos.
I think maybe some of them are missing.
But I think overall, I'm waiting on
maybe one or two more.
But it was awesome.
It was cool, right? It was. It was nice.
It was fun.
It was fun with all your members.
You got to see them.
So it was
we wanted the whole purpose behind it
was that, you know,
you guys get out of your comfort zone
because you know this everything
when you're online, you know,
it gets a little bit challenging
to meet people and things like that.
The whole purpose of it is just to get you
out of their comfort zone
at the same time, make you speak about it,
you know, talk about it.
You know, the ideas
might take some time to gel through
and hopefully glad
and I made all the so far
I think I made all the the class,
the recordings visible to everyone.
So you guys can you guys can check it out.
It was nice.
I saw some very cool ones
out there so far.
I think you guys are doing really well
on that.
Your your group is amazing.
There you go, guys.
That's how you started, you know,
wanting to break that,
you know, that that barrier.
Or you can say, you know, I ice breaker
for you guys later on you guys
can basically do this with each other
studying and things like that.
It was really hard without practice.
See, we are forcing you
into that practice. So.
Mammoth. Yeah,
you probably were in, I guess.
Is he?
I hope he can hear us,
but I mean, you went to the other class
or debug team is amazing.
I saw some of you guys
come up with a name, but a lot of you
still didn't come up with a name
for yourself, for your team.
But I guess I did.
Look at my my, you're in the right area.
Okay, so guys, really good job on the
on that name in the sense of
if you wanted to give a
a team project name or anything
for yourself if you guys came up with
I know some of you did it,
some of you did it, but it's
okay if you submitted already.
Don't worry too much.
Remember, we might do flip grids
and more projects in the future.
There will be a lot more for you guys.
This just the second would be great.
So we'll have a lot of times and you guys
will also be working with group members.
You'll get to know each other.
You know, by the way,
the members that you met
probably yesterday, the first time
you guys can do session with each other,
a group session come up with a time where
you guys can study together, anything like
that, you know, absolutely work. So
definitely do it, you know, try to do it
at times.
You know, someone might understand
the concept a little bit better
than someone, but then yourself jump
on a group, call basically a zoom one on.
And yeah, that's a good way
to do a practice actually.
So really good job, by the way.
I see a lot of you did, and I think
there's a couple missing at this point.
So if you did not is better.
Exactly.
Catalina, you learn better
when you can explain to someone.
That means the ideas are more clear
and this agile, this
and that, you know, this is basic theory,
but it's very important.
That's where we put an emphasis,
especially on the agile side,
you know, making sure that you get it
because you'll be working
in this environment,
majority of you will be working there.
So it was it was a good exposure to that.
So I'm glad that you guys enjoyed it.
I'm going to look at
I haven't looked at all of them.
I looked at majority of them, but
some of them, I'm going to look into them
and if there's any comments,
I'll leave them.
But very good practice.
I really enjoyed it.
I always like seeing, you know, the students interacting with each other, you know,
correcting each other in a
it's a good way to, you know, communicate
and bond as well, too.
Because remember, you guys
are going to be here for six months.
Are we going to start automation today?
Absolutely not.
You know, let a year, a month delay
for creation today, you guys are going
to get started into manual testing.
You will get into manual test.
The automation is a little bit far ahead
for you guys, maybe a little bit from now.
Today.
Basically, we have yeah, you going
to get into the stealthy part of it
and I won't be teaching you guys.
We're taking over.
I call him the King and Mr. Diego.
He's going to be taking over.
Actually, he's an awesome instructor.
He actually worked
on the mental testing part,
created a lot of these slides
and everything for you guys improved it.
So he's going to actually take over Diego
and then you can turn on your video
if you are able to do so.
But yeah, he's
the one going to be taking over for me.
By the way,
tomorrow is your first review class.
So I know last week, you know,
because the missus, Sal,
she wasn't able to join, but
because her she got sick,
we only went over one class.
But tomorrow's class.
Another instructor
Who will do your review, Mr.
Asger, he's
going to be basically joining tomorrow
to do your first review
of the first class.
So make sure you join that since
little bit extra practice for you guys.
And then, yeah,
you guys are going to be good.
Is she feeling better?
Yes, she is feeling better,
but she did get COVID,
so she's recovering at this point.
So that's why no one expected it.
But it happens, you know,
but she's definitely feeling a lot better.
So hopefully she will either join you this
weekend or the following one.
It is crazy, right?
You never know.
So. That's right.
So that's really about it, guys.
As far as myself, guys, I know I only had
a very short time with you guys.
Only taught you guys, what, three classes.
More like two classes.
Yesterday was more practice.
But, guys, I'll be here.
I know you guys.
Majority of you will forget me.
It happens all the time.
I usually come in the beginning
and then I go away and then I come back
towards the end and interviews
and I basically join you guys.
I'll try to motivate you in between.
I'll try to come in, motivate you
because it does happen, you know?
But it was he again.
Who was he again?
You mean Diego.
He's going to be your new instructor.
I, I used to teach a lot more before, but,
you know, I have awesome team members.
You know, they do a better job
since, you know,
I could absolutely teach you guys
some of this material.
But, you know, I haven't been outside
of the corporate field for some time.
It's not fair
for me to teach you something that's not
so irrelevant in my mind at this point.
You know, that's why we have Mr. Diego.
He's going to take over.
And since he is,
Diego will give you explanation
and he has background, you know, he
he manages a lot of teams.
A lot of people work under him.
So this guy knows what he's doing.
Are you retired? I'm technically retired.
You can say this, but I'll join
you guys towards the end in interviews
and in between guys, thank you.
Thank you so much. Not plenty to be here.
Time to time.
I do see everything, even
though you might not see me interact much.
But throughout the course you will see me.
Absolutely.
And you guys can always message me.
I love talking to you guys.
I wish we had something in person so
I could see you guys, but you never know.
Maybe you will figure something out
and we'll see you guys.
Can we DM you with questions?
Absolutely. Did me with questions.
This related stuff.
If it's related,
please do it out there for that.
And it's a long topic.
I used to, but I'll be happy
to answer your questions.
Absolutely.
Come to Buffalo.
It's a little too
cold, but I would definitely
know you
absolutely all will survive to me.
So guys, thanks again.
I'll basically sign up from my side
and Diego
he'll give you a introduction
and he will start the class with you guys.
All right, guys, take care
and I'll see you in between.
Sometimes.
High tech.
Our guys. Diego, you take care.
But you got this answer.
All right, man.
Thanks.
Let's see. Let's see.
Let's see. It's
all right, guys.
I'm showing my screen. Can you.
Can you guys hear me?
Can you guys see me?
Can you guys see my screen?
Yeah.
Let's see.
Who do we have today?
It's my first class, so I'm going to.
I. I start to get to know
some of you guys.
Nice to meet you. How's.
How's the class so far, guys?
How's everything? I was.
How was your first week?
Good, good, good, good,
good, good, good.
All right, good, good.
Well, it's awesome.
I see a lot of positive feedback,
so that. That's great.
So far, so good.
All right, Perfect.
Let's see. It is 713.
Okay.
I believe we have most people online, too.
Minor says so much fun.
Let's try to keep it that way.
Okay. Let's try to keep it that way.
Let's say.
All right, guys.
So let's see who else is here.
All right, guys. Perfect.
Okay, So are you guys ready
or you guys ready
today?
Like, the real class starts.
The real stuff starts today.
Are you ready?
Ready, Ready, Prepared, motivated.
Jeremy, what's up, man?
How are you? Good. Sarah.
I didn't know you were taking the class.
What's up, bro? Are you?
That's cool.
Well, yeah.
Let's touch.
Let's touch base later.
That's awesome, man.
All right, guys, let's get started. Right.
Let's see.
Alexis is also here, right, Alexis?
It's time for him.
What's up, Alexis?
How are you? Congrats on Congrats on your
eye, on your newborn and stuff.
I hope that's going
well. Good, good, good.
All right.
So, guys, let's
let's get started.
Okay.
All right.
So today
we start our first official testing class.
We're going to be talking about manual
testing
really for the next
for the next month or so, kind of like
maybe a month in a week and stuff.
We're going to be covering
very important concepts,
fundamentals of testing everything.
And I suggest you pay
very close attention to these classes
because,
you know,
I know that later throughout the course,
you're going to be learning Java,
you're going to be learning different
test automation tools
and everything like that.
But if you really nailed this classes
guys, you can actually retain
in of knowledge to go in the market
and get a good paying job.
Okay.
Today automation is really big,
but manual testing
is still also very important
and there's a lot of manual testing roles.
Opportunities
are still available. Okay, So
even though you're going to
be very technical, you're going to learn
your Java, your selenium.
Yes, the classes is recording.
You're going to be joining your
your selenium,
your your Java and other tools.
At the end of the day,
you're going to be a tester.
So in this next month, we're going
to learn the fundamentals of testing
and how to be a good tester.
It's recording on my end.
You guys see this right here or you guys
can see it, but it's it's recording, okay.
It's recording code.
All right, So let's get started.
All right.
So today we have we're going to discuss
pools of manual testing.
Like what is testing?
Why we test and that kind of thing. Okay.
I'll ask you some questions
and we're going to try to see
how how analytical
we can think about things.
Okay. So perfect.
So the question is,
why do we test,
like, in general, like,
why do we test anything?
You know, like basically anything
doesn't have to be software.
Like, for example,
like when, let's say a BMW,
they're about to make a new car, right?
Do you think they just make it
and then they just sell it?
Or do you think that they have to test it?
And when they tested, they have to test it
for many things, right?
Like there's so much out that tested.
Where have you guys ever seen those videos
where where they're kind of
crashing cars on purpose
to see how the impact is and everything.
Have you seen those videos before?
Right.
So that's one type of testing, right?
For those kind of cars.
The test, the security, the the how good
the security features are of that car.
Right. The safety features. Exactly.
And it's lot of the same thing
with anything that is being
developed
or produced or anything like that.
Right.
You check the quality,
make sure it meets expectations.
We're going to talk about bugs
and what they are.
Okay and how we can identify bugs.
We also test to reduce the risk of error
and to continually improve the product
overall.
Okay.
Now we're going to be talking about
software testing in general software.
What is a software based
what is software? You guys know,
what is what is software?
Someone says programs
like feel free to Google as well,
but I'd like for you
to put in your own words
like what do you think software is?
Go Someone says an application
and that's okay.
That type of someone says a soul.
What? What does that mean?
Machine readable code.
Okay.
Okay. Okay.
So I see you guys are kind of like
given some similar answers, right?
Is the Instagram app a type of software?
Okay, what about the Facebook app?
Is it a type of software to.
Okay, what about the
the the calculator on your phone?
How about that one?
It is it is a type of software, right?
Okay. Very, very good.
Okay. So
we need to test software.
When we talk about software,
we're talking about like applications
in general, wherever there is software
development going on,
there's always going to be testers needed.
For example,
you know, Facebook, Google, Amazon,
really any company
and any vendor that has applications,
these applications are developed
and they have to be tested.
And let's think about this, this testing
end for these applications or not.
Like, for example, the Amazon develop
their application to just be like that.
And like that said, never change.
Or do they always keep changing things?
Do they introduce new futures? Right.
Do do they change?
You know,
they have to keep updating stuff, right.
So along with that,
there needs to be testing.
Okay. And testing.
And I'll tell you what type of testing
we're going to do and everything like that
and so forth.
Okay.
Is it living software always changing
things are always changing.
Right? Exactly.
So let's talk about quality,
because when you apply for a jobs,
you're going to see the work quality.
A lot.
The rules are going to be called Q8
testing
or Q8 testers
or quality assurance engineers.
Quality assurance
for for quality assurance.
So so what is what is quality?
You know, and here's the
the dictionary definition on the screen
the standard of something as measured
against other things of a similar kind.
But when we talk about quality,
quality is really subjective, right?
For example, a good quality for
you may not be good quality
for for me, you know what I mean?
It just it just depends.
And we're going to talk about that
when we talk more about requirements
and how we know that there's
there's quality and so forth.
Okay.
Our main goal
as a tester, as a testers to make
better products
by trying to know
what makes the end user more excited.
Okay.
And when we say more excited,
we mean like, just have them
have them have a a better user experience.
For example,
if you have to go on your bank's website
to make your credit card payment,
you're probably not going to be excited
about that, right?
You have to make a payment
like that.
Doesn't sound so exciting,
but at the same time
they need to develop that application
and make it accessible for you
so that you can easily,
so that you can easily, you know, use it.
Right.
For example, let's say that you're
trying to make a payments, okay,
whatever bank
you have, the Wells Fargo, Navy, Federal,
you name it, and you can't make a payment
like something's wrong.
Like you're you're adding to the balance
that you want to pay
and then you click the paint up.
And for some reason the pay number
and it's not working
like it's just not working.
You restarted your phone,
you uninstall the app, you install it
again, it's just not working
and you can't make the payments, right?
How would your experience be
at that point of view?
It's going to be frustrating, right?
Let's say it's
let's say you had the deadline and and
you know that if you don't make a payment,
they're going to charge you
a late fee, right?
So you're going to get stressed out,
you're going to get called,
you know, you're going to get charge
a late fee,
probably you're going to have to call
and explain to them that you should,
you know, and so forth.
So this is
this is why we test application.
So it's not always for applications
that are going to make you excited.
Excited, right.
Like no one's ever
excited to make their car payments or
or I mean, maybe you do get excited.
I don't get excited personally.
I don't know if anyone here gets excited
to make any sort of payments, but,
you know, you want your experience
to to be like at least pleasant.
Right. And that's their responsibility.
But then we have other applications,
right?
Like who likes going on
Amazon and buying stuff?
You know,
who likes going
on, on, you know, on anything, on, on, on
like websites like experience
of look flights or what else.
What are the websites you guys visit
that were you guys purchase something
that that kind of makes you excited
there's Amazon there's
there's like you know
oh okay crypto Coinbase
yeah everyone says Amazon Okay
eBay, Alibaba.
That's fine syntax. Right.
Okay. Very, very good.
Right.
And it's not always like purchasing.
It's always like sometimes applications
can be there to provide more information
to you, right?
Like, let's say you're doing some research
and something is broken.
You click on a link and when you click on
a has anyone ever clicked on a link?
And then it takes it to a page
and it just doesn't work.
Like you get an RSS. Like
this page
is not not found kind of thing, you know.
So that happens to. Right?
And it can be important information.
Okay, So what is software testing?
Right. We talked about this.
Okay.
When we talk about
software testing in the projects
that you'll be working in for whatever
company, whichever company you work for,
you really test to make sure that
that that
that whatever is being developed
meets the business requirements.
And I'll tell you about what that is.
Okay.
And that everything is working
as expected.
Okay.
For example,
let's say you work for Google, right?
And as you can see, my screen here,
if you look at my screen,
right,
this is Google, Google, Google slides.
Right.
Let's say
that this is currently in development
and and the
Google says, hey, we would like this
common history button
to have four lines, right?
But the developers develop it
and it has three lines.
Is that a bug or not?
Do you think that would be a bug or not?
Right.
Does that you don't think it's a bug?
Who says it's a bug
and who says it's not processed? Who?
Who says it's a bug and who's it is not?
So we say some.
Some. Yes, some.
Now, okay,
I'm going to repeat the question.
Google is the client.
Google is the company
that is paying you and your team.
Right.
And they're telling you
that they want a button
that has four lines,
but you give them a button
that has three lines.
It works perfectly. When you click it,
you can see the comment history.
It works fine,
but is that what they want it
When you go when you go to a restaurant
and you order like whatever,
like, let's say a burger with no lettuce
and they bring you a lettuce,
they bring you a burger with lettuce,
Are you going to be okay with it?
Right.
You're not right,
but the burger is still good.
So are you going to be okay with it?
It's still exactly right.
So even though it's working
right,
would you consider this a bug or not?
Yes, it would be considered a bug, right?
Because that is not what Google wanted.
And it's your job to test
to make sure that
what's been developed
meets the business requirements.
And in this case, the business requirement
was to create a button with lines
instead of three.
Does that make sense to everyone?
Does that make sense?
Okay, perfect. So this is what we mean.
And that's just a very small example of
of of
of of a business requirement
that you may experience in the workplace.
Okay. You also have to make sure that
that the application is, you know,
it is smooth.
Okay.
For example, let's say you're logging into
to Amazon, okay, let's say
you're logging into Amazon,
and when you're an Amazon,
you're adding things to the cart, right?
But when you're adding an item
to the cart,
you notice
that it's taking a long time to load.
Okay. And
you know,
that's taking a long time to load.
Like maybe it's adding maybe it's
taking like a minute to add to the cart.
Right?
And as a user,
you don't know, you probably think
that your network isn't working.
You probably think that your Wi-Fi
is not working out good connection
and you're on your phone on Amazon
and you keep hitting, you keep
pressing the add to cart button, right?
And you keep pressing,
you keep pressing, pressing, pressing it.
And then after a minute
it says add it to cart.
But when you go to the cart, you notice
that every single time you press
the button, you actually added an item
to the cart and your cart, let's say.
So it has like 30 items after that.
Would you consider that a bug?
Let's see.
You said a bug,
but a bug is not related to functionality.
This is more
no bugs are related to functionality.
So the type of testing you will be doing
or the type of testing you'll be doing.
Catalina is is is functional testing.
Okay.
That's the kind of testing
are you going to be doing?
Is that does that make sense?
Catalina
And we'll
talk we'll talk more about that too.
Okay.
Yeah. So it's a it's a functionality.
And the type of testing you'll be doing
is its functions
as it's going to make sense in a bit.
But you got to test those things, right?
It's considered a bug, right.
So can you give me an example now
that we've talked about a couple of bugs,
Give me an example of a bug.
You give me an example of of a bug.
Like just anything like
imagine any application you've used.
Give me an example. Facebook crashing.
But that's a that's a big bug, right?
Not being able to log in.
That's a that's a huge bug. Right.
It's a huge bug emails sending emails.
Okay. That's good.
You can check out.
There you go.
That's a that's a big bug, right?
Accepting wrong passwords
so like option but goes to different pages
can enter username right a software
software bug is narrow for a computer.
So tell me give me more examples.
You guys are mentioning great examples.
And and based on these answers,
a lot of your answers relate to each other
somehow.
Can anyone guess
how it's related to each other?
Like based on a lot of your answers,
they all relate to kind of like one topic,
right?
What?
What do you think that can upload photo?
Okay.
Doesn't print when you press print one.
Right. Coding errors.
Okay.
End users not happy
having issues that are meta requirements.
Okay, that's fine.
So really
you didn't notice a lot of your answers.
They have to do with, for example,
not being able to log in, not being able
to check out, not being able
to make payment right there.
They all have to be somewhat related
and tied to money.
Right.
If you cannot buy something on Amazon
because you just can't buy anything,
like it's not letting you buy anything.
And let's say it's like that for an hour.
How much money is Amazon
going to lose in one hour?
Can someone take the time to Google
right now?
How much Google make I mean,
how much Amazon makes in one hour, Right.
And let me know how much that is. Right.
So this is why they take their testing
very seriously.
Right?
Same thing with making payments.
Right.
If you need to make a payment to your
if you need to make a car payment
that you need to make
any sort of payment,
who's really losing money,
obviously you're not
obviously have to make the pain,
but who's really losing money, Right.
It's it's the company, right.
The company, the like Google, Amazon,
whatever you're using, let's say Uber,
Right.
Do us know how much money yesterday,
Facebook, Instagram
and WhatsApp were down, right?
Obviously, people use that
for their personal life and so forth.
But did you guys also know
that many businesses around the world
use Facebook, WhatsApp and Instagram?
Did you guys know that?
Right?
I don't know if any of you guys have
a business or anything like that or any.
Do you guys know how much money they lost
yesterday?
It's it's it's crazy, right?
It's it's a lot of money. Right.
And this is just to show you, right,
that really most of these bugs
are kind of related to to money, right?
That that's that's exactly right.
So you already know how much Amazon
makes in one hour.
Right.
And they're going to hire testers like you
to make sure that that doesn't happen.
Right.
And they'll hire
different types of testers,
but they'll hire you
to do a specific testing.
Right.
And they'll pay you
100,000, 100, 10,000, whatever.
To them, that's a good deal, right?
They're like,
you know what, guys? That's higher.
Catalina,
let's pay $110,000 a year and let's just
this will probably help us prevent
such a big mess like this, right?
Catalina Catalina's happy.
She's making good money.
Amazon is, you know,
this is a good deal, right? So.
So think of it like.
That's right.
And obviously, it's not just one tester.
There's many testers
that do different type of testing,
and we want to talk about that.
Okay. Does that make sense so far?
That does that kind of makes sense?
And guys, I want you to start thinking
like everything business.
Everything. Business, right? It's
not just Amazon.
Where do you get your car
insurance from, right?
Geico,
you know, you tell me Allstate, right?
They make money off of that.
Where do you make your car payments work?
Who do you bank with?
How pissed off would you be
if you're trying to log in
to transfer money
from your checking account
to another account,
but you can't log in like it's
not letting you and it's down
for like 6 hours, right?
You need to make some sort of payment.
Your banks website is down
and the application is down.
It doesn't it doesn't.
You know,
you're having a bad experience, right?
You know what's going to happen there.
Okay.
Let's say, for example,
let's think of this scenario here, Marvin.
Let's say your who's your bank, Marvin,
You call you backwards guy.
Yeah. We're going to talk about that
SunTrust, right?
Marvin Let's say you want to log
to your checking account, right?
Just to transfer balance
from one account to the other.
You're not making any sort of payments,
right?
You're not making any sort of payment.
So SunTrust
is really not going to lose any money
because you're not going
to make any payment.
You honestly just want to transfer money
for whatever reason.
Then maybe you have to make a payment
or something,
but you realize that their app is down
for like 3 hours.
Okay?
And then for some reason it gets fixed
and you can use it in two days.
The same thing happens again in a week.
The same thing happens again,
right, Marvin?
You're probably going to be like,
I can't put a what's on trust.
I'm going to go bank with Wells Fargo
now. Right?
So guess what?
Now they lost Marvin as a customer, right?
So SunTrust ended up
losing Marvin Business.
Does that make sense, guys?
Do you guys see how all of this works now?
Right.
Okay, So it's time to
kind of I want you guys to kind of see
that that bigger
that that picture the
So what is the goal of testing
and why is testing important?
We did talk about, you know,
the goal of testing and so forth.
Here's this link I will share
with you guys, but I'll click it here.
Basically, let's talk about some bugs
that were very, very, very costly.
Okay, So this is Wikipedia
and it's bugs in every single industry,
guys you like.
And I'm going to share this with you guys.
There you go.
And you guys will also get these slides,
by the way.
But here you go.
You can open it on, on,
on, on your end.
And there's bugs of every single time,
of every single type
and every single industry. Right.
How big how big of a deal do you think
bugs are in the medical industry?
Right.
Like it's a pretty big deal, you know,
I mean,
like and now now everything is becoming
digitalized, right?
Everything is digital nowadays,
Right?
You know, we have now
do you guys have any family members
that have diabetes nowadays?
They're having digital tests, Right.
How big of a bug would it be
if the diabetes test tells your loved one,
your mom or your dad or someone
that your sugar levels are okay,
but realistically,
they're very high, right.
Do you think that's a bug?
Do you think that that's a bug?
It's a it's a huge bug, right?
It's it's a huge bug. Right.
And and and other things like this,
like imagine
getting wrong information
somewhere and stuff like that.
There's different type of bugs everywhere.
AT&T, right?
You can read about these bugs here
and these bugs are here because
they're huge.
At the end of the day,
these bugs can be very serious.
Okay. And a lot of money is involved.
And you know what?
It's a big risk to read, for example,
that that diabetes scenario that
I just told you, like for medical device,
you know what can happen.
Let's see.
Mazhar and Mohammed speaking about
let's say Maher has a family member
that has diabetes,
that that family member gets the
the wrong, you know, sugar levels.
And then for some reason, that family
member gets very, very sick, Right.
Or passes away. Right. Mom,
as soon as she finds
out that that information was incorrect,
she can sue
the hell out of these companies. Right.
And it's going to cost them
some serious, serious money.
Right. And it will be very hard.
These companies are going to have to pay
a ton of money.
Right.
Especially and let's say
let's say they do say
this family member doesn't pass away,
but they were close to passing away.
Right.
She's still going to file a lawsuit
and she and that company will still lose
a lot of money.
Does that make sense for everyone?
That makes sense.
And it's literally every single industry
transportation, right?
Yeah.
Take a look at this Wikipedia
link that I shared.
You know, in military,
there's a lot of applications they use.
I used to work in a Department
of Defense project.
One of the applications
that we were working with was basically
the the software or the applications
that they use in battlefields.
So whenever a troop gets injured,
they kind of carry them
to these tents for like quick recovery
or medical attention.
And these applications had to be very good
to provide
the correct medical information
to track the right medical,
the right medicine, the right
diagnosis, the level of of medication
that they should be treating a true.
So bugs happened there, too. Right.
And it's it's a very, very, very big deal.
Okay.
Now, having this said,
can anyone think of any other bugs
that you can think of any
that you can think of?
Maybe you've seen it in the news,
maybe you've experienced some
yourself aviation software.
Yeah.
Bedbugs.
Bedbugs is a
bed make or
is that are you experiencing bedbugs, man?
Is that
I would
I would kind of
be careful with that a little bit.
Space rays.
Some people are saying space sex
because
any other big bugs
you can think of anything
anything that comes out of it
that you can think of that
they dupes
video games right?
Airplanes is.
But do you guys realize, right,
that as everything is becoming
digitalized right.
You're really introducing
and it's becoming modern, Right.
And it's becoming, you know, awesome.
And everything I do
is like all of these electric cars
and everything and all these, you know,
green saving energy companies
and all this like Teslas, Right?
You know what?
That opens the door of?
That opens the door for many mistakes,
right?
Many errors.
And that also opens the door
to many more jobs, jobs
that require a specific skill set,
a technical skill set like yours.
Right.
As you know, at the end of this class,
you guys will be some really, really,
really good test engineers.
You guys will know what you guys are doing
and how to test
different types of software to school.
Do we have questions so far?
Are we good?
It's just making sense.
Are we are we starting to think now?
Right.
So can we all agree
that testing is important?
Right.
All clear. Perfect.
All right, cool, cool, cool.
Very.
So there are three types of applications
that we're going to test that.
That we test that you're going to test.
Yeah. Catalina, go ahead.
Ask your question. What is your question?
But let's say your test is
software is okay and goes out.
How does it get a bug once it's running?
That's a very good question.
So let
me ask you let me ask you this question.
Do you think that there is such a thing
of finding absolutely every single bug?
Do you think so?
It's not possible, Right.
Did you know that
there are a lot of existing bugs
that exist on the Amazon website right now
and they know about them, but
they haven't fixed them for some reasons
and now we'll talk about that later.
Okay.
Perhaps they're not that serious.
Perhaps their business their business is
not really affected by it.
Right.
So they know about the bug,
but they're going to save it later
because they have other priority tasks
that they need to work on.
Okay.
So more to Catalina, this question now,
what happens if you test right
something today,
Let's say you're responsible
for testing a log in future, okay?
The requirement is that you have to
be able to log in with valid credentials.
Okay.
So you go on the website, you log in
with valid credentials and you log in.
It's working today.
Does that mean that you are 200%
sure that that's going to work forever
or tomorrow or Sunday
or next week or something?
No, believe it or not,
these things can break code breaks
for many different reasons.
And while you test something today, tomorrow, there's a chance that it may fail.
What makes it very code?
Code is very code
and we'll talk more about that.
Catalina, That's a really good question,
but you can't ever really 100%
trust on code to always work.
Okay.
Believe it or not,
there are applications where
the first 100 times that you log
in, it works.
But the 101 time that you log in, it
breaks.
And and we'll talk more about why
these things happen
and that kind of thing.
All right.
Is it interaction between servers?
That's can be a very big one
and that's what we will talk about
in the next classes.
Okay.
Very, very good.
Catalina, Catalina,
you're ready to run the market, right?
Looks like it looks like you're ready.
I think. I think you're ready.
All right.
So three types of applications with tests.
Okay.
Lobo's sharing
an Airbus bug.
Do you imagine a bug on an airplane
and a plane crashing?
Right.
So. Exactly. So.
All right. So,
okay,
there are three types of applications.
We test
web applications, desktop applications,
mobile applications.
Can you guys give me some examples
of mobile applications?
It's very self-explanatory.
Instagram, Facebook, Spotify,
good.
Twitter, right?
TikTok, right.
Telegram.
Yes, Right.
Good slack.
Right.
Anything that you can download
on a mobile device, You know what I mean?
Like on your phone's tender,
You know, that's it's
good to know that you know
bank mobile apps
whether apps
exactly right now
what what do you think
is a web application just
what do you think is a web application
websites okay.
Google.
Okay.
Google Gmail.
Okay. Web applications.
Chrome, YouTube.
But a lot of these
applications, you're
saying they also work on your phone.
So what is the difference
between a web application
and a mobile application?
Someone said browser based,
they're from coding.
Come on, guys,
let's think outside the box a bit.
Let me ask you this.
Does Instagram require Internet?
Okay.
How about
does the calculator on your phone
require Internet?
But that's a mobile application, right?
But it's still a mobile application.
Yes. Well, let me see.
What's his name?
Not. No, no.
Is that how you say your name?
I may have said it wrong. No.
Is that how you say it?
Okay. He brought up a very.
That's a very good point.
A web application is any application
that requires access to the Internet.
God, does that make sense to everyone?
So there
are some applications and yes,
you can use them on your desktop,
on your computer, on your on your laptop,
but you can also use them on your phone.
And while they are considered
mobile applications,
they are still considered web
because they they
they access the you know,
they need access to the Internet.
Does that make sense?
Does that make sense to everyone?
Right.
Does anyone have any questions
regarding that?
And there are a lot of mobile applications
that don't need Internet.
The calculator is one of them.
What else is one of them?
What else is a timer?
Not all mobile applications.
What's to monitor?
Not all mobile applications
require internet right?
For example.
Very good.
The flashlight app. Right.
It doesn't require internet.
Okay, Calendar.
The calendar. That's a good one.
That doesn't require internet, right.
The note.
Your notes doesn't require Internet,
right?
It doesn't.
But does that make sense to everyone?
Okay,
So while it's downloaded on your phone
or your iPad, it's
considered a mobile application.
But if it needs the Internet to work,
it can also be considered
a web application that makes sense.
And then, of course, any application
you use
that requires the Internet on your laptop
is considered a web application.
Is that clear?
Exactly.
Okay. And perfect.
Okay.
So desktop applications, what are
what are desktop applications?
Give me an example.
Okay. Someone said Microsoft. Microsoft.
What do you mean exactly?
Word. Right.
Microsoft Office Eclipse.
That's a good one. Photoshop.
Good Excel.
That's right.
So Can these applications
so what we mean desktop, right?
That means you have to download them,
but download them where
on your computer, Right.
You're going to download
them on your computer.
Can anyone talk about a
a desktop application
that will only work on a desktop,
but not on a phone?
Does anyone know of any application that
will work on a desktop
but not on your phone?
You can download office to your phone
nowadays, right?
nowadays.
Okay. Java's a programing language.
It's not a it's not a software,
it's not an application.
Okay, So
okay,
a desktop application is an application
that you download.
Okay. To your computer.
Okay.
That does not require internet to work
and does not require you to use a web
browser.
The moment you use a web browser
that's not a desktop application.
Okay.
For example,
is this Google sheets that I'm using?
Is this a desktop application
or is this a web application?
It's a web application.
It's not a desktop application.
It's a web application. Right?
What if I open word
right now, like Microsoft Word,
like right here I have Excel Open.
So if I open this, is this a desktop
application or Web application?
That is a desktop application, right?
And can work
without being connected to the Internet.
Right. But there's another thing, right?
You should also realize that nowadays
these are these softwares
are these applications today, Right.
They're so modernized that
at some point
they need the Internet for what?
What do you need the Internet for?
Yes. Updates.
Exactly. Right. Updates.
That's right.
Very, very, very good.
Very, very, very, very good.
Okay, cool.
All right.
Awesome.
Very, very good.
Perfect. Okay.
So are we good on this?
Are we good?
Go. Does anyone have any questions
so far?
Good. We talk about a web.
A web,
a what you're going to get.
You're going to get these
You're going to get these knowledge.
We already talked about it.
We already talked about a desktop
application, mobile applications.
We really talked about.
Let's see.
Okay, are you guys ready?
You guys are doing it.
You guys are amazing so far.
You guys are so far
the best batch we have ever got.
All right. That's one
plus one.
Okay, bachelor, you guys,
you guys are on fire.
Got this. This is really, really good.
All right, So manual testing.
So what is manual testing?
Okay, so we already talked about testing.
We talked about the different types
of testing that, you know,
we talked about bugs, different types of
testing that you will be conducting maybe.
And we talked about some business
requirements, some potential bugs and
and so forth. Right.
Okay.
But what is manual testing? Yeah.
So it's basically
everything manually,
like manually without any technology,
anything like that.
And and what we mean is like
you guys logging in to like let's say
you guys have to test the log
in functionality for Amazon, right?
That means you have to go on Amazon.com.
You have to go to the site and buy it.
To click on log
in, you have to enter your username.
You have to enter your password
at the click right.
You see all the manual effort
that I just did there, right?
Like I actually had to go open the tab.
I had to type Amazon.com.
I had to go and click on, sign on.
I had to enter the credentials.
And so for assessing
what if you had to run a test where they
said, Hey, can you make sure that the user
can look up
anything and add ten items to the
cart and then check out?
Right.
So can you shop and check out?
Yes, you can.
Obviously running tests
and sometimes they'll give you
like fake accounts
and stuff to test to make sure it works.
Yes. By the way, Eugene,
when we say manually that means
literally any mail intervention.
If you have to type something, you have to
click something, something, right?
So let's say that they say, Hey,
Shareef, you have to go on Amazon.com.
Make sure to add things to the cart
and then you have to checkout, right?
So, sure, it's like, okay, cool.
And he goes and he does it.
But how long do you think
it would take Shareef to do that?
How long do you think it would take to
it would take him.
It would take a while, right?
It would. It would literally take him.
I mean, let's say it takes him like 15,
20 minutes, right?
Let's just say 15 minutes.
If he's fast. 10 minutes. Right
at most.
But what if they say, okay, cool.
Now, Sharif, we need you to execute
200 more test cases like this.
So how long is that going to take them?
How long is that going to take?
And that test case took in 15 minutes.
And now he has to run 200 other
scenarios or tests.
How long you think it's going to take him?
It's going to take him till retirement.
It's going to take him a while, right?
Let's say it takes two weeks.
Okay.
Let's just say it takes him two weeks.
It takes him two weeks
to execute all of those.
And then maybe he found the bug.
Okay?
And then they say, okay, Sharif,
we fix these bugs.
Can you run all the tests again?
Right.
And sure, he's going to be like
again, you know, like, I just,
you know,
and it's going to take him a long time.
It's going to be he's going to be doing
everything manually and stuff
that by the way, that's manual testing.
And there's a lot of jobs that still exist
with that go.
So that is what are you guys
is that starting to paint a picture?
And I guess
it's starting to take a picture.
Okay The truth is that
it and it's very important.
Okay.
It's very, very important
still to make sure that we always do
manual testing and stuff like that.
But this is why we do automation, okay?
Because with automation, we can automate
these test cases using different tools.
There's meant there are many different
automation tools that we're going to use,
and you guys will learn different
tools here that are the most
popular in the market today.
Okay?
Eclipse is not an automation tool.
Eclipse is an integrated development
environment, right?
In Eclipse, you can develop programs,
you can do anything, you can write
your Java code, you can do
all sorts of thing in Eclipse, right?
And you guys will get to know
that that's where you guys
will be writing
or coding your automation scripts.
Okay, next class,
what I can do is I'm going to run
some automated tests right here
and show you guys how that works.
That is of course, that makes sense.
Like, would you guys like that?
I'll actually run some automated tests
so you can see how fast
it can actually go.
So automation testing and when I show you
tomorrow, it's going to be like, it's
going to be good, it's going to be fast,
It's going to be, let's say
submitting a form takes
you like 20 minutes.
Okay?
Have you guys ever had like to register
somewhere or fill out a form
of any type, like in the like
maybe for a doctor or something like that
and it takes you like 20 minutes maybe.
Like it's taking a while,
right? So
I'll show you how an automated script
can run that very fast.
So when Shareef starts to automate,
okay, instead of spending two weeks
to test those test cases,
he can run everything within
like maybe two or 3 hours
at most, maybe sometimes four.
So now that seems very attractive
to these companies, right?
Let's say Amazon site.
That's awesome.
Like you just tested all of this
like in 4 hours, right?
So Amazon now knows, okay, we got to
we need to hire more people
like Shari, people that know
testing people that no automation, people
that know
selenium, Java and stuff like that
because it's really helping them, right?
So they're going to keep continuing to,
to automate that.
That makes sense to everyone.
Okay. But
before
I don't want you guys to get confused
I actually want you guys to understand
what automation means.
Okay. What does automation mean to you?
And feel free to Google it,
but don't copy and paste answers.
Put in your own words.
What does automation mean?
That's. That's okay. Yeah,
that's that.
It runs by itself.
Create the code that will check. No,
no automatic motion.
No automatic.
Okay. That's so when they're repetitive.
No, no, just tell me the definition
for automation.
Notice I didn't ask you to tell me
what is automation testing?
I just want you to tell me
what is automation?
Okay.
Tools.
That means hands free access machine work.
Okay,
You're kind of almost putting
everything together.
Automate manual work. Okay.
For example,
do you have you
guys ever worked in an office environment?
And if you're out of the office, right.
And someone sends you an email,
sometimes that person gets an email back
and it says sorry,
I'm out of the office, I'll be back
this day or something like that.
Have you guys ever had
that happen to you right out of email?
So let's say I emailed,
let's say I emailed
or months.
Okay, let's say I email four months
and her mother's out of the office.
Okay, I send an email.
Does her Matt have to log into his email,
read my email, respond to me,
say hey, sorry I'm out of the office,
No write today.
You can just send
an automatic reply right?
If I sent him an email,
I will get an email saying, you know,
I'm out of the office, I'll be back,
you know, whenever I go that
that process there, guys, is automated
does that make sense right?
Nowadays
when you work jobs and depends
where you work.
And this was I also used to work in
some places back in the day
where I would show up to work and
I would have to clock in my hours, right.
And then after log,
after clocking in or logging my hours,
I would have to go tell my boss like, Hey,
I logged in at this time.
Could
nowadays, if you do something like that
and you log your hours,
maybe an automatic message
or email of some sort get sent,
you know, saying,
hey, Diego logged in as hours, right?
So that process is automated.
This is this started big.
So it started to paint a picture, guys,
of what automation is.
So listen to this. Okay?
Auto automation, right?
Only helps us do what
we are already doing better, right?
For us to be more efficient.
Does that make sense?
It's about efficiency,
right?
That makes sense.
Who else can give me
an example of something that is automated?
Literally, anything that is automated.
For example,
you guys are exactly voicemail.
What about buying something on Amazon?
What happens
when you buy something on Amazon?
What happens is
you get an email right?
You get an email email confirmation.
Does that mean
that someone had to log in to Amazon,
see that you purchased something
and then they send you an email saying,
Hey, thank you for purchasing this?
Not right.
That process is already automated right?
Exactly.
So is does
this what someone said about something
locking car doors or something like that?
I don't I don't know. But.
Okay.
Scary, right? Perfect. Right.
So does that make sense
now, do you guys have an idea
of what automation is?
Okay, perfect. Right?
It's awesome. Okay.
Any questions so far, no.
All right, cool.
So if I were to give you a quiz,
next class, will you pass it?
Once the mom says yes?
Come on, let's play a game.
Okay, I'll.
I'll give you a quiz.
And if you pass it,
I'll give you, like, a gift.
Okay.
And if you fill it,
you kind of have to give me that gift.
But let's say let's say a $50 gift card.
Okay?
So if you fill it,
you have to give me a $50 gift card.
Is that is that cool?
Guys, I need you guys to be so confident
with this material
that you can literally play
something like squid games.
But I being asked these type of questions
and you just sort confident.
Okay, But you have to get them
you have to get them right
called.
That makes sense.
All right, cool. Cool.
All right, cool.
So how do we start testing?
How do you know when we start testing?
Okay, you guys already
talked about Agile, right?
Agile.
Cool. What can you tell me about Agile?
What is the difference
between Waterfall and Agile environments?
Agile is faster, Agile is quick.
Agile allows changes right?
Agile is flexible, speed over quality.
Yes, that happens a lot.
Agile this incremental
waterfall is not changeable.
Okay We'll talk more about that.
But if you go on Google right,
and you type in the definition of Agile,
it's probably like going to tell you
about like development partners.
To be agile
means that you can move quick, right?
For example,
you can like Jimmy when, when,
when Jimmy used to play soccer,
this guy was agile guys.
Jimmy was top of line, solid player
and the high school.
This guy had some crazy agility right?
He was agile.
He was able to move quick,
he was fast, pace everything right.
That's the same thing
in agile environment.
A lot of changes, quick changes
at any time they can happen at any time.
You have to and you have to be agile
and adapt to those changes.
Okay, very good.
So having that said, right,
there is something else
that we're going to talk about right now,
but can you guys tell me what is the
what is the
software testing lifecycle?
I know many of you guys are going to say
SDLC, right?
SDLC is acronym
for software testing lifecycle,
but what is software testing lifecycle?
And then tell me the phases in order.
Okay.
So the phases in order.
Good. Okay.
So let's talk about the first phase,
right?
We have what we have requirements
gathering, right?
Sometimes they call it requirements
gathering analysis, write or analysis
done.
What is the second?
What is the second phase?
Requirements
gathering someone's set planning.
Okay, what is the third phase?
What is the third phase design?
What is the fourth phase?
Development exactly?
Development.
You can say coding code, it's up to you.
Same thing. Five.
What is five?
Testing and testing.
And lastly, maintenance.
Okay.
So some say that deployment
and production and I will talk to you
about what that is and maintenance.
Okay. We'll talk about
all of this to work.
Okay. So
what happens in the requirements
gathering phase?
What happens is
be a that's a business analyst,
but what happens like a BA is involved.
But what happens?
They talk to client and gather
information.
Yes, exactly.
They just gather information.
This information is known as this data.
It's known as requirements. Right.
And they analyze these requirements.
Does that make sense?
Right.
I'm pretty sure
you guys already talked about this.
So once they gathered these requirements,
well, once they gather this data,
now they have to plan.
But what are they planning for?
What are they planning
time and cost?
How long it will take budget.
A lot of a lot of goes in the planning
phase, right.
Like, hey,
do we have enough developers to do this?
Do we have a team? Do we have testers?
How long will we take?
Do we have any limitations right?
If you work for a project like URS,
they may not allow you to just use
any technology.
They're okay.
Every Company has its own security.
Security,
you know, security protocols
that everyone has to follow
who works like at a company right now
where you can't use like Facebook, right.
Okay. Or you can. Exactly.
So maybe there are some restrictions
there.
Like maybe you need to access
website and it's not there
and now you have to find a workaround.
Okay. So a lot goes into the planning.
Does that make sense, guys?
It looks like you guys
got this notice down, so that's good.
Okay, so then the next phase is design.
What happens here
you are.
You asks how long it will look like
Blueprint.
Exactly.
Wireframe.
Some people are saying what?
You know, a wireframe is
you guys are saying you are UX.
What does that mean?
Do you guys are you guys
just like writing out keywords
or are you guys actually
answering a question?
You guys are saying UI. You are, you are.
What do you mean you are what?
What what? What do you mean?
So if I were to ask you in an interview,
what is the design phase?
Are you guys going to say
UI user interface and then that's it.
What is going to be your answer?
Right.
The design phase is where they design,
right?
What is
they design the requirements.
They they start to
to design the web application itself.
Okay.
Did they start to design the application
right.
They'll sit down and they'll be like,
okay, we know the requirements.
Okay, okay.
Let's say they want this log in function.
They want this here. Okay?
So they're going to start designing it
right?
And designers, graphic designers,
sometimes
they call them
UI UX designers or UI designers, right.
They will start to design this.
Are they doing development
at that point or.
No, But
no. Right.
They're just designing. That's it.
And that's a whole other role
that is important in this, Right?
Graphic designers.
Okay, now let's say they design it
and they're finished designing it.
They said, Hey,
we've designed a whole page, okay,
let's say Jimmie's a developer,
and they go to, Jimmy, They're like,
Hey, Jimmy,
this is ready for you for development.
Go ahead and develop this.
So the Jimmy is going to look at it
and he's going to be like, okay,
now this is what they want design.
So then they start the coding, right?
He starts development,
he starts running his code.
But there can be some issues here.
What can be some issues here?
What can be some issues?
Does anyone know?
What can be some
issues for the developers?
No, no.
At that point, let's say they designed it
right and the client likes it.
Let's say mom has the graphic designer.
She says, Hey, look, this is essentially
like we got to the requirements.
Is this you like this?
And they're like,
Wow, you did a great job designing this.
This is exactly what we want, right?
So then it's ready for development
and Jimmy starts to code it.
The developer starts to develop it.
But what can be some issues?
There?
Yes, for hot. That's a good point. Right?
What if Jimmy is like,
okay, I'll start developing it.
Right.
But then Jimmy's
experiencing some problems
and he starts to realize
that he cannot exactly develop
what was designed right
Then they have to go back to the client
and they're going to have to say, Hey,
we kind of made a change here because
we couldn't really we
couldn't really develop this due to this
and this reason.
Right. Okay.
But then the client says, Mom,
we were so excited that we really wanted
this.
You know, it kind of sucks
that now we can get this right.
And now the client is starting
to get a little unhappy right?
The reason could be a lot of reasons,
right?
It could be that
maybe there's like security
security issue with that, right?
Maybe that it's not going to be approved.
Maybe there's going to be like
a security flaw or something like that, or
it could be anything read point
is that something happened
or it just couldn't be developed
as it was exactly designed.
Right. And this happens all the time.
Does that does that make sense, guys?
It happens all the time.
Right? Okay.
So then let's say Jimmy starts
developing it, right?
He starts developing
whatever he has to develop.
Then what happens here?
This is
who will get approved for the design,
The team.
We'll talk more about that.
What is your question, Aisha?
What is your question?
You write SDLC software
Developer lifecycle.
Oh, my bad.
This is software development lifecycle.
Good call.
But the good stuff. Good stuff.
I said I did that to make sure
you're paying attention. So.
So the testing phase, right?
Someone said we test for bugs.
Yeah, you test for.
But what are you confused about?
Do we have to asses?
Is that
okay? It's
one of those
we're talking about the software
development lifecycle right now.
We're going to talk about SDLC shortly.
We'll talk about that.
We'll get there.
Okay.
Let's just finish discussing this first,
because then this is where
I'm going to transition to SDLC.
So the testing phase comes in, right?
Okay.
And someone said we test for bugs.
You test to see if there are any bugs,
but you also test for what?
What do you test for
it? Test requirements.
Okay.
The test functionality before you test
that,
whatever was developed works as expected.
Right? Right.
Guys, that's where you test for that.
Okay.
And that's where you guys
will be doing your testing.
Okay.
And then once you guys say, all right,
testing is good, our testing pass,
okay, it's good.
Then it gets deployed to production
what does that mean?
What does production mean?
What do we mean by production?
It goes live.
What that mean?
What does what does that mean?
Someone said it's put to users.
Where does it push to
ready to be used.
Okay, available on website. Okay.
We will talk about more on how that works.
Okay.
This is also another topic.
We have to we have to talk about.
Trust me, all these questions,
all these thoughts you have,
we will cover absolutely everything.
Let's take a step back. Okay.
And the testing phase, this is as the LC.
Okay. Does that make sense?
We just talked about the software
development lifecycle.
Okay.
This is just make sense, guys.
Right. Okay.
But then there is something else
that's called
the software testing lifecycle.
And the software testing lifecycle
happens in the testing phase. Good
software or
lasting lifecycle, Okay.
As TLC, as TLC
happens in the testing phase,
the SDLC, does that make sense?
Does that make sense so far? Okay.
So let's talk about what SDLC is.
So we already know that the code
has been developed, the application
has been developed, and now it's good
and now you got it tested.
So what does that mean?
So you look at my screen.
Okay, SDLC is another cycle.
Okay,
So process is a sequence of activities
to be performed to perform testing.
Okay.
So as a tester,
what you're going to do is first
is as a tester, you're going to
first
see what the developer is working on.
And you have to also understand
the requirement
that is being that that is, you know,
that's being developed.
Okay. You have to understand it.
If it doesn't make sense
to you, if you have questions
and you start testing.
But you're unsure and you assume
that you've figured it out and stuff
and you start testing,
is that correct?
Is that incorrect?
Never assume 100%. Exactly.
You never assume. Right.
So let's say
you are reading the requirements
and something doesn't make sense to you.
Okay.
There's some information missing.
What do you do?
What do you do? Yes. Someone Yes.
To answer your question, yes,
you ask to get more information.
Okay. And a development project.
Who would you ask for first
word, notes
seems seamlessly
good.
If you have questions
regarding a requirement
that you need to test,
you need to test
the ask first.
Some people say Scrum Master Product
Owner two way lead.
No, no, that's right.
No idea that I pronounce your name
correctly.
The thing is that
yes, you ask a VA, you ask
a business analyst. Go.
Why? Why do you ask a VA?
Why do you
why do you ask a VA?
Okay. Why?
Because they are the ones that are going
to be gathering the requirements
and they're going to be
the ones that are going to have
the most interaction with the client
in most projects.
Does that make sense? Right.
So let's say someone let's say
she's the business analyst,
okay.
And in the series, a tester
and he has questions and
he's going to go to the man and say,
excuse me,
I don't understand this requirement.
Could you clarify this a little more?
Right.
And tomorrow will read it
and she'll probably say, you know what?
You're right.
Let me make some changes
because it needs to be more clear.
Right.
But what if Seer didn't ask questions?
What if he assumed
and then he did his testing
and then he says, all right,
it's good to go.
What?
The thing happens, what you think happens.
That's the problem, right? So mistake.
Let's say they find a bug later, right?
They're going to go to first when there's
a bug, they're going to go to Messier.
They're going to say this.
You say you tested this and it passed.
But it's not working.
Right.
So they're going to go down to the Q8
first.
Does this make sense? Does
do you understand why?
Important for you to fully understand
the requirements
right.
But does it make sense?
Right.
It's very, very important.
Okay, so let's say
you get to the requirements, right?
Let's say you understand requirement.
Okay, good.
Then you have to do your test planning.
Okay.
And by test planning,
we meet, we mean like
planning for your test, right?
You start to say, okay, so I have to test
this log in functionality.
Let's say the requirement
has to do with something. Log in.
So you're like, okay, I got to test this.
I have to it.
This is probably going to take me like,
like maybe a couple hours to test, right?
So you start to plan for that, right?
And then there is test case development
that we will talk about.
And then there's environments
set up, test execution.
You run your test
and there's this test cycle closure.
I'm going to tell you
exactly everything about these phases.
But you all you need to understand for now
is that this is a cycle
that happens inside.
What phase of SDLC?
What phase
testing.
Right,
Exactly,
Exactly. Very, very good.
Okay.
You guys are doing very good.
So it's 824.
Let's come back at 835.
Let's come back at eight. 840.
So cool. 840.
Yeah, go ahead.
Take it to take 15 minutes. Yeah.
And I'll be here
if you have any questions.
But, you know, you should just go
enjoy a break right now.
You guys are doing great,
so keep up the good work.
Cool.
And feel free to ask any questions
if you need to.
What about Python?
What's your question?
ARIN is going to make some tea.
Make some for all of us.
Please.
Persian food time present.
What do we use for automated testing?
You will learn that with time
you will learn that.
What do you mean? It's good to have
anything, you know.
It's always going to be an advantage.
So automation, right, is a process, right?
That just helps us do.
We're already doing
better to for us to be more efficient.
Okay.
Automation is where any manual process,
you know, has been automated
so that there is no human intervention,
no manual intervention
for extra knowledge
as of the language of 2021, you know,
every programing language is popular,
you know,
So if you know how, that's good.
I'm doing cloud after this bootcamp.
What do you mean
you're doing cloud after this bootcamp?
Jimmy
Yeah, this is during automation.
Doesn't rule. Nope.
We're going to work with you.
I'll tell you exactly what it is.
Java is popular.
Think it's course Java is popular.
It's the
but we're going to do some practical
of course
we're going to do a lot of work.
A lot of work.
JIRA is a tool to see
if complete your sprints, get
patience, Sheriff.
Patience, grasshopper. Patience.
Trust me.
Later in the course,
you're going to start drawing gray hair.
You will see
changing.
So anyone else happy about Sheeba?
Don't be surprised.
Can you guys hear me?
PRC says Question In SDLC,
the planning is the first phase
in here.
They do a feasibility study,
then only requirements.
We can look more into that. PRC.
To clarify your question further
so we can be sure,
of course.
So what's up, guys?
Are you guys back?
Did you guys make your tea?
Chai like green tea
with no sugar
cardamom in there, Some saffron.
If you're feeling extra good, you tonight.
Bam. Right.
Did you guys, did
you guys do that or or what?
Some coffee.
What kind of coffee did you have for hot
coffee?
That, that anyone.
Hey, 15 minutes isn't enough time, right?
But you guys are all here to.
I'm assuming you guys are all here
to improve your lives.
Right? And
no cell phones.
Too expensive. Oh, sorry.
Maybe after you finish syntax,
you can take that kind of tea.
It'll happen in low. Will happen,
you'll see.
But let me tell you this, guys.
I know that you're making these sacrifices
and stuff, and
maybe some of you guys are like,
Oh, this is a get rich quick
scheme, right?
But once you start to realize how hard
this stuff is, you're going to be like,
Holy moly, this is like you're going to
work hard for this stuff that
you're going to work for this stuff.
So, you know, again,
stay on top of your assignments.
Don't miss any classes,
you know, stay on top of things, guys.
Stay on top of things.
Okay.
It's very, very easy to lose track
if at any moment
you're struggling with something,
you're struggling something,
if you don't think you can do it,
if you don't think that, you know,
if you start to think like, oh,
this Java stuff is hard or whatever.
Reach out to us. Reach out to me.
I will not let you fell,
but you can't let your self fell.
You know, this doesn't make sense, guys.
You can't.
There's no way.
Time is money.
It's only six months of your life.
You know, if things will get hard,
that's okay.
It'll get hard. No one said
this was going to be easy, right?
No one said, Hey, it comes just easy.
You're like, Then get a job. Now
you're looking
to to really get a career at this point.
Then you have to work hard for it.
Then you're going to
you're going to be very proud of yourself
once you start to realize that,
like you're doing very good.
But there's only one secret
to this formula, and that's
basically dedication your hard work
and to never don't don't quit.
Even if it gets hard,
even if it gets hard, reach out to me.
I'll help you out.
I'll show you guys how to do it.
An easy way
to get rich, Quick scheme.
It definitely isn't.
Michael I wanted to say that comment
halfway through the course
I'm going to say, So what?
So really, you're not laughing now right?
I'll just tell you
how to easily retain information
and so forth.
Okay,
you guys, there have been Uber drivers
that have never worked in technology
or anything like that
that have changed their lives completely
and now they're successful
construction workers, you name it, dude,
it's in Texas, all type of students.
We have a lot of students with degrees.
Did you guys know that?
George Mason, students, UVA, JMU, v Tech,
You know the people we have with degrees
that are here for a few reasons.
Most of them it's
because they can't find a job
or it's because they're in a job,
or maybe they're stuck in a job
and they can make more money and
then they realize how important money is.
Okay.
So we have students we have students here
that are probably working
at different professions
and they're just looking to change,
change, change their career, Right?
Maybe that's something I think
we'll get to know, to know each other
in a little bit. What's my story?
My story is
not that interesting,
but I'll tell you in another class.
Okay, It's not that interesting.
All right.
So let's let's yeah, it's tough.
So, Marvin, right?
You work in that field, right?
This is your way out of it.
All you have to do is work
six months, and then, bam, that's it.
Okay, That this is.
This is your ticket out.
And one thing is that if you're here,
you're completely blessed, right?
You're completely blessed
because there are a lot of people that
that can that that probably won't ever
have this opportunity.
There are a lot of people that, you know,
that just an opportunity like this is big,
big time guys.
The average salary for someone
coming out of this course is like 90,000.
Okay.
Do you know what people have to do
industries
to make that much
like they have to work on a company
for like ten, 15 years.
They have to like you guys know that
wherever you guys work,
you guys probably already know
how hard it is to to get to that level.
Okay,
How many hours
do you have to work in a week?
It's most of the time is like 40 hours,
but sometimes a little bit more time.
You're there.
You'll see.
We'll talk more about that later.
Yes, you can be a freelance
or you can be whatever you want.
All right. So anyway, back to this.
So again, SDLC is a cycle
that is a part of what
what is it a part of
testing?
What do you mean testing?
That is part of SDLC.
What phase of SDLC is
a part of the testing phase?
That's right.
Okay. Very, very, very good.
Okay, let's take a step.
And before we go into the slides, I'm
going to add some
some paint to or some color to the topics
we've been talking about.
Okay, This is for you.
This is important for you to know.
And by the way, we all learn different.
But I always tell you guys
to write your own notes down.
Okay.
Now I will share my notes with, you guys.
But I write high level notes sometimes,
and I'm not so detailed because I expected
to pay attention during class.
Okay.
But at the same time,
I found that to be better for you
to take your almost on as well
because it helps
you retain and learn the information
better.
Okay. Does that make sense?
Maybe you have realized that as well.
Even though I'm going to give the notes.
Okay.
Write down your own notes
because as you write down, it's
kind of like you're
repeating it to yourself.
Okay, So so keep keep that in mind.
So we've we've been single word
requirements.
What been saying like the whole class
write business requirements.
We've been saying business requirements.
We've and there can be any type
of, of business requirements can now
business requirements are can be like
hey I would like
we want a page to
we want our login page to have
a login functionality somewhere, right?
I'm just giving you very, very easy
are a business requirement
that users should be able to log in
with valid credentials.
Right?
Or users should not be able to log in
with invalid credentials.
Right.
That can be a requirement as well.
Okay.
But business requirements
are usually analyzed
and actually they are analyzed
into what is called
an acceptance criteria.
Okay.
And acceptance criteria. Okay.
And I'm going
to give you an example of an acceptance
acceptance criteria.
And acceptance
criteria is basically a summarized
and it's summarized in a way
to basically describe
what the user should do.
Okay. Bingo.
So as a user,
as an Amazon user,
I should be able to go to Amazon
dot com and
Amazon.com and navigate
navigate to navigate to prime video.
Okay.
And navigate to Amazon Prime video. Cool.
You guys know what?
Prime video's right and if not,
then you will know what it is right now.
Okay, so this a business requirement,
maybe the business requirement
was written like this.
We want users to be able to
access
access Amazon
prime video from Amazon dot com.
Right.
Maybe this is a business requirement
so the business analyst
will gather this requirement
and we'll turn this
into an acceptance criteria, stating it
as the way that a user should use it.
So as an Amazon user, I should be able
to go to Amazon.com and navigate to
to Amazon Prime video.
Okay.
Now I want you to have someone say
user stories.
Now User stories.
What are user stories?
User stories?
What are users?
What do you do stories?
Do you guys know to someone set task
requirements?
Yes, the requirements.
Okay, User stories.
A user story
do you have you guys learn about agile
ceremonies and artifacts?
Yeah. Okay.
Just to let you know, an Agile and Agile
A and Agile ceremony
ceremony is just
it's just a fancy word
for what?
For meetings.
Very, very good for meetings. That's it.
An agile ceremony is just a fancy word
for a meeting.
Okay.
For me.
Does that make sense. Okay.
And an agile right.
And artifacts.
An artifact.
I was going to say artifact.
Artifact is just the fancy word.
For what?
For yes.
Of tool documents. That's right.
Okay.
A backlog is a document
that, you know, a backlog is a document.
And you know what else is a document?
You know what else is an artifact? Yes.
Now, a sprint is not artifact,
but you know what else is a artifact?
Yes. A burned down chart is an artifact.
Very good, because it can be a document
that starts good.
A user story is also a document.
Okay?
A user story is a document.
So what's going to happen?
Listen to this. Okay?
There's the business requirements.
The VA gathered it and
and created an acceptance criteria.
Okay?
This acceptance criteria be inside
the user story.
Does that make sense?
So when you are testing a user story,
that means that you are testing
the acceptance criteria,
which means that you are testing
the business requirements.
Does that make sense?
Do you want me to repeat that?
Okay,
who's got this?
Noted that.
So let's take a few steps back
a user story
is what
a user story is, what an artifact.
And we said that an artifact
is a document, right?
Right.
Let's let's just get in the habit
of seeing an artifact because
that's how you refer
to it, an agile environment.
So a user story is an artifact
that contains
what is a document that contains what
an acceptance criteria exactly Right.
And acceptance criteria is. What
an acceptance criteria?
No acceptance
criteria is not a user story.
Acceptance criterias are written inside
user stories, right?
An acceptance criteria is a summary
of a business requirements.
Yes. Very, very good.
Okay, so you are testing user stories.
Okay.
When you're testing a user story,
that means that you are testing
an acceptance criteria, which is the same
thing as the business requirement.
So when you're testing a user story, okay,
that means you are testing
an acceptance criteria.
That is a business requirement.
Does that make sense?
This is why we say user
stories are requirements,
right?
Is that clear?
My goodness, is that clear?
It makes sense, right?
So what I'm going to do is go, we're going
say this, okay,
We're going to create a user story.
Okay? We're going to say user story,
user story.
We're going to say
give it a user story idea.
So one, two, three, four,
five, user story.
One, two, three, four, five.
Okay.
This is I'm going to say right here,
this is an artifact.
Okay?
An artifact is.
What?
Guys, what is an artifact
document?
Right. Very good. That
and this user story.
One, two, three, four, five.
Has this acceptance criteria.
Okay, I'm going to delete this
and I'm going to paste it here.
Okay.
Has this acceptance criteria.
Okay, Right here.
Okay, So the acceptance criteria here.
So here's the thing.
When this user story is developed,
literally, this is the user story.
So the first person to work on this user
story, who's going to be the first person
to work on to do the story?
What's going to be the first person
to know the being created,
the being created, The user story?
Who would be the first?
Yes, the developer. Right.
They're going to get this user story
right and then they're going to read it
and they're going to develop this right.
They're going to develop this.
Does that make sense?
No, no,
they're just going to develop it. Okay.
They're going to
develop a cool.
So that makes sense. Okay.
Once this developed,
then who's the next person
that will work on this?
The tester, Man, you guys are so smart.
So smart.
The best batch ever.
Like, not a Tesla, just the tester.
Okay, that makes sense.
That.
That makes sense.
Cool.
All right, cool.
So now notice
that this is the acceptance criteria,
right?
Does it say something like as a tester
or does it say something like
the tester has to do this
or anything like that?
Does it does it say anything like that?
No, it doesn't. Right.
Because
very good.
Very good. So it doesn't.
So basically everyone will work
on the same user stories.
Okay, cool.
Does that make sense to everyone?
I'm going to quiz you a little bit.
All right.
Okay.
This is the acceptance criteria, guys.
Go and test it.
I want you to go and test this acceptance
criteria.
Go ahead.
Tell me what you come up with.
Yeah, I'm gonna give you, like, 2 minutes.
Go ahead
and test this acceptance criteria.
Someone said pass.
Okay.
Yeah. Manually.
You can't automated. Right.
So how are you going to.
So obviously you can only do it manually.
Go ahead and test this.
I want to see
if you guys have learned anything
someone said manually.
I will need to have an Amazon account
to access Prime Video's
some people they passed.
Some people say it worked
like a sharp charm.
Pennock Dude, Hannah
is that how you say your name? And
and write your hand up?
Look round of applause
And that is 100% correct.
What is wrong with this acceptance?
Yes, Jimmy. That's right.
What is wrong with this acceptance
criteria? Yes.
You need more information, right?
So, okay, as an Amazon user,
I should be able to go to Amazon.com
and navigate to Amazon Prime video.
I saw a lot of different answers there.
I saw some people say pass and stuff, but
the acceptance criteria doesn't say how.
Right.
So let's go right now.
Let's go Amazon.com.
Okay. Okay.
And that says you go to Amazon.com
and it says that you should navigate
to prime video, right?
That's what it says. Right.
But how you don't know how right.
You don't know how.
So now you need you have a question.
And what do we do when we have a question
on of an unclear user story?
We asked the VA, right?
We ask the VA and we're going to go, hey,
so this says that Amazon
should be able to go to Amazon.com
and navigate to Amazon Prime video.
But how exactly like how like I'm on
Amazon.com, how am I supposed to go there?
There are so many ways to get there.
Someone said that they have to create
an account to access Prime Video's.
You actually don't.
You can go to Prime here.
You can actually click on all
okay By the way, this right here
you see this little button
with three stripes.
When you click on it,
we see a menu, right?
You guys see that?
Okay, what do we call this?
What we call this button? You know.
That's right.
A hamburger menu. Okay.
That's what we call it.
So we're going
to click on this hamburger menu
and then we can navigate to prime video.
Okay. From here, right. We can do that.
We can also go here and type
in prime video.
So How should we do this? Right?
And you have to ask them.
You have to ask to be
you have to get more clarification.
So let's rewrite this acceptance criteria
so that it makes it make sense.
As an Amazon user,
I should be able to go to Amazon.com
and navigate to Amazon Prime video
by clicking on the hamburger
Hamburger menu.
Navigating, Navigating to what it was.
What was it?
Hamburger menu.
Navigating to to prime video.
Okay. Navigating to
navigate to prime video.
And what is the last of those?
And clicking on prime video. Right.
And clicking on prime video.
Let's just write this down.
So and clicking and clicking on Prime
Prime video.
Okay. Now, does this make more sense?
Is it more clear?
Yes. Right.
Yes. For whoever asked
that question, should it?
Yes, it should say hello.
Yes. Okay.
Is that more clear? Right.
There are more details, right.
It makes sense now.
You know what to do right now.
You know exactly what to do.
Okay.
Before you guys said pass as the good,
someone said pass like a charm, right?
Bam! Out the window.
Right.
That's how you got.
So you get, you know,
limited fired, Don.
Right.
Also, a lot of you guys that said passed.
You know what you guys did there?
You guys assumed.
Right.
And what do we say about assuming
what do we say about assuming?
Right. Never assume.
And by the way, this goes for everything,
literally every situation that you're
in, that you're making assumptions,
never assume like never.
Right.
Especially when your job relies on it.
Does this make sense?
Right.
Does this make sense for everyone? Yes.
Yes. MUHAMMAD
Yes. And we'll talk more about this. Okay.
So are we clear?
Do we have do we have a good understanding
of everything, though?
Right.
Of course.
It pays to be picky, is not really called
picky.
It's called being observant
and detail oriented.
Okay.
That's what that's what
that's what we're talking about.
Okay, cool.
Does that make sense?
Okay.
The problem here was familiarity
with the website.
So the point is,
you should know what you have to do.
Okay,
cool.
Okay. And in the workplace.
In the workplace, when you go to
the business analyst and you ask questions
and you ask them to clarify it
and they said, oh, and let's say let's say
the ticket was like vague,
like the way we had it first,
let's say on the business analysts.
Alona a lot of sorry
and I say this is
how you're supposed to do it, right?
And Alon is like, okay.
And she goes back and she tested right.
What is wrong with that scenario?
Like I told Ilana how to test it.
I told her how it has to be done
and she knows and now she has to go
and test it.
But what is wrong with that?
What is wrong with that situation?
Yes, For testers, for SDLC.
For yes.
Someone say no.
I said So
let's say I'm the business analyst, right?
Let's say that the that the acceptance
criteria that we had was not detailed.
Okay.
Alannah comes to me,
I tell her how to do it, okay?
And she goes, and she does it well.
What was what is wrong with that though?
What is wrong with that?
I already clarified it for her.
What is wrong.
Yes, you'll get a yes.
Very, very, very good.
You get it. You are on fire.
You know what we call people like you.
You get it in the industry, you know,
we call you does what we call your here.
Call you.
We call you.
We call you a bag of money.
That's exactly what you are.
You'll get right a bag of money.
Okay. Stay that way.
Be that way.
Okay.
So she said it's not documented, right?
So as a business analyst, right.
If if Alana comes to me
and I clarify it for her,
Alana, the right thing to do is say, okay,
so can you please update the ticket?
So it reflects that, right?
You have to politely asked you say,
Hey, can you please update the ticket
so that it reflects that, right?
So that if anything wrong happens, Right.
So anything wrong happens.
You can say I went off of what
the user story said.
I went over
what the acceptance criteria said right.
Does that make sense?
No. Guys, verbal word of mouth guys
means absolutely nothing in the workplace
okay, word of mouth.
If you're if it's something serious, guys,
you know, ask for an email, right?
Ask for something to be documented.
Guys Word of mouth will like
it will hurt you.
Okay.
Your workplace can be like it could be
it could turn out to be toxic
if you don't have any documents.
Action. Right.
Documentation is a very safe way to go.
Read emails, documents, user stories.
You know, as for those,
make sure that you are covered as well,
because believe it or not,
even though you have to work as a team
when something happens
and there's a there's a bug
that is found,
they're going to come to you first, right?
They're going to come to you first.
Do you think that your team
is going to stand up for you?
Do you think that they're
going to stand up for you?
Like, are you really going to rely
on your team
to be there for you and say, oh, no, no,
Mustafa Like he checked them with those.
Like it's also our fault. Like,
Oh man, your workplace will easily
turn to Game of Thrones,
easily, easily, right?
So you can be so naive.
Very good.
Okay.
How exactly does that make sense, though?
Why? It needs to be documented.
Right?
Okay.
Do we have any questions on that
or have any questions that. No.
Okay.
Very good.
Is this making sense?
All right. Next slide.
Requirement analysis of
basically this is the first thing you do
when testing.
So let's say
that you guys start about sprints.
Okay?
Let's say you have two weeks
sprints, right?
And the sprint
starts, let's say, on Monday.
Okay.
Do you think that
testing will be ready for you on Monday?
You think that it's the product
that the feature
is going to be developed by Monday?
It's not right. It's not.
But does that mean that you just sit
and do nothing
while the developer develops that? No.
When the sprint starts right,
you have to read the user story.
Okay. You have to understand it.
Okay.
You have to
make sure that everything makes sense
and you start to plan your testing.
Okay?
This is what we mean
by requirement and analysis,
does that make sense to everyone? Yes.
You would create test cases,
which we will create.
Okay. So
so that that that's
what you will have to do.
Now, there's this criteria that's called
the smart criteria that you can follow.
You don't need to know this.
You don't need to memorize
It is there for your reference and
and just make sure.
So there are some times right,
some requirements
that are so for example,
following this smart criteria.
Okay, they have to be specific.
The acceptance criteria
needs to make sense, right?
It needs to be detailed.
You need to know what to do.
It needs to be measurable.
By measurable,
we can mean a lot of things like
how how long is it going to test?
How long is it going to take
for us to test this?
Okay, when we say attainable,
like can we reach these goals?
Can we finish this testing on time?
Right.
Is it relevant to anything else
that's been developed?
Is it something completely else?
So, for example,
let's say you have five user stories
that are all related to the homepage,
but then you have another user story
that's related to something else.
Okay, You have to measure that as well.
And time based goes
time, time, time, time.
Will you have enough time
to finish testing that or not.
Okay,
if and this is very, very important,
if you know that
you're not going to have enough time
to finish testing something
like what should you do?
Should you wait
to the last day of the sprint
to tell your team
that you don't have enough time?
What should you tell your team
that you probably won't
have enough time to test one?
Someone said ASAP
as soon as you realized, right?
As soon as as soon as you can,
the sooner the better.
How would it make you look if you wait
till the last day of the sprint
or even the second
to the last day of the sprint?
How would it make you look if, let's say
Sebastian's testing
and then all of a sudden two days
left in the sprint he tells us
that he doesn't have enough time,
you know, and then we're like,
did the sprint ends in two days?
You know, like, did you
you should have known about this.
You should have said something.
Okay.
So you kind of have to, you know,
be be aware of that.
Does that make sense?
Cool.
All right.
So test
documentation, proper documentation.
So we're going to talk
about documentation.
We're going to write test cases
and so forth and that kind of thing.
Test planning.
We'll also talk to you
about what is a test plan
and stuff like that.
Okay.
So test plan content.
What the test
a test plan is a document.
Okay.
That's
I'm going to answer this.
I'm going to go over this later
with you guys, okay?
Because I think it will
I think it will paint a clear picture
for you
after we start creating test cases.
Okay.
So let's revisit that. Okay.
Test plans. Okay.
And test plan content.
We need to revisit. Okay.
But first, let's talk about test
case development and what is a test case?
Okay.
As a tester,
you will also be developing test cases.
Okay.
A test case is also another artifact.
What is an artifact?
What is an artifact
document?
Right.
That has a set of actions.
Okay.
A set of actions or steps
that need to be executed to verify
a future of functionality.
The software application. Okay.
Why do you need a test case?
Test case makes the whole quick process
more efficient,
and we'll talk more about that.
Okay.
And and
and because you guys are awesome,
we are going to start
creating our own test cases today.
All right.
So you guys ready or are you guys ready?
Okay,
you guys, you signed up for this course.
Are you ready?
Irina Arenas laughing.
She's ready.
Means like, let's do it right.
Who's ready? Are you guys?
I need you guys to be active, okay?
It's time to be active. That's okay.
That's it.
We're ready.
Okay,
so we are going to create a test case.
We're going to create a document
which has a set of actions
supposedly to be executed event.
Are you ready?
Everyone follow me.
So I'm going to be using Excel.
If you don't have Excel,
use Google.
Use Google sheets.
I think it's called Google sheets. Okay.
So whatever is going to help you
than just use it.
Cool. Go.
So we're going to do this.
I have the Excel document
right here. Okay.
Because it can everyone see my screen?
Everyone should be able to see my screen.
Okay. All right.
So go ahead.
Open up your Excel, get your sheets
and give me a thumbs up when you're ready.
When when you are ready.
When you're ready to go.
Okay.
Are you ready?
All right, cool, cool, cool.
All right.
So in this slide and we're going to go
based what this has a test case
contains the following A test case B
or test scores.
Name, precondition, steps,
Number of steps.
E tell respect the result.
Action, results, comments.
We're going to cover all of that
and we're going to create our own.
Before we create this,
I want
you guys to see two examples of test
cases.
Okay.
So a test case I.D.
or a test case, name a precondition.
We're going to learn about what
a precondition steps, number of steps,
details, expected results, actual results
and comments.
This is a first example of a test case.
Okay, Notice that there is the scenario
in the test case.
I b we'll talk more about those.
The test case.
The test case description.
Okay. The test steps.
The test step description
expected results,
actual results, status,
stars, column and comments.
Okay,
here we have a test case example.
Here's another test case. The example
you see same thing.
There's a test case.
I did this one has a created by
this one has a reviewed by.
We are going to create our own test cases
that look similar to this.
Okay. So let's go back to this slide.
Okay.
And let's create our own test cases.
All right.
So first, open your sheets and
let's start
by saying test.
Okay, test case by B,
what is the test case idea
and how do we create it
and how do we come up with it
and that kind of thing.
So listen, the test IDs, this changes
from project to project, okay?
Usually in projects,
what they do is this okay, so
say test case idea.
Okay, when they do this, this.
Okay, so
the user story ID is one,
two, three, four, five.
Right? You guys see that, right?
And in most projects
what they do is they create
the test case
idea based the user story idea.
So what they will do is this it will say
they will grab the user story idea,
which is one, two, three, four, five.
Okay.
And then they'll probably do something
like underscore,
test case, underscore one.
Okay.
Does this make sense, guys?
Does this make sense?
Okay.
Does anyone need clarification on this?
And by the way,
this varies from project to project.
It could be different.
But in most projects,
what they do is they create the test case
idea based off the user story idea.
Okay, so we got the user story
ID, we're saying test case one
because we can create
many test cases based off this user story.
Okay, So we're to create this test case.
Go ahead and just do what I'm doing. Okay.
And we're going to base it here.
Cool.
Okay.
Band test, case ID,
And what we can do is actually
let me post this when we copy this,
paste it in another.
So like this one.
Okay.
And I'm going to get this
and I'll make it import.
Good.
So that's readable.
Just makes sense.
Can you guys see
this test case ID is here?
Okay, so go ahead and do this.
Okay.
So we created the test ID, Okay.
How do we create the test case?
I think.
Can you guys tell me, how do we create it
in this in this case,
how do we create the test case?
I'd be
what would you like me to repeat
based on the user story?
ID Exactly.
That's how we create it.
What would you like me to repeat?
I don't
by Yes.
Are you yelling? Catalina, Is that.
Is that. Are we yelling out?
Okay, so
yes, we we created this based on the user
story ID.
Okay, so it's user story.
One, two, three, four, five.
And this is the test case one, right?
Okay, perfect.
So now let's go back here
and it says we need a precondition.
We need a steps number.
Okay, let's do this.
We need a precondition
let's open up our let's create the rest.
Okay.
Let's say pre condition.
Okay, precondition.
Let's
all going to click this to make rules.
So we have precondition, right?
And we also have
a test case description.
Right.
Test. Case
description.
Okay.
We have a test case description.
Just go ahead and just do what I'm doing.
Guys, we're going to cover up everything.
Okay? Test case description.
We had steps. Numbers.
Okay, let's see before that.
Okay.
The covered the precondition.
Now need the steps,
numbers, the step details.
Okay, perfect.
So let's start with the steps number.
So now this document that we're creating,
let's go say and say
step.
So step number, step number.
Let's make this bold.
Okay.
And what was it? Here we have the steps.
Detailed description.
Okay. Steps.
Detail description.
Are you guys doing this?
Are you guys doing this or what?
Yeah.
Okay.
And then what else do we need?
We have an expected results
and then
we have an expected result
at the results.
Okay.
Expected result.
We have an actual
results.
Result.
And keep in mind, this is very simple task
is that we're creating
good show result
and let's include our comments.
Okay.
And something that we forgot here is
yes or no.
Okay.
So we need our comments.
Our comments
that go ahead and based.
So everything is good.
And actually let's let's change
this comments to a pass
is not done.
And then most changes to comments
and okay, are we here yet?
Are we there?
And what I'm going to do actually
does I'm going to change this.
I'm going to stop this short these.
Okay.
And the test case description.
So I'm going to change this to
test test, case description,
copy, description. It's
okay.
All right.
So are we good or are we good?
Are we good or are we good?
All right.
Give me I'm going to give you guys
another 30 seconds all the minute
and give me thumbs up once
you guys are done.
Okay?
August says
that she's ready.
It's Alanna says,
let's do it.
Jimmy says Good.
That's right.
All right, Ready?
So, test case description.
So we make this use test case
based off a user story, Right?
And this user story,
what is the user story
right here?
The user story
has this acceptance criteria.
As an Amazon user,
I should be able to go to Amazon.com
and navigate to Amazon Prime video
by clicking on the hamburger menu
and navigating to prime video
and clicking on prime video.
Okay, So we're going to right here, okay,
We're going to write
a test case description
where we have to write a description
to this test.
Go Like,
what is it that we're going to test?
I'm making it like this.
You guys can see that right here. Right?
So I'm looking at the acceptance criteria
as you see here.
All right.
You guys can see the acceptance criteria.
There it is.
So we're going to say this test
verifies that a user
is able to navigate
to navigate to prime video
by clicking
on that.
What's it called on on hamburger menu?
Must be more descriptive
of this on Amazon's home page.
Hamburger Menu.
And navigating that navigating
through their menu.
Okay.
We're going to leave this description
like this.
Cool.
What I'm also going to do
is I'm going to say Rabbit and Marsh, this
here,
I'm going to expand this.
Okay.
So and center
of text as we want.
Good. Cool. Does this make sense?
You guys see this?
Okay.
Are we good?
There you go.
Looks nice.
Okay,
so I gave this test, this description.
Okay.
We're just going to describe
just a high level
overview of this test case Description.
It doesn't need to be super detailed.
Okay, cool
Are we good?
Are you guys ready or you guys ready?
Go ahead and take the time.
Copy this down.
That's fine.
Come and give me a thumbs
up, guys, When you guys are done,
give me thumbs up.
Awesome.
Okay, cool. Now
we need to write the steps.
Okay, so for use for user story.
One, two, three, four, five.
We know the acceptance criteria.
Okay?
We know what we need to test.
Okay, So now a precondition.
What is a precondition?
Does anyone know what a precondition is?
A precondition is anything that needs
to happen knows that's not diabetes.
It's a precondition is
what needs to happen
or needs to be available
before you execute this test.
Okay, So
so it can be something like
like user is on the
on the on the Amazon home page or.
It can be something
like user has access to either Chrome
Safari or respective browser,
or it can be
something that needs to happen before.
Okay,
of the test case that makes sense.
Everyone, something is happened.
In this case, we can read the precondition
afterwards so it'll make more sense.
But let's start off
by writing the test case for this.
Okay?
So and this is where I need you guys to,
to know you will
you can actually set the precondition.
Okay.
So and I'll show you right how to do it.
So let's let's start off
by writing this test case.
Okay? Step number one.
Okay. What is that number?
Number one.
Step number one is okay, a user
navigates
navigates to WDW dot
Amazon, Amazon.com.
Okay, that is that is the first step.
So go ahead and write this
right.
This step is to
okay, step
number one,
give me thumbs up when you guys are are
alignment says we're ready.
Who else is ready?
Very good.
We have a few members that are ready
who is not doing any of this.
I just want to know
who's not doing of this?
I want this is anyone not not doing
any of this.
Okay,
Very good.
Doing it. Good, good, good.
Okay, now listen.
This a step, okay?
I've got a step.
And the test case is an action.
Okay?
That is what a step is.
What is an action
is an action is something that
an action is.
An action.
Okay, What is an action?
Something that the user will actually do?
Something that.
How did you fit
all those writings in one cell?
What do you mean in one? So
if you're writing all this text
in one cell, Farhad,
you actually had the right here
to wrap the text, Okay?
And when you click on that,
it just wraps it like this.
Got cool.
Okay, So
yeah, thanks Denver.
Thanks to Mira Awesome text.
So now this is an action.
The navigates to amazon.com.
Okay and expected results.
Okay and why says
because this is important
and expected result
is not
okay guys I see this mistake all the time.
It is not an action.
Okay expected result
is what happens
once the action has been made okay
Aisha amazing bag of money.
I said I feel
like you're already in the field.
Are you already in the field?
Come.
Not yet.
Okay,
so Aisha says Amazon homepage displays
when the user navigates to Amazon.com.
Yes, that is the expected result Amazon
on page displays.
Okay.
And for Hot,
we can wrap this text right for her.
We can wrap it.
Okay.
So we can see like this. Right.
So okay, Amazon homepage displays.
That's the expected result.
That is what has happen.
Okay. This is what is expected.
Okay. Now let's do it ourselves.
Let's go and pretend,
you know that, we're doing this again.
We're going on
Amazon.com home page, this place.
Right.
So we're running this test.
Okay.
And does it display? Yes.
So now check this out. Go check this up
whenever you are writing this.
Okay.
And the actual result is the same as you
expect.
The result, okay.
You can say as expected, right.
It depends on your project. Right.
But in some projects,
what you do is you copy,
you copy the action,
you expect the result and paste it
in the actual result.
Moscow
Cool state.
All right.
Okay.
Now they did pass yes or no
the this the that this pass
that the Amazon home page display.
Yes right it did so we're going to say yes
All right.
Cool.
Step number two,
Step two, what is step two?
What would step to be, guys?
What would step to be?
Okay, Very good.
Allen.
That is a very good descriptive stuff.
Yes. So user clicks on hamburger menu,
read Hamburger menu on left corner.
Okay,
Top left corner.
Cool. We can just read this text.
Okay.
That is the step, the expected result.
What is it?
Expect the result when they click on it.
Hamburger menu. This place. Right.
Hamburger menu displays.
Hamburger menu.
This place right.
Okay. That's he expect the results.
Read the text. Okay. Now
obviously you will know
the expected results
before you do before you execute
task is okay.
But what we're doing is I'm showing
you we're starting this from scratch.
Okay?
If the first step did not happen,
what are we right?
Then you felt it.
You felt a step.
See? Was this pass? Yes or no?
You would feel it. Okay, cool.
All right, So.
All right,
so what happened when you click on it?
What happened?
Okay, the hamburger menu displays right?
And actually
second
actual result.
Okay. Right. So.
So what are we going to do?
You can read as expected or you can copy
and paste is go see what paste is here.
Like this
and you will read the text. Okay.
That it passed. Yes. Right.
Okay, perfect.
All right.
Step three.
Do we need to be descriptive
what happened instead?
So I'll tell you this
if and that's a good question.
If if something else happened.
Right.
If I clicked. On the hamburger menu.
And the hamburger menu doesn't display,
that means I actually need
to write exactly what happened here.
Okay.
I can say.
Hamburger
menu does not display something else.
This place. Okay.
And because we didn't
get the expected result, we will failed
that step because would say no.
Does that make sense?
Here we are
we are just creating a simple task is go
user clicks hamburger
menu on top left corner guys.
What is the third step?
What is
what is it?
So do you leave?
Expect the result Menu blank.
What do you mean?
That's what was an email and those.
Yeah.
And the region
Do you do
you leave the expected result name blank.
What does that mean?
Okay so three write
digital content and devices.
Okay, we know that we need to click on
prime video, but we should probably say
something like under digital content
and devices, click on prime video.
Right?
Okay. Right.
So we can say user
user navigates
to digital.
What's it called?
Digital Can't and and devices section
and and clicks clicks on prime video.
Right.
Prime video.
Cool.
You see how descriptive I was there guys?
You see that right?
I also indicated under what section
I should be clicking.
Did you guys see this right.
I said user navigate to digital content
and devices section.
Okay.
And clicks on and
and clicks on prime video.
Okay,
cool.
What happens if it opens the menu?
One of the many
those open that we filled this step.
We're just creating a test case
for the first time.
Okay.
So what is the expected result
when you click on this?
Okay.
Prime video menu displays, right?
So the expected result, right, is Prime
video menu
menu of this device.
So that's exactly what that's
what's expected
of. What are to the text?
Okay.
So you should know
before you create a test case.
Now we know that
you expect the results, Right.
But You should not expect the results
before you actually run your test case.
Okay.
So what does creating
want to do from scratch?
Everything So just follow along. Okay.
So let's say we're testing it, right?
What happens when we click on prime video?
Prime video menu displays
right so you can just copy this
and we can paste this right here.
Cool. And did it pass?
Yes, it passed. Okay.
Step four. What is that, Four, guys?
What is step four?
The user clicks on a video to play.
No, that's not step four.
That is not step four.
What is step four? Yes.
No, no, it's not done.
We're not in the prime video homepage yet.
Why Would we stop?
Yes, exactly.
Click on prime video button. Right.
So user clicks on prime
video button, right.
Say button. That's fine.
So user clicks on prime video button.
Okay, So what happens when we click
on prime video button?
What happens, guys?
What happens?
Prime video
on page displays, right.
Okay, cool.
We're going to cut this
and we're going to copy this.
We did that. So the actual results
are the same and that it passed.
Yes, it did. Okay, cool.
And then we can label
step five and we can say, end of tests.
Okay, The end of tests.
Cool.
All right.
So this right here, please, gentlemen,
that everyone do
this or not
that everyone do this
or not.
Okay, This right here is a test case.
Okay?
If you didn't do it,
take a screenshot of it now.
Okay, But this is what a test case is.
Okay, Now I want you guys to notice
some things. Go
a step is an action, right?
Every single step right here is an action,
right?
We're indicating it like an action
when needs to happen
and expect The result is what happens
when that action took place.
Would it be incorrect to have an action
and expect a result?
I see it all the time. So let's say like,
do you guys know what I'm saying?
So like
if I say user navigates to Amazon.com,
if you guys have an action here
and expect the result, then you will fail.
Test case review.
Okay, so in your workplace
you will have test case review.
For example, in our projects
we conduct test case
reviews to make sure
that the test case makes sense
and that it's appropriately satisfying
the acceptance criteria of the user story.
Okay, so
does this make sense, guys?
So an action should not be
and the expected result column.
Okay.
Again, it should not be
in the expected result column
and expect the result is what
what is it expect the result
is what's supposed to happen.
Right.
It's what happens when you take that
action, when the user takes that action.
Okay.
And then you pass or you failed that test.
Okay, cool.
So this is test case
one and we're going to save it.
Okay.
We are going to say we go ahead
and take the screenshot of it.
Okay? Take a screenshot of it
if you haven't. Okay.
And congratulations.
Give yourselves round of applause
because you took you your first test case.
You guys, this is it.
This is a big moment.
This is a big day right here, guys.
All right. This
this like needs a celebration.
All right?
Is it's a big achievement.
Big, big achievement. Okay.
But now you need to know the rules
of creating a test case.
Cool.
Okay.
Very, very good job.
All right, now,
let's go back here.
We wrote our test case. Okay?
And even though it had these these
you know what it needs to contain at work,
you make
you may create your test cases
differently.
Okay, But they will follow some sort
of structure like this.
Does this make sense?
I'm not saying it's
going to be exactly like this, like this.
And you project some things may change.
Some things might be a little different.
Okay.
But this is essentially
what a test case would contain.
Okay.
The expected result will be determined.
The request of the VA.
Yes, sure. It's very good.
So most of the time
the VA will tell you the expected results.
Okay.
We're going to talk about precondition
in another test and another test.
We're going to talk about another.
So here
we have two samples of two test cases
that are different, that have different
values like created by,
you know, what we can do
here, let's add are created by
created by.
Okay, go ahead.
And that created by your test case.
Okay.
And write your name.
I'm going to say syntax and structure.
Okay, cool.
So created by
and then you go into your name
and that's it.
Let's see, what else should we add?
We created
this one has a review by
because we did a test case review.
So you can add that as well. Yes.
Okay.
Test data, we'll talk about that
data as well.
Okay.
We'll talk more about that as well. Okay.
So does make sense go so far?
Does this make sense?
Well,
very, very, very good.
Okay.
Very, very, very good. All right.
Let's say.
Okay, so this is a test case.
Okay.
And now
if you see this picture right here, right.
You see that it contains test data. Okay.
So we have an acceptance criteria
that requires us to or requirement
that requires us to log in
with valid credentials.
Right.
What are we going to need?
What are we going to need
if what will we need?
If we are required to log in
with valid credentials?
Yeah,
we are going to need
the credentials, right?
We are going to need the credentials.
That information is test data.
Okay, Does that make sense?
We will create test cases like that.
Okay.
That information will be,
you know, test data and stuff.
Okay, let's set a prerequisites.
Prerequisites.
Prerequisite is what needs to happen
before the test case.
You can say access to Chrome browser,
but we'll talk about better preconditions
and stuff. What the next test is
that we're going to write. Okay,
so as a task.
Okay.
For homework.
All right.
And we're going to start
picking up a lot of this stuff.
Okay.
You guys are going to be experts at.
Okay. All right.
So homework could
create a test case.
All of
user stories that
story, we're going to make it right now.
All right.
Let's say
your story.
Your story.
Let's say
I'm just going to make something up.
That's a user story idea.
And we're going to say that the acceptance
criteria,
acceptance criteria is
as a Netflix user
user, I should be able to log in
with a valid
I should be able to
I should be able to log in
with valid credentials
from the home page.
Okay.
Let's say as a Netflix user. Okay
I've got Netflix dot com.
I should be able
to log in with valid credentials
from the home page
and your credentials what is different?
Each organization has their own template.
What is the question
is a story can know user stories
I'll show you how those those work okay
you don't the user story numbers up
they're generated somehow
and when we start working with JIRA,
you're going to see
I don't have an account
who wants to give me theirs
for homework purposes
just that.
That's fine.
You don't need a Netflix account.
I just want to see
how you would write the test case.
Okay,
so as a Netflix
when visiting Netflix dot com,
I should be able to log in
with valid credentials from the home page.
Okay.
This makes sense. And I'm going to say
just data flows.
Data.
Okay. Username,
username and password
if you have a Netflix account,
use your own data.
Okay, Don't share your username
and password or just make something up.
Okay? Just make something up.
But this is the user story.
Okay.
This makes sense to everyone.
So the homework is to create a test case
for the following user story.
Cool.
All right.
And that is going to be your homework
assignment.
Okay.
Now, does anyone any questions
on anything
we already talked about?
What does data is
what is what is test data, guys?
What is test data?
What is Tuesday?
The test data is any data that you're
going to need to execute your test case.
Right?
So in case in this case, when when we're
logging in with valid credentials,
you need a username and password, right?
So in your work environment,
they will provide with this information
for this purpose,
use your own credentials.
If you have a Netflix account,
if you don't just make something up.
I'm just really looking to see how create
how you create
these, how you create your test case.
Okay, cool.
Does that make sense?
Okay. Okay.
Now do we have any questions
how to use test data and excel,
but use just enter it.
So for example, I'm not going to
write it down because that's a homework,
but maybe one of the steps can be like
user enters username
and then you pass the data or something.
You figure it out.
Okay, cool.
And it should be in your steps.
All right, where do we share homework?
Okay, So listen,
I will tell you to share the homework
on Saturday or Sunday.
Okay?
I want you guys to want to see.
And actually, actually, you know what?
Don't post any homework.
And the channel.
I want you guys to send me a screenshot
of your test
directly to me,
not to the syntax instructor,
but to the d'ivoire's instructor account.
Okay,
I'm going to be teaching
you guys this weekend.
I think you guys are doing Java.
Yes. So
direct messaged me
a screenshot of test case.
Okay, cool.
Yes. On slack.
All right.
So what I'm going to do okay, is
I don't post my notes on canvas.
Okay?
Because
I want you guys to pay attention.
Okay.
So what we're going to do is,
you know what?
Actually,
what I forgot to do is we're going to say
that you test the
class one, get
went, set my own test in class one.
But these are the notes we took.
They may be very high level,
but we already had this conversation
earlier today right.
Just look up, Diego and you'll find it.
All right.
So what I'm going to do
is I'm going to share these notes.
What do you guys want them
on the life questions or of course,
announcements are where. But
what's easier
for you guys?
Yes, I don't post on canvas.
I don't post on on campus.
I don't post on canvas.
So I will post the task on course
announcements.
Okay, cool.
Posted there.
This over.
Does anyone have any questions?
Did you guys learn anything today?
Which by the way, congratulations
this is your first manual
testing course
that you guys have successfully completed.
Okay, cool.
And next class and the following classes
and so forth.
It's going to get very,
very, very hands on.
Okay.
So again, we are posting
you guys are sending me a screenshot.
Okay, Submit your assignments
by sending me a direct message on Slack
by sending me
a direct message on Slack.
Okay, cool.
The homework is due
next on Monday.
Okay. Or
due Monday.
Visit date October one, October 12.
Right.
So we're talking that October 11th.
Yeah, October 11th.
Oh, are you sure?
It's October 11, six, seven, eight,
nine, ten.
Well, yeah, it's 11 four, so due Monday.
1011. Okay.
And I will post this task
and of course announcements shortly.
Okay, cool.
All right, guys, do we have any questions?
You guys will also get the slides as well.
Okay.
You guys will get the slides as well.
Cool.
You guys will get the slides.
Slides as well.
All right.
So I hope you enjoy today.
Let me know
if you guys have any questions.
We're going to learn a lot more.
Okay.
You right now,
you may have a lot of questions.
We're going to cover all that
with the next classes. Okay.
Everything is going to make sense.
Yes. The slides will be on canvas.
They'll be updated, uploaded shortly.
Cool. Bye, guys.
Could you put your entire name
here, please?
My name is Diego Suarez.
Okay,
so thank you, Alexis.
All right.
All right, guys,
If you need help or, have questions.
Just send me an email or direct message.
Enjoy your night. Very good job today.
All right, next class,
we're going to hit the ground running.
Okay.
We're going to hit the ground
running Our of the night, guys.
Have a good night.