See her experience.
Can you see my screen?
Everyone?
Great
and great.
And I will send you the equity that will
definitely help you in that case.
So yesterday,
what was the first thing, guys?
We don't.
Tell me what was the very first thing
that we implemented
and we.
That's great.
This this is something I'm
looking forward to.
This is something I look forward from
you guys.
Yeah. Jamal. Correct.
First, right, we need to identify
whatever the operations in our framework,
whatever the operation in our framework,
we are using again and again, right
When we identify
that these are the operations,
these are the commands
I will be using again and again
in my framework.
What I will do, basically, I will keep
all of these functions in one class.
I have one platform right?
So instead of calling
and instead of using
those commands, let's
say 1000 things in my framework plate.
So it doesn't make any sense. Right?
But if I can drive
this particular command,
this particular function,
it will take from it one place.
In my framework, I can utilize
the same function again and again.
All I need to do is
I just need to change the element array.
For example, click operation.
So to perform,
click on any of the element,
I don't need to call the entire driver
defined element by dot dot click.
It doesn't make any sense.
So the very first thing, what we did,
we put all these common functions,
all these common methods, for example,
sending the data files in text,
clicking on operations of click bait
for applicability.
So grateful click ability
and then JavaScript executable click.
All of these methods
to put where in common methods
so that we can utilize these methods.
We can utilize these functions again
and again.
All we need to do
is we just need to update element.
That's it, right?
This was the first thing.
The second thing, what we did yesterday
was creating the object repository, right?
The principle of page
object, modern design, python.
That's what we know why we need this page
object model design python.
So the very first requirement is
if you are using
if you're using your locators again
and again,
if you are trying to use your locators
and in case if your locator change,
then what happened?
What would happen in that case, you have
to change your locators at 1000 places.
If you have written them
1000 business rate.
Instead, which object model allows you
to write your object repository
in a particular class,
in a particular feature
that belongs to a particular screen.
And then you can use the key
for that particular locator.
So now this time you can use the same key
for 1000
different classes in different packages
at the same time.
If your locator changes,
what you need to do is basically
you just need to update one key like this.
For example, if I have this user name
so I'm not going to use this I.D.
everywhere.
I'm going to use this key everywhere
because I made it public.
Right?
And then in future, if something changes,
I do need to change it 1000 places.
I would change it here only.
And then it will be applicable throughout
my project whenever I utilized it.
Correct.
This is what we discussed.
Next thing is.
Next thing is how?
How are we actually using this page object
model design?
So basically we are going to initialize
the elements by our page
three concept, right?
We generally utilize initialize
these elements,
how we define the constructor of the class
and inside the constructor of the class,
we write this speech tree, this element.
So init element is the command
to initialize the elements.
Whatever the objects we are writing
and the functions we are writing inside
one class.
This particular command
allows us to initialize all these elements
when the moment, the moment we create
the object of this particular class,
it allows us to initiate
all these elements, initialize
all these elements in any other class,
and then we can use all of them
there, right? For our writing
that that's what we call framework.
Doesn't matter which website you're using,
the fundamentals,
the basic fundamentals will always be
same, will always be same.
So if you're working for next website,
what would happen?
You will change the you are an objective
state where in configured properties
you have the setup right there
different log in bind.
You can go and put different
user name and different password,
find different locators.
Fine, you can change the pages
according to the application.
For example,
you might not be able log in page,
you might be having the registration page
or sign signup page as opposed to it.
Right.
So you can write the code for sign
a patent registration page here,
create a new page for that,
and then whatever, if you're
working on two websites at the same time.
All right.
So these are two different projects,
let's say.
Right?
If you're handling two different websites
and these are two different projects,
remember, you can't do much to project
in single framework, right?
So if you're handling two projects,
then you you'll be heading
to different frameworks.
If yeah, there are two scenarios, right?
IGLESIAS Let me tell you this.
This is the question, right?
When came to
the explanation came in my mind right now.
So it's going to create a new model
Whenever you go in a frame,
whenever you go and join a new project,
then you have to do it right.
Either
they will give you or you have to create.
Now, no too many of this sentence.
If you're working on two websites, see
two environment and two projects, right?
Blue Project means two different web
application for two different customers
or for two different products.
Basically right there,
obviously you have to use your different
projects, different frameworks,
different syntax, different approaches.
Everything would be different
because customer is different.
But if we talk about same website,
if we talk about same project,
but you're testing it on test environment,
you are testing it on stage environment,
you are testing it on a site environment,
right?
So these are the three environments
belong to same application,
getting their point.
What we generally do is in for example,
in my current project,
we first test everything on GW1
environment quality,
then we test everything on site
and land certified.
Then we test everything
on test environment
and then we deploy it onto the product.
And so how many And my mix we have,
we have five environments.
Dev served one test and tried
strategy.
You don't need to copy anything, right?
You just need to understand the concepts,
what you really need
in your framework, right?
This is just to open up
all the avenues right for you
so that you can create the picture
in your mind.
You can visualize the things you might
because copying
the configured properties
is not a big deal the way maybe.
Yes. Yes. Correct. Subject Correct.
That's what architecture does best.
Architect, Technical architect.
That's what the people do.
If you know the concept,
if you know how things work,
you are able to and you will be able
to create this from scratch.
All right.
So now in this case, right
where you're testing the same application
in testing one and the same application,
same coding decision,
when we then you need to create
two different frameworks.
No, you don't need to do that.
What you need to do is you just need
to a bit worried that you need to pass
to a different audience from your content
or property is fine and that is correct.
But if my environment is best,
then take this.
You are in.
If my environment is this big, this
you are like this
and then you will be dealing
with my people.
The way we're passing it for
browser is of no right.
Similarly, you can pass the same thing
for your multiple environments.
Your architect is a high level stuff.
Architect is a high level
engineer is basically a person
who writes the automation script,
but this artist architect is the person
basically who creates the framework,
identify the requirements from technical
point of you, set up the testbed
provides everything to create a readymade
working framework for Kuma engineer.
And what you engineer does
basically start writing
the code and integrate the reports
in the existing framework.
That's what the engineer does.
Yeah, you don't need right now
because we are using the framework, right?
We're using the existing framework.
So we will not.
Then the next topic was bossing
the data layer data provider, right?
So in the advanced degree
I told you right area of it
we created to the Eric yesterday
and we were passing the data
providing data provider
to verify the error rate.
So this was our data provider?
Yeah, correct.
Correct. Many of you guys will not
remember.
Don't call it a website.
This is a project right in the industry.
When you go, you call it project.
This is my project.
This is your project, right?
Or if this project belongs
to your organization,
it means this is your product, right?
You build in-house things when you will.
In-house things
you develop in-house things.
This is product.
When you build things, then you develop
the things for customer recall project.
This is the difference between project
and product.
Product in general itself.
You build in-house
and you try to sell right?
For example,
Amazon Prime Video, Alexa, Netflix,
these are products of these companies
right at the same time projects
if they guys are giving the contract
to other companies
to develop this things
for those companies, these are projects
and that's the difference
in European project and product
all great.
Also let me give you
because we are discussing this thing.
So let me give you another important
information.
Two types of industries we have in I.T.
The first is product based
and the second is service based.
You know, what is the difference between
product based organization and service?
But organization
in I.T., in I.T.
industry, technical part,
we have two types of companies
because this product based
and second is service based
product with company,
for example, Facebook I.T.
Company.
But they have their own product, Facebook
messenger, they have their own product,
but they have their own product.
Cisco that is also product
based organization, right?
They have their own products, static.
On the other hand,
the second one is for example, Accenture,
Cognizant Gap, Gemini, right.
They are service based organizations. Why?
Because they think the projects
for different clients,
they work for different
client. For example,
Department of Health and Security, DHS,
D.O.D.,
Bank of New York,
Ally Bank, Jp morgan Chase.
Right.
So these companies take projects
from these clients and they give their
services to those clients.
So these are service
based organization, right?
So two types of industry.
Always remember product based and service
based.
Fine, Let's proceed for the device. Yes.
If you want to work on a different
right now for testing.
Right.
Right now for learning purposes,
you can utilize this one only.
Right.
But when you go in the organization,
then yes, if there is no framework
in place already, then you're supposed
to create the new one from scratch.
In that case.
All right.
So now now,
let me ask you one thing, guys.
This one hour right.
This one hour, what we are going to
discuss is extremely important, right?
So I just want you to pay
your complete attention for this one hour.
The first thing, what I will do
basically, is I can see here
all in my
this normally first guess, right?
I am writing this discourse
like this. Fine.
But am I using any particular group
or I am utilizing
any text injured or text? Yes.
No. Right.
So let's execute it quickly
using one extended or take symbol.
Right.
Let's create some group
and using that group.
Execute this particular test
in just one minute or 2 minutes
and then we'll switch on to the new topic.
All right.
So tell me, guys,
if I'm going to add some employee,
what type of group would that be?
This test because belong to which group?
Any idea?
Obviously smoke, right.
So let me.
Right smoke right now.
Now, tell me strengths
how we can how we can create this
and you don't exemplify
how we can do that.
Right? Let me create
correct
right click on the project.
It says create a standard or text symbol.
Select this and it will create your test
and neurotic symbol.
You'll see.
Are you getting what I'm doing?
All right now, command.
Everyone knows for Windows users
control out and for automatic.
Let me not include the method name here.
Right.
And not take this class.
Also, I'm taking the simple class
now I'm giving
this name as I'm giving this name
as my smoke protect symbol fight.
Fine.
So this is my smoke
because I need a proper segregation.
Why you do not have you?
What do you have to do?
Basically is just click here
or for plug ins.
Right?
Right here, plug ins.
And here you have to select this one,
create test and examine.
Right in India.
And Masood, in market place,
you have to search for create, test
and do not examine.
For example, if I. Right.
Create this test and examine right.
And when I write this create
test into x email because it is already
installed in my machine.
Right.
It will give you a one green icon
like this here to install.
When you click on install,
just click. Okay.
And then after this restart
your intelligent idea.
Right. Intelligent.
Here you will be able to create a new test
and you detect someone fine.
After that, you will get that option.
All right.
Negates control all l
If you're a mac user, then it will be.
Come on, option.
Come on.
And like that, fine. No,
no. After this,
we have to include artist tickets, right?
Based on grouping.
So which group it is right?
The groups here
I'm going to write
in this particular test.
And inside this group,
I have to write the run
it since
I'm going to write
including name as
small
guys.
Any confusion in this?
I wrote it right
so that you guys can also write with me
which group I want to include smoke
right in this particular class,
whatever that is.
Because this belong to smoke,
I will be able to execute all of them
from here.
Correct.
You can change this.
You can change these classes from packages
also.
Right.
So inside your test cases, for example.
In in your this test cases because now
in out of the work we know one thing
all the test cases are available
inside this test
because this package only right
so if I want a single distribution
I don't need to mention any class
I can mention.
This package test gives this In whatever
the test cases belong to small category,
it will execute all those tests
to get this right.
So to do that, if not classes,
then I have to write what I have
to write packages, statements
if I want to use only packages.
And then here I will write
package name is equals to
statistic assets.
So now
with this setup, with this setup,
what would happen?
It will execute all the test cases.
Even if I have to test case 100 or 200
test cases belong to this particular
group Smoke, it will execute all of those
first guesses.
Right.
So let's see how many test cases
you can execute.
For me for smoke.
Yes, Correct.
And then when you created this test case
for error, employed? No.
Remember we called
this log in is fit inside the test case.
We already call that log in
step right inside.
So that's why it will execute
beyond the you showed.
That's what I am saying.
This is this segregation rate.
Now we are doing a high level
segregation rate.
So we are not going inside every class
and every method.
Intel, this one to execute
this will not be execute.
We are saying, hey,
go ahead
in your whatever the classes you have,
whatever the test gives
us, you have I want to execute
based on two separations.
The first one is the smoke.
The second one is regulation point.
I will create smoke,
not examine the way I created.
Right.
I will pass my package there
because I know
now I don't have to execute
all the classes.
All of my best guesses are available
inside.
Just one package contains this, right?
So I'm passing this.
This package gives package
and it will execute
all the smoke related scenarios.
Yeah, I will go.
Yeah, this is the best of it.
That's why we are using framework now.
Now what I will do basically is
see it executes an employee test.
You go you I just added one thing here.
This group smoke. That's it.
I didn't get any of that thing.
All right, now,
now the next thing you see,
this is my small symbol.
Correct.
Now, let me create another
another test and define.
And I will give
I will give this final name as
I'm creating another
test and do not like symbol.
And I will do
this by name as
integration vortex me.
Now when I give integration DOT
accepted here again I will do one thing
instead of writing packet classes
I will write.
I can just like
again all the packages
and then here I will write
exit name
has to get.
Then this time.
This time if I want to include any group,
I want to include any group.
So what I will write simply is
in this regression vortex symbol
I will execute only those test.
Is this there belong to a regression?
Sure, sure, sure.
I'll give you a time.
See, this is your smoke.
Right in your suitcase.
This is your smoke.
First done with this part.
The smoke part.
And then I will open the creation
also for you. Yes.
Just click.
Okay. It means it's done.
It's already created. Click. Okay.
And then just right
click on your project to reload from this.
And then you will find this test
and neurotic simplified
renaming to smoke and regression.
Right.
And then pass this
group tag in both of the file
all project level.
You don't need to do this
because see where you need to identify
with all of your test
to get this out of all your test because
it's available throughout your project
or just inside one package.
Where are they?
Because you already already collected
all of them inside one package, right?
So that package waiting here. Right.
The whole intention
is to simplify the process, right?
So we already made it highly simplified.
You don't need to
to go throughout your project, otherwise
it will probably lead to confusion.
Right.
You're having all of your test cases
inside one package that is test kits.
This this time.
This time you have to focus on
just one package and take it.
You're passing in your smoke
and both the same package you're passing
and segregation will be done right
based on your group.
I didn't I didn't do that.
Yes. Yes.
Correct. Correct.
So now let me do one thing.
I will go inside of my essay test
and I will make any test.
For example,
this because I will take it as
group score
integration.
So my one test
because belong to regression here.
One test because belong to.
Yes. Right. That's what I write. Correct.
Now same package I provided integration
and is multiple this time
when you execute this a smoke
doesn't matter if you have 1000 smoke test
get this in your test because this package
it will execute all of them.
I'm not doing anything.
I'm not doing anything at all.
I'm just explaining the things right.
I didn't execute anything.
I didn't do anything.
I just added this part here,
the one liner, because I forgot to
do that.
So I just did it
and I came back again on this part.
Now I'm giving you the time.
See, the smoke detector
symbol implement is done.
This is your regression or similar.
And here you can write
does this look
and eight.
That's what I'm thinking already.
It's a bit surprising for me also
I'll invite all north
by all just smoke this to get suspected
vi all there is no point date of execution
All there is
the point of segregation,
the distribution point, this group.
Right.
And when I'm specifically mentioning
that this distant symbol
has to execute, only those test cases
belong to small category date.
So it really never execute
all the test cases,
but only those belong
to this particular part.
Smoke
Then everyone.
And then.
Welcome back.
You already cross,
but maybe there
it will execute
because you're mentioning this right
with a direct test annotation.
The point of creating this test,
this package is
you are having all of your test cases
inside one package.
Great.
So now you found one
execution point that whenever
in this logic test, if you come right,
then admin log in here to put that in line
number 13.
All right.
So now you whenever you think that
okay I need to write new test case.
So where would you write in the framework
you know you have one package
you will always write your new test
kits inside test kits.
This package. Right.
And this part you've already parsed in
your smoke as well as in your regression.
Right.
So now all you need to do is just
you need to specify the group name
with your test case.
That's it.
And when you execute
this to detect single file,
it will execute
all of your test cases
below the smoke and ignition
category
of Actually,
this is the issue with the application.
Mike Sometimes I can say yes.
Machine also a
did some error. Yes.
Yes. Yeah.
My to be clear because you can see right
even when I execute
test cases on each right,
sometimes it gets weird.
So yes it happens.
Technically correct
followed.
Now guys,
shall we move on to our next topic,
which is super important?
They take me, do it.
So now, now, guys, remember
when we're passing this data to way
right here?
When I'm passing this data
away to the class, if you see
what is the problem, you can see here,
the problem is for small volume of data.
For small volume of data, two users,
three users, five users of users.
It is completely fine. Right?
But if I am having data 1000 users,
then this data provided is applicable.
This data provided is visible only.
It's not visible.
If you need to check
access groups
in integration, you put it
on, everything is fine
then money doesn't work,
nor does it work on you.
Executive Which one
should
I will. I will change that.
I will look into this.
What is the purpose?
Oh, come on, you'll see when you mention
this is equal to integration.
Right in that package name.
This is equal to regression.
You need to change it.
This slash rate after double code
slash out.
Right.
You're putting slash inside.
Getting my point.
If you see in your regression vortex
single file you put package
name is equal to post cases slash.
This should not come with test cases.
It should go out right in double code,
just name of the package.
And after double code it should be slash.
That's the issue.
Then you fix it you will be
able to execute your test, correct?
Correct.
All right.
So now
now my requirement is
because when you work in the real life
situations, your life project, right,
you always deal
with a large volume of data,
over 1000 users, tens, 2000 users
you need to test.
And the data is also dynamic.
Sometimes you are having three
or four for you
and sometimes you are having seven,
eight, six,
sometimes you are having ten or 12 pains.
Right here,
we know the fields are constants.
We are passing three, three, three, three.
That's fine.
What if we have to pass three things
here, four here, seven here, nine here?
What would happen in that case?
Data provider will not work.
Great, because your data volume is fixed.
Volume of the small size is fixed,
data provided is visible.
What if everything is dynamic?
Data provided is not a good option
in that case.
So what is the good option
in that scenario?
For example,
let me tell you this my application
and in
this application, when I right here,
let's see,
it means
I will go and try to add employee, right?
Yes. Yes.
So now now, if you see here,
here I have to enter first name, right?
I have to enter last name.
I have to intermittently
I have to choose photographer as well.
Right.
So why photograph?
Because I have to
I have to upload one picture
then I have to select
this create log in details.
I have to enter user name,
password, confirm password and save.
Fine.
So how many data I employed in case.
123456.
Right.
Let's a password control password right
the way you guys were saying earlier,
three belong to same thing.
Let's consider not seven, just six.
All right.
In this case.
In this case, when you work in the actual
right there, you might be having
1000 employees or 2000 employees and 3000
employees, right?
Maybe some of them are operating just
for the same last thing, not meeting them.
Some of them are providing all the names.
Right. Everything.
But the volume of data is not right.
The volume of data is large.
At the same time, when you have to provide
immediate support,
except Egypt, you don't see
and you don't give up to one minute.
So you have to test this part also
that you have to upload one image, right?
How you can upload the image
there is another point
how you can provide the data
in the same fields, right?
But for multiple sets of data,
you can pass in one scenario.
So these are the things these are
the things we have to perform.
And then we need one particular platform.
We need one for taking that we to check
and to save all this data
in my application.
And then at the same time I can keep
my data safe and secured, right?
So the physical solution is to have
one data, part
one fine for having the test data, right?
All just to keep all of your data
at one place in a particular file
and then read this data, read this
data rate, read this data in one function,
and then call this particular function
in your class in your test case, correct.
Understood the
approach. What I will do see,
let me explain to
you from this table.
Now, what I'm saying basically is
in this one particular fight, right.
I will keep all of my data right.
For example, my first name will be here
and then will be your last name will be
right, photograph would be here.
The user name will be here,
password will be
right.
When I keep all of this things
here, right?
I will.
I will do one thing.
I will write one function right.
I will write one function dysfunction
this function
and read read all the data
right from this particular file.
It will read all the data
in this function.
All right.
And then after this,
this is my actual test case, for example.
Right. So we don't want
this is my best guess, right?
While writing my test case,
I will call this particular function here.
Right. And based on the key.
Based on the key,
I will pull all this data in my function.
Correct.
So this part is separated
that I keep all of my test data.
These park is separated in my framework
that I'm reading all my data from fight.
These part is separated
where I'm calling the function
to read the data in my test case. Right.
So if anything changes, for example,
something change
in your data point noise,
you just change your function, right?
And then call this function in your test.
It will read the data
according to your form.
If next time your test scores
change, fine.
In your new test case, call this function
and your new test will work
only if you want to change something
and improve something in your function.
Fine. Just improve that function.
That new function will really work
as data use
that function in your test case
and it will get the data from your flight.
So these are three different
things will be available
in your framework, right?
In your framework.
And then no, you don't need to know.
That's what I'm saying.
This is the concept of dynamic testing,
right?
We call it data
driven test by Data-Driven test.
When we call it
data driven test, let me write it
when we execute
our test case.
Right.
Or I should write
STEM test is
across
people sets of data.
We call it
data driven testing.
All right, now, now
let me come here in my framework
and I will go to my notes.
Right. Couple of things.
Couple of things.
First, I would like to write here
and then we will go for the implementation
Part three.
So now what are the things I want
right here?
The first thing is
we have seven, right
as a big automation tool, correct?
We have MAVEN,
we have testing, right?
Testing as a tool
for testing 23
to grow
or test cases.
Correct.
To perform
batch testing.
Guys, remember to get the force
right.
And then we will
be having we are having ball
which are designed by then.
Why are we using this arm
as our design? Then
maintain
speed element to maintain simple
hosting?
Right.
If you want to write,
I can write in detail also.
For example, how are we using them
and how are we writing everything right
there?
For example,
using at the rate defined by page 50.
But every page we create a separate
Java class.
We create
separate Java class for
every page in form based object model.
Now, now we have data
driven test in our framework.
My framework supports data driven testing.
It means for
testing the same
functionality right
across
my people or
in different states.
All data, different sets of data.
This is the first thing.
This is what they said
they want test best.
Alright, how we can do it.
So basically using
the data provider.
And the second thing is using Excel,
correct?
Correct.
We have Maven.
I told you why we are using Maven.
We have tested.
I told you why are we using We have all
we have data driven framework.
So now if someone asked
what kind of framework
you have, so you have to explain
what my framework supports
data driven testing,
then they will ask
what is declarative want testing?
So you will understand
what your data driven testing is.
Something when I can execute, I can test
my single and same functionality
across multiple sorts of data
or across different sets of data.
For example, if a log in functionality
is there, I can send
valid username password in,
but it is a name password, blank
username, password, write, error
verification, everything I'm passing.
It means like multiple
or different sets of data I'm
passing to test to this same admin
admin log in functionality.
This is what we call detected event based.
If they ask well how many of
is blasting their data from?
So you can see we can pause the data,
our framework data for later
or you can pause their data point.
Right.
So data provider,
we have already seen a next point
which we have
seen now is using excellently
our data
driven test and is data driven.
But if I knew this of
the comparison rate,
when we will create another framework
called Cucumber, then I will give you
another approach is driven.
Here it is detective and rate.
That's what we call the driven
developing entity
of data is not that crazy in the market
right Obviously data driven test.
And the another one which is coming
that is more crazy in the market
even way beyond this just in the next one
which is coming.
So we'll compare all of these
different approaches when we learn that.
But also that is what we call BDD
behavioral driven development.
All right.
That one also, we will look.
So now, now, without wasting further
time to explore it further,
then we guys are I said right.
I already identified the scope
that I have to parse this data
to earn an employee,
so I have to add firstname with the name.
Last point I have to add the photograph,
the part of the photograph find username
password again, phone password.
These are the details I have to pass.
So let's see.
I want to add five employees, right?
Using Excel. Correct.
Now I tell you how this Excel file
will work,
but before that create one excel, right?
Let's create an Excel.
Find that we will keep in that symbol.
Now tell me if I want to keep my test
data safe and secure
in my framework, which is the place where
I can keep this data safe.
It which place I can keep
my data safe.
First of all,
creating the Excel file,
inputting that this data inside
the light is Java or non Java
non c, C
is data is not A configuration
B have to keep it in mind data sources.
So what I will do is I will create
I will create
another directory called
NS data.
Right?
And inside this is data,
I will keep my excel.
All right.
What I will keep
I will keep my Excel point here.
Okay, now, now remember this.
There are two types of Excel.
Find the older more general ways.
Using grade
B data is will be having DOT excellence
and the new over gen you guys are using
that you will be having dart excel
liquidated here.
Dart excellence and dart excel.
This is the new with one new login.
When you create the file
you will be having this extension.
Right?
So let's create one point
I already have one, right?
But I'm going to create the new one.
So let me create
new a complaint from here.
Thank.
This is my new Excel file I opened.
You guys can also open UNIX
and find everyone can open
this.
Everyone can open a new Excel file
and then you will see, Guys,
are you doing it with me?
Everyone?
Yeah, sure. Yes. Yes.
We are passing their data.
We will going to pause their data from you
next.
What we are going to add on right now.
So now, now I'm going to write C first
I need to identify from here.
First name, middle name, last name,
photograph, user name, password.
Right.
These are the fields I have
and I need to pass these data
in my application through these fields
I have to pass.
So let me write them one by one.
I will write it as
first name, fragrance, and then
middle name.
And then
the last name.
photograph.
I will tell you how to use this photograph
as well.
After this I will pass some username
and then I will
pass.
Correct? Correct.
We will put the if.
Now, if you see here guys,
what flexibility you have when you use X
and this is your one file, right.
This is your one Excel workbook inside
one workbook,
even if you have two files, data
belong to different department.
You don't need to create multiple Excel
workbook.
You can have multiple sheets.
They can you see this is my sheet one.
Okay, this is my sheet one.
You can have shoot to shoot three shoot
for in number of shoots.
You can have inside one workbook. Correct.
So next time what you need to do
is when you are going to read the data
for any other department,
the same file will read data.
From here.
You just need to click. For example,
this is mine.
Let's see, I'm going to rename it and I'm
going to give the name s employee data.
Right?
So this is my employee data. Correct?
Categories.
First name, last name.
So now I want to add just three employees.
Not much.
So yes.
And the ADL companies
use the Excel Files and sequel.
If there is a database connectivity
required in the Use sequel.
My sequence
sometimes Oracle or any other MongoDB,
but if the data they have
they kept it in the actual they use Excel.
So let me create some user guys
I'm requesting.
Don't use this user,
which I will be using.
Yes, right.
To add the employee,
otherwise it will not work.
So I will create some combination here.
I'm writing.
Yeah, right.
Don't worry,
I will change the last moment.
So let me take first to use it as and
middle name as sure.
Last name is
fine, right?
Is there to use
correctly correct. Right.
This is the first name.
Last name and really fine.
And then user name.
So let's say user
name would be I'm going to write is
and that should
one correct.
Great.
Okay.
And the password I'm going to write
password is not an issue.
So I'm going to write this same password.
This is the password.
Angry.
Now let's take the second one.
Black
mania.
Lena.
It would be black men there.
One, right.
And then the same password again.
I'm using now.
Now I'm writing for about 30 user
Michael
Andre
Jamal.
Mike the one
and then the same one.
So guys, I want to add, right?
These three employees,
both name last name and written name.
Now I need photograph
for these three, correct
names.
Can you
see I need photograph for these three.
So I have these photographs already
available with me if you want.
Right.
What you can do simply
is because your application
says if you go here
jpg image it accepts.
Right? Fine.
So you just go.
You just go here and write
images
from here.
You will find so many images, right?
You can download
any JPEG image from here, correct?
I have already downloaded images,
so let me show you
those images that I have available
on my desktop.
No, not in my data store.
If you add image three, right.
Image to an image, these are the images
I have
the actually correct.
So this is my image one, right?
This is my image too.
This is my image. Three.
Right. For all the three users.
For all the three users,
I will use this images to upload.
Correct.
Is it correctly?
Nice. So as of now.
As of now,
let me put away the part right from here.
So how can I provide the path
for these images
simply going to property right click
and it will give you the path.
So this is the part it is giving me.
Funny,
I know image one.
Image two, Image three.
I will keep it.
So let me go back to my Excel sheet.
There you go.
And here simply I'm writing this part
now. If you see inside photos,
the first one I have my image, dark
image, which image?
It is jpg I'm using.
Correct?
Is this correct?
And image two here I'm using this one.
Image three I'm using this one.
Fine.
Sure.
You just need to click on you
just write, perform right, click right.
It will give you the complete on Mac. Also
you will see other copy portrait prints.
There you will find that
the guys so far in editing this data,
there isn't any confusion.
All clear
now let's try to save it now.
So I'm going to save it anywhere because
anyway, I'm going to put it in my project.
So let me keep it inside or
anywhere on my desktop.
I'm going to keep it.
As of now.
So this would be my HRA.
This is data.
Yeah, I will give you time.
I will give you time. Don't worry.
I'm just trying to add
this file in the project
and then I'm going to give your time
so that you can also do the same thing.
Okay, So it's hard to miss this data.
Okay, let's save it.
Some of it.
Let me right here
magically correct
it saves each item is data batch time.
Let me check where I have this
this is the file.
I'm going to copy this file from here.
I'll be
and then
I will simply paste
my file here in my is data.
Put the actually correct correct.
Now if you guys see in my project right.
If you guys see in my project, I'd better
make this data when I added this fight
it is having the extension dot
excellent six right.
This is the newer file format for Excel
dot excellent six dot excellence we had.
It was the previous for
project
of Stepney.
You just need to copy the file
from your wherever you have stored
that same copy and paste it here.
And then when you pasted inside your test
data just posted by you can see this dot.
It's an extension of your file.
This is the Excel file
where you kept all of your data.
All right.
Okay.
So now please are download free images.
Like I said, right?
The location I gave you the JPG extension
and when you are done
with preparing the test data,
do let me know
up a sure sign, right?
You just right click on your image.
Go into the properties right right.
Click on your images.
Going to the properties, for example
here, right click.
Go into the properties and great exists.
And then this is the location, right?
You need to keep this location.
And remember when you copy this location
and when you paste it in your file
here, slash
the name of your file with the extension.
So for example, image.
Image two, image three I have.
So I kept all this three here
getting my point.
All right.
And then in this point, notice
Stefano, brick by brick time.
Sorry.
Today something very important
we are going to discuss
right now.
It says jpg It will accept the JPT
so we should go with JPG as of now.
Should
you see it says JP during
JPG don't be injured or if so, because no
jpg is of now right.
This okay.
All right now
I'm giving you the time because
the next 1520 minutes are very important.
Not I don't think so
but JP did the smallest small
one is the correct one.
I think so.
Just take the small one.
Next 25 minutes or half an hour.
I need your complete attention, guys,
because the code
which we are going to write and the what
the concept, which I'm going to explain
this is very important.
All right.
So let me do once you guys are done
with providing this file
in your framework and passing the data
in your Excel filing everything
in this point,
when you reach when you can see this data,
which I did this
rank and file, do let me know
and then you don't need to create it.
You have already created this file,
Save it in your machine
and just copy paste it.
Simple.
Copy this file better
when it is a stored and saved here.
A biscuit here.
All right.
I told you already. Right.
Long enough will have you can find.
Find the part.
All right.
No, didn't should be doing. Yes.
We need to identify that reason.
Another thing you can do
is maybe you can try, but I can drop.
All right.
Just drag it from there
and drop it inside of this data.
And I.
Can you try drag and drop operation?
Okay.
Alright, let's connect
after the session. Right.
And then we'll see
what is the issue with it Intelligible.
We'll look into that part.
Okay.
We'll see that for sure. All
right. My
hope.
Yes, we're doing ready.
Great.
So to all the geniuses now,
we have
we have one thing already in place,
isn't it?
We are done with this part, Correct?
I'm giving you the overview. Right.
We have one data point.
We kept all of the data.
One place we stored it in our framework
and this part is done or not.
So I need your full energy
now for the next half an hour.
It'll be very interesting, Right?
Done.
Now, now the next time.
Next thing.
This part that's taken by this part,
we are going to make
what we are going to make.
We are going to make a function.
We are going to make a function
that will read my X
and find doesn't matter how many rows,
how many columns, how many fields has
what kind of data it is.
These single function, universal function
will read all kind of data
from my Excel file and give it to me
so that I can use this data to.
My best guess is right.
This is the most important point.
Mentioning data here is not a big deal
using data here in
this case is not a big deal.
Trade.
The most important point is writing
this function, which will act
as an intermediary
in between these two parts.
So let's go ahead
and try to work on this particular
point.
Let's start.
So inside my utility again, I'm going
right inside of my utility.
I'm going and I am writing another method,
another class, right.
A separate class to read my Excel data.
Separate class to read my Excel data,
fine.
Let's go ahead and create.
So the name of my class,
I'm going to write simple one call,
Accelerating class, right?
Correct.
It is accelerating class by
I got this class here
now. Now, tell me one thing right.
First
I have to open my file before reading.
Write Whenever you read any book,
what do you generally do?
You open the book first and then you read.
Without opening, you can't read anything.
So my first math would be public
void, open
exit.
Correct.
Guys,
Now this method will ask.
All right, I have to open the Excel file.
I said Yes, it says
which with which excel fighting it open.
So I will say I'm going to provide
you defined but simple.
All right.
Now, delegates, this part
the part of my this Excel fight.
If I want to provide that,
I have to provide this part
to provide the part of my file,
which is the best place I have
in constants. Correct.
Because the bias part is final.
So I will copy this path from here.
Let's copy the path now.
Go In your constraints,
isn't it very easy right names
to identify where we need to add the
But why are we going to add the path here?
And there is entities can be
because framework
is allowing you to do
all of this things correct.
So I'm going to write
a public static line. Then
all this
data you able to find your exam point
right.
Sean, can you see the Excel file
you have here?
And then I'm going to give the name as
is data file
social.
Basically what you some you do.
How did we add you simply copy your file
it best to here.
That's it.
Now guys, tell me to come out to this to
achieve this particular project directly.
Right.
Instead of writing the hard coded part,
can I use this particular part?
Can I use this button?
Authenticates.
Right.
So let me write here.
System dot
good property
user talk, dear.
Right.
Let's
in double quotes.
Right.
You have to provide the same path
for the resources.
Correct.
So and the resources
and the resources here
inside of
resources you have what can we days
inside resources you have here
is data write slash complete name h.r.
And this data badge.
Then don't extend this x
so far in this part.
Any compute instruments?
How did i provide this data file? But
everything is clear.
So for everyone
I know,
even if you're not writing this part
or even if you're not getting this part,
are you able to understand
how I provided this data file?
But okay, just don't worry about adding
the file.
I take care of that.
I'll tell you how to how we can.
We will definitely find some way for that.
All right, great.
So now we have added to instead of fine.
But this time when I go in my Excel
reading right here, the very first thing
which I'm going to make
what I have to here is
I have to write this to open the
Excel file or any other file.
Right.
I have to use if I is file input stream,
correct
post existence of workbook rule, right?
That is for sure.
But right now must file input stream.
So I'm going to write file
inputs in which file.
So I already have a perimeter file, but
guys see it is again giving me the error.
What is the error?
Catch block.
I have to write for that.
Right?
Since we have already done this part,
right?
Since we have already done this part
and telling you how we are doing it.
File not found exception. Right.
So this one would be a file
not found exception E
and then you can write it or print
this file.
Not inside this inside this.
Right.
I have to open
my workbook. So let me write
workbook book is equals to new.
Remember?
I remember
it is giving you a workbook and x workbook
when you are using dot x
and A6 when you're using dot x
and as x extension file,
you have to use X's workbook.
All right.
And when you are using dot X
and as extension of Excel find,
you have to use edge as F workbook.
Make sure this gateway
to keep this point in mind.
I'm not sure you're using this audio
to sing topics to this, but yes, accesses
if in which case when you're using dot
Excel is extension and
F workbook,
in which case when you're using DOT
excellent extension clear.
And then here the if I have to find
so I will write if I use
all right again it is giving me the error
why it says add catch clause
fine for an exception.
So I get the catch plus
correct.
This is the function C is
I am writing functions.
Right.
Okay.
All right.
So take it
or not excel A6 you use
it as s f
workable excel A6 you use excessive
workbook correct?
It is file input string guys.
Why we use file input string
if I s is the object.
I'm not sure
whether you have seen it or not already.
Let me show you.
Can you see this file input string?
If I is, I have control here. Right
to read file we need file
input string should be correct.
So the object of file input
stream is a files which I'm calling here.
Now guys can see
this is the very segregated function
I have written very clean function
to open device.
So right now I'm just opening.
I didn't read anything right now.
Now let's talk about the possible cases.
What are the possible cases?
In my one Excel file,
I can have multiple shapes, right,
guys?
I can have multiple shoots in my one
file or not, it could be possible three.
So let me write another method.
So I'm going to write another method
for the
I forgot to make it static method three.
Now again, I'm going to write
one more method public static void
and see get shape.
Fine.
So here, here.
I need the sheet name guys.
Remember the sheet name
I have provided here?
Can you see employee data?
This is the sheet name.
You can provide.
Some X was issued name, but right now
because we are trying to add employee
so I am providing the name as employee
data.
It gave me this addition.
So I just took next edition
from your setup.
If you want to write it,
you can type it as well.
No issues. All right.
So now again, guys,
because everything is dynamic.
We are passing these files,
but also. Right.
So we will pass this sheet
name as well from here right.
So I'm going to write a simple sheet name
and then I will say, right,
I will write like this sheet.
The sheet
is equal to from which sheet.
So from book now, because this object
I have created for workbook inside this
method, can I use it inside this method?
Also this
is this book
object created for this workbook
is available in this particular method.
Can I use it here also?
Yes. So I'm going to make it.
I am going to make it as a
and that's correct.
And let's make it static.
So this is my estimate.
Similarly, similarly for book, right?
I have sheet also.
So let me make another one as starting for
sheet.
So another object for sheet,
it will ask for import.
So I will imported fine.
Now see it says book dot.
Right book dot get sheet.
So which sheet.
So I am seeing, I've already provided
one better with that from here. Correct.
So this would be my get sheet function.
Now what I am doing in this two functions,
I opened my excel, I took the sheet.
Now in this sheet, in this sheet. Right.
I have to read the data.
Let me tell you, so far in our code
what I what we did,
we opened this Excel file
and we identify this sheet name.
Now we are on this particular ship still.
We didn't read
any data so far. Is it clear
what is the code?
What I have written so far,
I hope it is clear to everyone.
All right, fine.
This is a very basic thing
I'm doing as of now, right?
Because the more things are on the we know
now, tell me what is the best way
what is the best way to read the data?
I have to take the rules count
total number of rules.
Right.
Total number of rows
closing. Correct.
How many rows?
I have one, two, three, four. Like this.
I can hundred rules, thousand rules,
500 rows and rows.
I don't know.
So I need total number of rules first.
And then I will read what the data is
available inside these rows.
Correct.
We don't need to be out of here.
We will not use any at a right now.
Let me tell you,
you are going to write public
writing. And
right when I say why?
Because I'm
going to get that out of the rule.
So I'm going to write, get a rule
now. See now see what this method does.
Let me explain this. Right.
What this method does see for
common trait,
I will write Hey, sheet dart
gate,
can you see there is a method
called get physical number of rules?
What does it mean?
This method returns all the rules.
Write the number of rows.
The number of rows which is having data,
physical number of rows.
Right.
There's total number of rules
and physical number of rows.
Different things in the rows.
There we are having the data.
It will return all those rules right
where you are filling the data it.
So that's how you can get the rule going.
For example,
if your data is available in ten,
in ten rules or in 15 rules or in 20
rules, you don't have to be bothered
about this things in your Excel,
you just call this method.
And this method is dysfunction row count.
It will return the data
which is available, right?
Exactly. Exactly.
So you'll see how many rules we have.
You still,
if I run this function across this
file, across this sheet,
how many it will return?
What would be the count for count?
Correct.
It. Now, similarly,
let me proceed further.
I'm going to get public.
I think
public static end gate.
I'm going to get
one stop right after row after row.
I need to get column count.
So tell me, guys,
how can change the column?
We do not have any better
get physical number of columns.
No. How can we get the column count
again?
Somebody gets
it. Yes.
And what I will do basically is
I will pass the row index,
for example in this rule,
in this particular home.
Right.
How many physical number of cells
available.
Right.
How many physical seats in this rule?
This is one cell.
This is one cell digit, 110.
So if I had one, two, three, four,
five, six, six,
physical number of cells are available.
It means how many columns I have inside
want to
write understanding for every row.
For every row
I have in possible index inside that rule,
how many physical number of cells
available I will identify
this physical number of cells
means your number of columns.
Right.
So here
in this function I will write in beta
row index.
Right.
And here this function returns me,
but it prevents me from the sheet
to get.
All right,
so from where
I'm going to get lateral index.
Right.
And in this rule
I'm going to get physical number
of six point
heading.
This is for my column count one by one.
I'm taking the things now this method,
this function will open my excel.
This one will give me the sheet.
Open my sheet.
This one will give me all row count.
This one is giving overall column.
Column
so far in this clipboard website.
Yeah, I'm
going to do that. I'm going to do that.
So from here I'm going to start.
I'm going to write Here is
Open Excel
book correct?
This one is
open sheet.
Okay, open
the rules.
And then this one is
so great.
So kind of
correct.
So far everything work.
All right.
Now the next important point.
The next important point.
I got the rows,
I got the columns and everything.
But what I really need
in the end of the day,
what I need is do I need to do
I need a column?
Do I need self?
Enza, I think your very best name
is Will correct?
Exactly.
I need data
here identified.
Right.
I need data. Correct.
So not the text.
Physically not fake, not the text.
I will tell you how we can do that
because see, sometimes you're making the
but sometimes you're getting something
else, right?
What I will do is
and let me write here another method
for the public safety element is
what kind of data
I be expecting from my from
my every cent, what of datetime expecting
string.
So my method should return.
What is string.
So I'm going to write get
then.
Okay.
Get cell data.
So in the cell data I need and
I will pass first as
row index comma
call index that is column
index from digital from which column
I need to get the data
so this method will return
from this index.
It will go,
it will take the row
original and the row index point.
Then find which cell.
So I am passing the column
index that this particular see
now whatever the data, whatever
the data I'm getting at, really don't know
what type of data is this going to use
one method point those
Now tell me guys
what this don't do the string method does
why we used auto string
exactly whatever the data.
Whatever the data I am getting right
this dot string
method will convert it
into the string connect.
So I'm using this state
hey excel sheet to give me the data.
I don't care
what kind of data you're giving me, right?
I will use this data as a string, so
I will convert it forced into this string.
And then in the in my this method, my,
this method will convert this data
as a string.
Correct.
So I will write here
to connect the data from every
in the form of its frame.
We use this function.
Is it correctness
right now?
Now, next 10 minutes,
Hardly 10 to 15 minutes.
I need your full attention here.
Just 10 minutes.
Explain.
What we are going to do is now let me show
now yard in after this definitely break.
Fine.
So now if you see guys, guys, please.
All right.
Just 15 minutes.
I need. All right, Mike.
Nobody should worry. They could object.
I'm saying one thing here in this sheet.
In this sheet. Right.
I'm going to use a part of this data
structure.
All right?
We are going to use the part of data
structure. Why?
Because now something
I'm telling you, right?
Might be you guys noticed.
Maybe you guys didn't notice.
If you see the format of my Excel file is
if you see this particular force to do
this particular.
First of all, tell me
what is the index for this?
First of all, if I'm going to pass the row
index, what would be the index?
Zero.
So let me keep the zero somewhere.
Let's say here this now.
Now, if you see on this false two,
I'm getting false
to name middle name, last name,
photograph, user name password.
What is this
correct.
Jamal, you identified
these is these are the keys, right.
Is there any other place
in my entire Excel file?
Is there any other place in my entire file
from where I'm getting the keys?
Is it any other place? No.
It means what?
I understood one thing from my Excel file.
I'm telling you guys,
maybe you guys are learning it first time,
but this is very interesting topic.
You see, that's how you can read data.
Even in your million dollar project.
You can read data like this
in your first of all, you got one clue.
What is that clue?
You got one thing that in my first rule,
I always get just three, correct.
I always good just right.
So everything everything.
Now, if you see every time right
here you go
and you check
this is unity in the first row.
This is your key, right?
And at the same time, in the same time,
if you are going on this second row right.
If you're going, this is your key.
Now, what is this?
This and then this.
Right.
So this is your key.
This is your value.
This is your this is your value. Correct.
Again, this middle name is your key.
And these are the values
associated to this.
This again, key.
So this one value
one value to a new three, 1 to 3.
Similarly a new one when to value three.
Again, this is your key,
right?
And this is when you value one value
and so correct.
No, no.
If you see
if you see here
in clear minor, if I write like this
understanding what is gain, what is value
we are getting from here,
from this simply
and just for one thing, one point.
Now let's try to understand
the second point.
When I see
when I see
this particular rule
is constant to gain the key
right finds zero
right after this.
When I ask here
this particular rule forced
this particular rule first, right
difference index one.
This particular rule
it means index to
this particular rule
it means index three.
Right.
This forget about it
because this is having only right.
So every single rule,
every single rule is giving me some values
or not
this and I shall return it is value
black Melia all in It is value every time
my index is zero
through my index zero purpose giving what
he my remaining rules
are giving me more values.
Right?
So the combination if you see with this
zero, this one, this zero with this two,
this zero with this three,
what it is returning what it is returning.
The first one is
returning me key and value.
Then the second row.
This is my first
and the second rule is again returning key
and value.
The third row again.
The third row is returning Milwaukee
And when new right
these three rules are returning keys
and values for example.
For example if you come here,
the first name is the key strength.
Fine. This is the key.
This is the value point.
This is the value.
So the key is having
the type of what is free
and is having the type of lock
string connect You're having this thing.
It means for every single home,
your every single rule
is returning a map
addict.
Guys can you see your
every single rule is returning one map
from the second one
it means which index position
you need to get the map.
The first one is zero.
Forget about it
because it is always returning the key.
You will start writing
the index of rules from one
because your action values
are starting from here.
Right?
So we need to do see,
this is for rule one, right?
It prevents map and string
keys and values again for all two.
Right.
Again, it will return one more
map called is string and again
string for a key and value.
Then for row three again
it will return another map.
Right again it will return map.
Now tell me one thing.
Is it possible
that I can have two data with same name?
Can I have two and two?
Andre two,
Black two, Michael or three Michael?
So for Michael's possible right
now, I need force.
The I need force.
I need rules collection.
This is a part of data structure, correct?
Based understood the point
how I'm getting map
key and value pair right now
because I'm getting multiple max.
I'm getting multiple maps.
I need one connection
that I can keep all these maps together.
Right?
If if I don't store this map
and I take another map, what would happen
if I don't see
after getting the values of this map?
If I don't see this map,
I will take another map.
It will override the value. Correct.
So what I have to do,
I have to find a V in connection, Right.
Which will not only add my map
after retrieving the value,
but also allow me, but also allow me
to add duplicate values as well.
Adding my point
is getting that point.
So now what is the need
to be correct?
Right? So what is the need here?
The need is to find edit
after edit again, take another point.
Added another move, find edit right.
And then take all of these things
in terms of what
we have to take it in the list.
Right. So when list.
Why in this case because this allows
duplicate elements, correct?
It is a part of collection
and it allows duplicate elements.
So guys understood, how are we going
to write this dynamic function?
So next time let's say you will be having
19 keys or 20 or 25 keys
and your first rule
will be having all the keys
again, your remaining rows
will be having all the values.
Fine.
It will get the data getting physical
number of rows, but we have function.
We have function for all the columns.
Do we have function?
We have function to get the data from
the cell and converted into the string.
Do we have that function?
We have the function.
Now what we need,
we need a function that can read my data
in such a way
that my every rule is returning a map.
So it will pick the map, it will add
this mapping list, it will go again.
Check that out again Next low again,
take the data added in the list,
then go again
in the time my rules are finished.
That's
why I took all physical number of rows.
Right.
So do again.
I have to use data structure.
We are using collection.
We are using loops.
We are using correct.
Now let's
go ahead and use loops in this case.
So remember, guys,
the structure,
the structure which we are following
is what inside list.
I will be having map inside a map.
I will be having two strings
together. Correct.
This would be the structure
I'm going to follow list and to map.
Did the explanation clear or not?
Guys, tell me first,
is it clear what I just explained
to everyone?
So let's go ahead
and we will write this function.
There's not much time.
Right, But I need you.
Attention probably is static.
First,
I am going to add my list inside my list
I would be having that right
and inside the map.
Come on.
What I.
I would be having my the string
comma
external to
this map.
Now it is just important. Fine.
I have an important message
about our students right
met no map into list
every single
who is regarding what map right.
So we are taking all this map
one by one into list.
List list will be having
multiple elements. Correct.
So first we are taking the map
and then we will add this map to our list.
Two things I need.
The first is to read the file.
I need file, but
that indicates.
The second thing is I need my sheet.
Then we days to get the file
path and sheet name right,
which method we have used
gave for file name and for sheet name,
which method we have used.
And you see
it says to open the Excel book.
We have open Excel, right?
And to get to open the sheet
we have to get sheet.
Okay, so simple.
I will call this two methods open accent
find file path.
Right. And then
get sheet and then provide this.
Get it correct.
Now I've opened my file
but I open my sheet.
The next thing what I am going to do
is I'm going to put this list Right.
Fine.
Matt is playing comma is string.
So I'm going to say the list to data
right.
That I'm going to use in Let's see,
I'm going to use edit
Okay.
And some time
we need to understand one thing
that we can't leave some topic in between.
Correct?
Because if I'm explaining something
and it requires 2 hours
to explain the complete topic, then it is
my responsibility
not to leave that topic in between.
Otherwise
the students will get distracted.
Sometimes topic is more important
than break
aggregates.
No, I'm not. I'm not any.
Sometimes you need to understand, right?
The breaks are not that important.
Trade topic is important.
If you leave this topic right now,
if you don't understand this topic,
if I leave this topic in between,
you won't be able to understand.
Even after watching the videos. 14
or 20 times.
Please try to understand this right.
If students are insisting me
to explain this topic
and this is something extremely important,
you are not realizing importance
of this topic that once you're going
to the industry, you have to use it
every now and then, right?
Like I said, just ten more minutes
straight then more minutes.
I need not much, but please
try to understand, do this for you.
I know how to puzzle data
from Excel. Right?
This is for you.
Let's.
All right. So now
what we
have to do is we have to add our map.
Whatever Every row is returning.
What every rule is returning map.
I'm going to add
back in the list. Correct.
That's what we need to do.
So now we are going to do it here.
Remember my outer loop.
I'm going to use to for loop.
The first one is to count
all the rows, right?
To count all the rules and then the inner
one, the one we create the map.
Right? First I will go inside of my role.
It will take the value from there.
I will go inside.
It will collect the values,
all the column face.
Correct.
So let's go ahead and do it.
Guys, what is this symbol?
Understanding.
So let writing for
outer loop.
All right,
so I'm going to write this for loop
right here.
EFC, I'm going to start right.
I'm going to start my index fund
role is equal to one again.
Somebody did me while I'm passing
this role is equal
get role count
and then the role
plus.
Yes, correct.
I'm going to create now I'm saying
the function is creating a map, right.
For every role.
The code which I'm going to
integer me.
So what I'm saying basically is here
I'm seeing in this function
what I'm going to do.
I'm going to create a map
for every single rule.
This is extremely important, right?
This is extremely important.
So we are going to we are going to read,
we are going to read every rule
and create a map.
So the function which I'm going to write
now because we are already inside
so I can draw.
So from second row,
we will start all right to exist,
go inside, create a map.
Right. So let's go ahead and do it.
I'm going to right here
is see in the list.
Here in the list, I will add a map,
but I need to map to add something
in the list.
Correct.
So let's create this map first, I'm
going to write here, Map eliminate.
My key is also a string.
My values also string. Right?
So I'm going to create this map
equal to nil.
I'm going to use link
hash my already discussed
when people thinks about link the hash map
right.
We have seen this.
I was the only one who explained
who taught you these maps. Now.
Now I'm going to loop
all looping through the values,
the values of all this cell.
It means for the next command, which
I am going to write, it will go through
all the values of my cells, whatever sense
I have right in my every single row,
it will return the values of those rules,
all of those cells.
All right.
So for another for loop,
I'm going to write C, I'm going to write
in Integer and minutes from which column
I'm going to read the values
guys.
Column one or zero.
Exactly.
Column is zero
because zero means first column, right?
And I'm getting the value
from the first column.
Column is my zero.
I'm going to say column
when get column count
point and column column
depends on my rule, which I'm passing.
Fine. So it's a column
that's a plus point.
Now, here, tell me, guys,
when I'm getting the values right,
this one is giving me the value.
I have to add, the values are starting
to the saving right
and start to the saving the values.
Okay.
It started with it's giving the values.
I have to add this value in the map.
What is the command to add
value in the map,
which method we use?
Right.
So let me write
the map, start to put right.
And then here, put what same data.
Remember I have method data, right?
So this tells
it is asking the row index date.
This is asking row index.
Tell me two things I need key and value.
Key and value. Right.
So first one is growing because tell me
guys, by default my rule is same not
my rule.
Always, always seem to get the key right.
Comma, comma.
I'm going to write this column right
in first row
in first to get all the columns.
It means this is my key
guys in first row
getting all the columns is my key.
Now, when it comes to value,
nobody gets cell data for my every rule.
It means there I'm
plus in this draw is equal to one.
From here
it will start and draw plus plus.
So from first or second or third row,
it will take my column.
Now, don't worry.
Let me explain you why.
Come on,
let me take the code of this part
from here.
Right.
Like snapshot.
Another one
right now.
Now you'll see.
It came inside of my first rule right.
It came inside my first rule.
Correct base.
Can you see when it came inside
my first rule, it is asking.
It is asking to prepare the map playing.
So to prepare that may to wait on to
the column is equal to zero.
It means this.
It means me.
My first rule and column zero. Right.
So let me open my Excel sheet, guys.
My first index is based on column zero.
It means this value right? For this venue.
It is trying to get fine.
So now when I come here, when I come here,
it says I have to add one.
This is my key. This is my building.
It says in the zero rule
first column, 000.
Right, Right.
Guess zero common zero.
So when it goes into zero, common zero,
what it will find,
what it will find in zero zero.
This is my first name.
Correct? My first name.
So here, if you come, zero zero will find
first name. Similarly, get cell data.
So it always starts from with one
right row starts from where
one comma column is zero one common zero.
Now let's go back. One comma zero means
correct.
So first name is my and
that's how it is working.
Correct.
Then again, column change.
What rule? Same.
So this time column is zero comma one.
It means what?
Middle name.
Right.
First row point but column this time one.
So one comma one it means what one comma
one means should correct
it will again change
and give you the excess.
Yes. Yes. Correct. Correct.
So now see my rule.
Same only column is changing.
It means I'm getting the keys
from first row but from different columns
getting my point.
And here
when getting when I'm getting the values.
So for getting the values right
every time my role is
changing, column is changing, right?
So right now
my role is one one common zero,
then one comma one, then one, comma two,
then one.
It means for looping
through all sense of my role
and getting the data and converting it
interesting way I get some data correct.
So when I'm done
with the first iteration of this part,
it will return one map or not. Tell me
this is what I am doing for wonderful.
Correct.
This is what I'm doing for the first title
when I'm done.
So for the next we will put row index one.
No, we will not put.
We will not put.
You see here we have
put this increment operator row plus plus.
Correct
in zero plus plus.
Now see how it works.
If this column is equal to zero column
plus plus it is increasing,
increasing increasing rate.
It says a row is equal to 40.
Everything is done.
It says one is less than one
in this situation.
So situation is false.
It will go.
And now the index becomes two.
This growing base becomes now.
So again came inside again came inside.
Column zero starts zero comma.
It means what this is for second row again
you're getting the key zero zero
it means false name but here this time
root index change two two.
Right, correct and correct this time.
This time your rule.
Let me tell you for the second iteration
right now.
This second for second row.
It works this time.
This time
this rule index becomes too, right?
So this rule becomes
two column is zero zero comma zero.
It means first
name as a key two commas needle.
It means the first name from second row
trade in two comma one middle name
from second row, then two comma
two made it the last name from second.
Right.
And that's how you will be completing
the data
grouping second
then similarly from third row.
But remember,
remember in our function here,
when I'm getting this data, when I'm
this data for every rule I told you
after creating the map for every row,
first we have to add this map correct.
First we have to do what?
We have to add this map,
otherwise it will overwrite.
So I'm going to write
it is to add the map in list point.
How can I add the map in this case?
Can someone tell me
this is my list object?
Right?
I want to add this map inside my list.
How can I do that?
Mystery data don't add what I want to add.
I want to add a map
correct?
Correct.
So now,
now it will add the data again.
Go here, find again. It create one map.
Edit here again, go here for another row.
Again,
it will create a map edit in the list
when it is done for all the rows
after the after
going out of this iteration,
when all the rules are done, what it will
do, it will simply return you.
This list data, which is heavy.
All the maps inside this list are data.
Correct
guys, guys.
Why so silence?
Understood. I will explain once again.
Don't worry about it.
But at least you understood
what I just said.
Clear to everyone.
You need to check the data. Maybe cursor.
Right. Maybe calibrations.
You're putting something else.
Something inside or outside.
That's fine.
So now, now see this function?
This is the universal function.
I have.
That doesn't matter how many rows
you have, how many columns you have,
how many sheets you have,
how many files you have.
You just change the file name
the sheet name it will read their data
for all the rules in all the cells
and convert this into this string for you.
Correct.
I recognize
you there, Marks.
I put everything right.
I put notes everywhere.
Can you see?
Yeah, correct. Correct.
Mike All right, guys, if you understand
right, if you understood the things
you actually, I will.
I can understand that.
Let's take a break for 10 minutes
quickly for you guys.
All right?
Just take a break for 10 minutes
and then we connect once again
after 10 minutes.
We had we had a day
read this part to add the Excel data.
But so far, so far, we are not using
we are not using this in a test case.
All right.
So now what we have to do in this case
first, we have create a new test case
where we will add employees
using this particular Excel point.
Right.
So now this is the time I remember
I gave you the overview,
putting the Excel pilot one place
and then writing this function.
Two things are done.
The third thing is to use these.
This function in our actual test kits.
So now tell me if I want to add employee.
Should I create the
new test case in which class
inside test case is my package right now?
Dashboard is my page.
This one
for creating the test gives us.
I have just to log into an employee test,
so I'm going to open it and
let me write another test.
No, no, no.
I'm going to write public
and the employee I'm going to write Void.
And how many employees?
I'm putting multiple add
multiple employees
starting
correctly.
Guys.
So to add employer,
what is the first thing you
post?
I have to log in, right?
So to read the log in page, right.
I can write log in page equals to new
log in page to call the log in function.
Right.
So this would be my log in page
start log in.
And there I paused the password
from config reader dart.
You can copy the same line from line
number 16.
Right.
But I'm writing it so
that people can understand what I'm doing.
This is for my user name.
The second one is for my
password.
Good property.
When I'm blasting the score here,
what I find
it is
all log in after log in after log in
to click on what race
option and dashboard button.
Correct
it employee button.
So let me can I take this an employee
retention option from here only?
Can I take that?
All right.
I'm just trying to save your time.
This way.
Navigate to add
employee
page. This
now now, the most important point here,
the most important point
which I am going to write
first.
First, I am going to write
because I need this list
that I'm having met
there, I'm adding data, right?
I'm having the data to read this function.
I'm writing as Neil
Employees write
Keep this thing to here.
I'm trying to write it as new employees.
What these new employees will do
this new
employees will have their data,
which I'm getting from my file.
So from which class I'm taking this case,
in which class I have
my function is going to be.
It says
accelerating
dart, which function?
I have to always get same data open
Excel column count
extending to list which function
the first one or any other one
can be the collective function.
That universal function is which one
we have
on the exact same data
we have already called inside X
and in the list map, correct?
Yes. The first one Excel in too
nice to map.
Remember the function.
Let me show you with
this Excel list.
And to my right, you'll see here
I'm using this data here, right?
Column and data.
Everything I'm taking. Yes, Yes.
So now, now when I go
my in my employee test,
it is asking what it is asking itself
excellent to list point.
So which part right
which party for providing.
So I'm going to see my file name.
The first thing I see from my
from my constants.
Right. Just take the data file. But
I recognize
comma it says sheet name is
what is the sheet member
employee database.
So employee
data correct.
Now my this new employees object
having all their data from my method.
The method is taking this data
from my Excel file right now.
Tell me to.
I tried to iterate the values one by one
and to check
that I am having all this values
inside the map,
right inside the for loop
having these values
right or to get the values
one by one, one by one.
Can I use a trade or not? Yes.
Let me show you that I just provided
the name at this point of time.
Can you see this employee data here?
They occupy nobody's notice.
So this employee
datasheet I already mentioned
is in this one line, right?
I have written this one line
only of new code
is everyone with me so far here.
But now know when
to write the iterator. Why?
I'm going to write the iterator
because I need to.
I need to read the values
which I'm gifting inside
my map.
I see in this apparatus I is equals
to which object I'm going to use.
I'm to use my new employees object
from where I'm getting the data
right.
Everyone knows
I created a concept already, right?
So each and everything
to get the data correct.
Correct. Right.
So now any guys new methods, new methods
we use for iterator,
which are those two methods
has next force, right?
Which loop we generally use
while loop.
Correct.
So I will write a dart as next line
inside this next right.
What I will do is go in my map
where you are getting
this is free comma another stream.
Right?
So you are going to take this map of new
employee is equals to it dot
till the time
you are getting the values right.
Just for this give new from every row
given new from every row
in this particular map.
Right
In the time you are getting the value,
go ahead, check it in my map.
The first thing
now every single thing I am having here,
whether it is first name, last name,
middle name, whatever the things
I'm having, I will keep it here.
Okay? I'm having it here.
If I want to access those things,
how can I exist?
Let me show you the very first thing.
If I open the application,
what is my application?
This is the first name, right?
I have to pass
very first key is my first name.
Right?
Let me do this.
I'm going to write
my assigned text. Correct.
First name is available
on which page goes to me.
So on an employee page rate.
No, no, no.
First name my locator.
Right. Let's check.
I have the locator for first name.
I have the locator form
within the locator form.
Last name.
Do I need more locators?
Nice.
We need more locator
exponents.
Are you with me?
Everyone?
All right, so we need more locators. Fine.
Let's go ahead and check
how many locators we need.
We need check checkbox for log in, right?
Correct. Yeah.
Username, password, confirm, password,
photograph, straight and checkbox.
We need all of this lipstick.
Let's take them one by one.
So I'm going to take for photograph.
Right.
First
when it gives me.
Is that ID photo? Fine. Fine.
So next we take it here.
I'm going to write this as
mine for photo.
Fine.
So I'm giving simple name as
photograph.
Correct.
Okay.
False name, middle name.
Last name photograph is done. Right.
Let's take the another part after right.
That's important as well.
We are to perform this check log in option
this low by default
it will be like this. Fine.
So let's take this check log in option.
So it says check, log in. Fine.
Let's take this check log in.
Also.
So I'm going to write it is
create log in,
check was
right after three log in check box.
We need username password entry password.
We copy this here for
username
mirror.
Make this create username.
The second one would be
weird password
and the third one would be my
password.
Right. So now let me come back here.
When I click here
it says this username.
So it is your username.
Fine.
I'm going to copy this idea then
for ideas
password and for confirm password.
Again I go, I will take this password
from here.
All right, guys,
I got all these locators. Yes.
Can you please see
these three pull locators
we already had earlier?
Right now
I'm having the remaining locators.
Wait with me.
Let's go ahead.
And now let's try to complete.
Artist is here.
So on this page, right on which page?
I have all these things
that I have to create.
Be what?
I have to create the object first.
So let me create the object
first here at one place,
I'm going to create all the objects.
So I said,
an employee feet is equals to new
and white page.
Now I have to write an employee page
start first name Correct.
This is my
now see using excel
find if I need to change their data
using Excel file.
If I need to send the data,
my is available inside this map.
New employee. Correct.
So I will make my new employee
dark gate.
Now remember that this is the only thing
you need to remember.
Method get everyone knows, right?
Look into values via key.
So now guys,
I should remember whatever they keys.
I mentioned that this key
should be the same key
which you have parsed your excel file
here.
If you are providing something else,
it will not get your data.
So I am passing the same key. Right?
What I have provided there
and I'm using that key here.
Correct.
Similarly, I can write
it for ADD and right page dot or maiden
name.
Also. Fine.
So do we have this?
Let's check it and then
again,
this is the key
I have defined in my Excel find.
So I'm calling this data from there
and start lastname comma.
This is the map object, right?
That I'm having all the values
my gear.
Right.
So for any confusion, if so,
for any confusion, they send me
no regret
after after getting this,
after getting this right.
I'm writing here select checkbox.
But now for the selection of checkbox.
Right again, I have to perform
just one thing
more before checking the checkbox.
Right? First let's upload the picture.
Send text
and employee page dart
photograph.
So from where
I'm sending the photograph dart get again
and then this would be the key
for my photograph.
Let's check
with Capital P.
I photographed
that capital photograph, correct.
Now, guys,
tell me before selecting the checkbox.
Right before selecting the checkbox,
do I need to check
whether my check box is available or not?
Or do I need to check whether my check box
is already selected or not?
Should I do this or not?
Tell me
we have to do it right.
So let's write one condition here.
What my if conditions is it
says if my dart
create log in checkbox is the negative.
I'm saying no, it means what
it means or not.
I put this not here. No.
See sunny or displayed.
It should be selected.
Right?
So if it is not selected I'm safe
because I put this not right.
Can you see? It is not.
If it is not, then simply click there.
Click on this
3:00 in checkbox simply
right now.
See when I have to write that best
guess how easy it is
to write that test because
because everything is available every bit.
I just need to collect all of them
together.
Yes, that's what I'm doing now.
After doing this, I have to go.
Wait.
Provide
credentials for user correct.
I have to provide credentials for user.
It is very easy guys here.
I have provided false memory
to name last name
which I should employ 80.
We are not using embroidery as of now.
This will be your task.
I will give you that
the task. Don't worry.
Right.
I will tell you what to do in that case.
Employee
We are not using any BRC right now.
I am not using Employee Correct.
General Can you see anywhere
if I'm using embroidery?
We are not using any BSP.
So now, now the next thing
what we are going to do is here
we are going to perform, we
are going to provide the username
and password and confirm password.
Right.
So again,
on the same page and employee page,
start my create username.
So here also I am putting this data map
new employee dark.
Okay, from there, what is the key?
The key here is user
name with capital you.
So I'm going to write here
user name with capital you
and again same text on the same page.
Start
create password
using the same key
capital P
and then again the employee page.
Start
the C password comma,
you map dark gate
and again you're passing the now.
But remember, I was talking about
one point with all of you guys, right?
That if someone reads your code,
even they create password, the password.
Right.
But we are passing the same string here,
right?
Even though this functionality is seen
right by here, it looks weird.
Password. Password.
But this this is safe.
That's why people generally don't prefer.
But since we are using right now.
So we will do this like this only right.
And this the guys
after putting all their data
I have to say would also.
Right. So let me play
the save time
now 10 minutes.
Is this correct?
Is this correct to add the employee
right,
this iterator, what this iterator will do,
I return every time.
Check.
All right. I'm having data go ahead.
Use it at employee.
Go ahead, use it
and employee again and again and again.
I am using this particular test case
to add the data from Excel fight.
So now,
based on the number of sets of data
I have in my X and find my this best case
and my this iterator
will add back
many employees using the same function.
Now just go back.
Go back one hour back.
I explained one topic data driven testing.
When we see
when we test the same functionality
across different data,
we call it data driven testing.
That's what we are doing
as of now. Correct.
My same test case
for adding multiple employees.
I'm adding multiple employees
using different sets of data, isn't it?
That's what I'm doing
anyways.
This is what I am doing or not
right? So
please, we want
right now.
This is the time to execute.
Sure.
Can you see this?
Line number 4 to 6 for me.
Okay, let's execute this.
Test kits support.
Let's see if we are getting any errors
or we are able to execute the test case
right.
Let's see.
I'm not sure what's going to happen.
If we make mistakes, we will learn.
If we execute,
we can see that we are lucky.
Flexi? Yes.
Correct. Correct.
Sorry, this is your universal function.
It will do everything for you.
Every single thing for you.
It will.
Even if you have 1000 employees. Fine.
You have 100 kids. Fine.
You have just ten employees. Fine.
You have just one key.
Find all kind of data. It will read.
That is for sure.
Let's see. Let's see
if you are getting
the error with locators or something.
That is fine.
We can understand.
That's great.
You want that?
You found one bug here
and the application.
See, it is getting the data correct.
Can you see?
It is getting the data.
It is not.
It was trying to add all the data
since the employee only exists.
That's why it didn't get the data
that was the problem.
It should execute for the tree basically.
Let's check it for username.
Fine.
Let me do one thing
right after I iterating their data,
I will keep my team option here right
every time.
Okay. Got it.
Got it. Got it.
Now what I'm doing is basically
right after I creating the data again,
I'm clicking on team option, I'm
clicking on an employee option, and then
I'm going inside.
Yes, he is.
Yes, I got it.
I got it. Yes. Accelerating fight.
All right.
If we should this accelerating.
Can you see this accelerating?
Yeah.
Let's try to execute once again.
I have figured it out.
What happened was we were not clicking on
an employee waiting multiple times.
I will tell you.
I will tell you that.
See, in our test case,
this click option on team
button and eight employee is, Something
we have to do every time.
Every time before adding the new employee.
Right.
I was doing it outside.
So before every application
it was not clicking on every option
and employee button. Correct.
But every iteration for every operation
the flow should be same.
That's what we need to do.
Okay, Now let me just do one thing before
executing it.
Once again. Let me change the data.
Guys, please don't use data, other data,
which
I'm going to use.
Which one is already there?
One, two, three.
Okay, fine.
We are clicking on save button, right?
So it is not going on to the next page.
That's what you need to see.
All right, Let's see that.
Let's see that way. It is not going.
If if user is already exists, then
they should not go on to the next page.
That is the case case.
I have again changed this data Now,
this time, let's try to execute this part.
Let's see.
I mean, I need to once again.
Yes, right.
Eugene, taking this screenshot
is the next process, right?
We will learn listeners
and in the listeners we will add
the screenshot.
Don't worry about it.
I just want to show you
this execution part because when you add
the user again, it will click on team
option, it will go the employee page.
From there it will execute this stuff.
That's what I want to show.
It means we're able we should be able
to pass their data from multiple files.
That's
what I'm just trying to explain here.
Now if you see right
it it created the data.
It came on to this page.
Can you see Jamal?
It came on to this page right
now again, it is clicking here again,
go there
uploading the file, getting data, right?
Yes, he is. That's what I said.
I just changed one part.
That's what I'm trying to show you now.
It is taking for the second iteration.
It means it is editing this.
Take an employee.
This time you'll see
it has added the second employee.
This is the third employee now, right?
Understood.
Is everyone.
Now let me show you what change
I did in this code
black.
And we have to check why.
So here, if you see this, click
on team option and an employee button.
Right?
I didn't earlier inside this work so
before I creation right before attrition
I was just clicking on one thing
on team option.
This should not be the case
after save button.
It doesn't matter on which screen
I am. Right.
It was trying to figure out this
first name field.
But first name field was not there, right?
The first thing it was not there.
So I have to make the full flow
once again.
So flows is going to be my option.
Click on an employee button.
Then you will see first name again.
Going to be my option.
Click on it employee button
and then you will see full speed.
Right?
So every time after clicking on
Save Button every time
after clicking on same button,
I'm clicking on same option, I'm going on
to add employee button, I'm coming on
to the first name and then I will write
I will enter all the data
to add the employee.
This is what I'm doing
now from the X and find we are able to
we are able to basically execute
and add multiple employees here.
So far, is it correct?
Guys understood.
Whatever the things we did so far.
Great.
Again, again, I know the topic is big,
right?
And I will give you a quick overview
of this topic inside this session
and then we will cover listeners
in shorts.
Sure.
There you go.
This is the end of my page
on the accelerating issue.
Line number 35
in your accelerator.
Just go and check line number 35
where you are
making the mistake.
And here it says accelerating
line number 52 and then line number 47.
So 47 line number, you're passing
the employee data insert off line,
but that is fine.
The issue is on the in your Excel.
Yeah correctly correct
on the
we need to check that just a moment.
If there is someone
available in the support
can someone please and in that case
why is not able to see that.
Because in the Excel file,
the accelerating pool.
Right. There was an issue.
Let me quickly commit
this code right into the repository
so you guys can have this code with you.
We just put it.
Everyone can get this updated code right.
Once you get this updated code, everything
will be working in your machine.
Andre, just try to get this code right.
You don't need to change the path
of any Excel. Fine.
You don't need to change anything
racially.
We have a setup in such a way.
We are using this system get property
so it will return the part of your system,
not my system.
That is the beauty of using framework
array.
The same structure, the same file name,
the same part will be working
in everyone's machine.
You don't need to change anything.
All right. I pushed my code.
I committed my call already.
Database? Yes.
Even the fight. Even the fight
muscle.
It will not complete constant file,
but it should be constant
start configuration federation data paper
or test data hypothetically
if you see constraints or file.
But it never comes like this
for sure.
An employee page. There you go.
This is the template page.
I have my
it's these web driver users.
This should be during class,
which is fine.
Not found exception.
I should leave.
You see this system dog property
We are using
this system do not get
property is returning your user directory.
It can means whenever
your project is destroyed this will return
date proper location of your project
and inside your project.
Since everything is theme.
Every location is same.
It will return that kind simple.
You see,
we are not hard coding the data, right?
We are passing the database system.
But property.
This one.
Can you please change the path
Mike the way you did for the configuration
file, but can you do it?
Change the slashes in the start
one slash before this RC
I guess I can understand.
No, no, no.
This will
already recognize.
So I think I'm done from my side
for today.
If you guys have any question can ask
a delays, we can step of the session.
All right, guys,
don't worry about the topic.
Right.
I will take you through the topic
once again, break on Saturday
and then we'll try to cover
and wrap up everything from the test
and your framework on security
in the time to this
when nobody is finding out.
I think I can take care to be one by.