Good old times.
Good old times, right?
For years, let's say all four months
equals to four years, right?
More than four months.
Yes. I think you guys have almost all
you guys have a little over a month
that is left, right.
I guess I miss you, too.
I miss you, too.
And it's been I hope you guys
how how is the journey going
as the journey going so far, guys?
Okay, good.
Great.
Good.
Learn a lot.
That's important. Right?
So now, now, guys, when are you going
to look back at the class Number one?
Right.
Remember,
as I told you, we're building, right?
We're building our building.
And what I said on the first class that
you have to compare yourself to yourself.
So now from from today,
if you're going to look back, guys,
did you guys learn a lot?
Oh, yes.
Oh, yes. That's good then.
And and yes, guys, think of it.
It's only, what, a month and a half left.
Maybe, maybe Max, a two month in.
Remember when you were just starting
and you said, Oh, my God, six months.
It's so long.
And then go say, go tag
time is going so quick.
And and I really hope guys
I mean, of course you're learning and
I really hope you guys have been enjoying
it, even though I'm sure it's
it's tough.
Right.
And especially for
those that have work and kids,
you guys have to sacrifice a lot.
However, guys, trust me. Trust me.
It's a beautiful, beautiful journey awaits
ahead of you.
A lot of things to memorize.
Remember, guys, hard work
always, always pays off.
So the more effort, and especially right
now, guys, it's important.
And I'm very happy to see all of you
right now.
I know, cause it's not.
It's not all of you, right?
When they used to teach your Java classes
in, however, I guess
it's still majority of you all still here.
And you guys almost made it to the end,
right?
That's that's what's that's
what's important
you feel like in in that six months
now You guys done year Another six months.
You guys will be good towards the end.
There will be a lot of a lot of things
that we guys will be doing.
So it will be a lot of fun. So
dark circles.
All right.
Therefore, for a friend and The Bachelor
he wants more practice uses scanner.
Yeah they just
they just start learning that
Java basics And you are guys all right.
There is a last push that you guys have.
And after that,
there will be another journey.
And just to share some good news with you
guys, we have batch ten.
Stewart is that went on the market
like two weeks ago
maybe now
a little bit over the in two weeks
there's a two different groups
that we have students who are ready
they go first
who students need a little more time.
They go a little bit later.
So we are ready.
We already have half in two weeks.
We already have eight offers, guys.
So and it's pretty, pretty impressive
because these days we always tell students
it takes
you should have a right expectations,
right in our expectation that it takes
about two months to six months.
However, however budget
and right now they are killing so
and I want to see exact
exact the same things from you guys.
Right
And it's it's it I actually very excited
because I just saw the message
and I can share with you guys we have a
we have a student
we have a student from that.
He's a 20 years old. 20 years old.
Let me see, guys. Today.
Today, there was admissions with you
because I'm sure you guys can see.
Right.
So we have a 20 year old student
today, got got a job here.
Here He he said it right
here, 20 years old.
And I'm like, oh,
my God, That that that's so amazing.
And then today
we have like four offers came today.
We were congratulating all the students.
They were cheering here.
Another student got an offer
and there we have another one more actual
our international student
from from Russia, she got an offer.
So today's been a really,
really exciting day, guys.
So and
exact the same things
a wage for you guys right
And I'm expecting then now wishing you
all of that right so
and think I guess another two months worth
of really really hard work right
Because remember
you guys all are going to get very high
paying jobs.
Very high paying jobs. Right.
Then when I think of a student
that is 20 years old
and, you know, getting in offers
$80,000 and upwards, it is crazy.
It's really,
really life changing right then.
But remember, guys,
everything requires a hard work, right?
If if it would be easy,
then everybody would be doing it, right?
Everyone.
So but it's important, guys,
that you right now putting all the vocals,
all the distractions you already made
more than halfway through.
Right?
And so now there's another really good
push that you guys need to do.
All of us are coming.
This offer.
I can come in
as long as you guys put in your efforts.
Jobs are there and offers will be there.
It is a real life
changing, life changing this year.
And especially it's you know,
sometimes we have husband wives
joining or sometimes we have brothers,
sisters joining.
So very, very exciting moments. Right.
So with that being said, guys, today
actually
will be a way for you
that you guys go into practice
and that's going to take your knowledge
even further
forward of of
based on the practices
that we will be doing today.
Right.
So today, guys,
we are going to explain you the project.
So right now
you guys just see me speaking. And
I second part,
Mozart will be speaking, right?
We will explain you how the project works.
And it's really,
really important, guys, to do with in
this time.
You guys, I know for the past few classes,
you guys have been learning
how to work together, right?
When it comes to
I give before you guys were doing
your own coding and storing on your own.
You have.
However, for the past few classes you guys
been learning how to work together.
So that's
what is our project is about this.
We kind of like are going to try to do
not try this project will be doing
for all previous
batches guys
and this project has been very,
very helpful
when it comes to the students.
All the students love the project.
They're very excited.
Even though the project
are not going to say it's super hard.
I would say probably it's a medium
level more in here.
What are we trying to achieve?
You in here, guys?
That you guys learn how to work together?
Basically, our goal is right now to make
you experience an actual life project.
How it works, and the only thing
we will be making it in a shorter right.
You are taking bootcamp, right?
It's a shorter journey.
So the same thing we trying to squeeze
our actual actual sprint, right?
And we try to squeeze it
within one week as well.
Right.
However, it will be very amazing
practice for you guys
and you actually guys
will learn learn a lot, right?
Even though everything that you know
already, you learn a
you know, they're ready by now,
you guys will be able to do it yourself
because before you guys were just fall
in instructor doing it But now you will
as a team will have to do it yourself
because it's very important guys, that
a framework that we developed, right?
It's kind of like it's a medium, medium
size, medium level framework, I would say.
And now it's important guys, that you can
put it this framework yourself, right?
But also, of course,
besides the technical part, guys,
we will be looking at the user
stories, right?
So what's going to happen
This I'm going to explain you
regarding your user stories
and how you guys will be doing the things
and Moazzam will explain you
how you guys will be working together.
Okay.
So let me actually all the team names.
One moment, guys.
I need I need your
so the file that I shared, right,
guys, the file that are shared.
So right now, guys.
And if some of you still did
not put your GitHub username, please
make sure you guys do it
because Amazon needs it so he can add you.
Okay, so he can it
right for now.
Okay. There's somebody is missing me.
We created extra projects in there.
Okay, so let's have a little this.
Let's have a look. Okay.
So what is going to happen this right?
So all of you right now,
you guys have groups, right?
You guys all have groups.
So. And groups
with two based in here, right?
I believe there is a ten groups
as of moment.
Okay.
I think there should be nine or ten.
Right.
So students
that are there two people or three people.
So I would suggest guys
try to get together.
Right.
For example, and we testers,
I don't know if there is the rest
of the team members do not add anything,
but if it's only two of you, Abdul
I probably would suggest you with
and we testers and with the bite Me
you guys tried to join together, right?
Because it's important
that you guys doing it as a team.
Okay, so you guys can gather together
and work on one project.
Okay, So and try not to go to Gene
right now because maybe some of you guys
forgot your access.
I will help you with that.
So basically, the very project,
the way is going to work, guys, it's fully
kind of like in two parts, right?
The first part where you guys actually
are going to have to do an actual sprint.
And you know, guys, whenever we are,
whenever we are working in that Scrum
team, right, whenever we are
following Agile, Agile, I'm going to ask
you questions right now on this.
Right.
So how long is this usually spring days.
How long?
Usually sprint
It's always two weeks.
It can be between two weeks
to four weeks, right?
So 2 to 4 weeks, different projects,
different companies
following their own structure,
even within the same company.
You guys, there can be a project
that will follow a different structure
is, for example, think of the Amazon guys,
Think of Bank of America, right?
Bank of America has multiple,
multiple projects, the same as Amazon.
They have multiple, multiple projects
within the same company.
So now those projects, my
my have different structure
right when it comes to following a scrum.
Right So now before right maybe
when just Agile came into the picture
probably four weeks were 3 to 4 weeks
work work.
Hammer However, now
because we are in the fast pace, right,
we in the first phase and clients
want more faster feedback, right?
Clients want to see a application
in a faster right.
So this way right now very, very common.
Mostly people companies are shifting
towards two weeks, right?
And there are some companies
that still follow three weeks.
Yes, there are still companies
to follow three weeks even where we hear
lately, guys, sometimes even companies
have a one week sprint.
Right. I think maybe you heard it from
from Suhail.
I think you compare his company.
They do sometimes a one week sprint,
which I think is pretty crazy.
Honestly, I don't know
what can you achieve in in one week.
Oh every two weeks is very common right.
Two which is very common
and within this two weeks.
Right.
We've let me ask you guys, for example,
if the project is for two years
is it means this month
it will be two weeks,
next months will be three months
or it's two weeks for the rest, two
years.
Okay.
It will be the same days.
It will be the same. Right.
If you are joining the project,
if you join in the project,
and if you stay on that project.
So they are following the same
because it's a set time box, right?
It's a set time box, guys. The company.
Right.
The team before the days before
you actually joined the company,
before you join the project,
there's actually a lot
a lot of things are happening, right?
So you might join on the sprint
number ten.
You might join on the sprint.
Number five, you might join on the sprint
number 15, right 20 in the middle.
Sometimes on the project.
However, even before those sprints
actually started, guys.
Right.
It means before before
the project was a sprint started.
So they product owner had to actually
talk to the client,
gather all the requirements.
Right.
Not all but at least at that time
that that they know what they want.
Right. All those technical part
has to be discussed
how the application is going to look.
So this takes time
before the actual actual sprint starts.
Sometimes a company spends eight before
talking
and in finalizing all the things right,
and then all the processes
will be discussed, right.
So before they start a project,
they define, okay, we're going to follow
two weeks sprints
and this two weeks sprints
will be for the rest of the project.
The same project, right? The same project.
Of course.
If you guys going to change projects
within the same company, right?
Projects
within the same company, for example.
Right. Let's say Google, right.
There's a separate team
that works strictly on
Gmail, there's a separate team
that strictly works on drive.
There's a separate team
that strictly for work
on other parts
when it comes to Google, right?
So there's a different different
different teams that work in there.
So different project.
So unless you move from one project
to another project,
then that timeline can change.
But usually, usually it's always
or I mean, when you join the project for
the rest of the duration of the project,
your your sprint will be the same, right?
You will be the same.
Right.
So two weeks,
that's what usually we're looking at.
And as I mentioned in here, guys,
what we will do, we will we will do a
short spring, we will do a one week
sprint, one week sprint.
Usually what it is,
it's a five working days, right?
So now within this sprint,
right within two weeks,
spring,
one week sprint, three weeks sprint.
So what kind of
meetings are there?
What kind of ceremonies. Right.
We call them as ceremonies.
What kind of ceremonies are happening
this we, we
select all
very clean.
Okay.
Right. Okay.
So there's a several similar
ceremonies are happening right.
So, for example,
if we're going to take a two week sprint.
Right.
It went down.
I don't know why you don't,
but two weeks sprint.
Right.
So and remember those
on which they on
which they sprint against targets.
What are this thing on which they
now maybe I will surprise you guys
but sprain doesn't mean
that it has to start on Monday.
Your spring kills happen.
It can happen on any day
probably except Friday Except Friday.
Right.
Because on Friday,
a lot of people, you know,
people are taking times off,
sometimes people doing the things
probably not on Friday,
but it's very, very common.
Guys use Sprint can start on Monday,
on Tuesday, on Wednesday.
On Thursday.
It does not have to be a monday.
Can be any day,
but most likely not Friday.
It's not Friday.
So now if you're going to talk about,
for example, let's say
let's take that, okay,
this is where our sprint starts, right?
And for example,
there was a sprint one
today is a sprint to.
Right.
And today's Tuesday,
I mean, today's Monday.
But let's pretend today's Tuesday, right?
On Tuesday.
So usually, guys,
what kind of meetings we're going to have
on the first day of the sprint
for you guys will be on Sunday.
So what are we going to have?
We're going to have a sprint planning,
right Sprint plan.
And what usually happens on the sprint
planning is
right.
So on this pre planning guys, remember,
it's not it's not maybe
I don't understand the term
general summary but I remember there's one
sprint planning, right?
You guys will be looking at that users
stories right.
So where those user stories are stored,
that's
the one that you have to look
for this particular sprint
behind your back.
Look what kind of backup.
There's a two type of backlogs.
We have.
We will be in this frame backlog, right?
So we'll be looking in this spring
when and you guys
will be looking at this sprint backlog
right?
That is spring backlog
because that's where we'll be
all the user stories
for this particular sprint.
Right.
And then Sprint one
also has its own sprint backlog.
Right.
But when we talk about all the user
stories, where all the user stories
story, that's
I will be
that will be a good refreshing
to the store in the product backlog.
Right? The store in the product backlog.
Okay. I'll just put it.
This is just I'm
just trying to refresh your memory.
Right? So sprint linear, right.
That's where you guys will be looking
at the user stories.
Right.
And in case if the estimation is not done
before, right.
You guys will be looking at user
stories, will be doing the estimation.
Right.
And besides the estimation Right,
besides the estimation,
what else there needs to be done, guys, if
you estimate right, you put those points.
What else we do, guys, is priority
really priority guys, the user stories
that will be in the backlog,
they already prioritize, right?
They already prioritize tasks. Right.
Remember,
guys, you will be assigning a task, right?
For example, there will be user story.
One, two, three, right.
One, two, three,
whatever the user's going to say.
Right.
As an admin user, I should user
should be able to do this and this.
Right.
So now this user story, remember guys,
there's a tasks
has to be assigned to this user stories.
A task will be assigned
by developers, right?
Because developer going to pick the
the story
and the task will be assigned by you.
Right?
Because developers has to do his own job.
You guys will have to do your own job.
Right So everybody
but for this user story, remember
this user story has to be developed uses
story has to be tested, right?
So for those this user story,
a developer will be assigned
and so a developer and developer
and the tester will be assigned, right?
One dev, one tester,
maybe there will be two to this, right
in case of the user stories to be right.
And now developer
going to add his own tasks and you guys
will be adding your own tests. Right?
So that's what
we guys are trying to do in here as well.
Okay.
So for we're created, right?
Engineer, every group is having a project.
That's a project.
So what we did in here, guys,
you will see a user stories, okay,
you guys will see a user stories.
And I'm just doing an example on, on
one of the users on one of the projects.
Okay.
I think there's a 14 user stories,
14 user stories.
So what do we want you to do this?
Okay, What do we want you to do?
We want you remember
you doing it as a team, okay?
You doing it as a team.
You guys will have to look at all
user stories, every single user story.
Guys, it has an acceptance criteria, okay?
It has an acceptance criteria.
And in here, guys,
you will have to add your sap.
Right?
So this 14 user stories you guys need
to distribute and lot of your team
members, for example, right here,
you guys are 11 team members, right?
So at
each, each
team member have to pick one user story,
right?
You guys will be picking your own user
story that you want to work on, right?
Nobody at actual work,
nobody actually going to tell you,
hey, you pick in this, you pick
and that's where you are choosing, right?
You are choosing.
So whichever user story you are
comfortable, you guys are choosing.
And then here, for example, guys,
there's a seven people, right?
We have seven studios in here.
So we want you guys
at least to pick one user story.
And then if you're done with one,
if you guys want to do another one,
you more than welcome to pick it up. Okay.
But so what do you guys will have to do
as a team, Right, As a team
you guys will have together on the Zoom
call, you will have to go through
each and every single user story
and analyze it.
Right. And all users stories.
Of course,
they're related to which application
they're related to our it
your most obligation, right?
So majority majority of the user
stories will be related to
they will be related to change in details.
Okay. Change in details.
You guys will be working
on personal details, contact details.
You guys will be working in here.
In here, in here.
Okay.
So all this forms,
you guys will have to seal it up.
Okay, so based on the user story,
so one thing I'm going to ask you guys,
please
make sure when you were doing it, testing
when you will be automating,
please try to use a nice data, right?
Not like John. One,
two, three, four, five. Right.
Or just any name. Right.
Try to use a nice data because after this
project guys, whenever you are
moving to learn a databases, everything
that you guys will store right now,
you will see it in the database and later
you guys will be doing the API tests.
And so you want to make sure that you work
with that nice data, right?
You don't want to see a name
that has just 1 to 3.
Okay. So
in here I will explain your way away
as specified this spring.
Woman in here and
and sprinkling in separate right So
and all of you
this is what you will need to do right.
Usually usually of course guys
as spring will be starting right,
The spring will be started.
However, in here
we will ask you guys to start it yourself.
And it's very easy. You guys just will do.
Create a spring and then whatever user
stories you guys are going to pick, right?
You guys going to pick you guys
just moving it, right?
Guys just went in. Woman
And then you want to click on
Start Spring, just select that.
It's the one week end.
Today will be a start date, right?
There will be a started
and then then there will be an end date.
Right. So now what you will do.
So technically, technically,
when we're look in here guys,
this is your product backlog,
right? Right.
This is where all the user stories.
Then you look at the user stories,
you analyze them.
Everybody should understand
every single user story
right then
and remember, guys, one understanding is
you looking at the user story,
you have to go to the application, right?
And then once you select your user stories
guys, then you pick them
and you move them, right?
You move them.
This is kind of like
will be your spring backlog
and then you guys are going to start.
Yeah, there's just one.
Remember guys, just select your team early
because your team lead should be
there
when it comes specially to the get case.
So select one team member.
So whenever
but this is will be your group discussion.
Remember this after me and was our done
explaining you how the project works.
You guys will drop from this class
and you guys will create your own zoom
links and you guys will be talking. Okay.
So now another guys term.
What we will look in here right?
Spring planning, right?
Usually it happens the very first day.
Not usually.
It always happens
on the very first day of this gets.
So now, guys, there's another meeting
that actually
happening.
It's a spring grooming.
What do you do?
What happens on the spring grooming days?
Yes, guys,
you're not going to have a classes.
So we are giving you a time
so you guys can practice.
We are not going to disturb you
with the classes
so you guys can put your full hundred
percentage attention.
Spring grooming.
Mohammad, you getting confused?
That's another meeting.
What could have done better?
Spring grooming
at spring more.
It's kind of like helping poise
this spring, right?
I remember this spring grooming right
when we talk about spring grooming, it's
you are looking at the user stories.
You are looking at the user stories,
right?
You trying to groom those user stories?
What do we mean by groom user stories?
Grooming usually guys.
Okay.
Usually, for example, in here,
right in the middle of the spring one
right here,
we might have a spring grooming session
and that's where we will be looking at
the user stories,
maybe upcoming sprints
or maybe just overall sprints. Why?
We want to look at the user stories
prior to this spring, because we want to
we want to look at them
and to make sure that everybody
understands, they accept this criteria
and Tim is getting suggestion.
He maybe what about this this scenario?
What about this scenario? Okay.
So that's what are we actually looking
into those user stories
and trying to understand them. Right.
Trying to understand them.
And if the time permits, guys,
if the time permits in the company,
you guys might also do estimation. Okay.
If the time permits
and the team has a not that busy
if if there is a if there's a
if you guys are following the plan.
Right.
If there's an actual if if it's a per
if we think of the perfect spring,
this perfect spring, usually
all these stories should be groomed
before they come to the planning, right?
So user stories should be analyzed,
entire team should understand them
and estimate them.
So this way, when this user story
comes to the planning, right,
you guys already know
what is this user story about
and what it makes spring planning quicker.
And at the same time, what do we just go?
We just go
and we just add our tests in there.
Okay, So but there's no perfect things
exist when it comes to anything, right?
So that's why perfect Agile also does
not exist.
So sometimes you might come to the spring
planning, half user stories might be
already will be groomed and estimated,
and some of the user stories
wouldn't be estimated in this way
you will have to complete them
in during the spring.
Planning.
Not understandable.
Okay.
And it's they're not going to change it,
but they're going to do
you guys go and try to discuss
in case of there's
any missing details
he has been a product owner will be there.
They will take notes.
They will go back to the
they will check or maybe the
some technical discussion
needs to be there.
That's why devs are there. Right.
So to to clear all the
all the concerns that we have
and for example, there will be a part
where you will get a suggestion,
Hey guys, what about this?
And then what about this, this scenario?
If you're going to go this way, right,
you give your suggestion and then if B
defines it that, hey,
it's really something that we missed,
they going to add it
as a part of the acceptance criteria.
Right?
So we just want to make sure
that user story is completed, right?
Completed in terms of the defined so later
it can be developed and tested. Get.
So that's why in here
you guys we will mentioned first
right sprint do spring grooming.
Right.
Spring grooming means that's where
you understand the user stories, right?
You analyze, you understand. Right.
And if you can do the estimation, right.
We trying to do a perfect sprint, right?
You're trying to do a perfect sprint
and then you guys moved those.
You you guys will need to analyze
You can analyze all of them right?
So this way you guys can select
which one you want to pick, right?
You guys can do the estimation.
After you do the estimation, then whoever
if you guys are comfortable,
you just drag them to the spring planning.
You just move them to the sprint, Right?
You will move them in here,
you will start your sprint.
And what do you guys will do in here
right.
Once you know which user story you speak
and then you guys will be adding
your tasks.
Okay. Yep.
I did something.
Report or delete
that something is not needed.
Right. Okay.
So that will be the part
when you guys work with the user stories.
Right.
And then of course, once you start
and for you guys,
I think you guys future testers.
Okay, Future testers,
I'm going to start your sprint by later.
Guys, please make sure you add more users.
Actually, let me show you on other teams.
Let me see.
Oh, finish. Right.
So there's this four columns
you guys going to have, right?
So remember the moment you guys are going
to start your sprint, all the user
stories will be into do York will be into
the moment you assign a person.
Remember there's you can assign yourself
right once you look in the store
and make sure you assign it
to yourself. Right.
Because you will want to know that this is
you working on this user story.
So the moment you guys start doing it,
make sure you move it to
the progress, right?
Because so this way entire team knows.
You start working on it, right?
You start working on it
and you will you will start adding
your task.
You will assign it to yourself. Right.
And also, guys, it's important.
Okay?
You guys will be creating a
you create a step test, right?
So remember, guys, this gear, right?
Why do we call it
a it's a it's a management tool.
It's a management tool.
So entire team is looking in here.
Your product owner,
your Scrum Master BS is there.
Everybody is looking at, right?
So we want to see the progress
because every day, guys, there's a need.
And what kind of meeting is there
every day, guys.
Okay, stand up. Right, Stand up.
So what will happen on the stand up
and who usually in
Let me see Farhad I so I saw a question.
I'll come back to a question.
Who usually runs this stand up
a scrum muster?
Luckily the Scrum master. Right.
Remember Scrum Master always always
in charge into those meetings, right?
It does not mean that Scrum Master will
or will participate
in the estimation or planning.
Right.
But it's if it's role of the Scrum master
to set up those meetings.
Right.
It's the role of the Scrum master
in invite all of you.
Right.
And it's a role of Scrum Master
especially when it comes to the spend up.
Right.
So usually, I mean, these days, of course,
you guys will be joining on Zoom and
and whenever
we used to work in the offices.
Right.
The Scrum master, everybody just gathers
or you guys will be joined in the zoom.
Right.
This grand master just opens
and everybody's seen this board, right?
This is the board of the entire team.
So team knows.
Okay, this story already interesting.
This story is still in the progress.
Right.
And usually in progress is this when
developers are also working on it, Right.
In our case,
all user stories already developed.
Right.
And you just guys have to test them. Okay.
But it's important guys to move them all
the time.
It's important to move them on time,
especially when you are done.
Especially when you are done.
Because remember this
when you are done with the user story,
right?
When you are done with this user story,
remember guys,
there is some kind of like graph we have.
What kind of what kind of graph
we have endured that shows
our work
burned down chart, right?
Burn down chart.
And what a burned down chart shows this.
Okay.
What do we have on the on the vertical
and on the horizontal line?
It shows the progress.
Right.
So here it will show you a days right
here.
We'll show you the user stories. Right.
A perfect a perfect burn down
chart should look like that
on the day Number one, of course,
there's all user stories,
but the more down the spring goes,
the more user stories left, right.
And we don't want to see something
like that.
All user stories there, there, there.
And then boom, Why?
Why they're there
because you forgot to update
and then and then your burn down
chart goes like that.
Right?
So that's why I have to make sure
the moment user story is done
in does effects that chart.
Okay.
And usually Scrum Score is going to look
into this is going to look at that chart.
So make sure you move them on time.
Right.
Make sure you move them one time. Okay.
So after you guys analyze user stories,
estimate them,
drag them to your sprint, right?
And then
assign the team member, assign it,
and then you guys create the tasks, right?
You guys create a task usually, right?
Yeah.
It will be automatically.
Yep, it will be automatic. Yep.
So and usually right the moment
the sprint starts, remember this
developers start working on that, right?
Because when you own the
when you own the actual project,
something has to be developed, right?
And the developers
depend on the size of the user story.
Right? But they tried to be cool.
So some small user stories at first
so they can give some work to testers
as well, right? They will. They will.
They will fix some small user stories,
big user stories, medium user stories,
but they want to make sure they don't
leave all the testing at the end, Right.
That's why they
they will start mixing those user stories.
But whenever a developer is finished,
right,
whenever developer is finished
with the user story,
right, whenever they develop,
whenever they perform the unit testing,
once they see everything is working fine,
then they move
the user story to interesting
writing you the user story in testing,
and in our case, of course, guys,
we don't have a developer is right.
So what do you guys will do?
You guys will move it yourself, right?
So but while you are being in progress
right.
Why is being in progress?
Guess what you guys will start doing.
You guys will start doing air
mental test cases, right?
You guys will have to create
a manual test case.
And you in this situation, as if you want
to practice, it means excel.
You guys are more than welcome
to create a test case in Excel
or if you guys just want to write
right away your cucumber set your file.
It's also totally fine.
So depend on you guys, right?
So majority of the times guys, of course,
when we work, when the cucumber projects
they do, I mean,
whenever we follow this BDD approach,
this feature files, they do so they do.
They do play a role
as a manual test cases.
Right. So would you throw
this is just for the refreshment.
You guys want to do Excel,
that's up to you.
But cucumber feature file should be
should be enough, right?
Okay. So
can we use JIRA?
Okay, in here,
guys, That's one thing that we don't have
the latest version of JIRA.
There's there's a little version of gear
that is JIRA, X-ray.
That's where you guys can actually read
your test cases right in here.
Guys, we don't have this option.
So this way, if you will. Right?
Whenever you ride your camera,
IQ camera, feature flag,
you can just upload it in here for us.
So we can we can look at a look into it.
But whenever you guys done right,
whenever you guys done
preparing and writing the manual,
this is a moment.
You ready The moment you're ready to test,
make sure you move it
into the testing right.
Make sure you guys move it to the testing.
And now when it comes to testing,
remember, guess always, always, always.
We have to do a mental testing, right?
We're not going to jump right away
and do the automation.
Okay.
So why we don't want to do automation
right away?
Yeah, you want to make sure that use
this door is going to pass, right?
You're not going to start automation
or something that fails.
Right.
And at the same time,
I think going guys to develop
automation scripts, of course,
user story can be very easy, right?
They can take very little time.
But think of that user story
that will take a lot of efforts, right?
What if you would take one or two days?
So now one or two days,
you did not tested manually.
You were trying to do the automation
and then you automation skills
and now you find out
that there is a bug, right?
So now you will have to report it,
but you wasted two days, right?
So that's why it's important.
The moment user story
comes into the testing,
you have to make sure you test it
manually.
You see, if it's passed,
then you continue with the automation.
If it does not pass,
you have to send it back to the developer.
Hey, this user story is failing, right?
So this way they can start working on it
right this day, they can start working.
It fixes any issues and
then give it back to you once they fix it.
Right?
So the same thing we want you to do
as you want you to do that
manual testing, right? Manual testing.
And only then you guys
will be starting automation only.
Only then you guys will be starting
automation.
Okay.
I just said you have deer, right?
Everything is reported in Jurgis.
No, no, no.
Everything's reported. India and
you guys just reported there
and in actual companies guys also,
it will depend, right?
It will depend.
You will of course your quick you manage
management will push you into log
in all the bugs.
However sometimes there's
there's some bugs there can be very tiny
and small
right sometimes to fix something for
and for a developer,
sometimes it takes 10 minutes max.
Right.
And by time your report the actual bug,
it might take you 30 minutes
because you have to
you have to retest to take the screenshot
steps to represent to to, to reproduce
and all this.
Right.
So sometimes I remember in my work
if the bug was a little small in
and you know when you in the office
environment that just told my developer
hey can you quickly
fix it right so and they're okay
and they fix it within 10 minutes.
Right. So but that will come
that you guys will know
once you join the actual project.
Okay so but usually usually
we try to log in in in our
in my last company
where I work developer hours we had a
we had a
thing is a developer something can be
quickly done within the same day
we were not reporting it in the however,
there was
something that we were not able to do
within the same day.
Then we were reporting it.
Okay, so but that comes from project
to project and it also comes from
you about your relationship
with your developers, right?
At the same time, remember,
guys, developers don't like to to see
what you report, but right, they, they,
they trying to do their work
and the thing that they do in it
everything amazing however we do find bugs
right so they try to do their work
with trying to do our work right.
But usually you guys,
you will have to look. Yes.
Right.
So user story, for example,
let's look at this user story, right?
It is.
As an admin, I should be able to change
employee contact details.
Right.
So developer already developed this user
story that's why we have seen it in here.
Right?
So then you go in here, contact details.
Okay, let me see what my user says
or my user story says.
So is in here right?
Except this criteria fallen field
must be displayed and edible.
Editable. Right.
And then you just verify
that all the skills are in there right?
To just verify that all it fills in there.
You click on edit,
you seal it up everything, right?
And then you click on Save.
It's working. It's saved. Okay.
It's passed right and it's passed.
And then once it's passed, once
you see that
those details have been saved, then
you just moving towards your automation.
Get in.
There was one question
one moment from for HUD.
Okay. Okay.
So for HUD, Yes.
If you guys are ten people, right?
If you guys are ten people.
So each of you guys just pick
one user story at first, right?
Pick one user story it first, analyze it,
and then if you guys have time.
And then if some of you wants to be extra
user stories, you guys can do it.
However, you don't required.
But we what
we want everyone to do at least
one user story. Okay
when do you moment tested?
Whenever you finish, whenever you
finish writing and then or test case
right the moment you're ready
to start actual testing
then you move it,
then you move it into testing.
And once you manual test it, once
you guys are
meet, automation is passed, automate it.
Only then you guys be moving it to them.
Okay, moving into that.
Okay.
So this process, this process, we want do.
And of course, guys, we
you guys will be talking to each other
every single day, right?
Because you guys will have you guys
besides this.
You guys are of course, we'll have to
do a framework which I will talk about it.
Okay.
And which I will talk about it
and make sure, guys,
every day when you gather guys practice
to do a stand up.
Right.
So what do we talk about on the stand
up this
right every single day?
Right.
So there's a for example,
if it's a ten working days, right spring,
there is two weeks, right?
Then here will be another spring,
three story, right?
So far, this is half right.
So here should be fast
then. That was done, right?
Three or five.
And here.
One, two, three, four, five. Okay.
Maybe on the first day
you're needed because you will be doing
this pre-planning in there.
Okay, So
You give given your update. Right.
And we just give an update.
And remember, guys, it's
not a day to give like to management.
You just giving an update
to your own team. Right.
Hey, I'm working on this. Right.
What I have done yesterday, right.
What I will be working on today
and in case
if I have any,
I can guess of the hammer and the issues.
So every single day we have our daily
stand
up, daily stand up, daily stand up right.
And how long is a daily stand up?
Usually guys, next 15 minutes, right, Max?
15 minutes.
Sometimes guys, it's even can be shorter
depending on the size of your team.
Right.
Also depend on
the size of work has been done.
Right.
Think of guys
after the very first day, right?
This is your second day.
So in the second day, team
cannot give that much of updates.
Right. What's your update?
It just spring planning beginning now
with right.
Developers will say that they start
working on such a such a user story
and you just going to say that
hey I started
I start writing my test cases, right
that that's pretty much an update
but here we'll update will be different
right developers will say
that the finish user story
the moved it then you start testing it
then that will be
that will be a little bit longer.
Right.
But that's usually no longer
than 15 minutes.
We try to keep it no longer
but could it be there.
Remember this perfect things are don't
exist right So could it be the longer.
Of course it could be longer. Right.
Okay.
So and what happens
at the end of the spring?
So let's say
this is the last day of this print.
Last date, right? That day number.
If it's a work in the right, we will
we will be counting working days.
So this is a day, number ten, right?
So if we started on Tuesday,
this will be day number
ten and it will be our Wednesday
and Wednesday.
So this way,
the next spring will start in here
and it will be another Tuesday in here.
Okay, Spring Retrospective, Spring Review.
What's the difference?
Okay, so
it's personal things.
Okay.
So remember, there's usually
in the morning, right On the last day
in the morning, maybe around ten, 11.
Right. So what are we going to have?
We're going to have we call it
spring review or we call it a spring demo.
Right. Spring demo.
So spring demo, we're showing our work
to the client.
Right.
What kind of work has been done
for the past two weeks?
Right.
Or in our case, for the past
ten working days.
Right. But it's a two week spring, right?
So and usually this meeting
is it's usually
about four one hour, one hour.
And here you guys will see entire team
besides besides the scrum team,
there will be there will be a
is my battery day.
There will be project manager designers.
Every everybody will
come in there to get feedback.
And then after that, of course,
there's the
then the last day
we're going to have our spring retro.
Okay, so what do we talk about
on the spring Retro.
Okay, so wouldn't you
success
and those right so we will go Yep we'll
talk about what one Well what went wrong
which things we should continuously doing
we which don't think that's one wrong
which
which we should improve and make sure
it doesn't happen with the next screen.
Right. It's it's it's learning.
So the same thing as we want you to do
after you guys finished, right after
you guys finish with everything,
we want you to do a spring retrospective.
So you guys as a team, right?
It will be your first time
when you guys will be working together.
When it comes to the automation
using GitHub, the same GitHub
together and developing things, right?
So you guys will talk about,
hey, what was to us?
What things do you guys maybe next time
we should do, do, do better, right?
So this is when it comes to this,
this is
when it comes to the sprint, right?
So now there's another part.
Another part.
I guess what? We want you to do this.
We want you to develop a framework
from scratch, okay?
We want you to do it from scratch.
So we want you to gather the same thing.
Remember this.
And now it's a team work.
It's not just Hallmark.
Pick it up and develops everything.
Know this.
So remember before you going to start
in actual automation?
This. So this way you guys can decide.
Maybe you will analyze all the user
stories first and then start working.
Or sometimes what students do, they,
they first discuss this
framework, develop framework
and make sure they set up the baseline in.
Only then they must do
the user stories right.
So we want you to
develop a framework from scratch
because you will have to gather together.
You guys will need to analyze
every single part.
We want to make sure every single team
member does understand
what is framework is doing right
is, for example, it's ten of you, right?
So you guys will discuss, okay,
this part of our framework.
We need this in this and try guys please
the best part guys also
try and I don't want you to copy and paste
anything else we want you to develop
every single method from this crisis
the way you did it before.
Okay, so this way, guys.
It will be amazing practice for you. Okay?
For example, you guys will take now while
I'm going to to take our
our configs reader, I'm going I'm
going
I'm going to create that that that, that.
Okay.
And then tomorrow
okay I'll work on the Excel right
And then how you will work
on creating something else.
Right.
You know features, not features as well
I guess features will start
when you guys actually will start doing
the actual automation common
methods, right?
Multiple people can work on the common
Okay.
No guys, this is setting out framework.
Structure is one thing.
Automating user story
that's a different thing, right?
That's a different thing.
So you guys, we want you to do a framework
together, right?
We want you to everyone should contribute.
And then once you have your framework
set right, once you guys have frameworks
and if you guys want to do the pages,
at least the beginning pages,
you guys know you will need a login page.
You guys know
you will need the dashboard page,
you guys need
you will need a boys page, right?
It will be your base skeleton.
You guys can distribute it, right?
And then once you combine, you call this.
Once you combine,
you could because remember, Aisha,
you will be doing it on your laptop, on
extender you will be doing on your laptop.
Then you guys will have to merge.
You could write and then once you merge
you, then you guys will have to take it
right after Merge and every single team
have to have that structure.
You guys will be working on your own.
On your own.
Oh, how do we call them in GitHub?
Speak my mind right now. Branches. Right?
You guys will be working on your own
branches, right?
So this way guys, it will be amazing
experience for you
to review everything you have learned
and to have an opportunity
to actually develop it from scratch.
Try to do every single thing right.
Somebody's going to start off
setting up the name
and somebody is going to add independency.
So you guys will decide how to do it
right.
Once you gather together,
you guys will be decided to do
it. Well, that's that you guys,
you guys should be
should be able to do it a lot of times.
A lot of times.
So try to help each other.
Guys, this is most important.
Why are we going to be there?
Yes, but you guys should be able to try
with resolve it together
when it comes to actual work.
Right.
Remember this, your first number, Help,
of course, will be Google.
But then and number two to help
will be your all teammates in there.
Right.
If you have two or three,
are there automation engineers?
You guys will have to talk together
and you guys will have
will help each other if you go into stock.
Of course, guys, we will be there. Okay.
You guys will be there.
So this way, guys.
Remember framework that from scratch
and then you guys will do an actual
and then of course, once you guys peak
user stories, then you guys will be
you guys will need your own pages,
you guys will need your own elements,
but at least the skeleton will be there.
Okay? Skeleton will be there. So
that right And Watson will guide you guys
that will guide you
because remember, we are trying to do it
as it's actually
you guys going to have at your work.
Right?
So all the repositories will be on our
on our on our GitHub, right?
That's the same thing if you join,
for example, Bank of America, right?
Bank of America
going to have its own repository
where all the projects
will be there, Right?
And then usually when you join
the company, they will send you an email
and you guys will have to create it
and they will give you access to it.
Right?
So the same thing, guys,
we will be giving you access
to your team members, all your team
members, to your particular repository,
to a specific specific repository.
I mean, if you want,
do you more than welcome back out
the exhibit, you guys can just
reconnect every time, right?
So branches, branches, branches museum
this is
we will will going to explain key branches
what I will explain.
Okay And then what do we want guys?
What do we want at the end?
At the end after your user stories
are automated,
every every single thing is done, guys.
Right.
When you do your retrospective,
what do you want you guys to do?
We want you actually to draw your homework
or homework.
So to draw your framework
and draw your framework in the way
Android in the way you guys
can actually look at it
and understand it, right?
For example, we have seen our students
draw their framework.
They split it based on packages.
Some students are split
based on even some very,
very details, like pages
and then common methods and this.
And this and this. Okay.
So can I show you this sample?
Yes, I can show you this sample.
So the but the same thing, guys.
Try to do it together. Right.
Try to do together because this particular
framework you guys will be using, it's
related to describing.
Okay. So it will be very important.
And you guys should understand how
the actual actual framework that works.
But once you guys develop it,
once you guys work on it together,
it will be easy for you and it will clear
a lot of a lot of things for you.
Okay,
I'm sure you guys,
you guys can do it right?
You guys are working together
now, not together as a team.
So a lot of you guys will help each other.
You guys will help each other.
Okay, So let me see.
Guys, what are we doing in here?
You see all the user stories
you guys will do?
Spring grooming, spring planning
on the list, each part of the framework.
Right? Create a framework.
You will created from scratch.
Don't copy and paste. Right.
Help each other.
Okay. So
ago, guys,
this is what we want to make sure.
Right.
Make sure you guys have a met.
That's okay.
Make sure you guys,
I want you to develop a methods
that can handle radio buttons, checkboxes,
dropdowns, alerts, frames.
Right. Frames, windows.
So make sure there's the code
after you guys will
I will give you this Google document that.
So what will happen? Right?
Whenever you guys will be done
with all the users
stories when they were
automation is completed, right?
So what do you guys will do?
You guys combine it, right?
So you guys eventually will push it.
You guys will push it to one
branch, right?
Because that's how it should be, right?
It actually work.
You will have multiple people
working on the user stories automated,
but in the end, after everything works,
everything has to be
pushed and on one branch in our work
should be there.
Right?
So in once entire work is there, I guess
make sure your code is executable
through Maven.
So make sure guys,
your code generates reports.
You guys already know those cucumber.
Nice reports, right?
And screenshots. Okay.
And make sure all the user stories
that you pick.
Right.
They are automated in,
they are on the GitHub and here Android.
That's why guys at first we tell you pick
at least
one user story
because it's it's meaty thing
you're going to do fast
but just because it requires a team effort
right This might take some time
but I promise you guys once
you actually do it together,
I'll ask you guys next week, how was it?
And I'm sure you guys
you guys will learn a lot.
Okay.
And of course guys and kids
or any questions.
But remember, first you discuss it
together, is the team
send them in the support channel
kids in supporting so and a few things
guys a few things one wait one second
charger just switch from the charger
to stream. Yep.
So a few things, guys.
Let me show you a little
bit of the user stories.
Okay.
We will do our review class this
we will go or we will do a review class
right on our on the project to talk about
maybe maybe next Monday.
That's what we will try to do, right.
That we will look at the time.
Okay.
So one thing let me clarify this.
There's a few users talk to one couple
user stories I want you to clarify.
Okay. I want to clarify.
So is is fine.
Multiple dependance. It's fine.
Or employees work
and then we should be able to me implement
different skills.
Okay.
So now when you guys look in here, right,
I want you to look in here.
So there are very similar.
So when you look at the user story
number seven, eight and 910,
11/12, okay,
they look similar, but they are different.
So user story number seven
and also guys, what you will see
we wrote
user stories except this criteria.
We ordered two different ways.
Okay, so some except this criteria guys
we wrote using a working right
and some users stories don't have a great
because a different project
you guys my experience different that's
why we tried to put it two different ways
okay in some project
these if they're not work
and they will be writing it in Gurgaon,
but in some projects they just going
to put it in the form of bullet points.
Okay, so what's the difference between
user stories?
Seven, eight, nine, ten write,
make sure you follow the steps right?
Give an admin user is logged
in when admin navigates to qualifications.
Right.
This is about user story number seven.
You have to go to the qualifications
you logging in
as admin,
you will go to the qualifications
and then what it says in here, here
qualifications and then select skills.
Then admin is able to add
any skills, right?
So this is what it talks about.
So you go to the admin, you go to
the qualifications, you click on skills.
Okay?
And here you need to add the skills.
For example. Amazing.
Just in skills, right?
Skills.
I did not save it,
didn't get said need not stated.
Let me show you
what I'm trying to actually
okay this but I'm going to speak right so
and then of course
you guys will have to work from this table
that you are,
that your skill is saved
and your skill and safe.
Now the user story number eight,
it says as an admin user
should be able to add employee skills.
So it means now after this use
has been added, actually added.
Now these skills can be actually
actually assigned to the employee.
Right.
So the employee.
And now where do we talk about employee?
We talk about employee
when we come in here.
Okay.
When we come in here
and you guys will have to go
to the qualifications and here.
When you click on skills,
you click on ADD.
And now you able to see
because without user story
number seven, guys, amazing skills
you will be able to see.
Okay, so let me see
if I'm going to delete it right now.
Let me delete my amazing skills
building the little
okay now is deleted.
Now I won't be able to select them here.
Okay, so now you're going to click
on Skills and there's no amazing testing.
Yes, they are dependent.
You see guys two different things.
At first from the admin side,
you have to add them to a system itself.
Once something is in the system
all then you can actually assign it
to the employee.
And this is related to user story,
seven eight.
The same thing for user story number
nine and ten, you have to add it first
in this way here, except this criterion
that we give to where you have to go,
and then once you are able to add it,
only then you can assign it, right?
Maybe I'll change word.
It should be assign. It is an admin.
I should be able to assign employees
licenses.
Okay. It's not at the site.
It does.
And so seven eight has a dependency
on seven,
ten has a dependency on nine,
12 has a dependency on 11.
I mean, not like a dependency, right?
You still can do it.
But this is just to show you
that they are different.
Okay?
If they're something be added
in through the qualifications only then
it can be assigned to the employee's
qualifications is adding it to the system.
And this is assignment to the employee.
Okay. All right.
And I think that was for user stories.
And of course, guys, I'm going to share
this with you, going to share as things if
any questions,
guess how to work with the GitHub.
Amazon was going to explain you.
I will
I will share examples of doing this.
I want you to let me see, for example,
and let me find it.
It's always good
or thing I say.
Let me see, I can go to the rest of this.
For example, this is
I don't know if you guys can see it.
This is what. Student Oops.
Freeze it. Oh,
okay.
This is a students from previous batch.
This is how they do it.
Let me see.
I have another ones.
This is another one.
This is another students.
This is how they do this new utils. What?
What kind of pages?
They have features them.
They finished. Right.
This is what another students did and then
let me see that they want everything
in all of them.
Okay, so this is should be something
that you guys understand.
Okay. This is this is for your team.
This is something that you guys should
understand because we will be using it.
We will be using it. Close it. Now.
It's needed.
So we
select
I'll I'll this all upload.
If you guys did not see it
I'll just I'll just
uploaded in the course announcement
as an example.
As an example.
Yeah. I'm on the big screen.
I'm sorry guys,
but I tried to make it bigger.
I'll, I'll, I'll, I'll share it,
I'll share.
Okay.
All right, guys.
Right.
So I think that thing
that's what I wanted to explain
and let me just do as a recap, guys.
Right.
So as a recap, we created a framework
from scratch together as a team.
One team member should speak which part
of the framework they want to work on.
Right?
And then you guys will have to combine
your framework, right?
And then once you combine it,
then you guys all should take the combined
code, right?
And once you have that all, then
you guys will start doing
the user story automation.
But before the user story automation guys,
you will have to do your own meetings,
right?
You will have to do a spring room
in analyzing user stories.
Then you guys will have do this
pre planning where you guys pick
your user stories
and assign your tasks, right?
And then before the automation
you guys would want to write your manual.
Just case right.
You guys will have to read your manual
this case
and you guys will have to test it.
And if user story passed
in majority of them,
there will be positives
because it's already in application.
Only then you guys will be started
doing the automation.
Okay,
Framework, manual automation, right.
And all together
this would we doing it together, right.
We're doing it together
and help each other make sure this
if you're stuck somewhere,
help each other, try to jump on the call.
Right.
So there won't be any classes, guys,
until I think until Sunday, right.
Until Sunday. There is no classes, guys.
So we tried to give you from today
and because we started today,
five working days.
Right. We'll give you till
That's you guys
right.
So we'll project today, tomorrow,
Wednesday, Thursday, guys.
No review class. No review class.
Okay, in here
you guys also work on Saturday.
Guys try to finalize your work
and then on Sunday, you guys going to have
your first school class
and then I'll double check this
probably on Monday.
We will try to review it.
Okay.
Sounds good, guys
know you guys will do it on GitHub.
That was I will go over
he will have this skeleton
in there that you guys
will have to do some pushing, pull.
You guys are experts in it,
so you guys will be able to do it.
Okay. Mostly, mostly guys. You are.
You will be we will pick just a peek.
We just have one on that
that we will share.
Right.
That we will share about
when it comes to the automation.
But mostly guys,
you will be able to check with yourself
if you automated all the user stories,
if there's no duplication
that you guys have, when you guys merge
all the code and you core code
doesn't have the issues guys.
Okay, so you guys will be able to you
on your own, see how you guys
are completed and all these methods
that you guys will develop.
Remember guys you have to review it in
in in the actual work,
you guys are going to have a code review
meetings and code review meetings.
It means somebody developed something.
Now you as a team reviewing it, right?
If there's any enhancements,
any improvement you want to make
you guys, you should be able to make
those improvements.
Okay?
Okay.
Okay. All right, guys.
Sequel guys, all you guys going
to have your Oscar back?
Okay.
So I was gonna be teaching you sequel.
All right, I will share the details.
Now, guys, we have a second part
that that Moazzam is going to.
Moazzam was going to explain.
So I know.
Do you guys want to take a quick,
quick break or let me ask Moazzam
it Mosab,
how long is the explanation going to take?
Well, it's
good to get around 20 or 30 minutes, but
25 minutes.
Okay, 20 to 30 minutes, guys.
Right.
Okay, guys,
let's take a five minute break.
And then after the break,
after the break, Moazzam was out.
Will explain you the process,
explaining the process, how it works.
And meanwhile,
I'm just going to send the steps in.
I think that's it from my side,
guys. Okay.
I'm happy to see you guys.
And I'm sure you guys got it.
It's a it's
a great experience for all of you.
All right. And please make sure you do it.
Take it very seriously
and do it together as a team.
I believe in you guys. All right.
Guess I'll see you.
I'll see you next time. 825.
Yeah. Let's be back, guys, by 830.
Okay, so this way, 30 minutes
was up and finish 9:00.
And then
if you guys decide with your team,
if you guys want to start working
tomorrow, today,
you guys will decide it. It.
All right.
Just have fun.
One more thing.
As for dinner,
remember, your username for dinner is.
Yeah, I maybe up.
Maybe I'll type just a
status
or your username for dear
guys is your gmail
without a gmail part
and the password is syntax.
One, two, three.
I think I'll share it guys with you
just in case of some.
You forgot how to log in into gear.
Okay.
Good morning, everyone.
Here, Marina,
I'll give you 5 minutes noise about the.
Okay guys.
So I believe that all of you
are back from break and roll.
Yeah. Hello, everyone.
Hide the windows
I shot and I'm not.
I don't have not.
I'm sorry about that.
However, the.
Okay, so let's quickly begin with our work
workflow that you guys be following
throughout and get.
We have already discussed that
but at the end of the evening.
So you think that I'm pretty much sure
that it's going to be real simple.
So I believe that all of you have chosen
the team needs, right?
You do have one team within your group
of the
perfect, so we are going to do this.
Then you made this meaning
visibility,
maximize the like from my side.
I think
I have shared the whole
you want me to please the deck face
of the group.
Okay, so now all of you, all the group
members are going to have one key.
So a team lead one more responsibility,
which I will be sharing.
The rest of you are going to be
following the same stuff.
Even the team leader
is going to be following the same stuff.
Only there is one more responsibility
associated with it.
So first
I'm going to share the responsibility
with Team Lead has to also.
Okay, so the task of the team lead
is to launder output
and create a broad sub.
So what you're going to do
if you go to your GitHub output
and you've got the repository, you know,
when you open up
your repo, you'll see only one branch,
which is me.
And in
this box I have pushed the basic structure
of the project
that you will be working on.
It contains your former example
and simply your desktop job.
That's it.
So it is just the basic structure
you have.
Pull the framework over it.
Now the purpose of creation
of a sub me branch was that
that is because I don't want anyone
be merging
any code into the mean,
not even your needs.
Because what I want is that once
you guys are done with the project,
it should be in a separate sub.
Me I'm able to view it,
I can best it and then after that, only
if that is correct
I will then be merging it into the main.
So is the as this clear to everyone
that why do we need a sub
me branch?
So you guys have to stay
away from me at all time.
Okay.
So here's what's going to happen.
So the task of the team, we
the team leader,
is going to simply
after cooling the project, create
a submitted writes
and he will make a comment in that
this comment is going to contain,
you know,
nothing, just an extra comment
maybe so that he can he's able
to actually make a comment or else
if he has just brought out something
and he has not made any changes,
he won't be able to make a comment.
So what he will do is
he will add some elements in the board
so that he can make a comment
into something.
Right. And push it to better.
So is this tier now to the team?
Is the task is it clear?
Okay.
Now let's talk about the task
which I associate with the team members
and now was the team
you guys need to clear out
and then make your separate boxes
to work on
the particular feature user story
that you have chosen.
So simply this is going to be
your apple is going
to contain main and supply to matches.
You are going to clone this repo.
So when you will know that,
what do you guys think?
Which what will you have in your local
repository after to make
do it?
Just have them in brackets.
Remember we discussed this in class
that whenever you thought
only the main branch is going to be there
and for the other branches to be there,
we have to stack up
right?
Do you guys remember that?
Okay, so when you will submit
submit contest, it's called submit seven.
So why
don't you agree to clone this repository?
You will only have in the main branch?
Because we discussed this in class
that whenever we clone something
some represent
because it's only going to clone for us
being in order
to move to the other branches.
We have the check out method for that.
Okay, so
let me now explain the team members.
That's
so all of you are going to clone
this rep of the tree
and after that you will be having
this particular
main branch in your
local repository.
Now you want to work on your best.
The teacher.
I don't know the story.
So what are you going to do?
Okay, so there are two methods to do that.
Number one,
you can either check out from Main
and create a new branch or you can
check out the sub may not be any branch.
So basically the code
and see one and C two, is it going to be
almost same instead that only dealing
with some comments and C right.
These two codes are going to be the same.
Right?
So it doesn't matter
if you check from sub me or me,
that's going to be,
you know, the same thing.
So let's say it instead of checking out
from sub main you check out from we
and we started working on a feature
which one.
And you had
certain elements on all of them.
Well now it's your tries.
How many branches do you want to
create
from Teacher One
If you need a more branches you can.
If you think that one branch is enough,
you don't need to create
another branch
to solve any issues or stuff like that.
It's completely fine.
You can simply go on
working with feature one,
but if you take any other branch
it ought to resolve some issues
or stuff like that that you can create.
Another way here
and then merge it back to work.
Now the most important thing,
similarly, just like
someone would be talking like feature one,
there will be another person
who will be working on feature two
and there will be another person
who do not feature
three.
So I'm not going to
make little comments, but
let's assume
that you also have some comments going on.
Okay?
Once you are done
working on your property to the one,
what should be the next step
that you will follow?
Exactly. Once you are done working on it?
Branch you check
that is were what it was working fine.
You are going to
post branch on GitHub.
Okay and you will push to which
branch on github.
No, you will not proceed to sub
Christine member.
I told you that some is just like me
so you are not going to be pushing
and suddenly
you will be pushing to your own branch.
Each of one.
Okay, so now everyone is going
to be pushing in their own
branches
and stuff like that. So
yes, if you have five members on team,
you will be having five branches
and one sub main
which belongs to no one that is actually,
you know,
main branch.
Okay.
So once that is that done,
so your interface on GitHub
is going to look something like that.
You will be having different branches.
Each one
feature to feature tree and you can name
your branch anything you like,
your name maybe, or whatever
you feel comfortable.
And apart from these feature files
she will be working
on, there are going to be some main
and main.
Okay, I want to just tell you something.
Who is the owner of me?
I am the owner.
Okay.
So will anyone be pushing to me?
No. You guys are not allowed to touch it.
You open up a pull request in main.
I'll do anything with it.
You guys have to forget that there is.
Who is the owner of something? Me.
Okay.
So will you guys push it in something?
No, he is the owner.
You will not be pushing him.
There was a feature one
members.
So where the person is, he is
the owner of that particular branch.
Once you guys have finished
working on your feature,
what you are going to do,
you are going to open up a pool request
that I do know
how to put a pool request right?
And you are going to assign it to
your team. Need
your team is going to do your phone
request.
He's going to check your code.
And once
he thinks that the code is correct
and he thinks that,
okay, this is fine to merge,
then tenure is going to be the person
who will merge it
to submit
and wild merging.
What's the best can do it
best and most all and you know
do the merging together.
How about you didn't understand the code
you can do that too which is going to make
you know life is easy.
So similarly the person who is working on
feature of
is going to open up
will request once he's done
for the team weekly just for like
everyone is going to put to request
and no one
no one is going to actually push to submit
after
pushing feature one,
then we do a pull request
tomorrow.
Let's talk about it.
Okay guys, so is this workflow here?
Great.
Now, once
your whole project has been compiled
over the period of time in sub main,
because no.
All of you
people have worked on the feature.
It's working
fine and it's always in the sub.
So there is one combat project
available in sub.
Then once you have that you do the team,
it is going to open up a pool request
and he's going to assign it and
then I'll be reviewing your code.
I will have to look upon it
if I find it to be correct.
If I find that everything is fine,
only then I'll be merging it with the mean
as I will not be merging with any
option.
Okay,
so let's go to the key points
that I've written.
Let's go through them quickly
so that make sure everyone
has all the info written in the notes
also, which may help you throughout.
So to that you need to among yourself.
We have already done that.
The task of easy.
This is the first step
that you will be doing
longer wrap on create a blog suddenly
now there are some tips
now said there are some tips
after uploading and making a separate
some branch.
Make sure to add some comments
in the course so that you are
to make a commit in the segment. Right
and push it to get up.
So at this point,
the team will be able to create
this sub main on the guitar.
So this is just so
that whenever anyone has done working,
he can open up a pull request
for something.
Okay, now
the task of the team member team.
But before moving on to that is this one
Okay, so these are
the task which will be performed
by team members and also the team.
So now what you are going to do
over there are things
that people were able
whosoever replica become part
owner that outside of that the owner apply
make your separate branches
to on your particular feature.
So now what you will be doing
all of you will be cloning the wrap will
and will be creating your own
particular branches to work on
look features.
Okay, now there are some tips.
Make sure that you do
create your own separate branch
before you switch to the branch.
Make sure you commit everything
on that particular branch.
Because remember,
if you accidentally switch the branch
without committing,
it's going to mess up the repository.
Okay, so before you switch,
make sure you comment
on that particular branch.
We can push everything all into your own
branch on the remote wrap.
That is important.
Just make sure that you will not receive
anything to submit on me.
That is again going to mess up everything.
I'm sorry I have to be done many times.
Does no matter what,
still someone will push to me.
I'm sure the height
of the most file
once you are done working on the part.
Well, one of two requests
to merge across to somebody.
Make sure to open up
all requests for that.
Do not do it directly
the not merge it that
the make sure that you open up
a pool request and assigned to your team.
The and please make sure that team is
you are the only one
who are merging the code.
Not anyone else knew.
The pool question merged after testing
to resolve the conflicts that there are.
And so you know how to resolve conflicts,
right?
You know how to best do good.
So make sure you are using
that knowledge to do
this.
Okay.
So we have already done
the examples of the projects
of such example, which are a similar
to what you will be doing in your project.
So this is someone
it was exactly almost the same,
and I tried to cover all the scenarios
that you guys may be facing.
So I'm really hopeful
that you will not be facing those problems
while doing the project.
And one last thing
is the women into combat.
So sometimes what happens
is that when you are on the log,
you are unable
to accept your common outcome or do right.
So in order to accept that,
you have to type file on Q or WG.
So this is something that I witnessed
a lot of people were facing.
I mentioned it before also,
but I think you guys forgot.
So I have written it over here,
but now you are terminal,
you are unable to exit the command,
just type in, you are WQ
also if accidentally some of them
and it opens up,
then there is something on your console
where it opens up a new window for you
in which there are comments on the top.
No, I exit that.
What you need to do is
you need to press escape
after pressing escape need to type
com WQ or Q So I'm going to show you.
Let me see if I can open up the women
over here.
Okay, so this is your limit.
In order to insert something or here,
what you can do is I can write something,
you can simply press on and,
start typing.
Well, well,
this is not something that we have.
This this I'm just mentioning it to guys
because you may have faced this problem
while you are working.
You may face this limit.
So I'm just giving you a heads up
how to deal with it.
Don't be confused.
Why is not anything working?
This is something related to Linux
and you guys need a few of you.
We have to deal with it.
Okay. So
typing whatever you want to
press ASCII and then column WQ.
You guys see this column you are proposing
to skip down at the bottom.
So this is to save the 5%.
So WrestleMania
file away you
women understanding the cookie.
Okay,
so this is how you can exist by writing
column Q column WQ It will exit your file
whenever it's open
so that will be it
just not something that much important
or you will be facing.
But I think that it must be mentioned
so when
okay, let's it, it
so this is everything.
I think
what you will be doing about cloning.
So regarding the cloning stuff,
these repositories are private,
they are not public.
So only those people who have access to
it will be able to view them.
So I have invited
you guys as collaborators,
and I think this is right.
This is future testers.
I have invited you guys.
Some has accepted and why
and this is what is desired.
And he has invited to invite Zamani.
So you guys are to go to
your email address
related to your GitHub account,
find an email over there.
It be asking you at subject.
You accept that particular invite
and then you will be able to collaborate
and work on this.
A group so
this people can use
assume that you okay casino have you
again followed which party
likely would be?
There's only one thing.
Yeah there's only one.
Do I mostly
I haven't sent you
that needed in white yet
so you guys
may not have the invitation yet
because your username
I still have to enter them.
So I'll just do it real quick
after the class and all that.
Right.
Just to make sure one thing
it's 854 to 10.
All of you are added
in the requisite photos.
Okay.
Because after that I want you guys
to start working on the project together.
And most really I would to be able to go.
I would
after
that, I will be available in the morning.
So till the time you guys have done,
send me your user names.
If someone doesn't have them,
you already have them in the file folder.
This would you have.
We don't have an email.
Yes, you do that because I have not
yet sent you.
Let me show it to you.
So this is the sheet
that you guys have right?
So I hope that all of you have entered
your credit username, but so some of you
there are two appearing.
So I just selected one randomly,
just let me know
if you guys I'm not at it.
And there was one group
I was having a look at that
I ask needed.
Okay, so eight
teams are going to be here next week.
So I was just sending you of Blessed.
Okay, so
once you guys have successfully
you know accepted and what you are going
to call it, you know how to go to do that.
Right.
And after that you are simply going
to branch your own job and start working.
So, yeah, questions Amanda
and whoever else has questions,
let me know
You can use them to automate all
information to good.
How whether it is going to take you
much, much time then
you know really plan.
How are we supposed to work on common
methods of others, pages, etc..
Okay. So
I believe that common methods is going
to be divided between you guys, right?
You will share that. Okay.
How some someone can develop
a few of the following methods
that a person can
upon matters relating to the tasks
run around pages.
You guys can decide that who is going
to be working on the low class aspects.
You guys also divide them among yourself.
But is your question related to the manner
that how you working on
that and GitHub?
Okay.
So this is something which
we need to discuss
and I was hoping that it's
okay.
So someone
I had asked a very good question,
she said that
how are we supposed to work on our
common methods and pages?
This is something that we will all be
needing right?
So popular
methods is something that all of you
will be
okay.
Now, there can be multiple approaches
to this
method, this problem.
You guys can have multiple approaches,
but I'm going to just give you one.
Good. You guys, me, follow me.
Not all of you.
So let's say that this is our main branch.
And in here,
this is the first time
I get synchronized
with me to this problem.
Okay, so now what?
What can happen is that, let's say
then it's all come to that.
Just let me answer this question first.
Let's say that this is the something that
and yet
none of you are right about it,
that this is the users.
And they'd be like,
Would you do it immediately?
But there might be a scenario
where one created
dependent on the other,
there might be scenario
where you need to have longer things
and your friend has already done it.
So you want to not copy, you know,
do not want to make spend some time
on that one.
Instead,
you want to have it on a computer.
So having that right,
I sure let me have that too.
But first, let's let's discuss that.
Okay. Yeah.
You can create the framework plus.
Okay, so now what's going to happen?
Let's say this is the branch created by
Aisha and I
be It's a branch out of me.
And let's say that one more branch
was created
by Dennis,
and this was started working on their
common methods.
So they started working on
common methods
and they made it over there
and then they got comfortable with it.
Now this common matter
on which I still work contains
some methods and also the Dennis one.
It also contains some method,
but they are not the same.
They are different.
It contains methods for,
let's see, opening up
browser tools in the browser screenshot.
It contains method for
sending text and something like that.
So to this point I'm a good
okay, now what you're going to do is
you guys can
either choose to open up
a pull request
for this particular Common Methods branch.
You can name this branch as common
methods of the methods by ISO.
Let's
and similarly
this Common methods by Dennis
so you guys can open up a pull request
to merge it to sub me
and then
your teammate is going to
resolve the conflicts
and add the code over here
for both the files.
So you guys know that in the attic
there will be a file common it,
which is going to have the code
of common methods
in which I just go to
and then it's called both are present
right?
So now let's see, there is a third user
who has not worked on common methods.
Let's say you use the system under system
and have done work on common methods.
You guys decided in a meeting that
the methodology working on common methods
but some are not,
but do need common methods right?
You need the common methods.
So what?
What them are not enough.
The man that is going to first see that
if there is an opinion Main Yes there is.
He is going to well,
he's going to
pull the sub main, the updated one.
And after pulling the updated sub
main going to check out
I'm new branch from here.
So now what you have here
will be having the common methods
available tomorrow.
So this is one of the rules
that you guys can follow.
And other books guarantee
that while you guys are, you know,
having this for you guys can decide
that you need to work on framework for us.
And once you have developed the framework,
then you guys will be working further.
So you can either have this team
that you can
have framework in your some in right
or just giving you the idea.
What you can also do is
you can have a separate
named framework,
you can have a separate branch
named framework, and all of you
are working on the framework, all the fine
members are working on the framework
and they all are pushing the branch.
Their branch is opening of the request.
From there, let's say
I shall have worked on the framework
that is are open to work on the framework.
And what they are doing is
now they are opening of the quest
to merge into framework.
So then what will happen when all of you
have done working on the framework,
you will be having
a branch named framework
which will have
the whole framework in there.
And then
as soon as you
guys are going to work on the user story,
you can simply have this branch
in the local branch up from over there.
I started working on that particular desk
is what I wanted to do.
So this is the one of another approach
that you guys can use.
Well, it's not about the purpose.
Is that what the matter?
Methods are correct.
There's nothing wrong with them
of whatever find most suitable.
Whatever you find more intelligent,
you get you guys to follow that.
That's the reason I showed you.
But it's your choice.
You are working with the team.
Whatever helps
you collaborate more intellectually,
just use that one method.
So I'm
as this clear to everyone the this and
I use the workflow that will be followed.
Okay, great.
So now make sure of one thing is just
using the second word.
If we want to do something cool,
starting with like features.
Okay?
So that is a thing that using the,
the point that we discussed over here
should he should remind the framework
to submit
before we started working the features.
Well there is that both expands upon you.
Even if you do it won't hurt it.
Even if you don't, you can do it later on.
Right?
So that doesn't that doesn't matter.
It's fine.
Even if you decide to do it later on.
Okay.
So regarding this GitHub stuff,
that is, just make sure
that you are very vigilant
about the rules that you have discussed.
Okay Just do not
try to make as much intended
commit as can use the
as a platform to communicate
because when you work
this is you will be using it
a lot to use that
to communicate among each other issues
help each other out.
We have discussed, I guess, all the
scenarios that you can help each other. So
just do that and
if you guys need any help
regarding any topic or any of us stuff,
get up.
Just make sure to reach out to me on Slack
and a support tag team.
I will be there to help you out
so not be having any problems
and how you understand.
Do it in can right along with Alex.
Do you mean to say that how I understand
whether you did it the right
only?
Well, I have your GitHub repository.
I can see that. Right.
So I will be reviewing
your pushes the branches and everything.
How know whether you do it better
right or not.
And I can also you go out on your project,
just run it so
I wouldn't do it. So
I'm doing all the
repository right
this representative belongs to and
let that this is my project
really check all the users.
So my main focus is not going to be
your industry of mostly focusing
on your GitHub execution and overall
performance of your user stories.
They are also going by civil law. So
but I will be checking
the performance of your code.
I can sit through it and see that
whether your test cases are running
smoothly or not
yet Anonymous and right.
And I want all of you
set up and start working on the project.
So once again,
I'm going to ask a few questions.
I really want you guys to reply to me
so that I know all of this,
so that after joining the repository,
after getting the invite,
what's the duty of the team?
After getting meanwhile,
what's the duty of the team
launched it
and create a summary branch
in order to create a something right.
What you have to do
is remember
he has to add some comments in the code
so that able to make a comment
into something in branch
and push it to get up.
Okay.
This is important.
If he does not make any comments
or anything, he will not be able
to make the comment
that is the meeting.
Okay.
So is that clear that he will be making
some comments, comments
like you can simply open up the project
and write down testing
and, you know, just make a comment
and let them know.
Okay, So once the submit is there,
what are the rest of the group members
and the team, a member team is going to do
code repositories
and branch out your own branches.
Okay. Is it possible that you out for me?
I know.
Remember
I told you guys that the submarine and me
are going to have the same code right?
They are going to have the same code
so you can either branch out
from some men
or it will not make a difference.
Okay, Just
don't confuse about it.
You can add in Roger from sub made
on me.
The purpose of submit
is that you guys will be opening up
your request to merge the code in there.
Okay. Yes.
So let's say in the start
you are behind in
any framework, right
in the starting like me, having
you guys will not be having anything.
So you guys can graduate from anywhere
and start working on the framework.
But once you guys have some thing
in your some then you need to
do. Okay.
So apart from that push your will get up
in your own particular branches
that do not push to anyone else.
Max Just make sure of that
and open up the pull request.
Assign it
routinely to merge into something.
Unless the project is done,
then it is going to
open up the request and decided Can you
share
completely close to me
the rest of the stuff.
I got one question over here.
Is it possible for you to do it on the sub
lunch?
No, it's not possible for you to go.
The surprise member
You guys can only the only members.
Okay, let me do it for you guys, because
I think that there's going to be a lot of
the guys want me to show you a demo.
I think I can show you. I know.
What about that?
Oh, okay. Here.
So let's see.
I'm going to create a new repository and
name it.
Good project.
So, Jimi, I'm just walking it through,
so just give me a moment
and I'm going to give you
a practical example of how
you have to proceed a bit.
That's my good that
I'm going to
send everything to this particular piece
so that I can build a small demo for you.
I'll get the items
on the move.
What to remove.
So give me more. I'm
okay.
Let's.
Okay, guys.
So now I'm going to show you a practical
I hope that it's going to create
more sense to have.
So these are the repository that we have
right now.
What you will be like, Do want to go
look here?
Okay.
Are you guys with me?
Okay, so I'm going to first pretend to be
a team and I'll show you what the task.
Okay.
So first of all, I'm
making a folder named Team.
We from all the task and action
the team meetings to do.
So I'm going to open up the notes
and also tell you
how I'm going to follow them
and create a branch.
So this is simple.
I'll simply open up my get back here
and use get clone
and the URL.
Okay,
so it clone the representative for me.
I'll go to there
now check it, get status.
Okay guys, so as you
can you tell me right now which launch
am our
I'm on my end right
and what's my task.
My task is to the honorable which I have
and I have to create a brand subnets.
Okay so for that I do get
branch
subnets
and then get check out subnet
to two.
Now I'm in the branch subnet right.
Okay. Now I need to push it to GitHub.
So what should I do.
Get add dot and it come in.
But first
let me show you that I do get abnormal
and get comment dash and
that's a new comment.
It's not making the comment because
I have not made any changes in the file.
Right.
So I have to add something in the in here.
So let's see, I just open up my project
and the inside of test.
I see
testing
Now can I add it.
Come commit that
let's call it
the sub main is ready
and now I need to push it.
But first that you origin sub me.
Okay, so now everything is
pushed into my sub.
The task of the team is done.
The main branch is did the sub minutes do
stuff?
Open up my notes.
This particular stuff is done.
Make a committed submarine
branch and push together.
We are good with that.
Any questions still here?
Awesome. Great.
So now let's follow
the next step.
The thing you need.
I'm going to place it aside
and I'm not going to
put a ten to be team member,
so this is my team member.
I'd love to get that here
and I set it long
enough to that.
I'm going to place the link
of the graphical
and I'm going to go inside
to represent free of the hero air.
Okay, So I want you to just tell me
that by default,
which branch do I have?
I only have the mean. Right.
All right.
We discussed this in detail
that whenever never put the branch
with a repository only downloads for us.
The main books.
Okay.
So now if I want to have my
some branch
also on my system, what should I do
now? Jimmy, remember I told
you guys that with the branch is
we cannot do get call.
Remember?
But we want a new branch.
We cannot do it Pool.
What's the what's the matter
to have a branch on to look for?
Did we discuss that, guys
To have the a local.
So first of all, get branch dash
E it is going to show you
which out there on your remote right
now let's say
you want to have this particular submarine
branch, then you are going
to simply download it on your local
using the command,
get checked out
suddenly.
Okay.
It just revealed that for you.
That's so that your monthly runs
you're
going to
it's just to view the number of branches
out of there.
For example, a new branch has been added.
Let's feature right
And you want to see that
or maybe you do not know
the exact spellings of submarine,
so you can do it without branch
stacking also.
But it's good to first see that
which is the price you want to say to.
Okay, so let me have these commands
in the notes.
Officer. So that's going to help you
giving Branch that same
view.
The branches
that are clear on remote
and it branch check out
branch name
to download
a particular branch
from the GitHub
list.
If I did share with all of you
those commands and I'll would that when
I think I should teach you
to do all of you.
Yes I did.
I showed them again
the course announcement.
Okay. So
whenever you need to have
whatever you need,
whenever you close the report,
it will only download
the main branch
to have other branches.
Use that for us.
Okay guys, tonight
I that you guys will not forget.
Now. Okay, I'm
going to answer the question.
Just I Aisha and Dennis,
just ask me on what I have gone for it.
Okay, guys,
so let's let's proceed further.
Now, I told you guys
you have the choice to either
check out from somebody
or either check out from me, right?
I Just taught you
how to have go talk to him.
Even if you want to check on some submit
now you can
even if you want to check up for me,
you can absolutely depends upon you guys.
So tell me that from which approach
you want to see.
Do you want me to show you
how to check out from, submit or make?
Okay, so
we will be doing some
this one
we learn how to clone the main branch
and then download to submit.
Right?
So you have that right.
And now if I put up my terminal,
I'm in submit branch.
So if I create a new branch over here,
this means that I will be out
from some made into a new runs.
Okay, so let's create a branch over here
and let's see
that branch.
Let's name it
framework by modifying
that check out
framework by person
whose values are not correct.
Okay, So
if I show you
the file
file there. Right.
The testing
is there because we checked out from sub
means.
Okay.
Now what I do is I start
adding the framework stuff in here.
So let's see
the python, the tree is there. And
let me quickly add the framework.
So let's say I added a new file
with the framework.
That's
if there are few functions out there
for the framework.
Okay, so I'm done
with writing down the framework.
So what do I have to do next
in this branch? What should I do?
Let's assume that I'm working
on my framework and a log was done.
Yes, I have to first added
and come. I do
my part of framework
is done.
But so it
if I show you on GitHub, oh,
what did I do.
Oh I know.
Get pushed that to origin
framework
myself.
Now then now if I show you guys
I have this framework
over here that's like working.
Now let's say that.
Meanwhile, I was working on the framework.
I was also working on the framework.
No, not, not the pull request right now.
Let's discuss it in detail.
Let's set other
person what's working.
I want your concepts to be really clear.
Let's say it wasn't
worked for by a framework, but
I sure that's okay.
So in this scenario,
what's going to happen?
It's going to be a new form or
limitation.
Okay, look,
I shall be working on the project.
So he is going to have
also this particular proposal
is this making sense
to all the future, this one.
Okay.
So I need to get the correct you'll
get screwed on I'm pretending to be now
I shot I'm
going to show you first I showed you
how I was going to work on the project.
Now show you how I finished working.
So get see, get wrap up.
Excuse in there.
No, I learned it from the project demo.
So this was a mistake.
It did not work. Okay.
Okay, Now
I said it there.
Right.
So you have this smart does it
and you only thing to be.
So now let's do this.
Let's have job.
Yeah. Yeah.
Branch
Dashti
And then
she will go to the subject branch of you
because she also wants to work
on the frameworks and right now
she does not know what
the framework model is, complete or not
you will start with your own frameworks
that she'll say, get checked out
some of it.
So now she checked out in some me
and over here she'll start working.
No, sorry.
Not from here. He'll be at home.
I get branch
framework,
but I sure
she'll decide to check out
framework, but I should know she is.
I'm not go into the project and
let's say she also created a file
framework
and she added some code in there.
She's
Did we have the same name
for the framework or
let's check the name of the file
we had in framework
framework.
Okay. Correct.
No, let's assume that he has done
working on the framework.
What she's going to do now
is get at DOT
if comment that I show
the of framework
I'm supposed to work on is done
in the name
two classes and what no idea
if you have ninja classes
differently, how
are you supposed to merge them together?
It's going to be higher than it will not
be able to know that it's the same file.
It's going to be a different file, right?
So you have to name your files.
The should be same so that I'm just
giving you the idea of how to proceed.
It's very important
that before you begin the project,
you all sit down in the meeting you
you have your brainstorming session
in which you decide the task
that each will be doing.
This is really important.
It's not about just,
you know, the technical needs.
Rather it's more about your team's
operation, how to work in a team.
So it's going to be very important
for you guys to sit down in a meeting
and decide for yourself, How are you going
to propose diverse little bit?
You can also make changes, not necessarily
follow the exact same things
I have told you.
You know the concepts, how it works,
you know how all these matters work.
You know how this concept meets
the workflow is
you should be able to come up
with your own workflows.
Also, just the conditions
that you have to not push in
is not to make a framework in
one branch that is well, again,
I'm saying this is your own choice.
You have to decide.
I'm just
telling you guys that this is
one of the tools that I think, well,
if you guys how to do this,
you have to in a meeting, decide
that, okay,
we have one framework branch in which
all the framework is going to be there
and then it's going to merge in some way.
So that's all you
what's your intelligence, how you think?
So this is your decision.
So yes, similar Brussels difference.
Yes. So now let's make Isaac,
which are good.
So he's going to get pushed you origin
framework by Aisha.
So I'm just telling you
one of the good guys, okay, remember that
one of the rules, but it's also there.
Now let's assume
that the framework is complete.
That was it for the framework.
The framework is complete.
So one of the project can we
you know,
followed by this particular process is
that I was unaware of all the previous.
And I do know that
this is our is
as you guys move forward,
everything comes together in the end.
You guys have a better understanding.
So that's how the whole course laws and
okay so one of the approaches
that we can have a separate branch
in which we can combine
the whole framework and then you know,
push towards that or what we can do it,
we are sure that our framework is correct.
We can just simply,
you know, merge it to somebody.
So let's
go ahead with merging this to something.
So for that, what we will do,
we'll pull up the request,
create the request.
Okay.
So me no,
no one is going to pull it for me.
Remember that
submit and then framework.
My wasn't
this is going to be
in the bonus last mentioned name
they would
to functions and framework
create a pool of rest.
Okay so you are not going to see that
like this will not be shown to you
or even if it is
do not have the multiple requests.
Okay.
This is only
one team need to do.
You do not have to do this.
The team members are not going to do this.
Please make sure of this.
If you are not synchronized on this one,
you guys are going to have
a lot of problem.
Please, you should do synchronize.
Only the team leaders will do that.
Then the other pool request
is going to be open and it's going to be
for our framework language
and create the pool
request.
Okay.
Now the team is going to go to the pool
request,
have a creation of the same pool
across the board.
Oh, my mistake.
So I need to open
this first out.
So this date
flows the pool request.
This madam want is blue request.
So I have closed it
and now the favor by Mazloum.
Yeah, this is done.
And the other one is
should be the for the Asian one.
Right.
I created the same for what
I? Need to open up the pool request
for access framework.
And this is going to let this
be a pool request.
Yeah. Suddenly. Sorry.
Look, I'm also making mistakes
last. So.
Yeah.
When you guys go make the save,
when you're working with the questions
about her.
Well, very honestly, like
you guys can, but
just make sure that don't.
I do not have an instructor telling me
not to do this, But you have an instructor
telling you on the Internet
you can try to do this right?
And I'm in a hurry.
So the team is going to open up
this framework by Amazon
and he's going to say,
I've been let's have a look at the files
of this posting.
And he has added this function that he's
going to draw to the conversation.
Let me go to the same request
and confirm
this.
So because of that critical purpose,
you have merged it.
And now the second one,
we are going to merge it to.
Okay.
So now let's go to our project
and let's have a look at our plan
with fixed.
Yeah,
the problem is that I have merged to me so
okay that
so the problem,
the mistake that outselling me not to do
so I merged one of the my
the more than one in the main box
which should not have been done
and I need to know and move it forward
here I can simply move it.
It's not going to be a problem for me,
but I time you guys don't
need it from the top.
I'll tell you how.
So let's open up.
Pool request for the branch wasn't a game.
Okay, So it's going to be something
and it's going to be similar by myself.
Right
now it's telling me
that can automatically merge it.
Does that make sense to all of you
that why is it showing that?
Because I showed me
word on the same one on the same file.
So on the same file that that's
why it's saying that it's not going to,
you know, merge automatically
to create the flow request.
Okay.
A result of the conflicts,
what you guys are going to see
the control that have been added by.
So you guys can keep it and the function
that were provided by me
I can keep them too.
And after that you are given losses
that resolve commitments
and it's going to
be there in your subnet. So
my request as formats.
So let to show you on the diagram
what you did as we was
trained by Muslim and then you similar
I sure but not was
a three way merge
this this this one merge is called
which was
f f right.
The first one will f
and this is what now
is it going to be f?
No, this is recursive now.
So we have we were having a conflict
to resolve the conflict guys
who is on conflict
to resolve that.
Right.
I was I really
I said that okay here is the conflict
and I was in a meeting with,
you know I showed awesome
facial, huh?
On our hiding.
Yes. Okay.
Now let's proceed further
and let's see that this is something
that the framework is done.
Now we all have the framework.
And now what we want to do
is we want to work
on our user stories, right?
Everyone wants to do that.
So I'm going to
let's say I want to work on
I want to work on this user.
So what she's going to do now,
what should be the steps
I want you guys to tell me
and then I'll show you.
This is one step on out.
Not going to way.
Okay.
So I should have this
repository.
All right.
He has this repository, but
he needs to have the whole framework.
But he needs to have the whole framework
in which the Muslim contributed
and he also contributed.
So where is that line
that is in subdomain, Right?
So what he's he's going to do,
he's going to check out to submit.
So she is now in, submit and all let's see
the sub that we have
are in submit
templates and now off to be in the sub me.
She's going to do such.
So there is something in least
something that needs to be submit.
Cool.
Now she is going to open up her framework.
This is part of file this move so
let's
let's look at folder.
She just wants
I shall I show
let me first
show you the file in the action
so I show the project
demo associate task Java framework.
So now I should have common methods
updated
in which the Muslim contributed
and she also contributed.
She has that tools framework right
so at this point
the stuff main
which I still have is updated.
Right.
And now if you want to work on her
new user story, what she's going to do,
she's going to check out from
the point where she has
the framework available
and she's going to name
it, let's say
user story.
What let's say that.
And for that she's going to open up
terminal.
You get check out user
story. First.
Last question is to create a path
user story
one, then give
user story one of you.
Now if you do the story line,
she has the access to all the common
methods and she can simply proceed
on working with her user story.
Having the I want just using everything
how to
then you must demand
and know that were most of these
okay guys so is this now clear to everyone
that's how you are supposed
to work on the framework
and how you are supposed to work
in collaboration?
I really hope that now you got to not
be having any kind of problems.
You know how to call the code,
push the code and stuff like that.
You know how to update a particular
branch, you know how to download it.
And, you know,
I would think one last thing
that I want to share with you
that's going to be
if you get to work right
now, I'll just be sending
you what?
Okay, guys. So
here are
the gift slides that we have
that are a little bit complex like,
but we have all have all the things
that I have taught you already, But
I don't really like this structure, but
I hope that they are going to help you.
The contains all the information
that we have already discussed.
You know, it's
going to be a little bit more
detailed. So
I'm going to share these slides with to
on the canvas.
We have some screenshots we got in GitHub
also that
how can you work GitHub
and stuff like that on the terminal?
If you guys have a problem,
just make sure that you visit
these slides and
and where you need to review
every concept.
You can just, you know, for example,
if you forgot
how to open up a full request, just go to
the political section over there.
You'll see
how to open up a new tool.
First.
But there might be one thing
that the interface has updated
the got in GitHub, so you may need to find
those buttons like.
There may be some up and down
and there are
some slides are much less conflict.
So I'm going to share this.
All of you do have them and
see how I can help you out on the canvas.
Dennis I'm going to share it
with you guys on canvas.
Well, yeah,
everything that we have studied in detail,
letting out what we have to discuss,
nothing is going to give them.
Oh, you guys are the same with,
you know, it's
all we shared it with you on canvas.
The slides and after that, I'm going
to quickly send all of you the invites.
Just make sure that
if you do not get an invite within
15 minutes, just let me know
in the student support center,
because after that
I will not be available for the whole date
if any group member of yours is left out
because I'll be having the morning.
Okay, So I'm going to add everyone
in 15 minutes.
Okay?
Please have you telling me my name.
Do you have time to do that?
We do that after sending you what
I think, Christine or no, all you need.
So let's do it after.
I send the invite. So it's 915.
Let's do it at 1015.
Yeah.
So finally, in addition, in your emails,
what you guys out and the session now
you chat on these supports
and I.
Okay Christine Perfect.