All right, guys.
Can you guys see me?
Thank you. Thank you.
I hope you guys can hear me.
I probably won't be able to speak
too loud.
Thank you.
Thank you, guys. Loud and clear.
That's good for you. It's good.
Okay, I'm getting better.
I'm not.
I'm not 100% yet, guys, But
get in there.
So just have some leftovers
from the COVID now.
So I get the, uh, out of breath easily.
So if I'll be coughing to them. I'm sorry.
All right?
But I'm very, very,
very happy to see today.
You guys.
Yes, I'm happy to be back myself, Guys.
Yeah. Cool.
It is not a it's not a fun thing.
And I don't wish anybody to get it.
So is make sure you guys be careful.
All right, guys.
How how did things been going with you?
Tell me how the classes are going.
It's been great.
It's good.
You guys been having fun. All
right.
I guess I'm I'm I'm happy to hear.
I hope you guys learn a lot.
Okay?
Okay.
Yeah.
All right. I guess. Yeah, I should.
I should be fine.
Teachers been.
Meanwhile, guys, five days a week.
Yeah, well, Toys Day
and you guys are going to study
almost every day
to prepare yourself for the market.
And that's good.
That I'm very,
very glad that you guys had fun.
And hopefully
you guys get a lot of practice, right?
So now you guys have a homework,
homework to do also.
And there will be more
and more stuff will be coming right?
So what are we going to do?
Oh, I think I think that's not me moving.
The camera thing is
you guys can shove this screen.
All right.
Yeah, I'll I'll fix my camera a little bit
later, too, because once I start,
maybe after after the break,
I'll try to fix it better.
Okay.
But what we will try to do,
guys, let's do a quick recap
on the things that you learned
on the last class.
What did you guys learn last class.
Okay. So you guys were
looking into the typecasting,
functional, nonfunctional
test and you guys were probably looking
in the manual testing with Diego.
Right. Okay.
What can you guys
tell me about the testing
thing?
Less class, you guys you don't typecast in
in the if condition right.
So what
what did you guys learn about casting.
So there is in general
we have two type of casting right
so there is a one we have implicit casting
or the other one
we have explicit casting, right?
But when we talk about casting,
what we say casting casting is converting
one data type
into another data type, right?
Okay.
So when we talk about the implicit
casting guys,
can you give me
an example of the implicit casting?
Implicit right.
Something happens implicitly.
It means something that happens
automatically, right?
In which cases
we can convert something automatically
when we have something small
converting to a bigger type.
Right?
Doing widening when we have something
something in the small box, it's easy
to transfer to the bigger box, right?
So let's say three months, right?
So when we talk about widening, right,
widening or it's an automatic right.
So when we will take an integer, right.
So for example,
if I'll take an integer, which is ten.
Right.
And I'm going to try to store it
inside the bigger type.
Right.
And then if I'm going to do it and around
that screen line, right,
if I'm going to try to print
D, what will be my output? This
will be 10.0, right?
So what do we do?
We took a smaller type
and then we place it inside
a bigger box and that things happen
automatically, right?
So that is so here.
Not no problem.
Right in Y meaning it's actually very,
very popular guys
and widening will be used a lot
once you guys start learning more
about the classes in the objects
at that moment, you guys will experience
more process of the one in
just in this one in me
looking into the primitives right because
right now we do focus on primitives.
So we're looking into the primitive
casting and in about,
I don't know, classes, number 15 or 20,
you guys will start doing the casted
or non primitives
of this process with me.
So it happens automatically.
Right. And Mary Right.
Give me example.
Look, I've been there and this
what is the
purpose of the type question You will look
into the purpose of the typecast, right?
So the type question when it comes
to primitive, it will be beneficial,
especially when we have to work
with a lot of
our automatic operations. Right?
You guys saw that, for example.
Right. Well, what was the issue?
Whenever we were
taking the integers, right?
When we were taking integers and tried
to perform the arithmetic operations.
Right.
So here what will be
your output is what will be
the output.
Three. Right.
So here will be the output of three,
Right.
So here we are
losing that reminder, right?
So now whenever we'll be working,
right, whenever we'll be working with the
with those operations,
especially if it comes to the division.
Right.
It's always,
always best approach to use double right.
So there will be conversion
that we will have to do right in.
There's a mentioned more popular you guys
will see a lot of a lot of benefits
when it will be coming to the non
primitive casting think so
when when we talk about the nearing right
nearing or something
that happens explicitly right so narrowing
narrowing is when you try
to put something big into the smaller box.
Right.
So now this process doesn't happen
automatically Y
because there's a potential loss
of the information, right?
Potential loss of the information.
So now Java doesn't want to take
the responsibility right here.
Whenever you work, it means the data
are not going to be responsible
if you lose some data. Right.
So but if you still would like to perform
the narrowing, if you would still
try to perform the explicit crossing,
please take your responsibility and do it.
You're all right.
So and therein is going from the bigger
time to the smaller type, right?
So if you're going to take an integer
right by equals, Right.
So how am I going
to do the conversion? This
right.
So to whichever type
I want to convert, right to whichever type
I want to find here and here, for example,
if I'll vote and then.
Right.
So then what I'm going to try
to bring my eye right?
So this way when I'm going to put my own
so what I'm going to get,
what will be my output this, that right.
So what happened in this conversion?
Right. We cut out in the change.
We don't need to do 99
since we just keep in ten.
Right. Potential loss of the information.
Okay.
So while this process won't be very very
not very useful to our special automation
engine, using this,
we are not not going to use it.
However,
the same thing is a widening this.
Once we start learning about objects
in the classes,
then they are
and will play some role in that process.
But when it comes to the very primitive,
it's a very, very rare use concept.
Even developers
don't really use it, but it is there.
It is big
where you there's no right one in Mary.
Okay, okay.
I guess in last class
you'll start learning about the, uh.
It's stable, right?
What can you guys tell me about the
if statement
decision making?
Right. Okay.
It's one of the conditional statements
when we going to talk about the
if statement.
Right.
It will run as certain commands based on
when we
when we made the condition right
at first.
Right now we do guys
learn a lot of just printing.
Right.
But eventually there will be
some operation that we will prefer right.
For example the real life example,
when we go to the one,
we will start the automation.
So to do that, what is automation?
We will be automating browsers
because we will be running, executing
our code either on Chrome browser
or we can execute our code,
for example, in Safari browser,
or we can execute it on Firefox, right?
So what we will do,
hey, if the browser is equal to Chrome,
then our code will perform
execution on the composer.
If our browser will be equal to safari,
then our test will be executed
on this safari. Right.
So based on the condition
there's shown in action will be performed.
Right?
So now when we talk
about the eve statement of statement
is one of the conditional statement.
Conditional statement.
Conditional statement
based on the condition.
Right. Based on the condition
certain action will be performed.
Right.
And the very first one,
there's a two of them right.
If you guys look at the slides,
there's two of them.
Right.
Conditional statement. Right.
So there's a two types that we have.
The first one that we start looking,
we start looking into the eve statement.
And the second one, once
we learn all the things for these people,
we will start looking into the switch.
The right here we have each statement,
we have a switch statement,
right this statement.
So now you guys start looking, you guys
start looking of the eve statement, right?
And there's a different variations
of the eve statement that we have.
Right.
So when we look at the variation
on the eve statement, right.
We can have a simple eve block.
We can have just simple Eve.
And here
we always have a Boolean condition, right?
Condition. And we say, hey,
if the condition in which case
I will execute this code that's in
which is invalid, let's decode eight,
in which case my code will get executed
only normally right?
Only am only
when my boolean condition is true.
Right only and only
when my bowling condition is right.
So this is your symbol
if statement. Right?
This is your simple state.
So let's take a look an example. Right?
So you guys will tell me.
So for example, right.
Today's Saturday, right?
So let me take a variable
Boolean day.
Let's say
window one.
It's actually
okay, let's look me the integer.
You just
started it, right? The number six.
So now when you say, Hey Eve, there
is equals two, right?
In Bayes equals
50, we're going to see that out.
Today is Saturday right?
Day is
right.
All right.
So first of all, this
do I have any issues in my code
right now?
Okay.
So what's the difference
between one equal and double
equal
one equals sign?
We are talking about this
assigning right in double equals sign.
We talking about check in their equality.
Right.
So here, if you're going to keep only one
equal sign
and you have a will complete
Java will complain why?
Because for the eve statement, Java always
always looks for the boolean expression.
Right?
So now
all day is equals to six.
Right.
Okay, so tell me this in my line
25 is going to get executed.
Yes or no?
When to get it, you get it right. Why?
Because a certain condition
is true, right?
So now if I'm going to change it to seven,
am I going to see the output?
No. Right. So now what are we doing?
Our if statement is
a conditional statement
with the help of the statement
we are doing is select execution.
Right.
So all only know if condition is true,
then the story will execute.
Otherwise it won't execute. Right.
Then you said, Hey, if statement
right
if statement can have else flow right,
it can happen otherwise blah right.
They'll say hey is this is condition
is to execute this could otherwise
right
otherwise execute this right otherwise
let me ask you this
is the ls block
is it must or it's an optional
block.
It's very optional, right.
If we want to provide otherwise condition,
then we'll go for a else.
If they don't want to provide
that otherwise condition,
we don't have to specify.
Right?
We don't have to specify
in the other variation.
Right. You guys, last last time.
Look, what is the other variation of your
if statement?
What can we have This
the other variation.
Right. What do we can, huh?
We can have right.
We can have it work, right.
We can have this as having ls
we can have ls eve.
And for reals it's the same thing.
We will specify
some boolean condition right.
And then here
we can have the ls part right.
And here or
right.
We will go in here. Right.
So in here we're testing.
Hey, there is a different ways, right?
We are providing differential condition.
Hey, what if this could be true?
Or this could be true or something
else could be true, right?
Otherwise, if none of the condition
are true, then go look for that else.
BLOCK Right.
So how many blocks can we have this?
We can have as many as we need, right?
As many as we require, right?
Based on the based on the action.
Right. Based on the action.
For example, you guys did an example when
you have to compare two numbers, right?
So what is that?
How many how many options we have
when we have to compare
two numbers, two or three
or unlimited, when you have to define,
well, what do you have
when you compare it to numbers? Right.
So first you check number
one can be larger than number two, right?
Then number two
can be larger than the number one.
Or if none of the conditions is true,
then numbers are equal, right?
The numbers are equal.
So we will check for two true condition.
And if none of the conditions will be
match, we will go for that otherwise.
Right. So here is a three options.
We are needed, but do we have more
or can we have more?
Right.
When you get zero example with days,
how many days are there?
There's a seven days. Are they right?
So then it means you can have
seven times you can provide your else
if else if condition y
because seven times
you can have a true condition right.
And did you guys have any questions
for your
homework. It
was good, right?
I think it was good. Or was that easy?
So you guys also I saw
you guys were sharing it in your channel,
which is pretty,
pretty good. Oh, that's good, right?
So what was your condition in here, guys?
To check whether the number is positive
or negative?
What was the condition?
If it's greater than zero
or less than zero?
Right.
Then the number was positive and negative.
And what was the condition in here?
You guys use your modulus
operator, write modulus operator.
Hey, if I'm going to divide in number
using the numbers equal
to divisible by two without any reminder
that the number is even
if not, this is right.
And the last thing I want to see right.
Did you guys do
try to
write your if statement
without the braces?
Did you guys look at that option.
Okay.
So let's do a quick recap and here
we'll do class four right.
The samples
and the lab test
so that.
Okay.
And I'm sure by now
you guys are on the shortcuts, right?
You guys knowing the shortcuts
for your print statement.
And did you guys learn this shortcut
for the main method?
Yes. No. No. Yes. All right. Right.
So there's something that we call our
to complete this.
Okay, So there's our complete. Right.
So what is our complete? Our complete.
This is something that is going
to complete your
statement.
Write something
that is going to complete your statement.
So we will be using the letter
of the our completes later out to
complete.
Right.
So the way you guys did your print out,
right, what you did,
you did this all and then you did
the control plus space, right.
Central request space.
So when you do control space,
your space out was our completed write it.
Fill up your print statement.
So the same thing for the main method.
Right.
For example now if you forgot your main
method instead of the type in it fool
what you guys can do, you can just type me
and then do the same thing.
Control less space, right?
So control space types.
You worry, we'll do it.
Will our complete your main statement?
I do mean and then control space
and it gives you a suggestion.
I think. Use your suggestion.
You'll just hit enter and if our completes
now you would know how to bring your main
page and the floor
you will have to hit enter.
All right.
And there's the same for Mac users
and for Windows users.
Okay, So this is the things that you guys
were looking at, right?
Let me copy from here
my statements right
away.
Like all
the simple statement,
hey, that is equals to six.
Then we all execute
this block of code, right?
So now you guys will see that
with the help of the curly braces
we are then define the block of code.
BLOCK of code that belongs to your
if condition
block of code that belongs to my main
method.
BLOCK of code that belongs to my class.
Right.
So here.
Hey whenever condition is true, right?
So now I'm opening the block of code.
If the condition will be true,
if I'm going to get a green line,
then I'm able to enter this block of code.
Right?
And then we have the other,
which means we can have the other one
and let's do the same.
So today is inside right?
And then based on the condition. Right.
Based on the condition,
one statement will be executed.
Right.
Because the condition is true.
Of course, the code from the from
the block gets executed
whenever the condition will be false.
The code from the else
block is going to get executed.
Right.
Mine didn't work.
Or what exactly did not work for
the are complete
or the shortcut.
So let me just quickly get it out
then I'll bring it back, guys.
So you'll just that main
and then the potential space
and it should are a complete right
let me ask you guys is you'll side works
where I am and who are marked
if you
if you start out or completes then also
okay if you guys some of you who are not
able are complete and most likely you guys
using Mac systems.
Right.
So there's a
you have to change your settings.
There is a preferences.
Myriam,
you have Windows, then it should work.
This does usually happen
only when you guys have Mac it.
Yeah. Try it again, ma'am. Try it again.
Just do this or main
and then control space
and just keep center, keep.
So let me see this if I'm going to add
more statement in years.
So let's say we are having
we are having
Java.
What I have in general
and let me change it to sex right.
So how many print statements am I going
to see goes how many print statements
from which line from which line
you wanted and line in length, Right.
Line ten and line 11. Why?
Because whenever the condition becomes
true, right?
Whenever the condition becomes true,
and once you enter the block.
Right.
Once we enter in the eve block,
all the statements,
all the statements inside that you block
will be executed up to the bottom.
They will be executed.
But when only and only
when that condition is true, right?
When the condition is warped.
So now this.
Your currently braces identifies
the block, right?
It identifies that these two statements
belong to you if block Right.
So some sometimes somewhere maybe
what you guys saw
you guys or something like that.
Let me do another exact the same example
what without the curly braces
I saw the same thing.
I'll say if they right
equals equals to six,
then I'm just going to.
Oops, sorry, let me see this.
I will remove this box.
Right.
So now when we look into my code, right
When you look into my code,
Joe is fine, right?
Joe is fine. So it's not complaining.
So it means my syntax is correct
right now.
I can either have my curly braces
or I don't have to have.
Now let's see what will be the issue.
This let me just put
I'll use only one statement.
I'll use only one print out statement.
Today is Saturday, right?
Then we more
or more interested in this part.
So now when we look into it, right.
What what, what is it?
Gives me the right output.
Right?
Hey, if these equals two six,
it tells me it's bound to be.
And here I'll have a second statement,
but I will add a layer again.
Here it's execute.
No problem.
No problem. It executes.
But where the issue will come this
Now if I'm going to remove my comment
and now in here, I want to say,
hey, there's a two statements
belong to my eve block and here
I want to say that also two statements
belong to my eve block.
So now
maybe now you know what?
Okay, well, now it looks the same way.
Now it looks the same, right?
Okay.
Here it shows me today's Saturday
and we are having Java clause here.
It's also says to the Saturday
we are having the Java class.
No difference. Right.
But there's actually differences.
So let me change it to seven
and we can move to seven days.
So now let me ask you guys
if this equals to seven, which output
should I see?
I should see the else, right.
I should see the export.
And there's no way there's no way
I should see this line
or there is no way I should see this line.
Right.
I will add the statement in here,
but I want you to look at the output.
So now when I'm going to run in here,
when I'm going to run in here.
So this statement, because
I have curly braces in here, right?
I am.
You find that these lines belong to the
if statement.
These lines
belong to the statement in here.
Even if I'm going to,
I'm going to add else.
But what happens
this statement is getting executed
as in I think that I added for if part
but what happens this
what happens without your braces.
Without the braces, if statement
can able to execute
only one line, only one line.
So now if I'm going to format my code
right, if I'm going to format my code.
So now where I don't have a is
my Java things, okay,
they don't have the braces.
This statement belongs to the eve block.
However, this statement
does not belong to the eve block.
So if you
if there is a two or more statements,
you have to specify inside
if what you always,
always have to make sure you have,
you currently braces this.
If you're not going to have
a curly braces, you might start
having some issues in your code.
Let me add the else part in here goes
of the year.
Right?
And now it's of course
is going to complain to me for a l'espoir
because it takes time.
That's what it stands for.
Okay, let me know.
This is
one moment.
All right?
Not once.
Let me underline this statement in here,
because it's used
all the way.
And let me add one more statement. Yes.
I want to add this line
that I want to be outside of my
if statement right system that out.
All I want to say in of course and
of course what
let me
now let's let's do it again this right
so these seven condition will be false.
One condition is false.
I cannot go inside my eve statement
where I will end that I'm going,
I will end that I'm going to my else block
right inside my work.
I have two statements, right?
So this statement will execute
and this statement will indicate, right.
Why? Because I have my curly braces in
When it comes of
having Eve without the curly braces,
what happens?
Your Java is not going to complain
of your syntax.
Syntax.
It means your if statement is allowed
to be without the currently braces.
But when you don't have a curly braces,
your your java will assume
or this statement belongs to the eve.
This statement belongs to the else.
This statement is not belong
to the else blog.
This statement will be treated as
a regular code without the curly braces.
Java is able to read only one
line of code, only one layer of statement.
It will think, okay,
this belongs to the eve.
This will belong to the.
That's right.
So now let's take a look at this. Right.
So today's day seven.
I should have this output
and I should, of course,
is going to treat it as a11 moment. This
full brain
function.
Let me do six now again.
Let me do six.
Let me leave this statement
because I want to show you this.
Let me it's up to me. Right.
So this number six. Right.
I will see this output and nothing else
right now when I'm going to execute,
this is what we're going to see.
This.
So these number six condition was true.
One condition was true.
I was given the green light. Right.
I executed the line number
ten and my LS blog are ignored.
Right.
Then we have in
this line that comes from the line
17 and then the next eve statement, right?
It says, Hey, if these equals to sixth
condition is true,
I'm executing this statement now.
I thought. I thought that this two lines
belongs to the last block,
but that's what I thought.
But Java can read only one statement
that will belong to the else.
Or if so, now you're always executed
today, Saturday.
But then it thought that this belongs
to the else float.
If block
and it
showed
that this line belongs to the last block
and that this line
does not belong to any block of code.
It told that it belongs
to the entire main method.
And that's why what happened
it did executed this line.
Right? They did execute in itself.
So this is what happens.
That's when we don't have a script.
So that's why I always, always say, guys,
most most preferable way,
regardless of how many statements
you will put inside where they will
could one statement or two statements
always, always use curly braces right.
So this way
you are not going to get confused
and this way you are not going to have
any logical issues or logical errors
in your code because when you look
and do syntax wise, it looks fine, right?
Syntax wise you look fine.
But when you execute,
you will start wondering, Hey,
why this code got executed?
Because I thought
it belongs to the ls Black.
Not that's what you're told by Java
because you did not specify the curly
braces.
Now, Java told that only this statement
belongs to the LS black
as it makes sense.
Based. Is
there any other use in the done basis?
I you just so where are you?
Guys will see some ties when you guys
are given assignments, right?
Maybe that's what you guys are going
to see later after you guys graduated.
Then you start going on the market, right?
Sometimes you guys will be
given some assignments to do so.
This way you don't get confused.
Okay.
Why did they give me the code
that don't have any braces?
These there is a possibility.
Yes, there's a possibility
that you can have it.
But we always, always,
always preferred to use curly braces.
So this way you easily can see
where your block of foot starts
and where you block of good.
It's just
you just
not you just have to finish your
all your statements
and what happens does you again
when you try to format your code, right.
When you go and try to format your code,
you guys see when you formatted your code,
you add Java tells you, okay, you know
what, this is belongs to the board
and this is it already treated
as a part
that should belong outside of that your
if okay, when it was printed
in 1922 it
no they are printed
Catalina
Yes that's, that's what I'm explaining.
Right.
So because you did not specify
your curly braces,
that's why Java code that this statement
Java two that this statement
does not belong to the eve block
it it treats this statement
as an independent. Yep.
All in all,
if you go into adding curly braces,
then your code will be written properly.
Right? Then. Then then your java,
your java.
Read the code properly.
Otherwise it treats only this statement
that belongs to the elsewhere
and they treated us.
Only this statement belongs to the
if BLOCK okay. Yep.
So no matter,
you can have ten lines of code, right?
Let me do another example.
You know who
we would say?
For example, let's take a variable, right?
Blue marble
underneath and we will say, yes,
it is sunny right now.
You want to say,
here is it's sunny, right?
If it's sunny, no.
And for example,
you forgot to add your curly braces.
What you want to add multiple statements
is only weather, right?
So let me add three statements.
All I will go
or look
here.
Let's it all right
so I enjoyed
right.
So if you want to have a breezy Sprite,
if you to have a braces,
if you want to have them right
when the condition is true those are three
statements will get executed
when the condition will be false.
How many of our quotes
say are you going to see this?
How many outputs
if the condition
is false?
Zero zero. Why?
Because condition was false.
Entire block got ignored right by well,
what happens if you go to reboot?
If you're going to remove
your curly braces,
what's going to happen to statements
will get executed.
Why Java thing is okay,
this statement belongs to the eve.
This statement don't belong to the right.
So because this was false, now
I'm ignoring this block
because it belongs to the eve.
But there is.
I'm exactly right. There is something.
So now you can have ten lines of code
inside
by Java will treat it only only one.
Okay, I hope that makes sense.
And when I was going to try
to out of format
you could right whenever you want to do
come on shift or control shift F
your ID will help you to format
and this way you can like will see.
Okay, this is where your e block starts.
This is where it ends.
And this is outside, right?
That's why I always tell you guys, always,
always try to format your code.
All right.
So that's
if you going to have it with no braces.
But once again, this is 99%,
99% of the time
we are going to write our curly braces.
If you don't put the best condition
or. Yeah,
as of now, we don't have the l support.
These statements will be treated
as independent statements
outside of the
you block or outside of the cuts.
Right.
That's how
it is.
All right, guys, Any questions?
Any questions
or. I hope it's good.
I hope it's good.
Okay.
So today that was the recap
a little bit longer recap, right.
So but today, the topic is mostly
it will be a lot of a lot of practice.
So what we will do today, guys,
we will look into the nested E right.
But make sure you guys I hope you guys
all clear with the E Right.
That's all clear is that if statements you
know the variations of the state right.
So now there's another thing
that a week and a half in Java.
Nicole something nested.
E What is nested?
Eagle What then this E
Right.
So if statement it's
Eve inside another eve, right?
It's Eve inside the eve.
And as you guys saw, the variation of the
eve statement can be different, right?
We can have Eve, we can have Eve else
we can have Eve else Eve.
Right.
So are we talking about
any of this variation?
Can half inside another eve state.
Right.
So first
we will look into very simple, right.
So within what is in this book,
if ness that eve
when we have eve condition right
blooming condition in here
and now inside this
if we are going to have another eve
block of current year will be
when we can have some coding here right.
Right.
So what is nest
that eve nest of Eve is Eve
that we use inside another Eve.
Right.
So this Eve we call that this is our
our eve
eve and we all it isn't our either.
The okay
so first
the way it works, right,
the way works once
you have your condition, right?
So once you have your condition. Right.
And we know
when do I enter my eve statement?
I enter my eve statement only.
Only when condition becomes true.
When condition becomes true,
I am able to enter this block of code
that starts from here,
and it ends all the way in here right now.
Once the condition is true,
I am allowed to enter this block of code.
So now when I enter this block of court,
I see this line,
I see this line and this line. Right.
So first I will execute this code.
But as soon as I enter inside
what I'm seen, I'm
seeing another Eve statement, Right?
And we know how our statement executed our
if statement is executed
based on the true condition.
Based on the true condition.
Right.
So for now, all we said,
guys, that our nest that if it's
eve inside another if right
so now in which case
would you want to place in new inside
another eve
usually right.
Usually When do we go for nesting,
When do we go for nesting.
So for example,
let's think of the realized
scenario realized in that right
so nest that if
works it's like a check boxes.
Our first condition have to be pass
before you going to get a chance
for a second condition
or That's right when you go for a doctor
right when you go for a doctor
in doctor will ask you hey,
do you have any medication?
Right. Do you take any medication?
Now you have to answer Yes.
Right.
If you answer yes, only
then I'm going to do the further check.
Only then I'm going to ask.
Okay.
Tell me,
what kind of medication do you take?
But let me ask you guys,
am I going to ask you
if you're taking any medication,
if you want to answer to me, no.
No, you're not. Right. So what happened?
Our first checkpoint needed to be passed,
right?
Do you take any medication?
Yes, I do take any medication.
Okay. Now condition becomes true.
Now, let me take our duty.
Do you take any allergy medication right.
Or do you take any other things? Only.
And the only one?
My first checkpoint pass.
Then I'm going to ask. Right.
For example, if I'm going to ask, hey,
did you guys have COVID?
Right?
So now, for example, I'm going to say yes
and only in if I'm going to say yes, then
you guys will ask Me okay, how was it?
Right.
But if I'm going to tell, you know,
I never heard a cataclysmic
you guys not going to ask me
any further questions.
So what happens?
My first checkpoint has to be passed.
And only and only then I'm going
to check a second checkpoint.
Right? It's like first checkpoint pass.
If the first pass, then
I'm going to check the second one.
And can I have multiple checkpoints?
Of course
we can have multiple checkpoints, Right.
So like I'm an example
this how are we going to have a class
like you name it?
Is this the right to be?
Instead, if
you see me
again,
for example, let's talk about I don't know
this Daisy this days, right.
Very, very hot topic.
Give example this class, for example.
Right.
Let's talk about the
I don't know, vaccine.
Right.
So now I'm going to ask you, hey,
do you guys have a vaccine?
Right. And this is just an example.
There's I'm not I'm not asking you
whether you have it.
That's your personal choice, right?
So now if you go going, you tell me, Yes,
I have my vaccine.
Now, I'm going to ask,
did you get a second dose?
Do you have both doses right.
And then based on that, I make a decision.
But if you're going to tell me
that you did not take a vaccine,
I'm not going to ask you
how many doses you take.
Right.
So only normally or I'm going to ask
what kind they go.
Right.
That's actually like what option.
Let's pick out two variables, right.
So let me take a Boolean vaccine.
Right?
Boom. Next. Right.
And for example,
let's let's put a true well look into
different, different options.
Right? So Boolean mixing true.
And I don't know,
let's say a dose, for example, integer
dose equals
2 to 1 dose, for example, right?
Yes. An example. Right, Right.
All right.
So the way we're going to have so firstly,
once you have E, right.
So now I'm going to say, hey,
if you have a Z, right,
if you have a like stain, right.
All you only if you have a vaccine
only then I can ask you.
So how many,
how many do this?
Obviously only people, right.
For example. Right.
So now
looking at this simple, right, am I going
to see the output of the line 13?
Yes or no? This
Yes. Y
Because the condition is true, right?
Because the condition is true.
So now y line 13, they're executing
now all we know only one.
My condition is true.
Now I can take another condition, right?
If those equals two
equals two one, for example. Right.
If those equals one,
then everyone intercedes is all I.
Or when are you taking your second grade.
Something like that.
What are you taking your
place. Right.
Something like this. Right.
So now what do we have?
We have Eve inside another IEF, Right.
So what do we did?
We took one if statement and nested inside
another statement.
Right.
So now this is statement,
the one that is outside we call it
It's our eve.
And this eve statement we call it
It's our nested eve, right?
Which means when we do, we want to nest
when you want to
do this further check all we know
only if our first check point has volume
only if our first condition will be true.
Only then I'm going to do the
for the chip.
Right.
So now let's
let's analyze it.
Okay. Right.
So I always code
inside the main method executes
that put the bottom until it c
any for now it sees if statement right.
Hey is the condition is true.
Yes condition is true.
When the condition truth
given a green light,
I can enter my e block
telling me guys
where my where my are in block
ns Can you guys tell me
it starts in here, right?
This is my opening.
Curly brace is where it ends.
On which line?
17 or 19. My R is 19.
That's where it starts, right?
You guys see even the alignment,
it starts from here.
It ends in here. Right?
So now when my first check
point pass enter an inside.
So now am I insecure in line 13 days?
Am I executing line 13?
Yes, I am executing.
I am executing my line 13 y
because I got my green line.
Now I'm seeing the line that there's
no condition, I'm just going to print it.
Then your code goes up to the bottom.
Now what it sees,
it sees another if statement, right?
When I see if statement, okay.
In order for me to go inside,
I have to check the condition.
What?
When I was able to go inside.
All in only because my first two point
has passed right now.
Check.
Hey, if those equals two, one
is the condition for this
condition is true.
That same thing.
Now my condition has passed.
I'm able to enter my list of E
that starts from here and ends in me.
So in this case,
what I'm going to get, I'm going to get
how many those is how you take in
when you take in your second.
Now let me change it to false this.
Well, what will be the
output on my program?
Why no execution? My notes.
I specified those equals to one.
This is true. Y y y y.
There is no output
it will skip.
Right.
So now
this is condition is being nested.
It's being nested inside.
This is statement before
before I can check this condition.
First I have to verify this condition.
Right? First I have to verify.
So now in this case, condition is false.
One condition is false.
I'm given the red light.
I cannot enter this block of code.
So it means I cannot enter a block of code
that starts from here.
It ends in here.
So this entire statement will be ignored.
Right?
So they go ahead and this is the right
this is the right conclusion.
Your nested if guys units that if always
always has a dependency on you are if
you're in there if
will get a chance for two for execution
only if the are if condition will be true.
If the other condition is false
you're either
eve will never ever be executed.
Right.
So this small if the one that we nested
always always depend on our piece.
Well, all right.
So right now I'm going to have false
no execution at all.
Right. Okay.
Now let's let's do what I like to do.
Different variations,
because here we will have to
let me have two.
So how many outputs am I going to see?
One, Which line is
30? Right.
So, hey, if is the condition is true.
Yes, condition is true. Condition
it's true.
I am allowed to go inside the eve block.
My our eve starts from here
and it ends in here.
Right.
So as soon as I enter my eve
block, I'm seeing this C
So do I have any condition to execute?
This is out? No.
Okay, I'm just going to execute it Now.
Your Java runs into the another eve.
Oh, now the nested. Okay, cool.
Now when your Java sees if statement,
it's always have to check the condition.
Hey is that those equals two one note.
Those equals two two.
All right then.
I did not get a green light.
So this statement
will be ignored is even more
general.
This is our just our variation, right
e e inside
another x can win this, if else.
Yes, we can. Right.
There is a three variation
that you guys saw of the eve statement.
You can have just simple eve block
you statement can have Eve ls blank.
Your Eve statement can have Eve
ls Eve Lux right.
Can I have another ls requires
looking of another bills.
Okay.
So if if does equals to one,
where are you taking your second dose?
Otherwise.
Otherwise we'll just say
you are fully vaccinated. This
your only looks
and you see.
Okay. Alexander, can you.
Can you please do fix your alignment
and your both conditions are true.
That's why you see in two outputs. Yep.
You Alexander,
you both condition up? Sure. Okay.
All right.
Let me ask you guys in this situation,
which lines are
my going to see is an output?
I added one more statement.
Yes, I added my LS part as well.
30 minutes right there. Terminated.
Hey, it's the vaccine condition is true.
I can go inside, right?
Always. Always.
Pay attention, guys, Where you are.
It starts.
It starts from here.
It ends all the way in here.
And because we are using it, these guys
just put your one under the after
the currently basis and just double with
you will tell you entire block of split.
So this way you see
what belongs to the are is this way
you will see what belongs to the inner
right
So in this case, this condition is true.
So line 13 will get executed.
This condition will be false.
So we know when the condition is false,
we will go to the else work.
Right.
But how many have you taken?
You go.
There was two.
You are fully right.
It's And if I'm taking it to false right.
How many equals this
you are fully vaccinated.
Will will my else blunder executed. Why?
Why them?
Why My block is not getting executed This
let me try to run.
There's no output.
It's not printing anything
or printing anything. Why?
Because this ls block.
Guys, this ls BLOCK is part of this.
If right.
They appear in the where they leave.
They leave inside this if statement.
Because our if condition was what?
Because our condition was false.
Everything that ignore
everything are involved.
So don't get confused.
This part belongs to to the in there.
If this sport does not belong to the
if you like, the more examples
that are false,
you will see right in which cases
we will go for
this foot
in which we will go for our nesting
for example.
Right.
So, so we have an example, right?
For example we have an example.
So we will take two variables.
If we will take two variables, right,
we will take two variables.
So I'll have a they right and we can be
integers, they are nothing
I want to say Friday.
Let's take a string.
String
Li equals two press
right, right.
For example. Right.
In examples,
we want to check if it's Friday, right?
We want to check it's Friday.
If it's Friday,
then we're going to go for movies, right?
For example, every Friday.
You guys going for movies, right?
Hey, if it's Friday, I'll go for movies.
If it's not Friday, I'm going for movies.
Right?
So then what do you want to to
look you want to look into a date,
for example, Right?
You want to say, okay, today's Friday.
And you know what?
If today is a Friday 13,
if today is Friday 13th,
then you watch a scary movie.
Otherwise you'll watch,
I don't know, James Bond movie, right.
Something like this.
So now let me ask you this.
What will be your R condition?
What I will be your R
If you want to check the data,
you want to check the date first?
We will check the day. Right.
So first, I want to decide
whether I'm going to the movie
or whether I am not going to the movie.
Right. I don't care about the date.
Then they can be 13, 21st,
whatever the date is.
But my most important thing
Friday is the only day of
when you guys have right
sense from syntax.
Are you like, okay, if it's Friday,
I'll go for a movie, right?
Okay.
So then we will do say, Hey Eve,
how do we compare to strings?
This thing I've got to show you, right?
You guys did an example.
So if they if they write, if they now
when we have two strings gets right,
what do we have?
Strings we try not to use to equal sign
we not going,
oh, will you give me a syntax.
Why and I'm not going to have any errors.
Good syntax
is not going to give me any errors,
but a best, best way
to compare to strings
always, always use equals.
Once you guys
are going to have
a you guys going to have two classes
where you guys will be happy,
where you guys will be learning strings.
Okay?
So and in those days,
you guys will understand why we do
go the equals type in
instead of equals
using the two equals sign.
Yeah.
So never say, hey,
if the day is equals your Friday, right.
Then we will say I'm going for a movie.
See them once
I'm going to the movies to the right.
You only have otherwise by me. I
we cannot it right we cannot exist.
That's fine for you.
Interesting.
Oh I'm like
I'm going to say I'm going to study.
Okay.
I hope you guys doing all right.
So for now, what are we seeing?
We just in simple if statement, right.
If statement that consists of two blocks.
It consists of the
if block only consists of the else block.
Right.
So we have in this condition, guys,
which line will get executed
in pool? Why?
Because condition
will give me a true right.
They variable.
They hold the value of Friday.
Hey is the Friday equals to Friday.
Yes, condition is true.
So your line 28 will get executed.
Right? Line 28.
And then you also black will be ignored.
BLOCK loading. Go. Right.
So I'm going to the movies today.
Now what I have, I a condition.
Condition
that depends on the date right now
I'm saying, hey, if the day is Friday,
because it's my movie day.
You know what?
Let me check the date.
It's Halloween time.
And no, this let me see that.
They will be 13.
I'll watch a scary movie. Right?
So now what I want to do,
I want to add another if statement.
Right.
So now what I would like to do,
I would like to list
why I want to do this
because I had a dependable condition.
Right?
Only it because it's Friday
now I will check a date.
Right.
So now what will do inside this
if statement?
I'm going to throw another if statement.
Right.
Hey, all know
only because the condition was true.
Just make sure this
27 Why didn't you this
I use be it when they are here I said
I said D right here I have they.
So what we work is the variables.
We work with the values
that we have placed inside.
Right before I had this variable
and I added this value.
Now what I'm referring to is variable.
I see. Yeah.
Because I have a day.
What is the value in here?
In order for me
to compare something to something,
I have to have two values, right?
Yeah.
I cannot just say if they right.
Why I cannot see why I can.
Let's say if they guess which.
So remember guess the way the f works.
Exactly. Why.
Because that they exist.
Strings the way if works,
I must get a boolean condition.
Right?
I must get a boolean condition
if I can have a they if I can have a date.
It's not a valid condition like always.
Always inside the if still if statement.
There has to make a statement
that will give me a boolean.
So that's why.
And see now what I'm going to do.
I'm going to compare to values.
Hey, if the value inside the variable box,
inside the variable date inside
this box is equal to what is equal.
So you ready equals to
right.
So this equals to Friday only.
Only if this condition will be true,
then this things that will check right
now. So yeah, I'm going to the movie
now because I decided I'm
going to the movie now.
I have another condition I'm going to do.
I went to let's see if they is equal.
Right. We check in now again.
Right again, I'm not saying.
Okay. So sorry.
Not the right date right now.
What? I'm you. Why?
I'm using equality upgraded to come up
with the bulling condition.
Right.
I cannot say equal because it will be
in this time in operation.
I have to give a value. Right.
I'm going to say here,
if the is equal to 13, then
all I am
watching is is
moving right.
Well, we can leave it for now like that.
Okay. This
tell me the output
we just looking into this program,
what will be the output?
How many I will have written once this out
to see out three yourselves
How many statements am I going to see
is an output right now
when I'm going to execute my program,
which lines
I'm going to see?
29. Definitely I'm going to see 29. Why?
Because
they already is equals to Friday.
Condition is true.
I'm going inside that block. Right.
And then inside eve blocks
This out is just there, right?
There's no condition
to execute my line 29.
So I'm just going to print it.
But then your code goes down
and it's sees line 32.
You know what?
Line 32, the place to be inside at East.
So before I execute line 32,
I have to check the condition right
now, Hey, is the date
this equals to 13 years.
This is equal to 13.
Condition is true immediately.
Right.
So this way you're going to see 29 and 32.
What will happen to the line? 38
And what why is it getting ignored?
Why is it getting ignored?
Because you're Eve, right?
Because this Eve was still
when the if is true, else is getting
ignored.
Right?
Else is getting
you guys.
I'm keeping an example.
I will just try to change the values
right now
already.
What will be the output this
what what
what happens with this gear movie?
My date is 13.
What happens is watching a scary movie
days. Why?
Why is it get it?
Why is it getting ignored?
Because it's not Friday. Right.
But the right.
So this is your Eve statement.
This is your last part, right?
So, hey, is the day equals two Friday?
No day is equals to Saturday.
Write days as equals to Saturday.
So it means I cannot enter these F block.
It means in three
you block is get an oops is get in.
What is getting ignored is getting ignored
and because we have the otherwise part.
So now our code will go to the light duty
right?
I'm keeping
the cadets. I'm just changing the
different values.
So the difference between equals in
so one equals sign, right?
One equals sign.
It's an assignment operator. Right.
One equal sign is an assignment.
Operator Two equals sign, right?
Do equals sign.
For example, let me let me take another
variable integer
D equals two.
I need also 30, right?
So now I can say
they equal equal equal
to D, right.
So if I'm saying they equal equal to D,
what am I doing in here?
This what am I doing?
I am comparing, right?
So I'm comparing a one value
to another one.
So I'm saying he is the date
which is 32 equals to 13.
Is it true or false?
Are they equal or no.
Okay, we'll go.
Right.
So this will give me one bullet, right.
This will give me one bullet. Right.
And it will give me condition right.
But if I'm going to say
they equals to D right, they equals to D
then what I'm doing taking the value of D
and assigning it to the variable date.
Right.
Reassigning it. Yep.
That's what. Exactly, Exactly. It
is. Two
how to know ls if a sign to Well this.
That's why guys do so now
which ls belong to the
if so my suggestion as always.
Always When I'll give you
we will do couple more examples this
and then they'll give you a test and then
you actually will be doing lot of tasks.
So whenever you're doing this,
always, always try to write your first
if statement.
Don't go into the next thing.
Identify
first what you have as an R if statement
and whether you're going
to have the block,
whether you're not going to have the LS.
But once you identify you are eve
only then go into the next right
only then go into then this.
So here.
Yep. And if you guys have any
issues in the code, please
post it in the support channel.
Right.
So here we're talking.
Hey, if the day is Friday, right in the
this Friday you said you go into the movie
otherwise you're going to study, right.
This ls belongs to this E for now.
Give me give me your email
If you're in there, you have it ls part
can you either blog has a cameo in there
if statement has the ls blockers,
you can have it right.
So the only thing is always always
be careful when you will be early.
If these equals 13,
this is where you nest.
You've starts.
If you want to add the ls block to it,
it has to start in here.
Right?
We can add those
in. Let's say it's all
brim or
change.
Okay. This
Okay. So now what?
We did
this if statement that consists
of the eve block and of the LS what I did.
I nested it. I nested it inside.
We're inside my if block right there
always double click it.
It will show you where if block starts
and where it ends, right.
It always will show you that
this LS part two, which is statement in
this ls you want to do this right?
Okay, so we'll just play these the values.
We'll just place the values, right?
So let's do 14.
So what will be the
what will be the output? This
again, Right?
So just going to the right.
So first Friday is the these Friday.
Yes. Condition is true.
Automatically automatic.
When this condition is true
you'll go inside that you have block
so your else block will be ignored right
away.
38 is not getting executed right now
once you enter your block.
This is where it starts.
This is where it ends. Right.
So he lives
should go top to the bottom right now.
What you see you see the line 39.
Am I executing it? Yes, I'm executed.
Then going down while executing
your Java sees this keyword.
Right.
So remember that those key words
have a specific meaning for Java, right?
As soon as a Java is if it knows.
Okay, they put the condition.
Now when I see the condition,
I have to check it first.
Right?
I cannot just go right away
inside the put condition
only if it passed
then I will be able to enter.
Right.
Hey, date is equals to 13.
Condition is true or false.
Right?
Condition And this statement is false.
So I am given a red light.
So it means my eve block I am ignoring.
So when when my eve block is ignoring
Eve, I have the block.
I'll go inside the block
and this code will be executed.
Right?
Else will be print.
Right.
So my suggestion
this API when you doing then this
and if right because now guys you're
the one who can check
if you were raped in your code
correct or no how by providing
different different outputs.
So you guys right now will be able
to test your own code in
how do you test your own court
by providing different values
to those variables.
I always, always say,
okay, now you have if ls
and you have nested,
if always check, always check.
Hey, how can I get the condition?
How can I get the ls?
My my
I want to see that my ls block works?
What should I change this?
I want to check that this ls block works.
What should I change?
Tell me this. I will change my variable
to it to watch on to what?
I need to change it.
I can change it to any other day. Right?
Let me change it to Thursday.
Right.
So now when you change it to Thursday,
you check.
Okay. My ls block works.
My ls block works good.
Now let me check my block.
In order for that to work,
I have to change it for Friday.
Right.
And then you have to think right.
Then your logic should be okay.
I want my eve block to be executed.
If I want my eve block to be executed.
What I need to change.
I need to change it to the 30.
So you guys see, by providing you
provide different value than Friday,
you will check that your LS block
have the right condition.
By changing it back to Friday,
you will check that
your eve block
is working to check your nested condition.
You'll just do
variations of the 13 and 14.
So now by providing this three
for different
values,
you are able to test your own code.
You're able to test your own logic, right?
Oh, right,
right, right.
Okay, good.
So I'm going to leave the code
and let's take a break, guys.
We'll take a break and then after break,
we'll do one more example
where we will try to nest a bigger
if statement.
And then after you guys will go,
going to have a lot
a lot of exercise to get to the.
So there will be a lot of practice.
So why did I use
equals?
So for now those
I cannot go too much into details.
But Gerald, whenever you have strings,
always, always, always.
What is the variable day
Variable base of which type?
It's of the string type, right.
So any time we compare string, it's
always best choice to use equals
never go for double equals sign.
When comparing to strings, walk
for the double equals
sign when you want to compare
numeric values.
Okay, what?
Once you guys
start learning strings,
you guys will learn
that there is a different ways
how this strings up form.
Okay.
Behind this scene this and many different
operations are happening.
And once we start
learning about the strings, once
we start learning about something
that call
immutability and immutability, then
you guys will get a very clear picture.
Why use it?
Typing equals It's always, always
best choice. Yep.
So think of it
for when compare is in, right? Yep.
We can type it
with some theory right compared.
We will say two or more values.
Right?
So if your values are numeric, right.
If your values are numeric
use double equals.
If values are string values
used, that equals
No, it's not the same.
It's not the same, but equals will be used
only only for strings.
You cannot use equals when you going
to try to compare to numeric values.
Right.
That's
why we have there's a different data times
we have because with different data types
we can perform different actions, right?
So you guys learn with numeric values
when you go in to use the plus
sign, you will be performing
arithmetic operations
when you go into
is a plus sign with the strings.
You guys are doing concatenation right?
So the same thing. Why in here, right?
All in.
Only when you have numbers
used to two or to equal signs
when you use the string use that equals.
But on the class
13 or 14,
you guys will see in details why?
I'm not saying it's not going to work this
in some cases
using double equals sign
when compared to strings.
It will work,
but in some cases it won't work.
Right?
So once you know the difference, then
you guys will use your own best judgment
when to use it.
But before that, you need to know why.
For now,
just always, always use equal sign.
So this way you are not going
get any logical errors, right?
Syntax will be correct.
Syntax you in Java will be perfectly fine.
But logically this
sometimes might get some mistake.
So let's take a break guys.
It's 1134.
Let's take
in most
the mistake make is
an easy.
I'm sorry,
I did not understand your question
or two all day or exercises.
Exercises? No.
We will do one more example that cost this
that if I want to make sure you get it
and then you'll do, you'll do them.
And then we look into the scanner
and then we will combine
all the things with the scanner.
And then this that if
you guys are
going to have I'm giving you examples
what I wanted to say,
you know, and they'll try to deposit
as the only thing.
Well, after I time guys, I do go over.
I did not change anything in the code.
I just tried play this different balance
right to develop your logic stronger.
But for now, guys, let's take a break.
I'll leave your this screen in here
and yeah, of
course.
All right.
So let's come back in
a few minutes time.
You guys have issues in the code.
Please make sure you post in the support
channel
so Sheila can capture it right away.
All right?
Okay. Yes. Right.
So what are we are learning, right.
We are learning about the
conditional statement, right, Eve?
Right.
Whenever in our code we would like to
specify condition we are using if they.
Right.
There's
a different variations of each statement
we can have we can have our
if statement can consist of just only
if what it can consist of
if else block or we can of
if else if blocks
and now what we learning what we can do
we can nest if condition
and inside another if condition.
Right.
So and as there's
a many different variations
of the eve statement,
we can either in just simple eve
we can either in
as that if else statement or we can end
next the
entire eve else eve block right.
So another thing is about nesting, right?
But nest and we can do
we can nest eve statement
inside either one of the blocks.
We can either nested inside eve block
or it can be either
nested inside that else block
depend on the logic, depend on our
access.
Right.
And what we say about the
nested it right.
So in which case we would like to go what
we would like to do the further check
right when we know
that we receive one information.
But now we want to check
another information.
Right that in there eve information always
always have a dependency on the
our information, right. Yes.
So and it is as we look here witness
that inside just eve block right here
we had our eve else block
But nested inside of if right.
Let's look at one more example and
then you guys will be doing your tasks.
You have either else
here we have Eve inside in here.
Yes, we can add it, right?
For example, let's say
right, let's think of the condition
where we can have the condition
if they it's Friday.
Otherwise, if it's not Friday.
Right.
Do you want can you can
you add another condition?
Yes, we can add another condition,
for example.
Right.
If the day is not Friday,
let's say come up with some condition,
what do you guys want to do?
Throw it.
The day is not Friday.
What do you want to check
If the day is not Friday?
I don't know. Let's check the time.
That's fine.
Let's check the time.
Right. Let's enter the time.
I don't know, Integer
Just does maybe will be silly example.
Right. And
yeah, but that's right.
Or we can we can check if a date. Yep.
We can do. That's fine.
That's fine.
We can add another eve. Right.
So here we are defining.
Hey, if the day is Friday,
then you go into the movie.
Otherwise we are studying.
Let's just try. Now there are others.
So maybe the time that's fine.
But it can be.
You think, for example, right now
it's 12:00 or something like that.
Right now just is an example, right?
Maybe one logically make any sense.
But just to just to show you. Right.
Just to show you, for example,
we can say, hey, Eve thought.
Right.
If it's not Friday, right,
it means it can be any other day.
So now maybe, guys, Monday through Friday,
you guys work in Saturday, Sunday,
you have your class. Not, for example.
Now we can say,
hey, if time is more, then I don't know.
Let's take a 24 hour clock.
Right?
If time is more than 23, right,
which means 11 p.m.,
for example, I'm just saying this.
Oh, I have to go to sleep.
I have to go to sleep.
I have to go to sleep because I have work.
I don't know.
Of course I have work or something
or I have class.
He can logically
want to make any sense, but
this is just and I wanted to show you
that your Eve statement
can be nested inside,
that else can then be messed with. Yes.
So now you have. Right.
You have your else block and all.
We only if the if condition will be false,
then you go inside that else
block Right as well.
What should I change this?
What should I change
if I want to go inside the else BLOCK
What should I change?
Open day, right.
Let's change to Monday, right?
What is the Monday?
So now what will happen, right?
Hey, they is equals to Monday.
Hey, is these equals two to Friday?
No condition is false.
Condition is false.
My entire eve block will be ignored.
Right.
So then my code will go inside
where my call will go
inside the else block,
and then regular execution starts based.
Once you enter your ls block where you ls
block starts
you ls block starts from here
and it ends in here.
You can see the always line.
How do you know which one?
If you if there's no syntax issues, guys.
And if you want,
you format your code. Right.
Thanks to Elise.
You guys can see which block belongs
to which Eve starts.
Said this.
You have this level L
starts of this level ls close here, right?
Everything is like the same thing.
And that if ls block goes in here. Right.
So this way you can see.
So now, because condition for the hour
equals false.
Now we go in inside the ls point.
Once we enter the ls part
your java sees a C felt stable.
Is there any conditions
to execute this statement?
No, I can easily execute it. Sure.
I'll executing now once I executed.
Now your job is easy.
Now it is okay if it's a keyword.
What is this keyword means?
It means that my programmer
at it's some condition, right?
If I want.
So now any time this condition
I have to check if it's true or false.
Now I'm checking.
Hey, if the time. More than 23.
No time is 12, right?
So the time is not more than 23.
So your statement in here
will be in more, right.
And then I'll see as you guys,
so be all in the logic
based on the exercise, for example. Right.
We can say, hey, if they is not Friday,
then I'll do this right.
So it's all depend how we are
you guys going to place the condition
it can be either inside e port,
it can be either inside the LS block.
All depends what kind of condition
you guys going to have in here.
Like, for example, I give you the
in here, right?
You guys will do this after this, right?
So, for example, right here,
you will have your exercise.
Each says you will have a craft,
you create the Java program, right?
So you will have to
create the Java program.
And then which you have two variables
mortgage rate in mortgage price.
In your case, you will have to identify.
You want to check the price for a house
only and only when the mortgage rate is
less than 4.5.
I think that's what
the program is.
If the rate is more than 4.5,
you're not buying the house.
But if the rate is less than 4.5,
then you will consider buying
and then you'll start checking the price.
Right.
So what we seen,
we see the first the will dependency
price will depend the rate, right?
If the rate only normally
if the rate matches my condition,
then I'll check the price. Right.
So in this case depend
what kind of operator you put.
So if the price is
if the mortgage rate is more than 4.5,
you not buying the house,
otherwise you'll start checking the price.
Right.
So units that if will go to the last part.
But what if you do not
great greater What if you do
the less than equal operator.
Right.
Then your logic have to change, right?
You guys will do the assessment
and then as we will look right.
So it's all depend on the logic
is it's all will depend
on the condition
that you will place inside your statement.
Let's look
one that's just like this before
I'll give you the practice
that we've more
meaning,
for example. Right.
So what am I going to have this
What are we going
to I'm going to ask you this.
For example, write repo, right?
I'm going to ask you,
did you guys do the repo right?
So your question will be either yes or no.
Right? Your question will be either
yes or no.
So now only only
if you are going to tell me that yes,
you guys have done repo.
Now I can check
how many exercises you've done.
If you've done more than I don't know,
five exercises, I'll tell you.
That's good.
But you should have done more.
If you done more than ten exercises,
I'll tell you that you did good.
If you've done more
than 15 exercises, then, or if you done
all of it, I'm going to tell you
you guys did a great job, right?
So now let me ask you this.
What will be my condition?
Okay, So what is my order condition
and my check in?
How many assignments
you completed or I'm checking
whether you have done repo or not
doing it or not.
Right.
If you have not done repo, how can I ask,
Hey, how many assignments you've done?
You already told me
you have not done right.
So always, always does
define your first time.
You are condition right so let's take it
ball in repo company right
right from three
and then we going to say
I hope you guys will get it right
and then let's say
let's in your assignments
how many assignments you guys have.
19 in there thing like total 19 or 20
something before this year,
93, for example, it's in 1990.
All right.
So first, you guys already told me
that your order condition is
to check
whether
whether a report is completed or not.
Right.
So how do we specify the condition
we're using if state
What if I have to check something?
Right.
Hey, I'm going to say,
hey, if repo is completed,
right?
If repo is completed,
then I will perform some action.
Then that will perform some action. Right?
Do I have to have the ILS block?
We can have it.
We don't have to have it.
Like, for example,
let me add let me add it.
Right.
So I'm going to l
show you do homework. Right?
Let's say you want to tell me
you did not complete it.
I'm going to say, please
make sure you do homework.
Please make sure
you do homework.
Right.
We do your homework.
So my my suggestion this before
jumping into the next in writing.
You other could check this column.
Always check. Always check that. Sure.
If one works, always check that your else
part works, right?
Hey, is rep well, it's completed.
If the condition will be true. Right.
Let me see. Let's do me
right.
It's not out there.
Just like
for example, I'm going to say Agent
feedback
right before nesting because your nesting,
you know, get the little complicated
is always check that you're simple.
If works, don't go for it right.
And how do we check that
my even else works?
You have to provide two conditions.
True and false.
Okay, let's check who is the true.
Is my true condition works? Yes, it works.
Let me check if my false condition
what's right?
That my logic is correct what I did.
Okay, good. It work. Right?
So now go ahead and do the next ones
because you are.
Some guys will start becoming
a little more and more complex right.
So that's why
I always try to complete the simple part.
So now, now I've said, okay,
you know what?
I'm only when all the rebels are completed
now I will check the assignments.
Right?
So for example,
now I can say, Hey, be right.
For example, the assignments
always are more or equal than 90, right?
If you want or not more equal.
Okay.
Let's say let's say out of the 90,
if you completed more than more than 16,
we are good.
We are happy. Right?
So all agreed to
be to again, amazing
region, for example, right
here, We will start going down
this will start going that right.
And then if maybe let's check
why why do you do this
pattern is the highest because that's now
what are you guys will start looking
that's besides having this syntax issue
which is very very easy to catch.
Why Because we use an IDs, we might start
having the logical issues, but let's try
the first this way, and then we will try
to change the operator.
Keep.
And then for example,
let's say else elseif
E let's say you can say a standard
and then us build them correctly,
let's say are more than if you did
or we can add equal right if. You did.
That's fine.
Operator It's my main things right now
to show you guys.
Then this would be see
we get good,
but you should be more
we should be more.
For example,
statements right now
don't really don't really
don't really that matter.
Right.
All well, let's say,
do I want to have another elseif?
You can look another
see, let's say
something and
let's
see if you've done more than I don't know.
It's. It's more than six, right?
More than six
or two more
or more.
One like that.
Something like that.
Well, let's do this.
Maybe I'm.
Maybe I made him a logical mistake.
And we will see.
Is there a range of.
Yes. Once we start learning more.
You guys see right now you this
you see that we start facing him.
What if I want to do this?
We have not learned.
But of course we can do more stuff.
Next class
we will start learning addition of things
that we can add to our code in.
With the help of those additional things,
we can add multiple conditions,
for example.
Right. So now what are we see right now?
What do we see?
Hey, I have my Eve statement inside.
My is statement.
I notice that in that eve. Right.
And this another Eve statement.
And this is statement.
However, if else if if statements.
Right.
Did you guys know what
did you guys do on how to debug you could
how to do the low execution of your code.
No I will
I will teach you
I will teach you a little bit later.
But let me show you this.
Let me show you how to do it.
But I promise you I will teach you guys.
You guys will all will be able to do it.
But basically what is debugging
is debugging.
Let's look this.
If I'm going to click right now
and run, execute super quickly.
Right, Super quickly. You don't see debug.
Basically debug is a term
that you guys will start here in a lot.
You bike, it's a thinker,
it's a slow execute you know
by executing you could slow you can
you can first understand
what's going on in your code
and you can capture any logical issues
you might have.
Right. For now, I'll just do it by later.
I will teach you this.
So this way
it's easier for you to see right?
Okay.
Well, we'll do
it quickly.
Okay? Okay.
So this way.
Also through your actual let me stop you
this through your debug and you can
you will see that your code is actually
being executed up to the bottom.
How your eve statement works,
it will be very, very useful.
We will teach you this,
but why not try to watch?
All right.
So as we said, what happens?
Our main method is the entrance to your
to your to our program.
Our program is of class, right?
So this is where our main method starts
and the code executes plus to the bottom
that to the bottom.
Right.
So first, what happens?
What are we doing on the line? Seven days.
What are we doing on the line? Seven
Romney We will try to switch
and you will see what's the difference.
Keep we are initializing.
Then there will and assigning the value
right
or another term?
Another term you guys are declaring the
variable and assigning the value right?
Different different things.
But here we are just
initializing our variables, right?
First variable.
Second variable, right
first we'll get there now.
Right.
So now what are your code,
your participation if condition.
Right.
So now, in order for you for your code
to proceed, you have to define here.
Is the condition true or false? Right.
Hey, what is the value inside
this variable?
The value inside
this variable is false, right?
So now look where your code jumps
right away. Yes.
So no, because your condition is false,
but your code jumps right to inside it.
Right.
So it means here you're in start you book
now even on the
no blog that executed in
your core is finished.
Right.
You could say okay
now let's change the value.
Let me change it for true
with the actual
and now let's see.
Okay. Right.
The same thing.
Initialize two variables right now.
Chicken
hey is ready if repo condition true.
One condition is true.
We are given the green light so now I am
allowed to go inside the eve block.
Right.
So no Echo Greenway is given
now I am inside my eve block. Now.
When I am inside a block, I will start
executing the lines of code right?
I'm executing my statement.
Now you just use another EVE statement.
But what version of the statement sees it?
See is if else if state right.
So the way Eve ls if speaking
I think we call it a ladder.
Eve right ladder.
It's like a ladder right by ladder.
You go in one by one,
one by one, every single step.
So now it works. He
has Solomon is more than 16.
What is the value inside?
It's an assignment is 19.
Hey, is 19 is more than 16 now.
Condition becomes true
When condition becomes true,
the gates are opening for me, right?
The gifts are opening.
I'm going inside that eve statement,
right? I'm going inside.
If statements, I'm executing the block
of code inside the eve statement.
Right.
Once I executed,
what happens with the rest blocks?
What happens with the block space?
It will skip right out of the entire eve.
LS If only one condition always true.
There is no way
that there is a two condition.
It will be true inside a equals
each statement.
Right
So now executed executing one block well,
you can see your block was ignored,
another block was ignored
and obviously else was ignored.
Why this ls Now think of it
as this ls belongs to this.
This ls
does not belong to this eve. Right.
So this entire ls was ignored one
because this condition
was in this is true.
And now, in order
for you to test your logic, this right?
Okay. You check for true and false.
Now you have to check when assignment be
more than ten, but should be less than 16.
Right?
You always always.
Guys have to check your logic, right?
No something.
Let me put 12th let's look at something
Let's try to do the things right
initialize in two variables.
Take in the first order condition. Right.
Is the condition true or false?
This.
So I am going inside.
Right? I'm going inside.
There's no condition to execute line 12.
But now I have the execution of the line.
What? I see another statement. Right?
I see another statement.
Then drag.
Okay. If I see if it means
I have to check the condition.
Right.
Hey, if assignment is more than 16,
no condition is false.
So if.
Look, let's keep
here is the condition is true.
Assignment is 12. Yes,
it is more than ten.
Okay. Condition is true.
I am going inside.
So now your condition of ls
If block was true.
So now you were able to go inside.
So now the line 17 will get executed
and everything else will be ignored.
Right? Everything's
So now let me ask you.
And of course, you guys will have to test
for this condition.
Right? Let me do actually,
let me ask you guys.
What if I put condition five?
What are we dealt with?
Let me actually rule this bridge up.
Maybe I'll just so this way.
We don't have repetitive code.
All right, so what it will be now
tell me.
I'll give you a one.
So one thing.
This place, whenever I try to
whenever I try to type one,
explain some code.
This please try to pay attention
because it's important
to capture the logic in the code.
I'll give it to you guys. Code. I will.
I will have.
I will give you time right now,
you guys will be able to type.
So I remove something.
So tell me, guys,
what will be the output right now
from If
you did good one, you should do more.
Okay.
Please pay attention to the variables.
This one is true.
The other one is five.
So 21
I was coming to 2113 and 21,
13 and 21.
Remember this? One thing
I remember is statement, right?
This is statement. We'll have one output.
If this if statement possible,
we will have
because we did not have the right
not to cook this.
Now let's write.
That's inputs.
That's what I always say.
Also do your manual debugging.
No, it's it's complicated.
So with the first,
that's why we always try to write
from this simple case.
Don't Look into here,
don't look into here for now.
Ignore all of this.
What is our most important thing
to check right now?
What is the important thing to check? This
important
part is to check you our if condition.
Right.
So now now when you look into your are Eve
you are Eve
is it consists of only Eve block or it
consists of the even else block.
How many blocks you are.
Eve has
two outside of two
or how many always gets executed.
Only one only one number goes out of
the entire is statement.
There's always only one statement.
It's either will go to the eve
or is either will go to the right.
So now in this condition what do we have?
Condition is true.
So which block is getting ignored?
Else is getting ignored.
That's it.
Why? Because this
constant in this space,
this it comes in the here now
because Eve block is true Now you going
inside the eve black ls block that ignored
So now only know only this
when you are eve
condition is true only then start looking
inside inner Don't ever
don't even look
inside the inner
until you check the outer Keep.
All right, so now
what are we inside the outer embrace
Now inside our eve Now your java entered
your java and third in here.
So your java is standing in here.
Now what Your java is
your Java's use another eve statement.
But this eve statement consist of eels.
Eve ls eve blocks.
So all of the eve ls eve blocks.
How many blocks will get execute against?
Let's see. Let me ask you guys
what will be the difference?
What is the difference
if our little half Eve else Eve
And what is the difference?
If I'm going to have
this is one variation.
It's one variation.
This is the second variation.
If I'm going to have Eve
ls Eve
and else,
what is the difference between first
and second variation?
First one has the outer.
And that is true.
No, no, no.
Don't look at this.
I'm just looking into this.
What is the difference
if I'm going to have Eve statement?
But one statement when you have Eve ls
Eve BLOCK And this second statement
when you have Eve else Eve and else block
it will have three blocks.
This one has three blocks,
this one has two blocks.
This one don't have the block.
But this has the LS block.
So remember this.
In this case, we.
Chaikin Hey, condition can be true, right?
Condition can be true,
but condition can be false in here.
Right.
And condition for the elseif
can be false as well.
If you don't have that ls part
what will will happen.
This if there's no elsewhere,
what will happen?
There won't be no output, right?
There will be no output at all. Why?
Because our boolean, right?
Because our ruling can have either true
or either false.
In this case, if this condition was false
and this condition was false
and this condition
if also none of the conditions are match.
So what we did in here, guys,
we did not provided
the LS block, I didn't know provided
that ls block Right.
So all the conditions here are false,
but you did not provide
any code for the else part.
So if the condition is false,
if the condition is false,
I how you how you java can print.
You cannot print. Right.
If the conditions are false, great.
Now, but what will be the difference
in here if the if condition is
and the elseif condition is false,
what will happen is
evil print otherwise.
Right? Why?
Because condition either can be true
or either can be false.
Right.
So now you as a programmer,
you provided otherwise condition, right?
So out of any time
you guess have eve and else
always only one or always only one weather
you can have
ls if you can have hundreds of else
if it does not matter.
Right.
But as long as you have else block,
it means at least one
statement will be executed,
even if none of the else, if
it will be
full,
will be true elsewhere, will get executed.
In this case, I didn't approve this
because I did not added elsewhere.
So I wanted to see your logic.
All right.
So now let's look and back to our code,
which is so
now I don't have the density here, right?
So now, once again,
core condition was true, right?
We went
the moment we went inside your java.
So another
if statement Java so another if statement.
Now when you Java C is eve ls eve
blocks case E false eve blocks
it's like a leather this right.
The leather leather.
All right, so your java will go
by the leather one by one.
It will check.
Hey, is this condition is true?
No. Okay, I'll go check.
Has this condition is true? No.
Okay. I'll go and check.
Hey, is this condition is true?
Hey, this condition is true.
It will go one by one, by one by one
to check all the conditions.
And if it does not find, then this.
If it does not find it.
If you don't have the block,
nothing will be executed.
That is once again, if you have issues,
please, please, please,
please, please,
please make sure you put it in the in
the support channel
and then a little bit we will look.
Right. Right.
So and once again, guys, before you run,
you always try to look mentally right?
Okay.
Let's have a look in here.
This condition was true, right?
This condition is true.
I am going inside.
Inside.
Don't see because I removed one one line
code base.
You had great job. I did remove it.
So if you look into my code,
I remove that line of code.
Yep. Okay.
So is this condition true or false?
This truffles?
Oh, can I go inside that you block?
No, I cannot go now.
I have.
I have another else if. Right.
So now you will go and check another
if condition.
Hey, is this condition.
It's true right now.
What condition is false?
Condition is false.
Okay.
Remember, your Java
cannot make a decision to stop by itself.
Right? Your program is not smart.
Your program will do.
Would you as a programmer
have written it to do right
and your java will just continuously
check.
Okay, now I see another else
if it means I have to check the condition.
Hey is this condition is true?
No condition is false.
No, none of the can.
None of the conditional. What's true?
None of the condition was true.
What happened?
None of the condition became true.
But we did not specify the LS block.
We did not specify the LS block
for which if statements for you in there.
If statement, there's no else.
So it means none of this code
were executed.
That's why I don't have any.
Right. I don't have enough.
You know how they are.
But how else? One.
Yes, I can have the else.
What?
I'll just add the question.
Why write it then?
Now me adding the block right now,
what will be the output
this will be just the line 19.
You will be the option.
What will be the option?
Right. Let's plug in this.
Let's play games.
Well, actually, one more thing.
This let's do let's do some of you.
Some of you guys were saying right
so now listing.
Why did I use the greater
let's some of you guys were saying
what if we try let's let's try this right
Let's put it.
So I'm changing it to else right?
You guys don't have to change it
the new code
because there will be an issue.
But please look into the code right
now. Right?
I am changing less.
I'm changing less,
So tell me, guys,
with the current values of the variables,
what will be my outputs?
All of them.
17 All
you did amazing.
What?
114, 16,
16, 15, 17.
Okay, guys, don't run the code.
I want you to pay attention on the screen
right now.
Always analyze it. You are so this.
You don't even need to run the code
to see if your program gives
you the right output.
Right.
You know,
All right,
this is the condition, true or false?
True.
Can I go inside?
Which block is ignored right away?
Guess which block is ignored right away.
Else. That's it.
Else is ignored.
So now the moment I'm entering, I'm
seeing that if statement.
Right.
Okay.
Just now I have to check.
Java has no option.
It sees if it has to check.
Hey, is the assignment
less than 16 condition
true or false?
So what happens once
the condition is true?
I am going inside.
Condition is true.
I will execute the line.
13 What happens after that
That say, guys, that's it.
Everything else out of your entire
if else if ls if ls block.
Remember there is only one
block of code gets execute
only one based on the condition.
If this condition is true,
I'll give you the code.
Otherwise this condition is true.
Only one condition can be true, right?
Only one condition can be true.
So what happens?
The way Eve statement works.
As soon as it finds, As soon as it finds
the first true condition.
Guess it's out.
That's it. It's out, guys.
Everything else will be ignored.
That's why I want to. We.
When we build in the if f l e bloggers,
we have to make sure that we put only one
right condition.
It put only one condition.
That is true.
And then we put the logic correct.
Okay, so now is built logically,
this output will be there.
My output is my logically is
this makes sense
based? No.
So what happened right now?
This syntax is correct, right?
Syntax is correct.
There's no issue.
My I have all conditions
for boolean conditions.
I have my I have my curly braces.
Right.
But what I got right now,
I got logical mistake.
And usually logical errors are very
not very bad.
They are harder to capture. Right.
Because your idea is they're not going
to show you your logical errors.
Now you by debugging your code, you
by providing
different values different conditions.
You as a programmers,
you will be able to test your code.
So this way, guys,
if you go to put less 16, right,
even right
now, let's say you need 15 assignments
and based on my code,
based on my pool, I want to have right
I not 15, let's do nine right.
Based on my quote,
I want to see this output based on my code
logic with this one thing,
but because I did the different operator,
what be the output based?
It will be first.
So now, guys,
regardless, you might have zero.
You might have
one you might have two, three, four, five.
But because logically
you put the wrong operator,
because this condition
always will be true, right?
What if I'm going to put -100?
What will happen this
e will still be one.
Still going to be one, right?
That's why this
you always, always make sure you read
as time is correct.
And make sure you provide the
right
apparatus. Right.
So in this case, we should make it greater
right?
Can I write it? Sure.
I'll run it right now.
So right now,
which lines will get executed?
Which lines based on the values?
Is the first condition true?
This is the first condition to.
Is it more than six?
No, I don't think
ten is more than 16. Condition is false.
Next one,
I'm going to check this condition.
Hey, is it more than ten?
Is condition true or false?
No condition is false.
Now, you will learn in here.
So that's what we will get.
We need to try to do more homework.
Right?
Unless you guys can add greater or equal.
Operator, That's different story, right?
The difference for
my one thing is please, please, please,
always remember.
Right.
Where's your
where's your eve else
Here. Right.
I'm going back guys.
I'll bring back that screen.
But I want to make sure you understand
this.
I want to make sure you understand right.
So let me make this to make
the way I'll teach you this.
Let me show it.
Let me. Let me show it to you first.
And then
and then I'll teach you basically.
So this is the example
from your previous class.
I want you to understand how that
if else
if statement works, guess right. So
I wrote the entire statement
when we have if else
or when we have if else if.
But we also have the only one
condition will be execute only one always.
There's no way your java execute
all of them.
That's why you also
bullets
selective execution based on the condition
specific statement will get executed here.
I have written one, 2345678 statements,
but it does not mean all.
It will indicate
only when matching condition will be true.
And I want you to see how that statement
works.
Guess
if this equals two two.
Right.
So starting from the top
first condition to false.
False. Ignore condition.
True or false?
Now sure, I am going inside.
I'm executing line 13.
That's it. Existing.
Well, the rest of the code gets ignored
as soon as you show
Java finds one true condition,
it's out out of the door right.
But now look at this.
This I want to make based on
the what happens vs if else if this.
Okay so if else if we call it a ladder,
if it means one by one
like by the ladder
your java will be going and checking
every single condition
until it finds the true right look.
Good checks first condition, false check.
Second condition. Third, fourth, fifth.
Like a letter one by one goes.
Now it finds the right condition, it
executes right
and then the block, it's ignored.
So now when I'm going to have
90 that same thing.
What it does, it goes one by one, right?
Those checks, every single thing it has.
And only normally
when none of the condition were matched,
then they jump into the else. BLOCK Right.
So out of this five statements,
only one block get executed.
All right.
Do you guys want to do the exercise?
And then I'll teach you
the is how to debug
because what I want you best to try
without debug and without the running is
I want you to first look into the code
and try to make normally debug it
inside your mind
by trying to develop your logic.
Given all the assignments in here.
Vega Right.
First with the vaccine.
Simple one and this one right here.
Let me send you your sentence based.
Okay, one thing, guys, please read it.
Okay, Don't rush list.
Read it first.
You guys will go this fast.
I'll give you maybe 20 minutes
worth. Right?
I just share it in the course announcement
and then we will look into this.
Our we will try to make
with the help of scan
and we'll try to make our program
more interactive.
And after we learn the scanner, then
you guys are going to have more tests.
We will be combining our
if statements in the scanner.
Okay. Yes.
So all of it right
now, guys, I send it in there.
I send it in the course announcement.
So please take it from there.
And I'll keep the four in here.
Okay.
Silence, please
look into the semen. Right.
The shorter by the salmon, please.
Read it.
In the course announcement.
Everything is in there. Guess all three.
Try to do all three. Yep.
I'll give you 20 minutes for it. What?
I guys think.
All right, it's.
I'll give it 20 minutes.
I'll pause for now, and I'll just
take myself a little break, okay?
All of.
Yes, three guys, all of them.
Right.
So right now,
remove the extra bracket right there.
Remove the extra bracket.
So now, just by looking into this,
we don't
we don't even have to execute.
Tell me that, guys, why my job
is complaining, why McCaw is complaining
is on the line 28.
Okay. But
so now just by looking at our code
this way, just by looking at our code,
look,
there is an extra bracket in here, right?
Extra bracket in here.
Is it missing?
Now let's see if it's missing,
but I want you to pay attention in here.
This right can I can
I can add an extra bra or else.
Okay. Let me add what else.
Let me see.
Well, let's see.
For example, right now
I do still not good, right?
Still number.
But for example, let me add.
So what?
Because this sometimes there could be also
some logical logical each.
Right.
So what you guys
always have to check right here
where are your if statement starts
you intend
to start your statement from here
and then and all the way to here.
Right.
And this is should be your l statement
always do this.
Okay.
But let me see how my java reads this
statement.
Double click.
This is what you do right now.
Now would have happened your clothes your
if statement right
you started if statement in here
what you did you closed
now when you really really look
what happens
you have independent
if statement you have another if statement
and you have ls blog
then this by itself right
you have the blog than this by itself.
So that's why this is important.
Always, always check
where are intend to specify your e block.
Right.
So my e block intend to start from here
and not in here.
My e block in ten to end in here.
So it means this is
I am closing to and I'm going to
like this.
We will try to execute it right.
And then I'll show you what could be
the issues if you wouldn't have it right.
If you.
Okay right, right.
So this is just
how our program should look, right?
Hey, we decide that my GPA,
which case I'm asking GPA
only if the user has a diploma.
So now I have IGP
condition has a dependency on diploma.
So this a dependency.
It means I have to nested.
This will become my either if statement.
Right.
What is my r e my r it will be diploma
because based on this condition
I will start checking GP right so
and now would say he in diploma.
Right.
If diploma is equal to true
then I'm saying
and then I'm having
another issue statement
now because user has a diploma
I'll check the GP if it's more than 3.5,
I'll say that you eligible for
otherwise you should study hard, right?
Okay.
So without the execution,
by looking at the current output,
what will be my current?
What will be the output of my program
to their degree? Why?
What happens?
I have my GPA says 3.5
because the our condition is false.
I don't care what you have in sight.
I don't care is a moment. Why?
Because first our condition have to pass.
Right?
So now when I'm executed,
they go right to get a degree.
Okay,
so what if I want to?
An output is.
Congratulations.
You should have studied harder.
What should I change this?
I want to see the output congratulations.
And I want to see
you should have studied harder.
So me?
How should I change my values?
I have to make my condition true
in anything else.
And in order for this condition
to be false,
because I want to support, to execute,
I have to change it right.
So now what happened?
We check that our if condition is true.
And now the second condition
was false, right?
How do I make second condition true?
I want to make my entire statement.
True, True.
Okay. Is the GPA right?
All I do, I'll just choose DP.
Okay.
So by playing these values like that,
you guys
are testing the logic of your course,
right?
Okay. Let me ask you guys this.
I'm going to make some changes
making you change
and pay attention to any of this.
I'm making change in here
and I'm removing this.
What will be the output this
thing, right?
Nothing y because, hey,
one condition is true right now.
How I represent my if statements
my if statement consists of only if block
right
all I do I remove the otherwise condition.
Right I remove the otherwise condition
and inside my if statement I added this
but if and then here because of the e for
ls block always one blocks gets executed.
But in this case
the condition is also not right now.
So now you guys. So no output.
So now let me do something.
If is for this, then okay, you give it,
you can share your current.
Then we can see.
We can see
the No, let me do some things
guys, based on the
some code that I have seen this
I want you to look at
look at this at my screen.
So I'm going to remove this.
I'm removing the bracket from the line 27
and I'm adding it on the line 21.
Can you tell me, guys, just because I did
my brackets differently,
can you tell me what it will be?
My output.
You give the check, check your logic.
How would you do?
Why so right now here you saying that
you should get a degree in your else part?
You should get a degree.
But then how come you check in GPA?
Remember,
if there's no GPA, there's no degree.
We check in GPA
all in only if user has a diploma.
Okay, So In your case,
you must be inside the export.
So is the output in here
the same or different?
Or what am I going to see all
we want? 23
I change the brackets.
Remember this?
I removed it from the line 27
and I put my bracket
on the line 21
that thing.
Let me try to run.
It does me
You are eligible for scholarship.
How am I eligible for scholarship
if I don't have a diploma?
Let me.
Guys, what happened
if they go right, All good.
Because right now what have happened days
I misplace my brackets.
I misplaced my brackets.
So if I'm going to look at my code right
now, what?
How days instead of the nesting
I should have missed.
Right.
We saw already how things needs to be,
right?
I should have missed. Right.
So what I did,
I started my statement, right.
I opened my if statement.
But then what I did, I closed it right.
And now on the line 22
have another statement starts from here.
And together with the LS block,
it ends in here.
So now what had happened?
Because a misplaced the bracket that I got
two independent statements.
Right? So now I am not nesting.
And when you have two independent
statements remember guys
what Joe will do okay
there's no dependency on the statement.
Right. So it checks is diploma.
Diploma is false.
Okay. Diploma
I suppose I cannot go inside.
This blog gets ignored, but
because you could run stuff to the bottom.
Now goes down.
And because this if statement is right,
it's independent, right?
So now what? I will check all KGB.
Give me more than more than it's for It's
more than 3.5.
Condition is true.
And that's what is going inside and that's
why it's printing this statement.
Okay. That's
So that's why it's important, as always,
always pay attention, which if statement
you are missing and where you are
it starts, where you are, if it's right.
And what will be your best friend
in here, guys?
Always for my chocolate.
When you going to For my chocolate
because your I.D.
now you clearly see
this is one a statement.
This is another the two independent
they are not right
but because we want to list it means this
e you have to leave inside here.
Right.
So you cannot leave outside of the
our e right.
We have to live inside.
So you take it from here
and you must place it inside the brackets.
Right.
So this way
now is released inside this for like
no, our first program was correct.
This all I do that I just wanted
to show you different variation.
So here we had our block
that's first we look at the right way.
That's all You should get it right.
That's how it was
pulled.
But I just tried to show you
what kind of mistakes you guys might make.
Right. And
it's easy, guys,
to eliminate this type of mistakes.
It's easy
to eliminate this type of mistakes
by first defining your order condition
complete.
You are a condition, and only then
going forward in either statement.
Okay.
Okay let me see who
and I'll add the text in here.
So any time you guys want to go back
and take a look at the assignments in this
thing
is the problem.
So the same thing in here, this
what is you are condition.
Do we have any dependency there?
There's no no any dependency.
We put my name
my main condition is the rate.
What do know? Dependency.
I don't want to I don't want to buy
if the rate is not matching
My, my, my condition. Right.
If the rate is too high,
I'm not even buying the house.
I don't.
I don't look at the house.
Right. Why?
Because the rate is way too high.
Only moly when that condition will
match thing and I will think of buying.
Right.
So your
your rate should be your go to condition.
If we see
that thing.
Okay. Right.
So let me see
where that mortgage may go.
And that's where you
guys is. If mortgage first
a thing you did to seen
in there thing you again misplace
your you
misplace brackets in there. Right.
So how to execute your code by providing
different values and then you'll see
whether there's any mistake
or there's no mistake.
This equals you
price quite
or even 4.6 in your price, which
means
it's 600,000, which is
for me includes
which is home front.
So right, so, so fresh.
What are we doing? Right.
So we're saying hey, right, see
if the rate is than 4.5.
I'm not buying anything.
Right.
The house can be hundred thousand.
The house can be 1 million.
The house can be whatever price.
I don't care. Right?
I don't care.
So but what I care.
I care about the rate. Right?
So in here, what you guys see,
we put our IT condition
and we say otherwise.
Right?
So now inside the otherwise force
that's where we did our listing right.
That's where we did our list.
Right.
So no
Great.
4.600 thousand.
What are we doing.
So we buy no, we're not buying.
Tell me what will be the output?
Why are we not buying
so exact the same thing?
Hey, in which case I can check.
This is all.
Only my court will go to the else.
All in all.
But before my code goes to the board,
I'll have to check the if condition.
Right.
So now I'm checking.
Hey is rate is more 4.5?
Yes. In this case condition in here
became true
so your code goes inside the if block
so whenever the code goes inside of you
block else spot is getting ignored.
Right.
So we will get execution
of the statement 21
things it cannot buy the house I'm
look buying the house
right so now in order for me
to give a chance for minus
that even right
I have to make my condition to be false
so it can go inside the house for you.
All right.
I'm taking pay is the right.
There's more than 44.5.
No condition will be false.
So now your code automatically jumps
inside the board.
Inside.
That is for
there's no condition to execute.
Line 25 leads you to the line 25,
and that's the execution of the line 25.
Your Java runs into the if part right
the java ransom to the
if condition as soon as the
if it knows it's facing right now
statement
in which it has to check the condition
before executing particular statement
which no he's
the condition 12 false is
condition is a condition is false in here
so the same thing you gentlemen to
the bills for Anthony go exit
this exercise this this exercise right
good Have we got honest inside
that if bought as well right.
Because having this inside
that if bought as well how common
this being said that if part of this exact
let me make it revolutionary right
all this things try
and you know in different way.
Yes we are trying to do it to develop
a logic right to do all of the logic
and you always should know
that there's at least
different ways how the exercise
can be completed, at least two ways.
So how can make minus two inside the
even if I want to do next in inside the
if right.
If you guys will need to help me
with the condition.
How do I make this outputs. Good.
How do I make to make sure that no, I'm
taking
the price inside
that you look how can I do
that?
What should be my conditions as in here?
What should be my condition?
I just need you to change the operating.
Right.
So now in here, I'll just say here,
if right in
that case are used greater here,
all diseases say go right.
So what I do right
now, afford them, right?
I just flip. So now I'm saying he all in.
Only if the right more than less than 4.5.
Then I'll consider the divide
and then I'll add the 29.
So you guys see exactly
the same exercise. Why?
Just by using different operators, right?
By using different operators
when nested inside, different
based on the exercise.
Right.
Based in the exercise
and extend the Remember,
our prices have a dependency
on the rate, right?
I mean, logically,
maybe it does not really make sense
because we are paying cash.
Right.
But just by based on the assignment
what all our assignments specify.
Okay.
Remember, there's it
once again, how can you check
if you did your assignment for it?
All you have to do
just provide different values.
Just provide different and test your code.
Right. Let's try it.
Let's make right.
Write this 4.0 Home
prices, hundred thousand.
Let try to run it.
Both programs
give me exactly the same output.
Let me change the one right to five.
Right to
work programs the same up.
Let me change it. You see.
Oh, I'd extra zero and you know
what programs exactly the same outputs
so you guys are the who you are
the person who can test your code.
You are the person
who can test your logic.
So now, regardless of me
providing different values,
whether I in this step inside the block,
whether I missed the page, and if what
my program shows me the right output,
why does it shows me the right output?
Because I put the correct logic in.
I didn't just use the right operator,
right the box
put in right.
Any questions here?
This why, why did we sleep
and all that kind of stuff.
Any questions for.
Suffice
it to say that the
most system
blocks we
in. All right
this and I hope it's more than two people
that don't have any questions right.
The court will be on cameras
this the call will be on tenants.
Right. And plus you guys needed
so right now all you do.
Guys, you guys just come here, okay?
Alone wants to keep moving.
All the.
All right.
I think they were all very very similar
just to develop
your logic based on
the same thing.
Right. So what do we have in here? Right.
We have our condition
and in their condition.
Right?
So now it's
okay.
Farhad, I want you.
I want you to test your code,
because right now, the same with me.
Copy code.
Let me play this code animate.
And let me ask you guys, are we nesting
in here or we're not nesting?
I want you to look at the code
I just copied from you this,
and I want you to look.
I'm innocent or we're not nesting here.
Why not?
We should be nesting, right?
We should be nesting.
So now how can you find out for hot,
right?
How can you find out
that you made the issue right?
So it's you know, it's in.
You have to be eligible to the natural
blood if you're years old, right?
18 years or older. Right.
So now I'm going to change it to 16.
What will be the output of my program
if I'm going to logically, logically,
based on the assignment?
It should be I'm not eligible,
but based on this code,
what will be my output this
likelihood our copy your code.
You just have to look right now.
So what will be the output
with the current values
you will be what?
Tell me guys,
how many outputs water will be Outputs.
Tell me.
No, there's no error, guys.
I say the code.
My my java is fine syntax is correct.
Syntax is fine.
Racism of this index is still fine.
No output when you sign
you think it's
okay.
Guys, let me ask you let me ask you 21
and 23.
Okay.
So first of all,
how many if statements do they see?
How many statements
do are they dependent
or they independent?
They're independent, right.
So first here you have one each statement,
then you have another.
If statement, there independent, Right.
The independent.
So now it means are the two independent
if statements
you going to have output from one
and you're going to have an output
from another one. Why?
Because they have ls blocks. Right.
So now if you're going to run,
what's going to happen
right
here?
Right here?
Your program, no syntax issues.
What you told me you're not eligible.
And now you accepted me, right?
So now logically,
we need a mistake in here, right?
So now, instead of the nested,
you two independent statements right now,
this should be in this that statement
in which you blog this image block
about the weight
in which block should we added in it
you look right inside of E block
and now because my E block right now
will consist right
because my can walk right now
consists of one, two, three, four, five,
five lines of code.
What do we need This
We need our basis.
We need our basis
because without the braces, Joe,
I can read only one statement after that
it things that everything belongs to.
The main quote page.
Always, always.
Make sure you guys know where you're
nesting in the what are in here too?
Because I don't like to do the coding
in this races.
Right this way.
It's easier for me visually easier to see
because what you guys have
to remember right this
why we trying to
get you in the habit of
giving the
given the correct names for variables.
Right.
Remember, there's your variables
have to have a meaningful name, right?
Why we telling you that
you have to follow the camel case, right.
For variables. Right.
If the variable is long, we have to follow
the camel case right here.
Why do we tell you
that your classes should be.
Well, that's of
the should be with the uppercase, right?
Because when you're doing your own coding,
it's fine.
This your thing probably work.
You understand your program.
But eventually, guys, right.
Eventually, once you graduate it,
once you start looking for a job
and once you guys will be working, right,
So what happens?
You guys will be working together
as a team, right?
There will be a team of two
or three automation
engineers, maybe five, six, seven, 20,
whatever that will be right.
And you guys all will be looking
into the same code, right?
And every company
will have those coding standards, right?
And you want to make sure that not just
you can understand your code,
but other person, other person
who works with you, right.
You will understand you could,
but you want to make sure you are equal.
Understand this, right?
That's why we trying to follow
get all this coding standards right
now is to make sure you use breaks
is we use your data.
Right so this we to be
easier for you for now
just for you to read in the sense by layer
it will be very very beneficial
for your work.
You all right it's any questions?
Any questions for a nesting
because we now live in nest and we will be
combining honesty.
Give me the time to copy and paste. Okay.
And one thing is, if
sometimes you don't have enough time to do
this,
time is what my suggestion to you guys.
You can watch.
And this then and after class is over.
If you are not able to complete,
please sure you do those assignments
and I will ask you probably
to redo the assignments in any way
this whether understanding or not.
You understand? Okay. Yeah. Because
I want to be a
teacher and it's important guys
to pay to look into those details.
Right?
Because sometimes if I'm showing something
and if you guys type in.
Right.
You might miss some information
because your guarantee your code
and then if you're stuck
and you getting frustrated in there
with me, all God will be available to you.
This.
So now let me show you guys the debugging
and then
let me show you debugging this
and then we'll take a break.
After break,
we will look into the scanner. Okay.
So once again, what I said,
debugging is a very,
very useful feature
that everybody's doing.
Right.
And Maybe now you want to find
that much of the benefits you enjoy.
I will ask you to try doing it
the most benefits you guys will start
finding once we start learning
cycles, loops, some repetitive statements,
it will be visually very easy,
understandable for you to see and once
our code becomes longer, longer, longer,
then it will be very beneficial for you.
So every automation engineer,
every programmer, guys, they all
using debugging,
because only by using debugging
you can identify your mistakes,
debugging, you just slow execution
step by step.
So now when you just click on one, right
your job, it quickly runs.
What do we do in debugging?
So now you control the piece.
Okay, while debugging, you guys can define
where you want to start to slow execution
and when you want to end.
Okay So you are in the control.
So in order to start debugging, right?
So of course the will there,
there's an option when you click on debug,
right, One option
or on your for some of you
probably just top left top right corner
which it will be, there will be a bug.
Greenberg Right.
So meant that button is meant
for department, right?
But even if I click debug write debug
what I'm debugging me
writing the Java application
could still runs quickly, right?
You're not going to see the difference
where you click on what
or where you click on debug.
So number one thing,
what's important for debugging does
we have to add the breakpoint, right?
You have to add a breakpoint
to identify the point from which point
you want to start to slow execution.
Right? For example,
you don't want to probably debug
entire program, right?
I understand what's going on in here.
What I'm interested
I'm interested in this code.
Right.
So it means I want to start
debugging from my line 18.
So what I do, mess with your mouse.
Just left, left, left, left button.
You must you just double click
and it brings this button.
Hey, go it say is when you have an always
is line breakpoint.
So it means from this point
your code will be breaking down.
And from this point
you can control your code while debugging.
Right.
Your breakpoint is not going to work
when you just want to click on run.
Your breakpoint is going to work all in
only when you're going to click on debug.
Okay, So now what do you do?
Once again, if you want to remove the same
thing, you just double click,
okay?
If you don't have the numbers,
all you guys do, right click here.
It tells you show line numbers
with difference.
You guys can select all of this, right?
All you do just right click.
And this options are in there
if you don't see the numbers
because this isn't right.
If you want to see the numbers,
you just show clip, show line numbers.
So what do you do?
Double click with your mouse.
Now, once you have your breakpoint,
then you just do right click
and you see the option debug
and you just click on it.
So first time first by one,
you trying to debug
your idea will ask you for permission
because this is your java screen.
You can see it has a little g on the top.
So now your Java is asking your permission
to switch for the debug window.
Right?
And then this option
you just click on switch.
But if you don't want your ID
every time ask you for this option,
you'll just click.
Remember my decision, right?
But for now, I'll do it later
because I know I'll have to show it
multiple times.
All you do, you just go on switch
and what you will notice this one right?
You are in the debug window.
So every other window you guys can ignore.
This is your main screen where you guys
have to see and all you have to do.
There's only one or two buttons
that we have to do this.
Okay, don't.
First of
all, how do you know that
you run your code you to see here
is a red button, like a recording button
that you have, right?
That means your you're running your code.
Your code is on the spin by if waiting for
your input, it's waiting for your input.
So now when we go, I am running
and that's why I'm doing this.
I am running one woman
or one
woman.
Show you two buttons, right?
So here when you are on your debug screen
right here, my button selector.
So now there's this options
that we need to.
See this.
You just have to look into this.
Two errors, two errors.
So one option says run into
and then the other one sees run over
or now we will select this longer error.
You'll just select this longer error.
And what this error will do this,
it will execute the line by line,
by line by line your code.
So what I do are click on this option.
It says step over. So not run over.
It's a step override step
by step will be taking the step over.
Right.
Make sure you don't do you don't click
step into because it will take you
somewhere deep inside where you don't
want to be it right step over.
You just flip and step over.
Oh, can you execute
step by step right now?
Obviously. Jump in here. Why?
Because the IS was less than 16 right.
And then step over.
It executes that over exit.
That's a step back.
We will go as if some so
now how do you know that your call finish
execution issue the button is disabled
okay so let's do once again
the once again goes for a breakpoint.
Make sure you have a breakpoint for
whichever line you want to have a guess.
Right?
I want to how my if statement works,
I'll do the breakpoint in here.
Here.
I know what's going on.
I can I have this breakpoint in here.
I can edit this is initialization
or my variable know what's happening.
So I don't really care about the code
I hear from him.
Right?
So once you have your breakpoint,
double click right,
then all you do is just directly
and select the option.
Debug not running.
We are debugging right?
You book right.
First time this window will show right.
Please make sure you select.
Remember my decision.
So this way there's more going to come up
all the time so it doesn't bother you.
So just so I can remember my
decision and click on Switch.
If you
see green highlighted error line,
it means your debug mode.
How do you know you inaudible mode here?
Because there is a multiple sign
that you guys will see you right.
So all these buttons you could see
there is a run
button is enabled in the red button.
It means you are still executing
your code.
You want to stop, you can stop
and you step in and step over.
Buttons are enabled, right?
And all you have to do
is you just click, step over,
step over.
Mohammad You just can double click.
You don't have to do the right click
just to double click.
The only one thing this
the only one thing I want to ask
all of you guys,
if you decide to debug, right?
For example, let me change in here.
Right?
For example, this if you decide to
debug, that's I want to debug
right now.
Let's say I started debugging, right?
I'll step over.
I'll do step forward.
Okay.
Now in here I've got my output right
and you did not finish right.
Then later, whenever
you want to try to debug another program,
it might cause some issues. This.
That's right.
Please make sure if you are done debugging
right, make sure your code has stopped.
Make sure your code has that.
Make sure you're terminated. Okay?
Or if you want your program
to finish running
without you doing anything,
just click on Run.
So either
click on Run or either click on Stop.
Don't leave your program debug
in the middle.
Okay?
Because after that you're going to try
to run is going to run my run
something different when I try to debug
it might do something different.
Make sure if you start debugging,
make sure you finish.
Okay.
So if you don't want. Okay, I got it.
I got it. How that works.
I don't want to debug it. Okay.
Just terminated
terminated in the code will be terminated
or let's see if you debug in right
and then you change your mind
or you do just either click on run
resume or either
click on stop resume or stop.
But you want to make sure
your code is completed.
You want to make sure your Java stop
the execution, that it's
not spinning and waiting.
Because sometimes what might happen
as you might forget
and then what
you'll do, you'll go back to your Java,
you might start creating another class
and then you will be able to do the class.
But the program was closed in here,
so this way you don't forget.
Okay?
So always,
always make sure your this terminated.
All right?
So you can try
and of course we will try more
and we will be trying more
every from every class.
Okay. So let's take a break, guys.
Let's take a break.
Let's let's be back by 2:00
and then we will look into this scanner.
I'll give you a few examples.
And then you guys will
have your tests to do. Get
how they're running.
You figure.
But I changed the values right
now, as always.
Always.
If you see that my output is different,
always look into my values.
Look into the values.
Then try to identify your code
and then find out what will be the output.
And then compare it with the
second test.
Second test.
Here goes.
I promise not to confuse you guys.
I'll just keep this one
and I'll just do this one right.
Well,
let's try to try to look first. Right.
Try to.
You don't have to debug through the clips,
but the way I do because I like
because this is how you guys can develop
your logic.
Try to just manually think of it. Okay.
In which case code will go here.
In which case it will go here. Right.
Tried to analyze you don't
look about what's my.
Yes, let me try.
Right. So whichever program
you want to debug right.
Which your program
you want to do back at the breakpoint.
Right.
Are a breakpoint and then do right click
debug right click debug.
What are you debugging Java application
How to activate the button in tools.
Oh, the tools are gone.
You mean that
you mean while you're debugging, you have
you have to start debugging and
you have to switch to the debug window.
Yep. So you will have to start debugging,
right?
So from whichever point, right.
For example. Right.
Look, if you want to put the debug right,
for example.
Right.
Let me start just running.
So for example, if you want to try,
could you back from the line 23.
Right.
So in order for you to debug from line 23,
it means you code
will have to come to the last part, right?
So that's why I always,
always pay attention.
I always try to, if I'm going to debug
always for the beginning
your eve statement. Right.
And then for the breakpoint right click
do or
debug job application
switch to the debug window right.
And then if you did everything correctly,
you will see that
the line will be green highlighted.
It means where your code is pulse,
your java is in
there is waiting you to control it
and then you just
then hear the all will be there,
all will be
there, all will be enabled
in second.
Why do you think in the you
you are getting that you are not eligible
to download blood
because your our condition is your
your your condition is false right.
Let me see.
No, in here We we did it.
That's
why we did the right nesting. Right.
So now if you will be 17, right.
You just have to make sure if you fix
if you will be set.
Oops. Not been here 18. Right.
If you achieve this 17. Right.
So condition will be false in here.
You will jump only to the else for right.
You will be eligible. You will.
We can accept you only
and only when this condition will
be true. You
orange Leslie.
Okay, now it's already 152.
Let's be back by qualifying 12 Oh, replace
recording. Okay.
Thank you. Thank you for.
The remaining
work as well regarding the scanner.
Right.
So one thing I want you to remember
about the scanner right before we start
looking into into what it is,
and I hope you guys have a look already.
Okay.
We are bringing scanner guys only.
Only, only for learning purposes.
Okay,
So you are not going to use the scanner
after probably class number
ten or 11 or 12.
Right.
So we bring in it
and only to make our program
more interactive so
and to help you develop a stronger logic.
And of course, definitely, guys,
when it comes to the
working environment, you guys are never
going to work with a scanner.
So scanner is very easy.
So there is a two lines that you guys
probably will have to memorize
because
based on the current level of knowledge,
I won't be able to explain
all the details.
So you have to take it as it is.
But there is only two or three lines
that you guys have to remember.
Okay, so now when we look to this scanner,
this okay, scanner is a special class.
The way the way we have a string, right?
You guys look over the string.
You say the string is a class
that pulls the values, right?
That hold the values.
So anything you put inside a double code
is considered to be a string, Right?
So now this is another test of class.
We look at equal scanner.
Okay,
so why do we need scanner, for example?
We need to represent the values right of
multiple
the to do
the two two strings
we use to display the values right of
collection of characters.
Now, when we talk about a scanner scanner
we will be using
to take an input from our user.
Right?
Right now, who is the user?
I am developing my own programs.
I'm using them,
so I'm a user of my own program.
So now with the help of Scanner,
what I will be able to do,
I will be able to capture my own inputs
and to be able to use them in my program.
Okay, so now there's a two steps.
We will have to do this.
Okay, So step number one, this.
When you create in your scanner,
do not ever name your class scanner,
don't need your class and scanner.
Right. Why?
Because scanner, it's already
existing class, right?
The same thing is a string,
so don't ever name it.
Right.
You Can name it, Scanner them a scanner.
Example. What?
A scanner. Introduction. Right
now just
create a scanner.
Scanner.
Minimal.
Okay, I should be double in, but that's
and I know
it's it's not reserved for guys.
Remember any original words.
They are keywords, right.
And those keywords you guys can see
the way we specify them in here.
Right.
Scanner is actually should be true in
scanner.
Let me.
Okay.
Scanner. It's a class.
It's already defined class.
It's already created class
that is inside the Java library.
And the purpose of that class
is to capture input from a user.
The same thing
like we have a straight right
string is already
a class that we have created
and it stays in the Java library
for our usage.
So in order for us to create a scanner,
one line you guys will have to kind of
like memorize, right?
But just to give you a little bit
example, right?
So whenever we create a variable, right,
whenever we create a variable here,
right, let's say ABC, right?
So steps we are falling, right?
So we're giving the name the specifying
what is a type of the variable, right.
What type of values we need to store
and in this case storing and storing Now.
That's right.
So now when it comes to the scanner,
that's a case scanner.
It's a special right.
It's special type.
So it will be of the non primitive type
and as a string being primitive
and the scanner being primitive,
they have to start with the uppercase.
So we will type
scanner, we'll have to type a scanner.
And then based on their
rules, we have to give a name. Right.
I'll just give a name. For example.
Get right.
It can be anything. Remember this?
I have a box, right?
I can name this box whichever way I want.
Right.
So now here you created the variable
that can hold string type of values.
Here we create in the variable
that can hold a scanner.
What is a scanner
scanner is a special clause
that will allow me to take that
input from a user who is a user.
A user is me.
Okay, so now
the only thing initialization part
will look a little bit different, right?
So in here we will have to type new
and if you guys see
it's a special keyword, okay,
you guys will only know what is means
and now we will have two
or three types scanner
and then so this one, you guys
will have to memorize it once you start
learning objects in the classes, then
you will get you will gain more deep idea.
Why do we use new
and why do we use the parentheses in here?
Okay, so in here,
this big system that system that we
so system that out when
I tried to print something system
that in one they try to capture something
so where we will be capturing this system
but in this slide what it enables me
it enables me to capture the
any input
that we will be doing from our keyboard.
Okay, so our scanner now, once
I start executing my program,
I will be able to type in my console.
For example,
I want to type my name, right?
I want to check my name. Okay.
So now, with the help
of how how it will be possible,
it will be possible
with the help of scanner and using this.
So now what?
I read the name,
I will try it or whatever the value,
I will try to type from here.
Then this
I will have to store it inside my code.
Okay.
So that's what
this line does because it just creates
as a scanner and enables
a keyboard for us.
That's what it does.
Okay, so now our program is ready.
Now in your console,
you can enter whatever thing you want.
So now when it comes to
different values, right?
So remember this.
There is a different data types in Java
that represent different values, right?
So what type of data type heroes case?
What type of values
it doing?
What if I will enter 12?
What is 12
engager?
What if the 1299
double right?
So there is a different type of values
I as a user can enter.
Now I have to make sure my program
is able to capture captured.
Okay, so now because I can enter
different type of values,
there is a different ways house scanner
can capture for every different
type of value is scanned,
there uses different way.
For example right.
If I want to capture
and the name is a string value.
So now what?
We will have to do all in here guys.
We will have to do import
because this scanner right now
scanner the code of the scanner
class is inside this library.
So think weighted lead somewhere
in different country.
So now what we have to do,
we have to import it to our class.
You have to bring it to a country
so you can use it.
Okay.
So if you click in here,
it will give you the option import
or there is a shorter way
how you guys can do it.
Shortcut to import.
Do you just shortcut to import to import
existing class?
So then you do the current class
first class.
So a short way will be
for Mac users.
You guys will use
a month the last shift plus four.
Okay, this is Mac users.
What you guys will do
and the Windows users
you guys will do control shift
what you and I can do it
or you can do it
manually just by clicking Windows
Control system. Yep.
So what do you do?
Come on shift or so now what will happen?
Our import will come.
So it means this scanner class
leaves in somewhere
utilizing some of the utility library.
We don't have to go that deep in there,
but that would basically it means.
Right.
So now once you importer,
once you brought it right now
there's no issue in
my code is not each. No.
We need to take our scanner.
We need to have our scanner
and to capture the value.
Now this variable refers to the scanner.
Exact the same thing
as this variable refers to the string.
Right.
If I want to reassign the value,
guess I'm going to say
straight SDR equals x, y, z. Right.
So what I'm doing,
I'm referring to the variable.
I'm referring to a box. Right.
So the same thing in here.
Any time you want to work with a scanner,
you have to refer to the variable, right?
We import a scanner.
This, you guys will see a line.
We will get imported in here.
So now we have to work with the variable
that points out to our scanner.
So now what I will do,
I will type scan right now,
what I'm trying to do, I'm
trying to capture the name.
Name is or what type of value
name is this tree
Now to string what I have to use,
I have to scan that next.
Okay, so scan that mix.
What it will do guys, it will
it will capture
things
value from console.
So for example. Right.
So for example, what will happen right now
when I enter my name.
Right.
So this line will be able to capture it.
Now I have a value.
What do we do with the values though?
I need to store this now somewhere.
This if I, if I grab the value
so now because
I grab the value,
I have to store it right.
We like to store things
because we want to use it in the future.
Right.
So now what type of variable?
I got a string right. I've got a string.
So now this value will be stored
in here, right?
It will be shown in here.
So now what I have to do because I grab it
all I do, I just have to store it.
So I will start it inside string
and I need to give a name.
I can just say name, right?
So now the value that you you type in
your console
will be stored inside this variable.
So now what I will do this
will allow me to capture any string value
from capturing the string.
Now leave a storage
inside the string variable right name.
And now what I can look into do so
and I'll just take me right now,
just type me.
So now let me try to run it
when I run it.
So I guess nothing happens.
Nothing happens.
But what do you guys will see?
You guys will see the red button in here.
So it means your program is running.
It's waiting.
Okay, It's waiting.
So now where is it exactly?
Waiting. It's
waiting for you in here. This.
It's waiting for you
to enter a string value.
Right.
Okay.
Yeah, right.
I entered, right? I typed.
So now, before you guys were not able
to tap on the console label.
So now what will happen?
This value will be stored in here.
And then all you're doing, you
just printing the value inside this box.
The only thing
in order
for you to continue the problem,
you guys will have to hit.
Enter.
Just hit, enter. Go here.
This name was capturing inside this box
and then we have printing it.
That's what happens.
Or we cannot add in here.
So no say hello
right now.
This is first time I'm running right now.
Can I run it?
Run it again? Sure, I can run it again.
Oh, plus if you need
signal,
you can even let me say I want to enter.
Delete. Right.
I want to enter the name Mariem.
They go. No. Tells me Mariam.
Before I was telling me.
Hello, Hanoch, I want to enter my name.
It will capture my name. Right.
So I guess you want what happened?
Our program become interactive right.
So now instead of the specifying
Hey value name is equal to us,
so what I'm doing, I'm able to capture it
from my console, right?
I'm able to capture for my keyboard.
So now every time I can enter
different names
and my program will display me
a different different names, right?
So now, for example,
I want to capture an H, right?
I want to capture the H, right.
For example,
let's add the statement for let's say we
enter
your.
Okay,
so now H is a different data type, right?
To capture a integer value the same thing.
What we will have to do,
we will have to refer to it as Skinner.
I'll refer to it as Skinner.
And now what I'm capturing,
I'm captured as an option.
We have to select next integer.
Next integer to capture a string values
we do next to capture integer value,
we do next integer.
Now what are this thing?
If I'm going to enter the age,
what type of variable it will be
if I'm trying to capture integers?
So what type of box I have to create?
Integer it's empty and right H Well, 1321
So when you want 51 right so it will be.
H Right
now I can think so.
Let's say whatever name
I capture captured right name.
And that's some confirmation
that they will capture the name.
Right.
So you are whatever age we capture it
let's
figure right
so now what you see
let's try to see how it will work
right again my program is waiting
where it's waiting you don't see
because a program was running.
But I'll tell you guys was waiting.
It's waiting on the line 18.
It's waiting for you
to enter a string type of value.
Right?
Echo You got this. My name, my right.
Then I hit enter.
So now what happened?
I saw nine here.
Now I'm printing. Hello?
Right here.
I captured now my program.
Nice to add the output right now
tells me please enter your H.
Right.
So it means this line 22 was executed.
Now my code is waiting.
Is waiting for me
to enter some integer value.
Now let me see. I'm going to enter.
I don't know.
Just I'll just add 21. Right?
For example,
so now 21 will be stored in here
and then I'm just printing date and values
that are stored inside this boxes.
Yep. Yep.
So that's, that's a good one of my rights.
And now if you guys really look right,
if I'm going to try to run again.
So now my program is waiting right
So you kind of like don't really know
what your program is waiting for.
Well, for example, right.
Maybe you have your friend,
you have your family next to you
and you want to show them
what you have done today.
Right now, you created this program
so you would
give kind of like construction, right?
You give it to your brother
insisting, going to say,
hey, can you check this exercise right?
You click on Run for Them
and you want them to do the things right.
So you want to do the instructions
so your user knows what to do, right?
Okay.
Now why don't we why don't we enter
the same statement in here?
Right.
So now, before capturing the name
we just ask, please enter your name.
Right.
So this way
be given the clear instructions.
Right.
You going to say please enter your name
right
system
that out we printed something out system
that anyone we captured
No now will be more Please enter your name
right.
Please enter your h
I go.
I see you are 25 years old.
Right?
But this is what my program captured.
So now when you look at this case
now, when you Look at this, guys,
do you see anywhere?
Right. Let me remove my console.
Is there any way in my program, guys,
I hardcoded the name what I mean
by hardcoded I say name equals to a self
and every time a princess.
So do you guys see this
any way in my program?
No, I did not specify.
So now I did not hardcoded
the value for h.
I did not hardcoded the value for me.
So now my program becomes interactive.
Right?
So now would be some things
that are running.
I can enter whatever name and those names
will be dynamically captured
right and stored.
So now when I entered
right when I enter my name
in here, let's, let's execute
manually, right line by line.
So in here, scanner is getting created.
What is it scanner?
Scanner is a special class
that enables us for this part.
That's what it enabled enables for us.
That's what it does.
Now when we see line 19,
it says, Please enter your name.
I see this output.
Yes, I see. That's output there.
One by right, one this to the bottom.
That's how my program is.
Now, when it comes for the assignment,
right
When it comes for that, there's
always, always operation on the right
happens first
and then the sign in the valley.
Right. And then operation on the left.
So at first scan that mix what it does,
it captures this value, which was a string
and what are we doing?
So now this basically captured
for yourself
and what we did
we stored inside this variable.
That's why
I've said that we seen this output. Hello.
So right.
And then the next print out,
please enter your age
now, because age is a different type
of value.
It's an integer type of value.
So now using our scanner.
Using our scanner.
Right, Using the variable, this always,
always point out to the variable
that refers to the scanner.
What do we capture
and we get an integer Next.
I know it means next integer.
Now 25 What it will be happening is 25.
It will be stored in here.
And then what we do name.
It's a variable, right?
You're referring to this variable.
Each referred to this.
That's what we do.
That's what I do.
For example.
Right. Well, I'll go one more
complete again, bring
you bring your example and try to put.
So now this is just simple examples right
in the are a date to change it to date
where I mean you
you mean you want to capture the date
the date of birth.
Then there is will
we will have to do this some operations
because if you really don't think
date of birth
it's will be a combination,
not just numeric values.
Right.
Because Java does not give us just
you know, I mean, it has those option,
but basically we will to capture enter,
for example, 0101 whatever year.
Right.
So it will be a combination of characters
so we can capture it
in the form of strings but
then we will have to do many operations.
But those operation
we will be able to do only and only once.
We know how to work with the strings.
Why do we will try to capture guys,
we can try to capture boolean,
we can try to capture double
because for every single option,
every single data type,
every single type scanner has an option.
Scanner has an option.
So all basically
you guys will have to memorize.
You'll just have to memorize this line.
And then just based on the data type
that you're trying to capture, you guys
either will use next to capture strings
or you use next integer
to capture, to capture integer that's
acting out.
For example, let's try to do one more.
Let's try to do one more.
Okay. I'm not going to mess up this class.
This I'm
going to try to create a new class
who will maybe want two more
examples I'll show you and then you guys
will be able to do it on.
Let me do them then.
Just think
and I know you best pipe in
and I'll give you the time after them.
Minute. So what?
We'll try to do this.
Let's try to capture
an item that we want to buy
and let's try to capture the price right
and the price right.
So now to capture the values,
we will need the scanner, right?
And then we will be capturing two values,
right?
One is the item and one is a price.
Right.
And then we will see which option
we should select.
And I'll bring this back after that.
So now to capture input from a user,
we need scanner, right?
We need scanner
and they'll try to give scanner
any variable name, any available name.
And I would like to change the names
so you guys don't
get used to the same memorization, right.
I'll name it. Input.
You guys can name it, whatever
whatever you want. Right.
Because it's a books.
I can give you a name, whatever I want.
Next one, just try to memorize it.
You scanner and then you can
be right the same thing.
Now you created a new class
in which you want to use a scanner.
The same thing.
We will have two important assured
way to import it.
You'll do command shift
or or control shift or
I want you all right there. Right.
So now what happened?
Our scanner that imported.
He was going to get that important.
Now let's.
Let's give instructions what's given,
because I want you to capture the item
and I want to capture the price. Right.
So I'm going to say it's all right.
Same point.
And third
item you want to buy,
right? Okay.
I want to enter banana.
I want to enter Apple.
I want to enter phone.
I want to enter car.
What type of value is that?
This.
It's a string, right?
So now it means here
I will be storing a string value.
Right. String. Oops. String item
straight.
Right, right.
So now who can capture that?
Who can capture that value? This?
Who can capture
input?
You get that.
Please make sure you don't name
your your class classes.
A scanner input. Right.
Who refers to my scanner input?
Know which option
I have to capture the string.
I have the option next to and tells
you will hear string.
I'm able to capture the string. Right?
I go, I'm capturing the string. Right.
Good. Okay.
So now whatever value
I will enter in here, Apple,
it will be stored inside this item.
Right now let me try to capture price
for a click.
And so this
all there and let's concatenate it.
Whatever the item you told me.
Right. You know, we sent the price
in, the previous item
that you will print out and now
the price is a different data type, right?
Price is a different data type.
So Now you guys will decide
how you want to enter.
If you want to enter using integers
or using a double.
Right, let's go for double.
So now again, who can capture
That was only my scanner.
Which variable refers to the scanner
input input
and then to capture the double values,
what do we will do?
Guess we'll just see next.
Double because we capture integer values.
We do next 90 To capture the double values
we will just do next double right.
And once we capture the price, we can
store inside this variable double as
And now this is the print out
about let's see
you selected and then plus item
plus item
something for the price
equal.
Then whatever the price
was first thing.
Right.
Let's see what will write.
Right. So this output came.
It means already a scanner was freed it
now we setting up the instruction
now you could put it in here.
It's waiting for a string.
Now I want to buy my nano bagel
as soon as I hit the enter.
Your program is still waiting This.
What do you see?
It's still waiting you now.
As soon as you going to hit enter
Banana will be stored inside this item.
Right?
And the code continues execution.
Now it is please.
And enter the price for banana.
Now your code is waiting in here.
You scan is waiting for you.
Now it's waiting for the price.
It will be zero nine. Right.
So now, as soon as you enter
zero 99 will be stored inside this box.
And then what we give you is selected
banana is price zero.
Right.
And once again, once we'll go.
Okay. So when that banana
store in this
item, how we were able to capture it
we were able to capture it using scanner
and using next next capture string value.
Then to capture double tap on value.
We still refer to the scanner,
but this time we select
next double, right?
And then when we select
the things that Bill zero 99 was able
to store in here,
that's how I was getting my right.
You enter in here,
but as soon as you hit enter,
your banana is getting stored
inside this variable
and your price is being stored
inside this variable you hit enter this.
Yep, you hit enter time,
you finish typing,
just hit enter.
And so all all the time
we have to use scanner.
Yes. Yes.
Any time you want to capture a values.
Right.
So you want to capture a string
you will use next
you want to capture double.
You use next double.
You want to capture integer
you will use next integer.
Okay, Next integer.
What do you guys will have it
on this length? You guys will have it on.
This lets us know when you think of this
now when you know is scan and right.
For example guys,
when you created your program
to see if the numbers are equal or not.
Right now those numbers can come from you
or from your program.
You don't have to hardcoded them.
And now by aligning different values,
you make your program into active
and you will be able to check your code.
Right?
So now that's what this can address.
And you guys,
you guys will have that on slides.
The only, only thing in order
for your scanner to want a nice
number one thing, don't ever
name your classes in scanner
And the part number two when you finish,
when you finish typing your value,
make sure you hit enter.
That's all.
And just make sure you guys know, okay?
Just make sure you know that you provide
and right values.
For example, hey, what is the item
you want to add?
I want to add. I want to add. All right.
Let's say please enter the price, right?
Please Enter the price.
Now, you have to think your your
your scanner is waiting for double value,
right?
What if I enter a string, for example,
I want to say $1, for example,
and then hit enter.
Now, what is happening
this now you will complain.
It tells you input mismatch. Why?
Because you tried to capture
in string value
and you tried to store inside the double
and all the crazy things are happening.
So let's let's just make sure basically
you're providing the right values
into the right options, right for the next
enter only strings for an X double.
Make sure you capture only
double type of values and for integer.
Make sure you capture
it only using next routine.
Otherwise Java will complete.
What if you want to combine
double in the string in the input
right here we combine combining it
with the help of the string concatenation.
We combine it all.
You mean you want to type it?
Okay, if you want to type it,
then there is a different options.
Okay, let me show you something.
Let me show you something.
But I want you first to be clear
with this thing.
This I want you to first to be clear,
was this two examples, right?
So now, with the help of scanning,
you can capture anything
we want right?
So now when we talk about scanner,
remember,
scanner is a non primitive types, okay?
To cast non primitive,
there's other things we will have to do.
Like trust in non primitives
will be different than custom primitives.
Okay.
In that
we are going to learn a little bit later.
Well you guys.
Yeah, you guys can then shrug
different different things, but if you
if you instruct
if you're waiting for an integer.
Right.
If you're waiting for integer
then there will be a little bit more.
You will you want to see if it's a number
so that is more complicated.
Things will come.
So for now,
just try to enter the right values,
okay?
So this options that you guys
will be learning, what are what is coming
after that?
Why do I have the parentheses
and why throws me specific issue.
You guys will learn all in details
why they've happened,
what just happened.
So one thing I want to show you this.
Some of you ask if I want one
to enter a string and then double click.
So now remember this Any time.
If you are touching
anything to the string, what happens next?
For example, when you did your
test,
you did your example concatenation, right?
So when you did ten plus ten,
it will give you 20, right?
But when you do.
Hi, did you guys do this example plus ten
plus then what was the output this
what was the output?
E was becoming high ten. Ten.
Right. Why?
Because anything this
anything you are touching to a string.
Right.
Whether the string will be on the left
or whether the string
will be on the right, it becomes
one big string in one big string.
Completely brain you but one big string.
So now if you say, Hey,
if I want to enter a string
and then double, right, so then what
it will be you need to capture.
You need to capture it as a string
if you want to capture them together.
Okay?
The one the only difference
I will show you this.
The only difference
you will see, for example, right.
Well, then let me run my item.
What I want to buy. Right?
I want to.
Here, please enter.
You want item
you want to buy? I want to buy
iPhone 13, right?
iPhone 13.
It is a string, right?
It is a string.
Now, when I hit enter, right.
Okay. Now it gives me wrong issues.
But what happens in here
is what happens in here
when you try
when you trying to enter the any string.
But that will have spaces basically
when your string value
is going to be more than one word.
Okay, then your next method,
then your next option
not able to capture it.
If you have a sentence right, think or
if you want to capture more than one word,
more than one.
What is going to give you
a different option?
Okay.
It will give you different option.
It will show you a different option. Okay.
But just make sure this is the help
of next can capture string field space.
Basically.
What are we saying in year
one word,
one where you can double captures one
one double valid
integer captures you one
can do that. Now
if you want to capture a sentence, right?
If you want to capture a sentence,
scanner has different option, right?
Let me show you that option and
we will repeat the quotes of this, guys.
It will stay in your head. Yep.
It will have the option next.
Like okay, let me do first
and then.
Okay. Right.
Same thing. Name
anything Repetitive line.
Repetitive line.
So what we will do will be scanner, right.
And every time
I try to give different names
I will try to give different meanings.
Depend on the scene. Right.
So this way you'll get the logic logic
instead of the memorization.
Right? You
scanner and then
let's
add something import
because it's a new class
and you want to use scanner again,
we will have to import
come on, shift or control shift all right.
Now I want to say, hey
is in their sentence is
syntax
in sentence. Now,
if you want to capture an entire sentence,
the scanner has an option for it.
And as Angelica said, it will be in that.
And will just type next.
No, instead of the just next
we will see next line.
So next line,
what it does, it equals to capture
entire line
that you will enter in your console.
So now
and if it's a line, right remembers,
if it's a line that will have combination
characters,
pieces, numbers, it still will be
write
string.
And then let me just print
like, let me try one
means enter any sentence.
Oh, no dice.
Right now I can enter like go
my next line was able to capture
entire line including space right now
would say any sentence
I am very happy to be
like, okay,
so now your next line is able to capture
internally.
Okay.
You can enter combination of
double values with a string
because you know going to happen,
everything will be tracked as a string and
it will be stored inside sphere, right?
Where if I'm going to use next,
that's what you guys will see.
Now I'm going to use next, right?
I'm going to say hello
floating, right? They go right.
If I'm using units next
is able to capture
only only the first word till space.
That's why if you have a long
sentence this always go for a
way to capture to
capture for
more than one or two.
You must be most of the time you guys
will be capturing either one string value
or either one integer.
Any questions?
This any questions?
Was the wording on the line
or is just because
again, that's a non primitive type.
What we will have to do,
guys, we'll just have to close it.
We will just have to hold the option
to close it.
So but this is not
this is not mandatory for now.
Just leave it.
No, just think.
But if you want to use calls, we can use
this can be
all right.
Let me see.
So here is right.
So here I'll fix it the little bit to it.
Strings we use next. Right.
I'll add that if you want to read
the entire line re not numbers.
Next integer decimal values double if.
You want a single character,
you will have to use this right drag.
You try to practice with them.
And what I'll give
you guys, I'll give you an
sast.
I'll give you five tests.
Actually, probably five. Six. Okay.
So all of this is this
you have to use scanner.
And now because we learned scanner
we will combine it
with our nested E right or with our eve.
Well it, it will be nested right.
So in here you'll want specialists
you need to ask user what is the amount of
loan is needed. Right.
So now you do not want your heart code.
The value double or equals to this, right?
So now you can enter loan anyway, right?
Whatever value
you want with the help of scanner, then
capture it and then you guys
will true in your if condition.
Hey eve email that you enter.
It is less than 200,000.
You'll give the money,
otherwise you won't be right.
So what do you will use?
You will use your if condition.
And then here you guys are thing you guys.
We will need to see
what kind of condition you will use.
But all this test, they will be using it.
They all will be using scanner
with the combination of then this
that is okay
all right.
I think
I'll give it to you right now.
So try to complete it by tomorrow class
because tomorrow classes
also guys will be very interactive
for tomorrow class.
What I will ask you guys, please,
please make sure you look over
the logical operators.
Okay.
And then and then tomorrow
also that there will be more tasks
that you will have to do. Okay.
So it's very they're very practical
today, so they won't be you, do they guys?
What will be all this assignment.
So this way you can practice, right.
Well well, good.
If you have any questions,
please ask me them. Now.
If you don't have any questions, guys,
I'll upload the code.
But please, please, please
make sure you practice
and look into the new material
that will be there tomorrow.
Right.
All right.
I'm very I'm very happy to see you.
It's actually not fun of being sick
because I enjoyed teaching.
And actually now I was scared a little bit
by the end of the class.
I actually feel better.
So I will take some right now.
Thank you, guys.
And please, please
make sure you practice it
and I'll see all of you tomorrow. Right.
And that will I will upload the slides
for tomorrow class as well.
Yes. I'll post in the course
announcements.
All right.
Thank you, guys.
And I'll see you, all of you, tomorrow.