No question, Sebastian.
Good.
All right, guys.
So let's start from the region.
And I hope now the hard days are gone
and now you guys will start enjoying.
Thank you.
You guys will start enjoying your Java
and all your.
And you will be combining it
with selenium best.
And you could come by our Excel files
text file.
So you guys will now be able
to do much more fun with Java
instead of just learning those dog
classes and cat classes and all that.
Mm hmm.
Um, today's
class number 25.
Oops. What class?
And you guys are using intel,
right?
I feel like in addition, when we do
selenium.
Yep. Yep.
You guys will be like magicians.
You guys will be able to do much more.
Oh, my God. How many are there?
I just know Selenium.
Oh, there are so many.
So many.
We will be creating year dogs and cats
looking worried or
looking worried.
So. So last class,
we discussed all about interfaces
and the differences
between interfaces and abstract classes.
And we also went through the encapsulation
part.
Right?
So what do you guys remember
from that?
Let's start from the abstract classes.
So if someone asked you
if someone asks you in your interview,
what is an abstract class,
how would you guys define an abstract
class?
Let's say
you are explaining it to an interviewer
and don't use Google not finished.
Don't try to come up with
your own explanation so that you guys know
how much more prep you guys need before
you are ready for the interview.
Don't look at your notes.
Don't look at your lot, look at Google.
Try to explain it
in your own understanding,
in your own words.
Every class participates in inheritance.
Okay?
Every abstract class
participates in inheritance.
This abstraction means
hiding the implementation, but showing
only the functionality to the user.
So now you guys
should be able to explain these things,
right?
It's class
without ways of how to implement.
Okay.
To completely,
you need to create a subclass
in the class where we can have implemented
and some unimplemented method.
That's also a good definition
and they are classes
with the abstract keyword that we use.
Then we are not sure how to implement
the meters.
Perfect. Perfect.
So let me copy that collection
of some defined end and define.
So all of your explanations.
They they are good. They are great.
If you guys are coming up
with these explanations on your own.
But what most of you are doing,
some of you are discussing the properties
of the abstract classes.
Some of you are discussing
how the abstract classes are implemented.
Some of you are discussing how
what does the abstract classes contain.
So all of these are good, but try to put
more things to your explanation. So
the more you explain to the
interviewer, the more they know that
that you know more.
Right?
And if you guys are not sure
about something, let's say
70% or 80% sure,
then you guys can say I am 70 to 80% sure.
This is what an abstract class looks like.
And if you are just 50% sure,
I would say don't
even discuss that concept
because interviews
there will be starting
from a simple question.
Then you once you answer that question,
they will.
The next question
will be from your answer.
So be careful how you explain
to the interviewer your answers.
Don't use terminologies or things
that you guys are not sure about.
Every abstract class should have a method,
but we cannot instantiate it
without creating a subclass.
So abstract classes they are classes
with abstract keyword right
that we can use.
Then we are not sure how to implement
some or all
methods right.
So this is a very simple, difficult
definition of the abstract class. Now
rules, right?
So now tell me about the rules
that you guys remember
about the abstract classes
extend
skyward.
Yes, Alexia, can you try to explain more
extensively
what do you guys mean by extend scalar?
Abstract classes need to have abstract
methods, guys.
So nice saying abstract
classes need to have abstract methods.
Is it true?
Can they have a class and abstract
class without any abstract method
must participate in inheritance
right.
So rule number one
must participate in inheritance.
Otherwise we will not be able
to use any
methods
or any
instance, methods
or peers.
Can I use the static methods
and static fields from abstract classes?
If I don't have that in?
So the inheritance relationship,
if there are some static methods
and static fears inside an abstract class
and I am not making
any other class inherit from that abstract
class,
can I still use those?
Yes, I can use those. Right.
Because abstract matters
and abstract
fears, they don't require
an object of a class, right?
They don't require an object of a class.
So that's why I have only mentioned
about the instance
methods and instance fields in here.
If we are not participating
in inheritance,
we will not be able to use instance
spheres and instance methods.
But still we can use the static fields
and static methods.
Abstract is a non excess modifier
for classes methods, but not variables.
It is used to achieve abstraction.
Yes, if you are perfectly
right, child class
must give the implementation
of abstract methods from after class
if inheriting from that class.
So definition cannot be final. Yes.
So. So second thing
so must participate in inheritance.
Otherwise we will not be able to do
abstract class can
have zero
or any number of
abstract
methods.
As soon as one method of the abstract
de class needs to be declared
as abstract, perfect.
So rule number three
as soon as one method is
declared
its abstract,
the class needs to be declared
as abstract.
We can have non abstract matters as well.
Inside the abstract class, right?
We can declare a class as
class, even
without any
abstract methods.
All right or not,
we find an abstract keyword cannot be used
with fields and constructors not be final.
LSC see cannot be final, a class cannot be
final and abstract at the same time.
This is what you mean.
Okay, please don't do this.
And in your interviews,
if they if they are asking you, define
the abstract class known.
Tell them abstract class
is an abstract class.
Try to explain more
abstract class inheritance,
abstract class final abstract class
not final and abstract.
We need a child class to provide
implementation of abstract class.
Yes, Alexia,
if you are not comfortable with English,
you can type in your native language
is Ukrainian
or what is your native language
cannot make object
of abstract class directly
and we will consider the gap.
So we need egide class to provide
the implementation
of the abstract matters.
Right?
The abstract matters.
Now, can I do this, guys?
Can I have a chart class
which is only providing implementation?
Let's say, let's say my parent class.
Is that an abstract class?
It has been abstract matters
and in the general class
I only want to provide
maybe the implementation for five meters.
Can I do that?
Oh, yes. No. Yes. 5050.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
But turn it to be abstract, too.
Yes. No.
You just have to make the class.
Absolutely.
Yes, we can do that.
I if I have a parent class
that has been abstract matters
in my child class, I can provide
maybe the implementation for one method,
no matter no, no implementation,
not at all.
On maybe all the implementation
for all the matters.
But in case
if I am not providing implementation
for my one
method, right,
even if there is one single method
for which
I am not providing the implementation
which child class must be declared
as abstract as well?
When we extend an abstract class,
we must either do implementation
of all unimplemented methods
or we must declare that class.
Abstract Also, no, not all the.
Yes, yes, yes.
Actually, actually you are right.
So when we extend an abstract class,
we must either do
the implementation of all.
We must
provide
the implementation
of all unimplemented methods,
or we must declare that child class.
Abstract.
All right. Okay. Perfect.
It rules What else you guys remember?
Can I have constructors
inside of the abstract
classes?
If there is anything else,
you guys can also give me feedback.
Let's say
if you guys want me to go more flow.
I can also do that right if you guys want.
It totally depends on you.
How you guys want to learn.
We can't use abstract class.
Oh, there is someone who can understand
so you can mother
like three.
You are saying you
or it's the Google who is translating.
You do something wrong.
You mean the parent class so you can
like Google.
Not all this model smart
be mother class Google ask bug
if the fashion.
Okay, let's let's not use the class later.
It needs more machine learning
so we can extend only one
abstract class.
Yes, we can actually let
let's put it this way we can extend
only one
class
in Java
abstract
or non.
It's really bad.
You need two tools.
Ukrainian authorities
translating from Russian.
Yes, you can have.
Okay, perfect
can create is equal to non abstract. Yes.
And oh actually
actually let's not put it this way
because there can be
other types of classes as well.
There can be so many things in Java
Anonymous classes in all classes
that big classes I can keep on naming.
I am and I don't even know
how many types of that we have.
In other words, are different
was about to get to
a very wrong way.
Always coming? Yes. Every six months
they have data classes, silly classes
and all that. So
and now they have a release cycle in which
they are losing new things and color
and articulate it.
Not uncle and auntie,
but they are friend classes in C++.
Friend class is going to access
your private members and other.
There is a lot lot lot of story
then all that other programing languages
those brands
so can you please explain rule number nine
or you're about inheritance
it's it's about
I cannot have multiple inheritance in Java
rule number nine you guys remember
there can only be one one
there can only one parent in Java.
It's about that.
The parent can be abstract.
That parent can be non abstract.
I have just written it in a different with
it is clear.
Rule number nine.
Okay, so is there any relative class
who just find out
better than a class
that does not even exist? No.
You have to find your editor on your own.
So then we discussed
about the interfaces, right?
So what is an interface guide
outline for the class for fact?
Perfect.
All right. How how many meters
will a
class
have if that class in that intersect?
So it's kind of an outline blueprint
of a class on.
Yes. You can see it there.
Doesn't
can have only unimplemented methods.
No I, I guess I told you from Java eight
they can have static method
from Java nine.
They can have private matter,
they can have default matters,
They can have so many types
of methods Now,
before Java apps there there
they used to contain
only unimplemented methods.
He has started and abstract mementos
unrelated systems meet.
It can only have abstract methods.
No, no.
It can have many different types
of methods.
You can have many different interfaces.
A collection of public static
final variable and public
abstract methods.
So you guys can start your explanation
from here.
Interface is a collection of public static
final variables and public
static methods.
Here's a
contract
that a class has to
implement.
It's the public static final variable.
This is put up and public abstract
methods, plus
a static
default and
private methods
from Java eight and nine.
So you guys can add this as well.
And most probably be
and most probably your interviewer.
They will be surprised
to know that that you guys know
that there are, there are private
methods as well in interfaces
because believe me in the industry,
they, they just keep
on using the old technologies.
They don't even know
if there is something that is introduced
in languages.
So I'm
interface
have only static final or default methods
and they can have private
as well from java nine
and God knows what from Java
16 or 17 interface is an abstract
used to declare. So
every interface in Java
by default is an abstract class,
but is an abstract class.
We are not supposed to write abstract.
You work with interface.
It's not an abstract class of the
every interfacing
Java by default is abstract.
You can say that
they don't don't use this class schema
interface cannot be extended by class
but implemented by a class.
All right, so let's discuss the rules
for the interface
so the famous rule can only have
public
spare.
The final feels right?
No instance fears,
no private fears and no protected fields.
Nothing. Only public static final fields.
Right.
Can interfaces?
Can they have constructors?
So as there are no
instance
fields in
interfaces?
Yes. They don't have
constructors as well.
Okay.
All right.
So if they don't have constructors,
can I create an object
of an interface? Yes.
So urban,
we can create an object of interface.
We cannot create
objects or interfaces
because they can have
an implemented
desired is the same story
that is with the abstract classes.
If there are unimplemented matters,
then and you are allowed to create
the object, then there can be a problem.
Right?
If someone or someone tries
to call and unimplemented
method,
it will not know which method to call,
which method to call. Right.
Because it's something incomplete, right?
Incomplete. Sorry.
So let's say, for example, it's a card
that has only maybe the Indian
and there are no tiles, Right.
So can you drive that car
or you should you be driving that God
is about.
It's like any anything that is incomplete.
You think of mobile phones, maybe
the mobile phone does not have batteries,
maybe it does not have implementation
of how to make calls,
how to send text messages,
how to use Internet.
Should you be allowed to use that?
No, because it be misbehave
or the user will be at least frustrated.
Right.
So in real life as well,
if something is incomplete.
Right.
If if something is incomplete,
you should not be using that thing.
Right.
So that's why these these classes
and these interfaces,
they are not allowed to have objects.
Right.
Because if once you have the object,
what if you try to call some matters
which you do not have
body so it can be a problem.
All right, guys,
what else
do you remember about the interfaces
you could use to achieve loose coupling?
Rule cannot extend to a class.
So it a class then. Now
extend an interface right
again.
Again
and interface.
Extend and other interface guys.
But it is
implemented by
a class.
Instead of extending, we will implement
the interfaces
so an interface can
extend it.
And another
interface
and interfaces can
they have multiple inheritance
in interface
can extend multiple interfaces
between interfaces for multiple
inheritance. Yes.
You're correct. So
an interface can extend
multiple interfaces.
It means interface board, multiple
inheritance, right.
There is the use are.
No, not quite because there are so many
other uses of the interfaces as well.
So if you are looking to the JDK,
you guys will find
if there is only one method
or only two methods are there
that are unrelated to each other selector.
For example, there are multiple classes
which are not related to each other
in any way.
For example, a laptop class
is not related to a class, right?
There are no attributes which are
common or not that many attributes
which are common.
So what you guys can do
instead of creating a parent class
and putting the common features
inside that parent class, you go for the
interfaces, you create an interface,
you do find the common methods in there,
and then
you make those child classes
implement those methods.
So if you do classes on and they are
related, you go with a parent class.
If two classes are not related
to each other, you go with an interface.
Can you show an example of rule
five and six?
And interface
cannot extend another interface or.
Yes, it's very simple.
For example, if we saw this
rule five, it's saying that
if it class instead of implementation,
if it says expense,
you will be getting an error.
This is a rule five, this is rule five.
With classes and interfaces,
we don't use the expense.
Whether we use the implements
to fight
and the next one was an interface
connection
to multiple interfaces or this one.
So I think in the example three would this
now in we go
this class is implementing
multiple interfaces.
Okay.
More than one.
And there was another example
I guess this one
in which one
interface, this interface syntax employed
was extending
from multiple interfaces.
So that's how the multiple
inheritance is allowed.
Can you guys tell me which shorter
time using right now?
So I am switching back and forth
between the files
and is your
paper model working now or you're still
misbehaving?
So it's control plus tab.
What are the differences
between externals and implements?
Can you explain one more time?
The only difference is that with classes
we use the extent.
With interfaces, we use implements.
When we need to use an interface,
we should be using the interfaces
when there are two unrelated classes
which have something in common.
Mine is working.
I am not using it like an eclipse.
Like an eclipse.
What do you mean?
Someone like an eclipse?
What?
Switching tabs? Yes.
All right. And
what else do you remember
about the interface?
You guys?
Well,
all variables are final.
Yes, Yes, we.
We have our ribbon in here.
All right,
You guys don't remember anything else?
I also don't remember anything else.
So let's discuss about the encapsulation
that.
So what?
What is encapsulation, guys
are doing that
encapsulation is using that variable
sphere
and board matters together
as a single unit.
Perfect.
So can you guys tell me where we are?
This encapsulation Also, you guys
have been doing this encapsulation
all the time.
Can you guys tell me how you guys
were doing encapsulation
all the time?
Main method
storing and giving
combined variable
and methods for a single content.
So what is it called in Java?
What is what is it called?
Endo It's called creating a class, right?
It's a class.
Class has the meters and
and variables, right?
So whenever we create a class,
we are actually using encapsulation,
right?
And more
refined implementation of this
encapsulation is when we make our fields
private and have getters and setters
for those fields. So
yes, yes,
you are right.
So be it.
Your fears
private and
make getter
start the methods to
access those fields.
So the last task in your
in last week
when I shared the task the last task
in the list of task was about
encapsulation. Right?
You guys created both email method
and then all the fields were private.
And then you guys said
the value of using those methods
and you guys tell me,
what are these getter setter methods?
Yes, getter and setter to access
and update
the value of their private.
So there are certain methods
we use to
access and update the value of a private.
Is there anything else
which is confusing you
or if you guys want me to ask
before we start the
project, ask
today we will do project of Yes.
You guys don't want to do them.
By the way.
How log the task were easy or hard.
We used encapsulation for control of class
attributes and method.
Yes, you are right.
Yes, we can do them.
Okay, My Highness, let me.
Let me do the doc
moment
in the
create
a new package.
Okay.
We did them all and push them
to create co-branded non fourth dimension
because you told us not to
group.
Okay, that's great.
So now you guys can compare this solution.
A reminder to go over the
specific steps in account so
again, I mean,
I was surprised why it has confused you.
So it was somewhere here.
Let me check with the class.
So it's a contest.
All right. We
So can you tell me now
what was confusing you?
Because it's really be
super clear in here.
But we are doing on line
five, we are creating an object.
Then I am calling this segment third,
who set the value
of this name field.
And then here I am
calling to get my third value.
Now, if you are not setting the value
first
and try to access the value,
you will be getting a null.
So it makes sense
to first certainly values
and then all the getter matters
to get P values.
This is what will last this confusing you
and we please do one more example of later
seconds.
Yes, we will be doing another example.
So this is how we
we should call it in the same sequence
in which I have written in here.
It was the two constructor.
This one.
Okay, so if you have multiple constructors
in a class,
that means who whoever has created
this class is giving you the flexibility
that you can create an object
without forcing
any data to the constructor.
Or if you know
about all the fields
that are present inside the class.
If you want to initialize all the fields
of this account class, then you should be
calling the other constructor.
So it depends on you
how you want to create an object,
passing all the values
or without putting all the values, almost
all the classes in Java, they will be
giving you this function flexibility.
Create an object by passing.
I think confused
because you tried to first get turned off
and then drive to set.
No certain is first O in here.
In here.
So in here the sequence does not matter.
I can buy etc.
First I can try to get the sequence
does not matter,
the sequence matters.
Funny, when we are calling,
the sequence matters
when we are inside the method.
Let me put this in sequence matters
when we are inside.
This method can mean method.
This method can be a construct.
This this can be a method.
Sets the sequence methods
when we are inside the method.
When we are inside a class,
I can define these fears at the bottom.
I can define this method in here.
In here the sequence does not matter.
We are now
well clear.
Is there anyone else
we have confused about anything? Yes.
We will be doing a lot of examples.
Don't worry about that
then if you are also confused.
I am a bit confused about all the Java
that we have learned
from the day one and now
only a little confused right.
Okay. Don't worry.
I am also confused
about so many things in Java. Yes.
Can we start over again?
It will take years to understand
all the concepts.
Okay.
It's not something that is learned over
our months or something like that.
So still I am looking for the answers
for some things.
I still don't know the answers.
I do a lot of research, read
a lot of blogs.
Why double guides
have created some things.
Many things.
Looks very strange to me, so I have to
do a lot of research and then I find it.
And so
you guys don't need to know everything to
to code.
If something is working,
you, you just don't. Bastard.
Copy paste time.
This is the first rule of program.
Do you guys know the first rule
of programing today?
So you would be first rule
of programing? No.
Oh my God.
You guys don't know the first rule
of being a rule.
So this is the first rule of programing.
If something is working,
don't let it in.
Whichever way someone has written
that code, whether it is
walking by legs or whatever.
Yes, don't try to use it.
And then
we can state
apply to p m position to any company.
You mean the Prime
Minister position? Yes.
You can be a prime Minister
after the need.
Never.
Project manager. Ah, I don't think so.
I think you should spend
like four six months in a company
first to check out how things work,
and then maybe
you can be a good product manager
or a project manager.
In my opinion, the parts of the company,
the programmers.
Okay,
so the first task was to create a shape
interface. I
And are you guys
also done uploading your videos?
Not yet.
I will do it during break.
I have one request for
for ladies it can you.
I don't know why you guys looked
so different in pictures.
And when I see you in your real videos,
literally I am unable to identify
many of you.
So can you please try to look see
even me?
I don't know what kind of magic
you guys use.
The power make of it. Yes.
Can you guys please?
We are widening one of our preventers.
Either
get good look, identify who they are.
So I was just kidding.
I hope you guys are.
Have introduce yourself
before the before the before you.
Start explaining.
I will indicate that we would like
to create an interface shape
with undefined methods as calculate area.
Right.
So I i during class
we are all tired and never look more
so I see
calculate area and calculate parameter
be two classes that we implement
functionality defining shape.
Okay.
So did you guys created the wide matters
or the matters
that that done something
so both of them are correct
if you guys created wide there
also good if you guys are
going to create a wide X also
so calculate area
and did you guys boss any parameters
if you want to see us the same way
we are on our profile pictures anyway.
Invite us to party, not to go to project.
Oh, I thought there are two ladies.
They are.
They never want to look bad in any picture
or in any video or anything like that.
I in my opinion,
I think the ladies, they are always they
they want to be on top of that in that
they'll always want to look good,
not in all cases,
especially when when they are presenting.
Not anymore.
My God. So.
So let's use a double.
Did you check Sebastian
profile picture? Yes.
Did. Oh, well, why?
I'm getting an error, guys.
Not roster for me. Sebastian,
this is not fair.
I love rosters, no implementation.
So inside the interface
I cannot have an instance
method with the body guard.
So I must remove that in here.
Right. So I should.
Okay.
Can I put private in here?
Guys, can I clear this method as private
or. I also used to have that roster,
but I don't know where it has gone off
without parameters also.
Okay.
No, without parameters
then how you guys will be able to pick.
So all the formula, like for example,
to calculate the area
parameter,
you need some kind of input, right?
So how you guys have passed that input,
if you guys didn't create these parameters
in here,
okay, I will request
more them to not eat it alone.
Invite me as well.
Did anyone have experience? Why?
They showed different pictures,
but if you meet them in person for coffee
or something with you
never being expected,
something like that.
All you have to do to the values
hard coding is
is never a good idea
then is always always.
Try to write genetic code
that can work with any type of input.
It will always be a better piece of code.
Okay, so can I put private in here, guys?
Can I. Can I make this method private?
Can I make it protected?
Can I make it public?
So yes, it is
already public.
Okay. It is already public.
So we're going to do that.
All right.
So calculate area and then define
calculate parameter as
the void, calculate parameter,
and then
double it.
So then create two classes
that will implement functionality
defined in shape interface.
Test your goal.
Okay, So oops,
let me create maybe a circle class.
So class
circle
which keyword
I should use to implement this interface.
Guys, the implements, right?
We don't use the extended keyword in here
and then I add I shape
and now I get error.
Right? Why?
I get error because I must implement
the methods.
Yeah. So I have pressed all plus enter
so that
are that so that intelligent
automatically right.
The bodies for me
entire the set of class. Okay
so to calculate the area of
of a circle
in the middle
what is the formula for the area.
But we need the radius
and it is by so now you guys have learned
about the classes.
Let me tell you
about some building classes
which will help you
solve your mathematical problem.
So there is this math class in Java
and there are so many
building matters
that are present inside this class.
So, for example, if you have to calculate
the power of something,
okay, if you want to build the absolute
if you want to calculate the cosines,
if you want to check out
the exact additions,
sine tangent,
the ceiling, copy sine, blah blah, blah,
cosmos hyperbolic.
And all of these matters
are useful matters.
They all present inside of this class.
So you guys can now start
using these classes.
Yeah, log in, log B, blah blah blah.
All that.
So in this class
we also have this value of pi, right?
And is
we can use it like this.
It's a static fear.
And can you guys tell me,
should this by feel,
should it be final
for it to be final or static
or what should be the type
and why it makes sense.
So if I hold down the control button
and if I click on this,
you guys will find out
it's a static and final key lie.
No, no, it's fine.
It's fine.
Because this value is
it is a constant value, right?
If we are referring
it is one of the constants.
So that's where you should be using
the final keyword with your variable.
The things which don't change.
You see, this
e is also a mathematical constant,
so it is also defined as final
Y because it should not be changed
otherwise.
Your calculations
they they made the result a wrong result.
So. So that's how we use
the final with the fields.
If something
stays
constant, we should be using find it.
Okay and
so so the idea of the of the circle was
by asking right.
So if my are
and what I can do, I can again
use the math class map not w
yeah I passed the value
and then the power of that value
like this.
Do you guys understand
what I am doing in here?
Do you guys understand this piece of code?
So okay,
then to calculate the parameter
again, the parameter
is to buy into radius, right?
So to
then buy
and then
oops, then the value
of it
like this. Right.
So we have to find some letters in here.
All right. And then we are
providing the implementation in here
and let's create a
sphere class as
that class
also implements the shape interface
and I am pressing art and enter
and implement map and selecting letters
that I want, but increment and then press.
Okay.
So the
the idea of a
maybe let's, let's,
let's say it's a length
so area of
the square is
then we can collect it
calculated in this length
and then the parameter
is for into any side.
Right.
So let's use
for into
length.
Okay.
So these are some of the examples
of these classes.
Okay.
Is it here you guys did the same way
or you guys used a different approach?
What kind of classes
you guys created squared circle
or something else?
I didn't use the math methods is fine.
It's fine. You
right.
So now during
the break,
I will give you five X from inner
and I want every one of you
to explore this math class.
Okay?
I want you to explore this class.
And there is one more assignment,
because now you guys are familiar
with all the concepts,
almost all the concepts,
all the keyword search on the Internet,
the top ten most widely used classes in
Java.
Okay.
And I want you to go through
those classes, explode those classes.
What kind of methods are prevalent
in those classes
in to try to have a look
inside those classes?
Okay. So this is how
this is one of the ways to solve the task.
One, okay, there
there can be many different grades.
Are you guys following me
or just watching me?
It's always good to follow
because the more practice you have with
Java, the more code you write
in, more better.
You will get
the at writing code.
So it's always good to follow.
Even if you have written
that piece of code
already, we do step by step.
Okay, so
if I say shape
circle is equal to new circle,
will I be able to call all the methods
from the circle class
I did the Yes, that is also correct.
For one.
That is also correct.
But in here inside these methods
we are passing different parameters.
But it's it's fun.
That's fun.
I think you love it.
You really love polymorphism. So
so will I be able to call
all the matters around circle? Yes.
Because they are only law matters.
And both of them, they are defined inside
this ship interface. So
I love it because I understand it better.
So circle dot calculator area.
So let me pass five
circle dot calculate parameters.
Let me pass again five.
And now if I execute this code.
Oh, here we go.
Let me use the polymorphism
here as well.
So now you guys see I see
a values of many decimal places.
So after the break, I want you to tell me
how can I limit this
to only two decimal places?
Or you can do it right now.
Search on the Google
how to limit the decimal
input only two decimal places
and tell me the method name.
And here is the E.
Here is the hint.
It is present inside math class.
Oh, I thought that.
But tell me, how can I do that?
I don't want to get
all of these decimal places.
I only want
maybe two of them.
Mad Dog Brown.
Okay,
so if I say
math, not
wrong. Mm.
This mismatched dog Brown.
If I do this
and if I execute
this code again, I only get
I only get
the integer part known decimal part
at all.
So this is your homework.
You guys have to find out how we can limit
the output
to only two decimal places.
We can use the format.
You mean when we are printing out
the output?
You guys want to use the format?
What if I want to use these
in further calculations?
I don't only want to print it,
but if please give me this output.
So it's a little tricky.
It's a little tricky,
but I hope you guys will be able to do it.
I don't want to print it, only
I want to use these calculations.
Maybe in
in some somewhere else in code.
Then I can not use this.
Use out.
So you guys have to find out
how we can do that only.
And that method should be generic.
If if I pass today, it should print three.
If I pass it to print four five like this.
No, no.
I don't want to use the print
or print alone.
I don't want to print it.
I want it to store inside a double.
And only two values
should be stored inside of that variable.
And this is your task.
So let me remove this.
Let the not wrong meters.
This is not working.
But my expectations
here.
Okay.
All right.
So this is
just another way to do
it, is using the polymorphism
in and then
we get the idea of this and learn
all of that.
Okay.
Are there any questions, guys,
from the staff?
What was the shortcut shortcut forward
in Mac?
I forgot if I have to limit it
to three decimal points.
Here we go.
The more and more generic method, right?
Double value in the decimal point
method or power of.
So actually inside Java
is. No, actually
there is no specific method
to achieve this directly.
So we have to use some kind of logic
to achieve this.
So here is the method from
emit.
So guys, tell me this is a static method.
Can I use this static method inside this
calculator area?
How did you bring line 16 frontier?
Oh, it's all done.
Enter alternate end so you extend option
and enter on Mac.
So tell me, can I use this
method inside this instance method
This is a start taking method
and I use it inside a static
mapper.
Yes or no
can I use?
I don't know.
I think I have repeated this
at least ten times.
You guys still don't know.
It's a very famous interview question.
Math guy.
This is a very famous interview question,
I think.
No, we can
and I do the other way
and I use an instance method inside
a static method
static with static non static
starting a non static. Yes.
You your right.
Here we go right now or I only see
output output two decimal places
if I want to see the output of four, maybe
four decimal places.
So I can also do that. Okay.
So that's the this is how your
this is how you guys
will be using your subject skills.
What was this question?
How can I make this matter?
Return to decimal quiet three decimal
points for the decimal fires?
I don't
have a method of change in my ISCA.
Well, it's not present in intelligent.
You have to write it on your own.
So I might send me this from the internet.
Here, Here.
If you guys want to have this textbook.
All right, So do we move to the next task?
Do you guys have any other questions?
I need one minute.
Okay.
Do you guys want me to go slow
or always add
as far as we're asked
if you have any questions
questions, go slow.
Otherwise you will be issued
a speed decode.
Can you repeat the question on static
and not static? No.
Do you guys want me to go to a mental
hospital?
I already repeated that at least 50 times.
It will be in in my dreams if I repeat it.
One word I can.
Yes, please.
So because static methods are fields,
they belong to the class.
They have same values
for all the instances of that class,
we can use them inside static
or instance spheres in certain instances
instance methods,
but because instance methods
or instance fear,
they can be defined and they can behave
different for each object.
And because static is something universal.
So that's why we can not use a,
an instance
field or instance method inside
a specific method
is how to learn the when
we really go
there first, then we get a break
where reasonable
do it
with the only subject
which was making me to leave
the class lost Java.
So to change decimal upper to apply it,
we have to enter line
50 onwards.
You have to define this method
and then you to call this method
on on the output for which
you want to change it to load two
decimal places or three or four or five.
So during the break
I will give you five extra minutes.
Your task is to search on the internet
before
ten most widely used Java classes
and tell me at least about three methods
that you guys have learned from these top
ten classes.
Tell me how you can use three methods.
So the name of the method
and a short description about that method
after the break.
Okay, if you guys
have understood how to use that method,
so three methods from any of both top
and Java classes
and you guys have to tell me
how to use that matter or why
that method is present in that class.
What is the of dark matter?
Okay.
Okay, perfect.
So let me give you 3045
and 50.
Okay?
And you guys have to tell me
about three matters,
okay?
And please remind me about the recording
and be back before
11 5050.
All right.
Bye bye.
Yes, stop.
And they didn't change.
So from this top ten classes,
you guys already know
about the string class
and then the object class, right?
The parent of all the classes
and the remaining six classes, we will be.
We will discuss these classes from today.
So today
we will discuss about the ArrayList.
Then this hash map,
then exceptions, the iterator.
So we will be discussing these classes.
So can you guys name Dementors
the three methods that you explored
from these classes?
Bring class methods.
Any methods from these three classes
that you guys looked
during the
but in the line
method, you guys have also used
your system class right
to set the properties of your driver
worker.
So I want you to explore these classes.
Okay.
If you guys haven't explored
this, it's fine,
but you guys
will be needing these classes,
so you guys should know
the methods to uppercase.
So we have already discussed these
methods. Right.
I want you to explore
three in those three methods,
which we haven't discussed.
Okay, So
break statement.
So let's solve the task two.
Or why? The way I.
I forget, I forgot about
I wanted to show you
about how to move your classes
from eclipse to intelligent.
So after we are done with this task so
remind me I will show you how to do that
and how to have multiple projects
in one window inside the intelligent
also previous reptiles disappeared.
No, no, that they didn't disappear.
Then you guys have to actually scroll down
to check those wrappers.
So let me show you.
They didn't disappear.
They see problem one, two,
three, four, five.
And then you have
131 3135.
So all of them, they are,
I mean, my own solutions.
Did you upload those solutions to canvas?
You mean they disappeared from it?
Okay,
They should not disappear, but
they are available here.
Oh, now
the solutions are available in here.
Clear solution.
So I will create the solutions
inside these proposals.
Maybe so.
How many of you don't see your wrappers?
Wrapper number one, two, three.
Can you guys check with the
Do you need to log out
and then log in again?
Or maybe clear the caches of cookies off
your browser? Yes.
You guys should see all of them.
You see, Abdul is working on 139.
Catrina is working Monday night, working
the one night, working.
Okay.
So they should be there should be
so in the in this
how long we will have an access to
videos class recording on Google die
after completion of.
The course are I think in the contract.
It is mentioned for about one month,
but I don't think so.
We remove the access to Google right?
Even after one month?
I don't think so.
We ever remove the access,
you will always be able to access
those you do, in my opinion.
But I have to check with Patreon.
Okay.
No, I think you can still access them.
I can. I think so. But I have to ask.
I have lost.
I'm not sure
what I heard six months or to get it all.
All right.
But to be honest,
at the end of this course,
you guys will not be having time to watch
those five
or 3 hours of videos
you guys will be needing.
Only you guys will have time
to go to the slides on
and you guys will be
you guys will be able to test your
let's say, for example,
if something is not clear,
you guys will be good enough
to find resource from YouTube or Google
because then you will be knowing all the
terminology is how everything works. So
you guys will be able
to find everything on
the Google as well.
Just the
initiative.
Don't worry,
don't worry, don't worry about it.
So we have to calculate the percentage
of marks obtained in three subjects,
each out of under my student A
and in four subjects each of our 100.
By student we create class marks
with an abstract method
of get percentage. So
let's create award get percentage
in Why I'm getting another guys
because now
I am not providing the body
to this method.
So first thing,
I should declare this method as abstract.
And if I have one abstract
method in my class,
that class must be declared
as abstract.
Yeah. Now the other goes with it.
So there will be three
which will be used by both these students.
So let's be clear.
Those fields
inside the parent class.
So A and B
class A and B, each
having a method with the same name
which returns
the percentage of the students.
So it should return the percentage, right?
So instead of Ward,
let me make it integer.
It is inherited by class
A and B each having a method
with the same name with returns
the person data student.
The constructor of the marks in three
subjects are parameters
and marks for and okay so
plus error
expense
marks.
And let me create a construct
as well in here to initialize B fields.
Okay. And how can I do it
quickly?
I can click on generate and then construct
and then select these three foods.
So now the constructors created
and now I should provide a matching
constructor
inside my child classes.
Yeah.
And I should provide the implementation
for this method.
Now all the arrows to go of it.
Just give me all.
Okay,
so this is class A,
then let's define
class B also extends from
marks
and I have near the constructor
and I have to implement
that test.
And this class B
actually it requires one more fig
because student has student visas for
subjects
and then
double
or four,
and then
they start cause four is equal to
or four.
And how can we calculate the percentage?
We can calculate the percentage by
adding the first one plus
of course, to plus
or three, and then
dividing that third
by three.
If we make it double.
Otherwise we have to cast it
linguistically,
because how you guys implement
these classes,
how do you guys do something different?
What effect would
the Now let me create a test for class
E Let me look
and just think you that change it to
fourth
A is equal to nil here.
Then I pass maybe 95, 96, 92
and I call it out
and get percentage.
So I want
you also use polymorphism in here
b b is equal to a new B
is if
I do two 9495
minus different days of trial, not
also fine, it's also fine.
But usually what we do,
we only pull those things
which are common in
both D classes inside of the parent class.
We only put those things
which are common in
both the classes.
So it's also good.
And then we can use
the polymorphism in here.
Let me copy the code from NYA.
Now if I execute this
either 94, 94 and 97
for marks more
percentage.
So you guys see
I can also use that same method that way.
That only gives me values
up to two decimal points.
So you guys will be needing it.
So I am planning off.
So try to create a class inside your
inside your project and
let me call it.
So in projects
you guys will be having a UTILS package
and inside of those packages,
those things
that you guys will be using frequently
and which are not present inside of Java,
you guys will be creating the matters
for example, map util
and then you guys will be defining
those common methods in there
and we put public static work in here.
Okay.
So this is how you guys
will be creating your own framework.
Okay. Yes.
So I can use
I can use this is how
the frameworks are derived.
So let's say, for example, I can
I can use that
Matt util
dot change in here as but
and then I need
to pass, let's say maybe two
and let me
rename it to
Rob. Yeah. So
now let me
and I need to gain.
So now
I only get after two decimal places.
So this is how the frameworks
are developed
and you guys will see in around two weeks
how to develop your own framework in test
and then give them the.
What do you share this code?
Yes, I will post this course
right after the class.
So from now on, guys, if you are repeating
something again and again,
make and method for that
and create a class
in meaningful having a meaningful name
and for that matter
as a static matter,
if method is not using the instance feels
and then put those matters in there,
where should we create the packet?
You you you can create your inside
your project like for example,
like neutral utils in here.
So this is how all the classes in
they are developed
as, as the time passed as the day
as the encountered different problem,
they kept on creating new methods.
Make it public
so you can execute from anywhere.
Yes, I made it public.
I did make it inside the project.
All right, guys,
are there any questions from this task?
Okay.
Should we move to the next task?
Right.
Just to clarify,
it might be a stupid question.
These util package public
so there is no public or private package.
The public and private teams,
they are used with classes, methods
and figures available in my project.
How others get accessible.
It depends on method.
I mean, yes, you have to project public
than anyone can use it.
Not sure if you mentioned it already,
but if a method has multiple parameters
like method
in, would it also serve Benetti? Yes.
Yes I am.
And you can also pass. And adding
it's in the overloading class I guess
if you guys want to revise
something.
But the our task in the tar
dos you guys had to create a registration
class
weird registration class
in which you would have variables
as username
and password that have an access scope
only within its own class.
So task three was about the car
was about the car.
Okay, let's do it after this.
This task
because one
if it don't work,
it's about encapsulation.
So those who were asking
about the encapsulation, this
this is where you should use
the encapsulation.
So create a registration class
in which you would have variables
as email, username and password
and that have an access scope within
that class only.
So guys, can you tell me
which access modified I should use
if I want to restrict the visibility
only to this class?
Okay.
But I we tried
private means only and only accessible.
And what should really default
access modifier
that I should try to use with my fear.
Well what is the preferred access
modifier?
Five feels
that I should always try to you.
It's the
oh, sorry for the interruption.
I don't know what went wrong.
Let me start the recording.
Yeah. Yes.
It was something related to the internet.
Can you guys hear me?
Actors
Hey, I like so private
and then
string
email, perfect private
string username.
Private
string
password.
Right? Yes.
Because the
Ukrainian they have the famous calls
and the Russians,
they have the famous hackers in the world.
And then now the Chinese,
they are also getting famous
after creating
an object of the class, you should be able
to call the methods and in each method
separately, password use to set the user
email, username and password.
Valid email consider to be only.
Oh. Did I miss something
only gmail once
valid user and password cannot be empty
and should be offline.
Okay.
So these are the requirements are
hackers are always working for government?
No. No.
They don't work for governments.
It was Yahoo and I did it. Okay.
Well, only Yahoo or Gmail,
but both the email and Yahoo!
Actually let me put Yahoo!
And is there anything else
that is different from the task
that I shared?
Okay, perfect. So
this is the registration class.
And now inside this registration class,
I have to set the values to this field.
But I have some requirements
before anyone can set the values.
So what should be my approach?
What should I do?
Guys, getters and setter methods right?
Then how can I quickly create them?
I can click on Generate getter
sector methods,
select all the features indexes right?
And now
I can write the rules.
I can write the rules for this method.
So only valid email is the Yahoo!
Email. Right.
So how can I check if if an email contains
is Yahoo
was M has a lot of organic rosters
contains right if
if email log contains
the Yahoo writes in
I should do one more thing.
I should say
a spring not to
so email,
not to lowercase
and then not contains Yahoo.
I check it in single method.
In single method.
Uh, and what?
What do you mean in single method?
Else?
Let's print out something.
Not a
nor a
valid email.
Oh, you mean signing method.
Okay, sign in method.
Or where is that signing method?
Do we have to clear defining method?
Was there some kind of requirement
for the sign in method
highest good.
Heis you are
password cannot be empty of any land.
Also valid password cannot continue user
name Can you send me complete requirement?
Maybe I don't have the complete
requirements.
Then.
So in getter setters we don't need
curly brackets after a failed.
No, no. If you want you can put.
But because I only have one line of code
after else.
If that's why I didn't put
much, let me follow the best practice
you guys should always put to be curly
brackets.
You guys should always.
You declare back later to use bugs.
So this is
this is the recommended approach.
So this is how we can set the value
to the email.
And then for the username
and password cannot be fast.
They can not be empty
and should be of length
larger than six.
And also valid
passwords can not be so in here, guys.
In here
I am trying to do the same thing
inside both the methods.
I want to check inside the both methods
that they cannot be empty.
Then they
they are larger than six characters. So
I see there is no sign in the requirements
like Miranda for the step.
I question how we know
conditions are need to pass and get
Rosetta
condition need to be passing a setter.
I am not putting any condition in
get rosetta now.
What do we mean?
So inside this charter I should say
valid username can not be empty
and should be of length
larger than six characters.
Right. So.
So if a user name dot
is empty
or user
name dot length is less than six,
so less than equal to six,
then we should printout
user cannot be
empty
or less than six
characters.
It's else
also valid passwords cannot continue
then else
we can set the username
to this value. Right.
But it's better to do it
at the rate of Yahoo!
No at that.
It will be common with everything
with Gmail, with Yahoo
will be the Hotmail entry.
It be everywhere, right?
Dot com will be everywhere.
But that's why we don't need this right
and dot com.
I can be anything
on so
guys in here Intel
is saying something intelligent
saying their tasker the condition username
is empty covered by subsequent condition
the introducing the task good.
If you are checking this condition,
you know what you are
already checking this condition
so you don't need this condition.
Do you want me to simplify this and I see
this remove unnecessary user name.
Dot is empty
and now it has simplified my if condition.
So when you guys will be writing complex
conditions intelligible simplified those
when you will be using wrong concepts,
it will be it will help you out.
Try to do that in eclipse and eclipse is
super is okay with everything.
You don't write anything
you will not complete.
How about nested if conditions
if for two conditions?
Yes, you can use the nested as well.
I mean user can in the name
where the Yahoo is.
I mean user can in its name
the Yahoo word.
Oh yes. Organ. Yes. Yes.
You are right.
Yes some someone can can do that as well.
You will be a good test of you.
You cover all the edges.
Guess this is.
Yes, you are right.
Let me prove that you
you will be a good test.
So you see Google test
and they cover all the cases.
Why can't they know?
As long as it does not give us error
we use if or
and instead conditions.
So like now I was asking
how do we know where
to implement
implementation setter or getter?
You should always
implement setter and getter.
You should
always implement a good translator.
Always try to make your fears
private, implement together and setter.
Never ever allow anyone
to set the values to your feels bad.
That's why it's the fourth pillar
of object oriented programing
they have given this
this concept a complete pillar.
It's a complete pillar in loops.
There is a reason Is a pillar.
If name should be less
greater than six required.
Or do we still need code for check,
empty or not? Yes.
Then you will be needing because are not
know if length is greater than six.
You is understood that this this
this name is not empty right?
If something is greater than having a
length greater than six, then it means the
third thing is not empty.
But it also depends on your condition.
Why is user
name door is empty and necessity?
Because even if so, even if this length
this username is empty is still
this condition will be true.
So this condition is covering
both the conditions.
You do not need to explicitly write
that condition.
Less code.
Better code.
And then for the password
I can also do the same.
If password
not length
is less than six,
we are going to be great developers,
hopefully inshallah
because you guys have me right. Why?
Why not developers? User
password
cannot be empty
or less than six characters
otherwise
we oops.
We have to
but we have to check another condition
in the in the
in the in the case of password so if
if my
password contains
username
then one more printout
password cannot
contain the username.
All right.
That sounded so not optimistic us
that you are not sure about us
if. No, no.
I am hundred percent
sure you guys are doing much better
as compared to batch then believe me,
I actually don't tell this to students
because then the students they get lazy.
So I always tell them
you guys are doing very bad.
We cannot both conditions in the first.
If we can, we can,
we can.
But then if any of the conditions is met.
AMR, the user will not be able
to find out easily
which condition are was not met.
That's
why he or she is getting that error.
So yes, you can put multiple conditions
in here as well.
But but it's always better to check
conditions separately
and then print out separate messages
for each of the conditions
so that whenever the other developers
or testers,
whenever they will be using your code,
they can instantly find out what is
what were what went wrong,
but not the best batch.
Right?
So best batch, it will depend
once you guys are done with your cucumber.
So we will be giving you projects
and you guys
will be working in beams and you guys
will be implementing your projects.
Then I can tell you if you are the best
or not, that that's have
the actual test is is there a difference
between elseif and else?
If yes, if you are.
And so in here,
if you are not using the brackets,
then we can only write one statement.
So the second approach
in which you are using these parentheses,
this one is the recommended one.
You should always use this one.
So we still have a chance.
Yes, you guys still have 3 to 4 weeks.
What two alone is?
Those projects will be in Java.
Definitely they will be in Java.
No they, they will be in Arabic.
Said if all those projects
they will be in Arabic.
I am changing my code completely,
but only if you will repeat
static question each class.
I am not repeating that question
before.
So are there any questions guys
ready to this task?
I am sure it is.
Still, if I ask that question again,
50% to 50% of
you will answer it wrong wrong.
NOI as a class,
you guys are doing great, by the way.
I'm not kidding. As a class,
you guys are doing great.
The responses that I get from you.
So other than Sorbonne
and Maryam is not available in here
and now they are the fastest, but they are
most of the time they are wrong.
So there is a dojo on this as well.
So in the interview,
the guy asked you What is your
best skill?
The the candidate says, I am very far,
very fast at the Met.
The interview say what is 2345 into 59?
The candidate replies, It's 23.
Then the interviewer said, It's
not even close.
So then then candidate says,
But it was fast, right?
So you guys are at least fast
you guys are responding fast.
It does not matter
if it's very fast in wrong answer
It gets.
So it's also a skill, right?
It's also a skill at least.
At least it gives encouragement to
the instructor that someone is responding.
Right.
The still that is good.
And those who condition is right,
they would not know the right answer
either if they are making it up.
So any close answer would do that.
Yes. Then we met interviewers.
They they usually have the answers
in front of them
when they are sitting in the interviews.
Are we fast or or we are fast?
Okay, so should we move to the next stop?
They look.
It was fast right?
Fast and furious. So.
Okay, let's move to the next oh,
it's already 1235 and we have to cover
some concepts as well.
Did you guys like the videos that I hear?
Yeah. So for at least make sense.
Sorry, I actually
I didn't want to post it earlier because
I thought there will be so many postings
related to selenium
and the video will be
but under something
under these code
and these, these announcements.
But then I forgot and forgot about that
and then that's why I didn't
posted.
So let's create a car class.
You always show us the simple way,
then show us the smarter way
like the edit in the earliest.
Yes, incremental step by step.
Not feeling too well.
Kids and I are sick.
May or may you feel better?
Give me
when you told me that you just don't need
all the words
like the best interest
in our selenium class yet
so create a class car
that would have the following four years
car price and color.
So let me put double
car rise
and by the way,
did you guys ask them before
making names on their names on him?
I don't know about the other instructors,
whether they like the names
on them or not.
I am totally fine with that.
But I ask these instructors
before you do that, it
is fine to
I have saved some work for them.
He already did mean for himself.
He said they like me
and when they are not about to.
And so create a car price, color
and method.
Calculate sales price
as long as
we have got the best in group instructors,
but not tons.
Did you guys create created
this method as void
or double, but you didn't ask us before
and bring those reports straight.
Yes, it for that is
a little
let's have a default implementation
in which we only
return the car price without anything.
And let me also create a constructor
generated constructor
and let's now create the
Apprize of God.
Create two subclasses.
So Don and Truck
will not be better
if we create this instead of this car.
If we say vehicle, class or trucks,
They also fall
under the car category.
They are also fallen into the category.
You are the master
personal truck is calling car vehicle.
What we have I think what he is better
let me change
to recap.
Oh, actually I'm not the master of cars
This in my opinion,
this is better.
The default implementation
then we have to create two classes
sedan and truck.
The truck class has filled as wait
and have its own implementation
of calculate cars.
Okay so
class and then so your don.
But we didn't use color for the folder
you guys didn't use color
in any of the features
you guys didn't
use the spirit.
Okay let's remove this
and unnecessary
and looking to move it from as well.
But so
it expands the rear he girl
he only in the start
suburban but you would want from me
you want me to retain that a little feel
you want me to remove that will
actually
let me read the all the requirements
So down track the class has filled
as we can has its own implementation
of the person
that are going to be in place.
So what?
We don't need that
right.
But don't use it's useless.
And in in this class
why I'm getting an guys
in this sedan class Why
why I'm getting another great
need matching constructor.
You need a matching
constructor as individual class and.
There is is there any additional field
in the in the sedan class?
Yes, it's the
length fill.
Right.
This door blend is equal
to length.
My messages long standing.
Okay.
And then I have to provide
my own implementation for the sedan class.
How can I do that?
What is the
override?
Right,
I, I can override that, calculate my.
And inside this method
I have the requirements.
If length is greater than 20,
then the item
car price should include 5% discount,
otherwise 10% discount.
So if land is greater than 20, then
5% discount. How?
How can I calculate the discount based
the return?
Only the
95% of the original price
ls return 90%.
And then we have
the class rock
extends
the magical
have to provide a matching constructor
should have its own fear
like this.
And in here I have.
I want to again override this
and the conditions are
if rate is more than 2000,
then return
price would include 10% discount.
Otherwise 20%.
So if we wait
is greater
than 2000.
Looking at the copied
word and 2090
Otherwise, if the
or you are using
the shorthand operator for the
if conditions.
I didn't teach you about that. Right.
Do you guys want to learn that
so yes that there's also good
I think there is
there must be an option in here
as well.
Oh, here we go.
Replace if else, with this shorthand
operator.
Oh, intelligent has old.
So this is called the shorthand operator
for the effects condition.
So if you are you guys see in your here
we are writing four lines
for to five lines
but these can be replaced
by the short hand operator
and how this works.
How did you do that?
Let me let me first explain it
and then I will tell you how to do that.
So in here we are checking
if it is greater than 2000.
And then this question mark,
then we are saying do this operation.
If this
condition is true, this condition
that we are mentioning before
this question, mark, if that condition
is true, execute this part.
Otherwise, we are specifying this column.
Specify this block, okay.
And return this value.
And this value will be returned
from this method. So
if you select this piece of code
and if you click on this button
icon, then you will see
this option that says replace
if else with question mark and short.
Then you make a command old one
and copy it and convert short
once a week and see both.
Oh yes, yes. Let me do that.
So this is the old one.
This is the new one I select.
Oops,
I select this
oops.
And then I click on this. Well,
let me
do double.
Oh, no, no.
I don't want this
to be the last line
or it is not fit.
Remove press is on
and then
let me
exclude boot.
No or not
extract my third one.
Yes, I
or it is not appearing now.
So do you guys.
I think you should select
the upper bracket as well.
No, I don't think so.
Okay, let's do it manually.
So let me comment this out
and then for me,
there must be something wrong
in my intelligence.
So and this is how we can specify this.
So let's for example,
I have a double variable.
Mine is same in walk
and on on on base on on
if I want to write an effect condition.
Okay.
So what I can do, the condition
that I was specifying in here,
I can copy this condition here
and then I need to write
a question mark like this
and then I specify this part
which I have to write inside
the if part.
Okay.
If the if condition is true,
whatever I want to do inside
that,
I write that line in here, then Colon,
and then I write the as part in there.
Now this if condition will be evaluated
and whatever
the results are,
they will be stored inside this.
Okay?
And if you are only returning this value,
you guys don't need to store it
in a variable.
You can directly return this as that.
So these results,
they are returned by this operator.
Okay.
And you can return it from the method
or you can store it inside a variable.
Can we add more else conditions?
No. I mean, yes, inside this
you can write.
And so, for example,
you can write in here,
you can write if then is greater than 20,
you can write like this.
And then you are the question mark.
And then you can
specify something like. This
in here.
If you if this is the case,
you want to maybe
assign you want to do maybe something
with the vehicle, otherwise
you want to do something else in here.
So yes, you can have the nested
if felt conditions as well like this.
Oops.
Yeah.
So now if this condition is true, first
this part will be executed.
If this condition is not true now,
I will check this condition.
If this is true, this part will be
executed or otherwise this part executed.
Okay.
But I don't suggest to write nested
if conditions this shorthand operator.
Without it, it will not be that readable.
It will be less less readable.
And there is one more thing.
Maybe not everyone in your team
can understand this, this syntax.
So we always try write
easy code that everyone understands
and the shorthand operator is also not
present in other programing languages,
but this is false condition.
It is present everywhere.
And those who don't understand
this, it's not for you.
This isn't hard to understand.
Just just curious.
If it is hard to understand.
It's all because of dummy. Okay?
You're not me at the he.
He asked me to do this
if when you nested the
if you lost me, that
that's why I didn't
want you to have nested conditions
in Java with cover.
It is hard, but we will see it somewhere.
It is good to know. Yes. Yes. It's
a very good part.
I actually used to teach this
to previous batches.
Who did the review for ifthe conditions?
Did I do
the review for effects conditions?
Maybe I should have shown you this
in that review class
as well,
because I always try to put
these kind of things in
in the review classes,
not in the actual classes anyway.
Let's let's move forward.
But we have spent too much time
on this task and everything.
So this is how we implement
the lexical class
and let's create a test for class.
No one showed it.
And what you will do review for next batch
is so
in you guys sending me the code for test
for class quickly
so that we can forward
to you.
You guys are going to see a lot of things
and then you guys will be
searching on Google.
What is what is meant by
so what is meant by question
Mark ten weeks
and then putting conditions.
You will be setting something like that
because you guys will not be knowing
the proper terminology on the Google maps.
I am coming to Turkey in my shared
love experience.
That's great.
Me too.
AM In June or July.
Okay.
And what if you are hosting a party then?
I am also planning to do with the turkey.
Can you scroll up the parent class?
Yes, Emre can.
Dammit.
Nice time to list all I heard on the news.
There is some kind of
thunderstorm
or I don't know, some kind of bad,
very bad weather in Turkey these days.
I heard the winds are
a 150 mph or more than that.
Let's have a jello party.
Well, what is going on in what
we're going on?
Interesting days.
Can you send me the desperate class?
It's a picture here.
There was a storm last two days,
but It all calmed down.
Oh, my God.
Again, Polymorphism.
Yeah.
So let me quickly add security.
Yeah, you see, we can use that
around the method again in here
if we want.
So let's do.
That's all right.
Are there other tasks
one more
seriously
the picture on all my
okay let's let's do that in the next class
I get as we will be spending
all the time on those products
and will not be learning anything new.
Remind me in the next class.
I will do that in the next clip.
So let's have a break
and I'm giving you a 20 minute break
because I want you to watch those videos.
I think they are hardly 5 to 6 minutes.
Where do you.
Okay.
That's what I said
when you centered in the first time
you do, you go to.
No, actually, I am running out of time
and I have to teach the class as well.
So that's why otherwise I always love
coding.
So please be back by 123
and watch those videos guys, please.
And reminding me about the recording.
All right, so let me close
these classes.
Are we going to repeat ArrayList?
Did you guys do you guys know about the.
Did I teach you about the list?
No, of course.
We will be learning about the ArrayList.
We not be repeating,
but it's
all right.
So today we will be starting the
collections framework.
And before I teach you
about the collection, some framework.
Nice.
Tell me if I have to score a single value
in Java, what should I use?
If I have to store a single value?
It can be a string.
It can be an integer double.
I use variables. All right.
So let's say for example,
if I have to store the name, I can use
a variable right like this.
But if I have to, all the names
of the students
that are present in this class,
will it be
a good idea to use variables
or should I use something else?
So if I have to store multiple
names, it's not a good idea.
Not a good idea to use the variables
because each time
I have to come up with a different name
and essentially
I am doing I am always storing the names
of these students, right?
So in that case, I should be going
with adding right
like this.
So can you guys tell me?
Okay, so the add ins, they look good,
but there are some issues
as well with the ads.
Can you guys me the issues with the ads,
maybe there are some limitations
or maybe you guys
can point out
some deficiencies in the ads.
Can I can I store
single type?
You need the index
number to print.
So is it
is it a limitation that we have to
know the index to print out?
Here we go.
They are fixed in size, right?
So for this size of this.
So that index is also a problem,
but we will discuss that later.
Mohammad was mentioning this in the index.
So if I try
to store
a new element
inside this
area, will I
be able to do that? Guys
know if I execute the score,
I will be getting an exception
because areas
it is are fixed in size.
Okay.
Well, what are the other limitations
that you guys see
to change an area?
You have to do it manually.
What do you mean by change?
And at a moment
to remove
or add?
So, for example,
if so, the more limitations are
if I have a certain element
from this area,
what I have to do, guys,
if I have a certain element
from this area,
so either I should know the index
or I have to write a far
look to search element
from this area right.
And what if
I want to replace an element
again?
First I have to search that element,
then I have to find that element out,
and then I have to replace that element.
And imagine this, guys.
Imagine you are an event planner.
So the ad is they are fixed in size.
If let's say you are expecting 200 guests
and if there are
210 guests shows up,
then you will be having an issue.
Let's say you arrange only for 200 guests,
but now there are 210 people right?
So you will be having an issue
or if you arrange for 200 people
and there are only 100
people are in the party,
so the 100 spaces they will be visited.
So for example, if you are using AD is
and you are declaring the so let's say you
don't know about decides in advance and
you declare the
size of the array, let's say maybe 1000,
but in actual
you are only using maybe, let's say
100 fields or 200 fields,
those 800 fields, they will be wasted.
The memory will be wasted
for those fields.
On the other hand, if you are, let's say,
having a size of 500 elements
inside an area and now you have to store
seven or 800, now you cannot do that.
You because the ad is they are full
and feared that a fixed in size.
So because of these major issues
and there is there is this third issue.
There are no matters building meters
already written methods that you guys
can use for example to certain element
or to insert something in between
or to remove an element
from a certain location
and this kind of thing. So
due to these
limitations, Java guys have created
something
known as ADD Alias and it's present
inside the collection framework.
And those really is
before we discussed the ArrayList
or the collection frame.
But can you repeat line
16, Line 16 in here,
the NCAI is lost two loops
and I was trying to store a third element
in here then.
That's why I got the error, the
common practice of our culture.
So what I can do
instead of using ADD is
I can have something
known as add a list
and this is how we declare the ADD.
So it's a class.
So I can say ArrayList and I use.
Have you guys seen these angle brackets
before?
Okay, it
so these are called a genetics.
These are called genetics.
And in this collection
framework, it uses genetics heavily.
This would be
this is also called a diamond operator.
So this is a diamond operator.
So for example, with the added
we specify the data type, the type of data
that we will be sporting in the edit,
we specify it before, before
name of the addy.
But in ArrayList
we have to specify this data
type inside this diamond operator,
and then
we give the name to our ArrayList.
Okay, maybe let's call it
list of names.
Okay. Diamond.
Now you get to the girls.
And then again, same way
we use the new keyword,
and then we will write
the name of the class in here.
Okay?
So same as if I am creating the object
of this ArrayList class.
But new thing in here are these
diamond operators.
Okay, so
this is how we create an error list.
And now why we are discussing this.
Is this at least
it has this property that it can grow
and it can shrink its size at
if you insert and element,
if you keep on inserting the elements
inside this,
at least it will keep on increasing your.
If you remove some elements,
it will automatically decrease your size.
And you guys don't have to do any of this.
It is all automatic.
So for example, I am not specifying
any size in here inside this list.
Okay. But
once I so
and if right now, if I print out the size
of this edit list,
if I print out the size right now
the size of zero.
Okay, let me put it. So
right now this size is zero.
Yeah, size is zero.
But as soon as I insert
an element
and this is how we insert the elements,
at least as soon as we use this, add
the matter because this is the class,
it does not have those square brackets,
it has meters.
So we have to call methods.
So we call this add method.
If we have to add any element in here.
And as soon as we
in certain element
and check the size of this analyst.
Now you guys will see
now the size will increase to one
you see
the size has been increased to one.
And if you add more elements
like for example,
if I add three elements, so now
the size will automatically be change
2 to 3.
Okay,
two sides has been taken
and there are other methods as well.
So let's say, for example,
if you want to remove something,
okay,
so if I remove something,
I need to call this remove matter.
And after that, if I print out this size
besides has been shrink automatically.
So if you keep on adding the elements
it will keep on increasing your size.
If you removing some
if you want to remove some elements,
you also have this flexibility.
You call the remove method.
That element is removed
and the size is shrink again.
Is not it great guys?
So does it mean that the ADD is
they are useless
or there is some kind of
benefit of the add
is as well?
What do you think?
Does it mean they
add if they are useless and
I think
no on the arrays they are not useless.
The areas they are super, super fast
and the ADD is they occupy
very less memory inside your computer.
If you are sure about something,
if you are sure about the size
of something, always always use ADD is
they will occupy very less memory
and they will be
super super fast
in all the games and intensive works.
Like if you have to implement complex
people, they always prefer arrays,
they always prefer at and and if you guys
all down your controller
and click on this class name
and use your structure window
so you guys will see
inside the fields
internally
the array list
it also uses eddies
so all the logic to increase
and decrease the size
it the ArrayList they are still using.
The ADD is internally,
but These Java guys,
they have written all that knowledge,
all that code to achieve this shrinkage
and this growing of size and of these add
the method removal method.
But internally they are also using arrays.
So the ADD is they are based,
they are primitives.
Everything in Java is
built on top of that.
They, they are not useless in gaming,
in algorithms wherever you will be needing
performance and less memory,
you will always be using the arrays.
Okay.
But as a tester
and as a programmer, because these days
computers are super, super fast.
So 90% of the time
you guys will be using endless.
Can we use a red list instead at eight
if we know the exact site is yes.
So in at least as well,
you can pass the size in here.
So if you know the size.
So what is happening in here?
What is happening internally?
So let me tell you what is happening
internally when you guys so
there is a default size in the edit list
when you guys don't specify any in here.
So Java is creating an array internally,
let's say, of size ten.
When you call this add the method.
This element is added here.
The next element is added here.
Add here, here, here.
Once the ArrayList is full
in new, add a list of bigger
size is created internally
and all the data
from the previous list is copied
to this new list
in here, element by element.
And then new list is used once.
The size of this list is also used
completely,
even a bigger add of bigger size
will be declared
and all the data will be copied in here.
When you delete an element,
the elements will be removed
at a certain point.
But once the size of the once,
once you have removed
half of the elements again
and new array will be declared
and the remaining element
will be copied in here.
So there is a lot of computation left.
There is a lot of code
that is going behind the scenes
to achieve this flexibility,
this automatic shrinkage.
You see this ensure capacity, internal
size plus one, and then you see this.
This is internally still
we are using element that our size
plus plus and then we are splitting
this element in here and then return true.
So still internally they are areas
but there is this ensure capacity method
which is doing these calculations,
which is checking
if mini capacity is less than minus size.
Then you see this group method.
It is increasing this size it is checking
if the capacity is full,
then grow this size.
If you guys check this group method,
you see new capacity all capacity
plus all the capacity greater than one
then mean capacity,
max size and new capacity, huge capacity.
All of these could it is achieving that
automatic growing and shrinking mechanism.
So if you guys are interested in learning
how Java guys are achieving all of this
shrinking and
a growing thing,
you guys can look inside these methods.
Can we say that
if we give size to ArrayList,
this is another way to declare ArrayList
as array, which have fit size?
No, we cannot say that.
But if you initially give decide.
So if
let me show you.
So if you go inside this class.
So there is this default capacity element
that are in here.
So there is this default capacity in here,
which is in Java,
which is in this,
and this implementation is ten,
which means after each had been elements
the size of a new array will be created
once you insert the ten elements and new
array will be created, those ten elements
will be copied to the new, bigger
add A and that's
how it will keep on increasing the size.
But if you specify so if you specify,
decide internally what will happen.
Let's say you know that least at least
there will be 2000 elements.
So Java will
not declare this initial at all size,
then it will declare
that initial size of thousand
and then once that thousand locations
are filled,
then a new add will be declared.
So you guys will be saving
a lot of computation
if you know the size before hand.
Otherwise, after each ten element,
the Java will be growing,
the size it will be increasing.
Besides declaring new array, copying
all the elements to the new elements,
and there will be a lot of computations.
But if you specify the size
initially,
then you are saving a lot of computations.
Is is this being used for Instagram
followers since you're so flexible?
Yes. All of these real life applications,
they are built using ArrayList
or something like that.
Does it make sense to guys
that if you initially give the size,
how you can save
a lot of computations, but
so it's always, always a good practice
to specify the initial size
when you are declaring an array
so that you guys can save a lot of code.
And if I show you the removal method,
you that there are
so many things
that are going behind the scene.
Force remove index index is equal
to equal to null.
And if we go inside the false,
when will we check?
All the computations for
this size are going in?
Then you see this add a copy.
So after each removal we are copying
the old saw all the elements.
We are kind of shifting
all the elements and.
We are doing a lot of computations.
Okay, So
yes, they are flexible.
Yes, we have building methods, achieve
many things,
but they should be used with the gear.
Okay.
They should be used with gear.
So this is the
start of the collections framework.
So this ArrayList is the first class
that we will be learning.
But before we learn that.
So is the complete collections framework.
So we will be learning.
I want to cry every time you open
those methods and calls.
Don't worry, you guys will be comfortable
with those course.
So we will be learning
about all of these classes
except for you.
Okay, We will be not learning about
this class
and we will be learning rational.
Let's say we put initial size ten,
but input, let's say eight names.
It still runs,
does not need as much computer
part as if we didn't
put the initial size. Yes.
So if you all already know
that there will be eight elements
specified, it still it can grow.
If you add more elements
still it will increase your size
and it can decrease this side as well.
But you are saving a lot of computation
now to learn this complete.
And they are not all the classes.
I think there are more than 100 classes
inside the collection
framework,
but we will be learning only these.
So to use this collections
framework to use
all the classes, to use everything
that is present inside of this framework,
we need to learn about the wrapper
classes.
Okay, so what are wrapper classes and why
we need them?
So you guys have learned
about the primitives, right?
So you guys started from byte
and then are
embedded in beta
and those were
the good old days.
Then float.
Oh, I forget about the long
and then about the boolean, but
writable
and then about the right.
So these are the primitive data types.
Now, the benefit of using these primitive
data types is that they occupy
less memory
inside your computer, inside your RAM.
But the downside of these primitives is
there are no building methods
present inside of these primitives.
So let's say, for example, if I have to
convert
their safe, I have to I have a string then
and I want to convert it to an integer.
Are there any present inside
these primitive primitives
to convert this number? No.
So these wrapper classes,
they are not primitives.
For each wrapper.
Java guides have created wrapper classes
and they.
They have the same names
almost always have the same names.
So for byte two, we have our object type.
We have a class. So this is not a class.
This might is not a class, but this B
with capital beat is the class actually.
And if you hold down your control button
and if you click on that bite,
you guys will see that it's the class
that is extending number,
implementing compatible.
There is this
constraint
inside this class that tells you
what is the minimum value
that you can store,
what is the maximum value
that you guys can store?
And then there are some matters
like value of method pass
by method,
overloaded methods, value of the code.
So there are so many methods.
Why it's a class because of capital B no.
Yes. Classes. They have capitals.
They have their first letters
as capitals, but
they are
separately created classes
for each primitive
Java guys have created a class Y classes
because collections framework
does not work
with the primitive data types.
It requires a class type.
So for example, in the previous example,
if instead of starting
if I tried to specify integer
so it will say die
argument cannot be of primitive type.
That means yes, the collections.
They are very powerful,
but we cannot use primitive
data types with these collections
inside these angle brackets.
We cannot use any of the primitive types
that we learned before.
So to this issue,
for each primitive type,
Java guys created a class by an object
or type
so far by it, we have a bite class
far short.
Is it like because
there are no hidden methods in those?
Yes, I show you are right
for and we have integer
instead of capital. I
then for long we have long
for float.
We have a float with capital F
or double.
We have a double with capital D
for boolean
we have a boolean with capital B
and for Char
we have that character.
So for each primitive type
because because collections framework
does not work with primitive types,
we have a class type, we have a class.
Java guys have created a class
like this.
And what is the benefit of these classes?
Now let's say, for example,
I want to convert
this number string to an integer so
there is a building
method available
inside the integer class to do that.
So for example, if I have an integer
number,
I can say integer dot
boss in and if I pass
number declared,
I can use these building methods.
So this is just one of the examples.
I can use this passing method
to convert this spring to a number.
And for all the primitives
I have this method
to convert a number from one letter type
to another data type.
I have methods for in all the classes to
convert a bite into a corresponding type.
So for example,
if I show you the integer class.
So we have these fields
and we also don't have those fields guys
inside the primitives.
We don't even have those fields
right in here.
We have this information that we what
is the minimum value that we can store?
You guys remember, I used this min value
and max value fields in your group task
when I showed you the solution,
I use these fields, right?
So they are,
they were coming from this integer class.
And then there is this map
to convert these integers
from other data types.
In here there are those string matters.
For example, if you want to convert
a number to a string, so you can also
that as well.
So unsigned, unsigned, and
I can convert it to other number systems.
So how many of you know
about the hexadecimal system?
Hexadecimal system of numbers?
Do you guys know
about the hexadecimal numbers
or only
the MIRNAS?
Okay. No, no issues.
So they are dated in most the time.
You guys must have seen the numbers
that all the numbers that are represented.
I don't know how it is in English.
So you guys know that is awful.
But the numbers that you guys are
specifying, they are octal write them mir.
They are octal, not hexadecimal.
Hexadecimal.
They have 16 unique characters
to represent the numbers.
They are used in computers a lot
and they are binary numbers
which only have two characters
like zero and one to represent
all the calculations in this world.
So different systems,
they use different numbers systems,
but in real life
you guys must have only seen the numbers.
029 right?
We represent all the
all the counts and everything
using those
unique nine and ten characters
is 029 byte.
But there are other number
systems as well.
And if you want to convert
a decimal number to a hexadecimal
or if you want to perform
a conversion between these,
then there are methods for that as well.
You see two octal, two heads
supporting the binary.
But what you guys
don't need to worry about.
So there, there are so many things
which Java guys have already done
to perform these calculations,
to convert between different numbers
systems,
to achieve many other different tasks
and bills.
All of those matters, they are present
inside these wrapper classes
and that's the reason why collections
framework uses
these wrapper types
Instead of putting with this primitive.
They don't have any fear,
they don't have methods.
Then the collection framework
does not work with the primitives.
So that's why we
have the wrapper classes and
there is a concept.
So now you guys know that. So
guys, what if I have to?
What if I have to convert this, buy
to this, this, this class type?
Right. They are classes,
They are putting motives.
I cannot do that. Right.
I cannot store a primitive in an object
type variable.
Right.
So for example, if I have a string class
or car class or dog class,
can I store other objects
inside those variables?
I can only store the objects of that type.
Right?
So for example, if I have a car class,
I can store objects of car inside there.
So. So what if I need a
what if I need about if I have my data
in primitives that I have,
I have to use collections framework.
Does it mean that every time
I have to use a collection framework,
I have to convert my data
to these classes?
So technically, technically,
if we should be converting these types to
this one right, because they are classes
and they are primitives.
So but so Java guys realized this, guys
realize this and a day
they made our life easier.
Okay. They assert that. Hey, hey guys.
If you are working with primitives
and you want to use a collection
framework, you guys don't have to convert
your primitives to these.
Are these non primitives.
What you guys can instead use is a concept
of boxing and unboxing.
So Java guys allowed us
to convert this type
to this byte
with the of boxing and boxing.
So for example, if I have a bar, it
looks like me using if I have an interior
number,
if I have a primitive number to set, then
and now
I want to convert it to a class type,
then I can simply do this.
I can see primitive is, equal
to class number.
I don't have to call any methods.
I don't have to convert anything.
I don't need to do anything.
All the convergence internally
will be happened automatically.
And I can
I can directly assign these numbers
to the other types.
Okay.
And I can start using them
inside collections for them.
So I still got them right.
So if you have a primitive
and you have a non primitive
corresponding non primitive, remember
I cannot do that.
I cannot store in beta inside,
but this is not possible.
So if I have this then I can
easily convert it to a class number
and I can convert it back as well.
So I can say primitive
is equal to
plus number.
Okay, so
this is called auto boxing and boxing.
What we are doing, we are picking it
primitive and we are putting
that primitive in the box inside
the object of the corresponding type.
So in here
I am picking this primitive bin.
So let me give you a more example.
One more example.
So technically, when we have to, yes,
the results will be
same when we have to, let's say, create
an object.
This is what we do, right?
We write the name of the class variable
name, new keyword, and then we
call the constructor. So
Bastian, this is not
work, but believe me, right now
I am starving.
And the first thing that will do
after this, this class
I like this.
And I was planning
of having a zinger burger.
So class number is a variable.
It is this class
and this is an object with the
you may be already answer this question,
but what the purpose of this?
Oh, because primitives don't work
with the collections framework
and now we are learning the collection
framework.
We have to learn the wrapper
classes as well because
collection framework
only work with the wrapper classes.
These are called by the wrapper classes,
object types, class types
dominate it.
Clear.
I see. Sebastian.
Why you have a row or why your weight
is that much?
It's.
Is this manipulation
only available to enable wrapper classes?
Can we make our own class
that would retain
invariant value
when it's instance is called?
Instead of making a method like get value?
No assignment?
I don't think so.
You can do it with your classes.
It's only possible
with the wrapper classes.
Building classes.
Yeah.
So we converted the variable
to the object of the class,
and that is automatic.
So this, this is how we create the object
of a class,
right.
But Java guys said that.
Hey, good. Hey, guys.
Hey, Batch.
Then you guys can.
You guys do not need to do extra
again.
I don't understand
what is the use of this?
The use of this is that
better level?
We cannot use primitives
we cannot use integer long short
inside the collections frame.
But we can only use these object types.
Inside of that use are the best that
okay.
Maybe because now
because of Sebastian
I was already storing and now
he is.
So that's why
we have to learn these wrapper classes.
And how do I think I am one of those?
Like for example, if the food in my home,
it is an art of my I will never eat it.
I will just go to bed
without eating that big.
But if even if I have just had my dinner
or breakfast
or lunch or whatever,
I see something that is off my drive.
I can again need the act
as a good texture
and a friend to make nice dinner for you.
You do that a
So let me show you
what kind of dignity that I am
expecting from our thing.
This is what I will be getting from
a surely.
First you see, you
see does not know how to cook.
So I am preparing myself mentally.
Looks like I wouldn't think that
you guys
are different.
Okay, so what Java guys have done for us,
they have given us this flexibility
that if I have
a primitive in here and a primitive
instead of doing this number dot
input value.
So instead of why this is
because it's
unnecessary, it's unnecessary.
Java guys have already done this for us.
So intelligence
saying you guys don't have to do that.
You guys want me to end this class
right now and eat something
first?
Let's
to call for an ice cream.
So this is how we declare an object,
right?
If there is a class
and if I have to clear the object,
that class, we do this like, Oh,
we cannot be object like this.
Right?
Nice. But
in Java, guys, what Java guys have done
Guys said that.
Hey, guys, you can simply.
You guys remember the string class?
In string class,
we we store the value directly.
We're inside the double core.
We also don't create the
we also don't use that new keyword
and then call the constructor and then
pass the value first things as that.
So those classes, which are a widely
in Java, they have created this shortcut.
So for example, I can
I can directly do this.
I don't need this new,
I don't need this integer.
This if I can directly
an inside in here,
the results will be same.
The results will be same.
So this
this is called boxing.
Will being a
primitive
inside
a wrapper.
This is called boxing.
Okay. This is the long, long way. Okay.
It is not recommended way.
But what?
This is how you guys will be doing
if you are creating your own classes
assignment, this is what you have to do
for your own classes.
But Java guys have given this shortcut
that instead of writing new and an integer
and all that,
you guys can use something called auto
in boxing.
Do you guys see
in here we are using a shortcut.
We don't have to buy a new and indeed,
every time
we have to store a primitive inside
inside a box which
is off type.
So this is called boxing.
We're being a primitive
inside the wrapper.
If we are using this shortcut,
it is called auto Bolt auto in boxing.
If we are using the longer way
it is called boxing,
and when we have to get back
the primitive from that object type,
it is called on boxing
and it is also possible which shorter we.
So we just can assign this number directly
instead of writing number
than dot in the value.
Instead of calling this method,
we can do the shorter curly
and if we are doing it the shorter way,
it is called auto in boxing.
But on boxing,
can you please repeat line 14
is on boxing, right? We are
extracting the
value from an integer, which is an object.
I beg a primitive type.
So putting a primitive inside
the object type boxing.
If we are using the longer
weights called boxing, if we are using the
it is called octagon boxing,
and once we have to get back
the primitive from that box,
then it is called unboxing.
Okay Or if we are using the shorter way
it is called Octagon Boxing Charter.
We here is line nine necessity.
No, I just wanted to show you
that we can convert
between these variables
by just assigning them to each other.
This is not possible for ordinary
Java classes or other classes,
but this is possible for wrapper
classes and primitives
and the the only thing that I want to show
Can you
guys now explain what is boxing in one?
So it's a very famous interview question.
What is our goal in boxing
and what is boxing?
Can you guys now explain this?
Let's go boxing after this class.
Okay, perfect.
Primitive sporting object is boxing
and getting back that primitive is
unboxing their suit.
So let me go to the titty boxing,
putting primitive inside wrapper longer.
Why we're not welcome and yes, longer.
Wait Not not needed. Not recommended.
Yes, the wrapper classes
provide a way to use primitive data types.
So let me repeat wrapper classes,
but a wide array to use primitive
that are types
like for example integer boolean APC as
okay, they can now have matters.
You can call the construct,
you can create the object and all that
that you can do would be classes
when we put primitive inside
the wrapper is boxing and putting it
and getting it back to primitive is on
boxing chart cards are auto boxing
and boxing. Yes. And have
so wrapper classes in Java provides.
They are.
And they are called the wrapper classes.
Okay.
The object types for primitive
they are called
the wrapper class in provides
the mechanism
to convert the primitive
into object and object into primitive.
So we can do both.
We can go both load sides
from primitive to non primitive
wrapper type
and from wrapper type to primitive type.
Sometime We must use the wrapper classes,
for example,
when working with collections object.
So that's why we are learning it.
Sometimes We must use
the wrapper classes for example,
when working with collections slide
because collections
they don't work with primitives
such as at least we are putting.
The two types cannot be lost
and that's why we need these primitives.
And in these wrappers clear one
when we need the
why we are learning about the wrappers.
Each java primitive has a corresponding
wrapper class so far.
Boolean
we have boolean with capital B bar byte.
We have a byte with the capital and offer
all these.
ArrayList is the only collection object
we covered, correct?
Yes, ma'am.
But what we have have not covered that.
I will teaching you
about all the metadata, brethren.
How can you have them and all that?
So I have just just give you
a glimpse of the in this class.
We have not covered that.
So this is just a kind of it's
wrong in in this jar.
It should be correct. It's not just
Rasta looks good.
So boxing refers to convert
being a primitive value
in into responding to wrapper object.
This is what we call as boxing.
When a wrapper object is unwrapped
into primitive value,
then it is called unboxing simple, right?
So converting this,
this is the longer way putting wrapping
new keyword, dropping
the name of the class, and then passing
that value inside the constructor
This is the sharper way
in here.
So this is the longer we in,
this is the factory.
And then on when unboxing,
this is the longer way
and then this is the shorter.
So that that that was all about it
upper classes.
So now let's discuss about the collection
framework.
Collection framework in general provides
an architecture
to store and manipulate the group objects.
This storage part was there with the edit
as well, but the manipulation part,
we had to write that part always
whenever we had to do something
that represented as a single unit.
This framework has several
useful classes which have tons of useful,
which then makes it programmers
life task super super easy.
Okay,
I will teach you about those matters.
Java Collection Framework is a collection
of interfaces and classes
which help in supporting
processing your data efficiently.
Large amounts of data collections are used
almost in every programing language.
The most frequently used for
the best automation are list set map.
But the map is not a collection,
but it is used heavily with collection.
So this is just a picture
of all the classes
and interfaces that we will be learning.
And these are the commonly used methods.
And you guys have learned about the and
let's now learn about more
methods
from this collection stream.
Let's
go let's say we
we want to instead of add,
we want to have that flexibility
and now we are calling the
ArrayList class.
We are using the ArrayList.
So these are called
this is called Diamond Operator.
And inside here I specify in here, guys,
I specify the data type.
If I have the store integer,
then I writing well, while why
I am getting an out of
well, I'm
getting an error on print,
I must specify integer right
then I will not be having any issues
so I can say numbers dot and
then oops, numbers
don't add on the right
and then I can print out all the numbers.
And in here we also don't need any loop
or something like that to print that.
I can just write
the name of this ArrayList
and it will be printed on the console.
See then in complete,
these are the elements inside my it.
Okay.
If I have to store, maybe
booleans
I specify boolean
and then I can specify
who was
any value that I like
and then I can print to solve
who falls who in the clear days.
Are you guys done typing the score?
Super, super easy right?
Is making an ArrayList
without data type bad practice?
Yes, it's a bad practice. Simon.
I will teach you why it's about practice.
So first thing.
So let's say
that I am not specifying
this the data type in here.
I can also do that. Okay.
And now what I can do,
I can add maybe
Simon in here.
I add maybe. Oops
and number in here.
I can add, maybe this was
so this is how the areas were before
Java file.
This diamond operator was introduced
in Java Phi
before that I could have saved
any value inside my editor.
This is how programmers
used to write the pronouns.
But the issue with this approach is that
so? Let's say, for example,
I am writing a loop
ArrayList here.
If it were to add a ArrayList.
So now the issue with these approaches
that I have to keep track
of all the elements
that I am storing inside this list.
So for example, I know
that the first element is of type string.
So what I can do,
I can convert it back
to a string
and then maybe if I want to call
some methods from the string class,
like for example, and I can do that,
but can I do that with the number as well?
Do I have a length
method on the number as well?
So what will happen?
And so you are not getting any attacks
on compile time.
What will
you will get an error on runtime.
So Java will try to convert this
then to a string
and then I will try to gossip
to this twisting.
You will be getting an error at runtime.
Now think about this and tell me guys,
are the errors on
runtime better
or the add on compile time better?
Which type of items are better?
Compile time or runtime
compile time at outside of Baghdad? Why?
Because the running times add out
what happens when the user
they are already using the app
and if you have to fix those runtime
errors, there is a longer way
that you have to go through.
You have to go through development
and then testing staging production
and then if you are getting a compile time
error and the developers,
they can fix it right away.
So what Java guys did,
they realized that programmers were making
so many mistakes using this approach
because they have to
keep track of the elements
and there are no restriction.
Anyone could add any type of element.
So they introduced this diamond operator
and now once the
diamond operator is there,
if now you try to add a in here,
you will get an edit right away
at compile time.
Okay.
You will get the error right away.
Yes. Mean,
it means you filled out your testing.
So that's why these that
this diamond operator
was introduced in here.
There was no restriction.
Anyone can add anything and you will be
facing a lot of errors at runtime.
Imagine
a list is passed through your method
and you have to write the logic
for that matter.
So someone is passing
some data to your method.
You have to write a logic for that.
You have to write a lot of checks
if you have to use any building
method for that class.
So that's
why type safety is there in Java.
That's why Java is called a strongly
DI programing language,
because all the variables
for all the variables you do,
you know the data type, you know what
you can do, you know what you can do.
If you have to do something extra,
you convert it and you do it.
You you don't program blindly.
Or this is
there is another way of saying this that
your programs, they are
independent of the of the type of data
that that is passed.
So it's very important
if your program is failing
on certain types of data, you you
you are a bad programmer.
You should always cater
for these kind of features.
That's
why dysfunctional programing is so famous.
So that's why it is it's
not it's not a good practice.
So let me type it down.
It's not a good time.
Do you understand why
it is not a good practice?
Okay.
Are there any other questions, guys?
No questions.
You guys understand
how to create any any type of idea.
And how good are the elements? Right?
So do we move to the next demo?
Okay, so let me teach you
about some methods in here.
So for this example, let's create
an analyst.
Let's use the diamond operator
and specify the data type
that we will be using in here.
The Subindex is
equal to new and then it is
a So you guys started with
SDLC, right?
Then you guys learned
about the men we're testing.
Then the easiest part of this course.
And then you guys started
with selenium, right?
Oh, there was also
then you guys will learn
about the best trending
and then you guys will
learn about the cucumber
and then you guys will learn
about the squirrel.
Then you guys will learn about the APIs,
then you guys will learn about the Docker,
and then you guys will learn about the
buried abilities.
Then you guys will learn about the
more we're testing,
then you guys will learn about the
work and reviews, right?
I feel stressed.
And finally, you guys
will be dead.
That's good.
Because yes, we are adding
some classes on mobile mobile as well,
but they are not mandatory. So
so what this
that not inside cycle it's
okay.
So now if you want to check out
do we have shorter to reach that.
Yes you you
guys can directly jump in front of a train
now you have time
so I can use
whatever comes first.
So urban will use polymorphism
for all of them. Yes.
So and the first method
that we have learned is this ad method.
We use the ad method to add the elements
to the ad list.
And the second method
is the removal method.
If You don't want to use some math
or something you don't like,
you don't like some elements.
You guys can.
And so let's first check the side in here,
okay?
Okay. Let me let me remove that.
So sub decks not remove
and let's remove the deck.
Okay.
And then if I print out the
size again, what size
I will get guys,
I will be getting tired being
okay.
So this size of my part, it returns us
the number of elements
are present inside that list.
Okay, this removes matter.
It removes the elements from that list.
Okay.
Are these matters clear, guys,
can you repeat all this size?
So size just tells you
how many elements are there in
your list.
Is size like length?
Yes. Housing.
Your slight length
and inside and list guys,
if you have to find out
the index of a specific element,
if you are using an array
and if you to find the index
of a specific element,
is there a method building for that thing?
It is.
If you have to find
Alexa, for
example, if you are using it,
then you want to find the index of school.
Is there a method available in areas?
There should be, but there is. There are.
There is.
No matter where you have to write a follow
up, you have to compare the elements
one by one, and then you will be getting
the index of that specific
element right.
But in here we have this building method,
we have this building method
that is an index of you guys
also that is disappointing,
but fine because they are primitive types
damage areas, they are primitive types,
they cannot have meters.
That is how they are super, super fast
and it occupies
less memory.
So inside ArrayList
we have this index of method
that you guys can use
to find the index of a specify element.
Okay, so let me copy
this is everything
layer on on inside this class
is everything layer
What I am doing in here,
adding the element, removing the element,
checking the size,
and then finding the index.
So let's move to the next level.
Looks like still looks like.
Okay, so the next method
is an overloaded version
of the ADD method.
So if you guys allow me
to put into this subject.
So I have commented out this line, okay?
And I am printing out the subjects.
So see, I see all the subjects in here,
but now I have this requirement
that I want to add this selenium
at the fourth index.
Can we do that An array of guys,
If I have to insert something in between
inside an array,
it will be replaced.
Right?
Even if we try to do that,
if we try to insert an element
specific index arrays, they are static,
they don't move the element.
It will replace that element, but at least
it will shift
all the elements towards the right
and then it can insert an element
at a specific location.
So for example,
if you say a subject
not add, you're going to see
there are two overloaded methods.
Add that only takes a string, but
another one that takes the index as well.
So if I specify the index
and then specify the selenium,
and if I print this out again.
So now you guys will observe that
all the elements
So SDLC is same,
manual testing is same doorway,
same duty, same, but at index number four,
now you see selenium and all the elements,
they have been shifted towards.
Right.
And it is also automatic.
You guys don't have to write any logic.
So with
help of
analyst, you guys can insert any element
at any index
without writing any extra logic.
Just to specify the index, all
the elements will be shifted automatically
and your element will be inserted
at that specific location.
Is it clear, guys,
how this add method with
with this two parameters working?
So if you have to insert something
at a specific location.
Yes. The flexible city adds
after index four.
So we add index PHI.
So this is index zero.
This is one,
this is two, this three, this is four.
And then we have their selenium.
Okay?
It means after index 40. Yep, yep.
The appeal are right here
and you guys don't have to write and loop
to print out the elements.
You just write system not out of subjects
and it will all
be printed automatically.
Arrays always start at zero. Yes.
The analyst.
They also start at zero.
I also don't like loops.
So this is we spend hours writing loops
before us.
And at the end of this course
I will tell you, you guys only need
to write one line of code
and it will test all of your website,
everything.
By the way, this is possible.
Some of the companies they are using
some frameworks
and inside those frameworks
you don't have to code anything.
You just specify your best guesses
and then the best guess
will be executed
No, no, there are frameworks,
there are things,
but not all of because they are bad,
not all of them.
They use and they are also not flexible
using Java, using selenium.
You guys can write any piece of logic
and you guys can build
your own frameworks.
Yes. Let me put BigCommerce
where is this company
can No, I googled know the names
but there was this or yes I know a student
who used to.
I think it was cyber.
Cyber something.
And now you guys want to be
after those companies.
You guys always want a shortcut, right?
You can never want to learn something.
Okay.
Life is short learning.
Shortcut is also learning.
If so, the next method
is again,
very simple method.
So let's say you have to add a list.
So I have some elements in one list
and I have some other,
but in a different list.
And now I want to combine those.
When you guys think of life is short,
think about me.
I spent 40 years in engineering,
two years in Masters,
and then five years in the industry.
And when you guys will be getting a job,
essentially
you guys will be doing the same task
that I am doing.
But I have to go through a very long
and on the job.
I studied
44 subjects in my engineering degree
and that job
I was only using three of them
and now I don't even remember those
subjects.
I don't think so.
You know what? You don't think so?
You don't remember all
Okay, well, you are a hero.
At least I get some appreciation
from Katrina. Yes.
So let's say, guys, I have two lists.
And now instead of having these two lists,
I want to all the elements,
maybe inside one list.
So let's say, for example,
I want to create.
So let me call its
subjects one oops.
Now I want to build a new list
and I have to combine
the elements from these two lists.
So in our list, if I have to add, is guys
both of size, let's say maybe ten, 20
or whatever, and I have to create a new
and I have to put all the elements
inside that list.
How much code you guys have right?
A lot. And it will be difficult, right?
Finding out the sizes of the arrays
and and all that.
But in at least what you guys can do,
you guys can use the
building methods,
I can save subjects dot and all
and all
and I can add the list to this list.
Then I can again
say a subject dot and also this time
I'm using an all method
and then
subjects to
and now
if I print out the subjects
list.
Yep, that's all.
Now the subject will contain
all the elements,
all the items in here, no loops, nothing.
Just.
Just call that mental.
And there is one more thing I
if you want to remove
all the elements from a list.
So for example,
I have copied all the elements from
this list and this list, this ArrayList.
Right.
I can also do this.
I can remove
all the elements from the list
because now
I have duplicate data in multiple, right?
So I can say a subject.
Subject one
subject one dot clear.
I can call this clear method
and all the elements
will be removed
from this.
These list again, we can index it
and list the place where we want to add.
Yes, yes, you are right.
Oops, I can print that.
So if I now print this subject one
and if I put in the
subject to
you see
the both are empty now.
Nibble currently now.
And what you can do if you if you check
so this
and all method it is also overloaded.
So right now if you observe this test
and it is being added after selenium,
write this test and is being added
after selenium if you want to be inserted
after manual testing, this second list,
if you want to insert in here,
you can specify the index,
you can specify the index.
And now
you guys will observe that
this firstly is listed it
let me show it in one school, if you
is it readable, right.
I hope you guys can perform this readable.
So if you guys observed
we have this SDLC, this is in here.
We have this manual testing.
But right after that,
instead of having Java
Gate and Selenium,
we have extended, right? Why?
We have extended because we specified
in here we said, Hey, Java,
you know what inserted this list of first
at index two and once we have inserted
all the elements.
So if you see after Mark interviews
now we have Java.
So we are inserting the complete list
in between by specifying the index.
Okay, does it make sense?
Is it clear how how this index is working
so I can
insert the elements just like that
or I can specify the location
and at which I want to insert
my elements here.
Okay.
Remove all
and then
we have remove all matter does that.
So let's say, for example, if you want to.
So let me do this.
So let me,
let me create a new file from there.
Can I move to the next one guys in it?
Claire Everyone is done typing.
Okay?
We don't want them young to develop.
So let's say I have a list.
And from that list.
So let me make it a shorter one
so that you guys can see you.
So I have a longer list.
And from that list
I want to multiple elements.
Okay, So let's say for example,
are from this list.
Subject one
I want to remove all of these elements.
These four elements.
So do I need to do it one by one?
No, I can use.
So let me first print this out.
So in here.
I see all the elements from this list.
Okay.
But if I want to remove these four
elements, what I can do, I can see
subjects one or two remove all
and I can pass the second ArrayList
in here.
Now, all the elements
which are present inside this list,
and they are also present in here,
they will be removed from this list.
And now if I print this out, you see Dr.
A.W. as mobile.
Mark interview the four elements
they have been removed from this subject.
One using the remove all third.
Is it clear right
how the removal is working?
So let's stop here for all the
We need two different list. Yes.
Only subject one printed
without these elements.
Can you scroll up the
if we want to
remove just blue from the list,
how do we do that?
Then you can create a list.
Put those two in
or you can remove them one by one.
Or you can specify their index.
A range of indices are.
I don't think so.
Range is possible in a bit,
but you can write a loop
and after that loop
you can start removing all the elements
and that is the retain all method.
So let's say for example,
if the list is big
and you want to repeat a retain
only 5 to 6 elements,
you can pass those elements
and all other elements
will be removed.
Last which line? Now
I wanted to take three.
I am just printing in here
and. I am removing these subjects,
these subjects.
I am removing these subjects
from this list, from these
objects. Now
let me if
you I can, I think, do some
to try to do these tasks. Yes.
Let me go back to the format.
Otherwise, I'm going to show you
how to do that in the next
class.
Mine never print subject to list
because you have commented out
that piece of code and then how
it can print out.
You are not printing
and you are not writing out for that.
You didn't write us out for that.
Then how can print out
difference between remove and clear player
will remove everything from the list.
Remove
only remove the elements that you boss
the reader.
Question is
no questions.
Okay, let's call it today.
I will post decode
and we'll share the slides
and all that and.
Try to watch those videos
that I shared in the course and all smart.
I am posting this board
and see what will help you out.
Bye bye.
Take care. Take some rest.
How was the class today, by the way?
Can you post out of any or all? Yes.
By the way, try to upload
a lot of you.
You'll be thanking us.
Okay. Bye bye.
Take care.