I did not talk to Suhail.
Maybe I will try to talk to him
after the class.
Yes, I do have a few.
I will let you know, guys.
Maybe in the next class.
Inheritance in to continue.
So let's create a new package
for today's class.
Do you guys have any questions
from yesterday's
class or from homework?
I am so in efficiency and I tried to.
Quarter of your Fakhar Zaman reports on
how you guys are doing
what they are doing. Same thing.
Don't worry,
everyone.
When the task is inherited
by B and B inherited by C,
the main class is C, right?
If you mean B, stop most parent.
B Grandpa.
Yes. B Grandpa. C
I just wake up.
I am sick.
I hope you feel better.
Sharif.
Do you feel good now?
I was also not feeling well.
All right,
guys,
can you tell me about the inheritance?
What do we mean by inheritance in Java?
What is it?
How we can define it?
Evening.
Do you mean
daddy class?
Share school, maybe. Class?
Yes, it's correct.
Are we ready?
Can you guys tell me what is this joke?
I don't understand.
This is a mechanism in which one class
requires all the properties and behaviors.
Members of the parent class
to handle
the global savings.
I mean, what do we do with it?
I am little afraid
you will forget reporting.
Could someone demand please report?
I think we are recording.
Yes. Yes, we are reporting
inheritance in jail.
I mean that one class years.
All the properties
and methods of the subclass
inheritance in Java
is the mechanism
in which one class acquires
all the properties and behaves.
Matters of the
parent class.
After break, I hope you will report again.
Thank you.
Is we can create a new class
upon existing class?
Yes. Using the existing class
methods and fields,
we create a new class inheritance
window on me and start one class here.
So all of the properties
and methods of the subclass
private
members.
You all better be ready
and so.
Well, what are the things
which are which do not participate in
in inheritance.
Inheritance is a mechanism
in which one class acquires
the properties of another mixture.
That's good.
I would not be able to attend the class.
I have terrible headache and fever. Yes.
If you can take some
and maybe you can watch difficulty.
So what are the things
which do not participate in inheritance
case?
I think it's because together
is changing hearts and a lot of people,
they are getting sick.
The constructor and the private members.
Can you guys tell me
what do I mean by private members in here?
I experience, yes,
and private matters
argued. And
what else you guys remember about
the inheritance
fears and matters?
What is the keyword that we use
if we want to inherit
from a class?
One of the main disadvantages
of the inheritance
exchange, right?
We lose expand.
You are to
inherit
from last.
Now let's discuss about the benefits.
So we how many benefits were discussed
yesterday?
The combined subclass
Jala class and Superclass three.
Right.
Money and money is the benefit.
Yes, it's actually to money.
So the first benefit is that
it saves time
before right?
And it
takes less humanity
and therefore time
engineers performance
is big time really,
execution time
is less
important
or application
is reduced.
And what about the
this advantages?
How do I open it for you to write
and also intelligent.
So Mohammad
inspired and you
package like you can do or you can
you can right click
and then you can click new
and then you see this option
that says file.
You give it any name and then you have
to provide the extension as that.
So if you type, it will be a text file.
If you want to make it a Excel file
or docs file,
you just mentioned the dependency
and and then to do is create that void
if pop up class and is all
the subclasses are dependent on their.
Yes. Very dependent on each other.
So then there is a
there is a special keyword in Java
that we use for this behavior.
Need to be careful
when general function and get in class
and inheritance based class
and are all applicable.
And hence, if we change equal of bit
in a class, it will affect the
all child classes.
So this is a very big
disadvantage,
especially in agile environments.
So let's say we are
using some fields
from the parent class inside our methods
or let's say we are using a method
from the parent class, right?
And there are maybe 2000 classes,
this thousand child classes.
Now if we change that name
to something else
or if we remove their name already,
we didn't change that method
or remove that method,
or if we add something to that method.
So any modification to existing members
will affect all the thousand classes
and we have to make changes
to all those classes
if we want those classes to work properly.
So this is a very big disadvantage of
inheritance.
All right.
And after that we discussed all about
the types of
inheritance.
How many types are there guys
which are supported generally by most
of the programing languages?
So most of the programing languages,
they and they support four types
of inheritance.
But in Java only three types of
inheritance inheritance are supported.
Okay, so
there are
four major
types of
inheritance
which are
supported in
most of the
object oriented programing
languages
or Java.
Only because
the types
with the classes
right before type is supported by
a new concept which is called interface.
We will learn about that.
Techniques.
So these are
so the first one that is supported
by Java is
single.
Then we have the hierarchical
and then
we have the multi level
and the fourth one
B multiple
of one node
or third
are classes in Java,
but it is supported by interfaces.
So let's discuss.
This was type
what is this single inheritance?
Oh yes, the diamond problem.
And because at the time
one parent, one child, single base
class and single drive class, single
one parent, one charter type.
So if we have only
one parent and
one child
with all single
so for example, if we have
public class
error
and it is this
class child
which is
extending from parent, then we will say
this is single inheritance
is the parent class and B is the child.
Since we inherit the future
learning behavior in class.
All right.
And then we have the second type,
which is hierarchical inheritance.
One parent and multiple children
parent w more than one subclass.
The child has siblings.
Yes, one parent and multiple children.
So if we have one
class and
merge people
to growing classes
and then it is all
an inheritance.
So let's say here we have
again the parent class,
then we have maybe
child one
which is extending from parent
and another child
may be trying to do extending from parent
and then another child.
Child
three was also extending from the parent.
So now there are multiple classes
or parent class is always the same.
It's only the only one class.
Yes, this is called
hierarchical inheritance
lang grandpa for other children
and of course for inheritance.
And then we discussed about the
multi level
inheritance.
And many people tried classes. Then
as part of
class experience to another class
that is already extended
from another class
experience, from another class
that is already extended
from another.
All right.
So let me copy that.
We have a class
which is extending from another class
that is already extended
from another class, right?
So, for example, we have a class
grand incident.
Then we have another class
event and it is extending
all grand and
we are
extending all
data.
Then it is called
Have an inheritance.
Okay.
And the last one
is multiple inheritance.
Okay, what is this?
Multiple inheritance, right?
One child and multiple parents.
Right. It
said we have the last one.
You have been Who
was so close
parent.
And then
this is
the type of inheritance
which is not spoken by Java.
Let's see.
Inheritance.
The properties and behaviors of Class
B and Class C are the same level.
So you're able to update our classes
for C in
which we discussed in the last class,
right?
I hope everything is clear.
And if you guys are confused
about anything, you can ask me.
Miguel's next class is.
Today's class is actually related
to this inheritance.
Can you tell one more time?
Diamond problem.
So diamond problem is this.
So let's say, for example,
we have Ward three
named
and this
and we have the exact same method
inside the parent to
that we have this is out
here and it is
going to
be 1120
here experience.
But now
if I create an object of this child class
and if I call the name
method, which method should be called
the method from the parent one
or the parent two
or there is an ambiguity.
Next time I will be creating these notes
after the class.
So this is where
the problem arises.
So this problem is not solved in Java.
It's not that it cannot be solved.
Yes, it can be solved.
Other languages like Python.
So for example,
Python shares are solved in this example.
Like this, if you are writing the parent
one first after this extension one,
the priority will be given to the method
from the parent Fun.
So this is how the python solved
this problem.
So C++ also has a mechanism
to solve this problem.
But Java guys, they thought that
maybe it will be creating more confusion
and it's less beneficial, less beneficial.
So they didn't allow
this type of inheritance
in classes will be a question
about multilevel attributes.
Yes, they can be asking you
these type of questions, and
most of the questions
you can say 60 to 70% of the questions
which are asked in Java,
they are from oops again,
they are from loops
there.
There will always be a question
from inheritance.
Is that important?
There will hardly be an interview
if they are asking you from Java
and they will definitely be asking you
from inheritance.
So these oops concepts, they
are very important for your interviews.
But if you guys ask me that,
I really will be creating
these building classes and all classes.
I will say you will be
you might be doing it
for like 20% of the time,
but maybe only 10% of the time.
But the frameworks,
the JDK, the libraries on the Internet,
the code that is already written,
they heavily use this concept.
Okay,
So it's very important to understand.
So let's say, for example, if I show you
how this
is used in JDK,
so let's discuss about the string class.
Okay.
So I hold on my control button again
and I click on that class. So
because you guys don't know
about the implements,
let me find some other classes
there.
Okay, So you see the string Builder class
is extending from Abstract String Builder.
Okay,
If you guys hold down your control button
and if you open this abstract
string builder
so this implements thing
we will be learning in the next week.
So this is the class from which
that distinguished the class is inherited.
Similarly, if we check out the
final class,
which is also using the implementation,
let me show you my class.
So this object class is the parent
of all the classes in Java. That's
each class,
whether you guys are writing it
or whether it's a part is written
by the Java
guys, all the classes
that they inherited from this class.
Okay, So this class has to be
very famous matters
and they are also off in the interview.
So those matters are the hash code.
Now, you guys might want to read
about these matters in here.
Then there is this equals method.
You guys remember that
equals method in the string class
so that
equals method is actually coming from this
object class.
Okay, this object class.
But because every class has to extend
from this class for Java guys has done
that.
You guys don't need to write
extends keyword and then this object
that the name of this class
it is inherited by default
by all the classes in Java.
So if you guys check the class,
you will not see any extents
keyword in here.
But still this method is available
inside the string class.
And if you go to that
equals method
in here,
so you guys will see that this equals
method.
It is also present.
Yes, it's kind of DNA code for Java DBAs
for every class you guys will see that
equals method is also present inside this
string class.
Okay, So
and this is the topic of today's class.
What happens if we have a method
in the parent class
and if we have the exact same name method
in the child class, then how things are
happen.
Okay, so this is what we
will be discussing today. But
this object class.
So so most of the time
they will be asking you
what is the purpose of these
three methods in the object class
is Java uses the concept of multi multiple
behind the scenes for this language,
but do not allow for public use yet.
So this is called hidden for programmers.
So some things are allowed
for only Java guys,
but not for general programmers
like you and me.
Okay, so behind the scene, yes,
you are right, because technically
every class
that you are extending from another class
by explicitly writing
that extends keyword,
you do already
extending from this object class.
So technically that class
already has one parent
and then you are extending
from another parent.
So you are extending from two classes.
So but that is only allowed by Java base.
Okay.
What if we tried to extend it explicitly?
If we tried to expand from two classes,
then we will not be applicable that.
So I will encourage
you guys to read through these matters.
So let me just quickly explain this
returns a hash called value for object.
This method is supported
for the benefit of hash table,
such as those provided by Java
hash map.
So there are more structures
in Java like arrays and variables.
So you guys have learned
about only two structures, right?
The end is which can store
multiple values.
The variables
which can only store one value at a time.
But there is a whole collection
of structures and other classes
which can store the data
in many different places.
So this hash map is one of them.
How can we see those methods
so we can go over them?
So you guys have two, right?
You guys can just type object in here
like this.
You hold down your control button
and then you can click on that.
This method
and to take you to the object
class.
In simple words, what you guys can see
can see is that hash code is kind of
hashCode returns a and integer value.
That is kind of the address of that object
in the memory.
Okay, it's not the actual actual address,
but it is
created using that.
So what I learned why I am saying
that you guys see this native viewer.
So the whole Java
server,
some parts of the Java, they are written
in other programing languages.
So like, like C and C++.
So how I do that in Eclipse.
So Muhannad, why,
why are you still using Eclipse?
So by the way, you're saying you,
you hold down your control button
and you can click on that for that food
and to go to that class
and you likes Eclipse
So wherever you guys will see this
native keyword, which means the
disk in
this matter, you will see
there is no body for this method.
So we only have this name,
this parentheses, and then there is
this semicolon.
So this more body of this
method is not present.
So there is that body of this method.
So that body of this method is actually
written in other programing languages
like C and C++.
I need to support
another denoted by by your JVM.
So there are very detailed
explanations of order.
Now there is this equal to my third,
which checks
so the equals method in the object class.
It only checks if two objects,
if they have the same hash code or not.
Okay.
So you see
this is equal to equal to object.
And if we go to the string class, there is
there are a lot of lines of code in here.
Okay. So it's something very simple.
In here
we are only checking if two objects,
if they have the same address or not,
then we have this boosting method.
You guys remember that two string
method arrays got to string
or whenever we have to clear that
and then we have to convert that builder
class object to the string.
We call this boosting method
so that
that initial value, if you guys prior
to print out your adding without calling
that add is the same method.
Actually this method from this object
class is being called.
Okay.
And that's why you,
you guys see that name of the class.
Then this started fine
and then these are hashCode,
okay, Those are symbols and all that.
That's where they are coming from.
Then this notifies the market writing
or if I also
it is also for market threading
when you guys go going
make you worry about now
there is this finalized method
so whenever we create would be
objects would declare the
we initialize the values
through constructor.
Now once you guys are done
using that object,
this finalized method
by your JVM is called
and this finalized method is where
all the memory for your object is removed.
Okay, Next. Clearly.
So there is this concept of garbage
collector.
Do you guys know about the garbage
collector? No.
So when we write the new keyword,
when write the new keyword,
that's when the memory
is declared inside your your ram file.
That object. Okay.
And as a programmer, for example,
in C++ language,
the programmers are responsible
to remove that from the memory
once they are done using that.
Okay.
So if a programmer in C++
is declaring an object
or if it is declaring a variable, once
he is done using that variable or object,
he should delete that variable
to release the memory from the RAM.
Okay.
So but in Java or Java guys did.
And so they have tried to solve
all the problems
that were there in C++ and C,
so they written the program
and that program is called
The Garbage Collector,
and they have automatic measure
of that process now in Java.
Java automatically detects
when you are done using a certain object
and chromatically deletes
the memory for that object from your RAM
before deleting that memory.
This is the finalized method
that Java will call.
So all the classes because they will be
inheriting from the object.
So technically every class will be having
this finalized method right?
So if you guys want to perform
certain things
before the index,
audio classes will be moved from the RAM.
This is where you put that code. Okay.
So that you are sure that before
the memory is released, before
the object is deleted from memory,
maybe you want to send an email
or maybe you want to save that
that's actually a file.
Or maybe you want to send that out
to a network or whatever
you want to do with that so that you are
sure that you will never lose data.
So there we are.
This finalized method is used,
so I will repeat these things
in the next week again.
So at this point, if you guys
don't understand all the concepts,
I just want to give you a starter
in this class because in the next classes
we will be discussing
these kind of things.
So it's fine if you guys don't understand
all the things.
Okay, let's, let's solve the tasks
in this and the
statement for gospel and write a program
for movie level inheritance.
So write a program
for multi-level inheritance.
We have class inherited by B
and class B, Inherit
class
C, okay, so
class A is inherited by
B, So can you guys
tell me which one will be
the parent class?
Class is
inherited by B, so the
E will be parent.
So let me create
next and create a new package.
B extends s
So this is class A
So there is one more thing
that I want to show you that is related
to how the constructors are called
when we have the
inheritance relationship.
So once we are done with these tasks,
remind me about that.
There should be class B extends E?
Yes, give me. Okay,
so I intend that
this is what I inherited.
I mean, and let me,
let me show you guys how
I, how can we create multiple
classes inside a single file?
Okay.
So you guys have not done this before,
right?
Creating than one classes
inside the same part
of the school that I
recommend
to this class from here.
So remember this rule.
And it is also asking in interview
some sometimes
in a single Java file.
We can only have one public class,
but we can have other classes
without that public keyword.
So for example,
if I try to put that public
inside with this class as well,
I will be getting an error.
Okay, so this is not allowed.
Can you guys tell me why you do not allow
conflict prior to Java?
Always solving
every file that you create with distort
Java extension
when you are executing that.
Yes, Java gets confused
when you are executing that file
and with the JVM.
So JVM first looks for the public class.
Is this the right way?
Yes, this can
and this can be one of the solutions you
it is being already
declared as a public class. Yes.
So then we have the spin class
and then we can
in yet another class, Class B
and let me know
if you guys want me to slow down.
And then we have
seen, okay, so
let's do this.
I don't want you to confuse.
So let me quickly,
can we change the statement?
And if you whatever way you guys have used
is fine,
because the main purpose was to make
a multiple inheritance example.
Not if if, if you want
which class is inheriting
from the other class. So
in a class C
inherits from
Class B and
Class B
and from
class, if
so, and I want you to focus so
all right, I stems here
and I write
externals B, Okay.
Are you guys done writing this code?
So in our task one classes, we can create
three different classes like ABC.
We can create any number of classes,
as many classes as you want, with only one
public class.
And same is created on package Explorer.
You mean in here?
So these are
no copies are getting created?
Yes, But you see,
this is a part of Task One or Java.
So these classes, they are part of Task
One or Java.
Okay.
Yesterday there was three windows,
but it's much easier.
Everything in one page. Yes.
So we'll we will be using this one.
How you create Java inside of Java.
This is how we could here Java
and try to go
and yes,
let me show you.
So let's you have to do this inside
that task alone.
Well this package as for the task one,
you have to write
this class A and B and C like this
if you still face any issues.
So let me create
let me create an object
of B, class B,
So b, B is equal to new B.
Can you guys
tell me if I execute this code,
how many lines I will see on output
or digital lines?
Nothing.
Okay. No.
Now, how many lines?
Those who are saying to anyways, explain
which two lines
I will be getting on the console and why
experience error.
So let me first try the security score.
So what happens is that we first
see this error and then we see the speed.
So what is happening behind the scenes?
Even though we are only creating
the object of Class B,
the object
and the constructor of the class,
it is also called again.
So whenever the constructor,
whenever the object for the child
class is created, always, always.
If that child
has a parent class
first, the object for the parent
class will be created.
Okay.
And to create we can the object.
The constructor of the parent
class will be called first.
And let's say if you have tags
and more classes in the hierarchy,
in the level in multiple levels before a
then all those thousand classes,
the constructors of those classes
will be called,
their objects will be created.
And at the very last
the object of that child is created.
I am getting ahead of
so our law
and everyone to make sure guys,
you are writing your classes
after this
ending bracket of this task. One
and also are
why you are missing these parentheses.
So after
and there are these parentheses after we
we have these parentheses
because we are writing a constructor.
So you should also write
these parentheses.
Yes, that is also so put together.
So is the other thing.
Look.
So let's say
if I am creating the object of class
C, if I'm creating the
I'll go see how many lines I will see
on the console guys
and in which sequence
A, B, C,
you can think or you can think
about the scenario like this.
First, the grandparent is born,
then parent is born
and then child is born.
So first of all, the object for
the grandparent is created,
then for the parent
and then for the child.
My goodness,
whose life is worse than mine?
My child is coming on.
I still have the editor
even when I do a Russian.
The screenshot again
and make sure you you are removing it.
You are
writing it after
these parentheses.
So now if I execute this code,
getting error off duplication,
can you share the screenshot
of the error from
Is there
no one in this channel?
Let me show you the whole code. Yes,
we can have only one class with one
name.
All this time you are missing.
You have to type after the new keyword.
You have type B
and we are right.
Also having a long day for
Would you please explain line nine?
Line nine.
This one
I am creating an object of class C on line
nine.
I'm creating an object in line 13.
Please. This is just a constructor.
Constructor of class it.
Right? Same name as the class name.
No return type
between two constructor
Is this best way to use inheritance?
I mean best practice?
You mean they are creating the classes
inside the same file?
No, no, no. This is not the best.
I have just written it
because if so, this is weird.
You should use it.
If this.
If you know that this class B
only and only this task
class will be using this class B
or class E or classy,
then you should drive two classes
inside the same file.
If one class is only
and only related to another class,
then you should combine these two classes
in a single file.
Otherwise, the best practice is to create
a separate file format.
Class
is the main imperative
should not be after of class.
No, it can be anywhere.
Really.
You started with work with that?
I mean with. See? No, I started with me
class.
I wrote B
at my first.
I wrote B as before.
You told our Java code.
I think you from top to bottom
it executes from top to bottom
inside methods then is.
But here
we call C class about the classes.
It works because it is constructor. No.
So then is in here.
We are defining classes.
We are not calling these classes.
We discussed this class.
It will never be executed unless
and until you write it inside any method.
So that top to bottom approach
is only followed inside the methods.
Okay.
Outside of that method
it does not follow down.
Do not follow this.
You can define variables any way
and you can define methods that wouldn't
be any anywhere.
You can define with any view.
And then other questions.
That was my question. Now understood.
I still have the issue now.
Can you share the screenshot here
all our
so this first task one,
I hope you guys were able to do this
what the task tasks harder
easy.
I did not get a chance to do it
right program
couldn't hurt
class said that has been tough with you
starting again on call
or we used that method
in the class B
I want to see the output.
PS Yes, sure.
This is the output.
Give me
all two former decode
intelligent control all then and
control out.
And this one
it gives me
an error.
So Mohanlal
do you have to remove the ending
calibrated at line 29
or do drag lines mean no?
The intelligent process?
Yes. Intelligent process.
And I will make sure this
class
that you are writing
it is with lowercase C, not uppercase C
if we call B and C object both.
So first seem B for the B object.
The constructor of A and B will be called
because B has one parent
and then if we call the object C, then
all three constructors will be called.
Right?
Because C is the child grand grandchild
and I'm about to throw
my whole laptop off the window.
Maybe you want to go with it as well.
You string
the entire loop
does not exist.
Homework one.
So Areva, you are making a mistake
in a different file.
Okay.
That the name of that filed by is
capitalized w one
you have to fix that issue first.
So it will be almost one.
Okay, so it is the same class
on line number three.
Can you show line number three?
You are doing something wrong.
On line
number three, indicate or swing or enter.
All does not exist.
Not Java. The class looks good
and that caused me yesterday.
I had to go to class and
if it does that we will be
okay.
I hope the building is only having
one floor
and the window is not more than one
or two feet
and this is also been declining.
So I am definitely in the
the arrow.
Well,
why are you writing the indicators swing?
Don't interrupt nursing, blah blah, blah.
I removed that line.
Then I will be teaching you
on the question why I didn't do it.
We put void on the methods.
Mohammad, These are not matters.
They are constructors.
I thought I am only having a bad day.
It automatically adds that.
So no, it
automatically does not add that you
you might have written something
like the name of the
class or something like that.
And if that class is from that package,
then it will automatically import
that for you.
Can you show the entire or if
in fact
I am getting at a on line 11.
So we put on grand child class at the top.
Of course, since we know
we are going to reach see at the end.
No, no, you guys can write this in here
like this.
I just ordered so that
you guys can understand it.
Easy now.
So the be for public is capital.
It should not be capital
line nine.
I mean,
in here
I am just creating an object of class C
this creating an object of class
and C can be any at all
to shift to written word format no control
I plus L to format and guide.
You can also do this so those who are
having a hard time with the shortcuts
there is this
and there is this option for this shortcut
and I think works
the mapping like this.
So if you type the map you guys can see,
do you guys see this option?
So right now I have selected
Windows copy one for all for redo.
Okay, so right now
I am using these set of shortcuts.
But if you guys are more comfortable
with the shortcuts of Eclipse,
all the shortcuts from eclipse,
you guys can also have those shortcuts.
So you just have to select Eclipse
and all the shortcuts
that you guys are used to having.
Eclipse They will work in here if you want
and if you guys are coming
from Videostudio Sublime NetBeans
so you guys can have shortcuts
from everywhere inside the intelligent.
How do we get there?
So you guys have to type.
You guys have to click
double shift quite quickly
and then you have to type IMAP.
My printout is a
b A instead of a, b, c,
you know, can you share a song
showing this screenshot?
And you guys can create
definitely your own shortcuts, but
let me know if
if there are other students
are also facing some kind of issues.
How do the yours become task one dot Java?
Because I wrote Task one Dark Java
and see B and you see so
you know, you have to show me the class C
as well.
All this try to share complete
screenshots based
medium B
and the the letter C for the classes
capital
you why are
you guys are making these mistakes
I think people need doable
and that's what
five days feels we are losing common sense
and maybe it's because
of the new environment
you see inside the constructor
on line number 28, you have written a man
then then should virtually printed
on the console definitely will be printed.
Right?
You have to type C online number 28
if you want to CC on the console.
I have an error in line.
Something in B here today.
Yes, I
I also will that I have an edit online
then.
So now you are writing all the classes
inside this this main class.
So the inside in here make sure
these classes they are outside of this
closing curly bracket.
Maybe I should not have shown you
this method of writing classes
inside the same file
that they're my biggest stuff here.
That's my big, biggest fear.
When when I whenever
I have before something new,
I have to think the end times.
If you guys will be able to digest or run
selected clicks
thirds.
Can you guys imagining Python?
There are no brackets and in Python
you have to make sure that before
this public
there are eight spaces and right now.
I am working on Python
and every time you and I have missing
one space, the code will not work.
Fatima. It's just a warning.
Just a warning that you are not using the
you are creating the variable B
but you are not using it.
So it's fine warnings. They are fine.
You guys can ignore them
because it is redundant
to put public on the constructor
since they are all in the same class.
Yes Mohammad, you are right.
There is no need of this public in here.
You guys can simply remove the
look,
not giving the output because you are
you have not selected the console.
Fatima, you make sure
from here you select this one window.
Not the total window, not the problems
window, not the messages window
frame like that
mean when something happens these days.
Are the repos hard?
But I thought the rebels are easy
and then they are easier then those loops
and then those printing out
those combinations and.
All that. No, it's not easy.
Some of them, they are tricky loops
seem easier.
What about the Helloworld show?
Is that easy now?
Even the Helloworld is not easy.
Both are also would
I saw the onset of effort in 100
the table jokes
and it often gives us and otherwise
so as
intelligent more like intelligent guy.
We're still hitting on the eclipse repo
just made all info at one place in mind
so the rest
of you can do it.
Easy peasy.
So can we move to the task to now
if all the issues are resolved
and everyone looks good.
All right.
So then you guys
send me
the poster.
Thank you.
Let me so
Java code not working.
This struggle is read write program
to inherit class here
that has my third plaintiff
which is static
and call or reuse that method in class B.
Okay, so
let me start class here.
In that class
it has a method of putting test ward
reading for
and we have to make it static
here.
Do make package or class.
Yes, I created this sub package task to
register date and
or reuse that matter into class B.
Okay,
so how can I use methods
from one class guys in another class
expense?
Write
only one answer.
What?
You guys feeling okay? I
So now
I can create the object of class B
word because this method is
start starting.
I don't even need
to create the object. Right. Right.
Do we need the object?
If I want to call a static method,
why static word?
Because most of
it was written in the requirements.
So can I call this print method
by writing only? B
not even B and then parentheses is yes. B
and then print F, Right.
So this is what we do for static meters
as a best practice.
We read the name of the class
and then we can call their method.
Okay, so we see
a phone
plus.
Okay,
so the point of this exercise is
we don't need to create an object
for static variables s moment.
We don't need to.
The point of this exercise was to show you
as you can inherit the instance method,
you can also in the static methods
as well.
And the same.
Are you creating different packages
for tasks?
Yes, so far.
Task one I created this task one package
for task to add another package.
If you guys to follow,
you can create new packages.
Otherwise
you can solve inside the packages. But
I did same class but named a one.
It's also fine
and that change your class name? Yep.
If you add s out in line 23
giving outcome of line 16.
If you add solid in line 20,
you want me to add NYA in here?
Do you want me to add something?
There's also word
we will learn about this concept.
Like, for example, if I have this method
in this class B as well, and
if I execute this code again.
So instead of render from B,
I will be seeing printer
from a printer from
I will be seeing graphically.
But this is what we will discuss
after the class.
I am creating new class, not package.
So are there other questions?
Life.
But I got an interesting error.
Yes. Issue that
no questions.
Should we to the next task
ask one class.
It is a duplicate for class here
in task to
all the in same package moment.
So we always have to create. Yes.
Then you can go inside one package.
You can only have one class
with your name.
Do we always have to create a new package?
No. This is just for organization.
The as you.
If you want,
you can create. Otherwise you can ignore
right in
Java program or teacher identifier.
And the behavior of that class cleared
three subclasses method
math, teacher,
chemistry teacher or teacher
that would have it there on features
and behavior
test all four classes
right now my mind
was not printing a there.
What are you going to discuss
later, right?
Yes, that's what we were discussing you to
build
the feature class.
So I class
feature
and then identify features
and behavior of this class.
Okay.
So can you guys tell me the features
or or behaviors of
a feature class?
Maybe only one behavior
and one one feature
being
name all the teachers.
They have name right?
And all the teachers, what do they do?
They teach art.
Let me be clear.
The math teacher.
So cross
math teacher.
Okay.
And then we can having have maybe
or did
we use
math? Why?
I'm having this error, guys.
Expenses and input.
Right now I can access this name field
in this classes but
then quickly
replicated for the chemistry teacher
and for the
piano
teacher.
Well how do we format into its control
art and
so right that our program
or teacher identify features
and behaviors of that class clear
three subclasses and that would have
their own features and behaviors
and test all those four classes.
All right.
So so when you combine this in same file,
you don't name
the teacher best of class. Yes.
We don't need we can we can write that
inside this to the main method.
Then we create administrative task to the
new place.
So the whole period, Yes.
I hope it is available to you guys.
Let me remove this
so that you guys can see it before class.
So this is the whole class.
Let me know what you guys are done typing
then.
Okay ask the method
and see
that we couldn't as
I don't dare should be teaches piano
to one minute.
So now what we can do?
We can clear the objects by writing
math teacher,
teacher easy for the new math teacher
Who is the math teacher in our class?
Guys, the math teacher dog name is
in here.
Yeah.
And then we can see that
teacher dog statement right?
And also is also a math teacher.
And then we can create the objects
in the same way.
By the way, let me show you something
new. We have the
chemistry teacher as well.
So in an intelligent guys,
if you have, let's say,
multiple classes,
you want to change something
so you can enter to do things
in vertical fashion as well.
Yes, I wondered that
when you took all method, but
so you can hold on the art
and then you can select all the things
vertically
at once.
You can remove them
and you can replace them
like this.
So vertical anything is also possible.
Intelligent.
So hold down your art button
and then place the vertical line
with the help of your mouse,
the left click, and then select
keeping holding down your art button.
And then you can select
whichever you want,
you can remove, and basically
you can edit things in vertical
any place.
Scroll down.
Yes, it is same.
We have the all button on Mac right?
Or it's the option button in Mac.
There is no artwork on.
Oh, okay.
So there are so many weird things.
I mean the Mac is or the window by the way
they can have the same buttons
but I don't know why they do that.
There is also a
kind of law in the protocol.
So the Europeans, they and the Europeans
and the Americans, so they are technically
doing the same things,
but for the same things.
They have different names.
And just to make things different,
I mean, literally,
they introduce so much complexity.
So when I was learning networking,
they introduced so much complexity
in networking and protocols.
And and
the same is the case with the players
in the in the United States.
You guys write the month first
and then the day, right?
And then the year
and then in the other parts of the world.
Then they don't follow this
this approach. Right.
I'm going to why, why, why?
They cannot have the same
outline 30 word wide.
Each piano is more suitable.
I think.
Oh, yes.
So that's
why copy pasting is not a good idea.
It introduces a lot of issues
and it was actually a rule in my company
index.
Don't copy and paste the code
and we can do the same
for the driving left
and you can buy it can be from.
Yep. Yeah.
I mean how much complex it will be for
for for the person as well
because the person cannot become
comfortable if one have been writing
left and then
he or she has to switch to write.
And then for the benefactors
as well, in one country
they are building cars for the left
and then the other ones that are.
Right.
All right. Okay.
So let's have a break.
And after the break, we will start our
topic Neural topic.
Yes, the super keyword.
So please be back by 850.
And if I don't come back,
you guys can assume I went to sleep.
And you guys can also take some rest
and we will see the concepts on the
on the set for this class.
Guys. Remind me about the recording.
If I forget
the third text
that that issue is actually this.
So let's say, for example,
I am using this math class and I
misspell this, okay, so now
or maybe we should
the sometimes Oriental idea is doing
if a piece of code is causing an issue
so intelligible, sure, you That
that link to that class.
So let me
try to create the here
we have already this issue.
So in here
it is saying two related problems.
Now this piece of code
that you have written in there,
it is causing problems
in other under classes.
And if you want to check we have that
problem is you can click on this to
a related problem.
The different text,
and then it will show you
this related issue.
You see in the
in the recap class on the on the class 16.
So in here,
this recap is having
this integer number in here.
This recap is having this circle
standing here.
So what is happening in there?
Because
this piece of code
is causing problem in other classes
so intelligent is
telling you that link that where this code
is causing that problem.
So if you make a mistake in one
and if other classes are impacted
by that mistake, it can tell you
that link that which classes are affected
by changing this piece of code,
you can click on, click on that text
and it will take you to the class we are.
The problem can happen
because of this code.
So you you can ignore that.
You can ignore that because right now
if see, I have multiple classes and I have
multiple issues in those classes, but
I have excluded them from the compilation.
So you guys need to worry about that.
But if there's something very useful.
So when you guys will be working
on big projects, finding the classes
and inside the classes,
finding the specific meters
which are which,
which are affected by that change, it's
a very tough job.
Okay, So this creates those links
and you can click on that link
and it will take you to the end of that
line number.
And the problem is happening.
So it would not be present for us for now.
You can ignore that.
Okay, but it's very useful.
Big projects
and you guys might have also noticed
this that
with each method
or with each class,
you have these, these signs
and if you click on that,
you will see this class error.
Then three doors and then curly back there
so you can shrink some pieces of code
in here.
I don't know if we can do that
indicates or not.
So and by default in the intelligent
shrinks
some some matters and classes
and if you guys want to have a look,
you can click on these three doors
and it will expand that code
or you can keep on shrinking.
Now, if you have a very long file
and you have some meters
and you are calling these matters
in other matters and you want to check
how that code is working,
maybe you want to shrink that
the code that is in between.
Okay.
And also was also helpful in
in reading long files.
So do not get confused about
about these three doors as well.
And then one more thing I have noticed
is that there are all these
expand all at fault button.
So if you have messy project
Explorer like this
and you quickly want to shrink it,
you can click on this shrink call
and then everything will be shrink
and then you can expand
whichever classes
you want to span from here.
Okay.
And if you are on a file
and you are unable to locate the back
end of that
file or well, that file is located,
you guys click on this round icon
and will show you the class
which is open inside the editor right now.
Okay,
so because now you guys
will be building the framework
and you guys will be writing a lot of code
for these things,
they will be very useful for you
and I in each class almost.
I will keep on
I will keep on telling you about this
class and all that.
All right. Okay. So today's
topic is about crew.
This class is about the super keyword.
Now, super keyword is just like the
this keyword that you guys learned.
So again, you guys tell me
what was the purpose of this keyword?
What were the use cases?
And so if there is a there is
between local variables
and instance variables,
we can use the this keyword
to distinguish these variables.
Right?
I tried to create com dog syntax,
dog class and the same line and it changed
one package
and two packages, class 18 and 19 y.
So I showed this,
this part
and that is the part that you are writing.
This com dot syntax is actually
the base package and intelligent ask
feel about this base package
when you create a project.
Okay.
And then after that
you only write the sub packages.
So you have already created that base
package and you are trying clear that base
package again.
But in Java only three.
So you can go down to three levels.
So let's say for example, if
I tried to create a package in here
and then inside this,
so you see after this,
it does not matter how many packages
I create inside this
task, it will start appending those names
with this door.
Fine. Okay.
So you can go only up to three levels.
So that's why you are facing that issue.
Okay First, for the current
object can be used for that
for immediate parentheses, just variable.
Okay.
So the functionality of this keyword
is related to the current class.
By current class I mean the class
in which we are writing that piece.
Of course this is used to create
constructor features,
so now there is no such thing
as constructor field.
Okay.
The first they belong to the class,
so let's say nice.
I have.
And do you guys are you guys okay? Great.
One more example.
Go. Okay,
let's create
a class.
So and
and the all the pairs they will be having
names, right?
I will keep things very simple. Read
color
and page.
So let's say this is my parent class
and I have some fears in here.
Mejorar Lola, I mean, Vaughn's argument,
this is used for that.
Oh, no, You can also use this in
in the methods as well.
So with the help of this keyword, I can
all be constructors of this same class.
We if I write those parentheses,
I can distinguish
between local variables
and instance variables.
And, and the third thing
that we do don't focus that much was
we can also call meters from that class.
Now. Now let's discuss
the use cases of the super
keyword.
So this keyword
super is also a reference variable.
This was also a reference variable
by reference variables
mean a variable through which I can refer
to or add the variable through
which I can access the fears, methods
or constructors of a class.
Okay, so in the case of this,
we were accessing the fears, methods
and constructors of this same class
in which we were writing that.
The super keyword, however, is used
to refer to the immediate parent class.
Okay, so let's say for example,
I have these fears here
inside this class
and I have another class
or, or dog.
And inside your dog
I am simply
putting things in me
along
with me.
And from fact
like this.
Okay, now I don't have index
and then
let's have a character
expand that
and maybe
I am sprinting
edge in here
like this.
And then
so I hope did this.
This is better
from what we did yesterday
in the last class.
So I have some fears, guys,
in this super class
and I am using those fears
inside of my child classes. Now.
How do I initialize the school fields
if I am using some fields
from the parent class, how can I
initialize them in the child class
on what should be the best approach
to initialize those fields?
Import class?
How do we initialize the fields
in a class?
Constructors. Right.
We use the constructors right?
So what I can do,
I can create a constructor.
All right. I can write
the names.
Oops,
grade and
then an integer H.
And then I can say this dot
name is equal to name.
This ought
read is equal to read.
Is there a shortcut to generate E?
Yep, yep.
There is also a shortcut.
I will tell you about that.
Just give me one more.
This is for
and then
they start it.
Usually for h
in the intelligentsia what you guys can do
place your cursor inside that class
for which you want to create something.
Right click and then click.
I'll click on Generate.
Do I see this option?
You can do it and then you can
select the constructor like this
and generate
constructor and here you will see it.
So because there are no fields inside
this class, so there slide,
it is not giving you an option
to generate with fears.
Okay, so
now if I have to initialize
these fields form the get as well
because it is also using these fears,
what should I do?
Indicate class.
So it is already extending
extend from dog.
But constructors,
they don't participate in inheritance.
That means even though I inherited
from that class I will not be able to use
to use that constructor.
Remember this.
So the only way is I rewrite this
constructor again
inside the car class.
Okay.
Like this.
But tell me guys,
tell me if
if I have maybe 5060 100 child classes
and if I am following this approach
and I am rewriting this constructor
again and again, is it a good practice
or do you guys see some kind
of code duplication? Yes.
So even so now really saying
why don't we create this constructor
inside, inside the class,
inside the parent.
So yes, we can create the constructor
inside of the parent,
but because constructors
don't participate in inheritance, so
still it will not be a part of this class.
But what I can do,
instead of rewriting this call,
I can write super
and then I can pass this information
like this to the parent class
and I can do the same.
I can remove
this, I can write super with parentheses
and I can pass this information
to the parent constructor.
That way I don't have to repeat
these constructors
for all the child classes
now what I am doing because constructors
don't participate in inheritance,
but we can call the constructor
of the parent class
by writing this
super and then these parentheses.
Yes. If we remove this constructor
from this banner.
No, no.
Where this where the super is referring
to, there is nothing in the parent, right?
So you remember using the this keyword
we used to refer to a constructor, right?
If there is there is no constructor,
then then how we refer to that constructor
whether is if the discovered
or the or the super keyword.
Okay.
So again in here I am just calling.
So I call the the constructors
or using the
this keyword
with those identities of the same class.
I am doing exactly the same thing.
But in here super is calling
the constructor of the parent class.
There's the only difference.
Yeah, super easy.
You can say it's kind of a shortcut
to access the constructor
of the parent class.
Is this similar as this?
So yes, you can say that
now. Good.
Because we use the this keyword
to call the constructor
and we are also using the super keyword
to call the constructor.
The difference is that this calls
the constructor off this same class,
but super keyword calls
the constructors of the parent class
so that we don't have to repeat
the constructors
in all the child classes which are using
the fears of parent class.
But what do we call dog
and the B parameters?
This is also a constructor
to the also constructor.
If does that instead of initializing
the fears, instead of initializing
the fears,
I am calling the constructor of beta
to use this piece of code.
Yes, the same rules. The data types.
They must be
same as the data types of the parent class
and we use it for method and variables.
Yes, this is what we will discuss next.
We can do this.
All the methods and the variables.
Well, so effectively
constructors are inherited
with the use of super keyword.
We got this.
This will not be correct to say
that they are
inherited.
We are calling in here.
So there is something
like for example,
we have well, when we define something
and when we call something, when we define
a method and where we call in method.
So in inheritance, if you have defined
something in a parent class
and if that thing
participates in inheritance,
it will be copied
as it is inspired by child class.
But in here we are
calling that constructor.
We've combined
all last three topics together
expense classes, methods and constructors.
Yes, right.
So now what I can do,
I can create the object of,
the class,
and now I can use all the fields
from the
from the parent
class.
And I am not writing
those lines to initially size.
They something.
So what is happening right
now, these fields,
this data that we are writing in here,
first
it is being passed
to the constructor of dog
inside these variables.
Then it is being transferred
to the parent class constructor
with the help of this super keyword.
So this name then is going in here.
We see it in here,
in here, and then breathe in here.
And then it is being assigned
to the variables of this.
And then because we are extending
and technically these all these fields,
they are available inside the dog class,
but they are,
they are having separate copies
in their file.
When we see a dog not print,
we see the name inside this field,
then we will hold constructor for one.
You mean invoke whole constructor.
So we are invoking a whole constructor.
Are you guys done piping the score?
So this is the first use
of the super keyword.
Does it make sense guys?
Can you guys tell the benefit?
Well, what is the problem
that this super keyword is solving
with our parameters? Yes.
Yes. We can call the.
So let's say for example,
for one is saying
if we have a constructor, oops.
If we have a constructor,
we doubt that entity.
Okay.
So yes,
we can call that constructor as a
we can call any of the constructor
less calling.
So again, we are avoiding duplication.
If there is a parent class,
that parent class has maybe 100 fields
and we need to initialize those fields.
And if the child classes
are using those fears so every child class
has to write a constructor
to initialize those fields.
Okay, so in every class we will be writing
separate, separate constructors work
we can do, we can define a constructor
inside the parent class
and with the help of super keyword,
we can call that constructor
of the parent class.
Most of all,
make sure that this first list,
this dog class,
is outside of this bracket.
Yeah. Yes.
I think this is this is your issue.
You are writing the class
inside in here
inside this method,
the class bracket
and the Yes now is also right.
You need to pass
two more values to this constructor.
So this dog is expecting for Max,
but you are only passing
two arguments.
Is there anyone else
who is facing any issues?
So this is the first use
of super keyword life
when the parent class
has multiple constructors with super peak
on the right one using condition
sequence of variable number of variables.
Yes mom, you are right.
Same rules apply
if there are multiple constructors,
I will decide based on the parameters
which constructor to call.
Can I move to the next example?
If you guys are
done writing
this code, you don't have any questions.
So perfect and super the you are right
and super.
They are same things.
All right.
So the next example it's not giving me
option and read
loops
and you need a comma
and after name.
So let's say guys, we have
this class
employee
and inside this class we have an
integer
with salary.
Yes. And let's say base
salary is 30.
Now you don't need to type name, column
and then Bobby and all that,
except it's a feature of intelligence.
Yeah.
It's just it's giving you a suggestion.
You don't have to time that.
Can you please go back for a second? Yes.
By the way,
guys, you can press control and
to switch back and forth between
the windows that you were editing last
like this,
I am looking for seven days off in a week
type for job.
And I want
I keep on telling you these shortcuts
slowly, slowly,
but and I want you to practice them.
Anything else?
We don't know. I will teach you.
Can you repeat the shortcut?
First control and then the tab button
to switch back and forth
between the windows
that you guys open last.
And if you exactly want to check
the cursor location
where your cursor location was
before you place your cursor in here,
you can press
control our back arrow to go to the last.
Why aren't we where your cursor was?
It can be in different
filed in different packages
and you can use the right title to move
to the next position
where you placed your cursor.
So you can even do that to your cursor,
your history of cursors,
where you place your cursor.
It will be very helpful in when you will
be debugging large amounts of bug out.
If we screw something up
and you want to go back a step
so you can press
control, easy to undo it.
You can now press control.
I left Arrow to check the last line
that the last line that you edited
you can press control tab to switch and
to switch
between the windows back and forth here.
So right now
it's 7:24 a.m.
was writing Undo control
or Bad arrow
and Intel also keeps
a history of your files
so for example other than GitHub Intel
is also keeping a local history of your
so if you right click
you will see this local history
if you accidentally delete a file
or if you do something wrong,
you can go to the history
and all the files
and everything that I have been
editing on this Intel year
almost from I started using it
from ten nine, so nine out of
the last month
so I can check out those files
and all the history.
Okay, so you guys can get back
your files from here as well.
Yeah.
So you guys can have a backup on your tab,
but Intel
also keeps a backup on your computer.
Actually, you are not using it
before.
You mean the intelligent global?
I was not writing code
inside of this project.
I have other projects.
I mean, there are so many projects
I always use.
So if you see my recent news
are all my projects,
I always use intelligence.
I have never used Eclipse in my job.
And can you show it one more time?
What do you guys want me
to show one more time?
History.
Oh, it's right click.
And then local history.
All right, so let's move to the example.
We got example.
Here we go.
And then I have them at third. Avoid
salary.
So tired
either B off with one F
or we double F
English grammar masters.
Then you tell me
in one F, right.
Remove one from here and one here
and two FS.
Okay, let me put it back
and do you guys
sure.
And let's see.
So this is the best class.
Stop thinking about cheap calls. Ask.
So let's say I have
now a manager class
and in this organization
every class is extending from the class
and then
so many years
the pay scale of managers is
is in companies is a little different.
So let's say
they also shared some kind of bonus
other than the
other than the base salary
and then some kind of allows.
And if and then if we have to
calculate the salary of manager.
So obviously it will be different
than the salary of other employees.
Right. So
with me changes to potentially
Okay.
So so
it's always different
will always be different.
Yeah.
So let's see now this is how we calculate
the salary for the manager.
Okay it's just an example.
So we take the base salary,
but we want to use the base salary value
from the parent class.
Okay,
So but
because there is no.
So first let me let me show you only
only the methods.
So I want to have this basic salary.
So I have this function,
the basic function
inside class.
And then I want to have the same function,
the same name function in my child class.
Okay?
And then what I want to do,
I want to combine the functionality
of the parent class
method inside of the child class.
Now, for that,
what I can do, I can write super
and then I can write
the name of the method
that I want to use from the parent. Now,
because there is this conflict of names
so is exactly doing the same thing. B
as we used this keyword
to distinguish between a local variable
and instance variable.
And here we are using super keyword
to distinguish between a method
from the parent class and child class.
If if we have same name method
in parent and child class, if there is
there are no same name methods,
then we don't need that super keyword.
It's only needed
when we have same name methods
in the parent and in the in the child.
And for some reason we want to use
those letters from the parent class
inside the child class.
Okay.
Yes. Like this.
So now I can write
super dot print salary and
I can write
bonus multiplied
by traveling allowance like this.
So now I have some piece of functionality
that I am using from my business class.
Okay.
And then I am adding that functionality
inside, inside the exact same method.
So now what will happen
when I execute you?
Can you print that at your notes?
So everything is written on the slides
and I will put back on the notes
in the next class and then we will be
reasonably sizing things.
So let's say if we have a
Y multiply
or yes,
I want to, I want to reward
many days as much as I can.
Let's talk about how you multiply
the time instead of adding
Let me add this
just to make things simple.
Let me give values directly.
So these variables, energies
are always based.
The manager manager
is equal to new manager
and and I'll see if I see a manager dot
print salary.
So what will happen?
Must be
from the
class will be called.
And then this line after
this will be printed.
Okay, so 3000
from this method
which is present inside the parent class
with the help of super keyword, and
then I can write anything for back method.
So this is helpful
when let's say for example,
you have a method in your parent class
and it is doing maybe 60, 70 of the work
already, right?
And you want to add
maybe some new functionality
to the method
and you don't want to change the names.
So about
about
scenario scenarios, for example, managers,
they also get paid.
They also take days off, right?
So they are also getting paid.
They are also they also have days off
developers to the same right.
There may be other employees in the
in the company that we be doing the same.
So instead of coming up
with different names
for all these child
classes, what we can do,
we can have the same names
entire to be paid in class and entire day,
child class.
And if for some reason
you guys want to use
the method from the parent,
you right super with that.
If you want to use the method
from the child you don't need, don't
write anything same as you do
with instance variable and local variable.
If there is a conflict,
we write this with the instance variable.
We don't write anything
with the local variable.
Okay.
How to remove compiler
to check all classes.
What I have and check one method.
Alexi You mean you are facing some issues
and you want to exclude those files
from compilation
is it?
Didn't make sense guys
how the super keyword can be used
for the for the for to call the methods
or testers bonus will be minus one
program collapses
sure will please.
Okay.
I have a lot of classes
and have to check all my mistakes
so no Alex, you can
you can exclude the packages as well.
So instead of selecting
individual classes,
selectively packages,
but we cannot calculate or to celebrate.
No, we can.
We can.
We can. So,
so let's say for example,
instead of using this,
but instead of being attorney,
you want to use to salary directly,
you can do you can do that.
You can see
would be a
salary like this to calculate the
I don't like it how to change anyone else
or do you want to change?
I show my classes are showing
horizontally.
Okay. Can you repeat please?
Can you data total pay?
Yes, we can prepare.
Can you have more than one
method under super?
Under super. Like this?
No, only. Only.
So, for example, let's say
you are calling this method in here.
So for example, let's
assume there is this based off method.
And so did you.
Me If if said if you your question
that if you can use this print off
method with the super keyword
as well after this point salary.
Yes we can do it.
But if you try to do
with the constructors,
you will not be able to do this.
So constructors allow only one line.
You're still printing only the base
salary.
Maybe we need to close it. Let me try.
I think the classes
they will still be opening horizontally.
I don't know. But
if you
close the intelligent entry opening.
So instead of tried to close
the only the only default.
So this is how we can distinguish
between the between the methods.
Now let's say guys,
let me make same variables as well.
So instead of base salary,
let me make a salary.
Okay,
so let's say a B basic salary
for the employees
is, is this.
And then we have the basic salary inside
the child classes as well, like this.
So now
if you guys want to use
the variable from the parent,
this salary variable, can you guys tell me
how can I use this variable
inside this method?
If I want to refer to the parent
class function?
So I want to use this 30,000
instead of the salary.
So right now,
right now,
if I write, if
I write salary, then
then I see this
50,000 plus ten plus 250 210.
Okay. Like this.
But if I want to use this base
salary from the parent, I again need
super and then daughter.
Okay.
And Now if I execute deferred
so now I see 38,250.
Okay so same as we case
with that with the with the case with that
this keyword here
if you want to use the variables
from the parent class you can write super.
If you want to use the variables
from the same class,
you can use simply
the name of those variables.
Okay.
And on this list there is another example
that will make more sense.
So let's say, for example.
So what is this super keyword?
Super keyword in Java is again
a reference variable.
This was also
this keyword was also a reference variable
which is used to refer to immediate
parent class.
What does this immediate period class
mean?
Guys, if I have a grade
A grandparent class, can I refer to
the variables of that grandparent
with the help of super keyword?
If I have grandparent, then parent
and then child,
and if I am, if
I am writing the code inside the child
class, can I Part of the variables
of grandparent?
I can not. Okay.
So immediate parent class means I
can only use or I can only
access the variables of the parent class.
So not more than that. Yes.
Just one level up
before use of java support keyword
so super can be used to refer
immediate parent class instance variables.
Okay.
Remember that you should use
double super for that. Yes.
Okay.
So a super can be used to refer
to the immediate
parent class instance to super.
Super can be used to invoke immediate
be it in class methods as well.
So fees plus method
and the constructor as well.
Okay.
So now I have more control over our
how I to write my code.
I can use now the constructors as well
from the parent class.
Yeah.
And if I have any conflict
I now know how to resolve that conflict.
Right.
Let's say for example,
someone has written a class like we get
Java guys
because we cannot edit that class.
So now don't need to come up
with the different names
for the methods
and fields in our child classes.
We can have the same name methods.
Super is used to that
for the immediate parent class, so it's
only works for hierarchical inheritance.
No, it will work for single as well
and for
multi-level
as well, but only until one level,
only one level up
can super be changed.
What do you mean by changed?
Can we make more examples with super? Yes.
So Alexa, right now I have.
I only have 15 minutes.
So first let me
so this is another example.
First let me go to this slide
and if we are left with time,
we will do more examples.
Can you explain the immediate
one more time?
So under if there is this class error
and here if we have an integer variable,
some, then there is this class
B, then
there is this class C.
Now inside C
I cannot access this integer S
If this B is extending
from here and this C is extending
from B,
okay, so now I have a class in between.
I cannot access this some
because this is not the immediate parent.
The immediate parent is the class B
and that parent class
has a super to another parent class
and their parent parent class has is super
to another parent
like immediate family members.
Yes. Of the you can see that.
But in inheritance, it's
a little different.
So let's show you guys this.
I have this for each of the class.
Then there is this
class, which is extending from fun nature.
Now, both the classes are
they have this color variable.
Okay, They have this color variable.
And if I want to print the color
of the Kir
class, I can simply write
this variable name color.
It will refer to this black.
But if I want the value of this,
I need to write super. Then
go back over
to this color variable in here and now.
If you print this
then you will see first black
and then you will see that
super can be used to invoke weird in class
method as well.
If you have same name third in the parent
class and in child class.
So now again
you will be having an ambiguity
because as is the case
with the local variables,
dollar always prefers by default.
Now I always prefer the local variables.
So same is the case with the meters and
the variables in here in child classes.
Always, always.
The methods from the child
classes will be preferred
the fields from the child
classes will be preferred.
But if you for any reason want to use
the parent class methods and figures,
you can this super keyword like
for example, and it's a super big change.
Like basic class
C has a super that refers to method
found in class B
and the method in class B has a super.
That is a reference to the method.
Yes, Mom. Well, you can do that
if I comment.
Our super keyword is still working.
How so?
Yes, it will work because it will refer
to the same class variable.
Okay.
But it will always be printing
that those results.
It will never be printing the results
from the parent.
Well, now,
does it make sense?
The only way to access
A jumping B is to use for.
No, we cannot.
We cannot jump on B,
you know, this is what I am.
I am trying to convey.
We cannot force this.
Maybe even with help of super keyword,
we can only access the variables of class
B with the super keyword,
not the variables of class
E If we are inside B, class C
or okay, so we use the super.
If same name is yes,
this condition should be there.
Otherwise it's pretty much same.
Otherwise it will not matter if you use
super or if you don't use super.
If there is no conflict,
if there is no same
variables or same name matters. Okay.
Otherwise it will be same
because you are actually adapting
to the same variable.
Super keyword also used to access
the methods of parent class.
We can also do that.
So let's say for example,
in the furniture class we have this color
in this year class,
we have also a color method.
And then
there is this wide working method in which
want to use the functionality
of both methods.
Okay, I want the
the color method from the parent class
and I want to.
So if you don't write the super,
the color from the child
class will be used inside
this work method.
But if we super the color from the parent
class will be used.
And this is the example of calling
the constructor of the parent class.
So in here we have the constructor
inside the furniture inside of it here,
and we are using super keyword
to call this constructor from the parent
or to the books
of like specific inheritance.
And super is always
the parent is super is always the better.
If I am in class C with the help of super,
I can only work with class B
with the class.
I will not be able to love ESL.
Okay.
You are right.
So this is the difference between super
when you use
without the parentheses
and independent to do so.
But it used to call the super class
variables
with our dependencies and
objects
when they are overridden by subclass.
So this new keyword overridden
it means if we have same name, methods or,
same name fears in the child class,
we also call it overriding the child.
The class is overriding the fields
or the methods from the parent class.
Okay, so let's say
you don't like something from your parents
and now you are independent.
You are more than 18.
So you can that okay,
you can have your own on
own thing on top of your parents.
Okay.
Well then if they are allowed
to live in their house or not,
it totally depends on them.
And then we have this super
is used to call super class constructor
from the base class.
Okay.
So inside you are inside the child class
and you don't want to rewrite
the constructor again and again
to initialize the fields
so you can use the super with parentheses
to call the constructor of the parent
class.
This is this keyword is used to refer
to the current class
instance as well as static members.
Okay, so Buddy is used to refer
to this super class instance as well as
static members or
we can use be
this as well as super animate
except this static area.
So let's say for example,
if I have a static method, I cannot use
super in there, I cannot use this,
I cannot use any instance variable
and because it
super and this they are always
referring to instance variable.
So it is not allowed.
All right.
So tomorrow it's a very simple thing.
You guys have already done this,
by the way,
this method overloading it
because I already know about this.
Also, we can cover
more than that.
Tomorrow is a review.
So next week is the week
for which all of you are waiting.
Okay, so you see this keyword
we were
and then everything will be easy peasy.
The reality is come out.
I need a major recap
so worth the period you
Maryam, I will ask you in the next week
or so after
after the class on Sunday
if it is the new joke for me
be is equal to two years.
So are you guys revising
the slides?
Maybe 2 to 3 slides per day?
Syntax Explainer Because
I think you will be having.
Okay, so you, you just have one more week
and then you guys will start
with the selenium classes, Okay?
From part B of this
year.
And yeah, so here is super slides.
So there have already been shared
before this class.
Yes. On Thanksgiving
there will be no class on 25th next week.
We are almost done with Java.
Yes, 8 to 10 more classes.
So here
the fun will start the selenium classes
because you guys will be using
all the knowledge.
All the knowledge you are.
So how are they doing this class, guys?
Well, they're tough, easy.
It'd be weird, this topic bit weird.
He said, We will cry.
No, no, no, no.
Listen to them.
They are discussing something else.
Is Selenium as hard as Java?
No, no, no. Selenium is super easy
in this whole course, if you ask me.
Most only. Sure.
And this is the feedback from them
that Java is the hardest thing
in this course.
No easier to solve there.
So Selenium is not a software
you can think of.
Selenium is all all Java
will talk about.
It's not easy to remember
when you need to use odd coding
or asking about selenium.
It's it was not
but now need to focus on punctuations
and keeping all things one place
nurse me right
now the name is very fancy
I thought it is a software
so it's a library, it's a framework.
It's actually a lot of things
is a lot of pain collection of
so many tools and techniques that you guys
can use to manipulate your browser.
You guys will learn about the frameworks,
the collection of a lot of classes,
solving something.
All right, So let's call it
a day or night.
I have already shared this slides
for my part overloading
and I will share the videos as well
and I hope you guys are
okay.
You guys will revise
all the Java slides before
before your selenium classes.
Then there
there are some very, very important
the slides.
I will share the notes and record
right after the class.
Bye bye. Take care.