We should be regarding.
Don't be that pessimistic.
All right.
So those who are for my moment,
is facing this issue, this issue.
So let's say I make a mistake
inside this file, okay?
And now if I try to run this file in side
this glass 15
intelligent will take me to the file
where I am having that issue
instead of running that file.
So those who are facing this issue,
what do you guys can do?
So I want you to double
click your shift button quickly.
If you do that, you will see this window.
Do you guys see this window?
Then you showed us how to transfer
from intelligent clips from Mac.
So, Sheriff, I will not suggest you
to do that right now.
Okay? At least to spend
one week with intelligent.
Once you are a little familiar
about the interface
with the interface, then I will.
I will show you how to do that.
It is very simple. Very simple.
So do you see the screen?
Now I want you to type
exclude,
not exclude
or ignore,
and let me first find it manually
and then I will show you.
Not excludes, not exclude it.
Excuse, but
we will.
Here we go.
So guys, type exclude
double shift
your double click on your shift
button quickly twice.
And then you should see this window.
So from here you can search
almost everything inside your intelligent.
It can be a file,
it can be a note by Java file directory
setting the get tab, any menu,
anything that exists in the intelligent.
You can search that from this window.
All the methods, variables, classes,
no packages,
settings, everything.
So do you guys see this excludes option
or now
I want you to click on back
and after that
you guys should see this window.
Do you guys saved
now those packages.
So we can exclude
if you want to follow those that way
in the future
you might want to use this feature.
So in here,
if some classes in my project,
if they are having issues
and I don't know how to fix them
or I just want to run any file
and I am unable to do that
because I am having errors in other files.
So what I can do, I can tell invalidate
to ignore those files
or even you can ignore complete packages.
Now, if you ignore
a complete package of the file,
that file will not be a part of execution.
So you have to click on this plus button.
Then you expand your project
scores.
How? And in here
you will see a list of all the packages.
Okay, So right now I am having an issue
in this main dark java.
So I will click on.
Okay.
And then do you guys
have you guys selected a file?
Just make any syntax error and select
that file.
So sorry if you have to click on this
plus button that says add
and then you should see all the projects
inside the intelligent
and then you expand your project
like this.
Then this whole folder
excludes exclude will
exclude these files from compiler.
I so compiler
will not compile these files.
Do you have any project
in your intelligent?
If you guys don't have any project,
then you definitely
you will not be seeing this.
Right?
So first you have to create the project.
Okay, I'm not.
I will summarize this for you,
but those who don't have any projects,
definitely you guys will not be facing
this issue and you guys don't need that.
If you faced this issue,
maybe you can later, at later
point of time,
you can watch this recording.
So just just watch me carefully
what I am doing in here.
Okay?
And then in the future,
if you guys need this, you can
you can follow these steps.
Now select that file which contains error
and then click on.
Okay,
It takes me to the document folder.
I can also share the screenshot
how you are selecting that file,
and then you guys have to click on apply
and then okay, so
let me repeat.
Okay, so now if you guys focus,
you should see a cross sign,
a very small cross sign
on ontology
or the title of your file towards
the left, left of your file.
That means this file has been excluded
from compilation.
It will not be compiled,
it will not be executed.
Then we can share the screenshot.
And now
we are third file.
And now if I execute my program
now intelligent
don't care about that file anymore.
You can exclude the complete directories,
complete packages
and even complete project
if you are working on multi project
application.
But give me and I shall kindly
share the screenshots.
It saves the code automatically.
You guys don't have to save
or you guys don't have to do anything
I share.
And you me First,
you guys have to look at your project so.
Right.
If you expand this window,
this is where my project is stored.
It is stored.
And see you the resident of the Idea
project and then blah, blah, blah.
Okay,
so first we have to look here, there,
and then you have to go inside the SBC
folder.
Did you open the project first time?
Is that beginning?
No, that was the part of that, that video
in which I showed you
how to create a project.
I hope you everyone has and has a project
in in Delhi.
Okay, let's create some
files and then I will repeat
these instructions again.
Okay.
These instructions again.
Is there anyone who who can not still run
that hallowed program?
No one. Everyone can run the intelligent.
Everyone can run the So
to create a new project.
But now I can not run the first
hello project and I will
I will show you how to do that.
How to do that.
Don't worry. Yes.
Dennis,
your your approach looks good.
Now you have to select that file
that contains the issue.
So this is the base package
and then these are the sub packages.
So if I want to create a new package,
I will right click,
then I will say a new
and then package here
and then I can see
last thing
and I'm creating a file
to write the note for you.
You guys don't need to do this.
Give me
You have selected the complete project.
You have excluded the complete project.
Well, why are you
have opened the project structure window
for it?
It was running.
That means you have to include that
file again.
I will.
Do you see this crawl sign on your file?
Okay.
So if you want to include a file back,
you guys can repeat these steps.
Double to double click on the shift
button.
Type excludes
and then you should see this file in here
so you can select that file
and you can click on this minus button
that should include the file
in compilation again.
Okay.
But make sure now you
remove the errors before you run back.
Okay?
So that's how we include
and exclude file from compilation.
So ha.
So we add all projects from
previous classes and that is that's it.
Nothing else.
So right now we will not be doing that.
Alex We will do at least after one week
and then in a weekend class,
not make the class
because you guys will be facing
a lot of issues.
Can you please show me
again how to create a project?
So, I mean,
this is how we create a project.
We right click on base package
and then new and then package.
You should see this package option.
It you take
medium expand that.
So this is what you see right now.
Expand your project.
Then you should see this SBC folder.
Then you should see your base package
create a new package
inside your base package
and then you can start following
all our guys.
Let's start from the recap.
So can you guys tell me, what did we cover
in the last class
construct
right?
What are the structures?
Can you guys define a constructor
the way you will be answering it
in your interviews?
I can't do it f as
it is this special type of method
which is used to initialize
the object are not method.
For one,
you can say it's a special block of code,
same as method,
but with the restrictions and limitations.
Okay, block off
code to initialize the instance variables.
So I don't know, but
it's not a discouragement for others.
So try to look at the definitions
from your little guys.
He always writes a good definition
and the students who are able
to explain the concepts
in a well manner to others.
Usually these are the students
who will be getting the jobs faster.
So it's a very important skill
to have to be able
to explain something in a proper way.
Constructing a Java is a block of words
similar to a method
that Vanguard mycology shows.
You have written this on
your own and not from Google
called automatically
when a new instance of an object
is created.
It's a block of code similar to the method
because in your interviews
they will not allow you to use Google
again.
So the structure is a
special block of code that
help us
build
or construct
the object.
And what do I mean
by builder construct?
Can you guys tell me,
what do I mean when I say I am building
a meeting, an object,
or constructing an object
is Class 18 is created as a class?
No, it's a package.
I mean, it's a package.
A special type of matter.
This is not correct.
Constructor is not a method.
Initialize.
Constructors are a block of code.
It has a same name as class name.
It does not have written type even wide.
There would also be.
Can you guys tell me what what does
what?
What do I mean by build or construct
the block of code similar to a method
that's called an instance
or an instance of an object
block of code
to execute preconditions for the object?
Yes, that is also correct.
Two types of constructors
non argument and parameterized
when we create an object.
Constructors already called. Okay.
So all of these answers
are not kind of clause,
but not
what the interviewers will be looking for.
Again,
if you guys are answering like this,
most probably they will not be liking you
so try to write something
more formal and complete a special method
to initialize.
No, it's a special type of method
which is used to initialize the object.
So if this is written on
the slides, let me fix that.
We go there.
It is not. Would
you give me a
can you tell me this slide number?
How can I import my java?
Please import my java.
You mean Java projects Now?
Okay.
Can you guys tell me what that
what does it mean
by initialize the object?
The constructors are used to better
control your code
and go through specific parameters
before executing a block of code.
Looks good.
Also, we can say it's a constructor name
which is with the class name
and if it does not have a written type,
yes, declare create an object.
So by constructing we mean
giving any initial value
to the fields.
Okay.
All right.
So when we write New and then
class name and these parentheses,
this is the line that triggers
the execution of the constructor.
When would our new class name?
This is the
world that
executes the
character for
our class.
Okay, guys,
what if I am not providing a constructor?
What happens then?
Builder constructor
means to initialize the states and behave.
Yes. Yes, you are right.
Java will do this for us.
Right? When we do
not world wide
and we do not.
I make some structure
before
vector
is provided
by java
compiler.
All right.
And if I have multiple constructors
guys in a class,
if I have multiple constructors,
how do Java know which constructor
to call
by the parameters?
Yes. But how? How what? What? What?
It will look inside those parameters.
Okay, so one way is it can check
how many parameters we are passing.
But what if I am having a constructor
with same number of parameters?
One is taking a string and an integer
and the other one is taking two integers.
Okay, so in here the number of parameters
they are same.
Both of the constructors
are taking two parameters.
Now what Java will do
by this type of parameters to
say And what if I am
specifying the parameters
in a different order?
In one constructor
I provide string first, then integer.
In the second constructor I provide
an integer first and then a string.
Now what I will do Now I have same number
of parameters, different types
of parameter, different data,
types of parameters, checks three things.
It will check the number of parameters,
type of parameters, and then the sequence
of parameters as well.
So if,
if there are
multiple
factors
in a class
Java will check
the number of
number of
meters
type of parameters
and sequence of
parameters.
So for some of you, it might not be clear.
So let me do an example for you. So
how do I create a constructor, guys?
What should I write
If I want to have a constructor
class name,
can I can I use the access modifiers?
By the way,
what are access modifiers guys?
Public priority
is is static.
A is a static and excess modifier
engrained so
I can have access modifiers
like public in here.
So let's say
I have a string named integer H.
Yes, static is non access modifier
and then if I try to write a constructor
in which I am again passing a string
and and indeed it also does these names,
they also matter
if I change these names will be like,
will I be unable?
Will I be able to get rid of this error
but only the data type
that matters?
So these names, they can be anything.
They don't matter. Okay,
so if I pass this in procedure first
and then the string again,
Java does not give me any issues.
Okay,
then then let me also have
B for the constructor.
That's only a zero argument constructor
not to default Me.
All right.
Okay.
Just to explain things,
let me just put the numbers inside
these constructors
do three
and four.
Okay, So now I have multiple constructors.
Multiple constructors.
Okay, In here I am only explaining
how Java decides
which constructor to call.
Okay.
In intelligent
Now, did you try that before
e map? Yes.
It will be slower, but with the time.
What intelligent does it
creates indexes off your code.
Your files and everything.
So let's say if you are working on a big
project, having maybe a thousand files
now after having
thousand files in delegate
will be much, much faster
and the eclipse will get slow
because it creates indexes of the files.
And at the moment you type something
to search through those files
or if you want to refactor something
or if you are want to do
anything about itself with those files,
it will be simpler, quick.
So with time it will get faster.
So. Right, because you guys are most
probably installing it the first time.
So it will take some time to
index all of your autofill settings
and other things and all that
searching.
Okay, let me show you one more.
Okay, So double click
the shift button quickly
and then type
font size
that is now
it's not giving me the option.
What type of file.
So say you just create file.
And if you put an extension
with the name like Dot XD,
it will create a text file.
If you write the extension as dot neo,
it will create a word file
excel file
so you can create any type of file.
Just click on that file
or you want to create a java file
and you are unable
to get an option for that.
So you have again imported the project
from Eclipse.
Oh no, this is not how we do that.
So you have to create a new project.
So to create a new package
now you have to write click,
and then you have to select
new and then package it
to double click on your shift button.
Quickly.
That's it. Twice.
One. Now,
do you see the option to create a package
to welcome?
Yes, if this is what I am showing.
So you guys have to double click quickly.
Then you have to click on font size
and then there is a quick
shortcut tools that
retain the font size from here.
And then you will see this option
that says change
font size with the control
plus mouse wheel.
The last option.
Do you guys see this option
and font size with control plus mouse Will
Alexa Right now I will suggest you
to create a new project,
but don't delete this one.
It will work.
I will tell you how to do that
on the Mac.
Your same check
if you have the shifter button.
How to change the appearance of Dark.
Okay.
I will tell you that as a
what do you mean by double
clicking on shift button?
So, Nabeel, this is my keyboard.
This is my favorite button.
I click twice on the the button.
This is what I mean,
click press.
So you guys have to double click
your shift button.
You have to press your shift
button twice quickly.
Okay?
And then I see how you can hold down
your control button and then you can use
the wheel of your mouth
to increase and decrease the font.
Okay. So do you guys see this option? Now,
I want you to turn on this feature
you select.
You have to click on new and then project,
and now you can hold down your control
and then press the you can
move your wheel
to increase the zoom or decrease it.
Click on next.
Alex.
Alex I share that with you in the course
and also our channel
in which I showed
how to create a new project
and how to install a JDK
if you don't have one.
And those who are asking for team,
you guys don't need to memorize
those long
and long navigations to the side view.
Just dive team
and you should it should appear in here,
you press in it, that's their team.
You'll see intelligent light windows
then Dracula.
By contrast, you can select whichever
you guys want. Yes.
Or double
click your shift button twice quickly
and then type team
so you guys can
then switch almost everything inside
the intelligent from here.
Do you see this
option? The option for teams
and this is how you choose the 18.
Are there other options?
Okay,
so okay,
I have created these constructors.
Now let me clear to test class
and let me open your
I hope you guys can read.
You are going to celebrate default
all our day.
So there is one more feature
of intelligent and that will confuse you.
So let me show you that we see Class 18.
We choose new file or plain class file,
new Java file.
You should see an option
to create a new Java file.
So let me create a
let me create an object
I have drive these two parameters
and now what intelligent will do,
it will show you to which variable
this string will copied.
So this named or colon,
you guys don't have to type it.
It is just
a just a suggestion
that this string variable
will be copied to a variable
which is named name inside this class.
So this named or column is to kind of hint
from the intelligent.
Okay, so you guys don't have a type.
Would you just type string comma
and then pull
and then you should see these suggestions.
You guys see these suggestions?
You guys don't have to type
in these suggestions.
Okay.
Previous pages,
they were making a lot of mistakes.
They they were trying to type
these name call
and then double code things
and then all that.
But you guys don't have to do that.
Remove that because we don't need that.
So now is there any hot forces out
in intelligent.
Yes it's s out and then you hit enter
I disabled that
did not work Katrina.
What what didn't work
as not you guys have to type s
out like this.
How many of you have not watched the video
on basic
overview of intelligent?
Because I have showed these things
already in that video.
Then that's why I showed them.
Because I don't.
I don't want to waste the time of class.
How to create a package, how to create
a class, how to create a project,
how to find out these shortcuts,
how to write these s out.
I showed everything.
All right, can you guys tell me
which constructor will be called
if I pass a string and an integer,
The number one, two, three,
or four.
So in intelligent, you can right click
and then click on run test or you can
click on this green button
and then you can run or
click on run test multiclass from here.
And then you should see the output
in your console.
Okay.
And if I change this to
like this, so still I'm passing an integer
and and a string,
but this time Java will execute
the constructor
number three.
And if I don't pass anything,
then the constructor number one
will be executed.
And if I pass three parameters, first,
add a string second, then beta
and third as double, then the fourth one,
which we will be called by mistake.
By the way, your instructor for Hal,
he is not feeling well.
He is having severe flu cough
and some other issues
and he might be hospitalized tomorrow.
So you guys might want to ask
how he's viewed,
how he feels once he is back.
New name.
So you see you have made the same mistake.
So this is what I was saying.
Can you guys tell me what is the mistake?
Well, why? And he is getting an error.
He he typed the name and then call and is
so you you don't have to type this name.
And then Colon
I still will do the review multiple.
So you guys only type string double course
and then don't type
this name and then column
if just a suggestion from the invalidate
that the string will be copied
to this name variable.
Is there anyone else
who is facing any issues
if this string
and so are you guys done typing the score
then can I close these files?
Just this string and save?
Give me.
You have also done the same mistake.
You don't have to type that name
dot column
and not worry Maria.
I am immune to you guys.
I will always be here is there is no place
to go.
Well, I had a problem.
It turns out by misspelled
the name of my constructor only drove
me insane for 5 minutes. And
so Dennis, you do not have a main method.
Come on, man,
I'm in this.
Is this the very first thing
that we taught you
that you guys need the main?
Please don't get sick
and don't get sick of us. Do
multi class guns Demo one related problem.
So, Katrina,
you are creating a class inside a class
line three and line four
import
com dot company and or multi class in fine
silver art fine.
You have created
that class in a different package.
So now intelligent is importing
that class from that package.
Are there other issues quickly
if there is if there are too many issues
in this four channel you guys can send
some of the issues in here
how to combine these two classes.
They now you mean how to
display them side by side
or you just need to drag
and drop your file
and then it will show you the option.
So for example, if I my mouse
is not working correctly, actually, if I,
if I drag and move this class in different
places, lady will show me where to.
Where do you want to place that file?
I am not getting a double file.
This is what I am getting now.
Will you have created a Kotlin project?
And you wrote that code in quarterly
as well in the previous file as well
so make sure you are creating
in Java project.
Not calling because invalidate or multiple
programing languages.
So when you when you say file new
and then project,
make sure you you select this
java from here, this JDK step two
and you don't select this
for clean JVM or anything else.
No, it's not an installation issue.
It's the project.
Yes, you guys can write Python as well.
In the Intelligent, they did a variant of
intelligent in which you can write Python
now will create a new project
and then select Java and make sure
you have the JDK and then you click Next,
create a project from template
command line and then you press notes
and you should see a project.
Are there other issues?
Just give me one moment. This
What do you do with Double Sieve?
We was adding something
so you same as you do in your database
that click on keep operating on that
header of this file
in this title area
and then you can drag and drop your file.
And what do we do with double shift?
So with double shift,
you can search to the intelligent
so medium.
You have done the same thing.
You have imported
the classes from Eclipse.
You have to create a new project.
Otherwise you have to fix all the issues
in your or all of your classes.
Okay.
Let's go back to the notes
of these files.
Okay.
So tell me, guys, what what are
the other things that you remember
about the constructors?
Are we just typing manually name and age
or can you repeat it please?
So right now you are again
the same mistake.
You guys don't have to type
that name and age
before the this keyword.
Can you guys
tell me more about the constructors?
Like for example,
can I have the return type or not?
When the constructor
who we have
two constructors are default constructor
and the parameterized constructor
must be of the same name as of class.
So these are some of the rules.
Constructors have
the same name
as the
class name
and then constructors
don't have
a rewritten types
not even required
by constructor.
Non argument and parameters.
If constructor does not have parameter,
it means before constructor.
No, it means that the zero argument
constructor
you are using constructor
to only slightly data series.
Yes, that is correct.
Use of code is executed.
Really? Yes.
How? If I have multiple
constructors in a class
and if I am doing something
similar in all the constructors,
can I do something to remove
the code duplication or maybe reuse
some code from one instructor
inside the other instructor?
How can I do that?
Guys, this scalar drive,
we can use this
this user with
this is
so in work.
By the way.
It is also called
invoking the constructors.
I can just another term. This to invoke
the other
things.
Characters
of the same class.
Yeah.
And there was one more
use of the this keyword
then you guys tell me that
and that as well.
So now is going to we can not have
an example of default constructor.
It is automatically added by a compiler
and it is hidden from the programmers.
We don't see that.
It's just what if we don't create one?
It is created
automatically injected automatically
and therefore called automatically.
What is the other use of this keyword
To differentiate
between the instance variables
and the constructor variables?
Can I distinguish between
local variables of a method as well?
Mohammad
Can we invoke constructor
from another class? Yes.
By creating the object,
this is what we do.
For one, this is how we have been
invoking the constructors
and when we write new
and the name of the class
and then parentheses, this is what we are.
This is what we were doing.
We were in looking at constructor.
This used to get instance.
This keyword can be used
inside the constructor, so
this can be,
this can be used to
differentiate
local and
instance
variables.
So these local variables,
they can be of a constructive
and they can be of a method.
All right.
Now let's quickly solve the homeworks.
So we solve the first two homework right?
First, what tasks
I like.
Can you guys send me the
description,
the question statement for question
number three? Yes.
Just give me one moment.
Okay.
I hope you guys can see it now
of eight
Java class that have four constructors.
And I close this
because I will be sharing this business
with you.
Yes, I sure we can do that.
Remind me if I don't.
You get concerned.
All you can do, you can always send me
a feedback and we can discuss in a class.
If majority is majority master, we can
do there.
Okay. So
yeah, sure, we will be writing these notes
in the start of every class from now on.
So right in Java class
that have four constructors
with four different access levels
of constructor,
private public default protected
and create for object of this class
one inside the same class
two from outside the class
three from different class inside
different package and observe the results.
Okay, so
let me quickly create
a private constructor.
Okay, let me call it one
then.
What is the next level of access
after private
if the default one.
Okay, not not known or public
and well, why?
I'm getting another race
are not protected.
Comes after the default one.
And today
we will learn about the protected
as the
duplication default
needs to be first
default are not need to be first.
It can be anywhere
but most restricted is private.
Then we have default, then protected,
and then public.
Okay, I can I can pass any argument
for their java.
Then allow me multiple constructors.
Then we have the
affected one
next class in period in here
and then the
public one
works fast
and double with me.
Okay.
So this is how I can create
for constructors with the different access
levels.
Now as per question, what we have to do,
we have to create
the objects
using all of these for constructors
first inside this same class
and we have to observe,
observe the result.
So let me try to create an object
to be
okay.
I am able to create an object for
by using this first constructor.
Then let me try this second one. The.
For the second one I have to pass a string
name for the third one I have to pass.
And indeed here.
And for the fourth one
I have to pass a double
so I don't get any issues.
Okay, then I am doing this.
Inside this same class
I am able to create constructor
for the objects
using any of the constructors.
Now let's try to do the same,
but this time in a different class.
So let's copy this code
and then when you demand method
and then let me open Firebase,
now we get an error.
Can you guys tell me why
we are getting an error?
Right?
It will be accessed only within the class.
Yeah.
So the access modifier as it works
with the features and the method
is the same with the constructors as well.
So because this constructor
is a private constructor,
I cannot create an object
by using this constructor
in a different class.
And by the way, this was,
this was a question.
So I gave an interview
and this was a question inside
that interview,
the question was
Make this class.
So there was a constructor
and there was no access modified
with that constructor,
and the question was modified.
This class
so that it cannot be instantiated
from a different class.
So we make the constructor private
and then no one will be able
to instantiate that class
from another class.
Is it frozen for everyone?
Okay, now, so right now
we are inside the same package
at the inside of the same package.
The You were a recruiter?
No, I was not a recruiter.
I was the candidate.
So let me create a class
outside of this package, mega
outside of this is
and let's try to copy
all the because
from here
oops the main method first
actually let me do this check me print
by make
the default
and then
I have been already hired
by more than 200 companies.
So let me try to.
Oh, by the way,
I forgot to take the screenshots.
Let me check if she had shared
only the email
from the company.
So at least we have one screenshot.
But like
I say, you can
you can have that in your repository.
By the way.
Now I guess it was you
you were deleting the file from the
from that shared repository
from batch ten.
So they,
they did, they were very confused why
someone is trying to delete that files.
I think you tried to edit those files
or tried to do something like that.
So guys, make sure you don't delete the
that are the questions on the screenshot
which are already there
if you want to modify something
or if you want to add more force for you,
you can create a copy of that file
and then you can modify
that file.
So you see Oops
is wrong.
But 11
always.
This keeps trying to clear things
from interview prep log
to see.
Now I barely
so let's
please make sure you don't delete the
existing data.
No I don't mean GitHub.
I mean the file.
I mean you will not study yourself
and you will not let others to study.
Right.
Okay. So
if it wasn't an interview question.
So guys, it right now
I am in a different package
and yes, I am unable to access
the private constructor.
So now you guys will
oops see the difference up.
I am also unable to access
this default constructor in here.
Okay.
So if I am inside a different package,
I can not access the private
plus I cannot access
the default ones,
but I can still access the protected one
and then the public one.
Okay, so
this is the difference.
So it's a little different from Eclipse.
Yes. Yes.
If you're seeing different from the views.
You mean the way we are unable to access
some of the files?
It's not because of intelligent
Java, Right.
Is there the task? Two and three?
Should we move to the task for.
But I just put all the questions in
same page to print them
and I didn't realize it until I printed
but open Google docs and make my copy.
It's fine.
Can you guys send me the question
number four?
Could you please post notes?
I checked for some.
I couldn't find it.
You couldn't find because I didn't post
right
program that have started constructors.
So sometimes I have to be north, slid
on the canvas, I publish on the canvas.
Sometimes I push
them, will be on the from now on
I will be pushing everything to the gate
hub, so nodes and everything will be
pushed to the gate and you guys can clone
these projects on your intelligence
and you can quickly get an update from the
variety program
that have static constructor
and observe the results.
So why did you create package for our task
if it's good for organization?
So if your task requires multiple files,
you guys can create a sub package
inside another package for further
organizing your code.
Let me create a task for
constructor
and then let me try to write code
parity with that.
Okay.
So the moment I did static,
I get an error.
The modifier static is not allowed.
No. We need to get back to intelligent
install for intelligent.
No, you guys don't need the mutable has
nothing to do with eclipse or intelligent.
You can push anything from any project
on your computer
if that folder if you initialize
that folder as the get repository,
if talk directly
to inherit your makeup or something,
you can.
Okay.
So this is a non access modifier
and none of the non access
modifiers allowed in here.
So the first output, let's have a break
and if you guys are having any issues
with the intelligence.
So we still have 5 minutes,
you guys can ask me those
who want to leave for a longer break.
You can leave.
I will not be showing anything.
And after the break,
we will start with the new topic.
From now on,
we are going to be using Intel.
Yes, Sebastian,
and depends on the instructor.
Some of the instructors
might be using different ideas
or so for selenium
cucumber test and you guys will be using
intelligent clips for that skill.
You will be using something different.
API is back to or eclipse.
Yes, most of the time
it would be intelligent.
I think I shared it over there.
The interview questions here.
Mohammad
Aisha has the link for that repository
so you can ask her for coding
when we are coming back.
We are coming back on it 40
No questions.
You guys want me to have some rest
squared? Thank you.
No issues in the intelligent.
All right, perfect.
Remind me about recording
once we get back
to, we start recording.
So can I close this and this task for
and task three files.
Great.
Maryam, to try to share
these kind of resources with each other.
Guys.
Alright, so
today we will discuss about inheritance.
Can you just tell me
what is inheritance in your life
when your father passed to you?
About only the wealth.
When you get something from a relative
parent's
is genes to all the habits
or not all the habits.
I mean most of the habits.
And then skin color, eye color,
hair color,
like we getting our genes
or anything comes from our elders
and so classes, they can also inheritance,
they can also do the inheritance,
they can also have parents.
They can also have jars.
So can you guys
guess what will what will happen
if there is a parent class
and there is a child class?
And if we do the inheritance
with those classes,
combine all properties to one main class.
Okay,
same behavior inherit matter
only matter.
The assignment.
When a class gives an output,
that output can be used
for another block of or are not know
Muhammad, This is not correct.
One class
and other ones that use the word extend.
Yes, yes.
The variables as well.
It's a mechanism in Java
in which we object acquired
all properties of the parent
object are not object class.
So if you replace the object
keyword with the class, your your
your definition is almost perfect.
New classes build up on existing classes
with similar properties and behavior
when object acquires all the properties.
So let me show you
with a very simple class.
Can you guys tell me,
can you guys tell me what is common
between a cat and a dog?
The common behaviors?
And is there anyone from a bio background
who can maybe tell us
if if there is something common between
not I think there is something common
between a cat and a lion, right?
Biologically
species,
they are mammals.
They are both animals.
Okay, let's keep it simple. Let's create
and okay,
so first let me create a class.
So tell me, guys,
some of the attributes of the via
the famous attributes of spring name
are Spring breed.
No cow. Yes, we can.
We can have a go as well.
So now you are
all of you are behind your guitar.
And that's why she disappeared.
Spring Bella Age
or GABA.
Okay.
And if you let me let me have some methods
well so avoid
it. Okay.
And let me create a dog class.
Be famous.
And the example.
Can you guys tell me
if I copy
everything from cat or dog
so cat can eat?
Dog can also eat like that.
Can sleep dog going out of sleep.
Cat can have a name, name dog can have.
So all these properties
that I am writing in here,
they are also present inside a cat, right?
They can also be present inside a
or almost all the mammals.
Right.
You guys will be seeing that those four
legged animals, you guys will be seeing.
You guys can have these
same properties, right.
But can't.
But yes. So
in the things in our real life,
the things which belong
to a specific group or something,
sometimes what happens is that
there is a lot of code duplication.
Can you guys see the code duplication?
So what I can do,
I can put some specific things as well,
but if I am building a real life
application and I am using
the object oriented programing,
I can be writing a lot of duplicate code
like this.
Right?
What is something specific about Cat?
Meow, Meow.
Imagine that could work.
You guys can write those programs
maybe in which you in your programs,
they will bark and everything like
you guys will definitely
be writing these programs.
Okay,
so how many lines of code
is being duplicated in here?
Guys, about cats Barking is
how many lines of code
are being duplicated in here?
And only two or three.
So this is one, This is two,
this is three, four, five.
These methods, let's count it one, six
and then seven so I can see seven.
But why you guys see only two.
And and now what you guys can imagine
is that
if you are trying to
create another class in the same family,
maybe a zebra class or a horse class.
So again, you will be repeating
this code inside that class.
Can you guys tell me
how can I avoid this duplication?
This by using expand
using method inheritance.
The the concepts
that you guys already know.
We cannot use those concepts
in this scenarios.
Again, to reduce the obligation.
To reduce this obligation,
we have a new concept
that is called inheritance
what do we do in inheritance?
If there are more, then
if there are multiple classes
and if they are logic
related to each other,
and if they are having
a lot of duplicate code,
we create a parent class.
We that common
common code inside that class
and we make these child classes inherit
from that class.
So I let me do that.
So what I can do,
instead of rewriting this code again
and again, I can create a class,
I can call it animal.
And instead of ordering
instead of putting this code
in here,
I can loop discord
inside
the animal class.
But we open inside of us.
All right.
I hope you guys can see the font.
It is still readable.
Okay,
so I will remove this code from this class
in here.
And now I get an error.
Now I get an error
that this name is not defined.
Okay, Andy, what are you trying to say?
Well, you just to make your subclass.
So what we do, we
check the when we combine the common code,
then you change to vertical,
then all slides be readable.
Slides.
I'm not building slides
now. Are you still lagging?
But I have not actually.
Windows. Shimmin
means windows.
Okay, so they are already vertical.
You are also feeling tired.
So these until.
All right. So
what?
Again,
we will not be able to see that well,
but I hope you guys can see it.
So I have removed
this cat class has only this.
We all matter. This dog has only bark.
And then I have placed everything else
inside the animal.
It's fine.
I also misspell things.
Right?
So I was working on my assignment
for the last
I guess we are logs
and then I am teaching a class and
so now what?
I can do, I can write here.
A keyword extends in here
and I can write the name of the class,
the name of the parent class in here.
And you guys will see as soon as I write
this animal,
that editor from the name is gone.
Okay, so what is happening right now?
All the fears from this class
and all the matters from this class,
they are behind the scenes.
They are kind of copied to this cat class.
Okay. So
technically they are still there
in the animal class.
But because of this expense keyword
and with the help of this
inheritance, now this cat class can access
all the things from this animal class.
So if you have already written
a class, guys,
and if that class contain
maybe 50 meters, 100 fields,
and now you want to create a new class
with slight modifications,
you don't have to rewrite
or copy paste that code.
But you can do
you can inherit from that class,
and then you can also add new code to
to that class so that new class will have
we will be having all
the features, plus the method
and then
the new
code that you guys will be writing.
So I can also do the same with expense.
And as soon as I write animal
now every thing from animal class
is available
to the dog class as well.
Just inherited
and can write the code in there. Yes.
Okay.
Now I can access all the fields as if
they are declared inside this same class.
Inside same dog and cat class.
Okay, So for example, I can write a method
in here
with an all in for
and I can access the name.
I can access the breed,
I can access the color,
I can access the same
as if they are declared
inside side the same class.
If as if these fields are declared
inside the same class
and then
let okay, then it show us examples.
So sorry for what is this
that we are doing it right now.
Okay.
Got it.
You guys also had a long day.
So whenever I teach a new concept,
first of all, I try to
write as simple as possible examples
so that you guys
can understand the concept.
And then
for real life example,
I can always show you real life examples
from JDK of writing, but other examples.
But first I will always try to write
simple examples just
just give me some time and I will show you
the real life examples as well.
This concept is heavily used in
in all the Java classes
throughout the year.
Okay. In all of the real life
programs
and I
can call this method as well in here.
Okay, I can call, I can say it
same as if this method is declared inside
same class.
Okay. And let me
so let me close one of these classes.
How about if we want to add field
only for dog?
Yes, you can also have that.
So let's say, for example,
tell me something specific
about a dog.
This smell,
you want to have a a Boolean smell
inside the dog class.
Loyal tags.
I'm not loyal.
Okay.
No, I mean,
I can see
I saw some videos on the Internet.
They have more attitude than a girlfriend.
Want you to be loyal.
The boolean
loyal is equal to Crowe.
Like yes.
So this field is only specific to the dog
and the cat can not access this
service.
They don't care about anything.
So now let's create
a test for class as well.
And so I'm closing this class for now.
Let me squeeze this.
So I'm making the font a little smaller.
But what I hope you guys can see it
the let me clear the main
method of descending is get in the sports
channel.
That's how bad cats are.
So it is Java.
Back. Back to Muhammad, your cat.
She went to sleep.
So last time
she was looking at the screen,
if she had an issue done with Java
sleep 16 hours a day.
All right, So let me create
an object of the dog class race.
So dog dog is equal to new.
No. Okay.
My dog is learning Java just every day
so I can see your dog books.
Not to I can say your dog dot
name.
And so, guys, I don't have this name
field inside this dog class
from where the skill is coming
animal class how with the help of
this expense schema. Okay
and now if
if I think that cat is equal to neo cat
and then cat or dog name
you give me a name for the cat
because dog inherited all the info
taxi.
So can you guys tell me if I bring dog
or dog name what output I will get?
Will I get bobby our taxi taxi?
So because this name field
is an instance field and instance fears
they always have their own
separate copies.
Okay. And
this is same as if we have created
in this name
field, inside the cat and inside the dog.
So there is no common storage
if we are inheriting from a class.
Okay,
So if we are inheriting from this class,
it does not mean that this name will be
same for the cat and for the dog.
Okay.
So they will be having
their separate copies
and everything that you guys can do
if you write these fields.
Indeed, they are in the dog class
separately or in the cat class.
Everything that you can do
if you write them separately, you can do
all those things when you write them
inside the animal class
and you inherit from the animal class.
So there is no change
the way you use the fields
or matters when we use the inheritance.
Okay, For the instance fields or instance
method static,
they work a little different
and I can call.
I can say your dog.
Dog, dog, dog
bark.
I can call the methods
which are only specific to the dog class
or to the cat class.
Same as if these methods are
present in combination with other methods.
I can call the matters
which are coming from the parent class
like the
E to sleep
method.
So this is a common method.
Let me talk this line
on here
and now.
If I execute this code
to call this matter as well.
After I set the name.
So Bobby is barking, Bobby is eating
meow meow.
And then we get the Bobby
because we printed the dog.
Okay,
so this is how we use the inheritance.
One thing when running output comes
faster than eclipse light because eclipse
reads one file
intelligence checks all the files
for all the issues
inside your project,
and then it executes your file eclipses
directly only executing that specific file
on which you click
that when
all our dates Are there any questions?
No, no. It's very simple.
Very simple.
So there are certain things
which are not in the tree,
not make sure you are
setting the name first
and then you are calling them at first.
If you do the reverse,
like all the method, the first.
So I wish the entire
java was like this serif, which
which class you find
hard questions will only be
when completing the homework.
So which class you guys find the most hard
or hardest during all the class?
Oh, my God, Don't ask me.
There are these.
There are remarkable classes.
Gutierrez Don't worry about it.
Or the areas
I have never seen to the areas
in my 40 years of coding experience.
Strings.
No, no strings are very heavily used.
Strings are very heavily used.
Instructors are also very heavily used.
I don't like the
it is not very if you don't like the areas
console very long relax
me wide use use of less
loops are also very important
strings
matters classes of decks and other stuff.
That's great.
Taisha
As to that,
I feel like you are not telling us
everything
in this of what we don't need to learn.
So. Silva
So for example, the two areas like that,
they are not used.
So I have told you clearly,
but what happens is that at the tester,
80 to 90% of the time, you guys will be
setting this solution on the Google.
You guys will be reading the code
written by others.
Now, if you don't know the concepts,
if you don't know,
what does these words mean?
If you don't know how inheritance work,
you will never be able to figure out
how this matters.
Our fields are coming to this class,
and if you don't understand already
written code, you will never be able
to modify that code.
You can not introduce new features.
You cannot integrate new test cases.
So some of the concepts they are,
we are teaching you
so that you guys can understand and
the code that is written by others.
Okay.
Now the code might be written
by some advanced developers.
Every developers
totally depends on the company.
So that's why some of the things
we have to learn
hard landing a job.
It's not that hard work.
Keeping that job is really hard
if you don't know what you are doing.
Yes, it's true.
True what?
I mean, like memorizing the whole thing,
but understanding logic only
focus on the don't
focus on the memorizing part.
You will eliminating the memorizing part
for your interviews.
And again, once you are on your job,
you will be allowed to use Google notes
or anything that you like.
Then you will be needing that.
Now you will not be needing
that memorization part.
You will be only needing that skill
as debugging
skills,
searching skills, troubleshooting skills
and the logic building skills.
Yes, it's fine,
but I'll try to read these slides 5
to 6 times a day and it will be fine.
You will be able to memorize them.
So let's
let's go through some of the
concepts about the inheritance
5 to 6 times until you die.
And so there was a bit of this teacher
of art in the college.
He used to say that
you guys don't have to memorize anything.
So we were learning English
from him, right?
So and he said,
Read this, this, this story three times
in English, read this story
three times in Urdu.
Our native language was then read three
more times combined with English and Urdu.
And you guys don't need to memorize it.
So inheritance in Java
is a mechanism.
Hope you will live long
to have enough time to learn all the Java.
So if you ask me, I don't have to learn
all the Java
because I have the basics clear.
I know the be all the keywords,
the meaning behind those keywords
I can understand any good.
And if I don't even
know, if I don't understand something,
I can quickly Google it because I know how
we are to find data sources.
Therefore the developers and the testers
that they do on their jobs,
they they are always using Google.
So inheritance in Java is a mechanism
in which one object acquires
all the properties and behavior
is like, for example, the methods
of the parent object.
Okay, it's more.
But the idea behind inheritance in Java
is that you can create new classes
that are built upon existing classes.
So let's say
if you already have a class, right?
For example
there is a class in the JDK, right?
And Java guys have already written
a class, but that class
has, let's say only 50 to 60%.
What do you need to do it?
So what you can
do, you can extend from that class,
you can get that 50 to 60% from that class
and then you can write the remaining 40%
inside that class
and then you can use that code.
So that's how it will be useful for you
if you are creating
multiple similar classes
and if you see you are repeating
a lot of code in all those classes,
what you can do,
you can create a parent class,
you can put repeated
code inside that class
and you can make your classes
inherit from that class.
In that way, you have to rewrite that code
again and again.
Works in the same package only.
No, no, it will work everywhere.
Will extend
also work on private method structures.
Are all there limitation?
Yeah. No, no, no. There are limitations.
It does not work
with private and constructors.
We will discuss that.
So when we inherit from an existing class
we can reuse
methods and fields of the parent class
and we can add new methods and fields
also.
Okay,
so use something that is already created
and then you can your methods
and fears as well to the child class
and extends is the keyword
that we use for the inheritance
to inherit properties and methods.
So for example, in this example
there is this LP class
that has some background members
and some matters.
Now, if this student is inheriting
from this faculty,
all the that are members logically is
same as if you have written those fields,
those methods inside that student class
once you extend from that class.
Okay, in the diagram
that our members and methods
are represented in Broken
Line are inherited from the faculty class
and they are visible in this student
class, logically,
you will not see them,
but logically they are there.
You can access,
you can store the values inside them.
You can call the matters.
You can do all the things that you do
with the
methods and fields of that
child class.
Well, we have a terminology class
at the end of the course.
Well, we have a terminology test.
There will be mock interviews.
And in those mock interviews,
we will be testing you
how well you can explain the concepts.
If you don't explain the concepts well,
you will
we will not be suggesting you
to apply on the jobs unless
and until you work on your terminologies
and the way you explain.
And once you are good,
so your mock interviews
will be held for each week.
And once you pass those mock interviews,
then we will build resumes
and then you guys can start
applying on the jobs
If we don't.
Or do you give correction?
Yes, we will be giving you the feedback.
Definitely Definitely.
Right now, maybe you guys
can try to record your videos
or maybe you can stand
in front of a mirror
or maybe you can try to explain
these concepts to someone in your family
who are don't have an IQ background,
and then you will know how
well you can explain.
It will be individual.
The interviews be individual,
I guess the preparation and everything.
It will be groups
I do every single time
mock interviews. This
so we can go back
and look at the feedback. Yes,
I will explain it to my cat.
Take your cat in your interview question.
So we should go through all the slides.
Definitely.
We are going to do the studies till March
and then the rest of the country
is processed. Yes.
Okay, Good listener
if it makes sense for them.
So inheritance represents
the is a relationship.
So let's say you are trying to solve
a real life problem
and you don't know if you should be going
for inheritance or not.
So there is a simple check
we call the check as is a relationship.
So cat is an animal right?
A dog is an animal.
So if you see this relationship
between these entities,
then you should definitely
go for inheritance, right? So
a cat is not an animal, so
you should not create an animal class
and then you should not inherit
from that.
You should not a car class
you've not inherited from that
animal class, then
maybe you need to think about your design.
So this is how you guys will be.
This this simple test will help you design
these classes better so that the others
who will be reading your code,
they will not be looking for you.
Just try to decide to kill you.
Right.
Because reading the code, it can be
so frustrated if it is not making sense.
If you have not used the proper name
for your variables, methods and classes.
So it will be very frustrating.
Can we find a parent from different
package? Yes, we can
inherit inheritance represents.
There is a relationship
also known as parent child relationship.
So if you see this relationship
you can use the inheritance there.
Now, other than this code duplication,
what are the other things
that we can improve with the inheritance
other than this code?
Duplication is application development.
Time will be less write you.
If you are writing less code, definitely
it will be taking you less time
applying and will take less memory.
Okay, if you are repeating
because again and again
because these classes that you guys write,
these are the things that get in
that that are loaded
inside the memory
when your program is being executed
and application
execution time will be less.
Okay. So it also reduces the time.
So it will make your applications faster
to the
pre benefits.
But there is also this advantage
of the inheritance.
Can you think of any disadvantage
if we change something in parent class?
All other child class
will get
No, we cannot less
minimal and time forgetting what matters.
We used.
If something happens to parent
when we make a change in parent child,
it will be it will be everywhere.
That's not thinking negatively.
So even if we're not team negatively,
like the issue
will still be there.
So guys, if
so, let me let me show this.
So right now I am inside the animal class.
What if accidentally
I gained you something,
I changed something
inside the parent class and now
do you guys see the issue?
Now we must update all the child classes
if they are using this feature
from the parent class.
Okay, so once we have written something
and if some other classes
have extended from that class
now making one simple change
can cause the issue to all those classes.
Okay, so this is what again,
the parent class will be protected.
Some not so such mistakes don't happen.
Yes. Mohammed we can do that as a
so it's like a virus
if the word
what what do we call this issue?
We call
these classes are now tightly coupled.
So if we make did
in the parent class
now they all guys,
all the children, they will get defective.
So we need to be super, super careful
when we have to make any change
or when we are designing a class
which we what we are planning to act
as a parent class,
we need to be very careful
about our writing,
the matters, writing the fields.
Now we have to have the about
all the child classes
that will be inheriting from that class.
So it's a very,
very difficult
to design the classes in this way. And
because in the software world,
the code is always changing,
it's almost always changing.
And especially especially the environment
in which you guys will be working
the Agile environment,
the Agile is all about change.
So in these kind of scenarios
you should be super careful
if you are using the inheritance,
like if the grand die,
all the family will be dead
in this In this scenario,
if you remove the parent class,
none of the child classes will work.
So Grandpa takes all the power with him
and Grandpa is digging in.
So this is the issue with the
parent child relationship.
When we create a parent child relationship
or when we have inheritance.
Now advantages,
good reusability,
the same methods and variables
which are defined in parent.
Okay, so we have multiple names for the
for dependent class.
Sometimes you guys will see that
in the industry.
They will be called super classes.
They are also called base classes.
They are also called parent classes.
So in the child classes they are called
subclasses and then derived classes.
So there are multiple names for these.
So Barbara, they are all same.
That is when we get the heritage,
when the grandpa is that
so? Now you have to be on your own.
You have to create your own fields,
you have to write your own letters.
Now, Grandpa
is not helping you anymore, nor
is there any way to connect them
to the parent class.
That is, you make a big change in parent
class will automatically
you updated the child classes.
It's not possible, Michael,
because what happens
is that let's say
the Java guy is written, the
classes in the JDK, right?
And then the team makes it so you
and you are inheriting from that class.
Now, Java guys don't know if you have
inherited from their class or not, okay?
And you don't know the Java guys, right?
But you are using their classes
with the help of inherit.
And so what happens is that in industry,
usually whenever there is a new version,
there is a document
that they release a document
in which they mention the changes
that they have made,
and then you can read their document
and you can modify your code
accordingly.
Yeah, that million dollar idea. Yep. Yep.
You are right.
No. So good reusability.
We are reusing the code from the parent
so it's useless to make it private or
protected constructor
because accidentally lurks.
Use private and protected.
No, no drivers.
Even if you use expense keyword private
fields, private matters,
private constructors,
they don't participate in inheritance,
so they will still be the part
of only that class
in which you have written
those.
So application performance.
Application performance is enhanced?
Yes, protected ones are inherited here.
So I will show you how what is
the difference between a protected one.
So redundancy reputation of the code
is reduced.
The main disadvantage of using inheritance
is back to classes, parent and child.
You are tightly coupled here.
This parent class should be very useful
for saving time.
Yes, this class is easy.
Thanks a lot.
So if we need those, we need to create
those variables and method.
Yes, if you want
to use the private ones,
they don't participate in inheritance.
You have to create
on your own in your classes.
This means that
if we change the code of parent class,
it will affect to all child classes
which are inheriting
deriving the parent class and hence
it cannot be independent of each other.
Now, if we don't want to break this code,
we need to go in all the child classes.
We need to check which classes are using,
which features,
and then we need to be very careful
when we need to change something in the
parent class.
Now there are multiple types
of inheritance.
The famous
types of inheritance, there are four.
There are four ways in which we can
in which classes
can, inheritance in programing.
But one of
the types is not supported in Java,
but the three once
they are supported in Java.
So we will be discussing those three types
guys.
Do you think it will be easy after this,
as we have it today?
So sure, if there is only one class
that might bother you and this time
I am planning to break that class
into two classes.
So hopefully that class will also not.
But it will not be that difficult for you.
Then the child class
behave as parent Child to another class.
Yes, ma'am.
So this is how we would define the four.
How do you do
you know someone in these previous
batches?
Okay, then, then, then, then, then.
Let's not write
anything in the live journal
about the difficult.
I know over here from last batch.
So based on a number of ways
inheriting
the so based on the number of ways
we inherit the features of the base class,
the parent class, there are two types.
The first is
single inheritance of the simplest,
the easiest one.
And then we have multi level
and then hierarchical inheritance.
So let me let me first discuss
the single inheritance.
Single inheritance is very simple.
We have a class
one parent class,
and there is only one
child of that of that class.
So in real life,
if the parents, they only have
one boy or one girl, right?
So this is
this is something similar to that.
Okay.
So a parent is having only one child
if this is the case.
So in the previous example,
how how many cards were there, guys?
The example
I showed you, there were two types.
So was that single inheritance?
No, that was not single inheritance.
Okay. So in single inheritance,
a parent has only one child.
Okay, So In this example, we have class
and there is only one one class.
Class
B, which is inheriting from this class.
Is it easy to understand
or do you guys want me to explain it more?
It's easy, like
a parent having one child.
If a parent can have multiple,
multiple times
multiple children,
then it is called
hierarchical inheritance.
Okay.
No, no, multiple is not supported.
Fatma In Java we have multi level
single and Oracle.
So if there are multiple dies,
which type of inheritance
is this
hierarchical?
So the last example that I showed you,
which type of inheritance was there
hierarchical, right.
So this is what we call
as this second type.
So when a class has more than one
child classes
are subclasses.
In other words, more than one
child classes have the same parent class.
Then this type of inheritance is known
as hierarchical inheritance.
We then we have like 11.
Oh, what do we mean
by multi level in real life guys,
when we use the multi level
keyword in our real life?
Can you guys tell me how it can be
mapped to inheritance?
What will happen
in the multi level inheritance?
So now the fields
and the property has multiple stages.
So the fields and the properties are
they will propagate to multiple levels.
So what will happen?
There will be a grandparent,
the parent
inherit the fields and matters
from the grandparent.
Then there will be a child, child
will inherit from parent,
then there will be a grandchild.
That grandchild will inherit from child.
So there will be multiple,
multiple levels.
All of this of fields and matters
propagate.
Again, if we see this case,
if a class is inheriting from Class
B, Class B is inheriting from class
C classes, inheriting from class D,
then it is called multi level inheritance.
Okay?
And then we have multiple inheritance.
Okay, so there is a difference,
multi level and multiple.
Now it also not makes sense
in the real life, right?
So multiple inheritance means one child
class can have multiple parents
of more than one parent three, four,
five, six.
It is supported in C++
and other programing languages,
but it is not supported in Java
because it creates an issue.
And that issue is is very famous
that it has this special name.
It's called the Diamond Problem.
But would you know,
is the parent class the class
which you are writing after
the extents keyword is the parent class.
That's how
we know. So
how often do you use
multi level inheritance in real life?
It will be used heavily.
So do you guys know how many of you know
about the diamond problem?
So if we have my people inheritance,
like there is this parent of 1b1,
there is another parent B two,
there is another parent B three
and there is this child C one.
Now, this child is inherited
in from this parent, from this parent
from this parent.
Can you guys tell me
what kind of issue it can cause
if a child is inheriting
from multiple parents,
that means all the fears
from all the parents
they will get inherited inside.
C one. Right?
So what can happen
is that what can happen is that
what if parent one
is having a failed called name,
then parent who is also having a field
called name two?
Parent three is also having the same name.
Parent one has a method
and two also have the same name Method.
Parent three
also has the same name better.
Now there is a confusion right
whose method
the child should set, right
title should accept.
So it's a very big problem, right?
So to avoid these issues
and because it causes a lot of issues,
Galois guys decided to not have
my people inheritance in Java.
Okay,
So they didn't allow multiple inheritance,
but it was present in C++,
and C++ was invented before Java.
So this is a very famous interview
question.
They, they will ask you,
can you explain the diamond problem?
What is the advantage of this?
There is no advantage.
You know, we are just discussing that.
There is and there is a feature
which is not allowed in Java
and why it is not allowed
and that there is no advantage,
I mean, in real life.
So the advantage is
that you will be writing
less buggy code.
It's not allowed in Java.
So the benefit is that
you will not be getting so many bugs
related to this inheritance.
There there's the benefit
know you have tips for us
what we have more focus on.
You have to focus on everything sheriff
because
let me be honest guys
I did my engineering in
in 40 years
I studied 44 courses on my job.
I only used three courses, 41 courses.
Then I don't even remember their names.
But somehow they are helping me in in
almost every program or in in every job.
So what you guys are doing
you are skipping that 40 years of degree,
a computer, A computer degree.
Then you are skipping 3
to 4 years of industry experience
and you
will be directly earning the same salary
that a person has to first attend
the college for four years of university
and then have to spend three times
in the three years in the industry.
So you guys will be competing
with those people, right?
So you are already taking a shortcut.
A very, very long
path is already combining
to adjust to six months or seven months.
So please don't find further shortcuts
in this course,
even to try to learn the things.
So we are using a cheat code
for financial security,
so please don't look for further
shortcuts.
Okay. I try to learn everything.
Diamond problem is same variables
in different class, right?
Yes. Then you are right.
So do we get any kind of certificate
from syntax?
So for harder you will not be needing
as in a certificate deal
directly with getting a job
in IP.
There is no
big on
the there is not that much of a difference
if you have a certificate or a degree
or a certification,
if you know how to solve a problem there
saying that's what they did.
They are looking for 40% of the employers
from the Google.
They don't even have degrees
or anything like that.
I hired some jobs, ask for W2
Silver. I am not sure about that.
But you can ask the placement team
and the Aziz or others.
But I have not seen any of the students
having any issues with having a degree
because there are so many jobs
that they don't care about.
Degrees.
Do I look better on your wallet
or it looks good on walls?
We have W-2 that for taxes.
All right, guys. So
do you guys now know the
famous diamond problem
that can happen with
multiple inheritance
and you guys also explain
if the interviewer
asked about it.
Okay, so this was multilevel in multilevel
inheritance,
there exist a single best class,
single driver
class and multiple intermediate
based classes one child and more than one
parent, single best class,
single drive class, and multiple
intermediate based classes.
And intermediate base class
is one in
one context will access drive class
and in other context
the same class access base class.
Okay, so B is an extending from a, C
is extending from B,
B is extending from C,
So everything that E have
will be inside the B,
then everything that B plus
everything that it inherited from me
will be available to C
and then D will have access to C, B
and A duplicate names of variables.
So day weekend,
but tomorrow everything will be deleted.
They may
going to ask about W2,
but you have the right to refuse
because they are not allowed
to ask for that.
So this is another example of can you guys
tell me which kind of
inheritance is used in this example?
What is W2 form of paycheck?
No, Alex
So here's the multi level inheritance.
So at John is extending from cycle B, D
is extending from HRT
and then size is extending from there.
So can you guys tell me
will this floor total,
will it be available to size?
Yes, it will be available to Sisyphean
in multiple inheritance.
There exist multiple classes,
multiple parent classes classes
and single derived class.
The concept of multiple inheritance
is not supported in Java
through the concept of classes,
but it can be supported
through the concept of interface.
So this interface is another concept
that we will be discussing next week. Week
we have this workaround
that we can achieve something similar
in a better way.
If you still want to do this
multiple inheritance thing in your core.
Okay, If you still want to inherit
something from a
as well as from B as well as from C, D,
or any number of classes.
There is a workaround and that workaround
is with the help of interfaces
and the interfaces,
they have also a mechanism
to solve the diamond problem,
to reduce the complexity and simplify
the language.
Multiple inheritance is not supported in.
Java.
Consider a scenario
where A, B and C are three classes.
The C class inherits A and, B class
if A and B classes have same
method, same
name method,
and you call it from child class object,
there will be an ambiguity
to which method
from A or B should be called.
Okay.
Now you are lost in diamond
problem are multiple inheritance.
Or if you can tell me this slide number
words the difference between multi level
and a multiple inheritance.
Can someone tell Mariam the difference why
there should be multiple parents
if everything can be done with one parent?
So for other it is.
Sometimes it can happen
that maybe some of the methods
only present in class
C, some of the methods are only present
in class B,
and now you lock all those matters.
So in that scenario will be needing
you will be inheriting
from multiple classes
multi-level go from main
to child and child or grandchild.
I wish we have live examples
so far multiple
because it is not supported
and because you guys don't know
about the interfaces.
So even if I showed the example.
So first it is not possible.
So we will not be able to do that.
Only thing that I can show you is that
so. Let's say for
example,
this dog is already extending from animal
and now if you try to extend it
from there.
So now in here, which type of inheritance
I am trying to achieve, Guys.
So I am.
But it is not supported
through classes and.
If even if it is supported
with the help of
interfaces,
it's not that perfect.
It's just a workaround.
Okay.
That you can use if you want.
So it is not supported
through classes.
So we are learning this,
but no, don't need to use
sometimes if you badly need this
you can go with the interfaces
but it is never recommended.
It is.
It's always a bad practice
to have multiple inheritance
so yes, you guys will not be needing
it, but you should it.
We will
do never know what the interviewer can ask
to which type inheritance
I am trying to do in here.
I am making this dog
extend from animal and get you.
Can you tell me what type of inheritance
I am trying to do in here?
It's multi word
file or level
is the multiple inheritance.
Right?
So this is not allowed in Java.
Okay. So
we will be getting an error.
And if if I do this
so dog is extending from animal
and if I where is that gap class
and if I say that extends from dog
Oops dog.
Now can you guys tell me what
type, which type of inheritance
is being used in here?
So now we have
B might be level inheritance.
Okay, so
it is extending from dog and then dog,
whereas dog dog is extending from animal.
Okay, So now we have multi-level
inheritance.
Okay, so this is also important
since compile time
errors are better than runtime errors.
Can you guys tell me why?
Why compile time
errors are better than runtime errors.
Sorry, no rest memory.
They are actually waste of memory,
money and time.
So less of them guys.
You have a
you have an error
that only occurs on the runtime
and when the user is trying to run
that application.
Okay.
So the developers have already developed
the application,
the testers have already tested it,
they deployed it on the US server
staging server production server,
everything is done and now an actual user
is trying to use that application.
Now that user is getting that issue
right now.
We first of all, it can cause millions
if you are having this issue now.
Second of all, if second,
if you have to fix that issue,
you you have to go through so many cycles.
But if you know
at the time of compilation,
the moment you are pressing
that player button
and if the error you can
you can check out the error,
you can fix it right away and it can avoid
so much frustration, right?
So much money and time. So that's why
compile time error.
They are always preferred over
runtime matters.
So since compile time
errors are better than runtime
errors and java renders
compile time error.
If you inherit two classes
then it means compiler.
We can see and fix it.
But the other one
we have to go and find out.
See what is the problem. Yes,
once the application is already
running, it's very hard to find the issue.
You can only guess the issue.
So let's say, for example,
if you are trying to use Google
Chrome and Google Chrome
is not working for some reason right
now, you cannot debug that. Right?
So what they do they have these
this mechanism of
do you guys see that option
if some of the programs
they don't work the trial and error
they ask you to send and report.
So when an application is is running
what that what developers
do, they write a file in which
all the steps that the user is doing,
all of those steps are recorded.
Okay so we are in which button
you are clicking,
which button you click first
and then you click next button.
Then you use this option,
then you use this feature.
So all of these steps,
they are recorded behind the scenes.
And when you get that error there,
the application is asking you that, can I,
should I send these steps to the developer
so that they can figure this out.
That's why they need your permission,
because technically, whatever
you have been doing on that software,
everything was recorded
and we never had developers.
Yes. Like
bug report we did in manual testing.
Yep. So that's why it's it's very hard.
So whether you have same method
or different,
there will be done by time at our now
by the way, Google Chrome,
it also records all of your steps
when you are browsing on Google Chrome.
So now what is not in inhabitants
private members of this superclass
are not inherited by the subclass.
So private fears,
private matters.
They are not in
the structures
are also not inherited any of us.
Tell me why. Why?
It makes like makes sense
that the constructors
should not participate in inheritance.
What do you what do you want to do?
What do constructors, logos?
It's not the same class name.
Same class name
The initialize the fields of a class right
now if
if we are inheriting the constructors
there no point in
initializing the fields
in the child class because child
might be having some other fields
and it might initialize
only two fields, three fields.
So what happens is that Java allows
to call the constructor
from a child class,
but it is not inherited
inside of the child class.
We will learn about this in the next class
and about the protected keyword as well.
But I can show you the protected giver
before we are done
with this class. So
let me make
this class
a variable as private.
Okay,
So you guys see, as soon as I make this,
we use the expense keyword as well.
And inheritance
can be a lot of players. Yes.
So as soon as I made this private,
you guys can not extend
extend that field in the class
because now it's private.
So it means if make something as private,
they don't participate in the inheritance.
So let me remove that
and bring it up
and ready to it.
And now the difference between protected
and the default.
So this annual class right now,
it is present in package number 18.
So when using do not make private.
No, not make private.
But if you are planning to share
that information
with your child classes,
then you should not make it private.
So guys, right now,
guys, I want you to focus right now
this field.
I have made this protected field
so I am not getting any issues.
If I am inside the same package right
now, all the classes,
they are inside this inheritance right.
But what what happens if I move this dog
in a different
package? Now
I am having issues on color,
so I am having an issue on color.
Guys.
Well, it is having a default access.
What happens when we move something
from a package to a different package
and the access modifier is protect
is is default.
It will not be accessible. Right.
But what what what are what is happening
with the breed guys, you see this breed.
We are not getting the error on breed.
So if you want to something
in a different package,
but only with the classes
which inherit from your class,
you make it protected
macro.
You make it protected
because defaults are not accessible
outside of the package
and publics are accessible everywhere.
Now what if you want to make something
available only the child classes
and you want to make sure
that even
if they are in a different package,
they it is it of this field
is available to those child
but only to those child.
If there is another class,
it is not available to that class.
If you make it public,
it will be available to everyone.
But if you make it protected,
only your child can access it.
Whether it is inside the same package,
whether it is outside of that package.
Okay,
so there's the functionality of protected,
but it makes sense, guys.
If you want to feed your child,
you need to protect
first. Yes.
Can we do examples of this tomorrow?
Yep. Sure.
Yeah.
So let me move this dog
back to the same package
and now all the arrows up.
Yes, there is a homework.
Well,
can you guys give me just find one
winners.
So members that have default.
Accessibility in the superclass are also
not inherited
by subclasses in other packages,
so the child can go away to college
and still take from the parents.
Yes, my.
As these members are only accessible by
their simple names in this have classes.
Okay.
So this is what it means
if you make default,
it will not be available
in a different package.
Should the classes
be already assigned to parent
then change to variable protected
so the classes will be
already assigned to parent.
What do you mean by assign classes
that are assigned to parent
and then change to variable protected
like in the last
thing which we make you see
since
constructors and any slider blocks are not
members of the class,
they are not inhabited by a subclass.
If subclass can extend only one
super class.
Okay, so let me share
the tasks with you.
I will share so tomorrow or tomorrow
the very simple class
or the in very simple class
voting for.
Okay, so are there any questions guys?
I like very simple classes.
What if we move the child
class to a different class?
Is it still accessible with protected
move to a different class?
But maybe you mean different package?
Yes, it will still be accessible
there.
Simple.
So we'll ask for this class. Hard.
It's a simple question.
All right, guys, take some of the above.
I see you tomorrow, Will. Right
now then inherit.
But why do you smile and don't comment
then If you are, you also know
someone in the previous badges.
Please don't make my students afraid
of that polymorphic
in the class and ask M.A.
Now's a good
I will share business.
Aisha.
I will share for previous classes
the difference between multiple
and multilevel from what
I will explain in the next next class.