Aisha explicitly told me
to record this class.
Still, I don't remember.
Good morning, everyone.
Good morning.
All right.
The maps are data structures
that can support the data
in the form of key value pairs.
Is it cold in Pakistan?
I think it's six degrees centigrade
or something like that.
Oh, it's got two degrees
in here.
Yep. It's
actually not bad, but it's very good
weather to enjoy at three
in my place.
So we discussed
many different types of maps
in the last class.
Can you guys tell me the names?
I thought in Pakistan, always hot.
We have winter
like now for one month in December.
So there are
three
famous
types of maps.
By the way, just to tell you,
there are more
than 125 types of maps in Java.
But we will be learning three
or maybe four of them.
Okay.
There are so many
types of Java maps in Java.
And if
you guys want to learn more about that,
you can search
for the implementation of that.
So let's say, for example, if I
the map interface
and if I am on the
if I hold on the control button,
only three please.
Otherwise will be a mess.
So if you hold on the control button
and if you go to the map interface
and once you are in the map interface,
if you click control I and B,
then it will show you all the classes
that implement this map interface.
So they are all maps actually.
Why there are so many types
because they are very
heavily used in all of Java.
They are super, super fast to search
and you can store multiple types
of data inside these maps.
No, no, we are not
going to we're going to do the additive
typing here.
So abstract, do a little bit
map, abstract hash to map.
So you guys see this terminology as well.
If the if classes abstracts.
So these double guys,
they are putting this abstract
word explicitly before this abstract
art treble map.
So they are all these abstract classes.
And then
there are so many types in here.
But we will be learning only three
or maybe four of them.
Here we go. Link to hash map.
Link map lazy sorted to map lazy map. Did.
Maybe you guys should use
these maps.
Lazy method Lazy search map is a good
list.
Order to map logical message contacts
app expression map property.
Okay. But we will not be discussing maps.
So I am telling you so that you guys
don't tell in the interviews that
Hey guys, there are three types of maps
and we will know all about the map.
There are these hash
map, the map and it's so good.
Why are you guys talking about lazy?
Okay, so
the famous ones, they are the
hash map.
In the hash map
and then the
free map.
Right.
So this map, the
that that extension,
it can also be and defiles
and defaults.
I will use lazy maps
from now on all the time.
But what is
what is the property of this hash map?
If you're like me, some Western men,
maybe you should create
a Facebook page as well
and then maybe monetize it
to have some income from there as well.
It's e is single value can be duplicate.
It does not maintain the insertion
order of key elements.
So insertion
or not is not
maintained.
And when should we use the hash map guys
starting there to do that?
The hash map.
So yes,
it does not maintain the insertion order,
but it's super, super fast.
So when we need good
performance
and we
don't care about the order of the data,
we should use hash map.
And this is the type of map
that you guys will
most probably be using in the industry
for speed. E
end type of map laws
laying the hash map.
It maintains the insertion
order of the key elements.
So in
session
order is
maintained
law in
requirement.
Then a
hash map
much better
in version speed,
then three maps.
So by key,
yes, everything is maintained in the maps
by TS.
So the data structure, this map
that the structure it operates on gives.
So in insertion order is not
is maintained in the linked hash map,
but it is lower in performance
than a hash map,
but better insertion than three maps.
And what do I mean?
When we insert the data in the hash map,
we get the best possible speed.
When we retrieve the data from the hash
map, we get the best possible speed.
But they are a little bit behind
in in how the store did that in memory.
They sometimes they occupy.
So there is a concept of memory management
in the operating systems as well.
So they will be starting the data
in in kind of a scattered form.
But this link, the hash maps,
they will be storing the data
in a linear fashion, but
sometimes the retrieval is
not as good as these hash maps
and the three maps,
they will give you faster retrieval speed,
but not a good insertion speed. Why?
Because every time we insert
a new piece of data in the tree map,
first it has to find its location.
Because remember, they store the data
in salted form so fast, that tree
map has to find the perfect location
for that newly added data.
And then the insertion happens.
So they kind of first compare that element
with all the existing elements
that are present in the tree map,
and then they decide
where to put that newly inserted that.
So that's why the insertion is slow,
but retrieval is fast.
It all those elements
in the ascending order, ISIS.
So in such an order is maintained,
but it is slower in in performance
than a hash map. But
or maybe I should say it is
slower when it comes to
retrieve the data.
So insertion order is maintained,
but it is slower
when it comes to retrieve the data
as compared to
a hash map.
But back to insertion speed,
then three maps.
All right.
So we want to use
when we need to
maintain the order of the
after backup, when we need to maintain
the insertion
order of detecting it.
And then we should be going
with the limit, the hash map.
So what we are compromising in here,
we are compromising a little bit of
retrieval speed, but the insertion order
will be maintained. Then
we discussed about the
three maps right.
Three maps
for the data
started to fall.
Insertion is slow,
retrieval is
fast. Yes.
We will remember all of these rules
for the interviews.
Yes. So
it's a very famous interview question.
I was also asked about these maps
in my interview several times.
So they will be asking that,
hey, guys, what is the difference
between a tree map and a hash map?
When I showed you the tree map,
When I showed you the hash map.
So you guys should really focus in here.
So there are three types of these sets
that we have discussed.
And there are three types of the maps
that we are discussing
right now.
And you guys don't need to remember,
actually, if you focus on on the
on on how a data structure
is doing something right,
if something is sorting the data
that we are inserting inside back,
definitely it will be taking more time
to find out that
that perfect location of newly newly
the data that we are going to insert
please explain
not suitable for thread safe
operation in context of the maps.
Okay. I meant that.
So guys focus on on the properties
and from these properties
you guys can derive the benefits
and the advantages and disadvantages
of these maps.
So tree maps in the
store story
that are in, in, in sorted form.
So insertion is slow
because
tree map has to
compare the data
with existing elements.
Right.
So let's say if you are
so if let's say there are maybe
102 houses right
there, let's take the example of house
and they are numbered like ten below 15.
So on the
200, 300 and then let's add
this lot is empty, right?
Or maybe less than 50.
Now, if a new element comes in
so they are so let's put it 500.
So right now they are all in sorted form
right then 1250 increasing
order 2200 350
Now if a new element comes in the 75.
So the tree map, what it will do for us,
it will compare it with ten.
Okay, it's greater than ten.
Let's check the next next element.
If we get to that, well,
let's get the next elements to get it.
And here it will say, okay,
this element is greater than this one,
but it's a smaller than this to this 200.
That means I should
put it somewhere in here.
So you
guys, to see why the insertion is low?
Because tree map has to find that location
first.
It has to compare the element
with existing elements
to find a perfect location.
Otherwise,
the data will not be in the sorted form.
So this extravagant that tree
map has to go to
it makes the insertion slope
so the existing data elements.
So it has to compare the data
that existing elements
births of are
insertion is slope,
but retrieval is fast.
Now that that
read the safety.
Let me first explain that
y in link the hash map retrieval is slow.
So, Alona, you remember the link the list,
the link listed that we discussed
when we were discussing the list,
what was the disadvantage of link list?
If I have
to go to the next element,
what I have to do,
I have to first
go to all the previous elements.
Right?
If I am storing their type in a link,
the hash map.
So the linked hash
map internally, it is a link
to list of the stored in that.
Now the link list, it only remembers
the address of the next element.
Right? It does not know
the location of the last element.
If I have to go to the last element,
I must.
I trade to all the elements
that are present
before that.
So if I have to go in here,
I cannot go in here directly in the link
list.
This node, if I am
this is my starting node.
If I want to go in here first,
I have to go in here.
Then this node will tell me
the address of the next node.
Then I will go in here.
Then in here, then in here, and then
finally I can raise to this element.
Now, if there are maybe,
let's say, 1 million elements before
and before this element,
I have to go through all those 1
million elements.
That's why they are slow.
But on the other impact, on the other side
where this hash map is doing,
hash map using the special function
called the hash function.
The beauty of that cache function
is that the
then the data will be stored
in the form in the lesson this is are that
computer memory will be stored.
All the data
you guys will be using the hash
maps, lost hash maps super, super fast
for searching, for storing, for retrieving
super, super fast.
If you don't care about in such an order,
if you don't care about sorting,
always go with the hash maps
most widely used data type.
So the beauty of these hash maps
is that they using the hash function
and this hash function,
it is built on very hairy matter.
You guys don't need to go into the detail,
but in simple words,
you guys can understand this
if I give the key.
So the the the map,
it stores the data in the form of
let me actually
recommend.
Right.
So this
let's say this is our storage area.
We are studying Google
and there are so many memory locations.
They are also part of memory cells in here
right.
So these memory cells,
they all have addresses of, for example,
this is the address
it has addressed and so on.
B, maybe 15, maybe 12.
So this hash function,
what is the beauty of this
hash function if we give it the key?
So in, in, in hash map,
we stole the data in the form of
is there are no values, right.
Like this.
So this is key one, this is two,
this is three.
This is for right.
If I give the key to this function,
it will add the output.
It will tell me the task of the data
that is stored will be number one.
It's on memory location ten.
So I don't have to go through any link
list or any three map or anything either
directly be jumping on that exact memory
location.
We have that is stored for that specific.
If I give it the value of three,
it will tell me that
that the value for the key
number three is 15.
So the the the beauty of this hash map
we give the key,
it directly gives the address
where we where the data is stored.
Okay.
And there is a complex
math behind there and how it all works.
But we we don't need to
go into those details.
So that's why they are passed
all the things.
So now that that parent safety right
then we guys
let's see.
But since it is a function
input can be more than one
but only one output.
But since it is a function,
input can be more than one,
but only one output,
not only one output for different inputs,
the outputs will be different,
but they can collide.
Damir If you are asking asking
about collision, a collision can happen.
And in that case, what do we do?
We create a linked list.
So let's say for example.
So guys, this is only for the it.
So let's say a key is being mapped
to to the same output number.
So what will happen this, this map,
it will grow this way
in the form of a linked list.
If one input is being
if multiple inputs are being map
to the same output,
there will be a collision
and to award that collision
the data scientist they have created
and they will add these.
This map will start to grow
in the form of a linked list
for that specific memory location.
And then it maps
1 to 1 in the sense of location collision.
Yep, it can happen.
So the they
they also have a solution for that.
Okay so guys let's imagine this scenario.
So this is related to traffic safety.
So guys
what language are those two using guys?
It's the mathematics.
So guys, have you guys noticed that
when a new iPhone comes
in, you guys see long rows of people
standing out outside of the stores
to buy a buy sometimes
those iPhones right.
So as sometimes in our real life
as sometimes in our real life,
what can happen?
The resources can be limited,
but maybe multiple
people want to access that same resource.
Now, if there is no organization,
what happens is
if there is no organization,
what can happen?
There can be a fight right?
So in in programing,
if you are storing a piece of data,
you guys already know
that these days are computers.
They can have multiple brains,
multiple CPU cores.
Right? Multiple CPU processing.
So it's kind of having
multiple brains, but
having the same memory
we are with stored the data.
So if you are writing your programs
in such a way
that you want to utilize
the underlying power of your CPU,
what can happen?
So let's say, for example,
there is a very big list
and that list is stored inside direct.
Okay, on then there may be a map.
Now there are,
there are maybe 5 million elements.
So 1 to 1 million
are stored in here.
Then from
one zero, 1
million to 2
million are stored in here and then so on.
So now if you try to process
this very big list
using a single simple from your computer
and let's say to process
the 3 million entries
we need left at 30 minutes.
Now, tell me, guys,
if I am processing this list
with only one CPU,
how much time it will take?
It has 3 million elements
and I am using single sip
you to, let's say,
maybe find an element from this list.
So if
1 million
elements required
30 minutes to process, guess
how much time? 3 million entries.
We are ten days.
90 minutes.
Right.
You can also
imagine maybe I am trying to build a house
and there is only one worker
that is working right now.
And if that worker keeps on working,
it will take maybe
for him to construct that house,
Maybe it will take six months or one year.
If I double the number of workers guys,
if I double the number of C bills
that will start
and this data, how much time it will take.
Now, 45 minutes
prior to the time will be reduced by half.
If I again increase the number of
workers to three.
So initially it was taking 90 minutes 90
divided by three,
how much time it will take?
Now it will take 30 minutes.
Right.
So what we want to use, what we want to do
because we have extra
C bills in our memory, you can you
can think of excessive use as
workers working on something.
If I double if I utilize all of my CPU.
So right now in my laptop,
I have six CPU cores.
You guys can also find out
about your CPU cores.
So for example, if I to the task manager
on my computer
and if I go 13 800 x
so it shows me that there are six goals
in my processor
and there are logical
there are 12 logical processors.
Okay, this means each worker you can think
of like each worker has four hands.
So not only the number of workers,
they are six,
but they also
they are double in efficiency.
And if you guys notice in here,
there is something that is called
as ten X, okay.
Now, what is this terms
and what are these processes?
Each program
that is running right now on
my computer, for example, Slack
Chrome intelligence world, Zoom,
all the programs
running in the background.
For example, if there is an email,
I automatically get the notification
how there is a program
that continuously keeps on checking
if there is a new email or not. Yes.
So right now, my on my computer,
there are 282 programs
that are running right now.
And each program internally
can use multiple symbols
to make things faster.
For example, if I try to maybe on Intel,
if I am executing two programs
or on Google Chrome,
if I am opening four tabs or six tabs
eight tabs on one tab, I am running
maybe YouTube on the other tab,
I may be running Netflix.
How all of these they are separate,
separate, different tasks.
If I want to run them in parallel,
I want that many workers
so you guys can think of
these workers as terrorists.
Now, the whole
story why I'm explaining this
is that when you are writing
such programs,
which can utilize the complete power
of a computer, all the logical cores,
all the threads, what can happen?
There can be a fight, right?
If there is only one store that is selling
the iPhones right.
And if my baby multiple people,
they all want to access this store
and at the same time,
there can be a fight.
So what happens
is that to avoid this fight,
we have a concept that is called terror.
Safety
that to stab safety.
Black Friday and
back to train safety makes sure
that there is no for a fight
and everything goes slowed.
The person who comes
first should get the iPhone first, right?
The person who comes after
that should get the iPhone after that.
And it keeps track of all those persons,
all those workers
who are looking for the same resource.
These maps,
for example, the train
map, it does not have that organization.
It does not have that mechanism
to ensure this
this this organization.
That's why we say it's not thread safe,
because if multiple staples
are trying to access this dream map,
if there is a dirt outlet, 50 million LTE
elements are stored in a tree map
and you want to utilize
the full power of your computer
and you make use of carriers,
there can be a fight
because there is no organization
organizing
mechanism in in three maps.
There are other maps
which have this organization.
So 1050 you guys can think of maybe
a bodyguard, a security guard holding
a big a giant stick in his hand
who make sure that everything
is organized.
So these teams built
and they don't have that again, they act
without security guards.
So that's why we say they are not Tazi.
I hope it makes sense.
How do you guys able to relate it?
Okay,
so all these maps that we have discussed,
the hash map
they linked, hash map dreams, they are
all without that security guard.
They are all not tried safe.
If you want to make sure
make sure they had safety and safety.
Now I know what is going on Friday.
Well, can you tell me the name of map
that has this
this of safety?
So the
it was presented in the slides, right.
Did you guys go to the slides
that read safety the bill?
The question going to be
it was asking if actually it was present
in the slides.
That means you guys are not going
through the slides, right?
And then you complain.
Hall And we are jumping from the window.
Nothing is making sense.
We are about to die, blah, blah, blah,
because you guys are not setting right and
so that that hash
map is called hash table is are transitive
hash table plus implements a
hash table
which makes a map squares to values,
hash table implements the map interface
like the other.
So hash double is similar
to hash map, except it is synchronized
or we say it is safe.
All we hope is magic
hash table.
But we didn't learned that say that
that's all about the hash stable
all same all the methods are same
everything is same
if just cannot safe
two classes at the same time.
Java plus selenium one should have been
finished, then started.
So don't worry.
This is the second last class of Java.
Farhad.
So when you guys will be done
with the, with the Java,
is there anything else that you guys
want me to explain from this slide?
Bill Is there anything else
that I didn't explain in the last
class?
So tree maps, rapid retrieval,
slow insertion
on synchronized mean, not save,
which means it is not suitable
for tattoo safe operations.
Next Sunday's last, I think.
Yes I have just to be on safe side.
I have already started one more class
or the next Sunday
will see if we need that class or not.
Yes, I requested that class.
Yes, we need.
After
Java,
you guys will be starting the test and
putting all your knowledge of Selenium
and Java together
in the form of a beautiful project
that will do many,
many different things.
I hope the best of that's things
we have covered.
Are there any questions,
guys, related to maps?
It is more concept, but we do our best
and practice a lot, not anything.
We should definitely have a class
to review.
The whole Java would feel good examples.
Lobo deck.
We will arrange after you guys are done
with the your other classes.
So at the end of the course
we will ask you.
We will have a poll
and then you guys can request to specific
sessions on specific topics.
So let's see if something is not clear
from Java or Selenium
on manual testing,
you guys can all request those topics.
So when you will be revising
all the material for your interviews,
if something is not clear,
we will be having a poll
and then we will be having additional
additional topics.
And then you guys can obviously ask
for your favorite instructor
to have that session.
So there will be no distinction off
of hopefully of instructors
as well.
What we're doing with hash
table are we're using
to make like it as has three
just missed that part.
No the only thing with the hash tables
how simple they are class safe.
Yeah they have that security guard
who makes sure that whoever comes
first gets against the data first.
Those hash tables.
Otherwise, everything is same.
And they make sure that with the help
of a synchronized keyword,
when we are done in three months,
we are going to ask for the
how to put intel over it again.
Yes. Alright
guys, are you guys ready to start the
working with
files class? So
why is still showing
on the calendar that they're either
Java class on the second?
Because I just started back
now so that if something is not clear,
maybe we can discuss that
in that last class.
My import still didn't work.
Some of what I posted in the course
announcement 30 minutes before the class
that if someone is having issues,
please let me know.
But anyhow, she was there.
Ask him to,
connect to your laptop or computer.
And so for this working with files,
we will not be needing those jobs.
But be after the break.
Make sure that everything is working
as you are to connect with my friend
from Bastian.
Got his job recently. He is very happy.
Encourages me to.
Oh, by the way, the best
and they had the last class with me are
on today Saturday.
Right.
So they had last
class was on on Wednesday.
They still have to prepare
for their interviews.
We still have to teach them
how to make resumés.
They are still left
with Docker class database classes,
but they are they were so impatient,
they started applying
and they have started getting their jobs.
Maybe I will invite some of the best
and students as well.
Then we will be having the skill classes.
Please don't tell, don't
tell his name, otherwise
he will be on the newspaper next day.
All ladies are interested in.
They may write it.
I'm just kidding.
Yes, you guys can tell the name
and maybe if you know them,
you guys can have a meeting
or you guys can set up some kind of things
to ask about the experience
and everything to learn about.
Maybe you guys are how to improve
your learning experience and all that.
You guys can discuss that
I will invite.
I am waiting at least 2 to 3 students
so that all of them
they can share their experiences.
I have experience working as a journalist.
All right.
So today's class is very easy as always,
right? So
tell me, guys, this tell me this.
I know said that
I. I like that easy pie.
No, no, it's actually easy.
There are three things
that if you guys know
about those three things,
this class is super easy.
So assignment.
They don't wait for the course to end
before they can start having practice
or preparing for the interviews.
So Russell want the job
now? Soon they start preparing for be
for the interviews
and everything as they are learning
because so for example,
when you guys will be learning
cucumber understanding,
what I expect from you is that you are
you are also revising
at least 3 to 4 slides per day
from Java or manual testing or selenium
and all back don't rate.
That would be once because we learned
then we will revise everything
and then we will prepare for that.
Please don't do that.
You guys will not be able to do that
because it will be huge
and it be very huge material
and it will take like for example,
one month, it can take one month
if you are trying to prepare
all of that at at the at the end.
So try to break it down and try to have
your breakfast side by side
or don't wait for the course to.
And it will be very difficult.
You All right, guys? So you are saying
if I have to let's say guys
read the data from a file or a computer
manually, Right.
So what do I need?
What what do I need to know fast
if I have to?
Let's say I read a file from my computer.
What is the first thing
that I should know?
The location. Right?
First,
I must navigate to that specific file
that to that specific folder
where that that file is located.
Right.
So what do I do?
First,
I need to know the location. Right. So.
Okay, once
I know, once I know the location,
let's say from I want to read this file.
Now, what is the second thing
that should be present on my computer?
If I want to read the
Excel files, the program and
an appropriate program must
be installed on my computer
if I want to read a specific type of file.
Right.
For the PDF files, we have PDF reader
right for the text files.
We have the text file Editor's.
For example, on Windows
we have Notepad plus plus.
I would add the metadata
for the Java files we have intended
for Excel files. We have Microsoft Excel.
So all of these files well, for example,
if I tried to
use maybe PDF Reader to excel files,
can I do that?
No. Right. Some programs.
Yes. This port opening multiple files,
but not all of them.
Right.
So what happens is that
first we need the location of the file
that we want to read.
The second thing we must use
appropriate program to open that file.
Right.
And the third thing I must know,
I must have a little bit knowledge
about the structure of that file.
I want if I want to layer the data,
for example, in Excel files,
Excel files the data.
I hope everyone has an interaction,
previously had an interaction with Excel.
So for Exemplify, talk
about the structure, all the Excel files,
they are divided into workbooks
and all the workbooks that they have.
Then these shared and all this year,
then they have these columns
and rows, right?
Is there anyone who don't understand this
all the,
all the files,
they can have different structures, right?
If I am writing a program
that that can read the data successfully,
I must also have an idea
how that file is storing their data.
Right?
What is the internal
structure that file is using?
So, for example, in Excel files.
We have workbooks inside the workbooks.
We have sheers inside.
This year we have rows and columns
right in text files.
We don't have that much complex structure.
The files stores
the data in the form of rules, right?
So I can start creating row by row,
but different file.
They can have different structure.
So we choose to also keep that in mind.
Right? So
let me
let me write down those points for you
to read
the data from a file,
we must have below
things right.
Number one
part or
location
of the file
on are some people.
And the second thing
appropriate
program must be installed
on the stomach.
We would go to read the back from the
file, for example,
or Excel Sex.
I hope this is the correct extension
we use.
We use
Microsoft Excel
for not PDA files.
We we can use
Adobe Reader, right?
Because fixed followed order.
Right for
law to be free files the way
we can use
not read it.
So every file is kind of have have
that has that specialized
program.
The third thing
we must also know a little bit
about the
vector of that
file.
For example, in
Excel files,
data is stored in the form of
workbooks and
workbooks.
Workbooks here rows and columns.
So we must also know a little
about the structure of that file.
For example, in
Excel Files,
the data is stored in the form
of workbooks key,
and then inside.
Inside in the form of workbooks.
Inside
workbook.
We have
Fields one inside
here we have
a role and
columns or
cells or columns.
They are also cells or sometimes in Excel.
So are these three parts player guys.
Is there anyone who is confused
about these three points?
Only, Only now learn how similar it all.
You guys having any issues and any.
Okay, now we will try to do the same thing
but with the Java program.
Okay we will try to do the same thing
but with Java programs.
So the first type of files
that we will be learning
how to deal with,
those files are called property files.
And before I can show you that,
why we know
we are learning these properties files,
tell me this, guys.
You guys have started learning selenium.
And if there is a website
required for you to enter the username
and password,
we are you storing
that username and password right now. So
we will learn
the export as well.
You are you guys storing those usernames
passwords
you are allowed
and all that inside the code,
inside the java,
some kind of java variable,
maybe a string variable.
Okay.
And once you guys are done
with the programing or writing that
selenium script,
you guys will be pushing that
go to the GitHub right?
So tell me
on the companies, if you do that,
if you have a username and password,
if anyone has the access to your code,
will he also be having access
to username and password
for specific websites from your code?
Is it a good idea or bad idea?
It's a very bad idea because in companies,
every employer will be given separate
credentials.
Why separate credentials?
Let's say you are given the
you are given username and password of
maybe a specific website or database
and what do you do?
You try to delete the data
from the database or you try to look
for private data on your database.
So if you try to do
and if you have your separate
username and password,
companies will be able to track you,
they will be used,
they will track your username and password
and they will know which employee
accessed the private data
or tried to delete some data
or try to mess up
with any of their things.
The infrastructure,
the servers, the databases, the programs.
So each employee in companies
in real life, they are given
separate usernames and passwords
for the emails, for the database
is for the application and servers
for staging server production servers.
All of you will be having your separate
username and password for everything
so that
if anything goes wrong in
any of the areas, they can track it down.
Whoever this is.
So for example,
if I showed near the whole database,
they will be able to find out who did it
because so that
so if you guys
will be having a separate username
and password,
you don't, you never want to share
those usernames and passwords.
You will be definitely
you will be using those usernames
and passwords for your testing,
but you will never be sharing
with your colleagues.
Right.
Because using your username and password,
they can do something wrong
and then you guys will be in deep trouble.
So when you guys will be writing scripts,
maybe you are working on a banking
application, right?
So you are testing a specific part
which stores the
maybe the pins of the credit cards
or debit cards.
Right?
So it's a very,
very sensitive information.
So only few trusted employees
in the companies, they are given access
to the separate they create separate
usernames and passwords
and only using those usernames
and passwords, that data can be accessed.
So what do they do if they are writing
some kind of script scripts?
They never want to put that data
inside the code, right?
Otherwise everyone will be able to see
that username and password
from the repository
because it repository is kind of a shared.
Everyone will be pushing that to that
get reports.
The others will be cloning.
From that multiple people
will be working on the same project.
So we need some mechanism to separate out
some information from our code.
We never, never we never ever put
a sensitive information inside core,
but we do
we always put that information
in some kind of files,
and then
we write our Java code in such a way
that can read that information
from the files.
When we have to test that script,
we place that file on a specific folder.
Once the testing is done,
we deliver that file,
okay, Or we don't share that file
with anyone else.
So that's how we we separate out
our data from code.
It's very important.
The second reason is that if you put your
usernames and passwords inside the code,
sometimes you will be testing
your code on production server,
some sort of study on production,
sometimes on the staging servers,
sometimes on the unity servers, sometimes
maybe on US servers, All those servers.
They also have different
usernames and passwords.
So every time you push your code
to the next environment,
to the next server, you guys have to
change the code, updated
the username and password inside the code.
Now that is also not a good idea.
Can you guys tell me why changing code
when moving from one environment
to another environment is not a good idea
and why it is not allowed
Bugs and security.
Right?
Something was working perfectly fine
on the development environment, right?
When you had to test
that you changed something
inside of the code from some developer
or the testers.
They can modify the code, right,
to maybe leak the data
or to to to write some kind of virus.
So once the code is deployed
on the developer server, even before that,
it goes through a proper mechanism
that is called
a review architects or hired team members.
They they tested that code that would call
a developer has written
once that code passes the review,
no one is allowed to change that code
until there is a proper
testing done by AQR.
And he reports a bug.
And that bug is also discussed
with the team lead architects.
Then a new fix is created
the code exchange.
Again, it goes through the review
and then all the process repeats.
We never, ever changed the code
just because sometimes
we testing on other words or sometimes on
staging server, sometimes on production.
Right?
It can introduce
bugs. It's a very bad practice for
security purposes. So
what do we do for those reasons as well?
We also store the credentials in a file
when we have to best
that code on a staging server.
We update the credentials inside the file
and we place that file
on a specific location.
And in our Java program
we instruct out of our program
to always read the data
from their specific folder.
So from environment to environment,
we will not be changing the Java code.
We will only be updating those files
with updated credentials.
Can you show all text in the note?
This one you mean
or you want me to write
that down on the notes
is the environment is a part
of our testing environments.
Are dev environment
staging part of what we know
part of
Look, Alexia, here is the note here.
Here are the notes.
Let me write it down on the note.
The things that we have just discussed.
Why store
sensitive
part of separating
the codes is the environment.
Environment part of separating the code.
No code is always the same,
no matter on which environment
it executes.
We Never write separate code
for separate environments.
Code is same.
The files can change, the data can change,
but code will always be same.
Whether you are accessing,
editing or deleting it, it will be same.
There will not be a single character that
that will be changed from one environment
to the other environment.
You have to write your code in the form,
like you have to write genetic code
that can work on all the environments.
But once that the that code passes
the review, you will not be allowed
to change that code, right?
Otherwise every developer can write
a piece of code that can steal
all the sensitive data off the credit
card.
Right.
And can send that to his email.
So that then that is not allowed.
So why store sensitive data?
Why we
to learn about
file handling?
And by the way, this reading
and writing that out to file, it's
called file handling in Java.
We store sensitive data in
in files instead
of for food that no
one can
access.
And that data
will write the code inside
Java programs
to read the third in for at runtime from
some kind of
of file.
Perform the best thing.
So we try to be coding
tied to Java programs to read that info
at runtime from some kind of
file,
perform the testing
and once
everything is done, we
delete those files.
So why is store sensitive the time file
instead of work
so that no one can access that data?
We write the code inside the our programs
to read their data
at runtime from some kind of file.
Perform the testing.
Once testing is done, we deliver the data
to the
second reason.
When you guys know about the
about the specific type of testing
in which we use a lot of data,
is there any free wording
for the operator?
I could not find it.
I think there is a free virgin
use preview in Mac.
This there is almost nothing else
you will need.
You can also use some similar programs
to read your files. Yes.
So guys, do
you know about the data
testing terminology in which we use?
Use a lot of data to test.
Let's say for example,
if you have to test a field
and let's say that field
should only allow maybe
eight characters and
there should be a uppercase letter,
a lower case letter,
maybe a special character
or some kind of other rules
for how how you guys will
test these kind of things
is like
stress testing, something like that.
So you will generate
these different types of data
inside an Excel file
in a column that sometimes will be having
uppercase lowercase,
a number of special characters
length more than their length,
less than their specific number
of characters and all that.
And you all that data from the Excel file,
you insert that back to inside the fields
and you check if that field allows
that specific data or not,
or sometimes if you guys have you guys
visited that a syntax extremist website
for your selenium scripts.
So that web site has
first name, last name, employee's
date of birth, the joining date
and all the sorts of the
there are huge amounts of info.
Sometimes you have to enter
huge amounts of data
inside those forms to test them out.
So what do you guys think?
Is it a good idea
to put all that data inside the code
or we should create
maybe a separate file format as
separate file?
Right.
Because if there are new rules,
you don't have to change your code
or you just introduce that new data
inside of that separate
that Excel file and your program,
it will be genetic program.
It will pull the data from different
different fields from your Excel file.
It will pull that data inside those fields
and your testing will be done.
So you just need
to update your Excel files.
If there are new rules
when will be testing these forms
like like applications?
So in the industry,
you guys remember the first rule
of programing, right?
So we really never want to
change the code.
You guys don't remember
the first rule of programing?
No, no, no.
That is not the first rule of programing.
Why this is not playing.
Oh, here we go.
No, no.
Maybe this one we would.
It works.
Don't like it.
Here we go.
So if we have something, if
if your seniors have written something,
you never want to change that.
No, no. They.
This is the actual
first rule of programing.
If it works, don't touch it.
The entity that I notify
the change everything else,
but don't touch your code.
You never know.
Use danger something,
and the next time it will not work.
Okay, It will not work.
So now we want to change the code
as less as possible.
Okay?
We never want to change the code.
If something is working, we.
We can change the data
or we can change anything but not equal.
Because right now you guys are writing
very small programs, writing
15, 20 lines, 30 lines
in real life in the industry,
you will be interacting
with large amounts of code, write them
maybe
a thousand lines of code in a single file,
3000 lines, thousand lines of code
in a single file.
So if you mess up something, it will take
forever to to figure out to fix that.
So instead of inspecting every text,
sending keys,
we can put all that inside file
and write a genetic code.
So this is what you guys will be doing
in your frameworks.
The cucumber Framework Best
and the Framework.
This is what you guys will be doing.
Nicole maintains a good balance. Yes.
How long will it take to finish the code?
There will be tile.
There will be one of
developers and testers in big companies
who will be writing
that much amount of code.
And it takes years to develop that code.
It's not one person or not,
not the task of a single person.
So don't worry about it. You will.
Guys will be introducing small new changes
or writing
maybe small new files inside that you
you don't have to write all of that.
Otherwise, if you guys have to write
all the framework, then it means that
the company will be needing
you for next 10 to 15 years.
It's good on your pocket right?
You you are hired for next ten years
if you have to do all of that.
No, no.
It is very good movie actually.
Isaiah. Right?
You tell them,
Hey guys, it will take ten years
and they are not going to fire you
for the next ten years.
The reason is that
most work, most probably
because you guys have not written
so much good.
The code that you guys
will be writing, only
you will be able to understand the code
so you won't.
You may try to hire someone else to do it,
to change that order,
to understand that code.
It will not make sense for them.
Yeah, because the purpose
of the salary of the equity
I am a little person to
because that you guys will be writing.
No one else will be able
to understand that
I know company.
There are four developers in that company.
They are working a project and the boss.
I don't know what went wrong.
He fired them and what they did.
They changed the variable names and,
the method names to their nice
to their nephew names
and their children names.
Somebody is calling Isaiah for parameters
that have been passed to sortable.
And so one is it
it doesn't make a list and
so that also happened in small teams.
So that's why they will not be firing you.
I would definitely do that.
Don't you know about salary environment?
I think they are also offering
good salary.
Some of the previous best students,
they got government jobs.
I will always remember
for one for polymorphism.
So when we have two best forms
and so they are called web farms,
when once when we have
good best web forms, we
don't
put all the best thing in back.
The mean inside the code, we create
files
for that, read the
backed out from those files and
test those web
forms.
As this ever happen.
Two or more students
hired for one company.
Yep. Yep.
They they understand government positions
are more relaxed, don't you think? Yes.
Well, in all the countries everywhere
the government job is
if the that everyone is looking for
like for example, here in Pakistan,
if you are earning like 200 K per annum,
no one cares if you are competing.
The guy who had the government salary,
all the people, they will prefer
that person or a person
whose name maybe, let's say 100.
Okay.
So even if you are earning like 20
and if it is a government
job, everyone will the back
no pressure
protection.
Yeah, it's a lifetime job, right?
Normal job is the lifetime job.
You don't have to do anything. Be relaxed.
Don't do anything. No one will ask you.
There's all governments
work, like in private sector.
You have to work in a lot of miserable.
You don't have to work
dog security, laziness
and all that.
Can you repeat last one?
So I was saying that if
a family is looking for a groom
for how to gun.
They will always prefer a guy
who has a government job
over a guy who has a private job.
I think.
Is it clear now
because of stability and the relaxed ness
and because if you are a government
employee, you can have links
in all the other departments
and everything will be super, super easy
for you
in all the all in all your culture. Yep,
It's the culture.
In our culture, it is not the case.
That means your government
must be very super, super government.
So which country you are talking
about your hometown? Yes.
If we know he is a government,
we know he is bribery. Yep.
Yep. That's also the case.
They are made a lot of money
from other sources.
Or you.
You are specifically talking
about your family.
I was not spared specific.
We're talking about this.
I was talking about a general behavior
off of paper.
Jai Pani.
Here we go in here.
You know a lot, right?
So in government sector, if less, because
they have lengthy processes, right?
If you want your process to get super,
super fast,
you pay them a little amount of money,
they call it type money.
And then you, you, you will be done
with your task super, super quick.
All right. So
it files for that
raid the data from those files
and test those that forms.
Okay.
So you guys know why
we need to learn about files, right?
Why we should learn how to stored
and read that fine part of the files.
So let's have a break.
And after the break, we will.
We will learn how to read a file.
Oh 1127 1142
When need to ask Lobo?
Lobo, are you here?
Yes, we are. Good.
So we have a green dude from Lobo.
We can be on break
de coffee.
It's Booster.
Your Highness.
All right, guys, please be back
by 1143.
Stakeout.
Go take some fresh air, coffee, tea.
And reminding me about the recording
time that works Now.
That's great. One. Can you also try that?
Are we going to homework?
Oh, I didn't.
Yep, yep, yep. Definitely. Definitely.
Let me first go through the tasks.
Then you guys send me this statement
for the tasks.
Let me check what it does.
We did that building one right
The next.
Next one, create a map of countries
with capital.
This one.
But we have to start from this one right?
My student cousin.
You guys are both single
working on your own.
Do you guys are not
reacting to memes from Sebastian?
It can discouraging
and we don't want to do that.
Let me get let me be
it was all right
so create a map of countries
with its capital
that will store countries
in alphabetical order.
But in all keys and values
parameter entry map using for each loop.
And I prefer
print
all values from a country map
using for each loop.
And b I prefer.
Can you guys send me the map
that that has or so
should I store the countries in the keys
or should I store B capitals in the keys?
We are too lazy to choose the emoji
to react, so we waiting for someone else
to react request
Microsoft
actually high height of the lazy people.
So they intentionally hired lazy people.
Microsoft
because lazy people they can always try.
They they can always find a way to do that
task in in in less effort
in future time out
without going through that tired process.
So they are always thinking
about the smarter and shorter ways.
Believe me, it's not a joke.
They literally hired lazy people,
so maybe you guys should apply.
It's time to start applying over the
and Amazon.
They they give you 5,000 USD
if you want to leave the Amazon.
So did they say that we intentionally
we are paying the employees
to leave the Amazon
because we don't want those employees
who don't want to work on Amazon.
So we have to store the
know.
Whoever did this is not correct.
You see, if we do this, the countries
will be in the place of values
and we will not be able to store them
the thought to them.
Right.
Store countries in alphabetical order.
If I store them in in these values,
I will never be able to store them.
Right.
So can you guys send me and my.
Yes, this one looks good.
So this is not the correct approach.
There is a way there is a way to store
the values as well.
It's your homework.
Try to do that.
You are allowed to use Google
and everything.
So this is the correct one, right?
Because now the keys, they are countries
and the tree map,
it actually starts with that.
Our based on keys, not on values.
So it's important to know.
Okay.
To create a map of countries
with this capital
that will store countries
in alphabetical order.
That's
why we are putting the country's first.
Okay.
But into all keys and values
from a country map using for each loop.
And I tried to.
So which type of arbitrator I can use guys
which type of I try try can use
to get all the keys
only if I only need the keys,
which type of iterator
I should get from this map
so I can get the key set.
I can first go to the key
set if I am only interested.
So those who have done it
with the help of entry, start
and restart can give you both keys
and values.
Right?
Print all keys and values from a country
map using for each loop and iterator.
So for example, I can see
capital daughter
which type of start I showed that guys
can you guys name desert
that I that will return me both
he and will values
near the entry said pride
entry asset has all the keys
and the values
it can store bought the keys
and in a single
dad perspective can you guys name that
that structure that hold
both keys and values
know there was that
there was an other interface
inside of the map that can hold both keys
and values.
The entry interface right
so if I say I to
in here
what I will be getting,
I will be getting and I iterator
and the type of iterator works
through the builder type.
First I should have
iterator and inside of that typewriter
I will be having a
B and threes.
And inside of those entries
I will be having
two string type
values.
Right?
So this entry said
and on top of that
I am calling the iterator.
So I created an inside and by trader
there will be entries
and each entry consist of strings
in the form of keys and values.
Now I can use that for each loop right
in with the apparatus
I can use for it, or I can save for each.
And what should I specify in here?
Guys?
I should specify map door
and three
spring
string.
So I will be getting a single entry
one by one From this.
I tried to write
forcefully.
I should because I want to use
before this loop.
I should use
a setting here.
Yeah.
So this fact it has the map and trees
and each one of them contains
two string values.
One as the E and the other.
Well,
so now if I say
and three dot get e,
I will go to B is right.
And if I say
entry three dot get value
I will be getting D value.
And if now particular this program
so I get my data in here.
Okay.
Is it clear guys?
How is it working?
So this entry is hard.
It actually returns us, is set
and inside there,
except first we have entries
and inside each entry
we have a single key
and its corresponding value.
So using before each
we are grabbing a single key and the value
we printed, we grab the next one,
we print it, we grab the next one,
and then we print it.
How do you put the by alphabetical order?
I used to be three map.
I used to
remember it automatically source the data.
When we insert the data inside the map.
Now is it clear?
Okay, put into all the values
from a country map
using for each loop and the iterator.
So how how can I print
using the operator as well?
So how can I printed using the iterator
as well?
What I can do?
I can.
So it should not be an idea
that it should be a set
up, grab it
that and
so now I can get the iterator as well
and I can print out using the iterator.
So I will say while
which method
I should use inside to be wild condition
guys from the iterator to check
if there are any elements left.
The has an x right
I prepared or has a next
and then
each element has this and three
and three
which are how can I get to the entry using
which method from the
I get I can get the entries one by one.
The next method right.
I pray to
dark next.
So this I printed it actually
returning it, returning me an entry
and again using this entry
I can see and three dot e
and and three
you get two.
So I get these values
with the help of for each loop
I get these values with the help of
my data.
Is it clear right
now if I all are,
if I am only interested in values base,
if I am only interested in values
which type of
set I should ask from the map
collection by
either tradeable. Now.
So if I am only interested
in the values,
I can say
capital dot
values.
Right.
And I can also directly use
the entire default
to look, for example, for each
instead of storing it in a variable.
And then that's the same thing I can say
what type of value I will get right, what
type of variable I should write in here.
Back end, store the value
that that string is the wrap
is wrapped around
a collection, right?
And inside of that collection we have
the what is this returning?
It's returning a collection right?
Oops, sorry.
Yep. Yep.
So this collection, each collection
contains
a single string value, Right?
And that value is actually the value
that we have stored in here.
For example,
this Washington, Paris, Rome and Qatar.
So if I print out that value
in here, I will be I will
only be getting the value this time,
nor the keys,
only the values.
And if I am interested in and I trade,
that's why I need an operator.
If I am planning
to change this size of the collection
so I can see
capital dot
values, this will return me a collection.
And on any of the collections the
if I need the greater I can call this.
I prefer method.
So I try to
and then the type of the variable
will be I greater
and inside the separator,
what I will get is
I will be getting a string.
Right.
But look, this string is wrapped around.
Let me
let's call it I may be values.
I click
so it returns a collection.
And on that collection
I am calling the iterator,
which will return me
the iterator containing the
strings.
And again, same.
I can see.
I can again
use those three methods of value.
The typewriter has an X
and value
iterator dot
next like this.
So this is using this set for each loop
and this is using the iterator
and they both e
then value same as this one.
If. All right,
I'll get any question guys.
How do you concatenate them
with this
plus plus operator and this double code
same from third Java class concatenation
string concatenation.
Are there other tasks?
Is there any
create a collection of integers
in which you can prove duplicates?
Try the logic
to find the sum of all the elements
right.
So which collection can store
the Which collection can store
duplicate elements right.
Add a list or the list. Right.
I can use any of them.
So let's use the ArrayList
and I will be storing number.
So let's use number
for the number meal.
Add a list
last I heard a few numbers.
Maybe then that
that I can store duplicates in here.
And now, if I want to sum them
and declare a sum
variable, initialize it to zero.
How can you define it low?
Because I am only iterating
through the element.
So in theory the number
of numbers and then some equal to number,
we can print that.
How so?
I get 30, so I am able to store duplicates
and then I roll the logic to find the sum
to create a map that will store employee
names and salaries.
I write a logic
to retrieve an employee who gets
highest salary.
The to
create a map that will store employee
name and salary. Okay
the right logic to retrieve an employee
who gets the highest salary.
So let's first create a map so.
Let's use the hash map
because it is most widely used map.
And the key.
Should I store the name as a key or should
I store base
salary as a key?
The lost loop is also called
for each loop. Yes.
Yes. Enhanced for loop
is called for each loop as well.
I did also collection and linked list
and you go back for a second.
You want me to go in here
what I did wrong?
No, it was not wrong.
The passport affected is. Sorry.
Can I see one more time Pass to the
Let me know once you guys are ready
so that we can move forward.
But can we move forward?
I think he has left.
Okay. Okay.
So store the names of all the back.
We will be needing a string
and for this salary is let's use the
integer. Okay.
You guys can also use doubles.
INT yep.
All right.
So let's insert some that
this time
I want to perform a comparison
based on the values.
Right.
But what I also want is that so let's
say for example, so for example
two persons
they can have duplicate salaries
via so values
they can duplicate, but they cannot.
So I have to get a, B
key and P value, right?
So one of the ways
to achieve this is, let's say
I can initialize a variable in here
to store the name of the employee
who earns the most, and then
I can store
max salary as well.
But let's initialize it from zero.
And now what I will do, I will
I trade through this map one by one,
I will check a b values
and whoever has the maximum value.
If I find
an employee who earns more than that,
I will update both of these values.
So for example, if I write a 40 loop.
All right, what I can get,
I can get an entry said
right and
and present
returns mean both keys and values, right?
So keys are in the form of things
values are in the form
all in map
and I can say employee map dot
entry set.
So this entry set it will return to me
and is one by one
and each entry will contain a key
as the name and a value
in the form of this set.
And what I want to do, I want to check
if because these they cannot be negative.
So we are writing simple logic.
So if the
if the value that I am getting,
if it is greater than max salary.
So the that
I have initialized with my variable,
if it is greater than there,
I update my salary dog
Max salary is equal to MP
naught.
Get that right.
So I only update this salary variable
once I find a value
that is larger than what
I have already stored
and I am starting from zero.
Right.
So I am sure that salaries
they cannot be negative,
so they will always be
something greater than zero.
And if this is the case,
I also want to update
the max to salary employee name.
Right.
So I also want MP dog back
and once I am done
iterating through this map,
I will be having the employee
with the maximum salary
right.
And then I want an equal to sign
and then a dollars sign and then the
max. By
the way, if I execute this,
I get 130.
Maybe
I should ask it to an integer as well
so that I don't get that feel like
I got to
so that I don't get that feeling.
Do you guys understand how it is working
or you guys want me to debug it?
Because it can be a little tricky
for some of you.
Okay.
So whenever I want to debug the code work,
what should I do first?
What should be my first step?
I even have difficulty
determining the data type inside loop. So
this entry said Mohammed.
It will always return you a map dot entry.
So first I must place a debug point
line 29.
It will be now it will.
Let me debug it for you.
So once I have placed the debug point,
I can click on this icon and can see it
deeper.
Let me deliver this.
What is
all right.
So if I want to go to the next line,
I will say
should I step over or step into place?
If I want to go to the next line
in two over
in two
over 5050
or over, move
in to
when you are not debugging your code.
Right.
50% of your answers, they are wrong.
So I should say
step over into is if you want to see
into is
used, if you want to see the execution
inside a method,
if there is a method, call on a line
and you want to see how that method
executor to the code inside.
But then we use the into method
that is, I'm telling you,
if you don't practice
it will be very, very hard for you.
Java will be very, very hard for you.
Please practice reading 3 to 4 slides
daily and please practice.
So I see a step over
and then if I say if I want to check
what this empty target
value is returning me,
what I can use, I can use a lot, right?
So I right click and I say add to what is
so now this empty door to get value.
It is returning me 120 here
and what is inside my Maxwell view
right now is it's zero, right?
I initialize it with zero.
So is 110 okay.
Greater than zero? Yes.
So I will go inside the loop.
I will get back 110.
Okay. And I will
store that of the max cell
and I
also get MP dot get the key right.
The MP right now contains Smith
and that Smith will be stored
in max a cell
we employ
next time
when I will be doing the second iteration.
I got to be value, which is John
and John has a salary of one Kon-Tiki.
Now I have an employee that earns the law.
Ben Smith
So should I update this Max salary
and employer name or not?
I have an employee, so previously
I stored inside the max salary.
I store 200 and 110. Okay.
Inside of the max employee name
I stored previously Sumit
because it was greater than zero.
Now I have another employee, John,
which is earning even more.
So should I update these variables Value?
Yes. Right.
Because I want to get the max.
If I don't, if I get a max value,
if I get a higher value,
then the value that I already stored,
I should upgrade that, right?
That's how I will be getting to the most
maximum salary and employee name.
So I say okay, if max salary previously,
which was 110, if it is greater than 120.
So it's true.
I now instead of me, I store
the inside of the name, I store John
and inside the salary I store one config
because I have found a person
that earns more right
from what I have stored previously.
Now I do the next operation.
Next I get John
is John are earning more than John.
So previously I stored John and 128
is this John earning more than that?
No. So I am playing to the values. No.
So this condition will fail
and I could be next employee.
I only upgrade
if I get even bigger values right
and therefore
I will be getting to max values.
So I do it again
and then I get Jean right.
Jean is earning 130, right?
So should I update the values now? Yes.
So I go inside this condition, right?
I observe the values
and then I keep on going.
If I find even higher salary, I update.
If don't, I don't try and therefore I get
the maximum salary and employed name.
Is it clear now?
So somebody is just debugging big guy
when saying sorry,
I found the person who earns more
and then we add the all the salary here.
Yes. For hard.
Yes, you can add them as well if you want.
You can declare a variable in here
for example.
Oh for example some of
the double sum is equal to zero.
And before oops, zero.
And before you perform the
if condition, you say sum
is equal to sum plus
MP dark get really right like this.
And then maybe if you want to print out
that as well,
you can also do that.
Yeah.
So I get this
sum as the
okay, because how we can do it.
But why we write into Max
just to avoid that zero.
If you don't want to do this,
you can also do that.
Maybe instead of
instead of double.
I should use integer in here. Okay. Extra.
Extra step. Unnecessary step.
I was doing unnecessary extra steps.
Okay.
And for in here
as it was across by mistake,
I thought we were storing initially values
in if almost doubles.
Okay.
All right.
Are there still any any questions?
Nice.
Are there other are there more tasks?
Can you send me the next task? No,
there are no
not create a map of Best Buy store.
You assign somewhere
between 20 and 30 tasks every Sunday.
So there are always.
So I think you guys are not doing
any of these tasks.
I just assign them
and then follow them in the next class.
Right.
You guys are playing with me.
I Oh, that.
Let us assign as many task as we want
because we will not be doing them early
and he will be doing them right.
Okay.
We spend so much time doing the tasks
that we care about the or be it be as
my period is not going to be in Java.
Most probably we I will be
I will be writing
most of my coding in Python
and all that is mostly
based on Python.
Okay.
Create a map of best Buy store, place
item ID and item name into example item by
item deeper into
the retrieve All Eve and values
from a best to buy map using
this one is easy right base.
We have just to all this one in here
where we focus.
This is same using the end
to start to get all the needs and values
I had and it will solve this.
Can you, Katrina, can you send me record?
The complete code is the same for
let's let's not waste time.
It's the same store same code, right?
Creating an entry set
and then retrieving the value.
Well,
I do tasks with unnecessary console then.
Right?
So from this map
we are getting the entry set right
and are returns us these and the values
in the form of entries.
I can be form of entries.
And then what we can do from
these entry is we can write a follow
to get all the give and well, right
same cold,
same as before.
So I get all direct like this, you see
the same same task as before.
Is there anyone who was confused
or was unable to do that?
Maybe this is what has confused you right.
What should be the type of variable
in which we store this entry set?
Right?
So there is an easy way of doing that.
So for example,
if you guys are unable to figure,
figure out the type of variable
until you can help, you just
press all to enter, press
all the entry and click on this introduce
local variable
and replace all occurrences that's
intelligible right bit types for you.
Automatic you need even if they are
super super complex.
You guys don't have to worry about
the types, but you really should know
the types. Guys.
You should not be dependent
too much on, be on the IDs,
but just in case, if you don't remember
or I don't know,
unable to figure out,
you can use intelligent.
I gave it to batch ten guys.
They were also not able to do it.
Yeah, because they are away from Java
like maybe four months
to 3 to 4 months
of the.
Now we can speak
and they are still
getting the jobs right.
Are there more tasks?
Yes, still more tasks.
How many tasks file there?
I am not following due to
who gave you some of the tasks.
Forget today.
I am not going to.
I will only give you one or two tasks.
6 to 7 is
I didn't name a possible.
This is the last one right?
No, this is second last.
Maybe
third last
stay level.
Oh, now I understand your pain.
Sorry, guys.
Second, second, second, last.
I don't remember
seeing the entry sub interface
with map background we show on the slides.
Can you explain a little bit.
Yes. I think
it's not presenting these slides,
but if you guys are interesting
seeing that
map dot entries,
for example, you can click on this entry
and here
it is present inside this map interface.
It's an interface inside another interface
and all the classes
which implement the map interface,
they also implement this entry interface.
The Imagine jobs task
that I Apple, the Selenium slides.
Other schools will be possible
not only guys years,
just three more months.
I know it's hard.
It's very hard.
2.5 months.
You guys are in 3.5 months
into the course.
Forgot Kelson has the.
Maybe next time we should say that
this course is only for singles
who are long,
who are single for a long, long time.
Right. It's
so great.
Is there any chance you can show us?
Rappel 209?
Yes. All or not required.
We are at the end of the class
and you will forget that
at the end of the class
that we are going to have to show
that Bertuzzi tonight.
I will not agree. Let's see.
I am using this.
Thanks for the big for so long.
You remember Alexi.
Alexi left at the end of the class.
I never showed him
the encapsulation exam, but
still this day.
I'm just kidding.
I will show you
at the end of the class. Oh,
creative person
class with falling private fears
named, last name, age and salary.
That is all I ask.
That is not met.
It is doing is mastering.
Yes, maybe I am lucky.
Otherwise CBC would have killed me by now.
I am planning to have a wife like this
who can watch my
and she
invite is
just all the way.
See is good.
Going to please
just put it in there see it will work.
Well it is.
And both the all the way that way.
No. So.
Okay, let's get back to the class.
So name, last name and sadly,
yeah.
Okay.
So same name
and then spring.
Last name.
But don't give her Mac. But
it's all by the way,
I was reading about the weird.
There was the chief
just there was a gesture to celebrate.
It's very good for your health.
You did it.
And then, oops,
double salary.
And these matters.
They should be private, these fields.
They should be private.
No, it's not.
Don't encourage us.
It makes you laugh
and love exceeds your life.
No, I I am laughing even without the V.
I don't know why.
I mean, during my job,
my manager and I used to make
a lot of jokes about me.
There was also guys like me.
We used to have a lot, but
a lot of fun.
Okay, so they feel they should be private
because
believe me, this programing job,
it can be very stressful.
So this humor and all that extra necessity
create person class
with falling private fields.
Name Last name is salary variables.
Variables should be in this list
through the constructor.
All right, so
I can say it and insert right.
And then I can click on constructive
and I can create a constructor.
Easy peasy, right?
Easy peasy. W
My Muslim friend said that
liquor is not at Albert.
Holy book
never mentioned anything about Weird.
So he said I am still doing lot
so years
out and insert on my keyboard.
If I press that I get this generate
window
and I get this.
I think as a as a medicine it's good,
but otherwise it's not good in any way.
If someone is trying to justify
he's wrong.
All right.
So I created the constructor,
Dark Chocolate 85%.
And what is 85%?
Cotton.
Good.
Like muscle.
Oh, coconut dark chocolate. They are.
They are good for
to 5% fiber.
Okay.
We created
we constructor inside the class.
Also create a method
to print the user details. Okay
that is there.
So public Lloyd
putting you the info
and then we can see and name
plus last name
in he.
He has already told me that is good.
I don't know how to go.
I don't know anything,
so please be careful.
So I mentally prepared
and to
print out this. Oh
in the past class create a map
that will store the key in ascending order
in that map store.
Personal ID
and a person object.
Print it. Object or details.
All right, So
inside main class, we have to create
which type of map I should create.
I told my husband the same thing. He
the 3D map.
Right.
But coffee maps distort the data in the
spark data form.
So what should be the type off
the in here guys
in pages.
Right.
I can use integers or strings
whatever and as a value.
I am going to store sun object in here.
So what should to be my type?
The type should be person,
not the string class.
We specify the name of the class
whose object
we will be storing as keys and values.
Here we don't specify distinct
and then new
green.
And then
I can see a person mapped or bought
and then maybe one
and the new person.
And then
to insert that
ID in to suit
wanted to
oh, it should be in here.
But is fairly
or to not
has anyone creating these objects then
you guys and me, maybe we can speed up.
Can you please. Person code.
Yes. Look me up on your side by side,
including me
of new person.
I can see some
one person
who will then
put some pretty
creative person.
Class would be create
constructor inside the class
method and we create a map
that we store in that map entirety.
But each object details.
So if I want to bring to the details
what I try to do it like you're doing it
and they don't work it work. Why?
Why did it work?
It should work.
You see, my marina has done the same way.
So I am getting the values from this map,
storing in a collection
of persons and then
for each value
I am printing the user.
So I get all the details in here.
Problem with costing
should not be a problem
with costing as well,
because we are storing the person's object
and we are getting the person
same the same objects back.
The costing is happens
when we are storing a different data type
and want to convert it
to a different type.
Are there more staff guys?
I am about to die.
Please say there are no tasks.
Is it clear right.
One more.
Yes. We have
or right.
Listen me.
The requirement.
Can you explain Line 17 to 20?
This one
someone This one
All I am creating the objects in here.
The person objects.
And then I am using the put method
to store those objects.
To store those objects?
Yes. Just the long way
to do the same thing.
Just along with this.
It's my solution.
It's also good.
Okay.
And we move to the not next task.
Are there other questions?
Create collect the collection
that will store single unique objects
of string type in which order preserved
right A logic to conclude
which collection stores
the unique objects. Guys
Which class inside the collections
framework store b unique elements.
It does not allow
no no list in the entire
the list we can store duplicates
sets.
Right and which type of set
result the order.
There are three types of searches right?
So you said no, it will sort your data.
It's the Lincoln set.
Right.
That preserves the order
so I can see a set
and I am storing single values, right?
The single string values
linked to exact.
Have you guys created the
I have you guys added some values.
Can you send me that code
to speed up this task
alone and you created a list.
List can have duplicates.
That's why we cannot it.
At least we should go with the search.
I think you guys don't
read it.
It's just a name. Thank you.
I think a lot of the mistakes
in programing they happened
because we don't read the questions
totally
right. Mm.
Okay.
And now we have to concatenate
these values.
Right.
So let's say string
values initially.
Let's say yes.
Okay.
So I can say for each
string fbr inside the insert
values, the values of the two values
plus SD
who I am doing something wrong in here
device.
I says it will give me correct results,
but it's not good for
the performance reasons.
Can you guys tell me?
Look, look, can I improving the score.
I try to
because this size
change is is for how to correct.
Are we changing the size here?
No, we are not changing
beside this string builder.
Right.
I am making changes
to this same variable again and again.
Right.
I am updating.
I'm trying to upgrade this value.
So what will happen
internally each time will go
and check the memory
if that value exists in the memory or not.
Right. If I use string.
So instead of this I should use
string builder
and intel is saying the same.
I can tell you saying convert the values
from strength to strength builder
and once
you have those,
then you can guarantee nature.
I can put into those out here.
So I see all the values concatenated here.
Is it clear right.
Any questions from this task?
Yep, sure.
So they're still good
if you're just putting out.
Yes, it is good.
But if you have to
use these values further in your code,
then you should consider
storing them in a variable.
But it's also good for this task
if you have just printed them out.
It's also good.
You guys want a break
before we start the files or it's fine.
We can start to be working with files.
No break.
Okay.
Prints, Lubo.
Well, 53
looks to be back by 110.
Need to take my dog out.
All our guys will be back by 110.
He know which to produce.
Do you want me to book
person?
Okay. With this person?
Person? Person.
Not here
actually.
Let me push this code to the gear.
So you guys,
this is class 29, right?
We are using the
main branch or the master branch.
Then you guys check
if you have got to update or not.
Okay?
All right.
Please be back by 110.
So let's discuss the files
finally, can
I close these two files?
Is there anyone who is still typing
or looking at these files?
Yes or no?
Can I close this?
Okay,
so now you guys have the background,
necessary background for the files, right?
Why we need them
and how we do it manually.
So now we will learn it.
Be professional the programmer way.
Right? You guys are pro and Java pros.
So because we know Java
we will not opening
and closing files manually anymore. Right?
We will be writing the code
for our both tasks.
While I had you smiling,
I am always smiling.
I don't know why.
It's very rare that I am not smiling
when I have enough sleep.
I always smile.
Okay.
More than three.
Alright guys.
So the first type of files
that we will be learning
as you are
attending this class,
only to remind me about the recording.
But yes, we are recording it with ACA.
The only way to to make sure
that we record everything today
because she will be here,
she will be going somewhere
and she will not be able to attend
to complete class.
Don't worry, I said.
We've got we are recording everything. So
so guys,
to make things simple,
click on your project, okay?
Because you guys will be making
a lot of mistakes.
Right click on your project
and then click on New
and then click on this directly.
So you guys see this option, right
click on your project,
then Neil then directly, and let's call it
five five
and let's now right
click and click on file
and then create
a file called config.
You guys can name it anything config doc,
but this extension should be
for all parties.
Okay.
For all of these,
make sure the extension is not properties,
but you can name your file.
You can name it anything so
config not
properties.
I don't know where it goes.
It should be inside this
file files folder in here
you can create a new one.
I had already, so I just got back.
What did I miss?
Sebastian, I'm not going to tell you.
What did you miss?
You are five minute, five minute late.
You have to give us all party.
And then I will repeat everything for you.
Do we have a deal?
Oops, party.
Mine is showing like a little bar
graph. Yes.
That means you have done it correctly.
That means you guys have done it
correctly.
Why am I is not showing?
I think I have not installed that bluntly.
Let me check
labels.
Smart thing.
Yes, I have installed it
and still I don't
get that bar like icon.
There is a bug or something in my eye.
Like you should see that
graph.
Like when I come
I'd show him how to do that right? Yes.
Guys, please show me
that you have done it incorrectly.
You Google it.
Can you repeat the config properties
doors about Oh my God.
All right,
you guys,
if any instructor
is going to do anything wrong.
Right.
And you guys will not let him go anyway.
So a config dot property. Yes.
Maybe my laptop is boxed with so
yes it should be
something is.
Okay. Let me repeat.
Can. Okay.
So first I write it.
Actually let me type something.
How to create
a party file
in the intelligent
right
click on project.
You can Neil
directly
and directly there
again, right click and
click
nail file
and you
extension
you as
properties.
It's funny how babies are trying to
please double master.
Maybe your laptop does not have properties
and I got I I.
Okay so we have to do these things so file
and then new file and then new
so config naught
properties.
Okay.
And then you should see your file
here because
now I also have
the graph, I do not have this file
folder I'm running.
You can create one.
Go to the opposite,
create right click on your project
and then click on new
and then you can create this statically.
Yeah,
I know
you have installed so many plugins
inside my intelligent
so you are ready for market.
That's why there is this conflict. All
and let's try to store B
the sensitive data in here for example
so this property is files
is it's stores D
that are in the form of key value pairs.
So for example I can see
a user name is equal to
admin we don't need because
and password is required to administer
oh, let's have maybe
boss one, two, three, something like that.
And we know once you guys have stored
this data inside this properties files,
so the properties for file
will always contain the data
in the form of developers
because it is a child,
because it is a child of the map
interface.
This properties class
that we will be using to raid this files.
It also implements the map interface.
So all you guys done with these tasks
now. So now we want to read this
file, right?
We want to read the data from this fight.
So what is the first thing that we need
on our computers
If we have to read
the data from a file manually
the bar to right?
So I will first
brain, obviously brain.
So I will be needing the box
so I can get the part of this properties
file.
Sorry, one more time config step.
So Omran, right click on your project
then click on new and then directly.
If you do that, you can create this file
as a bad entry in here.
And once you have created
do you have this files directory
number
and do you have this files directory?
Not then create one.
What are you waiting for?
The waiting from Obama that once
he will say then you will create that
directory.
Let me know once you have the directory.
Trump
okay, create files.
So now right click on your directory
and then click on new and then file and.
Then you can give any name.
And the the extension should be properties
like this and hit enter.
It will be good good
if you keep the name same like I am
using config.
Let me know once you see this file in here
I'm run.
Do you see this file
is waiting on Biden's
first.
It's very simple.
Right click and then new and then file.
What is hard in
posting this portal
posting this portended.
Please do.
Please don't do this on your jobs. Yes.
If you have a different name
for your project, it will be different.
You will see something different in here.
Maybe that's the issue
that you are facing.
Okay.
Anyhow, okay,
so we need the part first, right?
So I will right click in here
and I will say
copy part.
So do you guys see this option?
But from Content Road,
it's the guys
like you get the bad 40 or driver.
Do you guys see this option.
Okay copy this and place inside in here
save one more time.
£1 fish.
You want me to save false right click
and then copy part reference
I could manually.
You are great for one
and then if you click on copy
then you will see all you guys can type
in the name of the directory
and the name of the file
with the extension.
But please don't buy the exact same thing.
If you have created a file
with a different name,
otherwise you will be getting an error.
Yes. Like driver chrome driver
Simon.
Well, y you are to the y,
you are to grab the air from this side
when you when you can get it
from this side, yes, it will work.
But why you want to do that? It's
okay.
So we have the part in here.
What is the next thing is that we need
I. So if the
location of the file on
in our project. Okay
that is actually not the full party one.
So he's using a rally.
So there are multiple types of parts.
Really part absolute part.
And there are two more types of parts.
So we will be speaking
with the relative part in here.
It's easy.
Okay, then I will teach you
how to the full part.
If the file is not stored inside the
inside of your project, we will be needing
the other types of parts.
So I will show you that as well. Okay.
But let's first try to
start from this very simple, basic thing.
So this is the location of the file
inside our broad.
So we have moved.
So we have the part.
Now, when we have the part,
we also navigate to that folder, right?
Or to that file
where that file is located.
That kind of task is done
with this special class in Java
that is called file
input.
Steam
file input scheme is equal to nil
file input 15 and we passed the part here.
Okay.
Like this.
So you simply you guys can think of
never be able to right now
when we do this file
or steam file costume,
we are actually navigating to this spot.
Okay?
We are instructing the operating system
to go and check this.
This file exists or not, if it exist,
make a connection to that file
so that we can start reading the data.
So you will be getting an error right now.
For now,
you can just select all two and enter
and then say add exception to the method.
The signature.
So you will see
this file not found in here.
Okay.
And then the error should go. Okay.
Do you guys see this same
file not found in here
and the error goes away.
So we got the bar to
we navigate to that specific file.
Now we need a special program
that understands the properties file.
Right?
That can read the properties file.
All to enter OneNote are entered
or you can just type it manually.
Right right close
and then file not found exception
in here
or alternate alternate.
Let me do it again.
So if I remove this I will get the error.
What about the Mac Illini?
I told you to sell that Mac
and buy a Windows.
Yes. Options.
I guess they're soft and then enter.
Well, what is the alternative on the
on the on the Mac
for the old.
You can click on the. Yes. Yes.
You guys can also do this
however your mouse over and then say add
exception
to the method signature options keep
options okay
yes Illini try washing your laptop
as I have.
Just do you and your husband
the laptop as well.
Okay.
So are you with me still here?
Is there anyone who is still getting
any issues at us or anything
like that?
No husband, no watching and
then then vice someone else has a laptop.
Maybe your neighbor your friend, but left.
Okay,
so we have never get it to that that.
But right now we need a special program.
That special again it's a class in Java.
Okay, so you guys see how useful
these classes are?
That class is called Properties.
Property is property.
Is it built on new properties like this?
So this is the
this is that special program which will
help us read the data from this file.
Okay.
I have five broken laptops.
If you guys need for practice,
I can give you for practice. Yep.
Just creating the objects. 30.
And now we can instruct this property
as class to load
that file by saying property is not load
and passing this file in
stream object in here.
Then you guys will again
be getting in error.
Right.
And again you have hovered
your mouse, click on this bulb
and then say add exception
to the method signature.
We will learn
what are these exceptions and how they can
effect are programs.
Are you guys done?
Okay, so
now we are finally ready to read the data
so I can see
property is door to get
you guys see this get the method.
It was also present somewhere else.
Can you guys tell me that's it.
This is the last class.
This method.
That method was also present
somewhere in you guys.
Tell me
in the least.
It was also present in the map as well.
Map file.
If you guys are open
this property is class.
You will see this is actually a child
class of hash.
So all the matters
that are present inside the hash map,
which are all the methods
which are present in map,
you guys can also use
those methods. Right?
Remember the inheritance concept.
So that's why we have this guide method.
And if I have to get
the value of a key in a map, what do I do?
I specify the key.
So internally, Java is storing
all of this desktop, the form of maps.
This is treated as e this as value.
This is E, this is value.
So if I want this user name
from this file,
I can simply say properties dot dead
and I specify the property in here
and I should get the corresponding value.
So I get admin same, same as maps
because it's the job of map
looking open,
look side by side.
Okay, you are not going anywhere.
I think this is also a bug in intelligent
so let's close and reopen it again.
You guys see excited side.
Maybe you have installed
too many extensions.
I should uninstall
some of them more intelligent.
Sometimes it does not behave correctly.
Oh no, no.
It looks
weird.
Well, they're fine having. Yes,
I remember those first days.
Those first days they are gone.
You guys are now. Pros null.
Alexa, you have.
You must have done something wrong.
Yes. You remember guys in the maps?
These words, they
they are case sensitive to
how many of you see
the value from this file?
This admin.
When you specify the
in you guys tell me the code
to get to get to this password
as well from this
file.
Can you guys write the code to get to be
password as well and send me in.
The live channel
is too hard.
These are just three lines of code
Walmart.
Just kidding.
I told you this is an easy class.
All right, so from a map,
how do I get the value?
I say name of the map.
Then I call the get method and I the
easy peasy right?
So I get the password. Well,
so this is simple.
This is how we read the files using Java.
Is there anyone who is confused
or maybe some piece of code is not clear
as the file have to be called.
The dot properties
are the it to work with a text.
You know it will not work.
BSD part.
It is only for properties file.
You can try that as well.
Try it and let me know
when it changes the extension
of your file and try it
if it works or not.
I have never tried it, but 99
I am sure that it will not work like that.
So properties loading the
that side inside properties object
from the file
and then I can get all the files
when I hit all controlled files.
This.
So Mohamud, I told you about this
all I think 15 minutes ago
and you are clicking all to enter now
let me check why you got this
file part. Yes.
You have to select this first option.
Add exception to method signature.
The first one. Yes. You are doing it
correctly.
Check the first option.
Let me know if you still face an issues
getting the
locks with the file as well.
That's great.
So value
menus or the
corresponding
fees.
Okay, so we specify the key
and then we get the value back
and then we specify the key
and we get value back.
Are you guys able to read
all of you are able to read this data
from the files.
Okay.
So right now
we have this file inside the intelligent,
but I should be able to read the file
anywhere from my computer.
Right.
So for example,
let's say this is a folder on my computer
and I have this configuration
property that check
what is presently not in here.
Okay, server
password, loop name, user name.
Let's try
so you guys can create a new file
anywhere on your computer
and let me know once
you have created a file and
has stored some data inside that file
to any folder you should know.
You know the location of that folder?
No, no, not any type of file.
It's it should still be configuration
dot properties.
Okay. Name can be anything.
The extension should be properties.
So let's try to learn
how to read from anywhere on our computer.
Let me know once
you guys are done creating these files,
those who are related to create the files.
Let me send you a file
while you need to create the Excel file.
No, you guys don't need to create
Excel files.
Just fill this properties file.
Are you guys done creating file
this properties file
is created automatically.
You didn't show us. Oh, it's simple.
Right?
Right.
Click then. Neon.
And then you can choose, let's say,
for example, text file,
and then you can say config.
Oh, my God.
You are still maybe voice
config and the extension should be
properties
that suit.
Why do we need to do this
so that you guys know how to?
Read the files from anywhere,
anywhere from any computer,
any folder anywhere
to just create a file anywhere inside
your computer.
Let me know once you guys are done.
I hope the Mac users know how to create
a file with Dot Properties Illini.
Do you know how to
create dot properties file?
Yes. Notepad is also good.
The American you guard Illini
how to do that
or use my file guys use use my file.
Just copy and paste
this file on your computer
as the Mac users.
Just copy and paste this file.
Download this violent story
to any of you on your computer.
And yes,
I have shared it in the live questions
so you guys can copy
this part to this file as well.
You guys can also copy this right click
and then copy
and paste it anywhere on your computer.
Just just copy this file and paste it
anywhere on your computer
desk.
Let me know what you guys are done.
And also make sure, guys,
you have some data inside your file.
Now, let me create a new
demo for you guys
and from your previous demo,
just copy and paste this code
so create a new main
method and copy and paste the code.
And now
you have to be exceptionally.
Are you guys done creating a new file,
naming it config tool
config file
demo two and copying and pasting the code.
Okay, now go to that file.
So for example, this is.
Yes, just changed the part.
So the windows do your dirty.
You guys can just
right click in here.
No, because you are not using Windows 11.
So let's do this.
Just click on your file and then
copy this part from here.
So this is the part of this file
on my computer, this
and just go inside this address
bar on Windows.
And I think the Mac users,
you guys can right click and you click on
properties or something like
that,
you will be able to get this path as well.
The Mac users.
Can someone tell you how the how we can
get to the part of a file on Mac
or if you guys already know the part,
you can just copy it from here.
Okay.
This is called absolute part.
So now I just need to change
this part in here.
Okay. This one.
And you guys can use double backward
slashes or forward slash.
The both should work fine
like this.
So copy the part of your file
and a lot of you will be messing up things
in here
and district type config dot properties.
Okay.
Before these backwards issues.
So Jimmy, we are trying to read the file
from a different location outside of Intel
number.
Can you
show Illini how to get the part of a file
in Mac. Yes.
If you guys want to add some back
to inside that config file, it's fine
if you guys don't want to do that,
it's also fine, but should at least be
one key and value pair
so that we know for sure
that this code is working fine.
So you can like Windows 11.
So what is the difference to Windows ten?
Don't recommend it to upgrade to Windows
11 now because it has a lot of bugs.
I regret upgrading it,
but I also like the sound,
the feedback, the look and feel.
They are all modern,
but it has a lot of bugs.
Maybe next three months or so.
Once they fix it, then you guys can.
With the Windows 11.
Yes, so many bugs
in Windows
XP was good, Windows seven was bad,
then Windows eight was good
or Windows XP was good.
Seven was bad, right
then Vista was good,
eight was bad,
ten was good and now 11 is bad.
And then but with good
system
for doors.
Vista was good.
I mean. Yes.
No, not that bad.
I mean, all the windows from Microsoft,
they are bad, right?
I used it for a very short period of time.
Vista was not good.
Horrible.
95 was good.
What about 92?
But I have used Windows 95 as well.
I am that old.
Oh My God, Windows 95 and 98.
You have used both of them.
3.1 DOS.
That means you guys
have not specified the proper, but
those who are who are getting this
system cannot find bought file specified.
It means to you.
I did it correctly.
No, it's not correct.
Let me run here.
Let's let's see if I can find my.
You see, I also get nothing else
configured on the properties.
Let me check if I have some dirt out.
Not inside that file.
I don't have any dirt in here.
Let me call the dirt
from here.
Control and see.
Control we and then control this.
And then if I run my demo
now, I shouldn't get invalid capital C
No, I did not have any data time.
India, any issues with Mac users?
It works for me, but for me
I got it correctly.
And so now you guys can read the files
from anywhere your computer,
you have nothing.
That's great to me.
You are different from others, right?
You get nothing.
Others gets simple values.
I don't know what to do.
Mac users are not working.
Please sell your Macs
if you don't know how to use
and buy the windows one.
Actually, we were thinking of suggesting
the operating systems to the to the
to the students before joining the course.
But then we thought
maybe it be too much buying
a Windows laptop just for this course
in a nicer.
Can you show me the complete data.
No those who are getting issues
please post the screenshot here.
Half of you can post in here,
half of you can post on this.
Fortunately
for you
it means you guys are not specifying
the correct but board certified.
Make sure this c is lowercase.
It is.
Make sure the c is lowercase.
My c is lowercase.
You have specified uppercase.
Maybe that's the issue.
And now you have not passed
to configuration
dot properties at the end.
Therefore you are getting the issue.
Silva What is your issue?
So I was having the same issue,
but I had to add or add.
The ESD is also good
if it is working fine,
but I will suggest to stick
with the properties extension.
I got the same same really tired
also having the same issue.
I think maybe the C should be capital
you'll get your c is not capital
result up.
Get configured properties
so you guys can let me check
if it works.
I think it does not work
outside of intelligence,
but still.
So just copy this path
that you have written the Windows user
and inside this address bar
based with that fire that that part,
if that file opens,
that means you have specified the correct.
But if that does not open,
that means there is an issue
with the default.
It was configured, configured
or properties not to de to to extensions.
No remove and remove from end
with the door to exterior works.
Otherwise it feels
mind does not work without load.
The extreme.
Okay.
So those who are having issues
working outside of the intelligence.
So let's not go outside
of the intelligence.
Maybe I was too excited to show you
how to read the file from anywhere.
Let's forget it.
I didn't show anything.
This tool does not exist
for whatever reason, we can't create
or properties files outside of the Intel
or PowerShell.
No, we can.
If. If I learn, if you allow.
So for example, on my
Windows machine
I have allowed to edit the extensions.
If you guys don't allow to edit
the extension,
I think the setting is available
somewhere in here.
You see this file name extensions.
I don't remember where it should be
on Windows ten, but there is this setting.
Yes, Windows by default.
It hides the extension.
You have to enable this extension
and then it will work
those so for which it is working with DOT
the it is because of this reason
as good of a language file
no us God from which files
we can get in for using method.
Oh. As you can see,
we are getting the info from properties,
files and text files.
Now it works.
Confident dot property is not pages
until you have pages file
and that is just copy and paste my file.
Okay. Let's let's.
Let's not worry too much about this
because we will be doing the same
the Excel file as well.
Okay.
So whatever is working for you is fine
for now.
Is file is like creating
a new folder on gnome.
It's actually something different.
Question Can we say a file
name with any name, but in intelligible
it must right on Filbert properties.
No, no.
We should write the same name in here as.
But if you are
giving a name Donald Trump to your file,
you should write Donald Trump.
Can you
not config dot properties Otherwise
how would your job.
I know that it has to find
the Donald Trump or configured
properties. Yes,
I cannot say that, but I.
Angela knows everything.
So guys, are you guys good? Yes.
I assume you guys are good.
Let's move forward.
So this is how we
will read the data from the file.
Let's now learn how to create new files.
Okay.
Let's learn how to create new files.
Not good.
Not me.
Okay.
We will do this experiment
of creating the file
from our side of the integrity
using the Excel files.
Okay, let's.
Let's forget about this for now
you'll get
is working because you have not enabled
the extension.
I will show you how to do that.
How to record to inside,
how to record inside of the file.
Out to the code. What do you want? Record.
So we are already recording.
So let's create a new
Java class.
Add info to the file.
That's what I am teaching you now.
So this is how we read the data
from existing files.
Now let's understand
how we can create these files
using programing. Oh,
yes, yes, I know,
but let's not go this
is so
if I have to create a file again,
I need to first
find folder or that location
where I want to create that file.
Right.
So let's create a file inside
this are the files folder.
So let me copy the path
from previous demo
or the part from the Windows machine.
So let's look and copy this one
from demo one, not from demo two.
So I want to create a file inside
this files directory
and I want to name that file.
Maybe Trump dot properties.
Okay, so now
I have this path in here right?
The next thing, the next thing that I need
is D So now is the concern of
anyone facing bad connection issues
or only me?
Actually, in the bill
we intentionally did this
because the.
Okay,
let me let me try to be
spelling problem actually here
is how the
prime minister of India.
This is how it pronounces here.
So I have a part. Okay
And then now I need to
go inside this file to detect tree and
create this files. Right.
So what I will do, I will say
properties, properties,
new properties,
and I will say maybe properties dot
but. Right.
Do you guys remember that would matter.
Same as maps support may be
user name as
a single 1 to 3
and maybe
put a password
as false.
One, two three.
Okay.
So I have a but
I am creating the object of this
special properties.
Then on that object
I am putting two fields in here right
now. The next thing.
So when we have to read the data
from a file,
we use the file import state.
But when we have to write the data
we use as different class
that is called file
output scheme.
And again, we passed default in here
and same again.
I will be getting an error.
So let me click on add
exception to the metadata,
letting me know what you guys are done
by putting this code up.
So now if I want to create a file
right now, I only have one file in here.
So now I will say a property is not
store
and I will pause file, output frame.
And as you guys put comments in the gear
table, we can also put comments in here
creating in new file and maybe.
Yeah, and then I will be getting an error
and I have to be
method signature.
So now if I execute this code in new file
inside
directory should be created with this name
and it should have these two fields.
So I see my file in here.
Now, if I open that file,
I see the comments on the first line,
then I see the date and time by default,
and then I see my fields in here.
Do you guys see the
you see new files are being created.
So this is how we read and write?
Yes. Let me show you. Okay.
Why is the file orange?
Because it is not added to the GitHub.
I installed the GitHub I have configured
to get out my intelligence.
So you remember before we can use
anything in the gate,
we have to add that to the gate.
So if I added it will change it.
Now it is the real world application.
You guys will learn about real world
applications
when you will be building the frameworks
on Macintosh properties are not needed.
Can you go back?
Let me know if you guys are facing
any errors or issues.
No one is fixing any issues.
All is working fine.
That's great.
Alexa, you are using file input steam.
We have to use file output stream
this time because we are
only writing the that at this time.
And that's why you are having issues.
What will happen when we store it?
When we started this
then the file is created in here
where we can see the file is created.
You will see the file on this part.
The that you guys have specified in here.
I stored the user name first button.
The file password is first.
It's because you remember that hash table
map is also
it does not care
about the order of insertion.
So that's why you guys can see sometimes
password,
sometimes you name
a nice place post in this corner.
What did I miss?
Maryam you have to add this froze
and an Iowa exception in here
and we do any operation and the result
will be stored inside of the file. Yes.
Any your ideal life
Christmas tree.
Then you open the remote to on the decide.
Yep. For this class is easy, right?
Nice.
And it's kind of more interesting
than the other dialog classes.
Very easy.
Is there anyone else
who is still facing issues?
Make sure to show me
the screenshot.
It's fine. It's fine.
The code should be demo three.
Yes, right now
we are working on demo three.
This is the demo three. No.
Oh yes.
This 140.
I hope it's still readable.
Okay.
No issues
guys.
Is there anything that you guys don't
understand?
The code that I have written.
Please go to this code and let me know
if you guys don't understand
any of the line what that line is going.
You guys don't need to memorize
the syntax.
Just write how to read the data
from a properties file on Google
or just write how to write to the data
to the properties file.
And if you have understood the concepts,
hopefully you will be able
to successfully create that
program to read.
All right.
Yes. Monthly.
It looks good. Yes.
You have created this object, this one.
Yes. Write the rest of the code like this
and the file should be created
or allowed for seamless file
in first name.
So you guys can think of it like you see
how water flows in our into our houses
and how it flows out from our houses
from the sink.
If you have to read the data
inside your program,
we use the file input stream.
If you have to write the data
out of your Java program, you
you use the file output stream.
Yes. Putting out information,
something like
and I moved to
the next demo.
So next actually, let's create a utility
utility class
because you guys will be needing
these classes and meters inside
your inside your frameworks.
So go with this.
Let's go inside to see what is
and let's create
a new class and let's call it
file utils.
Okay?
Let me know what you guys,
you guys all have this utils package,
right?
Nope. Please
create one. Please create one.
It will be needed.
You guys will needed
needing it in your projects.
So the useful methods
that we will be learning,
I will be putting all those matters
in your code.
We overwrite the file of the same name.
Or would it resulting in a note
if I execute.
Let's say for example, if I re execute
this code, they'll say if I re execute
the score, the file will be overwritten,
it will be replaced.
We will not be getting an error.
There is one more thing, guys,
that I want to
show you.
Let's say
I have opened this file right?
This Excel file.
If this file is opened and if I try
to delete this, I get this add up.
Right?
It says action can't be completed
because file is open in the spreadsheet,
which means
if a program is
using a file on our operating system. So
right now we are dealing with the entities
which outside of our gala programs.
So as a responsible programmer,
when we are reading some data
from our files
or when we are writing the data
from our files,
we should also close those files.
Right now we are not writing any code
to close those files.
So for the proper way, a good programmer,
this is how it will do so.
It will also
close that file
once it is done
reading or writing the data.
We should also close that file
so that the other programs
on our computer, they can also interact
with that file freely.
If we don't close this file
and if our program is in execution,
no one else will be able to interact
with that file.
So should also write this file output
standard clause
once we are done writing the data
and let me do it in here
as well.
While import stream dot clause
and in here is
why I am writing this file in perfect
game,
not clause.
Is this utils or directory
or regular packet.
Instead I go to regular package.
It's the regular package.
All you guys done
creating this file utils class
when you call my name good programmer.
You're making me very happy.
So let's create a static method in here
to read the properties file.
So next time we will not be writing
these five lines of code.
We will write a method and every time,
if we have to read the data,
we will just be calling that method right?
I know how to do it again.
Was like how method the config
file properties for Sebastian.
Can you rephrase your question
for creating the util file?
Or if simply a double class?
Yes, it will be same as we have been using
the other methods.
So most of the time guys, the
config files,
they will be stored inside your projects.
Yes. Now we are kind of creating a library
so that we don't have to
write the code again and again.
I think in your project for
you guys will be calling it Configurator.
I don't know, so
let's call it.
Let me actually rename this
to Configurator
because it will be same as off
your it be easier for you.
So let's call it
config reader.
Okay.
So that it can match your the future work.
In the future
you guys will be creating the
you guys will be creating your projects
and in that project you guys will be
using these terminologies so that you can
it forward, you can straight away
use your files that you are creating.
So let's look for the enemy
to configurator
and let's write a method
the public
static
string
and it will return us
the value of that property
that we be passing
right?
So we will be needing it.
But right.
And then we will be needing a key, right?
Because all the data is stored
in the form of keys and values.
And once we have the part and the key,
what do we need that next?
Guys,
if I have to read the data, a config file
and I have bought and the key,
what should I do next?
The connection, the file input scheme.
Right.
So file
import stream
file input stream.
The important new
file input stream and I pass the box
in here
and for now
click on this more options button
and this time click on this.
Surround with the catch block.
Later on I will tell you what does this
catch blocks
me okay.
Or is it confusing, guys?
It is confusing you.
What is this try what is this?
Cache and all that
you guys don't need to worry
about Next classes about this, right?
Catch blocks
is just a type of block.
Okay. All right.
So come here.
Inside the file performed.
The next thing is.
Okay, so we have the file. Interesting.
What do we need next, guys,
I need to create the object. Try.
So property is property
is equal to nil property.
So right.
And then properties.
Dot Lord and I need to pass
the file file input, string.
What is this shortcut fight. Right.
So now if you hover your mouse over
the error, it will show you two options.
Click on more.
Yes, it is like and if conditions or one
and then you can select
replace file
found with the more generic one.
Okay.
Basically
you can select any of these a first option
or the third option.
So I have loaded the ease
and value pairs inside
this property is object.
And how can I get the object
from this properties object?
I can say from is dark act
and I pass the key in here.
Right.
And then if I return
actually let me you will.
You will be getting an error.
So instead of doing let's
store
I will explain later why we are going.
Let's declare a value
setting a variable value in here.
Let's initialize it with
maybe null or anything.
You can slide it with anything.
How we fix load, add a
directory. Let
let's not do this.
I think it will confuse you.
Just delete that.
Try get block and
utilities
add method add to method signature.
Okay.
So this good it actually returns
the end object
if you want to get a string
you can use get property instead of get.
So use this approach.
I think that a better approach
will confuse you.
For now, I will teach you about that
by catch block and then we will use those.
Then.
Then we will change these methods to use
try and get blocks.
I think it's more simple and easy to read
it's easy.
Write this same thing, file in for same.
We are passing the path
then properties object.
We are creating object
and loading the properties and passing
the keys that will return as the value
and we are returning it
from this method.
Let me know once you guys are done typing
this code.
Can we write commands? Yes.
They they are the same.
Unless they are same.
For example, opening that
file,
creating the object of
properties class
loading, loading
all the property from that
file inside,
inside the
properties object
inverting the
value for
messy quick
e and
returning it.
So is it good now
the mean
you are getting any errors,
make sure that the key is in lowercase.
I think it's in uppercase online
then and on line 15
you are specifying in lowercase.
Okay.
So do you guys done typing this code
in any or remove that as well.
Make sure the code looks the same as mine.
That is. Let's do one more thing.
If someone is not providing this part
to this config dot properties,
let's by default I want to use this part.
So what should I do in here?
If someone is not providing
this string part
here, should still be able to call this
method by just passing this key.
What is concern that I should use in here?
I want to give this flexibility
to the user that he can call this raid
method by just passing maybe one argument.
Yes, the over loading right.
So if someone is passing
only the key,
I want to still return the value
from this default file.
Otherwise he can specify its own file
name.
Right.
So string key.
And do I need all of this?
Do I need to rewrite all of this code
inside this method?
Super
elect super is for the parent class
so I can all be read method,
but by passing to article
and as a part I can
I can pass files
then forward and then
config dot
properties
and then I will pass the key in here.
You remember how we
how we
re used the constructors
in that overloading example.
We don't have to rewrite all of this code.
I am just calling this.
Read the method from this. Read
the method.
They're passing
this extra argument in here.
So if Java is passing.
If only if someone is only passing
the key faster.
This method will be called
and inside this method
I am calling other method
and passing the to article.
Next. If someone is directly passing
the two arguments,
then this method will be called.
Do you guys understand
what is going on in here?
How the method overloading most guys?
Let's say you have to call this method.
How can I tell Joe
that I want to call this method
same name, but dual parameters.
And if I want to call this
method, I need to pass one parameter.
And what is happening inside this method?
I am creating this second
argument from my own right.
I am creating
this second argument,
am creating that part
in here.
And the key I am getting from here
and which method will be called.
I write of this line.
So actually let me let me show
by debugging here,
I think it will make more sense.
So in my run,
you have this one in my config,
I have this username right
and I want to get this value
so I will allow set config.
Then figure you do the trade
and if I pass this the username
and if I say add to method signature,
what value should I get guys?
I don't think so.
We will be able to make
to the Excel file assignment
today
guys.
If I say config reader dog trade
and if I pass the username in here,
what value
should I get?
Add meaning right.
And this time how many lines of code
I have written to read this
data?
Only one right?
So let's see if it works or not.
So I get this admin.
Now let's try to debug how,
how we are able to read this.
Start out
by just specifying one line right.
So I place the debug point first, then
I say debug
and now I want to check
what is happening inside this read method.
So should I click to step into
or step over?
I want to check what is how the code is
being executed inside this read
through takes a click step into
step over into right
and will take me to this method
or this method when I will be clicking
Stepping to really take me to first
method or the second one
second one and how does
it not that it should go to type
in the method
one on the right?
So if I click on Step Into
it shows me two options.
It says Hey, yes,
there you are calling this println method
and you are calling this trade method.
So which method do you want to go inside?
So I want you to go inside this, right?
So it takes me in here. Now,
in here I again calling the read
method about this time as a part,
I am passing files, select
config properties
and the key I have boss from here.
Now which method will be called
the one?
Right.
So again, if I say step into
I get inside this first one
and the path is a five dot config
and the key is username.
Now it will go
inside this config file.
When I say a file import
stream new file input theme,
then the object,
the properties files will be created.
All the
these and the values will be loaded inside
this object
and I will be able to get to that field
using that property.
Right.
So if I say next, next, next,
they problem in the second method is that
it assumes the part string,
but the first method gives you the option
to put in the path. Yes.
So we will we want behavior, right?
So that if someone is not passing
the part inside this read,
we want to read the data from the default.
But if someone is passing a specific part,
let's say, for example, if I pass
a specific port in here
now frame
from there it will be in the database.
So let me open that.
So if I, if I have this from
and if I specify this
from the DOT properties and let's say
I want to read this username,
so this time I am specifying
the path as well as the key
for which I want to get the data.
So will it still drain the data
from configured properties or this time
will it go inside this property properties
and at this time
will will
this method to be executor this time?
No, because now I am passing two things
and I will be.
This method will be followed right?
If I say
I execute this,
this time I get a similar one to take.
So with the help of overloading
and properties files,
I am able to give this flexibility
to the end user that,
if we specify, specifies
the path I read from that specific file.
If it does not provide the
but I read from the default
file is a clear guide
why I created this booted methods.
So when someone is not specifying
the path, I assume this part.
I assume this path.
Okay.
And I call method in here.
So do you have been teaching
for a long time?
I think you deserve rest.
If 15 motivators.
Oh Wrapper 209 okay.
Let me go to
by the way
these wrappers
for the interview questions.
They are also really
and now you guys should be able
to solve these.
Oops, we did it.
So you guys should now be able to solve
all of these interview as well.
So I will release these next week.
So wrap to zero nine.
Well, what a difficult thing to do.
It's easy peasy.
So let's first create the
public
standard, avoid the mean
and it says create
a list of map that is list.
And inside that list,
we should have a map.
And inside those maps we have,
we are floating
string and objects and call it that list.
Yeah.
So we how do we create list?
We say
ArrayList, right?
Oh, let's let's call it a list.
So list.
And inside that list we should have a map.
And inside that map we have to for
string and objects, right?
So let's call it object here,
and we have to call it
that.
The list is equal to new
exploded and a list.
Okay.
Something
like this.
And we have to do the import as well.
So this import is coming
from the util package.
So import
java or util and you guys can put a star
that means import everything
from this package.
Yeah.
All right. So a new release, right?
And then now inside this map,
we have to create this map as well.
So map
string and then
object and let's call it
Apple map is equal to continue,
maybe hash map or let's call it
plaintext now.
So you guys don't lose that. You.
I think not.
We'd be happy.
No, not happy anymore
anymore.
Not okay.
It will compile.
Fine.
Don't worry about.
So the I think the main thing
that might have confused
you is why we are using these objects
to store
values in here. Right.
For example, if I have to store 20.
Well, why I am using
an object right?
So this 20 is a double
and this quantity is an integer, right?
So if I have to store
multiple types of data
inside the same map, I can use
this object in here
they are English.
Oh, the edge
at that.
Okay, so we are good now.
So now I can store so create
apple map thing
and add below peers into it.
Right.
So items.
And then I should add so I should say
apple map dot port
so because I have
created this map of object type,
I can put anything in here.
Right.
I can put things I can put above right.
I can put integers whatever I want.
So the second is
for is
and it is currently for zero zero.
The third one is on 30
and that's the quantity
is ten.
Add apple map to the list right.
So once you have the Apple map,
I have to add this to the data list.
So I will say that to start add
and then I will say
and then create an orange map.
So this time let me copy
and paste this code in here.
Let's call it
orange map.
And in here the item will be orange.
The price will be
going to 1.99 in the quantity.
Okay. And then
and then add the orange map, the detector.
And so again, that values and
and then orange map, All right.
And then
create a loop
from that list.
Retrieve each key and store
in a variable,
calculate the sum of each object,
and then print the values of each
tradition,
same as shown below in the output.
So for example, calculate the sum
total, stored it in a variable called
total case after the loop
put into the value of total positive.
So items, the apple price is going to be
quantity is then subtotal is
200. Right?
Because we have to take this value
multiply with this quantity.
That's how we get to hundred.
And then we put in this line.
Then we pick the second map,
we get a big quantity
and we multiply it with the total quantity
and then we get that the total.
And then we also have
to get the full total in here.
Okay.
So can you guys do it now
or is still confusing?
It's easy peasy, right?
Okay. Let me let me play.
So let's create a variable of double total
and last initialize it
with zero.
And first
we have to iterate through this list
so that we can get all data from here.
Right?
So I can use the enhanced Guadalupe
because I am only retrieving the data
so I can write for
what does this
list guys?
Here we go.
Amateurs already done it
maps. Right.
So I from this list I will be getting
a map. Right.
So what?
I will be getting from this list,
I will be getting a map.
And inside that map, what do I have?
I have a string.
And this second
object, the second thing is object.
Right?
And let's call it anti
column.
And then
I need to pass this that listing.
Right.
So now
from this list,
I will be getting all the maps
one by one right.
So what I can do,
I can get
I can declare three variables right.
And then
so can I, can I use
if I want to get to be these
and the values inside this loop
from this map base from this map
I want both to be keys and the values.
So I use a loop.
Or should I go with the iterator?
I can use both. Yeah, I can use, but
both is fine, right?
But I will be needing another loop.
So if I say
if I say
four for this fact, the second for loop
that I am writing in here is to
the entries from this map.
Right.
It has multiple entries.
So I will say map
dot entry.
Right.
So I have got the map.
But inside that map I have three things.
I have the item name, I have the quantity,
I have the price right.
So I also need to get all three of them
because I need to print the
first key and value pair.
The second key value pair
the third to give a bit.
And I also need to get the total.
So therefore I need all of them.
So there.
So I am getting a map entry in here
right.
So it's this thing
and the objects right inside this.
Each entry there is the string
and object, let's call it
maps indexed.
Call this one as the entry.
So how so?
Let's say I have this map from this map.
How can I get the entry set?
I can go to the entry start
by simply saying
the bias was simply specifying
the name of that list.
Right.
So I already have the map in here.
So I am saying map dot.
What should I write in here?
I should write entry and dissect
right.
So it will give me the entry.
Exact.
And now if
so, once I have the entry, what I can do
from the first entry I can see here
I can say.
And the dot exactly
right.
So this will return me.
Where is this?
So this will return me apple
right
in then. Plus,
if I see a space and if I say
entry or go to value
so this will return me items.
Then I need a column.
Actually I should put a column in here.
So then I need a colony in here.
So items column
and then a space and then the app.
Right.
And then another
at the ending here.
Now put this blessing here.
So let me first execute
all part of the course
so that you guys can understand.
So if I execute discord
so I, I got the items
and then the did
I add
or have orange
the apple
why I don't see
the other ones.
The second list should be orange map
and then divided map is added here.
I got this from here
and map
and three and three maps thought
entries and in here
I mean and these
that are this
that this line 14 to 16
what is wrong with line 14 to 16.
All you would need to do
orange and orange and orange.
Now it looks good. Yes.
So we get the items
from the Apple map
and we get the quantities
and the items are everything
from the other maps.
So now what we want to put into them
out on a single line.
So let's remove this.
And then from here
and let me put
it printer in here.
Oh right.
So I get items apple
and there should be a space
after the Apple MacBook back.
Okay, it looks good.
Now the only thing that I need to do is
I need to get this subtotal as.
Well right that subtotal
I will get by multiplying the keys
with the values.
Right. So
let me go in this subtotal as well.
So space
and then subtotal.
But actually why not put it in here
plus.
And then I need to get this
and this quantity
and this right.
So what I can do,
I can declare some variables.
So if I need to store
that inside this variable,
I can declare three variables in here.
Right?
So what I can do
supposed to be orange.
So what I can do, I can set string.
So I only I'm only interested in quantity
and then this price.
So what I can do, I can see
integer
quantity.
Okay.
And then let's initialize it with zero
and one more variable to hold
the price.
Right.
Next, let's initialize it with zero.
So what? What is happening right now?
I am getting all the values one by one
so I need.
And if condition in here
because it's happening
all inside that loop.
Right.
So I need to check if this key
that I am getting, if it is equal
to the
key price, then
I will update this price variable.
Yeah,
I will update this private
surprise will be equal to
the corresponding value
from here.
But now I get an error.
Why I get an error because this values
that I am storing in here.
They are stored in the form of objects,
but I am trying to assign it to the
integer variable.
So I need the cost thing in here right
guys?
Is it making sense?
Easy peasy.
This is not easy peasy.
Just just step by step.
Right.
Okay. It will be fine.
So inside me, if you guys remember
those wrapper classes
I told you about, the
about the methods to do the convergence.
Right.
So first, what I need to do,
I need to convert it to a string.
Okay?
And then
or you can try it directly as well.
Okay.
So, for example, if I say
double like this
and then surprise integer
integer.
Okay, so what will happen now?
It will be converted to integer
or what you guys can do
are you guys can use the methods
from these classes as well.
So for example,
this, there is this method to
explicitly perform this conversion, right?
So for example, if I call that
value a dark integer,
the true value of method.
So this method, what it will do,
it will pick this value.
So from in here,
so it will pick this value from here
and then it will try.
Is it uppercase or lowercase?
The value of
okay, here we go.
So this in order dot value off
it will take that specify value
and it will convert that to end integer.
And why we have to go through all of this,
we have to go through
because we want to store strings,
double and integers, all of them
inside a single map.
Okay. It's
it says
must do metaphor.
What do this class really last?
And you need to head back to my computer.
I would have done this in
in about in one week
I'll have the
it guys.
But all this
this is also the last of that.
But right now
you guys know all about casting.
You guys know about the maps.
You guys know about lists, right? So.
So it should be easy peasy.
No, Maybe you guys should try it
after the review class.
So let me let me just print out
the quantity.
Quantity.
And this is the last apple, by the way.
So you should expect at least this
from the last apple, right? I
don't say it will
be not introduce.
If this is not price
we should check.
It might be the quantity right.
And you guys will be laughing
on these codes
after a few months.
So if it is a quantity, then
what I need to do, I need to update
this quantity variable.
Oh, it should be a double.
By the way.
And the price can be points right?
So now I have to do the same
for the quantity.
I will feel so much better
if the people that already got
jobs can't solve it.
So you, you have Farhad,
you Guys can try it.
So I get the price,
I get to the quantity and simple.
Now I need to multiply that right.
So say price multiplied by
quantity.
All right, easy peasy.
Are we do this in job site?
Most probably
you guys will not be doing it,
but I created this so that deal buys it.
So it's a combination
of all previous concepts, the cost
being the the maps, the list, the
if conditions default, loads of order and
and follow the operators.
I tried you guys
so that you guys have to do everything
inside this trap. No
both of them
need to be able to get the exact output
order quantities
can't get in the quantities being once
a month.
Y y. No, we need
doubles for both of them
will not work
when we don't understand our concepts.
That will be like
quantity 10.0 in the solution.
All Okay. But is that
I misspelled it in
better than double or
double?
No, this subtotal is still zero.
Right?
No. Subtotal ten.
Subtotal ten.
No subtotal ten.
So I think I should
do this.
So be printed
after
we are done.
Maybe we will be needing variables to
store the other variables as well.
Right.
Or we can do this.
Let's keep it inside in here.
And let's be clear.
These two things outside of the here.
So we get the price,
we got the quantity and it
and then we instead
of printing the account
in here, let's print
this last part.
And here
I said two days x,
everything multiplied by 0.000
unpublished extrapolate,
please remove this wrapper.
Okay Let's assume you guys never
saw this, but
if I could help
it. Oh, my God.
And if
I don't think so.
You guys have understood
a single line of this.
Have you got a single line of this wrapper
that we have in the last 30 minutes?
Code up the line.
It's as you
you can tell me this before
we spent like 30 minutes, right?
You guys could have told me
right away in here that asked everything
that you are writing off,
but that nothing is making sense for us.
Tell me something.
Seriously, bro, if we are doing this on
the go, I will not waste my time anymore.
But this is not
what you guys will be doing on your dogs.
And dog is is is very simple jobs.
They are simple. It's
all their advice.
Take some rest.
Imagine you guys never saw
what I have shown
in the last 30 minutes.
But okay, this this was not the.
No, no, no.
It is the ad made to.
So let's say this was not okay,
but am I'm not allowed to solve
this one as well.
Right.
That means my of my efforts. They are not
real.
Right.
At least some of you of the
you guys are able to solve it.
So I think Simon was also able
to solve it.
Yes. There we had to quote
I would share the solution.
Just have a look at the solution.
Amid the miserable
IKEA is desperately waiting for big class
recording
that line that said
store them in variables confused me.
Okay.
I hope the mere the confusion is now gone.
Spent some time honored.
All right, guys, take some rest. Bye. Bye.
I was trying to capture them all.
Have a good day.
Survived this.
Bye bye.