Ottawa Installing Intelligencer.
Unfortunately,
the video for Mac users is not ready,
and I want to record an additional video
in which I want to show you
how to debug and navigate
through your intelligence that we do.
It's not ready, but at the end of this
class, if we are left with some time,
I will show you how to install it
and those who are eager to use it.
You guys may start using it and the others
most probably
at the end of today's class, or
maybe
by the end of next class
I will share the videos care about
in the end because I don't know
language discrimination
16.11 Is it AM or am 16.11
is the best.
Alexi What do you mean by 16?
Okay, so you mean.
Yes, it it's, it should be if
you are closely monitoring the canvas.
Alexey
whatever clouds from 7 a.m.
in the morning till 10 p.m.
in the evening
somebody might read a lot about this
lives.
I am little confused.
Are we doing constructors
today are modified so we will be doing
both.
I am ready. Always.
Okay. Is it okay now?
Is the calendar perfect now
this class and the the modified one.
It was supposed to be part on weekdays,
but we will be having additional 2 hours
so we will start the constructors as well
today.
I can plan something if we know before.
Looks like we have a calendar
manager to. Yes.
How many days off on Christmas
at most one.
So you you can look at the calendar.
So it's 31st is on Friday.
Right. So
there you have your day off
it. Okay talk about New year.
I mean one day is more than enough, right?
So because we have to finish everything
before in six months.
So we will be
always kind of on the part schedule
maker.
Then business is the time is flying.
All right, guys.
So have you guys watched the videos
on Access Modified
constructors and discovered
did they make any sense this time?
Oh, looks confusing. So.
So. Okay, don't worry.
That's why I'm here.
I need more hands on
immediate.
Last year.
All right, so let's let's go to this slide
because we were not able to do that.
Make sense,
but don't have deep understanding.
Okay, Alexa,
maybe videos are simpler, I think.
Okay, you guys can
so you guys can pick up the topics.
So from the calendar
and then you can search the playlist
from and actually on
on those topics.
If, if for you
the Alexa videos are simpler.
All right, guys.
So we discussed three types of variables.
The first speaker very hard to understand
he has very good videos.
Okay.
I will try to share videos
from Alexi three.
So we discussed about
about the three types of variables
in the last class
and those types.
What you can tell about quizzes.
So I will do is I will be releasing
one more quiz today.
This is what I can tell you,
and I hope you guys already know
the answers right?
So we discussed about
three types of variables
in the last class, right?
So two of them
you guys have been using heavily in like
in last classes,
for example, the instance variables.
The variables again, you guys
tell me what, what are the instance
variables?
Event variable values change inside class.
Outside my third,
there's almost perfect definition.
You'll get the outside of my third
outside of the method and changeable.
So guys, all the variables
that we have discussed
till this point, they are changeable.
We want the static variables.
I guess I explained in the last class
that don't get confused
by the name static static in here
does not mean that that be there.
The value of that variable
cannot be changed.
Okay.
Static here in mean
a special area inside the memory
and whichever
value you support in that area,
that value is shared
across all the instances.
Okay. Of of a specific class.
So that's like static means in here.
But in certain space of too much memory,
it's not about making too much memory.
They stay longer in the memory.
Maybe you should say this,
that they stayed longer in the memory.
What can you tell about because this
what do you want to hear here
about the quizzes?
No time.
Yeah.
Can you write in your native language?
Alex and I will try to translate it
on Google
it. Writing a native language.
What do you mean?
What do you want to hear from me about?
With is very fast.
You want more time for the quiz?
Like, for example,
I have given you seven days.
You want ten days?
15 days, or the time when you as you solve
that with which time is less
the duration
or the deadline,
maybe three minute
are not 40 minutes enough.
I mean, even if you are
if you Google every concept
on the Internet and you
you can just copy and paste the answer,
I think then even then the 40 minutes,
nothing more than, you
know, 40 minutes are not enough.
How many of you think
that 40 minutes are not enough?
I not Google.
So this is the first time
I'm hearing from a student
about about the time that the 40 minutes
they are not enough.
How many questions were there?
1520.
I broke my brain. 25.
So usually this is what happens, guys.
So we are training you for real life
scenarios on your job interviews.
For one question at Max,
you guys will be getting one minute
on, maybe one minute, 10 seconds. Okay.
So that's why we have
40 minutes for 25 questions
so that you guys get used to
to use your brain faster.
All right, guys.
So instance, instance variables
are those variables
which are so right now,
you guys only know about methods.
So let's keep the discussion
only two methods.
So if a variable is declared
outside of a method,
and if it is inside a class
and there is no static keyword
with that variable,
which type of variable is disguised.
So there are three conditions
outside of method,
inside of class
and there should not be a static keyword
with that variable.
If we meet these three conditions, then
we can say we have an instance variable.
Right?
And when should
I use the instance variables?
When should I use
the instance variables?
In one minute.
I have to find a way
to find the answer or solve the problem.
Is there any job without interviews?
No. At least one interview.
Usually there are three, but
in some scenarios there is one interview
when we know that every time value is nil.
No, this is not correct.
Variable to be used across. Yes.
And then you can you complete that across.
But for common features are.
Yes. That is also correct.
I show when the value will be different.
Are different for what
to call method on null.
Then I have those with one across methods.
Across methods, yes.
So when I have to share
something across methods
and when I know that for each instance
the value of the
variable will be different.
These are the two conditions
when I should be going for the instance
variables.
Are these two conditions clear? Right.
Response variables are defined
within methods.
All this is not correct. Massive.
Those are local variables.
So let me repeat the conditions.
When I have to share a value.
So let me also show you
so that you guys can really see that.
So when I have to share
a value across different methods, okay,
so I want to access this name inside
this sleep
method as well as inside this name method.
Okay, So this is one condition. Okay,
So this is one condition where I should be
declaring the instance variables.
The other condition is that
I know that this name,
this name can be different
for each type of object
that I will be creating.
Right.
So if I open the dog for class, I can see
one dog is having a name Casper,
the other one is having Casper Sky.
Right?
So the value from object
to object is changing.
So if I have these two conditions,
then I should be going for the instance
variables.
Is it clear now or is there still anyone
who still don't understand this
that tag lags.
We will discuss about the static as well.
Okay. All right.
Now, the second type of variables
that we discussed
were local variables.
You can you guys define what are the local
variables
inside class?
Yes, they are inside class, but
they are also inside and method.
Okay.
The more proper definition will be inside
the method or we we are.
Can I also have these variables
other than methods?
Parameters? Yes. Parameters.
They are also local variables.
What about the loops?
What about the effects conditions?
What about switchgear statements?
If I declare any variability inside a loop
or inside a switch statement or inside
if health conditions are those variables
also local variables.
So they are all called block of course.
BLOCK of world.
So yes, the variables
they are all local variables.
Okay,
So can you guys tell me
if this dog too is a local variable
or instance variable or a static variable?
Don't rush, don't rush.
Take 2 minutes, take 2 minutes.
Think about it
and then tell me which type of variable
is this variable?
It's a local variable, right? Why?
It is a local variable
Because this variable
I am declaring inside this main method.
Right? This is also a method, right?
So if it's also a local variable,
okay, it's also a local variable.
What about this name? Variable?
What about this name?
Is it a local variable or instance
variable?
Yes, because it's inside the mean method.
Local instance instance instance. The Yes.
It does not matter
where I am accessing that variable.
What matters is that where I am
defining this variable,
because I have defined this variable
inside
a class and outside of the matter.
So it's an instance variable.
It's an instance variable.
All right.
Well,
when should I go for the local variables?
We use it across the methods. Yes.
If you are talking about the instances,
when should I go for local variables?
Can class
objects be called variable assignment?
They are variable.
They are variable. Okay.
So the more specific type is
that they are objects, they are variable.
So this is the type of these variables
and these are the variables.
Yes. When should I be using
the local variables? Yes.
And I should ask
now, I hope I'm
pronouncing your name correct.
What that law
would not be using other objects
when that variable
would not be used in other objects?
No, that is not correct.
So I clearly told
there is a condition when
when I should be going for local
variables.
No. Two is not a object.
Yes, it is or not. It is an object.
But that variable would not be used
in another method.
No, there is.
There was something else
that I told you about the local variables.
When it is specific to each object
or matters.
Now you may also declare local variables
within blocks of code.
Okay.
Which variable should be
your favorite variable?
Let me rephrase this question.
Which variable should be
your favorite variable that you will be?
You will always be declaring
static.
Local.
Local, local variable.
So the condition is is nothing.
But you should always,
always go for a local variable.
Why? We should always go
for local variables.
Otherwise
it is out of use
when you don't use less memory.
They got destroyed
once the code is executed.
Perfect on survived
so they all go by the memory
the least amount of time
as compared to instance
of static variables.
Okay.
So as soon as the execution is done,
for that matter,
the way the memory is released
and it can be used
by other variables or other programs
on your computer, okay, So that way,
your programs,
they will not be taking too much memory.
All right.
And then the last type of variable
was static
variable.
Can you guys
tell me about this tactic variables
all for
one copy created in class is shared
for one.
Why You guys are thinking and still
thinking about that
its value cannot be changed.
And then.
Did you join the class?
Let's someone.
It cannot be local. Yes, that is true.
Static variables of same variables
for every object.
That is true outside of my third
take is also true.
The special area
inside the computer memory
that holds values that are shared across
all variables, not all variables.
All objects
declared within class
does not need an object
to access the variable it has static
world can share across all matters
in a class common for all independent
can be accessed inside.
So it's very simple.
All the instance variables with a static
keyword are called static variables
that has been allocated statistically.
And by the way, all of your answers,
they are correct because they are
they are some some types
of characteristics of that static variable
that you guys are discussing.
So a static variable is just an instance
variable declared with a static DBA
and the properties of that
static variables are those that you guys
have just discussed right there.
The value is shared across all objects.
Only one memory location is declared
for the instance variables
for each object, but we create a separate
copy is created inside the memory.
Okay, but for a static variable,
only one copy is created
and that copy is shared
across all the objects
and they can be accessed by
the by just writing the name of the class
and then not in the name
of that variable static
we can use when we know value is same.
Most of the time
you can change if required
and declared an instance variable
outside the method.
Yes, that that is how to build
a single copy to be shared across
all instances of the object.
So let me tell you this instance
variable is
that is when we share the values
across methods.
Static variable is when you share
the value across objects.
Is it better
instant variable When you share the value
across methods static variable.
When you share the value across objects
and you recommend us to use
local variables Most of the time, yes.
Always. Always.
Go for local variables.
Can you make notes?
So we will be going through the slides.
Everything is written on this slide.
If something is missing,
I will make the notes for back.
Can you say one more time? Yes.
So instance variables.
We should be using the instance variables
when we have to share
the value across methods,
static variables.
When we have to share the value across
objects.
Okay.
Is it
is it clear now, Maria, how many of you
find it difficult to understand my accent?
Okay,
so I want that's why I don't write notes.
Because notes there,
they take a lot of time.
And instead I want to show you
as many examples
as as I can instead of writing the notes.
Because note I am exactly retyping
whatever is written on the slides.
Okay, So that's why I don't type
a lot of not a lot of notes.
Okay, So static variable is for example,
in this example, people
with accent understand each other.
So in here, so we are
where we met one condition.
The condition was that we
we know that the value of this variable
will be same, will be same
for all the objects.
Okay, so this is one condition
when I should be going
for the static variable again.
And if I declare this number of legs
as the instance variable by doing this,
how many copies of this variable
will be created
for this example?
So in here I am creating two
two objects
and now I have removed
that static keyword from here.
So how many copies of this number of flags
variables will be created?
They will be two. Right?
So am I wasting some memory?
Yes, because I can.
But if I don't have to,
if I don't have this requirement that
each object
will be having a different value
for this variable,
I am wasting a lot of memory right?
Because in real life
you guys will be creating thousands
of objects of a class in different things
scenarios.
So I should
be going for the static variable.
Now let's go through this lives
and then we will solve the homework
and if something is still not clear,
then we will do additional examples
as well.
Repeated again,
because this is where you guys
will be spending most of your time,
then you will be preparing you
when when you guys will be preparing
for the interviews.
Testers will do that to do what I
a variable
that is declared inside the method is
called a local variable,
creating objects and variables. Yes.
I mean if if something like if the ABC off
of writing a program
right in Java
because Java is object oriented programing
99% of the time creating an object, then
calling a method on that object,
that's what you guys
will be doing.
A variable that is declared inside this
method is called local variable, right?
Very simple.
A variable
that is declared inside the class,
but outside of the method is,
for instance, variables.
Okay,
just clarifying to wrap my head around.
No way back.
So the more you guys run from Java,
the more heavier it will see.
You guys will see it.
Okay.
So, so to try to understand,
it's not that difficult.
Okay.
And if you find
something difficult, I'm here and you guys
can always discuss with me a variable
that is declared inside the class,
but outside the method is called
Please explain more across method
verses, across objects in terms
of what is happening in the background.
Okay, so
this is what I mean
across the objects you see in here
I am accessing this number of flags
in here.
Okay, So
I have this two.
So there are five types of memory areas
that JVM uses to execute your programs
and all the
all the programs that you guys write.
Most of the time they will be
under the
the these type they will be involving
these type of materials, but
you guys don't need to worry about them
because those so there are special teams
who fine tune your programs
when they are executing on servers.
They find beyond these memory areas
how the variables are being declared,
how much memory
one program is taking and all that
they are required to performance scheme.
So even even the developers, they don't
know much about this memory area.
So they did it on very high level.
There is this static area
and this variable
in here.
It will actually be stored
inside this static area.
Okay.
But these two variables,
there is another memory area
that is called a heap.
All the objects that we create in Java,
they are created inside this heap
memory area.
Okay,
So first I will be having a bigger box.
Let me make it bigger.
So first there will be a bigger box
with the name of the to.
And inside this doll too,
there will be two additional boxes.
One will contain the value of name.
The other one
will contain the value of color.
Then when we will be declaring
and I've got a variable.
So let's say this is for sorry,
this is for dog,
then we will be creating another variable,
another box will be created
and then inside of that box,
two memory locations will
be created and then again
in this name
from here, the value of this spot
will be stored in here.
The value of color will be so linear.
And as we keep on creating new objects,
new and bigger boxes
will keep on creating inside the heap
and then
a separate copy for each
variable will keep on the player
will keep on the job.
I will keep on
creating the memory for you,
and then you can have your own values
inside baseball to all.
You can store the same values.
I'll get about this static
in here.
It's common for all the objects.
Even if you declare 1 million objects,
it will be same for all the objects.
Every object can access it.
Every object can change.
It is something that is common
for all the objects.
So if you have something common
in all the objects, you should be storing
that inside this static area
to save a memory.
I about book and carry that with me
everywhere.
A still I am forgetting things. Yes.
Sorry if you will be forgetting things
because it requires a lot of practice.
Just open your heart.
A lot of java within that class. Only
you'll get a.
You mean this tactic is within the class?
No, these are declared
outside of the class.
So we are.
We are where ever the values
for the instance variables
will be created in this static variables.
They are
they will be in a different memory area
then those
and for the methods.
So I actually don't want to go into
the details, but this is how it works.
There is an other memory area
that is called method area,
whenever we call a method.
So let's say for example,
I am calling this method creep in here.
So this method
I will quickly check how much memory
is required for this sleep method.
So this is called stack
method stack area, the value of the data.
So for example, in here the sleep method
is having this one local variable, right?
So a quickly
a memory, a portion from this stack
area will be declared to hold the values
for these variables.
And as soon as you are done
executing this part,
the memory will be cleared for this method
we will be needing more examples
regarding this variable.
So Shreve. Throughout this course,
we now will be creating
almost all of these variables
and the moment you guys so is not actually
so I think there are 6 to 8 classes
on Selenium right after the Selenium,
you guys will be creating your projects.
Okay.
And in your project
you guys will be using all types
of matters, all types of variables,
all types of classes.
So you guys will be able to
then combine all the knowledge
that you are learning in here.
So don't don't worry about that.
Again, we only use static variables
within the same package
or we can pilot in any package.
So static is not related to calling it
inside the method or inside the package
or outside of the package.
Okay. The thing which is
responsible for controlling this access
that we I can call
something is called access modifiers.
We will be discussing
those access modifiers in today's class.
Okay.
So no static has nothing to do with that
access modification.
Okay.
So this is again, again,
another example of
local variables.
So this is the main method.
I am declaring two variables.
Some very simple.
They are local variables.
So guys, they are
don't think that you guys will be,
for example, having specific
use cases for these variable types.
It is just to tell you back
how you guys can write better programs.
Okay.
So this is something that you guys will be
using in every single program.
There are no specific examples
for these variables.
You should be applying these concepts
in each program that you will be writing.
Okay, So each program is an example
for these variables.
Okay?
This is to to, to make it clear
how to write better programs.
Again, there are no specific scenarios
or specific examples for these programs.
If something very general OC applicable
to all the programs
that you write.
So it is possible to access
local variables
only in side the method
or constructor or block of code
if you try.
So for example,
this method is outside of this method, and
in here we are
declaring this integer variable.
E Right.
But the school of this method
is start from this bracket
to this bracket.
If we try to call this
in a different method,
for example Mul method,
we will not be able to do that.
Okay.
We will be getting an edit
because this is the limitation
of local variables, but it is not possible
to call those methods outside of that
block where they are declared
in this example.
This is important.
Okay.
These are some additional points
about the local variable.
So local variables are declared
in method constructor.
The block of or local
variables are created
when method constructor of block of bodies
entered.
Okay, so when.
So JVM is a program.
So when you guys installed
Java before starting Java classes
that Java also include a special program
that we called JVM.
It's too short for Java Virtual Machine
back to Java.
Virtual Machine is the program
that makes your Java code
and it converts that water to something
your windows can understand
or your Mac operating system
can understand or your Linux
operating system can understand.
Okay,
So all those programs, they are converted
by the fact that
are that JVM and compiler
and they are also executed here.
So the JVM is the
is the program that executes your program.
Okay. Who controls that you use currently?
It's kind of the manager of Java
on your computers.
So wherever you will be having
Java programs
being executed
or you guys will be needing that gave you.
And so that JVM is actually the program
which executes your matters.
Okay.
And then whatever those methods do, it
returns the returns
or brings the output of those methods.
So when the JVM starts
the execution,
only then the values
and the variables are declared.
And as soon as the last line inside
that method is executed,
all the variables
that were declared for dark matter,
they are destroyed
and the memory is free again,
access modifiers cannot be used
for local variables.
Okay, so those access modifiers
that we will be learning today
and the non access modifier, by the way,
the static is the non access modifier,
so they are not applicable
to local variables.
We can all static with local variables.
We cannot write
private public
or other things with local variables.
Okay.
Only the type of variable.
Then the variable name.
A variable declared inside of the body
of method is called local variable.
Again,
you can use this variable
only within that method
and other matters in the class
are not even aware
that the variable exists.
A local variable cannot be defined
with static keyword.
Okay.
And does it make sense
why it's static is not allowed
with local variables?
Static local variables.
They are not accessible outside of method,
right
outside of method.
If they are not accessible
outside of method, there is no point
of declaring those variables
in the static area.
Right. There is no need for that
because they are not accessible.
So Alexia, this is the example.
This is the example
we this my method
and one question.
So it's possible to create
both in the same dialog window.
Not sure if I am asking this right.
Silva What do you mean by Java window
Static method can
only can call only other static
methods and cannot call in on static
method from it.
So I said we will discuss
about that as well in today's class.
Remind me after we are done doing
the examples said remind me,
I will show you the static methods
as well,
like create a class first
and then public UPC, public UTC.
Well, what do you mean by public?
Is Silva
in the same window?
We cannot have two public classes
in the same file.
If you if you are calling the editor
window in which we write the board
and we are we declare the classes.
I sorry if someone else has understood
the question
can you guys can rephrase it.
Public static word man she asks.
I think, Oh, what does she want to ask?
It's hard.
So she is asking
if we can use the public keyword
with the other methods
like we are using the demand method.
No, it's okay.
No, no, it's not okay. Silva
Okay.
Maybe because we will be using this public
and all those things in this class.
If your questions, they don't get cleared
at the end of this class,
then you can ask the question again.
When you are trying to look at the code
you wrote a month ago or some kind of
in which I can tell you did
interpolate, we use same window.
Okay.
So first you have to tell me,
what do you mean by same window?
Maybe if you can put, for example, dog and
dog catcher and the same window for us.
Do you guys have problems?
What do you mean by same window?
Okay, so the example for you.
Okay, plus and objects in
in one
like in one class, we can
we can use two or three time public static
public static with word, with
method or with a variable
we can use with both public
and with with methods
and with with variables.
We can use these public and static,
and we can use it multiple times.
But that's what I'm saying.
We will learn it about today.
So let's discuss these things
after the after today's lecture.
Class and objects together means yes,
they can be.
Yes, they can be.
But that that is something very old.
We have done that thing multiple times.
This is what we mean.
And I said he is not he He is actually she
if I am not wrong
with static,
recreate the class window
and a test window.
Can we do both?
And we create a class window
and a tester window.
Can we do both in the same
without creating window?
Yes, we can.
We have done it multiple times.
Yes, we have done that.
But you said
we should not prefer to use them.
Yes, that is correct.
In my school we did
so what that Windows
politics called folder file on it
called a class
Java double file on the Java class.
We really need good explanation
regarding variables, please.
Okay.
So Serif asked me what is not clear
about the about the variables.
Okay, so in here
we have this method of my method
and in here I am declaring a variable.
Okay.
For any reason, maybe I have.
I am writing very complex logic.
That logic requires
to store the intermediate results
and then maybe use those results
in other parts of the code
when I am writing multiple loops.
Or maybe I am calculating
the results of eddies
roll by row and then column by column.
So for any reason
I have to store the results in a method
and if I have to store the results
I will be needing a variable.
Right?
So the result can be anything.
Totally depends on your logic.
So and if we are declaring a variable
for any reason,
that variable will be called
a local variable.
The difference between instance
and static variable main difference.
The main difference, Alex,
is that static variable.
We only
have one copy that is shared across
all the objects.
For the instance variable,
every object has its own copy.
This is the main difference.
All right, so this is my matter, doc.
For any reason, I have to
declare a variable.
So this variable that I am declaring,
it will be called a local variable.
Okay, a local variable.
And if I am declaring a variable
outside of a method.
So this variable is outside of this
method.
This method and it is inside this class.
So then this variable will be called
the instance variable.
Okay, instance variable.
Okay.
So the points about the instance
variable methods
and variables defined
within
a class are called matters of that class.
So the methods
they can also be instance and static.
Okay, we will discuss once I show you
the home,
but once I show you the homework,
that's all examples.
Okay,
so let me go through the slides, Alexi,
and then I will show you the example.
So methods and variables defined within
a class are called members of that class.
Okay?
Now a variable which is declared
inside the class,
but outside
the method is called instance variables.
Okay.
And one more thing.
It is not declared as static.
Okay.
Why the name instance
variables are defined within
a class are called
instance variables
because each instance of the class
that is each object of the class
that you will be creating
contains its own copy of these variables.
Okay.
So that's why
we also call them the instance variables
and the static variables.
They are also called class variables
because they only have one value
for all the objects.
Okay, one value per class.
Thus the data for one object is a separate
and a unique from the data
for another object.
So instance can be declared as static.
If we are studying none of those,
then it will be a static.
Then. Then it will be a static variable.
If you write static keyword
with instance variable,
then it will be a static variable.
Okay.
Is it clear LLC?
Is it not clear
that if we write static keyword.
Okay. No, no, it's fine.
It's fine
if we write static keyword with a variable
and let's see what type of variable
it will be.
Will it be static or will it be instance
static?
Then that's what we are
discussing in here.
Is it clear now? So
if we write this static,
if we are, can you repeat
or relative to the second paragraph.
Okay. Yes.
What I will do
so if we write this particular.
Okay.
So the condition is that
if you are declaring an instance variable,
this static evokes
from not me with that variable, okay,
we should not have this static keyword
with the instance variable.
Otherwise they will be converted
to a static variable.
And what type of variable is this?
This sprinkler
instance from the day.
Right.
And what type of the number of lines,
what type of variable is this
static.
Okay, so in my second paragraph,
you mean this one
one up, this one.
Okay.
A variable
which is declared inside the class,
but outside the method is called instance
variable.
It is not.
It is not declared as static.
Again, there is not, is there?
That confused me.
All right.
It's fine. Okay.
Does the data for one object is separated
and a unique
for the data for another object
it is called
instance variable because
it's value instance object
specific and it is not shared
among the instances.
Okay, Each instance has its own value.
Okay, we don't share instance
variables don't share their values
across the objects.
Again, instance variables are used
in a class but outside and not turned out
and subtotal Any block is flawed
for each instant variable
value is created.
I guess after access modifier
civil understand better.
We have three types of variables.
Instance
local static outside of my third local
inside of my third and any variable
with given static is called static.
Yes. That hard.
That is perfectly correct. This
instance variable
can be declared in class level
before or after you,
so you can declare that before the method
or after being that person.
Like, for example, I can declare these
before the matters
or off for the matter. Okay.
But I will still be able to access them.
Right.
But can I do the same with local variables
guys?
Can I use them first
and declare them after?
No. Right.
So this is one more property
of these variables.
Even you can use them first
and you can declare them after.
Okay.
But we cannot do the same
with the local variables.
So that's what that last line means.
Instant variables can be declared
in the class level before or after use.
You can use them first
and you can declare them off.
Are all these all these three sentences
are the clear.
Okay, so
this is an example of instance variable.
Again, we are declaring in here.
Then we are creating two objects
object one, object two,
and then we are printing their values
and then we are changing the value
for object to two
and again displaying the results.
So you see only, only the value for object
two is changed.
The value for object one it stays same
because each instance variable
has its own copy.
Maybe it's more clear at exemplars.
MM Yes, it will be.
So a public Publix name,
this instance variable.
And then I have this method,
I have a local variable. Okay.
And then I have
another variable
that is instance variable.
Okay, so same name variable.
So same name for an instance variable.
And in here I am only accessing it. Okay.
So sorry, not same name.
So actually let me show you an example
because
this is something that you guys
I seen you guys
in your API classes.
So today is class number 16, right?
Oops.
You have to create a package first
is next.
Let me cap.
And so if you guys have understood it,
maybe if more accurate
example was why.
I guess so.
I have this number
in here
then we know once you guys have
created these two classes,
I need an entity done.
All right,
So let's just create the object
name multiclass
if we're to sign new keyword again,
name of the class.
What will you get, guys,
if I execute this program
and by the way,
I will be getting 0bd
for the value of appear
default value is zero
because we going to declare a number here.
Now we have declared the number,
but we have not initialized it.
So guys, I want you to focus
on your terminologies as well.
Okay, So try to use proper terminology.
It is very important for you to introduce.
Okay.
So I don't want you to do this.
If your interviewer
is asking about elephants, I don't want to
that you guys are saying about
about fishes or dogs or pads.
I, I want you to understand
the terminology is proper and the onset
of the onset in the proper way
because you have not called this set
constant number.
Okay.
Who is sending messages again and again?
Let me flow it.
So right now I have not initialized
this variable, okay?
I have not set anywhere new
and I am trying to call it right
because it's an instance variable.
I can do that. Okay.
I can use that variable.
We will assign a value first.
Can I do the same with local variable?
No, I will be getting an error.
So a default value
will be printed in here.
Okay.
And if I
if I say number is equal to ten,
then what output I will get. Ben
Right.
Alexi What output I will get
and see, are you with us?
And do you understand
why we are getting ten?
Is there anyone who don't understand
You confused?
Confused.
All right.
That's why I asked you
so what do you think,
Alexi? What do you think?
What output
should I get instead of this ten
on line nine, we are calling a variable,
so you'll get that
this is not the proper term.
We don't call TV.
We don't call the variables.
We call methods
online.
Then we are accessing a variable.
Okay, this is the proper terminology.
We excessive variable we call a method.
We initial we initialize.
Okay.
Do don't feel bad
if I am if I am telling you
that you guys are not using
the proper terminology from now on
because earlier
you guys were in the initial stages.
Then you guys will be telling me and
that's why this interaction is important.
So if you guys are writing something
and I know that you are not
using the proper terminology, then
that's how you can get corrected, right?
That's how I can guide you.
But if you are sitting behind a screen
not interacting, I don't know
if you are understanding it
properly or not,
please keep correcting us
so that we can make it a habit.
Yes, I don't want to be saying fish
when asked to say elephant.
So let's see. What do you think?
What output
should I get instead of this ten
And then why you are confused.
What is confusing?
You tell me the line, Alexia.
Tell me the line number which is not clear
or which is confusing. You.
Is there anyone else who's confused?
No, no, it's okay. All right.
That's great.
All right.
And if I say
let me let me change it to 100
so that you guys can
can you can differentiate it.
If I say
Rick app dog start on start.
And then if I printed out
what I will get
and then and hundreds of you
everyone is
is clear on this
we will be getting handbook
here we go we have a word for ten
from Merriam
another word from Katrina
not hundreds.
Okay And then hundred so or so.
So we have a boat for ten and 100 as well.
I got ten.
So guys don't execute these calls.
That's where you
I that's where I want your brain to learn.
Right.
I want your brain to
to execute this code inside.
Right. And then tell me the output.
There is no learning
if you are just executing the code
that I am writing in here
and telling me the output.
So let me explain.
So yes, first we will be getting harder.
Okay.
And now let me explain why
we will be getting neck.
Right.
We we're going to be getting under.
So in here
we are creating an object, right?
This line is clear.
Super, super clear. No issues with that
on line number nine.
So what happens
is that when I create this object,
a box inside the memory, inside
the heap area
will be created.
Right? So let's say this is here.
This round center is a heap
I inside that heap
I have this box and this box is called
recap.
Okay, a box
to hold all the instance
variables, I get ten.
So, Katrina,
can you please post in this portion?
All right. And in here
and another box of type integer and number
will be declared.
Okay. Now this box is a specific.
So this recap object appeared.
This recap when I access this number
and I store ten
then will be stored inside in here again
inside.
In here.
Like when I call this method
if recapped or said constant.
So what will happen again,
I am accessing this same memory area,
this number.
Okay.
And this time I'm saving
hundreds inside this variable.
Now the the value of that variable
has been updated.
Okay, has been updated.
If now I tried to print it,
then I will be getting a hundred.
Right.
Because one way variable at a time
can only hold one value right.
And in here this number was updated
when I called this method.
That's why instead of 1000
was stored inside this memory location.
And I got
hundreds.
You can also verified by debugging. Right?
So I place this table point
and then I right click and I saved debug
as Java application.
Okay.
So guys, I don't see my variables window.
What should I do?
But you called two methods.
Yes, I called two matters.
So I go in here I solved
and the last effective
they are already in here.
Then I can drag and drop it in here. Okay.
So this video, this recap,
this recap object
has been created.
It's a recap.
And inside this recap guide,
you see one memory
location for the number
variable has been created right
when I say a recap
and then when I execute this line
you see it then has been stored
inside the number variable.
Okay.
And then I call this
set the constant number.
Right? I want to see nice.
I want to see what is happening
inside this method, which button
I should use the step
in to or the step over. So
Sebastian,
I have already cried for eight years. So.
So time for
my crying is gone and time to the
your time to cry is start now
or has already started
so I call the step into right
then it takes me inside inside the method
in here and again
if I say if I expand
if by expand this number in here,
you guys will see right now
expanding here.
But as soon as I exit you,
this number is equal to 100.
You see,
the number of variable has been updated.
Again, the number value has been updated.
And now
I come in here,
I call the the number again,
I call this step into
and I am printing this number right.
So the number it contains hundred because
previous method it updated that number.
So is
it clear, guys, why we got 110
Alexi The clear
Okay.
And if let's say if I call
and either my third recapped or oops,
that number why
we get only one two out
so we get only one to start
because there is only one result inside
this print number.
There is notice out insert constant
that is not a solid insert number.
That's we get only one
insert
number.
And if by force 50 in here
what output by will get based,
I will be getting a 50.
Okay.
Is there anyone who don't understand
why will be getting 50?
Everyone understand why we get 50.
You should decide first what number
you want to get.
Why not hundreds of dollars
saying Why not 100?
Can someone explain, Bill,
why we are not getting hundred
number plus none plus equal to.
Yes, Alexi, you can write any expression
inside those methods.
So under we passed this 15 here
and we call
the oops, we call this set number.
Right.
So this second number in here,
this 50 will be copied
inside this number.
Okay?
And from inside this method,
what I am saying, I am saying
assign the value of number
to number to number.
So this 50 will get stored
inside this number.
Right. And then we are printing it. Okay.
And then we follow this method.
That's why we get 50.
Is it clear now?
Okay,
so an assignment in one method
can variable again
variable values for many objects.
You mean can vary the value
for many objects?
No, no, no, Anabel,
It's only for bad object for,
let's say
for if I, if I create another object.
Recap, recap. Do
nothing that
I do with this object
will effect this object.
Okay?
So this object,
it has its own separate copy
zoom working
override times as you are long gone.
But we can change value
and it will replace the previous one.
Yes, we can replace.
But remember, guys, it's
only for that specific object
on which I am calling those methods.
Right?
Like, for example, if I say if I say
if I say recap dot set number
and I pass 50
and I say recap, do not print
but output,
I will get five this print number.
Guys, let me let me comment this out,
but I will get
I will be getting zero
because I am setting
the value on the cap variable,
but I am getting value from recap to that.
Recap to if it has its own memory,
it has nothing to do with recap.
That's why we have static variables.
If you want this communication
between two objects,
then you need that static variable.
That's why I was saying
that when you have to communicate,
when you have to pass some information
between objects, we use static variables.
When we have pass pass information
between methods,
we use instance variables.
Maybe we need to break
well, more minutes.
Let's see and then we can have break
and we will be getting zero.
Is it clear?
Right.
You need to ask global.
All right, guys, if you guys
have understood it properly, tell me.
Tell me, how can I pass this 50
to this recap to object
so that when I call this number,
I get this 50 from this object
to this object.
What should I do?
So I remove this line.
Okay, So I
okay, so the value
that I set inside this number,
I want to get that number
when I call this
print the number on object recap.
So I want to start something on recap
and I want to
I should be able to get that thing
from that recap
to when I call the recap to print object.
So tell me, what should I change?
So let me execute this
instead of zero.
I should see 50.
What should I change?
No, no, no.
I don't want to start it on object too.
I don't want to set it on object to.
I want to set something on object
one using object one
and I want to get that thing
using object to
number plus 40 on line
nine static making number start date.
Jane did
it. It's very simple.
Why are you guys are confused about recap
don't certain number 50
and then recap don't start number
and recap to recap
one don't start a number
and I don't know what else.
It's very simple.
I have to share something
between different objects.
I make a static
and make it static
because we want problems.
Do you guys understand
now how starting work?
We will do more examples
about the static and static work.
But I want to explain actually one concept
because before I
before we can dig down,
but I still don't know how we
got to zero in last example.
Maryam You
mean if I remove the static,
why we get to zero?
You don't understand in this part.
How did you guys,
how have you guys done your homework?
If you don't understand the static part?
Because the last example requires
this this concept of static
force, then
can we also do recap, do not start number
instead of making sense?
Yes, give me we can do that.
No, it's not Google.
Are you guys getting this homework
from your seniors or somewhere else?
Tell me, tell me honestly,
most probably we did it wrong.
I brought in what order.
The class and classes are triggered.
Classes are triggered.
Alexa.
You mean my grandmother had me?
Can we get feedback on our solutions?
Yes. Automate. I have shared
the solutions. Build rapport.
Number 50 on on canvas
so you guys can compare your solutions
with with my solution.
Maybe.
But sometimes it passes.
But maybe our solution is different.
I have shared it.
Okay, so Alexa you mean the property?
So the line that we
write first executes first,
this will be executed first.
And then this one. Then this one.
Then this one.
And this one. That's one bottom.
Did you get to your answer? Why?
We are getting zero.
Okay.
So we have 6 minutes
and let's finish this slide.
The static variable variable,
which is declared as
static is called static variable.
Static variables are declared
with static keyword in a class,
but outside a metadata constructor
or a block of four,
it cannot be local static.
They cannot be local.
You can create a single copy
of static variable
and share
among all the instances of that class.
Memory allocation
for static variable happens
only once when class is loaded inside.
The memory.
These are some more wires. Weird.
How do we add value?
To recap to using recap one
although we make it
static, we are not adding value.
We are assigning value
static odd in the know it can be anything.
It can be a string.
It can be a double, it can be anything.
It can be anything.
No, I mean a not local but international.
In this case.
And so by international you mean
you mean instance
of somebody
speaking and challenging
is that is gradually it is gold.
So you guys will not even realize
international here I am.
Okay static are here
it's all over so you can think of local
as maybe at city level
instance as country level
and then static as international level
if that helps.
That they got here all over us.
You can use a static inside them
at third outside of in that third
class, static
variables are also known
as class variable.
This is another
terminology that is used
because they are associated with the class
and common
for all the instances of that class.
Static variables and stored values
for variables in a common memory location.
Because of this common memory location,
if one object changes
the value of a static variable,
all objects of the same class
are affected.
Use this static variable for the property
that is common to all the objects.
For example, in the class student
all student shares
the same college name
if they belong to the same quality.
Use the static methods for changing
a static variable in this part.
We will discuss after the break.
So these are the static
variable of matters.
These are the static memory locations.
So we have two objects, one in here,
one in here.
This is object here.
This is object B,
We have a static variable
as to static variable.
So the memory for the static variables
is same.
It's being shear
static variable.
So the values for variables
end share a common memory location
for all the objects.
This is just another example.
This is static interior I.D.
so it will be same for student zero.
So one
student a static is not x non
axis modified, so you will learn
about the access modifiers today.
What are they?
Static
B word can be used to be the variables
matter so we can also have static methods.
We will discuss about blocks
and nested classes
particular
to being also d class than an instance.
Again, same thing.
Static methods can access
all static variables.
We will discuss this about the deliberate
and this last block.
Okay.
And also remind me.
So after the break,
we will go through the homework
and then we will discuss this.
So static methods could have been used to.
Yes. Now, Will, we're going to discuss
about the static methods in detail
after the break.
Are there any questions
Then please go back to the equal
40 ish or more.
Really, Sebastian?
No means.
Today.
How about Public-Private Default? Yes.
That is also the topic of today's class.
I don't know that you have static in
in class, but you change in in class test.
It turns out you can change every static.
Yes, we can change this static.
Yes, we can change this static inside
the methods, inside the test class.
Everywhere. Everywhere.
But Breaking Bad.
How do you guys know what to do
and hence do so well?
So. So I have I have noticed this
all the all the neighboring countries
like Tajikistan, Afghanistan,
Nepal, Bangladesh.
Is it because of movies?
No, no, no.
Then how how do you learn it
on the first place like you have?
If you are watching a movie, you have to
understand that language right?
Buddy? Is
the handbrake about.
And again, it's perfect.
I mean, you don't
even if you guys are learning it
from the subtitles
from childhood,
I understand the most commonly used words
I know do better than my native language
or low down the whole.
No, no, I'm not.
You are right.
It's a very famous movie.
I know Punjabi as well from my sir.
Oh, that's their big.
And we start because we are
just like people from most Soviet
countries.
I think they all know Russian
or at least understand it's all.
It's because of that water.
And every Persian grape is deep white
European features.
Indian or the.
We won't know that Sergei
I love Alex
and I'm going to have the mommy.
Sebastian when you and in those memes
why there is this blurring kind
kind of effect
make it perfect man
some app
on my iPhone so I will share you
I will share you an app in the break.
I'm getting that there is a very good app
for editing
one video as but
all right, guys, please be back.
Okay.
So this time let's have a shorter break.
The next break we will be having a longer
one and I will give you the
tasks as well.
Only for 15 minutes.
Let's do time for Alexa
to call the grandma who we speaks Persian.
Farsi, the Tajik.
They can learn all very easy.
I want to learn Persian.
I don't know why.
Because there is a great history
involved around that Persia.
All that other guys reminded me
about the recording.
And please be back in 15
minutes.
Familiar with Banjo. If an English thief
was not recording
Despacito,
what does it mean?
Modern?
What does it mean?
Slowly I
So the name of
the class is Employ.
And then we have to create the variables.
What one should be the employed.
So guys, tell me about the employed.
Should it be started instead or local?
It should be instance right.
And what about the salary?
Yes, it should be double
and it should also be instead.
So in here we are specifically talking
about the syntax employed.
So what should be the type of that
CEO variable?
It should be
static.
Okay.
And then we have to assign these values
to these variables
and then
create three variables.
Create two objects of this class 70
value of the ID salary
for each of the objects.
Print out the and feel for
all the objects
out there.
So let's build
the employee aster
And you guys done and done
typing this call.
So create three variables, right?
It's very simple.
We say
employ, employ one
or let's say
a new viewer
and then name must be class.
Then we set the values.
So we say empty already the.
First, let's say one, two, three,
and then not
then read the first
hundred
and then we create another object.
So let me quickly copy
this forward.
And the second
code, five, six,
and then one.
And then now
I have
lost it.
Anyone who was unable to solve question
And why now?
You and I were unable to solve this,
make it employed to
and now
I have to print out the value,
this static variable.
How should I print out the value? Guys
who will tell me the best practice?
Tell me the best practice.
What is the best practice
to call a static variable
as I did?
What is the best practice?
Should I call it?
Will name of the class
or with the name of the object?
The best practice is to call this tactic.
We do both on the name of the class,
not on the
and if you do this intelligently,
you will not follow the suggestion
to call it with the name of the object.
But any place that as so
we get this math
and we don't need to call it
we should not be calling it
with the name of the object
because the value is always same for
all the objects of a class vessel.
To always use the name of the class.
Okay.
Are there any questions from this task?
Is it only for static? Yes.
It will only work for static
because objects
they have their own own locations.
They can have their own values. Right?
So if we are always calling it
with the name of the class,
then how do Java knows
which value we are trying to refer
in? Let me put the question in here
on like
ask was to create a new class.
Are you guys done typing this?
All of this in both the classes
system do not print alone.
See, it also works.
No, it should not work
without
the name of the class.
It should not work.
I think you are creating the
DC out inside this class
then that's why it is working.
If the name of the class is mandatory,
if you are outside of that.
Yes Alex,
you object.
Add a
Is it okay if we call with the object?
Yes, you can call with the object,
but it is not recommended approach.
It's not the best practice
everywhere where you will be seeing
the professional code,
you will see that they will be calling it
with the name of the class. So
yes, because you are writing the main
method inside the same class
and that's why you are able to call it
without the object
name.
Welcome.
Yeah, because I, I was on mute
on Mondays.
Can I close these files
and create a class called a student
did three variables.
Student name, student I.D.
and number of students.
So what should be the default student
name? Guys
instance.
Right.
And because every student
can have its own name
and then student I.D.
again, same.
The number of students, on
the other hand, like, for example, if we
if we will be using this student class
to represent
the represent
the number of students in that class.
So we should be creating adds static.
Okay. Otherwise we can have it as instance
the static
number of
swallows.
Okay.
And then
create three objects
of this order class.
Start a p value class student name and.
Increment
the number of students for each object.
So that way we keep track
of how many students have been registered.
Okay.
And then print out
the total number of students.
So the
there is no life
question.
There is no life
and test.
No, it's like Mr. Beans
or Charlie Chaplin.
He made it as a gift
or student test.
And three, the main
method.
Okay, so again,
we create the object down
all done before.
We've done all new student
and then we see
student or
name.
Okay.
I think the variable names will be better
if we only call them name and i.t
because they are already
inside the student class.
All right.
And I see
who none of
school in the classroom.
Okay, But I created one student,
so I increase the counter by one.
Then let me quickly copy
and paste this code
three times
as not as.
Can you tell me the line number
the inner
order base.
So what are we going for?
The number of students
after this?
It will be three right?
Because I have three student solve.
So this way you guys can keep
track of the number of objects
that you have created of your class.
So what and why this is important.
So have you guys noticed
that on Black Friday is
the e-commerce websites.
If there is too
much load, they get crashed
or some other websites
and during their peak times
they don't work properly.
So it's because of the resources, it's
because of the hardware
that is handling the number of customers
and we have two separate computers,
one that displays the information.
We call that the application server
and the other server
that is called the database server
where we store that information
and we create a connection
between these two servers,
application server
and the database server.
Now this creation of connection between
application server and database server,
you create object of that connection class
and that is a connection class.
And then you intertwine one customer,
if you have an entertainer,
another customer in parallel, you create
another object and another connection
and then you build
X. Now when the number of
customers are too much and
you try to create more connections,
but there are not enough resources,
then these applications and they crash,
they get this
error or exception behind the scenes.
So sometimes you guys want to add
because you guys will be dealing
with that database server.
So, so you guys,
we might want to keep track of how many
objects you have created
of a specific class to avoid that.
Yes. Or limit the traffic on the server.
So this is how you directly traffic.
But this is one of the ways to do that.
The traffic.
How many requests are being entertained
in parallel?
Are there any questions guides
from these classes,
these tasks
or alerts?
Are you guys done typing this code?
Let's discuss about this tactic.
Methods.
So I'm closing this.
Actually, let me.
We already have a student class.
We already have an employee class.
Oh, here we go next to this.
Let's call this a dog class.
Our favorite class. Still name
and in here
works in my name
and works
a lot of flags is equal to
or if only
name.
And that deep
broad
display next
and looks created to
okay that we know
once you guys have this code
in order for fact.
So guys
this is how we can create a static map
here okay
this is how we can create a static method.
And the
and the properties, they are
same as off as
as we have the properties
for this static variables.
So I can call this static method
by just writing the name of the class.
Okay. And
what output I will let.
But when it was not static,
it was giving out.
Yes, I will explain that as I would expand
type.
Okay. So we get for now, let's do this,
let's do this.
So we create an object.
We say dog one, not name
equal to Casper.
Then we create another object
of blue
bubbly.
Okay, I put in a corner
object.
Now give me a name for a dog.
One. Okay.
And then I call
dog one or oops, buddy.
How was your review class?
It was great and was super total
screwed.
All right, guys, so I have three objects.
I have access the field
and I have set some values.
Then I am calling an instance man Pair
these methods to the static.
They are called instance meters
and I am displaying the information.
Okay,
everything should be clear
about this, right?
So far the slopes for this dog one.
I will be getting this name for this dog
though.
I will be getting this
for the dog three.
I will be getting the last name. Right.
And the number two floors.
Now think about this, guys,
and tell me
and I call
can I print out
And I print out.
So this is a static method. Okay.
Static method or static keyword means
that thing belong to the class, right?
We can call that thing
even without creating an object.
And even if we create object instance
fears, they will be having big
and we are having different values
for each object.
So if I display this,
if I try to display this instance
field inside this static method,
I get an error.
Now think about this
and tell me why I'm getting this as well.
What is the reason
it is local? No
name is an instance variable.
Yes, but.
But why?
I cannot call an instance
variable inside this
static method.
The name can be edited.
They are a source.
We cannot use the instance
variable outside of method
because it is instance
an outside thing method
and we change any time
you need to change it.
The public
in Java looks confused.
Here we go. Perfect answer. I
Java gets confused.
So let me do this guys,
let me do this.
So this is the perfect answer.
Gallagher's confused
what I am doing in here
and here I am setting the value of name.
So this caspir in here
I am sending it to bubbly.
In here I am starting to open right?
And then using the class name
I am printing display legs. Now
Java is confused back where that is.
Should print this value or it should print
this value or should print this value
because a static static
they belong to the class, right?
Static variables or static matters.
They have common things.
The things which are shared. Right.
But if we try to print
something that can have different value
for each object
now Java is confused
that which name is should print.
Can you guys tell me
which name this method should print?
How, how, how.
How can this method decide
which value should print?
It's confused, right?
Because I can have
I can have 1 million objects
and each object can can have its own name.
Right?
This method is confused, so
it is not giving an ETA
on the static value.
While why does not give
error on the static value lies
because it knows
that it will always be having one value.
Right.
These static variables,
they always always
they will be having one value at a time.
Right?
So it knows that
it always have to print out
this value.
Right?
Because a static variable is
only only has one copy per class.
Well static method knows that
which value it has to print.
But for the instance fields,
each object can have its own value.
Right.
So starting my is confused
static method is saying
I don't know about the object information.
Right?
You are calling me
using the name of this class.
This class can have thousand objects.
Each object can have its own value.
I don't know which value I should print.
How come it's not getting
confused when we use the name
in the display method?
So display
method is an instance method, an email.
We cannot call this plane name
method using the name of the class,
we must create an object first
and then only.
We can call this display method.
If we try.
If we try to call an instance method
by only specifying
your class name,
we will be getting an error.
So that's how it is. Not confused.
That's how it knows that
if this method is being called on dog
to object,
it knows that it has to print this value.
If the display name is called an object,
learn this dog.
Once it knows that
it has to print this value,
but for the display lacks
right display legs.
Sorry, this display legs.
If I put any instance field in here
now, we don't have
any information about the object.
Right.
I am simply calling the method
on the class name.
There is no information about the object.
If there is no information about the
how do I know which value to display?
Right.
So there slide on inside
this static matters.
We can only only call
static value static variables.
What will happen if you add spec
static in front of instance,
think string name in here
and then we will not be getting any
any issue.
Okay.
Then we will not be getting any error.
And the last value
that we are storing in here,
it will be printed on the console.
Yes, it will be same name for every dog
all our days.
Now think about this and tell me
can I call
static values inside instance
so I can call, right?
I can call No issues.
Well, why? There is noise. You guys.
Why there is no issue
when I am calling a static variable,
when I'm using a static variable
inside an instance method, why
there is no issue.
Java is not confused, right?
Because there is only one value
that this number of legs
can have at a time.
Right.
And don't know
that this value should print.
So d this is how the static
methods and static variables
work with each.
Okay.
And so we can only only call static.
We can only use we can only
access the static variables inside.
So we can access this static variable
inside static methods
and a non static matter.
But we cannot do we cannot access instance
mesh feels inside
static matters because each instance
can have its own value like its own.
Well, it is not something universal,
nor something
that is shared across all the objects.
So Java is confused and Java gets confused
which value it should print.
That's why it is not allowed
all life.
It's just like with blood types.
All can go to every block,
but those who have
or can only take or
or all negative or positive
or positive.
Okay.
Is it the guys why we cannot
call, in instance
clears
what's already why
we cannot access instance fields
inside a static method.
And same is the case with the
with the methods.
You guys so
I can let's say
if I have one more
variable,
we've got a
I and
I said they are terrible.
And only once she has learned
Java again, maybe that will help you
if she is
good in Java.
All right. So that's what I can do.
I can call a method inside another method.
Okay.
So for example, I can see display.
I can see inside a display color or
display
name.
But think about this, guys.
Can I call this method inside the static
method as well?
No. Right.
The reason is again same.
I can be using it inside an instance.
Fear Inside a method. Right.
And inside an instance method.
I again, I can use an instance field.
Now if instance fields are directly
not allowed
to be used inside static method,
the methods should also be not allowed.
Right?
Because the instance method
can be having these instance fields.
Right.
So is is same the same same thing,
but in a different way.
Right.
If I am allowed to use this
display name, it can again be problematic
because the display name
contains this instance.
Field Right.
So the instance methods, they are also not
allowed to be called inside
static methods.
Okay. And I do the reverse.
Nice.
Can I call a static method
inside the instance
method? Yes.
So against the same is the case with the
as the case with variable.
I can call this display lens
in here.
Right.
No issues because I always know that
it will only be allowing
to have static variables.
Right. And static variables.
Will they always be having same value
for all the objects?
Okay, so no issue in here.
Okay.
So these were the point.
These were the last two parts
that were written here.
Static
methods can access all static variables
and other static methods.
Static methods cannot access instance
non-strategic variables
and a method static
may need some object preference
from do that.
Okay, so instance fields or instance
methods, they always always need an object
preference.
Okay.
But these that big fields and static
methods
big can be called by the name of the class
and they will always be having same value
for all the instances.
What is object in our case?
So in our case,
this dog one is an object.
Start with an object
this dog treats an object.
Are there
other questions, guys?
And let me show you what kind of
energy
we'll be getting
if you're trying to build that
cannot make a static reference
to non static field
or light.
So now let's discuss about.
Now tell me guys,
are there any questions related to
types of variable? Was
what are these
when you should use them?
But you can insert dog
one dog name their diameter.
You mean inside this static? Yes.
If you have an object,
you can do that. Yes.
So more another you.
Your number of legs
variable is not static.
That's why you are getting better.
All right, guys.
So you guys have watched
the videos on access modifiers.
Can you guys tell me,
what are these access modifiers?
What are the access modifiers in Java?
No clue. Sorry.
It's fine.
Default. Public. Private. Protected. Yes.
These are the types of access modifiers,
but what are access modifiers
and control Access to that
perfect answer
Not only data but the methods
as well.
It is specific.
You can access different class or package
control or die.
They are across the package.
They put restriction to them
across the class or matter.
So first let me show you
what are access modifiers
and then we will discuss the APD.
So access modifiers.
So you guys have already noticed that
you can use the code
that is written
by other developers, right?
So for example, you guys have used
so many methods
from this string class, right?
So many useful methods.
You guys have used the scanner class
to read the data from the keyboard, right?
You guys can use the arrays
class to print.
The add is on the console
without the loop.
Now, these methods
that you guys are using,
this field that you are using,
if you want to have more control
over those fields and methods,
you can restrict the
who will be using your code.
So let's say, for example,
you are writing a method
or you are declaring a field
inside your class
and you don't want others to use it.
Okay, then what you can do?
You can use access modifiers
to restrict others.
Okay.
Or maybe you want them to be accessible
only inside
that package
where your class resides.
Okay.
Then you have another access modifier,
special access
modifier keyword
that will allow you to do that.
And then you have the third type
in which everyone can access your fields
and your methods.
So let's discuss about them.
So the fourth type
is the private.
So if write this private keyword
with any variable or any
method, then this sphere
will only be accessible
to the methods
of this class.
So I can write the method,
I can print it out, okay,
I can print it out.
And then the second type
is not having any type.
So if we don't want to specify any keyword
with any variable or any method
of that
variable, our method is only available
to the classes
that are inside this package.
And then
we have the card type,
which is public.
Public means this is salary variable.
It can be accessed inside this class
package
15 inside this package, 14.
Basically, it means accessible everywhere
inside this project,
open for all.
And they can also be used
inside.
All right.
Let me let me clear the display.
So if we don't specify any keyword
so first
let me show then then I will explain.
Then I will discuss the table.
So meanwhile, you guys can type with me.
Maybe.
Okay,
so what I can do,
I can have a mean method in here.
So this private means guys,
I can access
this name field only.
Only inside this class.
Okay?
Only and only inside this class,
I can create an object
and I can assign the values.
But if I try to do this
in a separate in a different class,
I will not be able to do that
for the name period.
So this is private.
So this private keyword, what it is doing,
it is making sure that this field name
is only and only accessible
inside this class.
Once you move
outside of this class to any other class,
this name field will not be able you guys
will not be able to access this, okay?
This is what this private means because
we have written this private keyword.
Now, we cannot access this name
because this is a different class
and this is in different.
Okay.
But I can still access the edge
because it has the default access modifier
by default access modifier we mean that
if we don't specify any modifier
and then the public one.
So the default one and the public one,
they are accessible
this same class, they are accessible
outside of that class. So
now not
able to change the private
variable are not able to even access. Yes.
So only
and only you can change and access it
if you are inside of these parentheses
starting from here to here,
not outside.
Now, right now, guys,
I am inside this package.
Class 16.
Okay, let me go to the class
and let me go to the package.
Class 15
and let me try to create this
class.
Line 22 would need to write
semicolon.
Thank you.
So, new class
access modifier test
mean matter. Yes.
Actually you guys will be needing this so
let me copy this code
and let me paste it in here.
Okay.
So in here, guys,
I was in this same package.
Okay, so the class
in which I have defined the variables
this access modifier demo one
this class and then and the class in which
I am trying to access
those fields were in the same package.
So I was able to access this edge.
But what, what happens when I move
to a different package in here?
I am an inside a different package now.
The edge is also not accessible.
The edge is also not accessible, right?
It is not accessible now.
Default is also not accessible. Now.
We only have the salary variable
which is accessible in here. So
how the access is controlled, if we have a
if we are using the private keyword, yes,
if we are using the private keyword,
we are going to access that filter method.
Guys only.
Where can I access that field
inside that class only.
Okay.
If the access is default,
which means I am not specifying
any keyword,
where I can access that field,
I can access that in see inside
that class,
I can access that any other class
inside same package.
Okay, inside same package.
But the package should not be different.
And if we have a public field,
it is accessible
inside that class, inside the same package
and outside of that package.
Okay, outside of that package.
And same
is applicable for matters,
but the same is applicable for method.
It's pretty much same
as we have things in real life.
Again, private means only belongs
to that specific person.
Public means accessible to everyone.
Okay.
And then we have this default one,
which is kind of intermediate
outside of project pool. Okay?
So if you have to access it
outside of Project Muhammad, No,
the public is not accessible,
then you have to make your file
from your source code
and you have to import those data files
and then you can access it.
But then there's
something radical outside.
Also the scope of this class
already.
So that was today's class.
I hope you guys have enjoyed this
and I will see you tomorrow.
What is the best practice like?
Are not big classes easy?
I mean easier than the first part?
Literally.
This is this is literally
this is the today's class.
Believe me, it
is. Okay.
Now we will discuss
about the constructors.
Okay.
So it is really this
this is this is all about today's
class and that.
So let let's go through the theory
and then we again
we will do another example.
Let everyone have a test
20 of time
to catch up on wrappers and liquids.
Today
after ten lines of coding.
All right.
So I was getting let's
get back to the class.
Okay.
So access modifiers.
Yes, we will discuss
the constructors as well.
Back to the reality.
So and there are two types
of modifiers in Java.
One of them,
they are called access modifiers.
They they control the access.
So we have public
protected by the this protected well.
We will discuss it
when we start the inheritance.
We will be starting the inheritance
in nest in next week,
maybe on Tuesday or Wednesday.
So then it will make sense.
Then we have the default one
and then we have the private one
and then there are
non-actors modifiers
out of which you guys
already know about this static one.
So okay, this final abstract and
synchronize they are for future classes.
We will discuss about these in the future
classes.
Access modifiers in Java help
to restrict
the scope of a class
so we can write these access modifiers
like private,
public protected and default with classes.
We can write them with methods.
We can write them with the fields.
Okay.
Restrict the scope of a class constructor
to that we will learn about it.
Variable
method or any other that I remember.
Okay, so there are more types of things
that you guys can have
inside the class.
These are used to control access
to that members or matters.
Now these that are members in here.
I am referring to the fields
actually. Okay.
So they are also part that are members
in Java programing.
These are classified into four types.
So private native class and by native.
I mean in which these fields or methods
or constructors are created,
then we have the default one
and if we have the default one,
that thing is accessible everywhere.
Inside that package
which we are writing that class
is protected when we don't discuss it now
and then we have the public one
which is universally accessible
everywhere.
Access
modifiers are always used to control
the reuse of features
within a package and access
between a class.
Okay, so say
you guys have written a piece of code
right?
And you,
you don't want others to copy it, right?
So what you can do,
you can make it private.
Now they will not be able to access
your fears, your methods.
Okay.
Spend, spend half the class
going over something very complicated
that nobody gets, or you guys
don't actually need to know
that I was just
put over in the equation.
I am about to give you.
All right.
Access modifiers,
but alive features
accessing and controlling
mechanism
among the classes and interfaces.
This interfaces, they are
they are something similar
to classes that you guys will learn later.
So they they, they provide us
the mechanism to control the access.
Not default is not
a keyword like public private
the keyword.
So default is when you don't specify
any keyword.
Everyone is learning Java.
I was also thinking about this.
Sebastian
tried to focus on the class as well and
at the end said that I was busy
making the means throughout the course
and now I don't understand anything.
All right, so this is just a table
that am sure
it will confuse you.
99% of you will be confused
if you try to leave this table.
So I will highly encourage you
to not not try to understand.
Okay.
But it is the same information
I represented
in the form of a table.
So in here we have this public keyword
and this public keyword.
It is telling us that be paying with
which we specify this public keyword.
Will it be accessible within the class?
Yes, it
will be accessible within the class
Will it be accessible from any other class
inside the same package?
Yes. If you specify publicly, yes,
it will be accessible
if you are accessing from any class
from different package
and if you have specified public.
Yes, you be able to access it from
any class in different package.
Okay.
Now there is there is this different that.
If you are accessing something
from a class
by creating its object
and without creating a subject.
Okay.
That difference we will learn later.
And then we have this private.
Is it accessible
within the same class? Yes.
Is it accessible in the same package?
Not from any other class.
Different package.
Not from any other class
in different package? No.
The last two.
They are not.
Then they are also not clear to me,
you know, it's so it's
fine.
Actually.
This class today involve something
that I will be teaching you later.
Okay, So let's this course.
Until then. So
if multiplication table was enough for us.
So if we are not using
private protected aid or public,
so if we are not explicitly writing
these three keywords, JVM is by default
taking as default access modifiers.
Okay.
And that means you can access these things
inside the same package.
Yes. So up till now, you guys were using
the default access modifiers.
Have you guys tried to access your things
outside of that package?
Maybe accidentally.
Okay,
the scope of this modifier.
So right now we are discussing discussing
about the default.
The scope of this modified
is limited to the package only.
Okay.
This means that if we have a class
with the default access modifier
in a package,
only those classes that
in this package can access that class.
Okay.
No other class outside
this package can access this class.
I guess what
if you guys don't understand, understand
this part,
it's fine because you will hardly
create a class inside another class.
Okay.
But it is treated
the same as variables that matters.
Similarly, if we have a am I right?
We have four type of modifiers be followed
by weird oblique protected
default is accessible
within the same package.
Publicly accessible everywhere.
Private is accessible
within the same class only.
Yes, for Hardy. All right.
So similarly, if we have a default method
or data member in a class
that I member again means fields,
it would not be visible in the class off
and other package.
Okay. So if we are accessing it in a different package, we not be able to do that
in that our members class are matters
which are not declared
using any access modifier.
They have the default access modifier
and they are accessible to the classes
which are defined in the same package.
Okay.
So in here
the packages ABC package, in here,
the packages x, y, z package.
Okay.
And then
we have this method add two numbers
and we are trying to this add
two numbers method
in a different package.
Can I do that guys?
But this is a different package.
This is a different package.
I have the default access.
Can I call this add two numbers
in a different package
and no, no, no.
The method that. Mm.
The method is having a default access
this integer default add two numbers.
I am trying to call this method.
No, not even if we import the package.
Even if we import the package,
the method has default access.
Again, I call
a method having a default access
in a different package.
No, we cannot do.
We can only access public matters
in different packages. Yes,
we can only it within the same package.
It should be in the same package.
Yes. Yes.
So that's why we got this add an exception
walang undesired compilation
program, blah blah
blah.
Addition. Being public is not enough.
Then yes, this public keyword
with this class
is defining the access of this class,
not the access of this method.
Okay, so in here,
my class, it was also public, right?
This access modifier demo
in which I created primarily for public.
It was also public,
but it does not mean that
all the variables or the methods
they will be having the public access.
Okay, each variable
and the method have its own access
modifier.
Okay, then we have the public.
If a variable is set to the public,
it can be accessed
from any class available in the Java.
Any method in any class
can access the given variable via
the instance or direct access.
I was kind of relating this
to Google shares
or docs.
So yes, this class
in which these variables
or methods are present,
it must be a public class, right?
It is the first requirement
that we should meet.
If the class itself is not public,
that means we cannot access the class.
And if we cannot access the cloud,
then makes sense
that the variables and the methods
will also not be accessible.
Right. So class is public.
And then we have these
different levels that class,
private and
public, and then default
and then protected.
Okay.
So again, again, same example.
Yes, it depends on
what is the access modifier of each
method and each variable
in order to access modify
not only the access modifier of class,
but I am trying to do the same thing,
same example.
But this time
I have placed this public keyword
before the name of the class
again before the name of the class. So.
So this time I don't get any errors.
I don't get any.
Yes, I will be having public access.
Okay. Then we have the particular one.
We are skipping the slide for now.
We will discuss it
when we discuss the inheritance.
So because this protected
is related to the inheritance.
Okay.
And it will only make sense if you know
about the inheritance.
And then we have a variable
defined as private.
Private will be accessible
only from within the class
in which it is defined.
Such variables are not accessible from
outside the defined class,
not even in its subclass.
Can you make package public
to make your metadata?
No, but in packages
they don't have these access modifiers
like public, private
or something like that.
Packages don't have these access modifiers
made it clear
packages don't have access modifiers
private that are members
and matters are only accessible.
The class, class and interface
cannot be declared as private,
trying to see
if there are any shortcuts. No,
that's why.
We have these access modifiers.
We don't want the access.
If we have any shortcut,
then then there is no point of it right?
If a class has private constructor,
then you cannot create the object
of that class.
This is related to the next class.
Any other class of the same package
not be able
to access these members.
So even if there is a class inside
the same package, that class cannot
also access this.
So this classes class ABC.
This class is class example.
I have a private member double name
and if I try to access this now in here
I get a compile time that is
okay.
So this class for this class.
Now let's do more examples
and then we will be having a longer break.
Then you guys will be solving
these examples.
So, so this access about the
about the fields in the clear guys
that I access these fields.
So if it is clear, then tell me, let's
see if I make the assignment of private,
if I'm creating this method private,
so can I call this method inside this
same class?
So this method is private.
This display name can I call it in here?
Okay, so yes, I can call it
here.
Can I also can I also call these other
two methods inside this class? Yes.
No issues, right? No issues.
So this has the default access.
Let's make this
public one.
Okay so I can call the exploit age
and then I can do the same for this place.
No issues with there.
If I am inside this same class, no issues.
Okay, so
this class is inside the package.
Class 16.
Okay, this class is inside the package 16.
So class is also inside the same package.
So let's left.
So tell me guys, tell me which method
I can call in here
and which method I cannot find in here.
Can I call the
different matter
in a different class?
But I am still inside the same package.
Can I call this method? Yes.
Within the same class
you can call any type of modifiers.
So the one is saying yes. Really?
If you're saying yes,
can I call the display name at third
inside this
class it's a different class,
but it is inside the same package.
No. Okay. So the one we cannot call it.
Okay, because it pairs
B, it has private access here.
It has private access.
Can I call the displayed?
Yes, because I am inside
the same package.
Okay.
And what about this display, Sally?
It's also possible. Also possible.
Okay. And
I move to a different package if.
Yes, but not a good idea.
You know why it is not a good idea?
If we can call Edge
and you see I'm calling this edge.
No, no issues.
No, no, it's not.
This is not private.
And I am able to call it
okay, if I am in a different package.
Can I call this display name?
If I am in a
different package?
No. Right.
Yes. Not even possible.
Inside the same package.
Then how we can call it
in a different package.
All right, well,
what about this display edge?
What about this display edge?
Can I call it in a different package
for one again? Yes.
Again?
Yes, I am in a different package.
Can I call it method or a field
that has the default access? No.
Default access means only
call label inside the same package.
Okay.
Only callable inside the same package.
Is it close over saying yes.
And can I call this display salary?
Yes, because it's public, right?
Public means I can call it anywhere.
Yeah, I can call it anywhere.
Okay, let's do one more example.
Let me know what you guys are done typing
this for.
Is there anyone who's still typing?
Maybe. Sebastian,
If you are done typing, maybe.
Meanwhile, I create another
you can work on your been.
Okay.
Let me close this.
So I was not joking.
This this is literally day to this class.
I mean
no but we will be learning
more stuff
something about constructors
and we just go over their tasks together.
Yes I will. Going over the tasks together.
But first
you guys have to try them on your own.
When will you do two lessons?
In one day
And I will do half of the lesson today.
Simon And Half of the lesson tomorrow
is this is where
we will be having two classes.
So we are still we still have 2 hours
and we don't have any homework.
Usually we spend revising the concepts
and doing the homework one not on that.
So we can call it another class
and it's of the change of schedule.
So this class was
supposed to be taught on a weekday,
but because we have a change of schedule,
that's why we are covering two classes
and don't understand.
The secret is still showing me
an error on this line.
Anyways.
So let's say guys now.
Sorry I should wait in this class.
So let's say I am creating a bank account
application.
Okay.
So if I am developing some kind
of banking application, oops.
And if I have to store
the username in here
so they make it public, private
or be followed or paid
what, what I make it.
It should be private. Right?
We don't want this behavior that.
Any other class is creating an object
of this class
and accessing these sensitive data right.
So whenever you are dealing
with these types also,
by the way, the best practice
is to always, always
your fields
as private entity for any type of field.
If you
not planning to explicitly share the info
that is being stored in that field,
you should always,
always create the fears as private.
Okay.
What about the password field?
Should it be?
Should it also be private?
Private. All right.
First and
what about the name field?
Is there any harm if I. If I.
If I.
If I share the name
of of of the person Whose account is this
number?
It can be public, It can be difficult.
It can be public, it can be flooded.
But again, the best practice is to make it
private.
All right.
So now I have a question for you guys.
If I have made these fields as private
and this is the best practice,
if this is the best practice,
then how can I excel this year?
I have I have to store the data as well
inside these fields, right?
When I am creating the
object of this class,
I have to store the data as well, right?
I have to initialize these fields as well
with index
within the same class.
But again, you go within the same classes.
Again, not in best practice
using protected.
So here is a trick really
the kind of shortcut dummy.
Maybe.
And this is what you were looking for.
Extend their size for individual.
Yeah, that's great.
You can extend it.
So what I can do,
I can make
my method public, okay?
I can make my method of public.
So this field is private.
Yes. Right.
And this is field.
It's private, but can I access it inside?
Hide this thing inside a method
that is inside the same class.
Right.
Well, if this field is private,
I can still access inside a method
which is inside that class.
Right.
But what I can do, I can change it.
The access, modify of that method.
Now, this field is still private,
but I can all this
method to set its value.
Okay.
Does it make sense?
The value of this field
can be set from anywhere.
But now you have another confusion.
If I, i.
If I am setting the value of this field,
then what's the point of having this
method?
Let's make this public
and anyone can set this field right.
Well, what is the benefit of doing this?
Anyone can think of any benefit
hide bid
errors
like you can access a private data type
to a public method.
Yes, but access method
we can use it in other classes.
Don't have to create a method to gain.
All right. Let me.
Let me tell you the better.
So what do you guys can now
do is that you can
write many, many sets of rules.
Have you guys noticed this?
That when we tried to sign up for banks,
they have this restriction.
You cannot set this password.
Your username
cannot be more than these characters.
And then you have proper mechanisms
through which you can deposit and be money
in your account,
proper mechanism through which you can
withdraw money from your account.
Now I can write all those rules
inside this method, and only
if all of the rules are passed, then
the value to my field will be assigned.
Right? For example, I can see.
I can see.
I can see
only and only if our account user names
if it if the length is less 16 characters
only and only then I want to set
this username in here.
Otherwise.
Otherwise I want to print on the screen.
I want to print on this thing. So
username or this link
is allowed.
You guys remember that? That
when we were
learning about this string class
and we did that task
and we in which we checked for many,
many steps before can
we can allow the user to sign up.
We can put all those rules,
we can put any other rules in here
before we set the value to this variable.
Right.
I can
I can have it
with a variable right now.
If I am allowing to set this edge value,
if I am making it public or private,
anyone can set any value to this age
variable, right?
They can set negative numbers.
They can set 200 or 300, 400.
I don't want to allow that.
It corrupts the data of my class
and because methods
they operate on this data,
they can also misbehave.
So I am controlling the flow
of information on to my class
with the help of access
modifiers and methods
so that collect ever logic.
I write inside the method.
It does not misbehave.
Does it make sense?
Guys?
So it's like you can access
your private data if you can.
The condition?
Yes. Only
and only if you meet the condition.
If you made the rules that I am writing.
So now I have more control over my data.
Okay.
And what I can also do,
I can also write another method,
and that method can also object
for additional things.
Right?
For example, let's say I have fear
account balance.
So in your real life,
guys, can we access the account balance
without the username and password? No.
So I can write
another matter
that will only,
only it will only only return
the balance
If someone is providing
the correct the username
and password,
I can so I am controlling
the access to write the data
and now I am controlling the access
to read the data.
Okay. I can see.
I can see.
I will not see.
I will not tell you about the
I will not tell you
about the account balance.
I will only tell you about the account
balance
if you username that you are.
Oops.
If the username is equal
to the username that you are passing
and if you are also also providing
the proper
password.
If you are not providing
the proper password,
I. I will tell you about
the account balance.
Yeah.
So if these two things, if they match
to the username
and password of the user, then only
I will return
this account.
Goodness.
Otherwise
I can read and maybe, maybe like this one.
Right.
To indicate that the username and password
are not correct.
Okay.
And maybe we can make it a while method.
And then let's make it a wild matter.
So I only display
the account balance if.
Yeah,
proper username
and password is provided to me.
Otherwise I can see
username or
password is not
on it.
Making more sense guys.
Now how we can use these access
modifiers and methods
to control the flow of information
towards the class
and from outside of class.
Okay.
Should be public void that balance?
Yes, it should be relaxed.
Let's make it public.
So yes, everyone can access your
but only and only
if they know the username and password.
Right.
This is how things work in a real life.
Everyone can see your balance, but
if they know the username and password you
everyone can sign up depending upon.
They don't have any other requirements
that we have to fulfill
the requirements of the banks
before we can sign them.
Before we can sign.
So now I am inside the same class.
Now I can.
I can create this class.
I've got all
round one is equal to
account.
Okay?
If I try to access
the balance directly,
I will be able to do that.
Okay?
I will not be able to do that.
So if is not allowed.
Okay.
But can
and I
and I said so first
I need to select at this time.
At this point I am signing up for my
username and password. Okay.
So I pass
password
and let's say
let me quickly create a method
set and
the password as well.
So now I have a proper check mechanism
before I assign values to my field.
And then maybe, let's say account
balance is
then. Yeah.
And then if I want to get the balance
and if I don't pass the
proper username and password
for now, I will get guys
if I ask a billion here and we didn't
create balance should account.
Yes, you guys can create more methods.
By the way,
there is a special name on this.
There is a special name for these matters.
Okay.
This sector, the method through
which we set to be valued,
they are called centers
and the method through
which we get the values
they are called getter matters.
I mean, line number nine in
here, all of the okay
there.
Come on.
That password in is it okay now
what does your name mean?
It means
so there are two brothers
and a sister
in Karbala, if you guys know about that.
So it means small, so younger.
So what are you guys?
Yes. Is the youngest son
was also my grandfather's name.
Please repeat
what our setters aren't exactly.
So the method through
which we certainly value
they are called setters
and. The method through
which we get the information
out of that class are called
getters methods.
I thought it was folder
Oscar in my language.
Okay, so I get the user
name on password is not correct.
Okay.
If I passed the proper information
then I see my account balance.
Okay.
I see my contacts in the clear. Now guys,
how we can control
the flow of information.
Are there any questions?
So if you guys have understood it
properly, can I get more confirmations?
And then everyone tell me
if you have understood it more
technically scrolling down?
Yes, sure.
It's also. Yes, I think so.
So congratulation, guys.
We have covered another class.
I want to write it down, please.
I understood the logic. What?
I got lost.
I tried danger syntax down.
What?
What is my mistake? Yes.
Maybe with more task, it will be clear.
Yes, I will be giving you the tasks.
So I'm not joking.
Literally. You guys.
You guys have.
I think when someone is typing,
long as their heart starts hurting.
Yes. And then if you are like
so technically,
if you guys so
because you guys don't have access
to these classes
of learning
overwriting so can make private first
and then converting
to public with conditions
and then call on start to see it.
Yes. Now, are you are you are
you are right
it is
that class that we have or what I hope
you guys will forget about this class.
So we have discovered these concepts.
They are called encapsulation.
It is called encapsulation.
One of the pillars.
Technically, you guys have covered
a complete pillar of object
oriented programing.
Okay,
So let's let's start the class
number three.
Right? Look at you typing.
I am a little slow
so you guys can always stop me. No.
So you are not you happy
that you have covered like, two classes
and now we are about to learn
the third class?
Yes. Let's have a break as well. Okay.
Now I
think it's better to do more examples.
Going to next class?
Yes, we will be doing examples.
So here are three examples.
Let's so try to follow them.
And then after the break,
I will follow them with you.
What is my error
account?
Lunch or set password? Oh,
it is the start password method.
You don't have your defined
that start password matter.
I am confused with Lobo
so let me post this tasks in here.
So first is create a matter
that will accept an array as parameters.
It will return
is sum of all elements from that adding
method is sure to be visible
only within same package
and accessible by creating an instance.
Create a matter
that will take a staying as parameter
and return the reverse strings.
So you guys have already
created these methods.
So we are just retyping these methods
with,
with these access
methods should be available to all classes
within your project
and accessible by class name.
Okay.
I should be able to call that method
by only class name
creating method
that will spring as AP parameter
and return
your string that consists only of vowels.
Method should be available
inside the class only where it is
declared and executed by calling its name.
So let's have a 30 minute break.
Okay.
And after the break, I try to complete
as many tasks as you guys can.
And then after the break, I will be going
these tasks
and then if we are left with time.
So I was just kidding.
Then if we are left with time,
then we will start of the next class.
Okay, We are still on the class.
Same class that we were supposed to learn
can please display the account page
s okay.
Can we be on break?
Any questions?
There's almost 147 so
we'll be back by one p
in try to solve these tasks.
I am missing some words for the account.
Can you extend the page so I can copy?
Yes Yes.
Is it better now?
Maybe it is back now.
Then I see the entire account page.
Yes Yes, all our days.
So try to see all these examples
and then we will be back
and remind you about the recording
I'm recording out.
So who was that?
Who was the guy that should remind me
about the recording?
We want to focus
fired over
and over should remind me.
James Bagels. So
tangled
we were all this use less memory
than a loop.
Yes, less memory and less CPU power.
So on this line, guys,
what I am doing on this line.
So the part that I have highlighted here,
what I am doing in here,
what do we call this? So
I am writing new keyword,
the name of the class and parentheses,
what do we call it
matter?
How do we create an object
builder?
Oh, I think I need to go through
all the concepts.
If you guys
want to remember how to create the object
So remember
whenever we add will be a new keyword.
You are
you are creating object.
No, nobody is.
Nobody is. All right.
So once I have the object, okay, once
I have the object,
then I am calling
this reverse method on that object.
Okay.
And then using the method gaining,
I am calling another method
that will convert the resource
to the whole thing.
Is there anyone who don't understand
how this is working
but maybe want to?
Maybe you want me to write it
in a simpler way, the way that you guys
have been writing code
so that you guys can compare
what is going on?
Do you guys want me to write it in
in an open, simpler way
so that you guys can understand
what is on?
All right.
So if you are not using the method
chaining, this is how you guys
will be doing it.
You guys will be
writing a lot of code string
builder. So
if you don't understand
something you guys have
prepared, are
there is to the new
thing builder then say and then you pass
this SDR in here
and then you see SDR
build a lot of the words
All right And you store back
Sorry.
And then
you see
being
your SDR is equal to
the are builder
board to being
and then you say, well return
new SDR.
Okay, so this is how you guys will do it.
And if you guys are not using method
changing
like this, it's better now,
then you check line,
then the reverse spelling.
If okay
line, then
this one.
Do you sure that we will unders understand
what is going on
already? Then if you are asking me
if I if I
am sure if you guys understand it or not.
So I get it from your responses there,
how I do it.
If you guys are understanding
something or not, you are missing an E
in reverse.
You guys are talking to me
or I'm replying to
someone on internet
or something like that.
Or you mean the name of the method?
Oh my God, you guys are so perfect, man.
This is just a method
like where I want you to focus.
You guys are not focusing on it
and you are all focusing
on the name of that method.
All right, Perfect.
Brad, let me.
It is better now.
This is I see a lot of grammar police
on Facebook as well, too.
People are fighting
on a long, long connect.
We want
to make sure you're still working the.
All right.
So let me
the unit
ask the tool.
Okay.
How can we pass the interviews?
So you you look in ahead.
I think if you still have
to learn the performance,
okay, then you have to do so many things.
Then you will be filling ten interviews
and then you will know
how to pass the interview.
Okay.
So you are to pass the interview, right?
Right now you are you don't even know
about selenium cucumber test and.
The databases API is a w as
not with this performance for sure.
Only ten years on average, only ten
so fast to
ask for it. So
and then I can
two or
three works of string.
And at the moment it made a small
Asia. So
let me tell you this.
The students believe me, the students
actually,
I don't want to tell you guys this because
then you guys will not be focusing.
But sometimes what happens is that
some of the companies,
they they will not be asking you
about decoding test, but definitely
they will be interviewing you.
And you guys don't have the right and
it goes and then you can also get a job.
Okay.
But indefinitely, even if you get a job
and if you are unable to perform
on their job, then then there is no point
that they will find you.
And I have seen that as well.
Yeah.
Are there any questions from this
task to guys
here to face
and voice change
by the time it is my interview time?
Yes. Maybe I have to contact my six.
We will send me that list of jobs better
if with article and no questions about me.
Your robotics project
now. Yes, guys, it's not about
get your the job, it's
about sustain doing their job as well.
Can you tell some people from previous
batch again and talk about interviews?
Yes, maybe.
Okay. So tomorrow.
So maybe we remind me
we can invite some students
in the next week, especially the ladies
out there.
Any questions from the staff guys?
I am.
And at this time,
I will be giving you at least one hour.
Okay.
So last time I was feeling,
I was bothering, actually,
and I had to close that class.
So no questions.
All right,
let's let's move to their next. Yes.
Like when you deliver a five hour plus,
even if you eat before the class,
all that is gone.
I eat before and after the class.
And at least three, 3
to 4 liters of water.
Speaking for 5 hours is not easy,
especially when the grammar masters
are sitting in front of you again.
Who can in seconds can detect if you are
making a spelling mistake or not.
Right. We have to be very
attentive.
As with
all like so
let me close this task.
All right?
So don't worry about it.
I loved how you said all my
grammar will be good
during the interviews.
All right.
So create a method
that will accept string as a parameter
and return
new string that consists only of flowers.
Method should be available
inside the class.
Only.
So what should be the
up? Please don't.
Don't talk about food.
Believe me, right now I am again.
It's like 10 minutes.
My food is ready and it's in front of me.
So let me please complete this task
and then we can discuss
about peas and burgers and all that.
So what should be the excess modifier?
It should be private, right?
Because we want it
to be only, only accessible
inside the class.
Again, lunch break.
Take us out.
No, but the muscle.
But I can't
get GI.
Okay.
If that's the study and guys
don't want to understand it.
All right.
So private and then method
should be available inside the class
only where it was declared
and executing by calling
it its name.
So should I make it static
or should I make it instance
s out translate.
So, Sebastian,
do you know about cracker and B?
It's is almost all the Asian countries
they have
this standard breakfast
in which they take the bread,
they put some oil,
and then they kind of put
that bread, that oil,
they cook it for 5 to 10 minutes
and then they make
they make David did
not garlic
and then they enjoyed a lot.
Yeah.
Here we go.
And sometimes they stuff it with potatoes
and other vegetables.
Oh, my God. It's so tasty.
Oh, so what should be the non
excess modified guys.
Should I put static
or there should be instance
remember guys.
So if I am calling this method
inside this class, what do I need?
Do I need a main method inside this class?
If I am going to call this method inside
this class, will
I be needing the main method?
Yes, I will be needing.
I will be needing.
Not again.
Oh, because there is this private
well and place.
Thank you.
So this main method is a static method.
This main method is a starting method
and I want to call this method
by calling its name.
Can I call the instance method by its name
only inside the static method? No.
So what should I do then?
I should make that method
static as well.
Okay.
And then
all loop
process string
or turbidity parameters, get it in here.
So it should be a string
here.
And again,
see was method changing.
I was said at one
that I was not able to do this task, but
I am going to happy, which was complicated
for the entire class.
The written
SDR thought which method I should use
if I only launched the was from that
that string.
Oh yes. The data type as well. Right.
I should be having the string replace
or replace
all the replace or
no the me.
I cannot use both
because I want to process
the individual characters.
I mean you will be
you have the right to a lot of method
changing
if you are using the replacement card.
Okay so how do I
what do I specify in
as the first parameter?
What is it called?
Life? Yes.
Next we can use the lowercase.
What do we call this frog?
What is the term for this?
So we want to replace
everything
other than
lowercase AP, IOU and uppercase IOU.
So this is called
the regular expression.
Okay, So this thing that I am passing as
the first parameter,
it's the regular expression, right?
And I am replace everything
other than lowercase and uppercase.
E I also like inside this string
that I am passing in here.
Okay, that's it.
Does it make sense
or do you guys want me to
rewrite the logic for this method
in a different way?
Is it understandable?
The method
that I am using in here?
Oh, replace with nothing.
This. Yes.
Write it in a different way.
So, Lenny, what should I write in
and in different way?
I declare a variable and store the results
and then return it
like this.
Because that's what we are doing.
Saying new SDR is equal to this.
Okay?
And then we return
a string after
they're set on only one line.
And now I can call this method
with by just typing its name.
Okay.
All right.
So we get a box and look easy.
Is it does it make sense?
You used
square brackets. So.
Muhammad, these square brackets,
they are used to specify
a regular expressions,
these square brackets in here.
I hope you guys
have not forget about this.
They are the syntax
of regular expressions.
Is it clear now, Muhammad
defined regular expression?
Please, please.
Did you did you attend the class on Sphinx
then?
Then why are you don't remember
about the regular expressions?
That's they're alarming, by the way.
I think the regular expressions
were just like two classes before.
Okay, clearly we don't remember anything.
So that means you guys are not not paying
the attention.
I could blame my own surprise party.
Or you could also execute this method
in at best, the class.
No, we cannot do that.
And let because the access modifier
it is private.
Seems like I follow
that regular expression too.
So this is where
you guys have to be efforts.
I think we need to get starting
and read them all lowercase,
so try to spend some time on the slides
guys.
I understand to ask in a different way.
That's fine. Alex
Are there any questions,
guys, I don't understand.
It works. So, Alex,
in here, in the regular expressions,
we are saying that if this string
has any of these letters,
don't replace them
otherwise replace all the letter.
So there's no sign.
It means replace everything,
but not these characters.
So in my name there was this error.
So I specified this in here,
I specified this
lowercase a, but there was no s d and odd.
So those s d at
the end are have been replaced
by nothing in here
and therefore I get this uppercase A
and see
where it was declared
and executed by calling its name.
Can you elaborate more on this part
from task three?
So you guys see, I am only calling this
method by specifying its name.
I'm not using the class
name. I'm not using.
I'm not creating any object.
This is what it means.
So that's why I created this static.
Where is the mean from Merriam?
But can't we go it
like private and then make it public,
make it fast, make it private,
then make it public
with default condition
and then call it Why, why, why?
If those conditions
like we learned before
and use the name now,
that was far variables.
Some method that was for variables.
It's a method
so mirror
you have forgot to specify the scatter
symbol.
Make sure you have the scattered
and x.
Do you understand it now?
Why on ripple are not tasked with
lot or types and access modifiers?
So because we have learned it today.
So now I will be releasing the labels
related to variables and access modifiers.
Not in make sure you have this
scattered symbol, not symbol
in here.
Please tell me what task that was about.
What we need to be done so Task
three was about replacing everything
inside a string, but not
D is electives, naughties marbles.
That was the task. Three.
I'm going
to share the screenshot again.
Yes. All right.
Oh, so those we want to leave.
You guys can leave those who have
some questions that you guys can stay.
We will not be learning new things.
I will only be answering the questions
if you guys have any.
It was the task and we are.
It's info about this letter.
Oh, so, Alex,
these letters, they are called
these letters.
They are called vowels in English.
These letters, they are always
made by
Owen.
Is it, is it clear now
prior to circuit test, prior to search.
What are what was in English
thou borrowed from me?
Alex.
I don't know what the word it means,
but I take some last guys
and try to revise the concepts.
Okay?
To get rid
to me.
Like, I mean,
I do have this symbol,
but it prints again.
All are all online.
That's it.
Boston, This board and
I will help you out
what is being imported. And from there.
Oh, it's just a mistake. Let me move it.
Then you'll know
you guys don't have any homework,
so try to revise the concepts
from previous.
It's very, very important.
Otherwise there all will be there.
There will be no benefit of spending.
These hours in in classes.
If you guys are not revising,
where do I have error?
So, Elinor,
you are creating the main method
inside that other method
and you master
all right, Bye bye.
Awesome.
See this word? Flowers.
All right. Anybody, guys?