And hopefully
things will start to make sense.
Hi, Miriam.
All right, guys.
So up till now.
So can you guys tell me how how do we
solve real problems using using programing
so you guys are half and down
so you know, the half of the concepts.
Now, the second part of
this Java series
will be to solve
the real life problems,
but in a better way.
So the basics, they will be same.
We will be using the same things,
but now we will learn some techniques
that will help you write better code
because that is understandable to others.
Because that is easy to manage. Easy.
But by manage.
By manage I mean easy to change.
If new requirements come in, comes in,
you can easily incorporate
those new changes.
This part of Java series.
It will help you better model
real life problems inside your computers.
So take a problem from real life.
Define the rules, and then those rules
they will keep on executing automatically.
We need a little help with to the arrays.
I do not worry.
I will be going to the to the editor.
But let me tell you this.
We really need to the arrays.
They are not used in the real life
as much. So
after these oops concepts,
I will be teaching you
at least five classes on collections
framework.
So those collection framework you guys
will be learning new data structures.
So the in real life you guys will be using
those data structures instead of the.
So at this point,
if you guys have understood the concept
concept that high level,
if you guys can access the element of a 2D
area and can store an element in the area,
that's enough.
I mean, we are trained to using the loops
or something like that.
So when I will be teaching,
I will be telling you how
much, how,
how useful
those concepts will be in your realize
how important they are
with respect to your interviews
and on your job.
And then you guys,
you guys can pay attention or can study
those concepts accordingly.
You can spend your time accordingly.
You really also tell me of laudatory.
So can you guys tell
me what do you guys think?
What does this programing do?
How how do we solve
that real life problem?
Using using programing.
No brain left to think,
but just just the just
the start of the class.
At least keep a little bit brain
for for my class but hard
by putting logical on the issues
for building the models
for transactions
so imagine imagine
how have you guys played the video games
Big B should provide for 3D games, right?
So in a game
you see almost everything from real life
is being billed
virtually inside your computer,
right? Yes.
Call of Duty, my favorite.
So using programing idea you
you must be very old format.
I played by
the using programing what we do
we build a virtual world
inside the computers.
Then we define the rules
that how that word will work. Right?
So you can fly cars, you can jump from one
building to the other building, right?
And then the rules,
they are defined like this.
So you build a word
using these programs inside your computer.
I like a blind person here.
It's fine.
It's fun.
So you guys must have at least played
some kind of games.
Not it's not super
3D or something like that.
So we build
a virtual world inside the computer.
Then we define the rules,
how that world will work right?
How many fires you you fired at
some person and then person will be dead.
How the rules of the physics will work
and then you let that word run, right?
So this is the case for games.
What you can do,
you can define those rules for anything.
Like, for example,
think of the banking applications. So
in big game in banking
application will define
that there will be a person,
he will be having a bank account,
he can put some funds in the bank account,
He can withdraw the funds, right?
He can transfer fast.
So all of these rules
we define using programing, right?
And then we put that those rules
inside the computer and that application,
it keeps on running,
entertaining thousands of customers.
So we will be doing this in
this part of the of the Java series.
It will be focusing on how to mimic
the real life things inside the computers.
Okay.
So you guys can think of yourself as
as the creator of those objects
on those things inside the computers.
So now you guys have to think if you guys
who are the creators of this word,
how, how, how would you have defined
all those things
that exist in the real life?
Are all those things
How did they work and interact and
how they look like and things like that?
Okay, do that.
I know or you.
So in real life guys, tell me, how can I.
So how can I, I define something?
How can I define something like, say,
for example, if I have to tell someone
that what is a human,
how how can I tell this this information?
How how can I convey this information
if I have to tell
someone how the cards look like,
Well, what is a bike?
What is a cat? What is a dog?
What do we what do we convey?
What is the piece of information
that we tell the other person?
If we have to define that things
to explain
the qualities, the perfect properties?
Yes, I show perfect answer step by step.
Explain.
Yes. So we can explain how that thing
might work in real life.
Right?
So previously, step by step
explaining how they're think.
So we define
by describing by their actions
how those things look like, right
by description, by their shapes.
So we will be doing exactly the same
using these glasses and objects.
And if I ask you guys
in real life,
if I have to build something,
what will be my first step?
You have to build a car
or a bike or an airplane.
So I will first
I will be having that blueprint right
that to die, that concept inside my mind.
I will I will think about all those rules
and how did that thing will look like, how
that thing will function and everything.
Right.
So the first step is,
is that blueprint, right, that planning,
that idea.
So that idea, that blueprint
that could die
on that plan is called a class.
So you guys have been creating
a glass, right?
But up till now
you guys have been creating a
simple class in which you guys are having
all your main method, right?
You, you didn't define
any of the properties or how that class
would look like or what is the idea behind
you creating that class?
Why you are creating that class? Right?
I grew up my dad making blueprints
manually.
I said we will be doing the same idea.
So this class in Java is the concept
that we will use to define line,
how it will look like
and how that thing will.
What are the behaviors of that team?
What does that thing do
inside the computer?
Okay,
so defining how that thing looks like
and defining how that thing works
for these
two things, we will be using a class.
This is a class in in
Java programing that we use, okay?
We use a class to define how something
will work, how something will look like.
So by definition,
the class is a user defined.
And one more thing is
I will be
reading all the slides,
I will be explaining all the sentences,
all the
definitions and everything
that is written inside this slide.
Because after you guys are done
learning Java,
you guys will be coming back to the slides
to refresh your knowledge.
And I want you to have clarity
on everything that is written
inside these slides.
So if something is not clear inside
this file,
stop me and I will explain that thing
with different examples.
Okay.
And I want you
to do one more thing because
this is what
I have observed from previous batches.
So you guys will be for the next
three weeks, it will be all your Java
and after three weeks
you guys will be learning selenium.
And as you move away from Java and start
learning other things,
you guys will start to forget things.
So I want you to follow this routine
that at least
you guys are reading
at least 2 to 3 slides each day.
So you guys are halfway down.
So I want you to go and start
from this slide number one,
and I want you to keep on reading
one or two slides per day.
Or maybe if you have time,
you guys can go back and check your repos
and you can maybe start or write
at least a few lines of code each day.
So it will be very beneficial for you.
Otherwise what happens is that you
guys will be sitting in the interviews,
you guys will be following
the coding tests,
but you guys will not even remember
how to declare an edit.
You guys will forget the syntax
of how good it be at edit.
This has been this and this has happened
and I don't want you to do the same.
So okay, so a class
is a user defined
blueprint
from which object are created, right?
So let's say, for example, if I have to
be, if I have to create a get,
is this required any specific program
or we can use the clips.
So now is it right now
we will be using Eclipse,
but I guess from next week
we will be switching to a different idea
that is called in telling you.
So right now
in the industry, around 50 to 60%.
People use intelligent and 40%
of the time
they use Eclipse or another ID.
So we don't know.
Depending upon your company,
you guys might be using Eclipse
or might be using intelligence.
We we want to teach you both.
So that's like
half of the Java will be part in Eclipse
and the remaining half
will be taught in an intelligent
and you guys will like it.
You guys will like it.
It's like using
this, like using Windows XP and Windows 11
or an iPhone
or maybe some third party giant
mobile phone.
So a class is a user defined so
the users define it.
Okay.
And it contains the blueprint, right?
The idea the sketch is the design
from which
we will be creating the objects.
Okay.
So let's say, for example, are we going
to be learning Python as well?
Northwestern
There are more than 10,000
programing languages
and we will not be learning
all those programing languages.
The basics, they are same
if you guys learn the rules
in one programing language,
here's the syntax that changes.
So if you have understood the concepts
in Python, you also have variables.
In Python, you also have loops in Python,
you have for loop, you have y
loop, you have little white loop
you have at is
you have everything that you have in Java.
Okay?
If the only the syntax
and some programing languages,
they are optimized for certain things.
For example, if you have to do some
machine learning task,
Python has a lot of libraries,
a lot of code that is already written
to solve those problem.
So it depends
what kind of problem you are solving.
For us, Java is good.
Yes, the student.
So class is a template
for creating different objects.
We which defines its features
are the properties and the behavior.
So how how certain
how a thing will look like features
and how that thing behaves in a real life.
Right?
What are the tasks
that that thing can perform?
We will be defining these proteins
in a class.
In order to create an object,
you need a class.
Okay, So first we have this idea and
we put all the rules,
like how things
how that thing will look like
and how that thing will behave
right then from those ideas,
those rules, that blueprint,
that design will create the actual thing.
Okay,
So we will follow this approach, right?
So in in a car factory,
if you have to build a car,
you you kind of build
that template, right?
And then you can build thousands of cars
out of that same template, right?
So you have
a little
you got
you can also have a little word variations
in different actual cars
that you produce from the same design.
Right.
So we can use that design to build
many real life
actual objects and we can have
a little bit different
different properties for those objects.
Okay.
So glass
is something that contain contains
rules or design or a blueprint.
And using those rules,
we create the actual objects.
So you guys already know
about the variables.
So a class can have variables
like the variables
that you guys are defining, like things,
integers, booleans, all those variables
that you guys have been using.
You can have those variables
in a class, this method.
So you guys right now, you guys only know
all about the mean method, right?
But we
can have many different main methods
and it will become super clear the moment
I gave you the first example, it will
super clear What are those matters?
What are those properties?
So don't worry right
now, this constructor thing
you guys don't need to worry about.
There is a complete class
on this constructor,
right?
So for now you guys can think of this
constructor is something that help you
construct the actual objects
from those classes.
Okay.
And the last bind, you can have
multiple objects for the same class.
Now, before we move forward, this is
these are the main concepts
of object oriented programing.
So you guys are learning.
You guys have you
guys will now be learning.
The object oriented programing and
object
oriented programing is built on these
5 to 6 concepts.
Okay?
You have the concept of object and class
that you guys will learn in today's class.
Then you will be learning
about inheritance.
I think it's pretty much same
as the inheritance in our real life.
Then we have polymorphism,
if the easiest topic
being object oriented programing.
So I said this is where you guys
have to hold down your peers
and then we have abstraction
and encapsulation.
So we will be starting
from class and objects. Look
and Java is an object oriented programing.
It's not 100% object oriented programing,
and it will be clear
at the end of this course.
But we are other object
oriented programing languages
like Seashore, Python, C++.
So object oriented is nothing,
but it's a set of rules.
It's a way of solving
a real life program, a real life problem,
using any programing language.
So it's a set of techniques
and like object
oriented, we have functional programing.
There's another set of rules
that help us solve certain
real life problems in a better way,
not where you guys will not be trying.
I will make sure that you guys don't try
so object oriented.
It is nothing,
but it's a methodology, okay?
It's a way of solving
error, a real life problem,
a set of rules, the set of guidelines
that programmers
have developed over the years.
So today we are starting with the object
oriented programing.
And object oriented programing is nothing,
but it's a methodology
code paradigm to design a program
using classes and objects.
It simplifies the software development
and a maintenance problem.
Remember guys
to solve real problems.
You guys will be writing thousands
and thousands of lines of code right?
And by now you must have noticed
that if you write the program,
you're going to visit that program
for two weeks.
And after two weeks,
if you see that program,
half of the logic that you have written
inside that program, you don't remember
why you wrote that logic, right?
The does this happens to you guys?
Or maybe after 5 minutes, Spike,
you write something and after five meters
you don't know why you wrote a bad thing.
So this object or in programing
will help us solve that problem as though
we need to worry about.
Lemma Did he make a bad comment about man?
Don't
fried
Canada, don't worry about Zima.
I don't remember. Next. Next.
There is a lot
the object oriented programing
will also help you in
in these kind of scenarios.
And the second hardest part is that
you guys must have noticed
you use your mobile phones,
you use different websites
each day or each week.
There are new features
in those mobile phones or the apps
that you use on mobile phones,
all of the websites and everything, right?
So this software
development is not a one time activity.
So it's not like that.
You have written a program
and then that program
will continue to work
fine if I am not talking about Microsoft.
So this rule applies other than Microsoft.
So you guys will be adding
a lot of features day by day.
Okay. So
now now to
add those features,
you guys will be writing NewCo, Plus
you guys will be modifying
the existing code.
Yeah.
So that modification of the existing code
requires you to understand
what is already written.
Then modify those things
and then
build those new features.
I am lost, Cosima.
I am also lost.
So this is what we luckily will be doing.
So today we are starting the object
oriented programing
and to learn about the object
oriented programing,
we need to understand
the class and the objects.
Okay.
The backpacks make much error.
Students they they.
When I used to teach them,
they used to send me off.
There
we are about to jump from the window. So.
Zimmer Don't worry.
Those those things,
they will not apply on base.
I know
polymorphism.
Wait for me. Yes.
All right.
So up now it's around
27 minutes and be honest, is this hard?
Does it require too much brain?
So, Emily, you guys will
I will ask you this question
after this class and you guys will tell
me, you guys, I want to hear from you
if it is hard or not.
We are just sleeping about you, okay?
Just give me like 30 to 40 minutes and
then all of your dogs, they will be here.
So I belong.
Do you guys understand?
Now what is object oriented programing?
I was going great, losing weight,
and I started this class
that you are gaining the weight now.
I think you should
lose more weight.
I was crying
because I don't want to lose my job.
Speaking about our exam.
When we see example, I hope we can.
Yes, you guys will be able to.
So guys.
But what is object oriented programing
is something specific to Java or whatever.
What is it?
Can you guys tell me?
Can you guys define it?
Oh, yes.
By the way, I forgot to tell you
that this part is easier than those nested
loops, Those body arrays
and stuff like that.
No, it's not just for Java methodology.
I'm losing weird.
I'm just thinking about course,
the whole time, not even hungry anymore.
So I was then I was learning programing.
I used to think about the programs
when I was in bathrooms.
I was eating or sleeping.
So give me don't worry,
it's the same for all
go to here.
I was happy with the nested loops.
Does this part include coding?
Definitely.
Nikolai A lot of coding. It's
a program
works easier only for you as the
instance with finger.
Yes, a lot of coding.
The nice
object oriented programing
is just a way to solve real life problems
using any programing language,
a set of rules, a set of guidelines
that help us write it,
and that then that help us
solve
the real life problems in an easier way.
And can you guys
tell me about the class one?
What is the class
what what were you thinking about
in the bathroom?
So, Farhad, when you will be struck
on a problem for us
then and that
that problem, it will, it will haunt you.
So you will be thinking
about those problems in the bathroom.
So it was not just me who was losing Their
idea of an object
type of low class may contain objects
or word, a blueprint
from which we can create an object.
Perfect answer.
Who know class will define
features and behavior. Yes,
I. I was dreaming about my class.
Describe the contents of
so how a certain thing will look like
This is what a class will be defining.
And can you guys tell me about the object?
Well, what are objects in our real life
template for creating projects?
Not projects, but objects.
Physical items like the mouse,
the computer, the laptop,
the chair, the room, everything around you
that you guys can see and touch.
That that physical thing
is an object, right?
We will be creating those things
inside programs,
inside computers.
So here is an example.
It is an example
so we can have an animal class.
Okay.
For for now you guys can think of animal
as some kind of idea inside your mind.
So then I ask you to tell me
about how animals look like.
How do they behave?
You guys can tell me
some certain things about animals, right?
It's all inside your mind.
It's a logical thing.
It's a logical deviation, right?
It's an idea.
If something that is inside
only inside of mind.
If I ask you, can you show me an animal
you guys can.
You can.
Can show me a
lot of different things. Like
lions, like cats and dogs.
Right.
But if I ask you about a specific actual
physical object,
you cannot tell about a specific,
specific physical object.
If I ask you to define that thing
using animal.
Right.
But are these objects,
are they inside our minds?
We can have a physical
a sorry, we can have a kind of definition
about all of these things inside
this animal class, Right.
So if I ask you that,
what is the difference
between animals and cars?
You guys can define it, right?
If I ask you the difference between
animals and humans, you guys,
you guys can tell, right?
All those attributes
how humans look like and how animals
look like all those behaviors
that humans do and that those animals do.
Right. You you kind help.
You kind of
have that picture in your mind,
like snake is a tail,
which quickly creeps around.
Yes, that's that's perfectly right.
So what we will do
inside
inside computers,
we will be defining these classes
first, like,
for example, the animal class.
And once we have defined the animal class
inside the animal class, we will define
how how the animals look like,
how they behave.
And once we have defined those rules,
then we will be able to create different,
different animals using those rules.
Okay, so getting the furniture class
and here are all the objects
that are under this furniture.
So let me first show you an example.
Today's class number 11 right? Yes.
When we create a scanner,
we are creating an object.
So let me create a class.
So now I want you to follow me
and I want you to stop me.
If you guys are unable to follow me
and I am going fast.
So. Com or syntax.
No class, no.
And this time does not create
that mean method.
Okay.
This time don't attack me method.
The name must not be
identified
in class
and so
let me create the package first.
Last 11.
Is this class 11?
Yes, this is class 11.
So let's create a doll between ten and 12.
Let's try to create a doll.
Okay.
Let me know what you guys see.
This this class in here.
Without that, to
go inside a class,
What do we define, guys?
What define two things.
What are those two things
that we define inside the class?
No, main class.
The method behavior
and the features are the properties.
So we will be going step by step.
Right now, we will only be focusing
on features, on properties,
and later on
we will be defining the behaviors as well.
Inside that class.
So tell me about the dolls guys.
What are they
some what are some properties?
What are some features that dogs dogs have
four legs barking.
They'll one they'll size
breed.
So let's start from something very simple
although
it's a little let's say
let's start from the name right.
So dogs they can have a name
physical then humans
against
dogs they can have a breed, right.
So string and breed
dogs, they can have color.
Okay.
They have some trade in humanity to
gain.
Well, what are the other things, guys,
that dogs have
a name breed color type.
So Alexa, Alexa, we will be specifying
the type and the size or the age.
So instead of size, let's have
height.
So for height, what should I do, guys?
Should I declare an integer variable
or a double variable?
Then how do we end points?
And so we should be using a double, not a
major.
What about the age?
So age is usually defined in figures,
so increase
the age
right?
Then we can have
the gender as estimate right.
So this is how
old I am.
33.5 years old.
So we will consider you 33 years old.
So this is how guys using these
simple variables
that you guys have learned.
We define the features
or the properties for certain objects.
Okay.
So we have defined inside this class
that the object
that we will be creating from this class,
it will be
it can have a name, it can have a breed.
It will be having some color, right?
It will be having some height, age
and integer.
Right now, if you look at the real life
dogs,
there can be thousands of features right
there
and there can be thousands of features.
But to explain the concept,
we will only be
considering 5
to 10 features of each object right?
So don't don't worry
about those number of LEDs,
those those things
and all those other attributes there
that you guys have specified
in this channel
in here in the chat.
Yes, there are all features,
but we will be keeping the example simple
and there can be other features
that we are
not maybe considering right now. So
all those things,
they are classified and procedures, right?
So we defined a class.
Okay, We have given the class
a name, it's our dog.
And then using variables, we have
some properties
or attributes of dogs, right
now we can have much more complex
structures to define the actual physical
appearance of a dog.
We can we can define to how how those legs
and those neck and body
and all that stuff, how they're acting
looks like in real life objects.
But we will be keeping things very,
very simple.
Okay.
So we will only be
considering these features.
So when we have now defined
the dog like service dog,
which is need for 2508
could be the
to test each class
or to clear the objects out of a class.
We will be following this
in this
approach
that for each class
we will be creating a test for class.
So we will create a dog
stuff in here.
And inside of this test,
our classes in here
we will be having the main methods.
So let me open these classes
side by side.
Can you repeat please?
Can we define behavior for features?
No, just give me 15 to 20 minutes.
I will tell you how to define behaviors.
So right now
I have defined some properties of a dog.
Okay. How a dog
looks like in real life.
For that I have created a class
and I have used some variables and
deficit. Okay.
And you created another class
like normal? Yes.
This is second class.
This dog best, the class in here.
We will create actual objects
out of these classes.
We can do.
We can create the objects
inside this class.
But this is how it is done in real life.
So I will try to follow the same rules
that you guys will be using in your
in your real life order, in your
on your jobs, in real life.
So are you guys done writing
most of these classes?
Okay, now to create
an object out of a class,
this is the syntax that we use.
So we write name of the class.
Okay, dog.
Then the object name.
Okay, It can be in there. Say
it can be
a Zima or not.
Okay.
And then we use that equal cosine.
Then we write new keyword
and then again that dog.
And of parentheses.
And this time we call it
the same as you guys have been doing
for this kind of class.
The name of the class,
then name of the variable.
So the name of the class,
name of the variable
and equal cosine neo keyword.
And then again the name of the class.
And the benefit is the dog is an Adi
likes camel and it likes Natty.
So that area is also class.
The class name is Guess Sensitive.
Yes, the class name is a sensitive.
Okay, so this is how we create
an object in here.
This is the object. Okay?
This is what we call an object.
This is the class.
This is just an assignment.
This new keyword.
You guys will always be
using a new keyword when you will be
creating objects of classes.
And then again, name of the class.
And by the way, this
this is what we call the constructor.
So basically we are saying, Hey, Java
effort of the model to our class
and to use features from there. Yes.
So this is what happens, guys,
when you write the name of the class
and you don't write any import statement,
You remember this
for the scanner to work,
you guys used to write that import
statement, write that import statement.
It actually tells you
where that a scanner class is
inside
the packages that Java guys have built
when you guys are developing something.
And if that thing exists
in the same package,
you guys don't need that import statement.
I missed it.
Did you explain why the dog class
does not have a main method?
Can it ever have main method?
Yes, it can have the main method as well.
It's just an optional thing. So.
So when you write the name of the class
lines, this is important.
I want you to focus when you write
the name of the class what Java will do.
Java will go in here and Java will check
if there are any import statements
for that class.
If there are no import statements in here,
then Java will double check this package.
Okay, Java will take this package.
So Java will say okay,
I am so this this dog best
our class is inside
this class 11 package here
and I don't have any import statements
that Java will do.
Java will go inside this package
and Java will search
for the four classes that have this dog
as the name.
Once Java has found this dog,
not Java, then Java.
Go inside this class in here,
okay?
And now Java knows
what are the properties of this class,
What are the methods
and how to use that class.
Okay,
if we have an import statement of that
import statement,
it tells you where to find that class.
If we don't have import statement,
the first priority
in Java looks inside this package
in which the class exists
in which you are
trying to create the object.
Okay. So far dog class
because there are no import statements,
Java will go inside this
class level and package the same package
in which this class exists
and it will try to search
the dog class is
the class was to be on same package.
No, it can be in a different package,
but if it is in a different package
then you have to write
that import statement.
Then it would be in a folder.
Not you meet.
You should be inside the package
import card or turtle
and dog would not need to import Asia.
What is the syntax import valid or tuple?
And so we don't need that import
statement.
We don't need any syntax.
Oh, then it is outside of the package.
I will.
I will teach you well what happens
when it is outside of that package.
No, don't worry about that right now.
What about if
there is nothing in the package,
then you will be getting an error.
Now you will be getting an
Dimas dog.
It's a variable.
And so it could be anything.
Yes, it can be anything.
It can be anything
you want.
You can say
the mark
looks are dog.
Yes, this is the object.
Okay.
So let me put a comment for you
when here we are creating
an object of
dog class. Okay.
So when we write this line, we say
we are creating an object of that class.
No, you have a dog, Rima.
Okay, Rima, tell me.
Tell us
more.
Tell us.
So I am writing this variable name.
That means.
But who has that dog in this class
alone now?
Okay, we will create the object
for all of your dogs.
So let's start from.
All right,
So tell us about the about the name
of your dog.
I have a bird.
Me or bin.
I need to.
Two birds. Lexi.
So the name of the dog
is mixed.
Okay, so now we are.
I have all got.
Maybe you can try to create objects
out of your your kids.
So in here, guys.
So in here we are now actually specifying
how a certain thing looks like, right?
If you see this dog, all the dogs,
they have some kind of names,
they have breed and they have colors.
They have height, age, gender. Right.
But when we create an object
out of a class,
we tell the actual physical objects
how that thing looks like in real life.
All right, So let's define it
and define more attributes.
So now we are assigning actual
attributes to
the object that we have created
from that class.
Okay.
So tell us about the breed of your dog
mixed
in the standard American.
Okay.
And then, oops,
I should say last dogs dog.
Okay,
so now we have defined the breed as well.
Okay.
And then let's define the color,
because there is the owner is female.
There have been color.
Well, what is the color?
I don't know.
Black.
Okay.
And then maybe define
the height
to be 2.5 or something.
I need another number.
And does it need to be in order? No.
The manner it does not need to be non
not. It may be ten years.
Okay.
So gender is equal to
and okay.
So have you guys defined all of your dogs
how your dogs look like?
What are their names,
What are their colors?
Height and everything.
I know it's my dog
these days you buy in is the thing here.
We went to position number seven,
right with this number
seven or six, I guess in the last week.
I am following along
as I don't have a dog.
It's fine.
It's impolite.
You are also an interpreter.
If we need one for our class,
I can buy two.
It did go up 4.5.
It even appeared with this.
We actually do buy a top.
Oh my God.
How many years you are into crypto
thinking of crypto?
24, seven, five months.
And that's why you did this.
I am like a stranger today.
I said we are talking talking
about cryptocurrency again.
That cryptocurrency is built
using programing
where you buy a few by Coinbase not allow.
I know nothing
of the everyday
for those who are new or those who are
in the crypto for one year.
I will suggest to you
to only start with $100
and after one year don't price.
Nothing is going anywhere after one year.
Once you have learned
all of that, do
this.
It happens.
All right, guys.
So now we have assigned bad reviews
now where you can get the values
of those attributes.
Why at a public class
model,
when you are defining
a class inside a class.
So when you define a class, inside
a class, yes, it is allowed,
but you cannot have two public classes
in a single file.
That's why you are getting an error.
So only one class, only one public class,
but qualified.
So now you have assigned the attributes.
You can also print these out.
So let's say I can say
why? What am I
doing wrong?
So Maria
and here
make sure that the spellings are correct.
Make sure you don't have color inside
your class.
You have colors variable. So
and both these type of issues
in this portion of
the classes there, he will help you out
there.
Show me my name,
your show me your dog class.
Okay, then let me go to this board
and see
what quickly
you guys can use the other active.
We are accessible.
Do you guys see the artwork?
Like I see.
So what we are doing
first we created a class,
then we created an object from that class
we assigned values to the properties
and now we are simply accessing
those properties.
Okay, so let's create one more object
out of this same exact dog class.
Okay,
So I will again say the name of the class
and this time
who else Will said that they have a dog
are Well,
okay, let's create a
give me you are the next
question.
You are next.
Next. Go with that. Yes.
We will create the cat as a next to
give me this dog this time.
Okay so and equal to sign
new favor.
And then again
the name of the class, the parentheses.
And in here.
So give me more.
What is the name of your dog?
So give me this dog, not name
I want to get Who can help me do
and then we can see him is
not read
is equal to
or this degree to give me
my dogs
Labrador
and then
I'll okay,
actually let me look you guys
the older I am then this should be color
inside instead of colors.
This should be colors. So
I will be so if I
can this color in here,
you guys will notice
that I will get an ETA
on line 23 and on line 11.
Right.
Because I have changed the name
in in the class
from which I am creating the objects.
Okay.
So if you guys don't
want to get these errors,
okay, you can right
click on it.
And then there should be an option.
Read that and then rename.
Okay.
And now
I don't know
why that option is not working,
but it will.
It should change
the names
in here automatically
when you change the variable name in here.
Okay, so color is golden,
so let me do it manually.
I have 2 seconds of same
clips like me.
No, the XP. I Can
you do it again?
Okay.
So I have changed because I miss
I misspelled
the color two colors,
so I have changed it back to color.
So I change it in here
and then I change it in here and in here.
So every year we are.
I'm using this property in my code.
I have to change that name
on all those places.
Should we change it as well? Yes,
you guys should change that.
It will be better.
So instead of colors,
make you guys everywhere, you have.
Oh yes.
I shouldn't change it in here.
Okay, now
it's just a just a change of variable.
Nothing special.
If you guys want,
you can keep it as colors.
All right, So let me assign more values
to the attributes. So.
All right, give me
what is what is the height of your dog
standing up?
Yes, you can tell us.
Standing of height
five feet the last five.
And then you can have
it, what,
five feet
standing on two legs. I
so and then gender five years old.
Okay, so
is not it if you guys are creating a class
that grouping of objects of that class
and assigning the values
can we combine
object and class in one file?
Yes, we can do that as well.
I would show you that at the
idea.
Guys done writing the score,
Is it a dog or the
other?
Let let's try to access these properties
as well.
Okay.
Let's start with this property.
Actually, let me let me copy this called
and instead of alone as dog,
what I will do, I will replace this object
feature
mentioned in the class,
but we need to specify all of them.
No, we don't.
So let's say, for example,
we can and we can only at this age
we can just age.
So I am replacing
the object in here. Okay.
So once I replace this object,
now I will see all the values
that are assigned
using this object.
So if I a security score, So let me know
if you guys see a different output
or if you don't see the output
that you have assigned in here
ordered a change.
So I copied this call from here
and then I change the object in here.
So this is a class we had.
We define the properties.
This is where
and this is how we create an object
and this is how we assign the values
to the
to those properties.
Previously we were calling variable.
Now we call object.
So you get that
if yes, we we use
this terminology interchangeably, but
when the data type is a primitive,
we call it a variable.
When the data type is a class
we create, we call it
an object.
Okay, if you want to be more specific,
but you can use it interchangeably,
your also fine.
It did not print the I and T
because I removed that
I didn't assign the value.
And if you guys tried to print
the value of edge,
you will be getting the default value.
So what is the default
value of an integer variable?
Right.
If I don't assign a value to the integer
if there's zero,
so do you guys will be getting a zero.
Okay, let's last it
this last dogfighter
out of a negotiation.
So again,
name of the class that I still forget.
We have to create a separate class. Okay.
Although a lot of the features
they are similar in cats and dogs.
Okay.
But logically
we should be creating a different forget.
Okay. Yes.
There are a lot of features
which are common in cats and dogs,
but there are differences as that.
Okay, me?
Yes, and all combined.
So again, how do I create an object?
I write the name of the class, right?
And you name
for that class.
Okay.
And then equal cosine, then new keyword
and then
these parenthesis and
moreover,
what is the name of their dog books?
Not Name
Melanie for gender.
You missing
in any of the classes?
They had an escort and a post posting.
This person
or mandrill,
If I am pronouncing it right,
it and let's say
we are now we want to define
only only this name property.
Okay, so we got we can also do this.
Define one property.
All of the property is
50% of the properties.
So it's all possible. Okay.
And now we can print this out,
not spell
our first name, and
we'll get
you have to use this name as
like this.
Okay.
No duplicates here, guys.
Only love.
Well, all.
All right,
So now let's try to
let's try to create a class for cars,
okay?
Because dogs and cats,
they are very similar.
So I want to give you a different example.
So this time next year,
let's try to create a car class.
Okay.
So are you guys done writing this code?
Can you print all of them?
Yes, we can print all of them.
If you want.
You can just print out statements
just adding plus
then we debug the dog.
Yes, we can debug the dog.
Okay, so let me get
a class
and let's call it a car.
Okay.
Everything works.
That's great.
All our guys tell me about
some properties of cars,
some features of car cars
make model right so we can have the make
or we can have an auto
part again.
Woops.
Or you can have a color.
We can have an easier right and easier
for fast and furious
country mileage.
Yeah.
So So these are some of the properties
so sorry for the.
All right
so these are some of the properties
that that cars cars have.
Yes. In our real life cars,
they have a lot of properties,
but we will not be going
through all of those properties.
Okay.
We are
we are keeping these examples very simple.
So this time let's create
the main method
and the object inside the same class.
Okay.
So if you want to do that,
you have to define the mean method.
Okay, so you write main,
then you hit control and space,
and then you should write the main
method for you.
Are you guys able to write the main
method using the shortcut
and just write mean any and mean
and then hit control plus space
or typing manually.
If it is not working for you, write
it manually
formatted command
plus space.
All right.
So now you guys will tell me how can I
create the object from this car class?
So the main method now stays there
or could go up?
Yes, you guys can use that.
You can write this
main method in here as well if you like.
Okay.
But it is a common practice to foster
define the attributes
and then by the matters.
Okay.
So we will be following that convention.
All right.
So you said common plus space
command plus space,
but the attribute should not be inside
the method.
Yes. The attributes should
not be inside the method
bar not make.
So no, it's not correct.
I am asking you,
how can create object of this class.
So for the hard you are close
but not correct here with Aleksey.
So God I shall ask God
then equal to sign nil keyword.
And then again name of the class
but with parentheses.
Right.
Okay.
Please explain.
What does main method is in this content?
Nabeel This main method is in
behavior in this class.
Okay, so this is how we define behavior.
The next after the break
I will teach you how to write a behavior
in a class as
All right,
So I write the name of the class.
All right?
And then
I just start
is equal to nil.
And are we doing two in one file?
Yes, All one.
This is what you were asking of you.
How to define
a class and how to clear the objects
inside the same class.
Okay.
So you guys can create objects
inside the same class
by having the main method
in the same class.
Or you can create a new class
and then you can define the attributes,
You can define the objects.
But remember that this
this approach is better approach.
This is how you will be doing it
in real life
work.
This is also possible.
We just combined two classes.
No, we didn't combine two classes and
we are creating the objects of a class
inside this same class.
It looks like just a scanner.
It's not like a scanner.
A running scanner is a separate class.
So this example looks like
a scan of the dogs.
Example
Odd dream
God, new pod.
Here we have the main
method at the bottom of our class.
Yes, it's a good practice
to have the main method at the bottom,
but you guys can have many method at.
The top as the
our shots are
not made.
Is that slow, let's say.
Okay.
And the model is
more or less.
Can I borrow your.
You guys now know how to create
jobs, airplanes, anything.
You guys can create anything.
Not using programing
color
is the same
as say
I am only defining these properties
in here
on the edge.
Are we for girls?
And then I can
I can define and print out is value.
Okay. And
and we can have
any Tesla fighting dog what if.
Well I don't do nothing
getting a job inside Tesla
and then buying a Tesla. The
some of the students from previous batches
they got their jobs in Amazon Tesla
and ended up
disqualified
from the final interview in Microsoft
and some of them
they are supplied in Apple and everywhere.
So if you guys are working hard,
you guys can go
for many of these companies.
Oh, by the way, I forgot
to invite the student from
from previous badges
so that they can share their experience
about making this bootcamp and
getting a job
and how they are doing in on their job.
So this Saturday I will
I will to invest in my total
three students from the previous batch.
My cousin is working for Amazon,
excavated, so this is what they tell me.
So they tell me that
when I used to tell them
the previous restaurants
that I used to tell them that you guys
will be getting jobs in big companies
and all that they did.
They did. They didn't used to believe me.
So I hope that most of you
are from referrals, right?
So you already know someone who took
this bootcamp and who is who has a job.
Now, why didn't I?
So, Emily, you are not from a referral
like this.
I am not from that. So.
So not very.
I will invite a lot of students
from previous batch.
One batch is not very
many people were writing a lot of people
or not very.
I will invite
ex coworker and it's all being made.
All right. So
I only
Sebastian is multitalented, but
so now let's try to execute
this new software and you guys
should get something like this.
You guys get this output this
going to.
Yeah.
So this is how we the
the objects inside this
same class.
Is it hard disk,
Is it hard to create a class
and then object?
There is no sound coding.
Please turn off.
Okay.
We will be going on a break Aisha.
And after the break we will define
how defined the
behaviors as then
we when
someone is singing.
Actually, he is not singing.
There is a mosque.
Yes. Next to my room.
Yes. That's
why you guys hear these sounds.
All right, guys.
So let's have a break
of 15 meters.
And after the break,
we will learn how to define data
on behaviors in a class as that.
And remind me about it.
You guys hear about why games
and doping bump from 0.0 to 2.8
and then was named as them. All
our guys remind me about the recording.
Last batch is invited for morning session.
I will invite them on Saturday or Sunday's
class.
Okay.
All right.
Let me start the game.
Okay.
I have talked to four student
from batch nine and two of them, they
have responded.
They will be joining us on Saturday.
So seriously.
Question
If we have object in in the same class,
can we call that class
outside the package?
If you mean by calling the class
outside of the package,
if you mean creating the objects, yes,
we can do that.
But there is no thing
as calling a class outside the package.
So we create objects of the from the class
and then
we assign the properties
and we call matters on, on, on an object.
So let me know if this is what you meant.
So, for example, if your question is
maybe, let's say in class four,
can I create the object of this car
inside this package
four or package three or this class?
So yes, we can.
How about the attributes?
Yes, we can do any everything that we are
doing in here, in any of the packages,
no issues,
getting an object of accessing the fields.
There are rules.
Yeah. That we will learn later.
There are things that
differ from one package
to another, package
that we will learn later. But yes, we can.
We can clear the objects
and we can call the methods and properties
for now.
Sound LLC.
You don't hear me
already, guys.
So let's try to define some behaviors.
Or what are the things that the cops do.
Then you add like this.
Yes, we can add like this.
Okay.
Cars, they can move forward.
Right?
So to define guys,
this is how we define and define behavior.
So before defining any behavior,
we would write this keyword wide.
Okay, We define this keyword wide.
Then the name of the behavior,
then parentheses.
Okay.
And basically, okay,
this is how we define a behavior
and we can clean out for now,
to keep things simple,
I am simply printing out line.
Wait, what did I miss?
Can you please repeat that?
Okay, so now we are learning
how to define
behaviors as well inside a class.
Okay, so previously
we learned how to define properties
like attributes, how to define some,
how something looks like.
Now we are defining how that thing
behaves in our real life.
Okay, What what are the things that this
this class can do?
Okay, so to define a behavior or what
that class can do,
we write this void keyword.
Okay, then name of the behavior.
So parents is
opening a bracket, closing bracket,
and then we can write any logic in here.
We can write loops or we can declare at
is pretty much everything
that you guys have learned
you can do inside a method,
but to keep things simple,
I am simply printing out
a line in here.
Is it clear me now?
So now we are defining the behavior so
how we use void Move forward in
logic. In our logic.
Okay.
What is to defining the behavior
of the class?
Yes, there are two types of behaviors.
One one.
One of them
they once they are done behaving,
they give us the response back.
Okay?
And the other behaviors,
they don't give us the response back.
So those who don't give us the response
back,
we use this wall keyword.
The other ones we will learn later.
Okay, For now,
just focus on how to define it.
Behavior, this word keyword,
what it does, where you should use it.
I will teach you all about that.
Move forward is not a keyword.
What do you mean by a keyword?
It is just a name you can give.
You can give this behavior any name. And
have you guys define
just behavior.
Okay.
So this is how we call this behavior.
So we write the name of the object.
So I just off dog.
No it.
Okay, so dog
and then name and then parentheses.
And now if I execute this code. Yes.
So I can see God can move forward in here.
Or maybe can see,
maybe you can see
moving forward.
Okay. So God is now moving forward.
So if I execute it again.
Okay. Moving forward.
So when when you call this behavior,
so this is what
we call as calling the methods or,
calling the behavior.
So we write the name of the object, a dog
sign, then name of the behavior.
Okay.
We say that we are calling the move
forward behavior on line 24.
Okay. On the I God object.
These
these are just some of the terminology.
So I am calling move forward the behavior
on I shall God object.
But yes, it's monthly monthly.
Write these lines
whatever logic we do so in Java executes
Java executes from top to bottom, right.
So it will declare this,
it will declare this, this, this.
Then it will print out this.
And once we call the method
Java goes inside this method,
whatever we have written in here, Java
first executes that and then it goes.
It comes back in here
and then keep on executing whatever
quotable you have to do.
Do you guys see this output?
So why is line pull not printed
non line printed?
You know, this is line ten
moving forward
and I see this line moving forward.
What do we mean by behavior?
So by behavior mean
what are the things that an object can do.
Okay so what are
what are the physical actions
that that class, that object can do?
We always
have to call the behavior at the end.
No, you can call the behavior
at the start.
Like you can call the behavior
right after declaring the object.
You can call the behavior multiple times
because we meant was,
is it an action? Yes.
These are actions actually, that all that
that those objects can perform.
How many behaviors?
We can write as many as we want.
And there is a limit of around
65,000 or something like that
for 32 bit systems,
and it's double for 64 bit systems.
So you guys can have thousands
of behaviors, no issues
with that.
Let's ask as many questions as you have.
Is calling a method is like calling
for a subroutine. Yes.
Maybe in some programing languages,
we call it a subroutine
in assembly languages
under the
what if I want to add another B of it?
Yes, you can add another behavior.
So let's say, for example,
I can have a behavior
apply breaks
if so, we can start it God again.
We can stop it.
God, we can move it or God forward.
We can move where we are backward.
We can apply the brakes,
all of the actions that a car
can do, we can define those behaviors.
Do we have to use the word
for every behavior?
No, we don't have to use word
for every behavior.
You guys will learn different types
of behavior
later on.
I ask a question like that.
You and the behavior
cannot be in many matter.
Yes, it cannot be in main method.
No, We have to be separated like that.
Maryland.
What do you mean by separated like that?
You mean these these matters?
They are outside of other methods.
Can we combine two or more in one?
Yes, we can combine two or more in one.
So for example,
you can call this move forward.
I don't want to go into these details now
and then can you part of this question
for our two classes.
But yes, we can do that.
We can combine,
but I don't want to confuse confusion.
That's why let's not go into there.
Any other questions, guys?
So now I can
I can call the other behavior.
Okay.
We can move it forward, backward.
We can apply it.
Every method has is on curly
brackets. Yes.
Every method has its own curly brackets
and y to know
some other methods,
they will be having something different.
So you're going to see this
man also has this word.
Okay.
But there there are other types of methods
who will be having something different
than the word
23 and 30 is same
going to be and 30 same.
Aleksey, can you elaborate a little bit?
What do you mean by same?
Oh, you mean
I am calling the same behavior again?
Yes, we can do that.
I can call in method
109,000 and all restrictions on that.
I can call a method inside the loop
current one time.
Oh no, it is not printing one time.
Actually, I have not expanded this output.
So you see moving forward in here
and moving forward again in here,
I want to see the two behavior of syntax
to behavior.
Syntax
I What do we mean by two behavior?
It will not print again and again.
No, it will print again and again
for you.
You mean this?
You can you can call this behavior
inside another behavior.
This is what I meant.
So you guys can also do this.
So can you guys.
Now tell me if I execute this move forward
behavior?
Well, what are what I will see.
So let me command this out.
Let me go mark this out.
So I will see moving forward
and then I will see apply breaks.
Okay.
So moving forward and then apply brakes
if I call this move forward method once.
Okay, So I can change these matters
one method inside another method
and then start another method
again.
All right.
That's not less.
I don't understand.
So I like the
inside this move forward.
The method we are calling
this apply breaks method.
Okay,
so the behavior cannot be inside
the main cannot be inside of this method.
So now we are getting the output
moving forward and applying brakes
when we call this move forward method
and index what we are discussing in here.
So we are calling only mode forward,
but we are getting both the outputs.
Okay.
Next, what happens if we call
a method inside and it doesn't matter?
Yes, we will be doing
many different examples.
Don't worry about it. Back
then you make separate class for behavior.
Yes, we can make a separate class
or behavior.
Behavior has its own W brackets.
Can we put the two behavior in one note?
We cannot go back
defining method inside
another method is not allowed.
What do we can call a method inside
another method?
So for example, if I if I copy
and if I paste it in here,
I will get an error.
So this is what we call
defining a method inside another method.
This is not allowed, but
we can call a method inside.
Another method
we cannot define, but we can call.
And you guys now know what happens
then We call it method inside.
Another method, all those lines of code
that are written inside this apply text.
They will be executed
when you will be calling to move forward.
So let's do another example
and you guys can keep on
asking the questions if you have any.
So let's
how did you play?
Did you place apply brakes
inside the first ward?
So I just write, I just wrote
apply Brakes Fantasy and Semicolons.
Can we create behaviors in one line?
Yes. Or one is possible
using functional programing.
I will show you a little bit
about the functional programing as well.
If we are left with something,
mine is read I up.
Can you share the screenshot?
But let's create a class.
Okay.
Or let's create a human class.
Let's stick to the class.
Otherwise we will be confused.
No, don't worry.
Shit, I will not be from now on.
I will not be showing the things
that are not supposed
to be taught in this class
and are planned for the next classes.
What is the difference
in line 13 and 18? Then
we go to line 13
and line 18.
So Nyah, in here we are defining a method.
Okay.
And in here we are calling it method.
When we define a method,
we evaluate a piece of logic
and when call a method
that logic is executed.
So if you only define a method, nothing,
you will see nothing on your consort.
You will only see
the code is only executed
when you call a method
and to call a method inside a class.
We write the name of the method and
these bénin pieces and these semicolon.
So we don't need to call after main class
or in main class.
Yes, we can call in the methods
that were nice if this is
what is confusing you.
So that's why I was not showing you this.
That's why.
I don't want to show you this.
So let's forget about that.
Why is it printing two times?
Because you you are you are calling
a method inside another method.
Okay.
And then remove that call from here
and you will not see two outputs.
But then there are a remote
that call on line 13.
We move applying braids
and you will not see it again.
Please explain line 11 and 15
if you can line 11 this one in line
15, this one.
So in here it is.
In here we are defining the behaviors
to define a behavior
we write this word keyword,
name of the behavior, parentheses,
and then curly brackets.
And inside.
And here we can write
any piece of code, any logic, any loops.
Add is variables, print after anything
that you like to put in here.
And once you call this behavior,
all that code
will be executed.
And this is how we call it behavior.
Is it clear Now, guys,
if you
guys still have questions, please ask.
Don't worry.
There are no dumb questions.
If things don't make sense at one splice
twice, it's also perfectly fine.
You can ask me to repeat them again.
So this is what happens.
Guys and
humans,
they can not focus
more than 45 minutes.
Okay, So even if you try your best
after four or 5 minutes,
you will not be able to focus.
So you will be missing
a lot of information.
So you guys can ask me again
if you have missed
some information,
maybe a part comes in your mind,
maybe something disrupts you,
but make sure that you stop me right here.
Don't do this.
Let's say, for example, I am explaining
something for the last 15 minutes,
and after 15 minutes you ask me to repeat
whatever I have been doing in 15 minutes.
If something is not clear,
stop me right there.
Okay?
Or Tell me the line
number which is not behave
that way.
We will not be wasting the times of others
who are paying attention.
I think
word can be if as if
no ward can cannot be effective.
But inside, while
we can have intelligence, no questions.
Now I will have million questions
when I try to do it myself.
So I know you are not following me.
Well, you are only watching, watching me.
All right. That's good. Yes.
You guys can ask me questions later
on today.
So let's do one more example next.
So I have created this human class.
Okay?
Now you guys will help me define the
attributes of humans
and the behaviors of humans.
What is the difference
between method and behavior?
In some places you are method
and in some places be they are same.
Obviously are same.
Let's make the perfect man then.
That's not possible.
Okay,
let's let's start from simple things.
Like humans, they have names
and then we can have age.
We can have
I can wear
you can have all gender.
We can have race and color.
Let's let's not go into these things.
Blood type. Yes.
The type is also an attribute. So
but like
many other attributes of humans
LLC, for example,
tell me about the behavior of guys.
What do what do humans do?
The simplest behaviors, simple behaviors
I thing is coming to my mind,
but I would not bet
so humans they
they eat right
fight war, cry, study, blah blah, blah.
Okay, so one more thing, guys.
So this is something that is new.
Okay, So I again, I can use
an attribute inside
in methods so I can say name
use a lot of
and then I can have
my sleep
investing wrong
is the name
is me being
we don't need after a while. Yes.
So this is semicolon Emily.
We near the semicolon
once we end a statement
and by end a statement, I mean something
that can produce
an output.
Something that can that
in which we assign something
like, for example,
this assignment operator.
So in here,
when we would define a matter,
we would not need to send out semicolons.
Like, for example,
we don't need to semicolon in here, okay?
Because it's not a statement.
All right, guys.
So then we can have a or
space before needs, right? Yes.
We are talking in number.
Okay.
So we can use all of the attributes
from our class inside the behavior.
So like I am using name
and here using blood type in here.
Yes. Now let's create
the human.
Okay.
And in here we will be creating the main
method so I can be gone.
I will take this checkmark
and we open side by side.
So you can you please?
Yes, sure.
How many of you will be done
with your projects by tomorrow?
Because I am planning
to show you this solution in models
class.
Not here the first part yet.
We also deadline is 6 p.m.
doing all
so make sure guys
you complete the project by 6 p.m.
tomorrow because I will be showing
the distribution in the next class.
Some work done, almost done will be done.
All right.
That's great.
We had we had a do
you guys can push it to the gate hub.
Daniel, please go back for a second.
Now, do you want me to go back to the
car class or the class
Human class?
I have opened both of them side by side.
It is the human class.
The last line
is it readable, default?
Is it readable? Guys
illustrative of the industry?
It really was intending
to send X student Yes.
Or one.
You guys have to send the links
in the same text
that we don't guys want.
You have this for
since we shared
weird software
field, one member posted it all in one.
No, everyone should push it.
I want you to have practice.
All of you.
I want you guys to have practice
pushing people
to the gear tab.
All right, guys.
So tell me,
how can I clear the object of human?
Let's say I want to build them on
into using Java.
I was. I need help pushing.
If you guys need any help,
you guys can posting this for General
and I was I was wasn't
human
so I will be writing the name of the class
right then the name of the object
I cannot name anything
than equal to sign then new.
Right?
And then
again name of the class
and that entity right
then using the object.
This, this, this.
Then he throws
someone, send YouTube videos on.
So don't send a lot about.
All right, guys.
So I will say
I use the name of the object.
Then I can access the property
by writing dog.
Okay?
And then I can see
someone under
age 16.
All right.
Good battles about always 16 and
one on the right.
Right is five four,
I guess I it
okay.
Okay.
So we are building building Miss Universe
in here, right?
And ideal. Ideal
rate for girls.
If 30 if I am not wrong
and then
I can say it online or
then the 3030
and then
I'm on one dog
blood type
principle to a positive.
So this is how we access the properties
and if we want to call the behaviors,
then we will save it and got it.
Okay, We can see
when to sleep
and then, yeah, can you guys now,
are you guys able to relate this
how we are building
things that exist in real life
using inside our computers?
Can you guys relate these
to things that they make sense?
And I am about to disappear.
So other than the appearance,
so we are not touching the appearance
here, other than appearance,
the attributes, the properties,
the behaviors,
we are defining all those things in here,
the appearance is done
with the help of graphic designers,
so they build a character
like, for example, in games,
they build a character,
then they combine this logic
with that character,
and that's how you see those characters
moving
and behaving and all of those in games
that.
So we will be writing logic
most of the time.
Can we use loop to connect to all void?
You mean
can we use a loop to call all the methods
among?
Yes, we can use a loop, but still
we have to type the names of the methods.
Okay.
So the
there is no point of using a loop. Yes.
If you want to call these methods
multiple times,
then you should use the loop.
But there isn't.
There is no mechanism that
you can call all the methods from a class.
Okay.
There is something called as a reflection,
but that is something that we are lost
and we will not be going
to that we will not be learning that.
All right. So do you guys see this output,
Dom or not?
It's a lot of nice sleeping in the blood
type is walking.
So this name that we have used
inside these behaviors.
So this is what is happening.
So we create an object in here.
We assign a name.
So once we assign a name,
this name is actually assigned
to this variable.
Okay?
And wherever
now you will be using this variable.
So let's say, for example,
I use this variable in here.
You will see this name in here.
That's why.
That's why you see this this name
with this output.
Okay? And it depends on the object.
If you create a different object,
then a separate copy of this class
will be created out of that object and
separate values will be assigned to that.
Okay, So let's say, for example, if we
if we give ear loops, we do.
Sebastian
So if we create a Sebastian, we use new
and then
Sebastian you also want to be 16 years old
saying
it's out is always in class.
Are you can put your guitar, you can put
anything to keep things simple.
I am using, I'm using printouts.
You guys can write any logic in here.
I can make word in class pasta.
Yes, you can.
You can make methods in here as well.
This is also class.
Now we have to create some new means.
Yes. Let's create a standard in here.
Okay.
So. Or
that means
okay.
And in here now we you need
because Dom or not or the other person,
they may not send any names.
Right.
So now we can use
and if condition in here we can say if
name la equals
Sebastian,
then only we send
like this.
So this is how you guys can put more
and more logic in here
to define certain specific
behavior for, certain objects.
Okay, so name
and sure,
we like this, right?
It should be a
all looks good now
so human not name.
If it is a question.
Right. Why? Why?
I'm getting an error
spelling.
Right.
So a lot of you are making spelling
mistakes in the sports channel.
So this is the reason that you guys
are getting those issues.
And then I can see
in or image
Sebastian 16 years or 1818
like million time
in my last error.
What about the height?
So sometimes I simply say
extra
and got
weird.
Okay, let me guess.
We're wrong from the picture that you have
on your profile.
So it's in kids
eight is more than 80,
maybe around 400.
It is
for 25
and then
not allowed to drink
alcohol.
Why 100? Could not be.
You guys can use Elvis as well,
because I am an engineer
and engineers, they use different systems.
So that's why my my units, they
they will be different always.
I will be using kilometers far distance.
And then kids are weird normal systems.
You mean
there was this joke
that it'll take 40 years
for the person to be an engineer,
and once he's an engineer, he can.
He can never be a person again, human
again, not age.
It should be
like I
mean, and guys, if I.
If I call this send means on someone. Now
what will happen,
What are what I will get days
then work it to LP.
Yes you guys can define different
different things.
You can have another property
in which you will be defining the
and the eunuchs.
Okay. Nothing.
And what if I call this
method on Sebastian object?
So if I execute this, it will say
sending me.
So let me let me looking
out these methods with
so we see on the left
me putting out some training so
that you can really differentiate in here.
Okay so all the outputs for Sebastian,
all the outputs.
Okay.
So this is how you define real life kings
in computers using programing.
Can you roll it down?
I want take notes, please. In.
You mean this class cities?
This one.
Is it better now
let me know
if you guys have any questions
or something.
Is not working out getting any errors.
So whatever is before
the sunbeams gets into
whatever is did before? No, no, no.
Because We are calling these matters.
That's why it is being printed.
Sebastian is sleeping years a lot older
because we have all these methods.
That's why we see them.
I'll put into fast system dart out
How fast?
What do you mean?
You to print at the speed of 247 means
flock.
Now can you elaborate a little bit?
What what do you want to ask about
send means
six out control plus space or
so Alexi You mean how to type it fast
and really.
Oh yeah.
So you can type S out
and then you can use control plus space.
I may ask how do you use send means?
I am calling this
to send me in here partner
on the Sebastian object and on this
and inside this send means I written some
extra logic.
That logic is checking
if the name of the object is Sebastian.
Then only print out sending means
why If does not play into Sebastian
is because of the.
Let me check if you have used the
it is printing.
Sending means
it is printing to sending means
on on on the console.
The last line is saying sending means
that he
means
Elena.
But what I you always get at is
com load plus 11 human log log
not to any the complete error.
I don't know it's one it's fine
you will get used to it
Lloyd
all because you are missing
that closing bracket
Melanie online 20 after the semicolon
you see in here after this log
I have this closing calibrator.
Then I am typing the next method.
Okay, then that's why you are getting that
that why the name it didn't print
or the name it
must have our because we are not
using them in any print out statements.
We are not using them in any method that
that's why they are not being printed.
If you want to print you can,
you can write this out and then can look
at those attributes in there
and then they will be printed out
maybe in another package.
Yes, we will do that.
Other permitting look, not now.
Why sending names printed 11
Sending this printed first.
It is not printed first Silva.
It is printed at the last same sequence
as I am
keeping as I am calling these methods.
Oh, because you are calling it first,
you see online,
it's line 30, I guess you are calling this
and the means first.
Next slide is being printed net
plus if you call this at the last
like me after these three calls,
then you will be seeing cannot last.
My Sebastian,
don't print.
Oh because you are not calling the methods
and see you are not calling the meters
silver.
Is it clear like Z and silver?
Is it clear now
that if there are other questions,
please ask.
These are
some things
that you guys will be using a lot.
So I want
I want every one of you to be super clear
on these things. Why,
yes, that's a
good idea.
To recap
why it is not printing age weird and high.
So Farhad, it's not printing it
and high again, all that
because neither we have use this age
or height or anything inside this method,
nor we are using any printouts in the
in the main method.
That's why I would not see them.
So let's say if you want to printout the
it right, So either you have to
write a printout in here,
then you have to write Sebastian
not age,
then you will see it,
then you will see it.
Or you have to put this image in here
inside some of these methods.
Then it be printed out.
Why? It's like, and I need them
in this plan, but hard, silly
standing means is not printing
in my console.
If name is
equals Sebastian.
So your s he not your s is capital
on line 21 inside the main method,
but the s
inside of your method online 25 is a law s
so the Java is case sensitive.
Make sure you guys are using
same cases in your methods
and in your
when you are defining something
and when you are assigning something,
let me know if it.
Let's make sure that
the s in here and the s in here.
They are same
same here, same here.
So I love you guys.
Please make sure that the spellings
and then the syllabus change.
They have same
and let me know if it's if it is also
the issue.
Yes, we can print
it out in separate system of all together.
Yes, we can print it out
and all together on different
I am confused output on
console is printing to the object tab
or class tab so you'll get to the output
being printed from this main method.
Okay. We are.
We are calling these matters,
but how that output will look like
it is defined inside this class.
Okay.
You can start typing
the name press control space
and it looks all clear to create a class
and then all that property will be here.
We are just wondering
how will we use these in our programs?
So, Ammad,
you guys will be combining all the logics,
using these classes.
So you remember back to scanner class
that scanner class has specific
behaviors, right?
And you use that scanner class
for taking pictures
of the input booleans as the input.
Other things you write the matters.
So you develop these to these small units
in the form of letters.
You write logic in pieces.
You combine those pieces
in a logical entity
that is called a class.
You declare some variables
called as properties, hold
some values inside the class.
Then you build this a unit of class,
you build
objects out of that class
and you use in your code.
I guess it's a way of grouping
those smaller pieces first,
dividing the task into smaller pieces,
writing the code for smaller pieces,
then logically combining them
so that you guys can remember
easily can organize your code easily
inside big classes and use that.
And those logics,
those features, properties and matters
by creating the objects and then calling
those methods of properties.
So if you guys,
if you guys want to see a real life
example of how you can use these classes.
So I will suggest you to look at that
standard class
because you guys are already familiar
with the scanner class.
So if you, if
you type this.
Yeah.
Okay. So
it's systematic.
Okay, registration purposes,
if we have upper or lower class,
is it going to give an error?
Yes, it will.
It not it will not give you an error,
but it will not work.
So we write on main method
and we print on class, right?
We call inside the method
and we define inside the class.
These are the proper terminologies.
I think we will understand
when we need to use that logic.
You guys will understand
next 3 to 4 classes.
Don't worry about that.
Is it possible to create class inside
another class?
Yes, So we can do that.
But I will not be showing you that
right now.
So, guys, this scanner is also a class.
So what you guys have been doing,
you guys have been creating the objects
of, this kind of class and then calling
different behaviors on this kind of class.
So if you want to check
how those behaviors are defined,
you can hold down your control button
on your keyboard
and you can click on this class.
If You do. So
Eclipse will Eclipse will take you
inside this scanner class.
Okay, we are that class is defined.
So hold it on your control
and then click on scanner
the name of the class
and me know if you guys
see this class or not.
Now I am showing you
the real life examples
ordered down
your hold on your control
or command button.
If you are on the Mac and click on
with your mouse
right on it. No.
Amid these classes they are written
by Java guys and they are read only.
You cannot change them.
Let me know once you guys see this class.
So yes.
So you guys will see a lot of errors.
You guys will learn
almost about all of these killers.
Okay, So don't worry about them.
So just focus on
this name of the class, okay?
And then you guys will see
we are declaring many,
many variables in here match
integers, backgrounds, settings.
All of these are properties. Okay?
All of these are properties right
click and choose work.
Just just clicked in displayed on it.
Just click on it.
Hold on your control and just click on it.
Next. Yes.
So it is the left control plus left with.
It's not for looking for any
go back and do from previous.
Yes so So Eve, let me close this class.
If I hold down my control, see it changes
to this hand kind of icon.
Okay.
If I if I take my miles,
if I take my pointer
to the name of the class, it it to this
blue color
and it changes it to this hand like icon.
Once you see this.
Yes. Left click on it.
That's it.
Control Netflix.
Does it work now? Yes.
You can do the same with human class.
Any other class.
But they know it's still not working.
So if it is still not working,
I want you
to right click on your name of the class.
Looks like those
If it is still not working
right, click on the name of your class
and then click on this open declaration.
Okay, Right click on the name
of your class
and click on Open Declaration.
And you guys also see
the shortcut to S3 for me.
So you can click on
you can click F3 as the.
All right.
I hope everyone, everyone now see
saw not not found.
I said please post in this portion of what
will help you out.
Same here.
It's fine. Okay.
You guys just that's just like,
okay, you guys can visit it later.
Yeah.
So you're going to have to attach
the sources.
You can click on attach sauces
and then you have the, the diary,
and then you guys will be able to see it.
Okay. Georgiadis, this should be attached.
You can post in the sport journal,
the class will show you
how to address that but did find nice.
Just just watch or just walk in here.
Okay.
So this is this of class.
Okay. And in here these are
the properties, all the properties
you guys see
all the properties
are defined in here by Javabayes.
But this is how when you guys
will be solving a real life problem,
you will be logically first
dividing that problem
into different parts.
Each block will be a class.
Inside of that class,
You guys will further
divide
that problem into different behaviors.
These properties,
they will hold values for you.
So for example, you see in
we are holding Ben closed is fas
blah blah blah null.
So don't click anything.
Marla Just, just, just follow me.
Just walk in here.
So that's how you will be defining
different properties.
Then you guys will be defining
the behavior.
Okay, So still properties, properties,
so many properties.
Okay, Now don't be scared.
You guys will understand all of this.
So you see, this is how you guys are able
to be to be input
from your keyboard
by just writing the two lines of code.
Someone Else has written
thousands of lines and very complex
logics to make it happen.
Okay.
To be able to get the input
from the keyword and all that logic.
All that code is first group
in the form of a class.
They have given a name scanner
to that class.
Then they grouped all those logics
inside different methods,
betters, behavior, like for example,
if you have to take an integer output
an integer input from the keyword, right?
So you guys will find you see
all of this logic, all of this logic.
And inside
a class, inside this class there are
2000 hundred and 18 lines of code.
Okay?
And you guys can see
you can take next decimal in here
and let me find out
the next integer for you.
So here is your method.
So you get this next input.
You have only 138
lines of code first, then
let's make sure
you are inside the scanner class
that is defined inside the JDK.
Please do not scare us.
Who asked this question that that's
how we will be building the classes.
You guys please blame that That student.
Okay.
Don't blame me.
So this is the logic
to take
the integer inputs from the keyboard.
Okay.
And you call this method next integer.
You create the scanner object,
you call this scanner dot next and.
And that's
how with the help of this logic,
you guys are able to take the input
from the keyboard.
Now, all of the logic has been inside
this next integer method.
If you have to take a boolean, you have a
you have a separate method.
Okay, So let's say, for example,
and someone has written a lot before to
let me find it next
boolean.
Okay, here is the next boolean.
So again, someone has written some for me
inside different
different methods dividing the problem
further and divide and conquer.
Okay.
And then they have written different
different logics.
So right now we have learned a very simple
way of creating a class
and then defining a logic and,
then having a properties.
But I explicitly went
I intentionally ran to.
So you used those examples,
those simple examples.
But this is the goal.
This is what we will be doing
with the help of classes.
This is how you guys
will be building your frameworks.
Okay?
If You have to open a browser,
you will define a class, you will say open
browser class,
you will define a method, open Chrome,
open Firefox, open it, i.e.
Inside these
methods you will write logic
to open and Google Chrome.
Then you will write a method
to move to a specific website.
You will write a method
to click on different different buttons,
getting the output interacting
with that side.
That's how you guys will be building
your name books.
Yeah. So it's just a stock.
Is it clear
how you guys will be using these classes,
methods, properties
and so, so
don't worry,
you guys will start building
your framework after selenium.
So if just one month, then you please
show us again how to go in again
order to undo defined
command is control S or X control S?
Yes, I think so.
But my opinion going to blow up.
Don't worry, it will not blow up.
These are just dramas.
I know.
I did not go there.
One they do work in the
So you hold down your control
and then press f
I feel more relaxed today.
Thank you for going slow
and reading our questions.
No, don't worry
if you guys have any other suggestions
that you want me to do.
You guys can also tell me those ideas
and then I will try to learn concrete
from the next class.
Do other values complain to
or just us and these dramas?
Yes, everyone does knows
the industrial dramas.
Don't worry
all Bachi advice.
They used to tell me who was there.
We are about to jump from the window.
What you have shown us how we will
be able to do that blah, blah, blah.
All of them. They are doing their job now.
So after you press control F,
then you can type anything
that you want to search for on this file.
Okay.
And those
who are still unable to get in here,
let me close this.
So there are multiple ways you can right
click on the name of the class.
You can click on Open Declaration,
and then you guys should see
that class in here
is not
complex. Yes,
I need to place the part.
Yes, you guys need to place
the part of your JRD.
So you remember you guys installed
that in JDK in the start of Java classes.
So so for example, in our in Windows
and those so
most of you will be having your Java
inside C inside program files, then Java
and there you have basically
you have to give this part to the page.
So here you import scanner just to show us
then that have nothing to do
with the task of the amount.
Yes. And I, I'm just
use their standard
class to show you a real life example.
When I watched that YouTube video today
and the comments out there
that everyone was so happy with the video,
I thought I was the only one
who didn't look at it.
Yes, that's true.
Do you understand it now?
So now I want you to go back
and watch that video again.
And now everything will make sense.
Should make sense.
You saw that part. It's not that.
It's all about explaining.
So we have only the element of blooming.
That's
what I will be sharing.
B This slide
and the next ones for the next class.
And I want you to read those slides
before the class
and I will try to find it easier.
The videos from next time.
Okay, I will try to find easier videos
and we will recap this
class in all those lives in the
in the next class.
Okay. So don't worry
now. He was moving
for 10 p.m.
is the British
holidays.
If you have any questions
and post in the sports
channel and
I will be, make sure you complete
your project before tomorrow's class.
And from now on I will be sharing
videos and slides
at least
3 to 5 hours before the class,
although I will try to share them
one day before the class and
try to have a look
at those slides and videos.
We wish course to get out from this class.
Yes, from now on, all of you should push
all of the code to the GitHub.
Anyone knows how to look at program
files on Mac.
So I posted this for dinner.
Maybe a class knows
how to find out that
rule of five.
All our guys
take some of us and exploit it today.
I see you tomorrow.
Oh yes.
There are hundreds
of yes here are be homeless
let me poster of course announce
I have posted people out
homeworks and equals task one does
on our guys. Bye.
I take some of this
and board and push for will do today
I will be pushing all of the code
now when we start using intelligence
okay I will combine all the code
from all the classes.
I will push it on the Google on GitHub,
and then you guys will be able
to see all the codes on the data.
What is the due date for the task?
The due date is Saturday
this coming
Saturday.