How are you guys?
Morning. Morning. Hello, Oscar.
Nice to be here.
Thank you.
How do I feel?
This crowd is a little bit still hurting,
but my mind has recovered that
that's the most important thing.
So today
I will only confuse you 25% of the time.
75% of the time. Plus you go small.
Is that okay?
Warning everyone.
So I watched the recording
in the last class,
so I don't remember anything
from the last class.
But I what I read the comments from you.
So a lot of you were confused.
So I don't
I don't even remember how I treated you
in the last class.
25% of my brain
was working in the last class.
So in today's class,
we will fix that as well.
Good morning, Amar.
And hopefully it will be fine.
And by and by.
So in the last class, I.
I told you to forget
some things, right?
Some concepts.
So I hope by this time,
if one week you guys
have almost forgot everything.
Right?
So starting from scratch this time
you guys will not remember anything
about the ad at least right?
A Maybe this is a good point
to start again in big words.
So today's class number 27
ArrayList.
You mean
the Virgin?
Indeed. One month is too long.
Even if you try to read your code
that you have wrote like seven days
before, you will be in the same condition.
I was out of control last time.
You guys have forgot everything very easy.
By the way,
do you guys know how many classes,
how many more classes we have for Java?
You know, for
one month, two more classes,
and you guys are done with Java.
Hello, And thanks, God.
Thank God.
Wait, really, It.
I and I are.
I am much better now.
How long Next week
you guys will be done with Java
and then the fun part will start.
Now you guys will be putting your selenium
knowledge,
your Java knowledge,
and your testing knowledge
to kind of build a complete program
that can
test multiple tests on the website
that can check multiple things,
multiple features are multiple buttons,
drop dropdowns, and all of them,
if they are working fine or not,
that's hard to believe.
Two more and my head is still empty.
Nikolai, You are lucky
if you are headed empty.
Having all that knowledge in your brain,
it can make you sick really, really fast.
As a you, you are good.
You don't remember anything
about that yet.
Open to anything new?
Do they look like England?
Gentlemen
in as girl I.
I'm feeling much better.
Come on. Whatever.
You guys are not ready for this all.
By the way.
So I wanted to show this
for a very long time.
So you guys don't.
They don't remember.
Remind me about how to shift your project
from Eclipse to intelligence.
So today we're looking
at the star of the class from that.
So first, let me tell you how you guys
can use their weather.
Cold are not that cold around
10 to 15 degrees.
I don't know.
Let me actually check.
It's not that cold.
It's extremely
it's kind of kind of enjoyable.
But because because I am it's
cold.
I'm not feeling well.
That's why I am having this check.
That's not cold.
Like Washington. Yup.
So in Eclipse, if you guys remember,
you guys used to create a work space
and in, in the workspace,
you guys used to create multiple projects
in Eclipse, right.
And then you guys don't have to open
multiple windows
to switch back
and forth between your your project.
So be structure in intelligent
it's little bit
little bit different and
it can be different from 80 to 80.
So in an eclipse you guys used to have
work space,
but now but bad weather is coming.
Have you guys seen what happened in
okay Spirit a few hours ago?
Be safe all what happened there?
So the web, the workspace
in Eclipse, it is tornado.
It is equivalent to
a project
entirely
today
and today.
I will also show you
because Nas girl had this issue,
she lost all of her files and project.
So I will show you
if you guys lose anything
to how to get back
your your files and projects,
even if you don't have that
your repository if you have not posted
your code to that repository,
how you can still recover
your files and projects. So
if you
accidentally delete this, this dot
IBM ML file,
this is the file that keeps
track of your projects.
Okay.
This file is very important
for the
for the intelligent to work properly.
So this file is very important.
Don't make sure that you guys
don't delete this file
first thing you do this second thing.
If you guys check out this project,
that's what I did.
So second thing, this SDK batch 11,
it is stored inside this repository.
So inside this repository, Intel
will always look for this dot idle folder.
Okay, In here
it stores all of its important files
and product structures
and all other information related to
without spares,
how many modules and everything.
So these two things, this dot idea
and this image file, they are,
they are super, super important
for the intelligent to work properly.
I don't have that file.
Maybe it is hidden on moment
you are using windows are Mac.
It can
be in it can be anywhere inside this
this special
so it might be hidden on your on your Mac
and that's that's actually better
if that is here do not know the name.
Yes the name of that file will be
same as the name of your project.
So if you guys focus this
and this project name,
they are saying, okay,
so these are two very important things
for Idea Project for Intel Project.
And after that in delegate, you guys,
you guys can delete anything in here
inside South Florida.
No need to worry about that.
You just need to double click
on that file to open it.
You guys don't need to open it in.
Open it because even if you accidentally
change something, let's not open it.
You can have issues in your projects.
Okay, Next, let's not do that.
And so Delegate will always look
for a project structure like this.
There should be a folder
the same name folder
as your
your project.
Good morning.
Now and then inside that folder
there should be a
another folder
s r c and inside that your base package.
And then you can have oops
and then you can have your project.
So if I right click in here
and if I click on Open in Explorer
so Mac users,
you guys will see Opening Finder
or something like that.
Okay.
So if I click on that,
do you guys see this option?
so it will take me to the folder
where all of my other projects are saved.
Okay, so this is where Intel has stored
my aspect, but 11 project
Finder in Mac here.
So if I open that folder,
here is my email file.
It is my daughter,
the folder source and SRT.
So Intel will always look for this s
of C folder if you place your dollar files
other than this AC folder again,
your intelligence
will not be recognizing those files.
So SBC folder then there will be this com
dot syntax.
And then here are all the classes,
all the packages, sub packages
that I have created.
So if you place
nice, if you place anything
inside this folder,
inside any and by anything
I mean any java file,
you will quickly recognize that
and you can execute that file.
So now the simplest trick
to move your project from
Eclipse to intelligent,
what we can do, we can simply do this. So
if I open my
eclipse, so
I click on launch the
SO and this is my eclipse, right?
This is the SBC folder
the same as possible.
So if you guys focus,
you guys will see that all the projects,
all the IDs, they all have this SBC
and then these these classes in here,
this class is in here.
So for example, let's say
I want to move
east then that's also good.
That's also good.
So if you guys, let's say.
But will GitHub also be both
these files when we push the code?
So if inside that main folder,
if you have initialize that folder as good
repository, then yes,
it will push those files.
So it will
create these files
as we have created some new files.
So I want you to
open your, your old project
in your eclipse.
So before.
Right.
For, for the first ten classes,
you guys do use the eclipse.
So I want you to open your,
your workspace. Use
inside the eclipse
and then open your, your,
your projects like this.
And let me know once you guys see
all of you, all of your packages
are imported by module.
I will also show that.
So I will also show that node.
I have two packages.
They are Java basics and Java. Okay.
That that's also good.
That's also
what window for the intelligent
should be open.
So you should open
this this this bot
your project the part in which there is
this FRC.
Yes this one Sebastian so
this SRT folder and inside this SLC folder
you need to go inside
com and then syntax
and then your packages.
So do you guys also see all of these
classes, all of these folders in here
from your intel, you
okay.
So now I want you to right
click on any of the package
inside your eclipse, right
click on any of your package
And then in here
also you have to click on showing
and then system
Explorer.
Do you guys see this option?
Okay, so can you show one more time?
So right click on any of your package
inside Eclipse
the the packages that you want to move,
the classes that you want to move.
Right click on any of that
and then click on showing
and then System Explorer,
I show audio cooking again, all the audio,
all of your focuses in class
today, I'm just getting
I was not cooking
and diapering the baby
and diapering the babies.
I was taking
my other class.
I don't think so.
You will be needing an MBA now.
I, I don't know already the situation in
in the United States, like for example,
how much you can earn using an MBA degree.
But I don't think so.
You guys will be needing
needing any other degrees.
Yes. Alex, we need to open two folders,
one for intelligent
and one for Eclipse.
You all right?
There's.
So if I click on System Explorer,
I see all of my files in here.
Okay, All of my files in here.
Ready?
Now, the files
that you want to move, you guys can
copy.
So let's say I only want to move.
Let's set last well and part B,
Okay, so let me open this in here.
And this in here.
So now what
you guys have to do. It's easy.
You just copy your classes from here.
So review classes already there.
Make sure you don't have duplicate classes
last well, 11 is also there.
1415.
Okay, let me check that
I need to the project,
but you guys will be seeing
a different view.
So as the s of C
class two
and then class three, it's also
all the classes
that I am already populating here.
I'll let me,
let me just pick back nine
files in here.
Will let me read them
then just to just to show you, uh,
let me change this to class four.
You guys don't have to build this with.
I don't have to do this.
Yes, Just copy and paste.
Just copy and paste.
So because I already have these classes
in here, so I am moving only class number
four from here to here.
I was wondering how would you do this?
I copied.
Why didn't you show that simple copy paste
before?
Because I wanted to
have you some group on Intelligent first
because in the previous batches,
if the so if you guys notice in here
and this form dot
syntax these base packages for eclipse
and for intelligent
they are same if they are not same
you guys have to reflect
that all of your classes so previous.
But some of the students
they didn't follow me
and then they had different base packages
and it
we created a lot of mess
so that's why I didn't want to do that.
And then did they kind of
some of them were not happy.
Why? We are using two IDs
because now they had to solve
all the issues and all that.
So that's why
when we first installed Intelligent,
there was an optional yes,
I will show that as the assignment
that import import option.
I will show you that as well.
Just give me some time.
Can I make a folder and then paste that
file with that folder to make sure back?
So you guys in all of your Java classes,
if you let's say
let me open
that Java file from a different editor.
So you guys see
there is this package statement.
Now, this package is actually nothing
but a folder inside another folder.
Okay, So there there is
this class is placed inside a folder
that is called form, then syntax,
and then this is where
this file is located.
If the pack, if the package name they are,
same means
the folder names in with
these classes are placed
on your file systems,
actually on your computers,
then you will not be having an issue
so you guys can copy and paste
as many files, create new files,
new folders create new file.
Did not put out anything
as long as the packages
they are same
and you can copy paste anything in here.
Now you guys have to do only one thing.
Now. If you go back to your
intelligent project
and if you click reload or from disk,
do you guys see this option
reload
from disk.
So if you guys
now click on that reload from disk,
you guys should see all of your classes
from Eclipse inside your intelligent.
Do guys see those classes inside?
Be intelligent. Now.
So this is one of the ways
if the simplest way is to move your files
now the second approach
I wanted to show you some
terminologies.
Do I paste it inside syntax folder?
Yes, I
just copy all of your folders
and paste it inside the other folder.
That's it.
Copy and paste.
Okay, so in Eclipse, repeat that again.
Sebastian, what do you want with that?
Reload. Okay, so right click and then
reload from disk.
So if you make any changes
outside of intelligent,
intelligent by default,
I will recognize those changes
the next time you open intelligent,
but you want to see the changes right now
you can reload from the disk and it will.
What happens if we
if the packages are different?
So if packages are different,
then intelligent will give you an ETA
and it will also show you the solution.
So you just have to click on a
you just have to press all and enter
and then it will fix the package
name automatically.
You guys don't have to rename
or add to anything.
It says the file is reloaded
in the wrong encoding.
So if you guys are facing
this issue, there are chances that
you have some comments in your files.
So Hossein is facing this issue right now.
And so if you are having this issue,
there are chances
that you have some kind of comments
and inside the comments
you are trying to use some characters
which are not present in UTF eight.
So UTF eight is a kind of format
in which you store
your that are actually on your desk.
Now, there is another format called
the UTF 16, which has all the characters,
Chinese characters,
those arrow symbols and all that.
So then you copy and paste something
that suppose that sports UTF 16
to something
that only sports UTF eight now,
because these characters,
they are not present in the UTF system.
So in Delhi they are the clips
of any other editor will give you an edit.
So what you guys can do,
you can click on this
reload in another encoding
or you can remove that comment.
And Elif, you asked me what happens
if the package is not Sam,
This is what will happen.
You will be getting an error
in here. Then you have to
place your cursor over the error
and intelligible will show you
the quick fix automatically.
So different languages.
UTF 16 Sports.
All Russian, Chinese, Arabic and all that.
But you DFAT
does not support all the languages.
So guys, this is one of the ways
to move your project.
I had company
instead of syntax in the part
that needed correction and it got dart.
Yes, and I'll be okay.
So if you guys don't want to do that,
there is another way
that is available, intelligent,
that is called
the import feature of intelligent.
So let's say if you had if someone
has created a project in Eclipse
and now you want to open that same project
inside Intelligent,
how we can do that, right?
So what we can do.
So first we have to understand
the structure a little bit.
So that means do you mean you are also
having the different packages in here
or. Yes,
if you have configured the GitHub
inside your intelligent,
then it can also mean
that you have not included these files.
You have not added these files
to the repository.
So try to do that as well.
So the first thing that I want you to do
is to
click any of these files
and then right click inside the editor
and try to run it
if there is no build.
So this second approach,
it will fix the packages automatically.
So those files
which are having issues for now,
you can just delete those packages.
So and let, let me tell you.
So it's a deluxe space inside
the eclipse is equivalent
to projects inside intelligent, inside
Eclipse, inside a workspace.
You guys have projects, right?
But in intelligent,
those projects they are called modules
and the
rest of the things they are,
they are kind of same.
Okay.
Do you recommend
to update this version of Java?
I will suggest to
stick with Java eight because
from next week, once
you guys are done with Java,
you will be starting different frameworks
and those frameworks and libraries.
They might not be compatible
with the latest version of of Java
and you guys might be having weird issues
and you will be spending a lot of time.
So it's always better to have this
Java 1.8.
It's better to best year
to use everywhere in the industry.
All the tools, they are compatible.
You guys will not be facing weird issues.
So now in in Eclipse,
we create new projects
inside the workspace in intelligent,
we create new modules.
So let's say, for example,
I want to create a module
so I have two options.
So if I click on file new
and then module,
I will be creating a module from scratch.
So you can create a module, which is it,
which is a project in Eclipse,
or you can import
that module from existing sources.
Okay, so let's say
you want to import your
Eclipse project as a module intelligent.
So then what you guys have to do,
like let's say for example, right now
I am inside this eclipse workspace.
I see this option.
So now I want you to move to your eclipse
workspace.
Okay,
So let me let me repeat it again.
Okay.
So for the next 15 to 20 minutes,
we will be dealing with a lot of steps,
tiny details.
So everyone, please focus so that
we don't have to repeat it multiple times.
Okay.
So file
then.
New. So,
Sebastian, you see this option
move package convert, blah blah.
Click on that and it will fix that.
So if you don't have new option for Mac,
it is not possible.
Maybe the placement placement
can be different,
but in the option it should.
Even though your window is small.
My my window is small.
Asia.
It's always on the top Sharif's
window. How.
How do you know his window is small?
Delicious.
Something.
Here we go.
I think sometimes it's confusing for Mac.
So you see this option
that says so on the top left corner,
it says,
You see that apple icon in Delhi, India.
And then this file option.
So I want you to click on that file
option.
So do you me delete
those files that you have imported.
Okay.
And follow follow these steps.
Delete
those packages that you have imported
from the clips and follow these steps.
Fine.
So Simon and
Damian was saying that
why we don't use that import
import feature in here?
So the reason is that if you want to copy
some packages
from one project to other part project,
then you cannot use that import feature
because it will create a new either
a new project or new module.
So let's say you already have a project
in Intelligent,
maybe on the same case
that we have 50 of our classes
or ten classes.
They are presently in Eclipse
and the rest of the class
is presently inside the intelligent right?
So you don't want to create a new project,
you don't want to create a new module.
You only want to have your code
in a single place inside a single project.
So that's we're told that that
copy paste will be helpful.
Is it clear
or is it also possible
and I am missing something
the Mid Simon
So if you don't want
to create a new module or new project
and you want to integrate the code
from your eclipse,
some of the files inside that new inside
that existing project in an intelligent,
then that copy paste
is the simplest option that we can have.
There is one more way that you can push
your code from eclipse to a get repo
and then
you can push
your from your intelligent
to that repo as well.
March those calls and then clone
those calls to a new project.
But you guys don't know yet
about merging and all that. So
after this Java classes I guess you guys
will be having four more good classes.
Then we will teach you
how to merge the code
from multiple computers
inside the same project.
So right now let's, let's try to use
the simplest things that are possible.
Claire Simon.
Damian
That why we are using that copy paste
So we don't want to create a new project,
we don't want to create a new module,
so we simply want to kind of merge
the large
sum packages from two different places
inside a single project.
So that's is a file Neo
and then module
from our existing sources.
Everyone see everyone.
You guys see this option.
Okay, so let me click on that
and now I want you guys,
I already imported
the classes that I would like to use.
Okay?
So even if you created a single class
in intelligent on the very first day,
you mean that's also
good and that's also good
the same.
But sometimes
you guys have to do this as well.
So I wanted to show you that as well.
And it's a very common practice number
because on companies, on a single project,
maybe 50 or 100 developers
will be working at the same time.
So you don't want to create 50
or 100 projects
for each of the changes
that other developers are making.
You always want to merge the code from all
the computers inside a single project.
You guys will learn how to do that
using it.
But this is kind of
so in here in Pakistan, we say
this is kind of the basic way of doing it.
Dugard
It's the easiest way.
So now I want you
to select the project from
the from Eclipse.
So here are all of my projects
from Eclipse.
Okay, all of my project.
So I can import any of the project
from Eclipse in here.
So if I click okay
and then it will ask me that, hey there.
So that's Jacob's phone number
two words.
So I did this project
for one of these students.
That's why you guys see
all those different names.
So now you guys see
that Intel is asking me that.
So that is it.
Is it a project from Eclipse
or is it a gradle or maven?
Now, these two things, they are
you can say they are tools
that help us manage
our projects automatically.
So you guys remember
you imported some jobs
for your selenium to work properly, right?
Downloading those jobs,
importing them manually.
So if you use these build systems,
you guys don't have to do any of that.
You just write the name of the job.
Every word your project goes,
your jobs will go along.
That project right now,
if you copy your project to a new project,
you have to re-import the jobs again.
And in real life, those jobs, they can
they can be 100 or 200 or 300.
But on Apple, I don't see any sell
your apple and by windows,
if you don't see that option.
Okay.
So now as will you we will be teaching you
a separate session on on Maven
and most popular on measurement
not great
So Illini post posting this partnership.
I will show you how to find that option.
So you guys don't need to worry
about this dreadlocked maven.
You guys will be having separate
sessions on this.
Maven Okay,
so, so you guys see
all of you see this option
that says Eclipse.
Okay, now let's click on next.
So now if you want to work on
the same project from Intelligent Eclipse
as well, you can click on this option
that says Link created
Intelligent ID module to Eclipse.
Okay, But we will not be doing that
because you guys will mess up again.
Everything
or you can keep on everything as default.
Create modules, file the near blast file
and then
simply click on next.
Then you should see ASP.NET Batch then
and that big mark in here.
You guys see this option.
That means you guys have not selected.
So if I cancel this, if I,
if I do file new
Oh you guys,
you guys would be seeing that batch 11,
not ten.
Definitely.
Guys,
how can you have that as that 410 project.
Right.
Because I have multiple projects
in my glyph that I see as that base ten.
Definitely You will be seeing
the name of your projects, right?
So you, you I remember saying go copy
and paste everything from other students.
At least try to change the parts right?
You will see anything that you have
created on your computers right.
He was upset.
So let me repeat it again.
So five new
module from existing sources.
So when we train a computer, we have this
problem with computers as well.
So right now in my research,
I am facing a lot of issues.
If I am teaching a computer
that Simon looks like this or causing
looks like this, and if I give a slightly
different picture to my program,
so an ABC program that tries
to recognize the person, the celebrities
and that computer thing,
that computer cannot recognize
that it exactly looks
for the exact same thing.
We call it
overfitting in in machine learning.
And so it's kind of memorizes
all the things like, for example,
if I give a picture of Alexa with glasses
and then the next time I feed a picture
without the glasses, computer will say,
This is not Alex.
Right.
So memorizing each
and everything is not a generalizing. So
you will be seeing different projects
depending upon
what name you have given to your project.
And if you are inside
this eclipse workspace or not.
So first thing you guys have to make sure
that you are inside
of the Eclipse workspace
and then you can select any of
the projects that you guys want to import.
So everyone, please
make sure that you are first inside
this eclipse workspace.
Are you all inside this workspace,
inside this eclipse
workspace
just otherwise,
you guys will not be seeing anything
if you guys don't know
how to navigate navigate
to your eclipse workspace.
You guys can tell me.
I can show you how to do that.
Maybe it is located on a different folder
inside a different drive
or something like that.
Okay,
so if you want to be 100% sure, let's say
you want to import this project, right
click on any of the project
that you want to import
inside your eclipse. Yes.
Because you guys were not in the eclipse
workspace.
Right. And how you can see the projects
and so if you guys still don't
maybe you don't remember
or for any other reason,
you guys don't know where that folder is.
You guys can just right
click click show in
System Explorer
and then it will take you to the Eclipse
workspace, right?
You can simply copy this part from here.
So my Eclipse workspace is stored
under C users as complete
and then eclipse workspace
so you can have a different path
to copy that path.
And now
you can paste that part in here.
Inside, in here.
Okay.
Like this.
And then you should see your project.
Yeah.
Do you guys see your eclipse projects now
or still lost?
Okay, so if I click on that badge, then
I and if I click on okay
then same steps.
It will ask me
from where you want to import the project.
Then next don't do anything
and click next and next
and then finish.
And then
if you guys see this option
module files found
so intelligent, seeing their task
that you already have a
another module file inside in there
because I already imported
that project multiple times.
So you guys can click on this option,
it's fine.
And now you guys should see your project
from Eclipse
inside the same window in here
and all of your files
in here
like this.
So if I, if I click on play
around, I see my house,
if I see my out. So
this time, what for the difference between
the earlier steps that I show
now, I have a separate module.
Previously I was importing
everything inside this same module, Aztec
Batch 11.
Now I have a separate module
and in here I see
all of my project from Eclipse.
And now you guys don't have to worry
about any of the package statements.
Intel will fix everything for you
before importing,
and you guys can just run your projects
by just clicking on this run.
I Okay, so
you can click on.
Okay, Mom, I'm honored
you can click on that.
Okay?
Because in Eclipse
you guys are using a different JDK
and that JDK is not present
inside the intelligent.
That's why you are facing that issue.
So click on okay and on inside.
When you click on any of the Java files,
you guys will see an option
that says Configure JDK a blue line
and you can fit that from here.
Monaco click on, Okay.
And then whenever you try to run a file,
you will see a blue line in here
that says Configure JDK, click on that
and you will be able to use the same JDK
that is already.
So now you guys know.
So what I was
previously what I was showing you that
if, if I, if I do this and this
so previously I was telling you that
these projects they are referred to as
modules in intelligence.
Okay?
So as they're about 11,
I have it somewhere in here.
And then this project is called Project
in and Intelligent.
This is called
you see this eclipse workspace?
It is called Workspace in here.
Show me this screenshot.
So now you guys can create
multiple modules
inside the same project
in an intelligent.
Okay.
Did I promise to show you anything else?
Guys? Yes.
If you guys lose any of your files. Right.
If you guys lose any of your files.
So let's say guys.
So there is one more thing
that I want to show you.
If you guys observe these buttons in here,
there is this button
that squeezes everything.
So the
expands everything, and then this button
that squeezes everything.
So let's say, for example, right now
my project loop.
Terrible, right?
Maybe you have opened
multiple windows are now
you have to scroll down multiple time.
So what I can do
I can click on this collapse all button
and it will nicely collapse
all the modules, all the projects
inside this project Explorer.
And now I can I can navigate easily
wherever, wherever I want to go.
So you can click on this collapse
all button.
Are you guys able to squeeze
your project structure in here?
Yes, it usually happens when the there is
a different JDK
on Eclipse and different Gun project.
Now there is this second option
that says select open file.
So right now I have opened this file
and I don't know where this file is coming
from.
Right.
This task one test per
I don't know where this file
is coming from,
so I can click on this round button and it
will show me the complete structure,
the package name, the module name.
So when you guys will be working with
multiple modules, maybe hundreds of them
inside modules, hundreds of packages,
inside packages, hundreds of files,
and you want to look at a file
or the file that you have opened.
You can click on this. This
square kind of button
will kind of button and then will show you
the exact location of that file
inside your project.
Explorer.
So now the next useful thing
that I want to show you.
So let's say
I have created this North Dart, right?
And what happens is that I accidentally
maybe delete
this file right now
I have not pushed this file to the
GitHub. Right.
So how do I recover that file.
So if you guys are in this situation,
you can right click on your project
and then you guys can click on this option
that says local history.
Do you guys see this option,
local history?
So if I click on that now,
what the intelligence doing,
it is recording all of your steps.
Even if you put a space inside a file
intelligence records that step.
And if you if you even want
to revert that space in inside
any of the file inside
anywhere on your project, you can do that.
Yes, it's kind of FBI.
So intelligence is recording.
You see all of my steps.
Intelligence has been recording
all of my steps.
I created a project.
I created a file, like I made
some external can use.
I created an authority module, weeks,
a certain demo.
So everything that I have been doing on
the Intelligent
Intelligence was recording everything.
And if I want to go back to that
previous step, I can just do right click.
So right now I have to look at my notes
file from plus 27.
I can right click and I can say reload.
And now if I go back, I see my notes
dot in here.
And do you guys see this option?
No, no.
It looks for any kind of file,
any kind of file,
anything, any package folder, anything.
You can reverse the changes
that you have made
and inside anything in your intelligent
and other way.
Another reason to love intelligent.
All right.
So the next thing let's say maybe
let's say I.
I arrived something in here like this.
Like this, right?
And then
if I click on this and this north door.
So now
Intelligent has recorded
those steps as well.
So I created a file
naught naught naught naught BSD, right.
Then I deleted that file.
That is also recorded.
Then I reverted that file on this time,
on this date that is also recorded.
So if you want to revert, delete it again.
That is also that I made
some changes in here.
In here I made some changes.
I wrote two lines that is also recorded.
So if if you click on
if you right click on that file
and if we click on show differences
so intelligent or tells me that there
previously
there were only two lines in here
and then you opened that file
and you wrote these
three lines, okay,
you wrote those three lines.
Do you want me to reverse those?
What do you want me to change those?
What do you want me to do at the end?
It is with all the files
or everything that is present
inside the intelligent.
So if I want to accept those changes,
I can click on this arrow.
And those changes will be
accepted for me.
So let's say, for example,
let me want to go back
and let's say I delete,
I deleted this and I see
intelligent is full rights.
Now if I right click
and if I click on show Local History.
So it shows me the changes again,
I right click on that file,
I show difference
and then now you saying that last there
there were three lines written in here.
You deleted those lines
and then you wrote a another line
saying intelligence school.
Do you want to reverse that option?
So if you want to reverse that option,
you can click on these arrows
and those files they will be now.
So now if I go back to Tool Node
or you see these
these changes, they are back again, okay?
These changes, they are back again.
Are you guys able to revert your changes?
Okay, so now you guys have to make me
one promise.
Okay.
So all of there are so many things
that are possible, but
modern will will show you
similar features
using GitHub using the command line.
Do tell was done that you guys know
how to do that using the UI in mentality.
Okay.
So he will tell you
all those things using the
using GitHub
and I want you to listen to him
and focus on that because these changes
are intelligent, can not record
all the changes forever, but
GitHub can record
all of your changes forever.
So those steps, they are important.
Don't don't try to show show your self
that we know
something better or something like that.
Those are super simple, important
and I want you to learn those, right?
And then I will show you how
to do all of that inside the intelligent.
Okay.
But that is all so important.
Okay, so now you guys know how to fix.
If you delete anything
in the intelligence,
you know how to import projects of.
Okay, the remaining things
I will show you later.
I will you guys will forget if
next two weeks.
All right.
So at least now you guys know
that you guys don't need to worry
if you delete anything accidentally.
How to import files
to get out from intelligent.
Alex.
It's super, super easy and intelligent,
but I don't want to show that
because Mohsen will be showing you
that using the command line
and then you guys will not focus.
This reminds me, when we were kids,
my mom took my sister somewhere
and told her not to tell Aisha
You had ice cream.
She comes home and says,
I did not have ice cream.
Yeah, you guys don't know how to do that
using New Delhi yet, right?
Okay, so let's start the two day of class.
So we started learning about
about the ArrayList, right.
Okay, So what do you guys remember
about the ArrayList?
Why? Well, what are ArrayList?
Okay,
They are flexible.
Okay?
Yes. So
ArrayList is a class
in collections framework
that helps us
store
delete,
retrieve
and manage
back to
easily.
Right.
As compared to
arrays.
It has many, many
better I mean, new methods
to manipulate the data.
Right.
And if I ask you guys behind the scenes
which data structure
this ArrayList is using.
So we discussed the two types of of lists,
right.
What do you guys remember the names,
two types of lists.
ArrayList
and Linked List.
So if I ask you specifically
about the list,
can you guys tell me how internally,
how data
is stored inside an ArrayList?
Yes, it's dynamic,
but what is the underlying data
structure
in case of ArrayList?
Okay, here we go.
Right.
ArrayList uses
arrays
internally to
store and
manipulate
the data.
Okay.
So if a data structure is internally
using an ArrayList, it's really an area.
So when I showed you,
can you guys guess if something is
internally under the particularly
if something you using at is,
then I should use that data structure.
What is the property of arrays?
What are the what?
What is the case?
We are at is they are best and worst.
So when to use
ArrayList,
when you have to,
when you have when you have to
retrieve
the better.
Mostly right?
You are doing you are writing a program
and you know that maybe 90% of the times
you in a once you initially have stored
the dirt on 90 or 95% of the time,
you will only be accessing that data,
right?
Specify the index,
get the data from that index.
Right.
So if this is the case then that
your read operations are more frequent
then right.
Operations then you guys should
use add alias,
right. So
if I,
I know that I will be inserting some data
in between or empty
at the start of the list.
Is it a good choice to use analysts
and non ben the link
list is better right?
I'm on
but if I have to write the data in in
and maybe in the middle of the
if the middle of the list
or maybe at the start of the list.
So what your computer has to go through
if you are using
and ArrayList.
So let's say there are some
that are already present in here.
All right, let's see.
Maybe this is then this is fi.
This is true.
This is three.
And these two slots, they are important.
They are empty. Sorry.
And now want to insert a new number two L
but on the first location.
Now what your computer has to do
if you are using an array list,
what your computer has to do,
it has to ship all the data.
Two words right?
Like this.
So create a new array, shift
all the data two words,
right.
And then place the next element.
Now imagine guys,
if there are maybe 10 million entries
and you want to insert something in front.
How many how many elements do you have to.
All of them, right?
Imagine million.
Imagine moving 10 million memory cells
just because you have to insert
something in front.
Or imagine
there are 5 million entries in here
because in real life,
think about the users of Amazon,
Google and all those big companies
banking applications.
They have millions of customers, right?
And you figure if you guys
are working on those applications
and you are creating an array list
and now you have to insert.
So 5 million entries are here,
then there is this empty slot
and 5 million entries are present in here
and you want to insert something
in between, right?
You want to insert something in between.
Then you have to shift all that data.
If there is a space inside the list,
if there is a space inside the list,
you have to move 5 million entries.
If there is no space available inside
this list.
It is not it is not possible
that you opened a new cell
in here
in the case of areas and edit lists.
In that case, if there is no space,
you have to move all those
10 million entries.
It's super, super devastating.
Super, super slow.
So think about the Android and the Apple
gigabytes of Android,
two gigabytes of Apple still effort.
Apple is fast.
Why Apple is
because they know what to use.
They are not randomly using
the data structures
to write their programs.
So in that yes, Optimizer
software optimizer optimization,
it can improve your performance
so much that you guys can't even imagine
saving the power.
Right.
Your your CPU has to do a lot of work
to move these entries.
You require at least.
So for example,
if you are using the earliest,
the first thing, you must have
at least that much space
that can hold 2 million entries
because you will be creating a new array,
pushing all the data inside there.
So you do you require space,
you require computing power.
You are wasting a lot of resources.
So that's why it's important to know the
the qualities,
the advantages and disadvantages
of a specific data structure.
And when to use.
That's why we are learning this collection
framework.
There are so many classes,
but knowing which to use,
then it's very important. So
now you guys know that
when we have the right,
the data in between,
most of the times
we would be use
linked list.
Do computers have random
epochs when processing?
Mohammad What do you mean by hiccups?
Let me let me jump.
Like atoms. None.
They don't have those errors.
The this is what Google shows me.
You guys are caused by involuntary
contraction of your diaphragm.
The muscles that separate your.
There is no terminology
in computers like this.
So, no, they don't have errors, but
they have to do a lot of work.
A lot of work unnecessarily.
So then
we should be
using the link list.
Right.
And but again, this is
this is very useful.
So how how link list solves this problem.
So link list instead of splitting
all the data and contracting.
So imagine this is are
this is are computers memory
instead of storing all the data side
by side in consecutive memory locations
linked list it's stores
that are randomly right?
Maybe somewhere here, somewhere
here, somewhere here.
But then it will remember
where it has stored the next element
link restores the elements and doubly link
so if you can go from previously.
So let's say this is cell number zero.
You have to store
you have stored in here. Okay
so in doubly linked list
you will be having 2.1 pointer
that tells the location of the next memory
cell and another pointer
that tells the location of previous cell.
So in simply a single link list,
you can move in one direction
because previous node
only knows the address of the next node.
It does not have the information of
so the previous node,
but in a doubly linked place, you can move
forward, you can move backwards.
So that's why it's called doubling list
because it has to point us.
So instead of so that I stored randomly
but link me list
W link list it stores
to point line
to tell the location, the previous cell,
one proposal, the location of it.
And now let's imagine you have to store
this new element 15 inside this link.
If I don't have to move a single cell
in this case, I will go inside the memory.
I will check wherever the location
is available, wherever the space
is available, inside computer,
I will place my data,
I will place my data.
So I want let's say I want to insert it.
And the first location I will like
this pointer to here
and this pointer
to backwards and how to link release.
Note that this is the starting point
because the starting node has this left
part as empty.
The the the pointer is empty in here.
That's how link list knows
that this is the starting point.
Okay. This is the starting point.
So I just place the data
anywhere inside the computer.
And here I rearranged the pointers
in case of linked list.
I don't move a single
cell of memory in here.
Yes. Still it maintains the order
because this pointer is empty.
And I know
that this is the starting point.
And if I know the starting point,
I can go anywhere, right?
I can ask for the next node.
Node location using this pointers.
I can do this or that node and that node
can tell me the address of next node
and then next node
and then I can keep on going
and let's say
I have to insert some new piece of back
maybe in here, right in here.
So what I will do,
I will simply remove
these two pointers.
I will like this that I in here
and in here
and then this here and here
that I inserted successfully in between.
I don't have to shift any of these things.
Right.
So this is how link list link list manages
the data under the code.
So in here, yes, it's also not perfect.
We will be learning a new data
structure that is the that is
I would say it's
the most widely used data structure
In that case.
Storing, retrieving
searching is super, super fast.
So when we have the right things
that are in
between
or in front
of the
list, most of the time
we should use the linkages, right?
So are the concepts clear
about the link list and the
and the and the ArrayList?
So if the underlying concepts
they are clear,
you guys will see that both of these
that are structures.
So both of these data structures,
what they do is
what if I cover my mouth
and if I click on that, at least,
and if I scroll to the top.
So you see both of these data structures.
So this is the ArrayList and
if I say new
link list, let me open them
side by side of the.
So you guys will notice
that both of these classes, this ArrayList
and Link list, they implement
this list
interface, right?
So if two classes
they are implementing the same interface
and if let's say they are hundred meter
and these classes,
they are not abstract by these classes,
they are not abstract.
And if this list last to contain thousand,
will I see
all the method in both the classes?
So you guys see the use of interfaces
we are forcing to class these
two different classes
who have the same meters.
One class is implementing
the method in a different way,
but the other class for meters.
They are same names, the same,
but type is same, but internally
they are implemented
in a totally different way.
So when you have to make sure
that two classes are more
than two classes,
they must have all same methods.
We make an interface.
We put the
those methods inside the interface
and we make those classes
implement, those interface.
And even if one of the classes
not implementing
a single method,
we will be getting a compile time matter.
So This is how we enforce the rules.
With the help of interfaces,
we bind classes
to have the specific methods
linked to syntax like set
list.
The syntax is like set, so they all have
the same same method. Why?
Because they are all coming
from the collections framework.
They are all coming from collections
interface.
I will show you that as well.
So if I go in here,
let me scroll
so they have some specific methods.
So let's discuss the remove
method.
Really the structure of the.
So you guys don't
need to open these files. So
I just wanted to show you that
although these two matters,
they are coming
from the same interface,
but check out the logic guys.
Same operation is happening in this method
and inside this this method.
But because internally
they are using totally different data
structures, the implementation
can be totally, totally different.
Now, does all the examples that we
we did they do they make sense?
So if you are trying to do
the same operation in multiple ways,
if the internal implementation is totally,
totally different,
you create an interface,
you make separate classes,
you put your logic you want to do,
and you make those classes
inherit that interface,
and then the programmer
or the other who will be using your code.
His life will be super, super easy.
You guys can use the same method
to add the elements inside of the list.
You can use the same method
to add the element inside the linked list,
inside a BQ, inside a set inside.
So classes.
So you guys don't
have to learn new methods each time
if they are essentially
doing the same things.
Does it make sense right?
So now how it is making your life easier
but is a totally different class.
This one is also totally different class.
But what I can do because both implement
the list interface,
I can store the objects of these classes
inside a variable of type list.
And then what I can do is
I can call the exact same methods
in here.
Okay.
And in. Whereas. All right,
I don't have to come up
with a different name
if I am essentially doing the same thing.
I know the internal implementation
is different, right?
From the perspective of a coder,
the person
who will be writing the code,
it has to do it.
It don't have to.
He don't.
He does not have to learn all those
those new methods
and then remember those names.
He will always be using The exact
same name matters because technical
he is doing the essentially
the same operation.
So you guys already know about the methods
that are present inside the list.
Right?
Add remove contains,
and all those methods.
So if I say students dot doc,
you guys already know, right?
So I got clear
and remove all add all contains is empty
last index of first index of
and all of these matters right
you can convert it to edit
if you want to convert a list to
the state is also possible.
You need to call the story.
So I want you, you guys to
to explore these matters.
Okay.
So let's do the homework.
And in the homework I will also tell you
side by side how we can use different.
So by now this should be super,
super clear
when we should be using the edit list
and when we should be using the link list.
Layers is same as hash map.
No, they are not same.
So if someone is confused,
what is the difference
between an ArrayList and being placed?
You guys can stop me.
You guys can ask your questions.
Then we will be starting
the homework questions. So
you guys are
not confused.
Let me check your first task.
So your first task.
Can you tell one more time?
Alex?
What do you want me to tell the difference
between this
early and the link list?
Okay, so the ArrayList,
you can think of the ArrayList as
a data structure
that stored the data
internally under the hood
inside your computer,
always in consecutive memory.
So it will always for your data
in consecutive memory locations.
Now, if you have to insert something
in between, order this start
what you have to do
because the data is stored
in consecutive memory locations,
you have to ship all the data
and that is very expensive, very computer
expensive,
takes a lot of memory computing power.
So if you have to only access
the elements stored inside, then
and at least always use the inside
list, always use the ArrayList.
If you are planning to do operations,
inserting the time between at the start
at the end and deleting the data
from between, manipulating these things,
then you should always
go with the linked list
for accessing areas.
For manipulating linked. Yes.
Is it clear
for subscription?
Let's say which one is better?
I said, What do you mean by subscription?
When is the break time? Okay,
we will be having a break.
So in this subscription,
what happens is that when we are
so when a news new user signs
sign up right?
So we take the credentials,
we take all the data from that user
and then we store that data somewhere.
And the next time that user
is trying to log in,
what we have, what we do,
we scan all the usernames
and all the passwords,
we compare one by one, and if that
username and password is preserved,
then we allow that user to log in.
Now me the frequency
of signing up new users
and the users who are logging
in your application on a daily basis.
Which frequency is more new customers
sign up or the customers
who are logging in
or using your website on a daily basis?
Logging. Right.
So what happens is that you decide
based on the operations.
So most of the time in your case,
you will be reading the data
and you will be comparing all the data
one by one
with all the data
that is present inside your computer.
So you should always go
with which data structure.
Guys,
most of my
operations, they are reading and comparing
at any stripe,
at least
none of them, nor the single ad is single.
It is. They are fakes.
If I if I make an error
for 10,000 customers again,
110 11,000 customers can design up.
No, I have to do a lot of work.
At least we mean.
No, no, you guys didn't have to be there.
At least I am sure about that. It
So you should be
using the ArrayList.
Sorry, silly question.
Is the link
list more efficient than ArrayList said?
If depends what of operation
you want to perform
with link list or be added list.
It depends on the operations
for subscription,
like people subscribing or unsubscribing.
Then use linked list.
So far subscriptions
in which are unsubscribing.
Instead of removing that customer data,
what companies do they have a flag
which is
actively
if a customer has active subscription
and if that customer
does not have an active subscription,
they don't completely delete
the user data.
They just put that flag to.
So still the analyst will be better.
Yes, you'll get that if you are planning
to completely delete that data.
And if you know that your customers,
they always sign up and always
keep on signing up an answer.
So subscribing and unsubscribing
these operations,
they are more than the customers
that are logging in your system.
Yes. Then you should go with the link
list.
So totally depends how your application
is working.
Like following your
likelihood.
To be very clear,
there are a lot of data structures
other than like, listen, they are a list
of these companies they use.
And sometimes because these companies,
they are so big
for a specific operation,
they create their own data structures
which will be more efficient
to store the data.
For example,
he is not using the link list of the list.
They are
using
something called the relationship graph.
So you guys see,
I am if I can have 500 friends,
those 500 friends
they can again have and have 500 friends.
So if something like this one user
having 500
friends linked to all of those friends,
then they can be linked to all others.
And in this hierarchy
it can be super, super complex
If this user or something right,
it should be visible to all of these
and then the friends.
If it has allowed, it's a very,
very complex
data structure that Facebook is using.
They they created their own data structure
because the scale was massive.
Right?
There was no pre-built data structure
to accommodate these use cases.
So it's always kind of this you
if your basics are clear,
you can create a new data structure
specific for your needs.
And there was a point
in which a lot of experts
and data scientists,
they said that Facebook crash
because the data was in,
that was messy, huge, that Facebook
was floating very huge amounts of data
and there was nothing already built
in the history to accommodate back data.
So they believe that Facebook
will not be able to cater that, but
they created their own data structures.
So it depends on your application. But
most of the time
for not that big applications,
this list at least, and the other
simple data structures, they will be fine.
If I can show you
I think it's prevalent over the internet
to maintain a total of the demographic
Facebook
have made smart, blah blah blah.
It's all about revenue
we are not interested in of
to see.
More than 250 billion
photos have been uploaded.
Facebook.
This equates to 50 million photos
for day each day 350 million
new photos are being uploaded
to Google on Facebook.
And then then there are people
who likes, dislikes,
put comments, put emojis,
public, private, shared with only friends
and all that.
You're the super, super complex system
on this list and linked list.
We can store string and integer
no primitive data types.
Again, we saw very primitive data types
collections framework
guys, you create
50 million photos each day,
so primitives are not allowed.
Okay, let's have a break.
And then after the break,
we will be
we will be solving the questions.
Okay. But.
Oh, sorry.
The homework.
Well, Lugo has resigned. I
Lugo already on break.
I'm waiting already.
Investigate that.
Alright,
guys, please be back in 15 minutes.
Okay,
So let me
all the time to side as but
create an ArrayList of cars
and retrieve
all the values using three different ways.
Okay, So
to create the ArrayList, we see
a list
and I will be storing the cars
inside this ArrayList.
So what should be the data type
that I should specified
inside this diamond Operator
Oh, string.
Right.
Okay.
And cars and then equal to sign new
and then edit just like
and if I have to add some elements
to an analyst
which method I should use
be admitted.
Right.
So I have two different
add methods that intelligence shows me.
One is taking an index and an element,
the other one only takes an element.
Can you guys tell me the difference
between these two meters
boolean and Ward?
Yes, this is one difference.
Well, what is this index?
What is the second parameter?
First, I want to add a specific index.
So let's say you guys,
I have this ArrayList here
and I want to add this new element.
Now, if I only use the add the method
by default,
this add method will always append
the new values at the end of the list.
But if I want to add the new element
at a specific location,
let's on this 13.
Then I specify the index.
I said that Hey Java, let's say
maybe I want to add this hundred.
So I say Hey Java, add this 100 add index
number one right?
Index number one.
So I specify
the class has started already,
so I specify
index plus the data that I want to add
to this section to add method.
And then what Java will do in
Java will shape all the elements
towards right. So
the 13 will
be shifted in here,
14 relative to being here, 15 here,
and then this hundred, this new element
will be added in here.
Okay.
So if you want to add at a specific index,
you pass the index plus the data.
If you always want to append
at the end of the list,
you only
pass the data. Okay.
So this is the difference
between to add methods.
So there are no elements in the list.
So if I see,
oh, here we go.
Yes, we can remove the same.
Here are the cards from
Jimmy.
Yeah.
So this in here
we are only passing the data
to this add method.
So what will happen?
A list will be created
first before it will be added,
then BMW, then Ferrari, then Mercedes.
Right.
So now
I can simply say cards.
And if I had secured this
to the U.S.
first we see Ford offer that BMW offered
that Ferrari offer that Mercedes likes.
So this is the default behavior
of the method.
But let's see, I say
Toyota.
All right.
And this time with Delta,
I also pass the index.
Right.
So let's say after this Ford,
I want this Toyota.
So what value should I pass in here?
Right.
I passed the index
where I want this delta.
So now, although I am adding this Toyota
in the last but because this time
I use the overloaded add method
and I specified the plus the data.
So to Java I will do
it will insert this specific data
at that specific index.
Or is it clear now
the difference between add and add all?
So the task was to retrieve
all the values using three different ways.
So let me are the comments helpful guys?
If I put comments with code
both, they
will be added at
index
number one.
Yeah.
All right. Plus
where to retrieve the data from
a from an
ad it used to.
So the one simple way to retrieving a data
and the
most common
and the most powerful good way to retrieve
the data is a
hard edge.
Look. Okay.
And I specify the data type
which is spring in here.
Then I specify the name for that variable
and simply the name of the list.
And now if I see car,
I will see all the cars
in individual cars
one by one.
All right.
But I told you that a using loops with
ArrayList is not good.
But what I am using a loop in here
the what is going on?
Why? Why?
I'm using loops if they are not good. So
here we go.
If I am I changing the
Am I doing some kind of operations of guys
which may change, which might
which might change this sides of the list?
Am I doing something like this inside
this?
Edit No, I am only accessing the elements.
So whenever you guys have to access
the elements,
you guys can use any type of loop, right?
The restriction is only
when you are doing it
and operation
that can change the size of the list.
It can.
It can be increasing
or it can be decreasing.
Right?
If you are not doing these two operations,
you can freely use any types of loops.
You can
just.
Okay, So this second way
I can use a simple for I loop.
So at
least they also told me that all based on
index is right starting from zero
and then point will decide
so which method can use to
get the size of the list.
I can see cars
dot size.
Most of our shortcut
for writing this for loop
just type four
and then put either the under
and hit tab or enter like this
f for r I hit enter
and it will create loop
and then you can press bear
to move to the next location.
So this is called using your keyboard
and this is what you guys should learn.
Always try to use your keyboard
instead of mouse.
You guys will see
will be much, much faster.
It will save a lot of a lot of time.
So now Google is saying what is the
difference between length and size?
So so can you guys
tell me what is this length?
Can you guys tell how
length
is for strings only if you want to count
the number of characters in this string,
then you use the length method.
So let's say,
for example, inside of this for loop,
if I want to not only get the
actual elements,
but I also want to get
its the number of characters
that are present
inside.
Each string.
Then I will be using
the length method.
So Ford has four characters,
Toyota has six
BMW has three like this.
Is it clear?
Okay.
Is there anyone else
who has any kind of questions?
And there is there is one more thing.
There is this lent without parentheses.
Can you guys tell me what it is that
only dot length
while you are having
some issues with importing?
Yes. Be
some is
it's a matter
side is also a matter
because we are using the parentheses
and length is for it is simple.
But will it be? It is
or it will be resolved.
And so I just want to say
don't don't don't
hurt point Dick of all
I don't wait anyone.
I will show you during the break
how to do that itself.
Something is not working.
Yeah I can
I know it can feel very very frustrating.
Right?
Simple things when they don't work.
You are unable to import this project
right from your eclipse.
I guess
the note will remind me during the break
I would fix that.
The import method. Okay.
Don't worry.
All okay.
I'm. And how can I use the why?
Look, guys, in here.
Yes, we
we will use the iterate, translate, etc..
So can I use divide look without iterator
can I use
I look without right
return to get all the elements.
Good question.
Boolean. No.
So this is how I can use
one of the ways to use the
why are is less than
RS or five.
I hope you guys have not.
But what about the values?
Because it's a what you guys use.
I can see
got don't get and I
will this code word guys
if I execute the score, will
I get all the elements.
Okay I think no.
Yes it will be an infinite low.
I have to do the
plus plus as well.
So this is by simply printing the array
using the s out.
One of the ways
to retrieve the method element.
So simply use this
s out
and you will get all the
elements in this format.
But if you want to use
the individual elements
and then what you guys can do,
oops,
you can write a loop
and you can get all the elements
one by one
in here
and then you can write
the symbol for loop as well
to get all the elements, a lot of buyback
and then you guys can use
a y loop as well
in here.
All right.
So what you guys are noticing
that I get all the elements
in the same order
in which I inserted a B as
So is it some kind of property of arrays
or I'm just getting these elements
within them The in the same order
and you use enhanced
for loop for ArrayList.
So what is this? Shareef
Well, what we are doing in here
Okay, so this
here we are already using the enhanced
for loop, right?
So on the onset of your question is yes,
So if I ask you
about the properties of list,
so when I write, when I write list,
I mean add a list
and the link or list.
So one of their properties is that there
maintain the tool in
insertion order
the, order in which we insert the data,
we get the data in the same order
when we use, they get print method.
Any other method,
we get the data in the same order.
Yes. Not to just give me one moment
and again,
can I,
can I put to duplicate elements guys.
No, no.
It's the property of both the list.
It can be.
It can be and released
or linked list.
All right.
We can insert
duplicate data as that.
Okay.
So for example, and you guys
tell me the shortcut if I want to go back
to the file
that law that I was editing before,
this knows file.
No, there is no difference.
But both they are same.
The only difference is how internally
they see the data.
Yes, it's control.
I press this.
I go back to the file.
Okay So if let's say for example,
if I say car dot Ferrari,
how many Ferraris I will see
now guys in the output
everywhere I will see too.
But if I do the same with sets,
if I do the same thing with search,
if I try to add to duplicate
elements in this set,
how many Ferraris I
will get, I will get only write
only and only one.
Okay, so how is the class today?
Is it still confusing?
Like the start,
like they started last Sunday's class?
Or is it better?
Okay, so the main point is to learn
how to use these structures,
like how to use the methods
of removal contains.
And the second most part is to learning
the underlying data structure
so that you guys can decide
in a certain scenario which data structure
you should use.
So how many ways we have learned?
We have learned.
One way to bring to be that.
The second way,
the third way, the fourth way.
And now let me show you the fifth way
using the iterator.
Then I will show you the sixth way
and the seventh way as well.
If you guys promise
me, do not get confused.
So now let's try to get
the elements using the I papers as well.
So I have a list.
List is the collection right? And
the top class.
What is the topmost interface
in the collections framework
based? Yes.
Do while is also possible.
Yes. Object class is the
is the father of all the classes
I treble is the father in all
the classes
are the interfaces inside this interface.
So if I show you
that picture again,
this I triple is is at the very top.
I think it's actually the so
what I can do
that means every class
or interface in this collection framework,
they have to implement
the methods
provided by that iterator interface.
Right.
So and this is the object of my error list
last night I have called it cause I,
I have all this object has cards.
So if I want to get the iterator,
I simply use the name of the object,
then dot.
And then I say
I try to
and it will return me and I return
which I can store
inside the variable of.
I create the interface and the data
that this object contains itself
string type.
So I will say string.
Is it clear, guys, this line
why I am using this iterator variable?
What is this string?
And I am calling this method.
So if I show you this, it returns at 30.
It actually returns another object of the
I prefer the interface.
And now what I can do,
I can use those three famous methods
from the iterator interface
to get all the elements right.
So what are those famous
three methods of guys
as a next?
So this next has next method.
It will always return mean true
as far as I have some
elements in my Creator,
so I can use that as a condition.
Right? I can see a while.
There are elements in the iterator.
Keep on looping,
keep on looping
and if I want to get the elements
from the side greater,
which method I should use guys,
I should really use.
I prefer dark next right?
And now
if I use this,
I get all the elements using the
I creator as well.
Okay. Are all these five meters?
Are they clear? Yes.
So if you want to use another I later
will need new one
just to repeat the whole thing.
Yes. Yep.
Yep, yep.
Is this also good eye cards?
Yes. Yes.
This is also good,
but it will only print one element
because you are using a
break statement after it has
printed one element,
it will break right?
So you don't want to do that?
No. That some
that stuff is for another class
or maybe not at all.
By the way, by the way,
if these lambda expressions,
they are confusing you, it's
all because of Simon.
He asked me
to show those lambda expressions.
So this this is important
from the same task that I have.
We used this.
I prefer once in here
if I'm just getting this statement.
Don't worry.
Actually, you guys don't have the basics,
so it will be confusing for you.
I will show you
what are lambda expressions
and then I will teach you
how to use those.
But if I want to print the last element,
not all of it.
Yes, but you can also do.
Guys,
how can I only print the last element
by not printing the previous elements.
So I am saying God is to get
and as the index what I am passing
I am passing
car size minus one.
So what I am saying
I am specifying
the index of the last element
right.
So I get the last element. It's very easy.
You see.
You need to specify the last index.
That's it.
You can get the last index by size
minus one outside minus one.
Is it clear?
So maybe let's move to next exercises
instead of going deeper and deeper.
No, it's actually I want to
I want to show you because these
this collections framework is the most
widely used framework in real life.
You guys will not be using A-D
or anything like that
99% of the time
you guys will be using this ArrayList
class or add a class
or this kind of stuff to solve
your real life problems.
Okay,
so Nabeel said that if I have used this,
I tried to to print out the elements once.
Can I use it again
to print out the elements.
So this is a good question.
Let me but let me show you in another
class.
So I had a list.
I created one I printer.
I used that I tried to once
to get all the elements from this list.
So my question is,
if I repeated this code again,
how many times I will see these entries?
Will I see them twice or only once?
So this is the question from Nabeel.
So if I execute this code,
I see the elements
only once why it is happening?
Because once we have consumed
and I try to to get all the elements
from start to end,
then that I can not
can cannot be used anymore.
If we want to iterate again,
we have to get a new iterator again
as well.
So right now, because we have consumed
all the elements in here.
So you guys remember that pointer
pointer starts from minus one, right?
And Pointer was here for this
Hydrator Pointer was minus one
when we called the next method
once as next return does true,
we call the pointer log move here,
then here, then here.
And finally the pointer moved
to the last location
and there are no elements off of the back.
So we have not reset that pointer.
This triple pointer inside this hydrator,
it is still at the last location.
So if the pointer that like
look at last location
and like all this has a next method
we like that
brewer follow this
I will get false
and if I get false that loop
will never execute execute
and I will never get the elements right.
So if you want to do that again,
you have to all this line of code
again in here.
Okay, get the iterator again.
He has got to be iterator again.
Store it inside the again.
No, we don't need to give different name.
Well we can store it inside the same,
get the numerator and then execute it.
Now we will see all the output splice
because we create here we got a new to.
So every time you call this iterator
method,
you get a new type of task.
So getting the
new fresh.
All right.
Return again.
Yes. Now the pointer has again moved
to the initial location, has really sliced
and now we can use it again to move
to the next member locations one by one.
And can we get the elements?
Is there anyone
confused this question, guys,
why will you have to write this line again
to to use use the creator
to print out
why we cannot use the same iterator, but
maybe no one is confused.
All clear.
Okay.
All right. So this was task one,
braving the elements,
using different different methods to show
Can I move to the task to Yes,
ask questions.
If you have
you just duplicate the iterator.
I i you I re initialize
the iterator
for one.
I re initialize the apparatus
or you can say I reset pointer
so that I can use it again
to go through all of the elements.
Can I move to the next task based
to use a string of necessity
I did with string way.
Both of the waves are good housing,
but this
one that you have written,
this one is more work.
So if you have written this,
getting the element first
and storing inside a variable
and then using that variable to print out,
it's more good
because you remember if you are
calling the next method twice,
your pointer will also move twice
to memory locations to cells, right?
So you don't want to skip the elements.
Let's say you want to use this string
to perform
further operations on your data.
All right.
So once you store the data,
you can do anything with that.
Okay.
So the task to
create an array list of words, remove
every word that ends with E,
you mean,
can you check the list that contains E?
Did anyone else just hear a loud feedback
with feedback
from me?
Is there anything wrong with my mic
or it's happening in there
or I thought I have
just scared you guys
from our side.
So it was that loud.
I mean, I hope you guys are located
pretty far away from each other right?
Okay.
And then then maybe
I have heard that as well.
Ammad, what what about you?
You have also heard that.
So I heard it to Alex.
Like, just kidding.
So I'm
so this time, guys, I want to remove
every word from the list
that ends with E.
So can I use the for loop
for this
task?
Can I use D for loop or why loop
without the iterator?
No. Why?
Because I am
I have I might be doing so.
If there are any words which ends with e,
I might end up
changing the size of the list.
Right.
So it give me. Yes.
Sometimes it will work, other times
it will give you errors.
Okay, So it's not a good idea
to use that for loop. So
because we can be changing the size
of the ArrayList.
So this operation
might change
if these size of the
original list
is not a good idea
to use
loops
with out.
I k. So instead
I should first get an iterator.
I use lambda grade for odd.
That's great lambda out.
If you just after maybe ten
or 15 years
everyone will be using lambdas. So
I should fast to get the iterator.
So I should say I straight
and. Then string
I create is equal to
at least talk. I
and again I can use those simple methods.
Right
while
iterator dot heads next.
So I see if
let me use the best practice.
So I first store the data
inside a string and work the like I say
I prepare dot next
and then I write the if condition
and I see
new word dot to lower case.
And you guys don't need to write this lock
located or walk
out ends with
e, then what should I do guys?
What should I write inside this
F condition?
I should say
I created a dot of remove right?
And now
if I print out
the a list in here,
I should not see this oriented,
this life, this powerful
and this slap right.
So only car and lap.
Is it clear, guys?
This task is clear.
And Damir has used the lambda expression
that is also good.
Less less lines of code.
But first I will teach you the basics
about the lambda expressions,
and then you guys can start
using those lambda expression
expression.
They are very powerful lambda expressions
once combined with the stream API.
If there are eight
physical calls in your computer
and if the list has 8 million entries,
your computer will divide
1 million for physical for each
kind of the brain of your laptop.
They will be processed in parallel,
each of them,
and then the results will be combined so
it can increase your performance by many.
For if your computer has 20 or 30 course
physical calls,
you can reduce the time of your data
processing by 30.
By 2020 times or 30 times.
You can you can all your data
that much weight using lambda expressions
and steam API is
okay.
What about taking the E letter
from the world?
How to do that? Can it be done?
You Want to remove the letter
E from each word?
The linear
that that is also possible.
That is also possible.
Can you guys tell me how to do that?
So instead
of removing the complete element,
Melanie wants to only remove
this last element
from each word.
So first tell me, guys, will I be changing
this operation of changing
this operation, of changing the last
element, removing the last element?
Will it change the size of the added?
So what I can do
and if anyone gets confused,
it's all because of William.
Because it's
so fast, I notice that okay,
I will not be changing
the size of the list.
Right?
So I can use the simple for loop.
I can see
ArrayList dot size.
And then what
I can say I can say is spring,
SDR is equal to at least
to get I right.
So inside this SDR,
I will be getting all the
elements one by one, right?
So then I can check.
I can check if SDR DOT
to load a start and with
E if this is the case,
I want to replace this word.
So for example, I take orange,
I remove this E and I store the ore
and energy back on that location.
Right.
So what do I do?
I see
ArrayList.
Dot said
the same index.
I am starting the data
back to the same index back.
I am only only storing
the word, not the letter E,
so I use the substring
to get all the letters starting from all.
Still this D
I get all the letters starting from L.
I don't include this E so I use minus two
and I stored this data
at the same index back and now
I actually let me
copy to a new file.
But in any you did this where you remove
the last character instead of
removing the complete work
I was trying that all the
so we are done with the task
going here now let's discuss about this
other task.
Okay.
So after I am done doing this,
I print out the adding, I put
minus one
because the last element is not inclusive.
So now e is removed from our life, E
is removed, the is removed from purple.
And no, do you guys understand
what is going on in here?
How how this example is working?
You want me to debug this
or you guys understand this?
If he is in the middle
and then you guys can use the
and then you guys
can use the regular expressions.
You guys remember the regular expressions.
You can find anything from
in between
you can remove anything from in between.
You remember it will replace all methods
from the string plus
and then you specify
the character that you want to replace.
So let's say, for example, if you have
you want to replace something from
in between.
Okay, I am very happy to hear that Illini
that you guys have for that.
I forgot everything.
If so, I say
Spain, don't replace all.
And then I say
I specify
the regular expression, right?
And then I want to replace it with the
nothing, right.
I want to replace it with nothing.
Yes, you guys can use the replace as well.
You can use the replace as that.
So let's say oops, you want to use
the replacement
E and you want to replace it with nothing,
right.
Like this.
So if let's say
now the E is let's say in between right
or in here. Right.
So I have placed the E in between.
I can be truly proud of you.
Don't
replace the replacement
as as the are or replace.
This should not be happy.
It does not end with e
but I changed the logic, right?
Oh, because it is not going
inside this F condition.
We also have good change this with
contains.
Right?
Because if this condition is not true,
we will never enter inside this pullout.
Right?
If we never enter the inside this block,
then we will never replace that
or this this code will never execute.
And so
now the E is removed from in between as.
But could you wait a minute for Decode?
Yes. Can you explain?
What does this have to do?
So set
replace the element
at specific index.
So let me debug this code for you.
Actually.
So this code was to replace that thing
which ends with
and that's what we want this.
Okay.
So to remove it removes the E from words
from diverse
at the end
from any
let me, let me debug this code
and let me try to show you
what is going on in here.
So I placed a debug point first
and now
I am trying to debug this.
So if I check my variables window,
I have this error list in here right now.
I have all the elements in here
and they are
indexes are also specified
with those letters
and the value of I is right now zero.
So I get the element
index number zero
by this array list to get right.
And I want to
if I want to check what is stored
inside this SDR,
I can do that.
So intelligence is showing me
the contents of this variable
which will be stored inside this variable.
Then I check if I convert it to lowercase
and then check if this letter
if it ends with E or not.
Yes, it ends.
So what I do
now, I am doing
multiple operations on this line.
So if I want to check out the output
of each operation, guys,
is there any way that I can do that?
So I am doing side the subspace in land
law to right.
I can say
substring dot length.
I can create a white
for this to understand what is going on.
So SDR dot land is returning me for
I am subtracting one from the for
so I create a white for that I get three.
Then I call SDR dot substring
and if I call SDR dot substring
instead of life
because there are four letters in life.
But I am only getting the elements
starting from index
zero be index
three
so I only get l i
f with the help of this substring method.
And then I set that.
So right now if you observe
at index number zero still I have life.
So I have done my operation.
Now I want to store the results back
inside this list at index number zero.
So I set, I passed the index
I and then whatever result I have computed
So you guys will observe after
this line is executed,
I now see l i f instead of life.
So I take this thing,
I check if it ends with e
I remove the last letter and
I store it back in that index.
Is it clear now
then is
is it clear?
You guys can divide it
into multiple steps as well.
So if you guys are not comfortable
writing this complex score, So let's see,
maybe some you are still confused so
you guys can be worried. This
you can get
maybe you can write in page five of word
you you get these sides
inside a variable.
Then you can say in the last index
you subtract one
the sides to get the lasting bags
and then you say
spring new F you a new string
by using the substring method.
So SDR not substring,
you pass the starting index to this method
and the last index right?
And then you store
the newly created string,
the modified string back
at that specific location.
Right. So now if I have your this,
if you guys are not comfortable
writing all the code
in a single line,
you can divide your steps
into multiple steps.
So I get all the letters by one.
So first I get the life,
I check if it ends with e e s.
I enter inside if condition.
Then I calculate the length
of the number of characters which is four.
So I get four.
Then I subtract one
because I only want to retain the letters
starting from index zero one and two.
Right.
So I get this last index which is three.
And because this substring method,
it does include this three.
So it will do this instead of three,
it will treat it as two.
Okay, It is not inclusive.
It is less than minus one.
Oh, yes, I will do that as well.
So if
if you guys are confused,
it might be because you
you don't remember how this substring
method works.
What is this length returning?
So I encourage you to go back
and wash that again.
Right?
So I go to the life
and I sent it back inside the list.
Right now, if I check my list,
I have a life
instead of life.
Then I pick the next letter, right?
The next letter is orange.
It also ends with E,
so the condition will be true.
I get the length number of characters.
They are six. I subtract one,
which is five.
I call the substring method
to only get the letters, build
the index, build the letter G.
Once I have the letters still,
I store them back
at the same index
from which I got that letter.
And then I do the same again
and again and again.
Then that's how it is looking.
Is it better now?
And in its because I
and then as we are not
replace
but or something
and then I pass the starting index
and then SDR DOT and then my investigating
and remember guys for your interview
with your coding tests, questions from UPS
and methods from screen class
and this collection framework.
They are very, very important.
I have seen like 70% of the time,
even more 80 to 90% of the time.
The interview questions,
they are from these decoding tests,
they are from stained glass
and from the collections framework.
So make sure you remember
all those methods from this string.
Yes, for the testers, especially.
Okay, so should we move to
the next task?
That is stressful.
Yes. If you guys don't study,
you guys will be in stress all the time.
Oh, okay.
I looked.
Let me know once you are done typing, then
copy and paste.
You want this code?
I will share this code on the top.
You guys don't need to worry about this.
Still, if you guys want this,
we go
task number three
for the year in the store for drinks.
And you can send me that list.
Oops.
We had a list of bank.
If I have a or e, replace it with water.
So have you guys created a list for this
task and negotiated that list
so that we don't have to
give me.
I cannot use that list, you know,
can we have some gentle list? Oh,
I have heard of this drink
for the first time.
Sex on the beach.
What kind of drink is this?
And you knew you are great
if you drinking this
very popular drink.
It's actually a drink.
And then screwdriver.
It's also a drink.
Come on, guys.
Will you increase my knowledge?
Can you show me a picture of this thing?
I really want to take out this drink.
Modica.
Or in your work, I think.
Well,
but it looks great.
Oh, my God.
Okay, so
create an error list of brains.
Maybe next time I will add this.
We will beat the hell out of me.
If I.
If I had a tricky.
So if any drink has a letter e
or E, it should be replaced with water.
Okay.
So in this operation, guys, might changing
the size of the list
so no
and will only be accessing elements.
Or I also need to update the elements
inside the list for this task
update as well.
Right. So should I use enhance for law.
Can I use enhance for look for this task
can enhance loop.
Help us update the elements as well.
We only access the elements
using that list
that loop right for each.
We use.
It will only access,
not update for update.
And because we are not using,
we are not changing the size of the list.
I can use this simple follow. Right.
So looking for the comment
out here as well.
So a lot
changing the size of the list
and updating the elements so
we don't use
enhanced for
Lambda.
Yes, I can.
We can do it with Lambda.
So I see at least size.
So most probably
we will be learning about the maps.
We will be having an extra class.
I will teach you about lambdas
because you guys were confused.
So it's one.
And so we will not be having time to
complete all class or maps, but it's fine.
I will arrange an extra session for next.
You know, understanding is more important
than just coding the concepts.
So like I do,
I can see if
if at least
to get
So I get all the elements one by one
if they contains.
So I need to convert it to
lowercase as the likes for better results
so that I can get a uppercase or yes.
So at at least don't get
I get all the words one by one.
I convert them to lowercase,
then I check if that word contains
the letter
E right.
Okay.
So what
are or the letter
E, right.
Okay.
So I use or
by the way,
there is another way to do this
using
the regular expressions
in which you don't have to write
this condition twice.
But, but let's not go there.
So if the letter contains error
and e
then we want to replace that special
drink with water.
So how can replace it.
I use the
at least dot statement.
Third,
I specify the and next and specify the
length with which I want to replace.
Right.
And that's it.
After they are replaced,
I can print out that.
So do you mean you were first
to removing the elements
and then adding new elements?
So that's why we have this set dramatic,
right?
It performs both of these operations.
Yes. Dammit, there is a shortcut way
to word insert the OR within the first
word.
You mean in here? Yes.
So let me show you.
It's it's not that difficult.
So one trick that I have been using,
if you don't want to go in to
details, what you guys can do,
you guys can say the place
to replace all of
and you remember
inside the lambda expressions
that we can specify
multiple characters
but just
more useful when you have
multiple characters
for which you are checking.
For example,
any other characters like this.
Then instead of writing
all of the characters, if
I have been doing programing
for the last seven years,
that's why everything is on my fingertips.
You can you do contains E
and and that means
if both the letters are present,
then you will be in this condition.
Then only it will be true.
Yes, we can do the.
So this is another way of doing that
right.
And I am.
I am duplicating the elements.
But I hope 90%
you have not understood
what is going on in here.
Do you guys understand
what is going on inside this condition?
Okay, imagine we never coded this part.
No one, I mean, takes some time.
It's not that difficult.
It's.
Here we go. Damn it. Perfect.
If I delete A and E, the size will change
and it will be less
than the original size.
Right?
There's how I know that the letters
and ever present
only them here has underscore like.
Okay,
yes, let me copy paste this.
So this code is all inside
out of them.
So if I comment this out
so I now get all the same results.
So let me tell you nice.
Because when you guys will be writing
real life programs,
we will be putting tons of method
called inside of the same line.
I am calling one, two, three, four,
five, six.
I am calling six methods on the same line
and then manipulating the results.
So that's why it is confusing for you.
So what I am doing in here,
I get all the letters one by one.
So for example, I get this D,
I get this t I converted to lowercase
and then I replace the E
and E with the nothing,
which means they will be removed.
So I will only be left with the T.
Is this
is this point clear till this point?
Is it clear till this point?
I get all the elements
I remove and Andy that will reduce
the size of divide right now
if I call the length length method.
I will be getting one as the answer.
Right.
But what was the original size
of the letter?
Original Size was three.
Right?
So this size has been reduced.
That means the letters
E and ever present inside this word
right?
And that's how I have my condition.
If the letters were present,
then I am replacing that.
So I check the original size,
I get the list again
and I get the other list.
Remove the elements
and then compare their sizes.
If decided to reduce and,
that means the letters were present
and this condition is now true.
And now I replaced that. So why? Why?
We have
why you have followed this approach?
Because in in in other case,
let's say if you are checking for five
or ten characters, you have to write
a very lengthy if condition.
So instead of writing
that lengthy condition.
So let's say for example
this drinks is not replaced
so I can put that that s as well in here.
This will also be replaced.
I don't have to copy
and paste again and again.
Yes, it is
more useful
if there are more than two letters
that you are trying to replace.
You see that that has also replaced.
So there almost everything is replaced
because all the letters contains e or
S, So this is regular expressions.
Maryam When we put B, e, e
and S inside these square brackets,
it means this or condition,
it means this or condition.
This means either the letter is present
or E is present or S is present.
Replace any of these.
If any one these is present
replaced for the or.
Okay,
So I have created some
so I have created some ripples
based on the interview questions
that previous students use.
I have have got in their interviews.
I have created ripples out of all
those interview questions, common ones.
And after the next week
I will release those ripples as but
so you guys can test
your knowledge and can test
how much more practice
you need for Java.
Or should we move to the next task,
which
next week is last
for Java?
I mean,
you guys will be writing the Java code
throughout this course
and for the rest of your life
if you are going to be an automation
engineer, I will teach Squirrel
and Jenkins and then I will prepare you
for your interview.
I will sit with your coding pads.
But don't tell this to anyone
because we had ten task.
I think we will have today's class
only doing those tasks.
It's fine.
It's fine if you guys, those
who are comfortable, the tasks
you guys can leave if you want.
But I don't want to rush
and I want to spend some time
on regular expressions.
Come to our selenium classes also.
Yes, the reviews will still be there.
Okay.
Are you guys done writing the code
in reviews?
I, I have planned something else
to page you a little bit in-depth.
Knowledge of collections, framework
and dealing
with objects.
How, how, how.
How is your selenium classes going?
Are they confusing fun?
Easy to learn, hard
remembering a lot of syntax,
right?
Will there deeper knowledge
learning those x spots right
or less for me,
not easy.
And doing real things is always better.
Better than Java.
Here we go.
Okay.
I like Java more
fast for
right here in Java.
For real.
It starts
worse than Java
spasticity
because the rest of your life
will be with Java.
So I will not suggest
to use these kind of words for Java
because if it here's to you
those words, your life will be very tough
to start, right?
I guess for more classes
and you guys will be done with selenium.
That's it.
Oh yes.
I am planning to visit Amazon
for that roster.
Okay, so create there.
There used to be a roster with me as well.
I think it was in batch. It
and then
it disappeared.
It's now part of me
just right
you give that
will create an array list of even numbers
from 1 to 50 right
and remove any number that is divisible
by five from that list. So
so first
I have to populate a list
that has all the even numbers, right?
So what I can do,
I can create and edit list
what should be the data type guys,
What should be there.
Right. For this task
in pride.
Oh, but I get an editor for in.
I cannot use the primitive data types
with collections particular so
so now
I have to populate this list
so I save for I.
I start from B to
mean it should be
50 right
less than equal to and then
I is equal to I plus two
and then I say or numbers don't add.
I but you guys understand
what is how
I will get all the order numbers.
What is this
I is equal to plus two boys don't.
Oh there should be one numbers.
Yep. That's
if even number.
So if I execute this
problem
I get all the even numbers in here
right.
So this is one of the ways
of doing things.
You can increment
the I twice for you can use I modulus two
if that is equal to zero,
then you put that element.
But in that case, you guys are doing extra
steps, right?
It's always good to reduce
the number of steps that your computer
has to go, both to go to go to,
so it will increase your performance.
So instead of putting that, if condition
then checking each number
and looping through 50 elements,
I am only looping through 25 elements
and I am not writing any
if conditions right.
So imagine if you have to do it for 1
million entries.
Do you mean in your case you will be going
through all 1 million entries right
then checking all those 1 million entries
and then inserting inside the list.
It's also good at this point.
It's also good.
I'm not saying it's about did you change
the order number to even number at once.
So it is
shift and f6 on your keyboard.
It's called refactor
and everywhere we are this
the variable value is used now A now
they will change that variable inside
all of the code,
even if it is used 50 million times.
So all those 50
million entries will be replaced.
You can also do this by right clicking
and then refactor and then rename
and got it.
Okay, so
once I have all the numbers in here guys,
now I have to remove any numbers
that is divisible by five from the list.
Now what?
One way of doing this
is I remove the elements.
I don't even add the elements in here.
Right.
So in here now I can put condition
right in here
and then I don't actually add
of those elements.
Well, why would I add those elements
at the first place?
But I explicitly wrote this line
so that first you guys create a list
and then I trade through that list again
to remove those elements.
I created this list manually. I
literally created a list manually,
but I wrote the Me too.
I want to have a salute for you ladies.
What if I put 200?
Like you will be doing this
amend with you 400 as well.
What's the point of teaching?
You look
well if you have to do it manually.
We are not looking for an easier way.
That's more time for the task
as long as it words don't take it.
Maybe I should add
using a loop as well for the next batch.
And maybe I should add
maybe, maybe I should do it to 500.
Then this students will think,
How can we do it for 500 numbers?
Right? Maybe that.
But then again,
maybe then they will use their mind.
Right.
Let me that
it is this task
application.
Okay. Let's see
what happens in the next batch.
And I will explicitly ask
from the students what they have done
for this.
I did manually too.
And after that I think it's not good. We
okay, It's fine.
It's fine.
But you should click your mind.
It should click your mind.
You are always more than welcome to ask
this kind of things in this sports journal
articles.
First, it should click your mind
that you are not doing something right,
and then you can consult your friends
and ask someone else
maybe what approach they have used.
But in your case
I say if you would have asked
and and then and I'll ask someone else.
You'll get that right.
You will be very happy
that all everybody is doing it manually.
Let's do it manually.
If Okay.
So I was just kidding. It's fine.
It happened some time.
So now I have to remove
the elements from this list.
Yep. Now.
Now I think you guys will remember
it forever, because now
you will
always try to look for better ways.
So that's why I saw all the gasp in the
classes.
So, guys, this removing thing
will change the size of my list.
So what should I use?
If you can change this side of list
I hear me use and I create the
what should be the data
type inside the site rate.
Today's
in beta, right?
Because we are dealing with numbers now
a beta equal to new.
And then I can see
not me, I can say even number
I triple
delete them manually
by using remove one by one.
Yes, I said so did
you guys also removed manually one by one
by specifying 50 or something like that?
Or do you guys use the look for that?
No, we are not at all in here.
You guys have used the looks.
So while
I will be
given the first task on the company
and the manager will ask
how much time you need, I will say,
let me let me go through the task
and then I, I will get back to you
and I can looks at the task
or let's do it manually.
It will take 50
is let's let's ask what 55 years
from the manager
that has next
I'm just kidding
a lifetime job yet
by the way I have done this literally
they give me a very useless task
and they asked me for the timeline
and I said it will take three months.
And I literally took three months
for that task
because it was all repetitive.
Same task again and again and again. It's
so if
so I say integer
number is equal to
hydrator dot next.
If that number
is divisible by five,
I will be getting the modulus and zero.
Then I say I try to start putting more
and I printout
the again
and yes logo.
You guys are genius.
You are already using them expressions.
Right?
Reducing one, two, three, four,
five, 5 to 6 lines of code
you are guys are doing simply in line
nine 2920
in here
I am dividing each number by by five.
If the answer is the remainder is zero.
I mean the number is divisible by five
and I am removing that.
Not 21, 20 or 21.
Yes, in 21 I am doing this
dividing each number by five.
If the remainder is zero,
that means the number is divisible,
completely divisible by that number number
is completely divisible by five.
And I remove that
I mean 2020.
I am only getting the elements
one by one using the next
line. 20.
I am getting all the elements one by one
and storing inside number variable.
Is it clear
moment?
Is it clear? Yes.
I was wondering
if integer needs to be gone
consistent and not used in.
No, you can using you.
You remember that
concept of wrapping and unwrapping,
not wrapping, boxing and unboxing.
So now I will automatically the data types
if they are the corresponding ones
from wrapper to primitive and primitive.
So you can use the integer as well.
Okay, now let's have a break.
Next.
That also works
because
yes are enough.
It also works. It's also good.
What I explicitly wanted you guys
to write a separate loop to remove.
So first add and then remove it.
But it's also fine
if you guys followed this approach.
All right, guys, please be back before too
many questions.
Before we leave.
I just
I just wanted to have
you have some practice with that later.
That's why I am doing it.
Additionally, otherwise,
this approach is more efficient.
No questions.
Okay.
Please be back by back to well.
And you guys sent me
the statement for task five
here.
The class insurance
that will have an attribute
the insurance name and implement
the behavior
as net code.
So let me
change this name
to insurance.
Okay.
The name of this class
create a class
that will have an attribute
as the insurance name.
So Let's create a glove
attribute insurance name
and unimplemented behavior
as in that code for.
So what would be the return type
of this matter?
Guys, I'm asking about the return type
so it can
be logged or it can be a double
that returns the code.
Okay, so let's do it.
So I first just specify the
access modifiers, right?
So if I check, there is no information
of abstract on, on the access modifier.
So let's use public
and then let's get for the non
abstract modifiers.
So we need the
right as the non access modifier
and then the method return type
and then the method name.
So get group
right.
Why I get an error
this class should now be abstract
because I now have one abstract
inside
here.
Can I make this static?
Can I use static here?
So if I try to use static
I get an error. Why?
Why? I'm getting another date
because
static didn't go with the abstract.
If we make static
it will not be inheritance contradiction.
Static is something that this year
the abstract is something undefined
until defined.
Starting born during compile time.
Then I override static
methods.
Then if I cannot override, then
who will be providing the implementation
right?
Can I create a constructor
inside this class?
Inside the abstract class?
Can I create the constructor?
Yes. Like.
So I will now be using
most of the time shortcuts.
So right now I am using all and insert
to a constructor
and I suggest you to start using
the shortcuts as a
okay,
so I have called and then insert.
Let me repeat, if we guys didn't see it
all, insert constructor then okay.
And constructor is created.
Okay.
Then create three subclasses dog part
then help you.
The class bar extends
insurance
and has its own attribute
as call car model, so
alternate alternate insert
the string
or model
and then I have to implement the method.
Right?
Otherwise I will be getting an error.
So I implement to get called
this this abstract method
I implement to cancel insurance.
Mac don't have all these options for Mac,
but there is no requirement
to have a constructed here.
You have this insurance
field for hard and here
whenever you have an instance field,
you should always create a constructor
for that.
And then there is non default constructor.
So constructor is also created
for this
car model and
car model equal to the bottom line.
Is there any issue in this code,
guys, that I have written
this line
is right, otherwise
Java will not be able to distinguish
between local
instance variable 23
missing This.
So let me let me implement this.
That's a code
for all
model
or model
from insurance name.
So. All right.
I don't have this insurance
name inside this class
from where this insurance name is coming.
So don't don't I need to put super in here
or this fine. Why?
It's fine.
And when I should use super,
What if I have the same name field
in here, in there, or still fine.
Or do I need to use super now?
Okay, so
if name name field is
present in the file and the
parent class,
then we could use this
loop.
You with the name
right?
And then I can write
a very
simple implementation,
then create a pet and health class
as well.
Create three objects of subclasses
install them in ArrayList
using for the was for loop
greater access
all the matters of the class.
Okay, so let's create the class pet.
It also extends the insurance class.
And if it extends the insurance class,
then what I have to do, I must
override
these two methods.
Right?
And because our model
is not tethered in here.
So I must
back type in here instead of
our model.
So model, car model.
Can you please show me your page?
Yes. Is it better now?
Are both creating this something?
But I
thought it was important to prototype.
And now Max called
for a fact
type or type
from this insurance company.
And then we should create
the health insurance as well.
The health class as well.
So class, health
and insurance
override the method
and have
no income structure that
let me know once
you guys are done typing difficult.
If you are typing it.
I did it with the constructor and without.
Is that okay?
It's okay, but not a good practice.
If there are instance failures.
Always always create a constructor.
You're not there.
Be a string inside the class
Health class
is it mentioned?
I don't think so.
It is mentioned.
Are you guys done typing?
Let me send this code in the live.
Just and let me push it to the top
as well.
Let's take 2 minutes, type it and
I will be right back in just one minute.
Are you guys done typing?
So let's create and released
what should be the data type
that I should mention.
Now, guys,
I have to store the
objects of that and then health
and then cough
insurance, right?
Because the parent object and hold the
all the child.
All right
so I see God
is equal on new car
right.
Let me specify
the insurance and then
because
and then let me clear to the backlog
and then the insurance name
and health as well.
And then
now I can use the ADD matter.
So insurance is stored and
I can store
it, I can add it, and then I can add,
as I added them to at least right of it.
There's also would actually let me do that
if it's better to do exactly
like you did like this
is your perspective.
So now how can I call all
the methods I can see for it
works would be the data type.
And you here guys.
Insurance.
Insurance and then
insurance. Yeah.
And then say I and
Connecticut and I can not
cancel insurance.
Same polymorphism
and legal territory.
Is that a legal
when an individual character
or you guys
give me one more.
Oh come on
I think I have to now fix
all of these.
I think 3 to 4 more.
Okay,
fine.
Mean, here
we see the outputs from all of this.
By the way, there is one more thing
that I want to show you that
it is called to do list on your companies.
You might be getting these to do list.
So let's say
you are writing some piece of logic and
you have to add
something to that, that logic, right?
Or maybe you are given a task
to create
only the class name, method names
and field names, and you want to
leave some type of comments
for the other person.
So for example
I can write this double double for slashes
and then this capital to do
and I can put anything in here.
So for example, create a
new method.
I mean, here and
implement it.
So now what will happen
all the list of four
for all the two rules,
if you on this to do a screen in here,
you will be getting the list of all
those classes which contain these photos.
So let's do for example,
you are writing a very big project
and you want to change something
in some of the places.
So it's kind of a marker,
a kind of a command
that you can access from this window
if you put forward slashes
and then capital to do after that.
So you can keep track of your ten years,
you can put comments
and you will be able to access
all of those totals from here.
So your artifacts, most likely
they will be using tools.
So they will be putting these comments
that you have to implement to matter,
that matter to pick this subject
and this blah, blah, blah.
And then they will
share the project video.
So what you guys will do is
you will go to this list, you will start
implementing the meters from top
when you
complete
it, although you do erase it. Yes.
So once you are done, let's say
you are done this task, you remove
this, it is removed from your list
and just a good way to keep track of
the tasks that you have to incorporate
in your projects.
Are there any questions
from this insurance task?
So next to the next task
on this
and with the requirement for the next task
is to guard the last
to create
a card class that will have implemented
and unimplemented methods
and a constructor that will initialize
the card
type created to your subclasses of card.
Create three objects of different cards
for them inside.
A link list used for loop advanced form
part later to access all of these matters.
All right, so
let me
zinging this to card.
Yeah,
let me put it a field
as a card by
now. Okay.
And then I have to create a constructor.
So I use the shortcut or insert
constructor.
It's created.
Then I have some implemented
and implemented method.
Right.
So let's see.
Public Lloyd
issue
the card
in particular.
And about the card I include
and then some unimplemented method.
So let's say for example, public
abstract.
Lloyd
There you go. Let
me know.
My class would also be abstract.
Come on
in now.
I don't get any others.
Okay,
Now I have to create three classes.
Right?
So let's see.
Class
credit card
interest.
The card
and the
first business.
Then maybe 10%.
Then I create the
private class, and then I see
your interest is zero.
And then maybe I can create ID
prepaid
class. Then
you must
agree on the
vehicle for.
Okay.
Delivery. Incredible.
Guys, has anyone created the test
for class? Only?
A simple so
linked list is equal to link list
name place priority.
And then we specify the data type
which will be card the parent of all.
And then I said link list and and then new
credit card.
All right.
So this loop
is the third of
interest.
So those who were following me,
we send you this test record.
If you are unable to do the changes
clicking.
Okay, again, very simple.
The purpose of this task was to show you
that how we can use the polymorphism in
with with the array lists as well.
And in this class has been
are there any questions from
this task place?
So we had
each again
simple, just implemented and implemented
method.
Each class is implementing the method
which is unimplemented in the parent
you can put solve out
or anything like that.
And then I am calling all the methods
using a loop.
But first, definitely
I have to store the objects
of all the classes, no questions.
All you guys are done from inside.
Is it because of the use of out to
nothing?
Could be an actually very easy
practicing the speed typing
easy peasy tasks.
Right?
Is there anyone who was unable to do this?
These tasks?
I am even partly data
from outside as well.
It was
by Berkeley who are not completely
you are still alive
after taking 30 Java classes.
I did not finished two tasks only
we are
still alive.
So then there was this meme
the humans God, please
let the year 2021 be better than 2020.
But you guys that still alive,
still fighting
now. Oops.
That a
there any questions
from this task of our anyone.
So basically our mission is to kill us
and checking if you still learning or
the no no that's not my mission
you guys have to describe
the company is still right.
We will be destroying production server
and all the data
if you guys are dead
we need to review.
So most of I am here.
The task was to create a class card
and create any methods.
Basically, one is sure to be implemented
method that has the body and the other one
that does not have anybody.
So I created one method that was
completely implemented in the parent class
and the
other one which was abstract method.
And then I provide the implementation
in all the
in all the trial classes.
Next.
The other thing is
I am only creating a constructor
and then I am creating the object
of all the classes,
adding it inside a link list
and using it for loop
to get all the objects one by one
and then call the methods on that object.
Same polymorphism concept.
The only difference here is that
instead of previously
we were using arrays.
Now we are using lists.
In the previous example,
I use the array list and here I am using.
This is the only difference.
Otherwise they are the same examples.
If you guys remember,
realize, remember this kind of examples?
I showed this kind of examples
earlier as well in the polymorphism
of the so
now you guys have good grip on intelligent
and on Java.
So in the next class
we will be learning how to
to write and read Excel files text
PHI is properties filed with Java.
Okay then you guys pull the data
from Excel files
and put the data inside
different different fields.
And if those fields
they allow that certain type of data.
So you guys will be able to perform
the data testing, right?
The test case cases, for example,
if you want to check a field,
if that allows maybe
special characters
or numbers or letters
so, you guys will be creating
different different combinations
of this data in your Excel,
then you will link that Excel
to your Java program.
So Java program
will read the data from Excel,
and with the help of Selenium,
you will insert data on a web
or inside of the web fields in the text
fields, the buttons,
and then you will check if that field
allow a certain type of checked are not
is doing that again
this word, but
what am I doing again
breaking the brand if it's a
task, I know you guys will be able to do
that after one class.
Believe me,
you guys are ready to join us?
End. Is there still English guys?
Can you send me the next task?
So in the next task,
we will move to hash map.
Yes, but hash map will not take 5 hours
manually creating the event numbers.
It's fine. It's fine.
It happens.
It's a
I hope
this rocket is not destroyed completely.
There was this,
I think, Japanese or Chinese guy,
billionaire guy who
whose rocket rocket was passed
and whoever
he was going inside of that space station,
that is there and he is dead now.
Health
and technology entrepreneur
flew into the space on Blue Origin rocket
with an actor, William Shatner
last month died Thursday
in a New Jersey airplane crash, and state
police officials
and people risk their lives
to have these kind of experiences
that are key.
So before we move to
the next task,
can you guys tell me about starts?
So this start interface,
what is the
what are the properties of sets?
So START is also an interface like list
as we have classes
at least ten linked lists
which implement the interface list.
We have the set interface
which is implemented by hash said
Bye bye,
risking my brain for learning java
or linked to high set and then preset
so cells.
There is this inherent property
of the service that they can not
they can't have
duplicate values.
Right?
And so if you don't want to have
duplicate values
and let's say
you want to maintain the order,
which type of set we can use in that case,
we can use the
link, the high set, right?
So this has the property
that it will not have duplicate,
plus it will
maintain the order.
Then we discussed about the
simple hash set.
It's fast, but no
in order.
And then the three hash
effect,
no duplicates plus
that is started.
And to be honest,
in my seven years of experience,
I have never used sets other than
for this kind of tasks.
So this task five is the only use
that I have seen in my entire career.
So let's say,
for example five, task five says
that we have to
remove the duplicates from the list.
Right?
So we have a list
and we want to remove the duplicate order
and duplicate. Yes.
So Gene is twice, right?
Jim dissolved supplies.
So if I want to remove the duplicates
guide from a list
without using this type,
can you guys think of the logic?
Did you guys try to write logic?
Remove these elements
without using salt or something?
Or maybe you guys can.
You guys think of the logic now
equals method using if
tried but give up.
It's not easy right?
There are special algorithms
like bubble side model side.
You guys can read those.
Actually, there is a complete course
six months course on that are structures.
There is this complete
my six month course on design patterns.
So instead of going all of that
maybe the simplest way what we can do
we can remove the duplicates
manually like right I show where we can do
and duplicates removed.
I can do another six months.
But if you don't know, how about the data
that you will be getting inside the list?
Come on.
So it's very simple, right?
That's why I told you this today.
Just create a new set fact
bring that is equal to new
link the high set
because we don't want to lose that
that order
and we pass a list inside this set.
Now tell me, guys, what is the property
Now you can
ignore that file from compiling.
So for example, you can share the code.
Why didn't you share that?
Edited with Shiva in the sports channel?
Okay, focus in here.
Don't tie focus in here
and then we will fix your
issues.
So, guys,
we know that this is a collection, right?
This is also a collection, right?
So what collections
can all of these collections,
they have this property
that inside the constructor,
if I pass one type of collection
inside the other one,
they are automatically
converted to back type.
So when I passed this list inside, this
constructor now it has become asset
checked without and SEC does not allow
duplicate entries.
Right.
So all the entries,
they are removed, right?
They are removed.
So what we can do if
we have to remove something.
Okay, we can take the existing data.
It can be a list, it can be a linked list,
it can be an area.
Also, we can convert and add it to list
and pass that data to that set.
Now, Set will perform all the
duplication removal procedure.
And because this procedure,
if you are dealing with a big data
and if you are writing your own algorithm
first, it will it can have buckets.
The second there can be performance.
So this start is all already implemented
by the best industry experts.
So what you can do is you can easily pass
this data inside
be certain that the duplicates are gone
and you can get a list back from as well.
So you can see a list is equal to new
ArrayList
and you can pass this setting here.
Let's say, for example,
maybe you the data in the
in the list
now in the original list and sorted
and sorting out sorted
you can sort as well
and no duplicates
so this is how we get back the list
we send new list
and then past the 13 here.
Now it will become a list
and again the duplicates,
they are gone so we don't have to write
any piece of code.
If you want to sort data
and you want to remove your data,
always use the SAP,
search the new search set
not at all list, not clear,
at least not add some.
It's also fine for one.
Yep, it's also fine.
So now the duplicates they are going.
Can I please see your notes? Yes.
They are very big problems
in computer science sorting
and removing the duplicates.
And there are so many algorithms
which have been
so research over the years
to solve this problem.
Yes, it's fine. It's fine.
So how how how was the two days class?
Was it still confusing
or you guys now have much
more better understanding?
What is the difference between link
the hash and preset?
So tree search will sort the data as well.
Copyrighting for odd
confusion is down 20%.
So these new classes,
they are only used to solve this problem.
Then if you guys really want to those
so long to go deeper,
you guys can search. But
the you guys will
find a lot of algorithms
just to sort the data.
Okay.
Very complex ones
much sought absorbed
in search and selection bubble.
And there are tons of tons of research
on these algorithms
and they are very simple, right?
It's easy.
This is just a piece of code
that will remove
the duplicates or will sort your data.
So those who want to do it on your own
don't want to use search
may be right or the preset. Yes.
You guys can also write this logic
in here.
It's very simple.
There is this integer law high in left
and right eye is left.
And then we are going left and then right
we are doing the middle plus one, then
left, right and then left is equal to K
and then I and J.
They both top zero right
and then left is if left and right.
Right. Simple.
We are saying attic is equal to left.
So that's the reason
why we are teaching you about the
sex sorting and removing duplicates.
It's very complex task.
Yes, you guys
can write the code on your own,
but you should use these building
data structures.
They are the most efficient one.
If we go that deep,
then we will get around. Yes,
here is the code.
Then you go over the last three lines.
So in here
I am creating a link that has said Why
because I want to maintain the order,
plus I don't want it duplicated.
So once I pass this list
to, assert
all the duplicates will be removed
and we get back a set
and then once the duplicates are removed,
I can get a list.
It's again from this session.
I can get the list back.
So I am assigning this list variable
to a new list that does not contain
why you put into line number 19.
If you don't want to blend,
let's see also.
Fine.
I just printed those so that you guys can.
Yes, you guys can use the set.
So I just sorted because what if you
the data in the form of a list,
not in the form a set
how we can get back from a set to a list.
This is how we can get back.
We can again
create, list and pass this item here.
Now we have a list. Yes.
The only important thing is to remember
what kind of search
to use for the specific requirement.
If you guys don't want to
if you guys want to retain the insertion
order,
plus no duplicates,
which which type of set I should use.
Guys.
Non duplicates
plus want to retained the order?
I should use the link. Dissect
what if
I want to sort this back to as then
what if I want the thought
to start as well?
I want to remove the duplicates.
Plus I want to store a thought director.
Then I use the three set
and then if I only care about speed
and not duplicates,
then I should use the haystack. So.
And they are very simple.
Just passed a list, remove, duplicate
and all that and get it back.
Your list
are the more tasks
or we are done.
Three more.
Really.
Well let's do you guys want to do it
now or tomorrow?
Tomorrow. Tomorrow. Tomorrow.
Okay.
Let's do it tomorrow.
Guess so.
If, if something is still confusing you,
you guys can post back
in the sports channel
and I can help you out.
Blah, blah, blah, blah.
Okay, I got it.
Yeah.
Tomorrow, set the
map for tomorrow's maps.
So, do we just rewatch the video fash map
for tomorrow?
Yes, If you don't,
if you are planning to delete everything
before you go back and go to bed.
So maybe you need to rewatch
that for tomorrow.
Are you enjoying giving us a task
that you didn't even pay attention
to how much you did give us?
Nicole I told you last week
might to 25% of my brain was working.
I don't remember what happened
with you guys in the last week.
They only attacked the comments
when I was feeling better.
I checked the comments
and a lot of you were complaining
that the last class was terrible.
So that's why I read it at class.
I don't know.
How much does I give to you
that day.
So I have this already.
I don't know.
With every time I get this flow,
it makes me terrible.
Only remember this.
Maybe I should not have.
No, no, no. COVID. It's simple.
Seasonal flu.
Maybe I should not.
Maybe I should have canceled that class.
But anything
I think you guys, it's kind of a revision.
And you guys have
learned something as well.
But I took it out when the timer went off.
Not on.
That was the smoke alarm
your knee
or that was the.
All right, guys, take some rest
and I will see you
guys tomorrow.
Bye bye.