I hope you guys are doing great.
Checking to check that.
Malik Salam Sharif, how are you?
13 120 So, yes.
Aisha, you should only see rebels still.
One 2030
I will release the rebels on the variables
keyword
access modifiers,
constructors, this keyword
so I will release around
30 more rebels today.
And then for your quiz,
I think the quiz is also ready.
I see more than 120.
So those are the rebels that you see
after 120.
They are the previous batch.
So you guys are only supposed to solve
until 120
Is the quiz
rate is 11 two days for think.
So let me give you one week for this quiz.
Just keep an eye on the deadline.
Is there a mistake on 119?
Answer why?
Mohammed Mine stops
and one one line and skips to 127.
Should I see 120 as well?
And yes, you guys should see this as well.
The 121 that is related to variables.
Okay.
I did one our time off with two
and now it does not
show me the results
or not.
The new day was last night.
So if you go to that, I, I take
now you can see the results
because the example
and if you don't see the results
shared a screenshot
in the course in the syntax sport down
because the example of code
does not match the answer
for computer signs.
So you guys don't see this
number one quantity.
Let me and publish
your candidate can publish it again
and does not show me.
Just check now
checking out those
who don't see the results.
Are there any other issues
that you guys want to discuss
before the class?
Yes, you if you guys don't see 120,
you have a lot of
and then you have to log in again.
All right. So we are left.
So this week
there will be two classes
and then two classes in the next week.
And from 30 you guys will be starting
the selenium classes.
So guys, you still have two weeks
before you start the selenium classes.
You should know all the Java concepts
that I have been teaching to you
or I'll have property.
Okay?
Otherwise the selenium classes,
they will be very tough for you
because in here you guys will be using
all the concepts, all those loops, arrays,
classes, methods and everything
that you guys have learned to build
some applications which will actually be
doing something useful.
Yeah.
Like for example,
opening the browsers on your computer,
clicking on different buttons on websites
and you guys can write an email
or whatever you can do manually
on your computer inside your browser.
Almost everything you guys will be able to
do using your Java code.
And if your Java skills are not code,
you guys will not be able to write better
programs or you guys will not be able to
even you guys will not even
be able to
understand the code that the instructors
will be writing for you.
So you guys still have to make sure
that everything is good
and you guys
and you guys have some practice before
you start your selenium classes.
All right.
So today is class number 17
and there are 10 to 12 more Java classes.
So you guys are also
almost also done with Java.
So make sure you guys are not for
not for not forgetting
what we are teaching to you.
Otherwise, as you move
through this course,
things will get messy for you.
Mohammad please post in this for channel.
So today is class number
and at the end of today's class
I will also share two videos on
one will show you the instructions
on how to install the intelligent
and the other one will show you how to use
the basic features of the intelligent.
So right to watch those videos as well.
Before you do this class, various
class number 17.
So let's quickly realize the concepts
that we check if we can
know we can't
open intelligent
for there.
All right, guys.
So yesterday is this Hondo
question, please revisit
why is second modifier
to a method, say a static
when there is already a public so now
Well first
the static is not an excess modifier.
Static final synchronized abstract
they are all known access modifiers
while public private protected
they are access modifiers.
So that's why we can have
a non access modifier
and an access modifier
in in a single matter.
All right, guys, what do you guys remember
about the access modifiers?
Well, what is access modification?
And giving access or controlling access
may be more appropriate, right?
Or maybe limiting access.
It's fine.
I we have just started.
So access modifiers, they are keywords
with control.
The access or
members, right?
Or what are members guys
what is,
what does this member keyword mean.
So keywords, keywords
which control the access of
members of the blocks.
Can you guys tell me
an example of a member of a class
so matter to the member of the class?
Right?
Variable is a member of class.
Everything that we define
inside a class,
they are called members of desks
in that class.
Okay, so
they can be creoles,
they can be methods, they can be
instructors.
Today we will learn about the constructor.
Today we will learn about the constructor
and how many access levels we have in Java
or right.
We have more
access levels in Java.
And how many keywords are there
to control these for access levels?
How many keywords we have?
We have three keywords. Okay.
Not for the default is not a keyword.
If we don't specify anything
that's alert, that's when we mean default.
Okay,
so there are four access levels in Java
and to be
keywords to
control, to
control these access levels.
Okay.
And if I ask you what
is the most restrictive access,
what is the keyword
that we use for most restrictive access?
So we have the
okay, so we have the private
and what comes after private
be protected.
Then we have the default,
which is not a keyword,
and then we have
the public ones, right?
So let's discuss about describing.
So what happens, guys,
if I write this private keyword
with a method or a field,
what happens to that
feel field or method
only in class,
It can only be accessed
inside the same class.
So if we write
for either keyword
with any class
number,
you can be
accessed only
in that class.
Yes. Then we access on in this class
and we we
are not discussing the protective one
we will use.
This class will be on inheritance
and then the end of that class
I will discuss about the protected one.
Remind me if I forget.
Okay, so then we have the default one.
What happens if I, if I don't provide
any keyword, any access modifier
with the member of the class, it's
accessible in same package.
Within that package.
So if we write, if we
do not write name
keyword with
class members,
we can access those members
inside
the same class and
in any other
any other class
inside the same
even in the same page
package. Yes.
Then we have the public.
Public Uber.
Okay, what happens, guys, if I, if I write
the public keyword, it is universal,
right?
Can be accessed everywhere
inside the program.
If we use
public keyword
with and
class member, that member
is accessible
and we will
be in the anti project
or quality best practices
here.
They always make my field private
or public or default
or should be the best
practice guides for the fields.
Always
try to declare the fields as
as private.
Always
or to
declare be
methods as
as public.
Okay.
Or you can see
more.
Most of the methods are
declared
as public,
but sometimes you guys will be
declaring the private methods as well.
So let's say, for example,
if you are writing a method
and you know that this method is specific
to that class, only
then there is no need
to make those matters as
public.
Can you please again clear
from yesterday's accounts task and task to
the we're not we are not same approach.
I want to understand
how to choose approach.
Any place
I can clear from yesterday's
account class.
Now, what do you want me to clear
Which method is more useful?
Should if it depends on on your program
and depends on your requirements
assignment
that protected keyword
is related to inheritance.
On Tuesday
we will discuss about the inheritance
and then we will call over the perpetual
keyword,
declare private
and change to public later.
No, this is not what we do now.
We are never first to declare
something private and then change it
for public.
What same approach
we don't use in task today.
We don't do that.
So most of the time we use
private or public keyword.
Yes, Most of the time
you guys will be using these bookkeepers.
How about non excess 25?
So up till now you guys have only learned
about one non nexus modifier.
The static one.
And I hope you guys already know
when you should be using this static
and when you should not
be using this static.
If it's not clear sorba,
then you should be using
the static keyword with variables or
everything that turns.
So now we always try to declare the fields
as private.
Okay, we never do this
first will be closed in private,
then change them to public.
And then we most of the time you guys
will be seeing the methods as public.
Okay?
This is the approach that we used
in the task. Be
so in here,
the task task explicitly
in the task, it was explicit,
only asked that
the method should be private.
That's why we made this method as private.
Okay.
Otherwise the best practice is that
we always try to make fields private
and most of the times
the methods they are public.
All right, so
today
we will discuss about the constructors.
So first let me show you the constructor.
What is a constructor?
And for the for the example
for this example,
we will be using the famous class.
What is the most famous class days
that we use?
For examples,
we build class right?
That we know.
Once you guys are
bored with this blog example,
then I will look for another example.
So let's create a dog.
Give us.
How about Bird?
Yes, we will see once you guys are bored.
So we still have almost 13 more classes.
So have you guys watched
the videos on constructors?
And you can you guys tell me a little bit
about the constructor?
What is a constructor?
Same name as class.
Okay, so this is one of the properties
of the constructor.
It's like creating object.
Okay, you are close.
How soon?
All in one is a block?
Of course. Similar to my third.
Yes, that is more formal.
Sebastian.
It is a block of code,
but method is also a block of code.
And then what is the difference?
Constructor is so similar with methods,
but same name as class
and without a written type
similar to a method.
Initialize is object called
an instance of class object created.
All might go there.
That's the perfect definition
and block of code similar to a method
that's called
an instance of an object is creator.
So this is
this is a good definition of code.
Creating too many classes in this same
method are creating
too many classes in the same method.
Now, this is this is this is not correct.
No, it is helpful class with making
less code lines with parameters.
This is a keyword.
They are not classes like matters.
I'll building on
the constructor
is a block of gold.
It is very similar to a method.
Okay.
But it also differs from the method
in many ways.
So the first difference is that in meters
we have the written types,
but the constructors, they don't have any
written types like a method.
It can have any name, but constructors
they have.
They always have these.
They always have a name,
same as of the name of the class.
So same name as the name of class.
And then we have to explicitly
call a method
by writing object name or sign
and then method name.
Then whatever code override
inside of that method is executed.
But for constructors.
Okay, as soon as we create
the object of that class,
the constructor is executed here.
So let's try to create one
constructor in here.
So constructors as they don't have
a return pipe,
but can they have access modifiers?
You guys can constructors
have access modifiers? Yes.
So let me write constructor.
Let me write an access modifier
for the constructors of public
and then the name will be same
as the name of the class,
then parentheses
as we have the parentheses format first
and then
to create brackets.
Okay.
And let's put this out in here.
And as you
have some fields as well,
and there are seven methods
so far, methods we need to return type.
So we write word.
We can also now start using the public
keyword because we have learned about it.
So public void
the name
and then we simply filled out
the name of the dog.
Okay,
so this is the constructor for this class?
No class.
So it has the same name
as the name of the class.
In Method, we have this return type,
but in the constructor
we don't write any return type,
not even wide.
Okay.
So if you try to write right word in here
now Java will create
this method,
this constructor as the method.
And if you hold your mouse in here,
the eclipse does not show you a warning,
but intelligent will tell you
that you are trying
to write a method with the same name
as the name of the class.
Okay, so
we should
not be writing the written type in here,
otherwise Java will not treat them
as the constructor.
Okay.
And then we have parentheses
as we have the parentheses for a matter.
Oops.
And after that, whatever
we can do with a method, for example,
we can pass the parameters in here,
as we can pass the parameters to a method,
and then we can write
any piece of logic in here.
And that logic
will be executed automatically.
When you create the object of that class.
Let me add, I can test
oops class.
So. So how can I create
the object of the class?
Is it either or?
Can you construct or methods?
And use constructor or method?
You'll get a
Can you rephrase your question?
Can you elaborate a bit more?
What more do you want to ask? So
we can create the
object by writing the new keyword.
What is the purpose of the constructor?
I will show you the purpose
in just a minute.
Constructors and methods are same.
Are the constructors and methods same guys
and you guys still should.
If if the methods
and constructors are same.
No, they look similar,
but they have many differences
so if they are not same.
So when to go for constructor
and when to go for method, somebody
just give me 2 minutes. Okay.
One or 2 minutes I will show you
the purpose of constructors
and then you guys know
when to use my holiday.
So what I am doing in here,
what is the proper
terminology for this line of code
that I have written in here?
What I am doing in here, in
I am creating an
object, okay, I'm creating an object
and so this keyword,
this new keyword creates the object
and then you see this dog
and then parenthesis
this piece of code
that we would argue in here,
it will actually all this constructor,
once this line of code is executed.
So can you guys
tell me if I execute this line?
Will I get any output on my console?
So yes,
because we are calling the constructor
we will be getting.
This dog's constructor is called.
Okay.
So this is the difference between a method
and a constructor.
For a method to work
what you guys have to do.
You guys have to
create the object.
And then on that object
you explicitly call
a method.
So that's when the code inside
the method is executed.
Okay. But as soon as you guys write the
yes, when as you declare the object
of that class,
that code is already executed.
Okay.
So as soon as the object creation
will happen inside the memory,
all the code inside
this block of code will be executed.
So can you guys now
tell me where it can be useful?
So let me repeat
as soon as the object of this class
will be created, the piece of code inside
the constructor is executed.
So can you guys
tell me where it can be useful
so you can also guess it from its name?
So constructor it comes from construct
and we are trying to construct an object
right after entering
username and password.
So every piece of code that you guys want
will be executed
before any method is
called on your object.
You want to put that code inside
that constructor.
The initialization of the variables.
If you want to initialize the fields off
your class, you want to do that
inside the constructor.
If you want to set up anything before
anyone can call any method on your class,
you want to do that
thing inside the constructor.
Okay, so all those
let's see all those pre requirements
pre wrecks.
Okay that you want to have before someone,
you start using any thing
from your class, any field or any method.
You want to put that code
inside the constructors. Yes.
Those beams can also be achieved inside
the method, but then you are not sure
that if that method is called or not
before
that person is using your classes
and that can
that can lead your class to misbehave.
Constructors
initialize the object with the default.
Yes, be the default and
you can put any value inside that as well.
So you'll get the all the initialization
of the fields
or anything that you want to set up
before any method or field
is accessed from your class.
You want to put that code
inside the constructor
so the party school
for and most of the time
we will be
initializing the fields inside a class.
So let's say, for example,
we have some fields
here,
so we have some field.
Now what we have been doing up till now,
we have been explicitly
accessing these fields
in here
and we have been assigning the values
to these fields.
Now if you use the access modifiers,
you guys know
that we can not access the fields
outside of that class, right?
So what we will have,
we will be having something like this
in real life.
And as soon as you make your fields
private,
it can only access them in another class
days.
No, we can not access.
Then how do we initialize these fields?
How do we initialize these fields
automatically?
So what we can do
use in methods and
then column matters in different class.
So what we can do,
we can force these fields
inside this constructor, so we can say
string dog name, string log.
Well, calling
constructor and creating object
is the same, right?
And these are dogs all the same. Yes.
You cannot call a constructor
without creating your object.
So they are.
They are something
very closely interlinked.
So now previously
you guys didn't have any mechanism
to force
this class
that whenever
the object of this class is created,
the values for these must be passed.
Now, if you have a parameter constructor
now, the object will not be created
unless and until someone is passing
all these things inside the constructor.
So now you are forcing that here. Hey hey.
The user or everyone
that is trying to use this class,
you have to pass these values
for my class to work properly
and then you can call any method
or you can use any field from my class.
So now you are forcing this
with the help of a constructor. So
it all
name is equal to
dog name
unless specified.
So yes.
So you can create
a parameterized constructor for this.
Okay.
Now no one will be able to call
any method
on your class.
Sorry.
Can you repeat?
Because I missed last 5 hours.
So certainly which line
you want me to explain.
And if you have missed more,
more than that, then
I think it will be better if you can
ask me this question during the break.
Or maybe you can watch the recording.
So what I will try to give you
kind of a summary.
Let me complete this code.
So breed
is required to
dog breed
and we reported the dog age
and in the last we had
the dog bit
of weird, right?
So now you guys see that
in here.
I am getting an error now.
Okay, so Java is not allowing me
to create an object of this class, okay?
And if I cover my mouth,
it says this constructor
without any parameters.
It is not defined.
Okay, that means now,
if I want to do anything with my class,
I must pass
these values in here.
Okay, so let me put an input in here
so that you guys can see.
Can you guys tell me a breed bulldog,
maybe the data breed.
Right?
And then we have the age.
Maybe then
and then we maybe then fly. Fly.
So now, as soon as
I was all the arguments inside this method
do we should pass all values or not?
No, I'm not.
If you don't pass even a single value.
So let's say
even if we are missing this weight,
you will be getting an of now
it is a must to pass all the values
inside this constructor
if you want an object of this class.
So now we have enforced this
with the help of a parameter
sized constructor.
And now you can call any method
or you can use anything from this class.
The player
dice those
who are asking for the constructor.
The use case of a constructor
when you guys should use them.
So it gives you more control over
how your class is.
Constructor, how your ID, how
the object of your class is constructed.
Whether you want to allow maybe
initialization of only two fields
or you want the values for all the fields
before anyone can use your class.
Okay.
And it also gives you like
I see that there's more cleaner code
instead of accessing the fields and
by writing this object's name in here,
it's a it's a sharper code
and it's more cleaner.
And you can see
all the values in a single line.
But same thing in method parameter.
We have not forced to pass
all values in parameter.
Is this correct? Yes, it is.
This behavior is same
inside method, but the method
totally depends on you.
You can
you can not call the method of a class
and you can still create an object.
We don't want to do that.
What about if we want to create
another dog?
These same rules will be applicable
if we try to create another dog.
Global.
So now
if I call this method,
what are what
I will inject on my console guys?
How many lines I will see
now we my execute this code,
this dog's constructor is called
because I have this printout in here
inside the constructor as well.
And then I see the bubbles.
So you guys see this sequence
before any method call or anything.
Always, always.
The constructor is the executed first.
Why I am getting an error.
Silva Is there no one
in this potential certainty
from which line you missed
the in the class?
Silva on line 15.
You okay?
So on line 12 the name
the dog name is with a lowercase.
You have to make it uppercase.
It's your capitalization issue.
So certainly this, this,
this code in here,
this is this special piece of code
that we call as the constructor.
Okay.
And the purpose of constructor
is to initialize
the fields of a class.
We don't have any
written type for the constructors.
The name is always
the same as the name of the class,
and then we can pass
the arguments like this
and that's how we initialize the fields
inside the constructor.
Okay.
And when we clear the object in here,
the values will be passed in here
and the fields will be initialized.
So constructor.
It's a kind of having materials get ready
before construction of an object happens.
No, this is where the construction
happens, you know,
This is where the construction happens
all to print all variables of constructor.
You mean for one
these variables, this dog named or color?
You you.
You can just write a print out
inside the constructor.
Then you can print them
same as with Dementors.
When you create the object,
the value given
has to be in the same order
as constructor. No.
Okay.
So in here, if you are asking me
about the sequence. Yes.
If this is a string,
the first should be a string.
If the second value is a string,
the second out of the if it's the same
as methods,
same as with the methods naming.
So I cannot do this,
I cannot pass this. Then
in here.
Okay, so the sequence should be same.
Same as with the methods
are we going to
face with this kind of task in real life?
So not almost everything
that you guys are learning
in this class,
you will be facing more than this.
These are just basics.
You guys will be facing more than this.
If something is not that important.
I will tell you about that thing.
So private on name is one less because
we enter it in public void,
we can access it and everywhere
so alone now we can access it everywhere,
but we cannot set it from everywhere.
So still it's more better
than having your field as public
because when you have something as public,
everyone can set any value to that
and you can also put
you can also have a mechanism
inside this method that someone can
if someone is passing
some piece of information,
only then this information
is visible to that
from first.
And you went right new dog in
object it was print dog
constructor is called
and now to call dog
dog new dog.
So Sunday is not
the expected output
or what do you expect instead
how can we print
the other variables on constructor?
You can print you want to print
inside the constructor. Guys
you want to print inside the constructor
or you want to write methods
to print out those values.
Yes, I will add the differences
and the differences are also
mentioned in this slides.
Can we use constructor with any method?
Chérif.
This question is not technically correct.
What constructor
has to do with the method?
You may be asked?
Can we use constructor with any class?
Maybe this is what you mean.
Oh yes, we can clear the
constructors for any of the classes
and then maybe we can write
if I want.
Print Edge I, M.J.
and 2221
Alexa on my Alexa
on which line are inside the dog class
or the dog test for class.
So in to print the variables,
we have to create a method for it.
Yes, we can, but we can also print it
inside the constructor as well.
If you want, you can also
print inside the constructor in here.
Like for example, you guys can print out
the values of
dog name like this.
You can also do that, can
okay, you can get specific terms
as well.
Like this
one to go for constructor
and went to go for method.
So constructors.
Most of the time you will be initialized
in the fields and you'll get the
converse.
Then you
should be going for the constructor.
Can we create any method
inside of constructor?
No, we can not create, but we can call it.
So for example, we can call this
print name
or print page inside the constructor,
but we cannot define a new method.
It looks like we can use method
after constructor
to put some conditions inside for you
in real life.
Makes sense.
So pretty much everything
that you guys can do with the metro,
you can do with the constructor.
But the difference is
that constructors are called
automatically when the object is created.
The constructors don't have a return type.
Constructors cannot have any randomly.
The name must be same as the class name.
Then we can say print
it like
this.
We get this line
and all constructor is called
because we have placed this line
inside the constructor.
We get this body
because we are printing the name
of the dog inside the constructor.
We get this then
because we are printing the age, we again
get this name
because we are calling that method
and we get this age
because we are calling index method.
Specifically
it clear guys,
why I'm getting five lines on
on the console.
All of
within the plus
variable is is a built in word
or we create them
put in the breed print name print page.
No, but we have created both methods.
I think I am starting to get good
and we have private constructors issue.
We can have private constructors,
then we have multiple constructors.
Yes, we can have multiple constructors.
Can you clarify lines 18 and 23?
So this line 18 is a simply print out
statement number.
I am printing the value of this variable,
so whatever value is being passed
from this constructor in here,
it will be copied to this variable
and then it will get printed
on the console next in line 23.
It's again same. It's again same.
But this time this,
this method is printing the value
of the instance variable.
In here I am
printing the value of a local variable.
This is the difference.
If you are asking. Yeah.
So dog name is a local variable, but
name is an instance variable.
If we can have multiple constructors, will
all of them be named with the same name?
Yes. They will all be having
the same name. Yes.
Selecting.
Scroll down.
So let's try to read a little bit
about these constructors.
Let's try to understand some rules.
What is more cleaner code download
print the name or case out dog name.
This one is more plain.
The writing a method
and then calling a method.
Can we create another constructor
and create another object as an example?
Yes. The next example
they mean we will be creating more objects
and we will be creating more constructors.
So I don't want to complicate
this example.
So let's keep it to initial stages.
I want more examples for sure.
Yes, we will do that, more examples.
So if you guys are comfortable
with this piece of code
and if you guys don't
have any questions, then
maybe we should move to the next example.
I just want to see two constructors
in the same class to see how it works.
Don't worry, we will learn about that.
Are there any questions
guys, from this example?
The constructor
sequence should be same when we call it.
There is no such thing
as constructor sequence.
Then it's because whenever
you will be creating the object,
the constructor
will automatically be called
and you cannot call in method
or anything like that
unless and until you have an object.
So a sequence will always be same.
First, the object will be created
and then you will be able
to call any methods or anything.
So you cannot do this.
You cannot call a method first
and then an instance method first,
and then call and create the object.
Yes, first we will go through this slide
and then we will do more examples.
I mean, name, breed, age and so on.
Yes. This one, they can be anywhere.
They can be anywhere.
You can even write it in here.
You can put the age even in here.
No issues with that.
No issues.
I did not understand how we got five lines
output.
Would you please show your console again?
So this is my console
line nine in dog tested?
Yes. We can change the sequence in here.
Three methods.
We can print the age first
and then the name.
No issues with that
button.
Do you understand?
Now? Okay,
so printed in line
18 will be using line six.
Line 26. Yes.
This line 22 print page
is being used from here.
All right.
22 and 26. Yes.
You mean what is
what is the issue in line 22
and 26?
Automotive need, line 21 and 22.
Mine is different.
The Sure, your output is different
for main line.
Okay, so let me put these matters back
because this is the best practice.
First we declare the fields,
then we try to deconstruct first and then
we write the methods.
And don't forget output.
Then you have to share complete
screenshot of the dog
best drug class because you are having
some issues on that.
Also, share the complete screenshot
of error and post these kind of issues
in the sports channel.
As always, there she will assist you
and let me know guys, once
you guys are comfortable with this code
so that we can move to these slides.
When declaring the figures, do
they have to be private?
It's a best practice,
but you can have any type of food.
Depends on what
you are working on, I guess.
Not really.
Jamie Farley feels it's
always better to have them as private
because you don't want others
to mess your dirt
on that
you will be storing inside your class.
If the data is not correct,
your methods, they can misbehave.
So you are so you always want to have
the fields as private
and then maybe write a method to
set of values for those fields
or initialize them
through the constructor.
But before you do that,
you write some rules.
Like for example, inside this age
field,
you don't want the negative values, right?
You don't want maybe values
more than 3000 or 200 or like this, right?
So that you
you don't have bad data in your class.
Why did we initialize the parameters
inside the constructor
while we already had it inside the class?
Well, almost.
Where did we have it?
Inside the class in here.
I am only defining variables.
In here I am assigning values
to those variables so it's not seen.
This is called a declaration.
This is called initialization.
These are two different things.
How can we print out the line?
14, 15 and 17 on dog page
down the line, 1415.
Same as we are doing
with these other variables.
That is why need to put into private.
We still use them later in the test
subclass.
So in here
I am doing it through the methods.
Okay.
To keep this example simple,
I am not writing any rules in here
and I am simply printing out the values
in here.
But in real life
you guys will be writing some rules
if you want to protect your data.
What about
when working with other coworkers?
Does not it have to be public
so they can access it?
Sebastian
You made the access through matters
because if there is a not a developer,
right?
Like said,
if they can change the data of your fears
in set in such a way
that they can manipulate your matter,
they can control how your methods
will execute, or they can break your code.
So you don't want to do that.
That's how the applications are hacked.
They don't control
if you are not controlling the data
that is flowing inside your class
and that is flowing outside of your class,
you are potentially letting others to
others to make your code misbehave.
You don't want to do that.
So public double blind,
then use a constructor in other words,
and members right methods.
Yes, they are matters.
This is a constructive
this is a constructive approach.
Think about the applications
like banking applications.
If I design up data
of the applications, the financial data
of the application right,
you don't want anyone to set
any random values to your fields, right?
Because this data will be having
so much value in real life, right?
You don't want to create a class in which
anyone can set any account balance.
So this is very important
how you you control the access,
how you control the flow of information,
log this.
You're creating an object.
And this is also a way to call
constructor. Yes.
You get to on the second line.
You are also creating a constructor
and calling a constructor.
Are there a lot of accessible classes
in Java like Scanner?
Then someone changed the methods
inside this kind of class?
No. For these classes
they are only readable.
You guys cannot change the code
inside that JDK.
So which way to follow?
So you'll get that
if you are planning to use that object in
after this line.
So like I am calling it a method,
then you should be first
just floating the object inside a variable
and then you can use that activity.
If you are not learning
to use that constructor,
then you
you don't need to store that in a variable
and then call the methods on there.
Most of the time
this is what you will be doing.
We should do separate out.
We should do separate this out
for each constructor
if we want to print out all of them.
Yes. No.
You can also use the single source out
and put all the variables inside that.
If we are able to change Java class,
there will be no Java.
Yes, you are right.
You guys will destroy all the Java,
all the JDK.
Can you give a real
life example of constructor?
Yes. That hard?
I can give you a real life example,
but at this point
that example will not make sense
because you guys
are not aware of the real life
that you will be using.
So for example, so one of the example
is this kind of class
you guys remember
you guys used to pass system DOT in,
so that was the constructor call, Okay,
That was something from the real life.
So if we say scanner, scanner,
scanner,
you see,
if I am not passing that system dot in,
I can not call any method
on the scanner class.
I cannot execute
anything on the scanner class.
So how that how Java guys are forcing
this?
They are forcing
because they have created a constructor
that expects that system
in and then only you can use course.
So if I
hold on my control button
and if I click on this scandal,
you will see that in here
you have a constructor
and Java guys need this information
before you can use any of the members
from this class.
Yes. System dot in.
We are actually passing a parameter.
We are passing an article
and this is the parameter.
But how does it make sense?
And you will see there are multiple
constructors and every construct
constructor required something
in here as well.
And then you can read these instructions.
What are they?
Why we are passing them and all that.
But in the next example we will create
constructors
like, like this cannot last. And
you guys remember that
String Builder class?
Almost all the classes
in Java,
they have constructors, all of them,
99% of them I can't name.
There will hardly be any class
without constructors.
So if I again hold down my control button
and if I click on the string builder,
you see again,
this string is being passed in here
and I have written something in here
that is using that string
and you guys can see
I have another constructors builder
that takes
this job sequence and under constructor
and under constructors.
So basically these are different ways of
constructing this string builder object.
Okay, thing builder object.
So most of the time
you guys will be seeing 15
to 20 constructors per class,
or at least five or ten constructors
per class
in real life.
Is it better now?
Farhad, who is Alexander,
he wrote something in the chat on Zoom.
My clips right there
to constructor dog dogged undefined
Alexander Can you send
the messages in the check
in the slack
in the light question?
Send them
suggestion.
Can we please go through the slides first
and then we go to the examples.
If you explain each slide and
give an example I think that will help us
a bit.
I have asked this in multiple badges,
so almost all of the students,
they like the examples first
and then the slides, they make more sense.
So now if I
then I will be going to the slides.
You will see that most of the things,
terminologies will make more sense.
So I can I can follow any of the approach.
It totally depends on you.
If majority wants me to go through
the slides first, I can go to the slides.
No issues.
It totally depends on
you guys how you want to learn.
Okay, let's to the slides.
All right. So
yeah, so constructor
in Java a constructor
is a block of code similar to a method.
So you see, now
if I am reading this sentence,
you already have kind of an image
inside your mind.
What is a constructor?
What is a method?
And then you can relate to things.
You can ask more exam,
more questions, more
better questions.
It is called when an instance of the class
or object created
and the memory is allocated
for that object.
You need a special type of method
which is used to initialize the objects.
Okay, so this is the purpose
of a constructor initializing the object.
Okay.
You can be having 100 fields
in your class.
Okay.
And if you want to force that, everyone
first
must initialize those fields,
give initial values to those fields,
and then they should be able to use
or class.
You force this
with the help of constructor.
And now there is also a not
so before this constructor example
we never created, but
it is not an object constructor.
Yes, constructor is not an object.
Constructor is something different.
So guys,
before this example we never created
a constructor, right? So
what was happening behind the scene?
Always. Always.
Your compiler was creating
a constructor for you.
So if there is no construct
building a class
compiler automatically creates
a default constructor.
Now what is the default? Constructing
the construct per
without
any parameters
is called a default
constructor.
Okay, so this is what we call
as the default constructor
me constructor
which do not take any parameters.
So when you guys don't create
any constructor
at all compiler
automatically behind the scenes, right?
This piece of code for that's why
you guys were able to call this dog
and then empty parentheses
for all classes that you guys
have been creating the objects for
because a default constructor
was already there, always there.
So this is actually calling
that constructor.
This is the syntax.
If we don't have a constructor,
we will be getting an error.
So your compiler was
adding a constructor for you
and this
is called the default constructor.
Okay.
It's necessity to compile your code.
All right,
So for example, we can ask you to type
the username and password for enter
the construct ideas
and only after that
something inside
this constructor will be happened.
He has done this.
You are right.
So these are some of the terminologies.
So when we create an object,
so when we write the name of the class,
right?
So this is the name of the class.
Then we write any name for the variable
for the object.
Okay,
so it is also called a reference variable.
Then we borrowed this assignment.
Operator. It's an assignment operator.
Then this new is
actually where your object is created.
The keyword used to create the object.
And this of code that you guys write
name of the class and in parentheses
you are actually calling a constructor.
But then you guys were not
this constructor.
Your compiler was doing it
automatically for you.
Okay.
That's why you guys didn't get any errors.
And then this is just a semicolon.
There is always a constructor,
whether defined by user or by default.
If you define one,
then Java will not creative default one.
If you don't define one,
then in default will be created.
And my right
constructor is the same as a method.
It is an
it is a name as the class name
as soon as we call the class on and
as soon as we call the class on an object
and no, no, no.
This is where you should practice.
When you create the object of a class,
the constructor is executed automatically.
If we want to make it private,
then we have to put
some fields in the parameters.
No, that is also not correct.
If you want the constructor to be private,
then you don't have to make any fields
private
or you don't have to do anything
with the fields
as soon as the parameters are passed.
Constructor. No,
as soon as you
write the constructor,
that's where the constructor is called.
It's not related to parameters.
So in every object creation statement
there is a construct of Yes,
there is always a constructor
when you are creating
object.
Okay, we will do the other examples. So
when we create instance object of a class
using new keyword,
how to understand
and remember all this form.
Now you guys have to go through the slides
again and again,
and after you start your job,
this will be on your fingertips
because this will be your day to day tasks
like writing the code, debugging code,
checking others code.
This will be your day to day tasks
so you guys don't have to memorize
these things anymore.
And then you are
always allowed to use Google
practice, practice and practice.
Try some more. Easy for now.
That's the key.
In order to use the constructor variables,
we still have to add new words.
You can also try all means if that helps.
In order to use the constructor variables,
we still have to define them first, right?
we still have to define them first.
We can just define them
inside the constructor. Yes.
Give me the if you are talking
about the parameters,
if the button and magic means
for your brain, become a tree,
and if when we create
instance of a class using new keyword,
a constructor for that class is called
new keyword is used to create object.
In Java
we okay
then we create object.
Who is born with that is lucky
otherwise all month will not work.
The two
years guys, we have some real stuff on TV.
I lost my brain
and I have to save the mental.
We don't have a leaderboard
hospital here in the US
when we create object
by using new operator
after new keyword back
part is constructor.
So in the part that you guys are right
after the new keyword
is actually call to the constructor
and it is executing a constructor.
All right, so rules to declare
constructor constructor
not allowed any return type, even void.
Okay,
so if you put a written type,
your java will get confused.
Okay. It will not
be that as deconstructive anymore.
So let's say for example,
if we put void in here
and if now I executed Discord,
now we already have starting
getting the other
and so it says the constructor dog,
blah blah is undefined.
So as soon as I put any return type
with the constructor that construct,
that constructor
is not a constructor anymore.
Now it is treated as a method.
Okay.
And you will be getting an error on that.
So this is not allowed with constructors.
We go there for having fun sometimes.
Constructors name class name must be same.
So the name of the constructor
and the name of the class
they must be seen.
I know these are desperate dramas,
you guys.
Even if you guys spend one odd per day
going to the slides,
you should remember all of this.
Easy for you.
Not for me though.
There are two types of constructors
no argument
constructor in which we don't pass
any parameters.
Thank you. I spent 5 hours.
Are we okay?
And then we have the parameterized
constructors.
Okay, so this is the example
of a non parameterized constructor
in which we are not passing
any parameters.
None is default.
Yes, this one is D for.
This is the constructor
that is created for you by Java.
Then you don't create one.
I You have a bad migraine over 24 hours
now and focusing now
and trying to understand
this compilation makes it worse.
So now when you have the situation,
think about in dollars
that you will be getting
when you get a job
that will resolve your migration
issue.
That's exactly what I am doing.
So this is called the
non parameterized constructor,
the default one.
And this one other one is the parameter
constructor.
I will never get rid of animals.
All right.
So inside this class,
if we are not declaring any constructor,
then compiler generates zero
argument constructor
with empty implementation
and the time of compilation
is called the default constructor.
Now this is how the default constructor
looks like.
So there will not
there will not be a single line of code
inside the default constructor.
There will.
There will be no parameters
for the default constructor.
So this is the code that your compiler
index for you
in your source code.
Get there dog and prior to constructed
by Java is a default constructor public?
Yes. Simon.
The default constructor is public.
Can we go for break please?
Yes, we can go for debris.
Definitely.
So we will discuss this example
after the break.
So let's have a shorter break this time
and the next break will be a longer one
and we will be solving some homework tasks
during that break.
Extreme.
All right, guys, please be back.
And please,
please remind me about the recording.
Is there anyone who can take this
responsibility?
Alexandre,
You have to post in the sport channel
if you are facing any issues.
All right, so we have multiple people.
That's great.
Let's see if you can remind me about this
because know it has already recorded the
has already coded
the Java program to remind us.
All right,
so this is how the default constructor
looks like.
So the compiler generated constructor
is called the default constructor inside
the class.
Default constructor is
it is in invisible mode.
So your source code that we write in Java
plus it is converted to
something called Bytecode,
and then that bytecode is translated
to the machine code.
And the machine code is the actual thing
that is executed on your computer.
So when it is converted
from the source code to the bytecode,
that will be compiler index,
those that default constructor
default values are assigned by JVM
to the fields
like zero or null, depending on the type.
So you guys see in the class
the instance fields.
If we don't assign any values
and if we try to use them,
we get the default values.
So who is assigning those default values
to these fields?
Is the JVM.
If any constructor contains
list of variable as in its signature,
I guess. So.
You guys don't know about the signature.
Do you guys know about the signature
over.
So this part that has this name
and the parameters is called
the signature.
Okay, the name of the class
Sorry, the name of the constructor or
the name of the method and the parameters.
This part is called the signature
of that Metro constructor,
and it's a very famous interview question.
What is it?
What is the signature of a method?
So it's only the name plus the parameters,
not the return type,
not the excess modifiers,
not the non excess modifiers.
The header, on the other hand,
for hard header also includes
these return are these access modifiers,
return types and non access modifiers,
but signature only means this block
parameters and name.
All right, so if any constructor
contains a list of variable
in x signature,
it is known as parameterized constructor.
Can you remind us in March?
Sure.
You will be having the slides.
You can go through those lines
and you will remember everything.
A parameterized constructor by the way,
apart from Doc, we will be having
we will continue having these sessions,
even if are done with the course.
So let's say for example,
if you guys don't understand
certain topics from Java or certain topics
from gate manual testing,
you guys can request us to host
those sessions again
and then we will arrange the instructors,
then we will host those sessions again
at the end of this course.
If parameterized constructor is one
which takes some parameters.
Okay, Parameterized constructor
is used to provide different values
to distinct objects.
Okay, so we can pass the parameter DE
and these parameters.
They will be assigned to fields
and we can have different different values
for different, different object.
So this is just an example.
This is a class
and this is the constructor.
And in here
we have some list of parameters
and that's how I create those.
So I pass value one value to
or I can say new class value one value,
just passing those values.
These are some important points
related to the parameterized constructor.
So whenever we create an object
using parameterized constructor,
it must and define
parameterized constructor.
Otherwise we will get compile time error.
So we must first
define in that constructor
and then we can call
the parameterized constructor
whenever we define the objects
with respect
to both parameterized constructor
and a default constructor.
Okay.
Can we call signature
also in typical method? Yes.
The signature is actually a term
from methods which the constructors also.
We can also use this term
for the constructors
and I am saying it again.
It's a very important interview question.
The difference between the method head
or they might ask you
if written type is included
in the method signature or not.
So the matter signature is only name
plus parameters, no return type.
Whenever we define the objects
with respect
to both parameterized constructor
and default constructor,
it must define both the constructors.
If first we must have those tokens factors
and then we can only call them in
any class
maximum one default constructor.
So only one default constructor
but and a number
of parameterized constructor.
So we can have
as many constructors as we like.
This is just another example
of the parameterized constructor.
So we have both Fields A and B
that is the name of the class.
So we again create a test,
then we boss integer values,
then We just put a green card statement.
We assign the values to the fields
and we are also printing values in here.
And this is where I create
the objects of text class
and all the parameterized constructor
will.
This is the name of the class.
Is this a construct provides?
Is this first one a constructor?
No. Why?
Because first it has a written type
and then the name is not
same as the class.
Is this a constructor?
Is it a default constructor?
No, it's not a default constructor.
Default
constructor is created by a compiler
and it does not have any lines of code
inside there in here.
First we are creating this constructor.
So again,
we have a line of code inside of this.
So this is called a zero argument
constructor.
Okay. Not default.
Is it also a constructor? Yes.
This one is a
what do we call this type of constructor
parameterized constructor.
So compiler generated
zero argument is called B
for constructor user
defined as zero argument.
Constructor is not a B for the constructor
constructor article are local variables.
Okay, so we are creating these.
So in here
I am first calling
my guess and let me clear this out.
So in here guys, I am creating an object
and I am not passing
anything to the constructor.
So can you guys
guess which constructor will be called?
So I have multiple constructors
in this class,
but on first line am
trying to create an object and I am not
passing anything to the constructor.
So can you guys tell me which constructor
does this number one
or this number
to which one of them will be called
the first one?
So compiler can automatically detect this
that if you have multiple constructors
and if you are not passing a value
in the form of arguments Java can detect
and it can the appropriate constructor
if you have multiple choices.
And when
we pass something to this constructor
now in Java, know
that there is a constructor
and this time
the number two will be called
this one.
So that's why first we get this output
and then we get this output
and then we are calling method one.
So there is also a print out statement.
So that's why
we get these print statements.
What if two constructors have same data
type inside its prime?
It's not possible.
MUHAMMAD If you put same data type,
you will be getting a net of
your smart allowed
same name and same data type in chalk.
If this signature is same,
you can not have two methods
with the same signature,
you will be getting in that.
What is the difference between
a user defined and the default one?
So default or default one,
he knows it created by compiler.
It does not have any piece of code
inside it
and that is called the default one.
The zero argument one is defined by a user
and I can put any piece of code inside
that is Mohammad.
So if these constructors, they belong
to the same class, you cannot do that.
You cannot do that.
You should not allow.
And also guys, this is also not allowed.
So this time I have only one constructor.
So when I write at least one
a constructor,
the default constructor
that Java provides, it's gone.
Okay.
Now compiler will not create
that default constructor.
So as
soon as I write at least one
constructor,
the default constructor is gone.
Okay, Java will not provide this one.
And now
if you tried to call,
if you try to create an object
and if the signature
of that object call is not mess
with the signature of this constructor,
you will be getting an error.
This Constructor is expecting an argument,
but I am not putting any argument in here.
If we try to do that,
we will be getting an error.
Okay.
So now only
this constructor is accepted, but
what is the difference?
Zero argument in default
and in defined is so zero
argument is defined by user
and default is defined
by compiler. Okay.
So you can also sorry if we are trying
to compile below application,
the compiler will generate
error message cannot find symbol
because compiler is unable
to generate the default constructor.
Okay.
So as soon as you write your own
constructor it can be zero argument.
It can be one argument to argument.
Any argument Now default one is gone
and now you must pass those arguments
inside the constructor call if you want.
That ought to be compiled.
Is it clear, guys,
why we get an error in here on line 14?
So far the rules of same
if you want to call a private matter,
how do you do that?
Same way you can call a private
constructor inside the same example.
What is confusing there?
Last part why we have an error.
Can you guys, can you guys tell now why
we are having attack on this line?
So now
in this test class,
is there any constructor
which does not take any parameters?
Where is that constructor which does not
take any parameters in this class?
Then you tell me the line number
is So
because this constructor on line,
Salman is expecting
an integer to be passed
and we are not passing that in there.
That argument.
That's why we got an error.
It is a signature matching issue. Yes.
And will you are you are right.
Is there anyone else
who is confused about this error?
No one is confused.
All right, let's do another example.
Let's
let's do it.
For example, this time, just
if there are two arguments
in line seven and we pass only one,
then it would still be an error.
Yes, it would still an error.
That means everyone is not sure
if they are confused or not.
All right, that's great
to hear.
Thank you for letting me do this,
this information,
letting me know about this information and
all our values.
So tell me about some fears of
a thought
I can have
them here.
This would be a number.
It can have characters, right?
It's not only numbers,
it's the players, particularly as
it's you guys tell me.
Two more fears, simpler one
that everyone can understand
is already there.
I can go out and check my car
and if you want it
or what modified mileage
match.
I think that these are enough.
So let's say, guys, I have this car, okay?
And I want to use the best practices and
I want to use the best practices
and I want to initialize
these fields
with the help of a constructor.
Okay, so how can I create a constructor?
Works for I'd
does.
Your field has to be private?
Yes. It's pathetic
if we make them private.
Okay, so
let me quickly do act.
So I need to write new car
or public car?
New car.
I'm not making fields private.
Okay? I need their.
Can we make them private?
Yes, we can also do that. Totally depends.
What are you trying to store
in those fields?
Okay.
It is not always the case
that all the rules
should always be private so we can have
a access modifier
and then the name of the class address.
So we are not trying to create an object.
Nassir and Fatima,
we are trying to create a constructor.
The syntax that you guys have written
is the syntax
to create an object.
So I write car and then I
and then I can initialize these fields.
I can see,
and then make
a right.
These are some of the fields
that an object can have in real life.
There will be
more, There will be more. And
if you are creating a construct
and if you make it mandatory,
it will be passed inside your constructor.
What do you guys think will be object
object creation?
Will it be easy or does
If someone has to pass
all of these fields when they are creating
the object of your class,
will it be easy for them or hard?
What if someone does not know the values
for all the fields?
It will be hard, right?
Having ID for zero or
having a default constructor
or zero argument constructor
is easy.
They don't have to pass any information.
They can create an object
when we make it compulsory
that they must pass these
five 1050, maybe 100 fields.
If they have to create the object,
it will be hard. Why?
First of all, they must have complete
information about your class
and then they must pass all that info.
Now what can happen is that as
you guys have used this kind of a class,
there are hundreds of methods
in that scanner class right?
And what
what can happen is that at most
how many methods you guys have used
from the scanner class, maybe two,
three at max, five, right where
there are other 100 meters in that class.
And not all the methods
they require
this information
to be passed to that class.
Right.
So what can happen
is that your methods in your class,
they might be using one
field of your class, might be using
two fears or three fields,
might not be using any field at all.
Right.
But when you and the
user, it might be only using
one method from your class two meters
or three meters.
Now, if someone is using
only one or two methods from your class
and you are asking that person
to, pass hundreds of values
before they can use that method,
how how that how that person will
feel. Guys
frustrated.
Right.
Because they might be using only one
method, right?
They as you guys have been doing
from this kind of class,
sometimes you only use the next method,
sometimes only
next boolean method or next integer
method.
Same is the case
with the builder class, right?
You might want to use the reverse method
now that those classes
they have so many fields.
Right?
So it's not fair to ask
for all the info from the user,
even if they will not be using that info
to make that happen.
What do we do?
We create multiple constructors.
We create multiple constructors
so that if a person is only trying to use
a small portion of the methods
from our class,
that person only passed the information
which is required for.
Those matters. Okay.
If something is not required
for those matters,
then we should not be forcing that person
to pass all the information.
We should not be forcing them
to initialize all the fields.
So in real life, what do we do?
We always, always create a zero argument
constructor.
Okay.
And then we also create multiple
constructor constructors
that requires less fields
so so in real life.
So let me complete this constructor.
So we will be saying
var model
and then
there will be is equal to on
marker
and then
here will be equal to
ugly.
Have already died this.
Thank you.
Okay.
And then you can see
and then we have
got we in the car mileage max period
and then some rules.
Let me create the classical assessment
and let me show
what will happen if we are forcing someone
to initialize
all of these fields.
Just yes, I will wait.
I will wait.
Let me know once you guys,
I'm done typing this code
and once you guys are done
typing this work,
excluding, make sure that you also don't
have any compilation error.
Maybe use loop for one week
and not use a loop in here
once a loop is used when we have arrays
or when we have to do something.
Well, it's very similar again and again.
And these variable names,
they are all different, right?
So even if you write a loop,
you will have to write these variables.
All of them.
Maybe I can send this code to you.
Okay, type. This call dies.
Let me to send this code for you.
Just create a class
and copy paste this code
inside that car class.
That's great
if your typing speed is improved.
Right?
Remember the days, nature days.
New York City used to take a lot of time.
Alexi Berardi from
Ukraine.
Oh, we have so many students from Ukraine.
Are you referred by someone?
So I heard in Ukraine
you can buy a goal for $5.
Is it true?
Is that cheap in Ukraine
if I go go for $5?
No, it's not empty.
Maybe a leg.
Okay.
How is it if you are getting paid 3000
to $4000 per month, 3000
to 4000 USD per month in Ukraine?
Am I going to play or should be under.
There was a student
who got a job around 30 $400
per month in Ukraine
and she was very, very happy.
I don't know how how foolishly
for quality of life
she can get in that.
And we don't need to start as the mean.
But no, no, we need that.
All right.
What is her name?
Her name was Maria.
She was from Batch eight.
Then there was another student
from Batch nine
and her name was
I don't remember her
name.
Oh, my God.
So next year.
And then after
we are all moving to our apartment song.
All right, so I arrived
in the core school.
You are.
Well, why?
I'm getting in error, guys.
Right there did not past parameters.
Name everything in the way
you are writing as my third.
We need to keep all the values
variables in art
so you mean it means
yes. So some of you
you still don't understand.
So it's not about math.
It's not about.
It's not about how I am doing it.
Like parameters of like that.
Because this parameter
experts, these values
outside of the structure, expect
these values and I am not passing them.
Okay?
That's why we are getting to Santa.
All right. Let's let's try to build that
have the class. So
can you guys quickly
tell me all the information
about related car
that is?
What do you mean?
No, this is not serious.
Keeping
change to constrict
your Tesla.
That's not the model X.
Maybe
make a Tesla
and then model is
model Y,
and then about the color black or white.
And tell me values.
And then here is Mr.
thousand 17, 18, 19, 18
and then CC.
I don't think so.
Electric cars have they have
are of power or something like that right.
Not available
let's put minus one
and then we are in week
and our last ones were trees and
then mileage is is again
we can see because it is an electric car
20215.
This is the mileage Alex on in one charge
plus minus one in here
upper please
if in and max speed is 350
and then sunroof is available or not
3.0 if you pay.
All right.
That's great.
So you see,
if I have to construct this object,
I have to pass all of these informations.
Okay?
If I want to utilize this class properly.
So in real life scenarios,
it will be very hard
for you to learn about all the classes
that are there.
I guess there are more than 6000 classes
in Java in JDK
and we go.
Joel, 14, has 4569 classes.
Okay, So, so many classes.
It will be very hard
for you to understand
those classes, understand
about all the parameters of those classes
and then use those classes.
So what happens
is that when you are developing a class,
you always provide
this flexibility to your user
that he or she can create the object
even without forcing any information.
Okay?
So you always go with the
zero argument constructor.
How can I create the zero argument
constructor guys?
So no parameters in here
and then parentheses.
Okay, so let's say for example,
a user is only trying to maybe
bring the name of the class.
So it's a very simple example.
So let's say a user is only interested
in getting the
name of this car right now.
If the user is only interested
in the name, we should not force their
to user to pass the Indians
to see the color
and all those parameters
that we have defined in here.
Right?
But what we can do is that we can create
a special constructor for that user
who is only interested
in this printed matter name.
We can see it's public,
but and we can see
only pass this information
and then
use this method print name from our class.
Does it make sense guys,
how having multiple constructors
can help us
know how the end user
can benefit from this?
What will the first want to do?
So I shall not say
here the user is saying
user is only interested
or user only wants to the printer name.
If there are thousands of methods
in this class and I am only interested
in print name, it is no point
asking all of this information.
Right? There is no point.
So what I can do, I can instead call
the one argument constructor
in this constructor
and I can still get the same results.
Why pass the other pieces of information
when I don't need them right
when I don't need it? Why?
Why should I pass it?
Why should I learn
about all the parameters?
Why should I care
what kind of values these parameters take
when I am only interested
in using one method from this class?
Right?
It's a great flexibility for the end user.
So If there are
any methods
which don't require any parameter at all.
That's where this zero argument
constructor will be helpful.
Okay, so let's say
there is a method in here
which do not require any parameter text
which it will be used for.
How can I know what the use of know
about car?
So Alexi, we don't know. Never know.
We never know. It depends on the user.
So for example,
when you use this kind of class,
Java guys don't know that if you will
be using only the next integer method
or if you will only be using
the next Boolean method. So
they have created multiple constructors,
they have created the matters.
Now it's up to you
which method you want to use
and which constructor you want to call
is. It
should be before another constructor.
So this is the best practice.
We start with zero argument constructor.
Then we write one argument, then two, then
three therefore, and we keep on going.
So right now is printing line 41 or 21.
So right now
it's still printing this line 41,
but the value is being initialized
through this constructor.
So GA two is equal to new.
So in one object I am passing
many pieces of information, but still
I am getting the results.
Still I am getting the same results.
So what is the point of passing
that information?
So what should we write in our class
for each parameter?
Separate code like we did for the name,
whatever needed? Yes.
So it depends on your methods.
Fatima.
If your methods they are required
certain pieces of information,
then you can build a specific constructor
for those.
What is zero argument
constructor purpose in this example?
So Mohammad, let's say
you have a method
that does not
use any arguments, any parameters
from this class.
Okay, so we have this method.
Now, if you are interested in this method,
do you need to pass the GA name
when you are creating the object?
Mohammad No. Right.
So in that case you can create the object
by saying three equal to new God
and say call three dot
C Hello.
Okay, so that's where the zero argument
constructor will be helpful.
But we need to write
all these separately. Yes.
As a designer of this class,
you will be getting this information
from the client that how you want,
you want to build,
and then architects and buyers
will help you out how you want to build
that Your architects are
the team lead specialists.
They will be telling you
the names of the classes we are what
which kind of method should be there
and all those things.
And then you will be coding those things.
How you called line
19 Constructor Investor Class.
Can you please repeat
on line 19 constructor.
So in here, in the
line, how
many arguments
I am passing to this this constructor
call Now?
One. Right.
So is there a construct of that takes
only one argument
inside this car class
is not a developer's job.
The developers will be developing
the applications same way
you guys will be developing the frameworks
to test those applications.
So if not
100%, you guys will be writing
3060 up to 60% of the code
as of the code
that the developers will be writing.
If you are doing the acclimation.
And so
this constructor knows
that there is a constructor
which takes only one argument,
so it will call that constructor in here.
In here
Java that you are passing
these many values.
The Java will start this class
from top to bottom
and it will call the matching
constructor from this class
scheme is the case for new country.
We are not passing a constructor job
insert.
If there is a constructor
does not take any parameters
so Java will call that constructor.
But that would have been achieved if we
just learned with the default constructor.
So Mohammad, if you remember,
as soon as we write at least one
constructor, the default constructor
provided by Java is gone.
So even if I remove this
zero argument constructor oops,
as soon as I remove this zero argument
constructor I will be getting an error.
Okay.
Because now Java is not providing
the default constructor.
Does it make sense now?
Mohammad.
So that's why we need a zero argument
constraint.
Why am I getting an error?
So I what do you have a one argument
constructor in your class
and you shared a
screenshot of the car class.
It is
better to create a zero constructor
just in case.
Yes, it's always better
if you have a method.
We don't need the fields
from your class.
You should always create
a zero constructor
so you need a new constructor
for a new object? Yes.
So now I have Georges.
If I am planning to use
only three fields from my class,
I can have a constructor
which only initializes those three fields.
I can create a constructive and.
That way the end user is not forced
to parse all the fields,
all the values
for all the fields in my class
so I can have one more constructor
like this,
which takes me b
fields
like this.
Okay, so now if a user wants,
he can create an object
by passing two pieces of information
on one piece of information.
All pieces of information.
No pieces of information.
So now a user is getting more
and more flexibility.
Yes, the law section contains these two
networks, right?
How how do you guys feel?
I can sense that a half
of the first
half of the class is going above
the above your heads.
Is it true?
Do not worry if this is the case,
you guys are not alone.
So why did we create line 28 to 42?
I am still not clear about that line
28 to 44
B to 44.
So this big giant constructor, Tom
or not, it's there.
If you want to initialize all the fields.
Okay, it's there
if you want to initialize all the fields.
That's
why we have this big giant constructor.
It's okay.
Like I said before,
because everything we are learning is
so similar to each other.
It is harder than loops.
I did not understand
after creating test for class
and to make changes again in car class.
So most of the changes
that we have made in the car class,
we have created new constructors
inside the car class
so that if someone wants
only initialize to four years,
he can initialize only two fields.
If someone wants to initialize
only one field,
he can have a constructor to initialize
only one field.
So we are giving this
flexibility to the end user.
Why don't we put in
parentheses or regional names
that we created originally
alone?
Can you tell me the line number?
The line number 28
why we have these benefits?
You mean?
Yes, some are not.
If we don't need all the fields,
we can have a constructor
with less fields.
It's that easy.
Why don't we enter name and model?
No, we did Alona on line seven.
We did.
We passed it as law.
We passed the model.
We did
right and we.
But not the original names.
Oh, you mean why we cannot have a
in here
as as as the name in here or there?
There is a trick.
There is a, there is an issue with that.
There is something you guys need to learn
before you can do that.
So that's why we are doing this.
And that is related to the discovered
that we will be learning next.
By the way,
how have you guys tried to give same names
to do the constructor parameters?
Does it work?
No, it can not work.
You guys must be doing something different
if you make so.
Let's say for example, if I make
this name
same as this name.
So this is the question of Alona alone.
I saying why we don't call this name
same as as this name.
So Alona,
if you try to do that, what what happens
if you execute this code?
You see we get a null value
on second point
as per constructor condition.
We have to give all values in parameter
when we call in the test the class.
So here we are making constructor
with one argument or with all argument.
Here we are
just understanding the difference
if we always put all arguments
linked to be.
Yes, yes.
Now you are right class. Best line nine.
So how put in all
line nine.
So Alexia, if you want to print you,
you just create a method.
You put everything inside that method.
Okay, So for example,
if I have a method, public wide
print
or in full,
then you can write this out
and then you can write,
you can write name
model
near,
and then make
and then you can keep on adding
the other pieces of information.
Okay.
Oops.
Which can be a plus sign,
which
let's see,
this is how you keep on doing this.
And then you can say card or
print.
Okay, Then you will be seeing all the info
in here as well.
So it's there for sake of completeness,
not completeness for the sake
of simplicity, for the sake of easiness,
for the sake of flexibility
to have these multiple constructors.
So, Alona, is it clear
now that if you have same name in here
and in here, it does not work?
So I will teach you why it does not work.
And what should we do to make it work?
So that's why I have different
variable names in here.
Now. It will work.
Now we get the proper results.
All right, guys,
are there other questions?
Nice.
We will learn a new topic today.
Totally depends on you guys.
If you guys are
left with an energy,
then yes, we can learn about new topics.
So that's why yesterday
I didn't teach you the new topic
because some of you were asking me
questions
and I realized that we need to spend
more time on that.
We scroll down regardless.
It totally depends on your feedback.
I have
I have been teaching multiple classes
on how to build
index top applications,
web applications, mobile applications,
how to use advanced concepts
like regular expressions like
lambda expressions,
functional programing to previous batches,
but it totally depends on the response
that I get
from the from that specific batch.
If we are left with time,
we can have both sessions
too. At one time.
It's too much.
So if we can create methods
for our objects
like, the linear constructors,
so give me the constructors.
They are there because what
first they are called automatically.
Then we call the constructor.
When we create the object,
they are called automatically,
but the methods are not called
automatically.
You cannot force through the methods
that someone is initializing
the proper features
before using any members from your class.
But you can force
that through constructors,
so that's why we should be going
for the constructors.
Constructors are called before
anything is executed from your class.
And yes, they also simplify code.
The object creation.
It's really hard for me to confuse today.
That's good for me.
If it is hard you to get confused,
then I get.
Then I can keep on teaching.
You told us.
You can tell later on how we are
doing compared to all all the bad news.
I think you guys are learning the answers.
Can you give us practical examples?
Forgive me. It's question, please.
So now the practical examples are
not start asking this question before
and I showed you the string builder class
and the
standard class,
so you guys can have a look
at the constructors of those classes.
Okay. So it is the same
answer for this question.
I mean, focus.
We are the worst so far.
No, no, no. This is not the case.
All right,
so let's create some more constructors
because
that's how you fix how I have
to teach you about the new
console.
Let's create a constructor
that the three parameters.
Let's create a constructor that makes
four parameters
posted in here
is not there in this channel.
All right, guys.
So I got this message from Russell
that you guys are not saving
the class before,
so you write a class and then you guys
don't to save that class.
And then you try to execute
that class from here.
If you are doing that,
you will be getting an error
and there is an automatic setting
that saves your files after,
I guess, 20 seconds or so. Now.
So he no, you do you have this constructor
that takes all these parameters,
the parameters that you are
trying to pass on line number eight.
If you don't have this constructor,
you will be getting an error
and make sure that
if you are passing,
if you are expecting three things in here,
you are exactly passing things,
then an integer to integers,
then again one string, then two integers,
and then a boolean at the end
and make sure you are saving your class.
So let me do this, guys.
Let me send you
everything that is President.
Actually,
let me share you the class with you.
So let me write some more constructors.
Or is it already too much
looking to send you this car class?
Okay, I open this car class
and then you can copy
and paste code.
I am sending it in the line.
Questions down here.
Is this class
is too much in for confusing?
Okay, let.
Let's keep it in here. In here?
Or maybe you guys can remove
some of these.
So let's create a new class
and let's have
a GED class this time
on the assembly to start to
please and locate and the car
maybe call or.
Yes, let's, let's create a call class.
If next class. Yes.
So we are done with this
God class.
And if some of you are getting errors,
you can copy and paste my code.
So let's put the first field as
raised and let's just put $5.
Okay?
And this is static.
All calls dollars.
Keep going.
Yes. Maybe I should rename this to you.
Call out our guys do call and do calls.
Have names.
Individual calls are fired in Ukraine.
The manner
of calls.
My name is Ludo.
It is.
It is lunchtime embargo.
Good call, Kamal.
All that I sell.
Let me tell you something, guys.
I don't know if it is available
and it
clips or not.
So if you guys right
click on your class name
and if you go to source
and then if you click on Generate
constructor using fills,
do you guys see this option?
All of you?
Because constructors,
sometimes they can be super lengthy.
So usually the idea is and they provide us
this assistance that they will create
the constructors for us automatically.
So if you select
you use like the fields that you want
inside that constructor
is like the access modified
and then you click on Generate and Boom,
the constructors is there for us,
even if there are thousand fields.
Okay, so you guys have to right click.
Oh, there are so many things
that I have not told you
and you guys will be surprised at the end
because I want you to learn.
So we right click, we, we go to source.
Let me tell you something, there is always
a solution, but you have to Google it.
If you Google so many of your problems,
you guys can solve them
very easily.
So source
and then
generate constructor and using fields.
This option
that there is so many
and there are so many things
which are available,
you can generate complete classes.
There are a lot to tell you,
but there are frameworks which we
you will guest once you guys have done
learning the testing,
you will learn about something
called as web elements
and they can generate the code
automatically
to test those elements and all that.
And you guys will be creating something
similar once you are done with selenium.
Okay? So once you have done this,
then you
need to select the fields that you want
inside that constructor
and you click on Generate.
Okay, Then a constructor
automatically will be generated for you
or the super.
You can ignore that.
I don't want you to get confused.
Will be super cool.
There is something related to that.
Are you guys done writing
these two constructors?
No, I will not tell you no,
because then you will not learn
all. Okay,
let's repeat this one more time
so that you guys are familiar with this.
So source.
And then generate the constructor
using fields
that are not clear to constructor far
on you appears.
And then we can have a constructor
for only two fields
and we can have a constructor for
only one field.
Then we can have a constructor for.
All right.
What is the combination to
pass and interview is really
combination is it?
Is the combination
sees output pass.
The combination is Java Selenium as well.
Give number test and API is a WAC
and then we are adding
other frameworks as well.
Why? Error.
So Sebastian,
make sure you don't have to constructors
with the same
parameters.
If you have to construct it
with same parameters,
then you would be getting this error
and try to read your errors.
Guys, always when you get an error,
try to read your errors
and try to figure out
what can be the reason,
because this is the most useful skill
that you guys will be needing
on your real life projects.
Because on jobs there will be no one
to tell you how to fix your issues, how to
figure out the solutions.
You will be
the one who will be doing all of this.
So try to make Google best friend
and you scroll down.
Yes, I will contact you every day
if you can contact me
and will try my best to help you out.
But as I am super,
super busy right now, I am
helping students
from Batch seven and it's batch 11.
So kind of having
it will be hard for me to help everyone.
Why I am getting super
I you can remove that super for now.
We will learn about this super
in next week
we are going to do.
I always love that
you need to take percentage of cell
people have only
and there is not enough and
from where we get
this north name.
Okay so
this is the this is about the
next keyword
that we will learning in the next keyword
is about this keyword.
Okay.
So this double course and keyword,
I will buy a car only if it costs five.
Helping them with interview or work mode,
helping them with interview and work.
So students need help
with what are different kind of things.
Sometimes they are working on a project
they don't know how to do something.
So They keep on posting other students.
They also help.
Sometimes
if someone is trying to switch their job,
they have to clear their interviews
and all that.
So kind of stuff.
So the next thing that we are going to
learn
is the this keyword.
Now, what is the use of keyword?
This keyword is used to distinguish
your instance variables
and your local variables.
If we use this
before the name of any variable,
we are saying that we mean.
So we are saying we are referring
to this name, not this name.
So variables
they can be instance variables
and there can be local variables, right?
So what can happen them
if they are having same names,
if they are having same names for example
in here, the local variable string,
it has the same name
as an instance variable
and now if you want
to travel to Java
that implied this assignment
on the left side,
you mean this variable
and on the right
you mean this local variable.
You can write this
and then sign and then name.
So when we this keyword
Java knows that you are trying,
you are referring to the instance
variable.
So if you remove this
now, what are you doing?
You are assigning a local variable
to a local variable
because whenever you are inside
block of code,
the priority is always,
always given to the local variables.
Okay.
So in here, if you are using
a local variable with the name,
then Java will never refer
to this instance variable.
And if you want to explicitly
tell Job out there to Java
when I say a name
and when I put this keyword, please
refer to the instance this variable.
So that's how we can use this variable
with keyword.
Does it make sense? Yes.
This is the indication for Java
of which variable we are talking about.
So if there is a confusion,
if there a duplication,
if there is this race between
a local variable
and an instance variable,
and if you want to distinguish
a local variable from a this instance
variable, you specify this keyword.
With that variable, it works.
What all types of variables
did you copy?
Instead of creating true source?
Why I have error in all
the same construct of having
same parameters
can not start with the name.
You have both singular constructors
you need delete,
you have same constructor.
All right.
So guys, is
this is the use of this variable
player.
Okay,
so that's why we use this keyword. Now
I want you to closely
analyze this code.
No, You guys see any duplication
in this code?
Am I repeating some lines of code again
and again inside with constructors?
In all the constructors.
So I am repeating
you see this name and breed.
It is in. Here it is.
I am repeating the same line of code
in here.
I am repeating the same line of code in
here I am repeating the same code in here.
Right?
If we see this name color,
I am repeating it again.
And here again. And here. Right.
So I am repeating the
same code again and again.
What if I tell you
guys that instead of rewriting this code?
So this constructor is assigning
values to these variables.
Okay.
What if instead
of rewriting these three variables,
if what if I can call
this constructor in here
and then I pass this information,
these three pieces of information
to that constructor and that constructor
initializes the code for us, right?
It will save a lot of duplication.
Okay, so
how can I do that?
But how can I do that? Is
So this is the piece of code
that is being repeated, okay?
And I am doing same thing again in here.
Again.
So what I can do, I can remove this line,
I can I base
and parentheses
and when I pass name
now Java will call this constructor
on this line.
And the field which was initialized
in here will be passed to this constructor
and it will be initialized
through this constructor.
And I see that again.
I am repeating these two lines in here
so I can remove these two lines
and I can again try these.
Yes, We don't have to initialize
again, again.
And this time if I pass name
and breed, they will be initialized
with the help of this constructor
and this constructor.
But let's see, I don't need to do that.
I can do the same for for this.
Right?
I can remove these three lines
and instead of these three lines
I can write this and this time
I can force name,
breed and color.
Okay.
And again, now I have successfully removed
these three lines.
I have replaced these three lines
with a single line.
And here
I can do the same for these four lines.
I don't need to repeat them again
because I have already written this code.
So I will usually construct the above one
and I pass the information here
and those fears
will be initialized automatically.
I can remove all of this code.
All of this code
if I have to create multiple constructor.
So this is the second use of this keyword,
this keyword
to refer to instance, variables always.
Yes, you'll get them.
It will always refer
to the local variables.
So for instance, variables
we can we using it like this
if we don't want to change the value.
Well all the time.
Correct. Yes.
More cleaner code.
But why you don't get error?
Because duplicate variables.
Where are duplicate variables are
are you have commented out this code
so I can actually remove the score.
There are no duplicate variables
before.
On which
line can you tell me the line number
but still
repeating the same constructor
too many times? Yes.
So now I am repeating the constructor
call.
Earlier I was four lines of code in here.
Now I am writing only one line of code
in here.
Earlier
I was writing three lines of code in here.
Now I write only one line code.
So yes, I am repeating
but I now have to write
Very good
in line for piece 42 we have.
Wait, what will happen to that?
So this word will be initialized
from this constructor?
Yes. Let me go up
the y color age and wait.
Separate.
Mr.. What can you tell me the line number
you. I am passing the age in here
and passing the word in here.
Line 33.
This particular
Oh, because this constructor
can only initialize three fields,
I am using the constructor
above to initialize those two fields,
but still
I need to initialize the third field.
That's why I am writing it in here.
Same is the case in here.
I can initialize three fields
with the help of this
above constructor,
but I still need to initialize this edge.
That's why I have to write it manually.
Now let me let me debug this code for you
so that you guys understand
how everything gets initialized
and so to make the code shorter,
we should take the values from the above
constructor.
Yes. Not take the values above.
From above constructor
we should reuse the above constructor.
Yes. But why we need that repetition
instead of writing
only to clean code
with all the parameters.
Because if you have to write
multiple constructors
then you will be repeating a lot of code.
What is this?
Add a recursive constructor invocation.
So you are trying to call the same
constructor inside the same constructor.
It will be an infinite loop.
Try to execute this code.
Your computer will blow up.
I am so confused.
Sorry if I am also very confused.
Don't worry, I am with you.
Whatever Mustafa asked.
I heard the same question in my mind.
Okay, I will.
I will debug discord. Don't worry.
Is there a code to put everything inside
this, including the weight?
Or is that your going on?
Need extra data types? No.
Do you mean you can?
You can put the code in here as well.
Okay.
You can initialize the fields
with the default values in here
we say we are reusing
the constructor from a
category.
Also randomly coding.
Yes Nicolai that I don't worry.
I will debug report line by line.
We will see line by line
what is happening.
So let me create some methods
to display the values, putting in
some people being
everything.
So I don't want to type anymore.
It's fine.
You can just watch this video.
They were students
from the previous batch.
They were in hospital
and they were still taking classes,
but only listening
alert and then age
and golden age.
We have weird
and we should only watch and drink
plenty of water,
so I wish we would not go hospital.
They were in after classes
if because of COVID.
Someone told me I hear
jello from this concert on Twitter and
starting from the constructor Sheriff.
No, no man.
This is where the real fun starts.
Flash
that smiley with that tape on my mouth.
I'm just kidding.
It's easy, guys.
It's easy.
Yes, it will be on your fingertips.
Don't worry.
Let me.
Or to scold a little bit
the way if you guys are confused
about so many fields,
I can remove some of the fields.
You guys want me to do that?
Maybe we can understand this
with only three fields.
Or is there a shortcut
to organize the code and spacing? Yes.
Control shift F
right.
So let me create a call
texture.
So, Marina, after this example,
we will be having a break
and if you guys are facing any issues,
I want you to type this code
based those issues,
read the errors, fix those issues
I want you to learn.
Okay,
So I will not be sharing this code.
Is that okay?
But you can ask me
if you are getting any errors.
I want you to type it.
It will be better for you.
Okay?
Yes, I will display the coding break.
Okay.
So it's a very useful skill to have.
Okay. Don't feel bad.
It's a very useful skill to
fix your errors.
I want you to go through that.
And typing is also good.
It is still readable.
Guys, it's
okay.
I am not removing anything.
You guys can see all the code.
Let me give you 2 minutes. Okay?
And I want all of you to make sure
that you guys have
the exact same code on your computer.
And if you are facing any issues
or errors, you guys send them in here on
in this fourth channel
and we fix those issues
and then we move forward.
Who wanted to go?
So it's because of that person?
Sebastian No means today
and you are also busy typing
code, so
let me know guys, once you
are done typing this code.
So first let's do,
let's try to understand how
this multiple
chaining of constructors is happening.
Okay?
All right.
Article oh is equal to new out
and then nice.
Give me the values for these parameters.
The name of the call Lola.
The name of the call is Lola.
And what about the breed
that had
excellent Australian code
and Mejorar Lola
and the color
is now the white.
And then Lola is 16 years
old, is in her teenage
and her weight is her 80
legs.
At least it is soon we going to do
and then we say, Go start
putting all the info.
Okay, So let me put a
debug point in here on this line.
On this line and on this line.
Let me know, guys, once you have placed
these three debug points in here on both
the classic.
So I right click
play, I click on debugging as
Java application.
All right.
So right now we are on this constructor.
Okay.
And if I want to see how
the execution happened
inside this constructor,
which button
I should click this step into?
And can you,
can you guys tell me the number
which which line number
it will take me to from this call class?
If I step into
37. Perfect.
I have error
because you are defining
that method entirely.
Constructor and
so I say
step into okay, so right now
I am on this line.
Okay, I am passing name.
Oops, I am passing breed.
I am passing color ID and way. Okay.
And in this constructor
I have not written piece of code
to initialize
name, breed and color,
but what I am doing instead
I am passing this information
to another constructor.
This given that I am writing in here
in the parenthesis that I had written here
it is saying that there is a constructor
in this class that takes four parameters.
So what I will do, Java will search
all the constructors in here.
Which constructor takes four
four parameters, three of them
as three string variables
and one integer variable.
Is there a constructor in this class?
Here's the line number 31.
This constructor takes name
breed and color and age.
Okay, so it will jump.
If I press on in blue, it will jump.
Oops.
I accidentally pressed this step
and let me really object.
So I say step into. Okay.
So first of all, the
static fields are initialized in a class.
Okay?
After that we initialize the constructor
and we start from line number 37. Why?
Because I passing
five parameters,
and this is the constructor
in this class which takes five
parameters.
Three of them are strings
and two of them are one is integer,
another one is Williams.
So this is the perfect match.
So Java will execute this constructor
by looking at
this better in these parameters,
it will execute this constructor and after
I am again saying, Hey Java,
there is a constructor in this class
which takes four parameters, okay?
And three of them are
string type of type string and one is age.
So Joe will again
search all the parameters
and it will execute that constructor
in here.
Okay, so right now they'll this point.
Okay, so
at this point we have not initialized
any of these fields. Okay?
These they are still null.
Now let these name breed and these are
the parameters of this matter
morality, but
is asking for source code again,
I am so understand at this point.
All right, that's great.
Okay, so now, guys, tell me.
I am passing a string and other string
and other thing So I am passing
three strings.
Is there a constructor in this class
which expects
three strings?
Yes. Right.
I have another constructor.
So now Java will enter that constructor.
I am again saying Hey Java
there is a constructor
which to exclude string parameters.
Please that constructor first.
So now it will go inside this,
then it will go inside this.
And now I am not calling a constructor.
So the first field
which will get initialized,
which field will be guessed
that initialized first.
So I have passed this information
again and again from multiple constructor.
So from this constructor
I pass it in here.
From this I passed it in here
from this passage in here.
And finally this is the constructor
which will initialize
the name field.
Okay,
which will initialize the name field.
So the first field to get the value.
So you see this.
So this actually
is referring to the instance.
So you guys will see right now
the name is NULL in here,
but as soon as I execute
Discord, the name will now have Lola.
Okay, but I still don't initialize
breed color and age where the breed is.
Get initialize
after the call to this constructor.
So now we are coming back to those methods
again.
Okay.
So in inside a constructor we have,
we were calling another constructor.
Inside that constructor we were calling
another arguing another constructor.
So Java keeps on going inside
those constructors.
Now I will come back to those constructors
from which we called
the other constructors and now Java
will execute the remaining code.
Yes, the reverse.
We Can you guys tell me which
which line will be executed
next?
Perfect. Alexi. Perfect.
The line number. This.
This line has already executed.
When we when we initialized this field.
Now this line be executed.
Okay, so if I say step
over, you see, it will be initialized.
Now, can you guys tell me the next
line which will be executed?
It will be 26.
So now we are coming back from the methods
called method calls.
So now color will be initialized,
then edge will be initialized, then wait.
And now we are done
initializing
all the features, all the fields.
And now if we execute print all in full,
then we get all the values on our console.
It is better now, guys,
how these constructors
are calling other constructors
and how the values are being initialized.
Why it does not print color in my them. So
Maria, make sure that you have this color
in okay.
In here.
What about the price?
So price was static variable.
Okay.
I never initialized it.
I assigned it a fixed value. Okay.
If you want, you can also initialize it
support in constructor.
Go from down to upper
and from up and down.
So Alex,
if you are calling multiple constructors
inside other constructor like this, yes.
Then it will first go to ours up
to the smallest constructor,
then it will come back once it is done.
Executing all those constructors.
Maryam Let me have a look at
the Maryam.
You are assigning the color
to bleed on line number 18.
Let you get null. So
what about the first constructor
with line 12?
So like, well, we will never call this
constructor again if.
You want, you can call it as well in here
if that contains something important
that you always want to execute
whenever there is
construction of your object, you can you
you can put that as well.
So let's say
for example, important line of code
that you always want to
execute, you can say this
and then empty parenthesis.
Okay, Now
this constructor will also be executed.
And there is one more rule, guys,
we cannot place this on the second line.
It should be the first line always.
Okay,
we can not have it as the second line.
This must be the first line in.
Okay,
so let's go to the slides again.
Let's try to learn a little bit
about the theory about the rules.
Then we come back
and we follow the examples again.
I'll 2 to 3 examples again.
First, we will try to solve them.
You guys will try to solve them
during the break.
Then I will show you the solution again.
And hopefully, after all that, you
you guys will be able to get a good
understanding of this concept
is equal to call name.
Instead,
we can do this name or not this name.
Yes, this is what I am doing.
You will get the
this is what I am doing.
Can you tell me the line number?
And really I should do this?
Oh, I'm just asking.
Yes, we can do that
if you don't want to use this keyword.
But then you always have to come up
with the different variable names.
Okay?
Unnecessarily, you have to come up
with different variable names.
Right.
In Java class
that will have a constructor,
one with parameters, and second,
without any parameters.
Create a separate class.
We will execute both of the constructors
via the Java Class
Forum that
okay, I hope.
I think you guys can solve this without
learning about the rules.
Selecting both of them in the course
and I'll switch General
and you guys can also solve these tasks
without waiting
for that explanation.
And you guys can also solve this one
because you guys are brilliant
and, and now let's have a break.
How are you guys?
Tired. Okay, let's celebrate.
So here's 140.
I don't want you to sit
and keep on solving the questions.
I want you to at least take a 10 minutes
break.
And after that, maybe
you guys can try to solve them
and then I will show you the solutions.
We have quite
we will collapse if we don't take a break
to celebrate for
2015.
Okay.
Take some rest programing.
If you are not tired,
you are not doing it right.
Oh, my God. I remember those days.
I have not slept for
three days.
So there was an issue on the production
server and I used to get like 2 to 3 hours
sleep and I was there all the time
and that's how I learned Java.
I need to eat something and pray.
Okay, so we are having 35 minutes break,
but I want you guys to at least solve
two problems.
Well, at least solve the problem.
And remind me about the recording, please.
Can you check my code
SO constructor
call the bar so I'm wrong.
There is no constructor car or not.
There is a constructor bar.
Can you make sure
that you have a constructor
that is taking all fields
and in the same sequence
inside the constructor parking
to share the screenshot of back
22 years
old? Yes.
Total six tasks.
If you guys are unable to solve
some of them,
we will try to solve them
during the today's class,
but if we are unable to do that
we will solve them in the next class.
You guys remind me about the recording.
Yes, we are on break.
Or are we on break?
Thank you.
Let me close the call.
Could you check?
Okay.
Let me do the tasks and then you guys
can compare Your solutions is good.
Why don't you write a program
that when you turn on Zoom,
it starts recording automatically?
Yes, that's it.
That is a good suggestion. Google.
Maybe if I have time,
I will try to do something
like this.
Okay.
Actually, my research is going on
and I am super, super busy
all there right now.
Once you are created, ask one.
There is a zoom setting that you can apply
all that.
That's great.
I will try to find that searching.
So the first task was to
write a program
that will have a constructor,
the one with the parameters,
and second without parameters.
Create a separate test class
where you will execute
both of the constructors.
Okay, so
let's see, I
how can I create a constructor that works?
Should be the name of my constructor.
It should be.
Okay, so I can use any access modifier.
Then the name will be task one
and pair and fifties and then
I can type
zero constructors,
then I can copy
this constructor and I can pass
in number two, maybe in here
and I can say when argument constructor
and now
I can prepare
one faster
and how can I call
both the constructors?
Right, Right.
And you ask one.
And then again, I are new
on and I pass
a number in here.
Yeah.
And there's how the constructors
we called.
This is how you guys have done it
in the press.
Okay then that's perfect.
I'll call you. Go.
But Sebastian, you are,
you have first of all,
you have created only one constructor.
Second,
because you don't have that
zero argument constructor,
you cannot also call it.
So you need to create two constructor.
Okay, so
one with the parameters
and second without parameters.
So this is
without parameters
and this is with parameters.
So you guys were supposed to create pool
constructors.
Just give me one moment
new task and our task and ask one.
Well, both are work, Alex Both good.
But if you are not planning to use,
if you are not planning
to use the object that you are
creating this line, then maybe it's fine.
You don't need to store that
object in any variable,
but if you are planning
to call methods on that object then yes,
you should create,
you should create a variable
and then you should
you should store this object inside
of that variable.
Yes, you are right.
The parameter here is only to distinguish
the other constructor. Yes.
So do we go to the task to guys?
I did not understand the point of ten
client of ten
medium.
You mean the ten
that I am passing to this constructor?
So I am passing this ten
so that this constructor is called.
So this constructor
is expecting an integer parameter
and I am passing this integer number
in here so that Java, this constructor.
That's why I get the second output
and it's fine in
this is outside of just
there to make sure that we are executing
both the constructors.
Even if you write 50 instead of ten,
it would not bring any changes.
Yes, if you can write 50
500,000
any integer.
The second task
was to write a Java program
of class student
that takes student's name
and three subject groups
inside your class
also have a method
to calculate average grade.
Test this order
for five the first lesson
is Is it okay if I use this
name of task two instead of student
or should I create a new student class?
Okay,
so how many instance variables
I should have inside this class?
For which one?
Can you guys
tell me the instance variables?
So first I need to store the name,
then maybe
and be able to store the subject.
One marks
and another one
to study subject to
and subject three marks.
Okay,
we are creating
one variable
to hold B name and three variables
to hold the sum of decoders.
And we we don't need to sum them.
Okay,
maybe you can do that inside your method.
Okay.
And then I need to initialize these fields
and start
to name.
Let me actually use.
Okay.
So we have a constructor,
initialize these fields
and then we have to
calculate the average grade.
So public record
for the
average
grade.
Okay, so how do we calculate the average?
We calculate the average
by first adding these numbers
and then dividing the eight by three
zeros.
Different names for your
local and instance variables.
Y and
it's in the tasks
that's just ordering for five different
with different marks
will around should print an average
mark of each student.
It will be in the main method.
But where is this requirement
that I should use different names?
Pick what you share
is an alternative.
Second task.
Okay. Of the above.
Sorry Mr..
So I am not using
so in here
I am using the same names
as the name my class.
Okay.
And because I created this using the
eclipse feature next why it uses
the same names as the name of the class.
Okay, so.
But you guys have already learned
about the this keyword right?
So it's it's fine even if the names are
same all you guys want me to do.
You guys want me to condemn
you? You understand
this code, right?
And by the way, this is the best
this is the recommended approach
that this is the best practice.
You should not use different names.
You should use the same names,
and you should use this keyword
selected.
This is the task to
do it best.
So class maybe need to delete note
in the task or no, I actually
the task was supposed to be solved
before you guys know about this keyword,
but I shared all the task
all together
and that's why this notice, dear?
So that you guys don't get any errors
So how many of you have solved
more than two questions?
No. One
are to
only two
working on food,
so I will not so
solve the remaining questions
and those will be your homework first.
I want you to try it on your own
and then I will show you the structure
for the remaining questions.
Okay, so I say
ask to
task two
Foreign language Task one equal to
task two.
And in here I pass
and see
and 98
define 97
and fast learning about
being
okay so averages 96.6.
Then I can do this like this so I know
how to
and then I say well
and you know I
monitor for not
doing that so I can do that
in one single line as a
so I get the image like this.
Are there any questions from this task?
Only one confirmation.
Are you guys asleep
or tired
Because it's a five hour
class, All good looking LG.
I got
confused both Task one and task to date.
Maria When went in name of the student
as but so Maryam, you are audio
still confused or is it better now
try to catch you I mean in line
it with this line you on in here
I am just
creating an object
and I am calling the constructor
passing the parameters,
the arguments in here.
That's what I am doing.
I put task to task to, okay, all
this is what is confusing you.
You can name it anything.
It just a name of a variable you can name
no difference.
Okay.
What is this obsession?
Compulsive disorder.
I don't know what it is called. Not print.
A grade can replace the S out
or to print a big to replace the S out.
All right,
so I am
in here and I am calling this method,
and this method is called
This line will be executed next.
What is happening on line 11?
What do you mean by replace?
So I am simply calling a method in here.
Okay.
All right.
So let me
let me walk you through the slides next.
Let's see if we are missing something.
I'm self deconstruct.
You can call it whatever you want
or it should be specific method.
No, it can be any method.
It can be any mental.
So constructor will be called
automatically.
Welcome when the object is created.
Okay.
So is the part of object creation process
constructor
should not return any value even void.
So as with the methods,
sometimes we write in page,
sometimes override write,
sometimes we use void.
There is no such thing
for the constructor.
They don't even have void
because basic aim is
to place the value in the object.
If we write the return type
for the constructor,
then that constructor will be treated
as ordinary method.
Okay.
For one of the task
that says to create a static constructor.
So yes to me you can not do that. It is.
I put that task just to
and just so that you guys know
that we cannot have a static constructor.
Can you guys tell me why
we can not have a static constructor?
Can you. Can you guys explain the logic?
New guys already know the answer.
Think about this static matter.
What is the limitation of static method.
Static is immutable.
No accessibility.
Can I access instance fields inside
a static metabolic constructor? No.
My question is can I access instance
inside a method
or a constructor?
No, we cannot do that.
We cannot access instance fields
because for each object
they can be having different values.
But static means something common
for all the objects if we cannot exit.
And what is the purpose
of constructor guys
to initialize
to build the object,
to construct the object.
Now, if constructor is unable
to access the fields,
then how can it initialize
the field? Right?
The whole purpose of constructor is gone.
If we are having a static constructor.
All right. That's why it is not allowed.
How many of you have understood this point
that having a constructor
is something very logical
and this should not be allowed?
And if we cannot access the fields,
how can we initialize that part
and if we cannot initialize the fields,
then what is the point of constructor?
Constructors cannot, static constructor
cannot access instance fields.
If it cannot access the instance field,
it cannot initialize them.
And if a constructor can not initialize
the fields,
the whole purpose of constructor is gone.
Right?
This is why we are learning constructor
so that we can initialize the fields
so that the reason static is not allowed
with the constructor.
But we can use static in a matter.
Is that correct?
Yes. With the method
we can use the static or the limitations.
They are still there.
If you use this as a static
with the method, you cannot access
the instance fields inside that method.
If one want to use static
then must use method,
not constructors. Yes.
All right.
So this is how I understand it.
Tell me if I am wrong.
Static needs to have a fixed data
that is shared by all class.
The constructor resistance of the data.
Hence constructor cannot be static.
No Mohammad, this needs a correction.
First the keyword fixed.
You should not use that keyword with the
for the static keyword
static variables
they can have different values.
It's the only thing.
The only thing that
will.
And the reason why we use static
is because
it is declared inside a memory area
and that memory area
is called static and the property
of that memory area
is that the variables that you declare
in that memory area,
they are shared across all the classes.
So instance fields,
they can have a different value
for each instance that you create.
But static fields will always be
having same value for all objects.
So that's why we can not use
the constructors,
the static constructors, the,
the instance fields make all the static
mean something common,
while instance means something different
for each instance.
Okay, makes sense to me after
and what line things
3.14 mind blown
because I constructed
a reusable block of code
and static cannot be local.
Yes, this
this statement is true
that the static cannot be local.
And this statement is also true
that the constructor
is a reusable block of code,
so it will only work in the class.
The main name of a constructed
is to initialize in the class.
Static is common denominator,
but it's got to be changed.
No static can change
while we use constructor
in different classes.
All right.
So constructor definitions
should not be static
because
will be called each and every time.
Whenever an object is created okay.
So for each object
and they will be taking the data
and initializing
the figures for that object.
But if you make it static,
that means all the objects will be
give and will be having same values.
Right? We don't want to do that.
Each object has this flexibility
that it can have
its own values.
Yes, for car one car to call
one and car to construct,
but it should not be private provided
an object of one class is created
in another class.
If you are planning to create the object
of one class inside the other class,
you should not make your constructors
private.
What will happen guys,
if I make the constructor private
and if I try to create the object
of that class in a separate file,
in a different class,
I would not be able to access it.
Right?
If I cannot access it,
I can not create the object from it.
Right.
So that's why
I should not be making it private.
What if you think that only
you will only be
creating the objects
inside the same class?
Just maybe then you want to have
the constructor as private.
Yes. It defeats the
whole point of constructor.
Constructors
will not be inherited
from one class to another class.
This point is related to the next class,
so let's leave
this now.
In this slide
I have mentioned some differences
between constructor and method Method.
Can be
any method can have any user defined name.
Right. I can call my method method one.
Method two.
Method three but constructor
must be having a same name
as the name of the class.
Method should have returned type
like void, integer or string.
It should not have any return type
construct.
They should not have any return type.
Method should be called explicitly
either with object, preference or class.
So if I want the code
that is inside a method,
if I want that code to be executed,
I must call that method
explicitly by writing object name
not then method name.
If it is a static method,
I write the name of the class and doc
and the name of the method,
but for the constructors
it will be called automatically
when object is created.
This is part of object affiliation.
Method is not provided by compiler.
In any case you want to write,
you want to have a method you created.
If no compiler is not going to provide you
a method,
but Java compiler provides
a default constructor.
If we don't write
one constructor on our own
method, we can
non access modifier
such as static final abstract.
But we cannot do that
with the constructors.
Okay.
We cannot have a static keyword,
we cannot have a final and abstract.
You guys will learn about this later on,
but we cannot have this.
Yes. Non de format.
There.
So in simple word, when we use method
and when we use constructor
if it is possible.
Real life example elects
to initialize the fields of your class.
You should use it constructive
to write a piece of logic inside
your class.
You should write that there is a clear
constructor inside the constructor
you should only initialize the field
for everything.
You should create a method
and it is all sorted and constructors
are used to write the logic.
These logics.
Are you executed during the object
creation?
Okay, so whatever you will be putting
inside the constructor,
it will be executed
during the distribution method.
Also used to write the logic.
This logic are executed
when we call those matters.
They are not automatic like constructors.
Then we learned about the discovered.
Now this keyword
is a keyword in java
that refers to the current object.
Okay.
And this is used to access
current class instance members.
I can
call the constructor offer
using this keyword.
By specifying those parentheses,
I can access the instance fields
by writing this dot the name of the field,
and I can also call the method
from database
with variables I can use.
This can be used to refer
current class instance variables.
So let's say
if you are having a local variable
and an instance variable, and both of them
they have the same names,
you can distinguish
these two variables inside
a method or, inside a constructor
by specifying this keyword.
Okay, if you write this keyword in
Java knows that you are trying
to refer to an instance field
with the methods.
This can be
used to invoke the current class method.
Okay.
It does not make sense or it's kind of
not that important because even if you
do not
specify the this keyword,
you can still call the class meters
because there is no concept
of local methods or instance methods
or something like that.
Okay.
So it does not matter lot in this case
with constructor,
you specify this,
then you passed the parameters
and then Java searches
for best match inside your class.
If you have a constructor with those
parameters, If there is a constructor,
that constructor will be called,
this is just an example.
So I have this foreign class.
It has a rule number named V
and now I am having in local variables
the role number, name and fee.
So now if I want to distinguish
an instance variable, I write this keeper
in you
and yeah,
this is the example of this keyword.
When I use this keyword
to call the constructor of a class.
So I write this, then parentheses
and depending
upon the number of arguments
and type of arguments
and appropriate constructor,
if it exists,
it will be called from your class.
If it does not exist,
you will be getting edit
So this used to be the variables
and methods.
This with parentheses
is used with the constructors.
Only one of the uses is differentiating
between local and instance variables.
A method call
used to call one constructor
from another belonging to the same class.
These are the tasks
and super.
So on Tuesday
we will
be starting with the inheritance.
So I will share with you.
I will share this slide
right after this class
and I will more wrappers
then we have super easy peasy
method of uploading, easy peasy
method over to our being easy peasy
final keyword,
easy peasy or yes, I will be sharing
the videos of intelligent as
it's not easy
peasy for you.
So there is one more class
that is a little hard,
but other than that class,
most of the time
it will be some kinds of keywords
and the functionality of those keywords
like we have learned about
disclaimer today, or there will be some
logical concepts that will help
you write about record
also in person
you will be.
I thought it would be easy peasy.
So are the constructors not easy.
We need to work on theory side
like super and they are not easy peasy.
Okay.
Not very. You guys will learn about them.
The companies if they will be paying 8098,
they will make you work.
Don't worry.
They they know how to how to extract work
out of you.
Unfortunately,
all time you
please both to the notes.
Okay.
I will share the notes and the record.
And what is the highest salary
any student caught out of school.
So one of the students here, he
or she bought, I think around 150.
Okay.
How many? $76.
But are
then you guys translated that to random
$76 per hour?
How much is in front of
us from batch 8.3?
So totally depends on your on your luck.
And even if for the first time,
even if you guys
don't get 150, what you can do,
you can a stock from any job like 80 or 90
and then you can keep
on applying on other jobs
and once you have a good job,
you can switch anytime.
Okay.
There is no one who can restrict you
from switching your job.
So that way
you guys will also be getting paid.
Would
like what, 90
is. But obviously
if someone is paying you 150,
they will also be expecting
more work from you.
So depends how much,
how much piece you want
in your life
and you can switch any time
if it is not contract job.
Right.
I think you can even switch
if you have a contract.
I mean, don't sign such contracts
that you cannot leave
a job is never recommended, never do that.
Even if they are paying you on 50.
No, no, Katrina.
And don't tell this to control
to the companies.
I am ready to work for free.
If they know, believe me, they will never
be paying you any any money.
If they know and they can,
they can check it out from your behavior.
I mean, it's you who tells your
your managers
how much work they can get on that.
And from you right.
Imagine how many calls you can bias.
That will be 158.
I will have a village full of cows.
You will get rate from you. The manager.
I am down to anything.
Replace that some experience.
It's good, guys.
It's good.
But don't tell it. Don't tell it.
Okay.
It's good to start for,
but don't tell it to the companies.
Okay?
Once they know, once they know
that you are a guy who is ready to work
even for free,
they will never be paying you and
always know your work.
Half of one job will be fired for a year
for 200 K Yeah,
So that they never call you
back. Lugo
Yes. That hard.
You are right. Yes.
Very simple.
Guys,
I don't know about your current situation,
how much, how much you are getting paid.
How is your life right now? But I can tell
the students which have
completed this bootcamp
and they were on schedule,
they completed all their tasks
and they were on top of everything.
None of those students is
is without a job right?
Almost all of them.
They are getting paid more than 90
and you guys can.
So for example, I can literally show you.
So this is batch nine
technical jobs for
and so you guys can read
all these messages.
The students they are themselves
posting their these messages
once they get a job.
All of these congratulations
all of them they are from
page nine.
Oh, my God.
So the original message
you see, they are also
telling me, telling about my rappers,
all assignments,
including rapping for us, the
AC one,
two, three, four, five, six, seven,
eight students
got the job at once
and we are on the free version of Slack.
So these are the question.
These are the messages
that we can see in here.
So just keep on pushing
and it will all be fine.
When should we expect some girls
Next week.
Remind me on on Wednesday
and I will invite them
on on Saturday or Sunday.
But how about another
batch or nine was the best.
If you ask me about the best batch,
I would say A-plus.
Batch it for me.
I don't know.
It's different for different instructors
because I was able to show them
how to build
next job applications.
They were very curious,
They were very interested.
So they were always after me.
Hey, girl, can you can you show us this?
Can you show us this?
We want to learn this.
We want to do this.
And some of were ready to be a developer
B and they build some kind of games
and all that.
Okay, it's fine.
As far as you guys are looking for
testing jobs,
the material is more than enough material
that we are covering during the classes
as well.
Some party
already, it reminded me on on Wednesday
I and I will invite some girls
from the batch nine.
What about batch
11 will see after you guys are done
with Java
Loco. Thank you. Bye bye.
Take some rest.
And don't forget that you guys
should be revising these slides.
You guys should be revising me. Java
whereby.