We there were three tasks
of the day.
We will learn how to
read and write data to excel, file,
how to create new Excel files,
how to detect from other files
like properties.
So now you guys will be interacting
with the things
which are out of your intelligence,
out of your ID.
Now you will start interacting
with real stuff
from your computer over the internet
and all that.
With the help of Selenium and other API
is that we will be teaching you.
Now, finally the training is over
and you are ready for the battle.
Are you ready?
Soldiers
out of your training
ground, intelligent or
we will lose right away.
For my soldiers returning backwards
to see, seeing the APIs of Excel. And
what are we?
Some of us will be able to take
it. Great.
Where is Colonel Lobo?
Right.
He will be helping you out.
Don't worry.
You have Lieutenant General Major Simon
that will help you out.
Right.
Lieutenant Dan Sebastian. For you.
To whom
do you have any in the army?
I will lead your army for a few days.
Look within breakthrough.
Oh, you mean the. Yep.
I have some friends who are friends
in the army, in ISI, in Special Branch
Police, and everywhere.
Actually, a lot of my friends,
they go to jobs in that field
because, you know, this is Pakistan.
And I don't want to say, but
most of that happens in
the Pakistan is controlled
by Security Security Institute.
I don't need army training.
I am here.
So you have served the army in Afghanistan
or somewhere?
I had a classmate being a friend
looking for soldiers. US.
That's great.
17 years.
All my involved.
All right, guys.
No jokes with NASIR.
I said you are better, You are best.
You are our best friend.
Alright,
so let's start from the tasks.
Well, thrown
into it.
So it's still hard
for you like you have been fighting
real wars.
Well, Java is on top of the
master is 80 to 80 years old.
But on that side,
I hope you guys don't do this.
I was reading this news.
There was a lady who blew up.
I think it's a petrol pump or something
like that.
Yeah,
she was having a bad time with her manager
and she destroyed the complete warehouse
or something like that
in the yellow.
Are, you
know, your enemy is building Java.
They need a lot of freedom.
Enemies.
Lady blew up on.
Okay, let me create a package.
I was here during the break
and you guys send me
in. You guys send me the requirements
for the
for the task.
These task are from yesterday's class.
I think Leonie has to do tasks
very serious this time.
I that we had a couple of minutes
about the capsule.
Can you repeat? Yes.
So we can use capsules
if we are having like high fever
or pain in the neck or something
like that.
Right.
You mean encapsulation, see.
So encapsulation
is when you hide your data by making your
member variables private
and then creating oblique methods
to access
those fields are to set
the that are to those fields.
So for example, if you are
if you think about the Facebook,
they take a lot of that out.
First name,
last name, username and password, right?
So if you are storing that,
that inside the class,
you don't want to make them public
because that way
everyone will be able to access them
and everyone will be able to modify them
without any rules.
Right.
For example, the Facebook might have rules
if a user is already
if someone has signed up
with the same username,
no two persons can have same username.
So when you are trying to create
your username, Facebook first checks
if this username already exist,
if this is the case
they show you and added, If not,
then they allow you
to be data in the banking sector
or other websites.
They have rules like let's say
for example, you can not have a password
less than eight characters.
You can not have a password
that does not contain maybe
special characters, uppercase, lowercase,
all of those checks,
they are performed in the getters.
You get a certain method
and once you pass those rules,
then do that.
I said to the fields of that class.
And similarly, when you have to access
that data, for example,
if you are using a banking application,
you cannot access your account balance
without providing
the correct username and password.
So you also have rules
if you have to access the data.
So you write
all those rules in getters and seconds
and you make your fields private
so that everyone goes through those rules
before
they can access their data.
Example
Well,
the thing that you have just
explained looting.
What was I to
what?
What was that LLC?
That was not an example.
You mean some client? I want you.
You want me to write some kind
of code in the ID?
Okay. So
I think the encapsulation laws
here, here we go.
Alexa, you don't have
access to the GitHub.
I have shared this coding to get up.
So for example, you see here name,
username, password and balance, right?
So I make all of them private
and then I make it public.
Speaking. Get the name right.
I want new examples.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
My Prince.
I will create a new example for you.
What kind of example
you want me to create.
Can you give me some kind of description?
Like, for example, how many fields
you want, what kind of methods
you want to include?
Alexa, Can we do it after the class
at the end of the at the end of the class?
Because it will take some time.
Maybe.
Please
remind me at the end of the class
or maybe during the break.
Okay.
He is going to forget
by the end of the class.
No, you. You can.
Can you remind me?
Actually, I had a good sleep today. The
I am fresh.
The sleep has a huge impact on your brain
and all that you do.
And the next day
I forgot.
It will be your homework.
All right.
Okay, so let's do the tasks.
I am not.
Yup, I am in. Good morning.
Although I have a paper tomorrow
to create a set collection
in which you need to add
the names of the countries in this set.
We want all the objects
to be sorted in alphabetical order.
Use two different ways
to retrieve
all the elements from that sector.
So first,
the requirement says we must have a
a set.
I think you did not burn your head
and that's
why you look happy.
I have a paper until midnight today.
I burned things
ex on the beach last night.
So there are two requirements.
First,
we have to use a set and the second is
the data
should be sorted in alphabetical order.
So can you guys tell me?
We discussed about three steps.
The start that spoke to that
alphabetical order
is called the Preset Guide.
So we will say
reset and we have to store
the names of the countries.
That means the data time should be
starting right
there followed
countries
is equal to new
and then the user of
and then we have to access the data
using two different ways.
Right.
So let's start from Alexey.
So the add metric,
because it is coming from the collections
framework and every class
in the collection framework
implements that collection interface.
And these add remove
and all of these common meters,
they are
coming from that collections framework.
So if I show you, if I click on preset
and if I you see
it implement the set interface
and this set interface,
it is actually extending.
Yep, yep.
We can write, we can even write.
Collection is equal to set same
parent child relationship right.
All these are they are collections
all the, all the P30 sets, they are sets,
they are implementing that set interface.
So if you guys see in here
all the classes in the collection
framework and they are actually
implementing.
So this is the top class,
the Iterable class, right.
The use you guys remember
the event operator that we used to get.
So here is backed by iterator
and because all the classes,
the implements, that means
you will be able to get this return
from all the classes in
the collection framework
and you guys don't need to worry about
this is for the lambda expressions
and this is for another type of iterator
with which we will all be discussing.
So all the classes.
So this I travel from the travel
interface, this collection interface
is extending this I travel and you guys
see in the array list and the link list.
This size method was there.
The use implemented was there contains
method the iterator right the operator
method that gives you the iterator
and the table extends
object estimate.
Actually the table does not extend
the object because object in the class.
So but all the classes in Java Bay
extend from object. Yes.
We will be having a review class tomorrow
so I prefer to array
and remove contains at all.
Remove all remove.
If this is the remove method that
Lubo and Simon you guys were using.
Right.
This is that remove if from that
that takes this lambda expression
and so they are all present
inside the collection framework.
So again, what we can do,
we don't have to memorize different
different methods
for all the collection framework.
We don't have to get methods in this act.
So get method is not present
in the collections framework
and we go to DB diving again.
So this is the table interface.
This is the collection interface
that I have just shown to you.
This is a list and that list,
the method is present inside this list.
What do you see in here? This
is not implementing this list.
That's why we don't have that method.
Also the sets.
They don't store
the data based on the indexes.
So that method is used to get the data
based on the indexes.
That's why it's not present over here.
I told you that the are
the the most wide
use case of the subclass.
All three are class.
Okay said preset and linked
I set is to only remove the duplicate
from other collections
and to sort your data.
There.
That's the use case that I have seen
in the industry.
So that's why it has very limited
functionality.
Okay, so there is no get
method available in here.
So how what I can do,
I can call the same add method.
Right.
Thank you.
Alexey and I have the countries
over here, so let me add
a few countries over here.
Okay.
So let's put Ukraine on the top
because keep calls.
So how can I trade through this data?
So the iterator is there, the loops,
they are there
right?
So one simple way, because I
was the reason for it being all
legacy,
you have used the retained all else
method as well.
So we we only had to retrieve
the elements from the side.
So it's your C the right what we can do
we can see
string country
and then we can see right.
And then we can print out to start.
So this is one of the ways to get
your data from any of the collections.
All right, guys.
So I put Ukraine on the top,
but I see Belgium on the top
while I do this happening.
Alexi I am sorry. Or the Ukrainians
because their the last position
that you see,
I put it on the top right it's yellow.
So because this is a preset
it will still be data
in sorted order.
All right
But it
okay so
and one of the simple ways if you want to
just print out through that our
so you can also directly just use intel
and then put the name of the
of this any of the collections.
Yeah.
So you will see that
that in this format this
and then your favorite operator
is also there right
so how can I get the right
this side to interface
it is implementing the collection
interface
and the title table is present there.
So how can I get to the operator?
I need to write, I triple in
and then I create
is equal to the name of any
any of the collection.
In our case it would.
So so I will say countries dot.
I try to write.
So can you guys tell me
what is this descending iterator?
Any guesses about this descending.
So first let me
let me show you this simple.
So from Z to here, so
there are three famous matters in this.
I create the right one I can use to check
if there are any elements
left in the iterator or not.
Right.
So I can call the first method,
which is iterator.
Dot has an x
and then I can simply say I prefer dot
next, let me put a line here
so you guys can distinguish, Oh,
we get that by using before the loop,
and then we get by using Dehydrator as
and I can
I use this symbol for loop as well
Guys, no need to string here,
all because the genetic apparatus
will also work,
but it's better to have that data type.
You guys remember what happens
if we don't specify the data type?
You might get some issues at runtime
and we never want to have issues on
runtime.
It's always better
to get the headers at compile time.
Just please leave each of the solution
where they are.
We want to know all layers of solution.
We will do that in the review class. If
yeah.
So we cannot be simple for law
to guarantee data from this act.
Okay.
Because there is no get method.
All right.
Do you guys have any questions?
I think it's clear.
No need of comments here
right these days to loop.
They are clear.
Do you guys want me to put some comments?
Maybe
you guys will forget after some time.
So getting the dirt
from insert using
one hand or little
symbol for loop.
Not possible because
in all that method is pleasant and
so maybe
Gohmert's always good
if someone don't need them,
there can be delete comments.
Yes, there was this example
on the internet. Oops
for comments like this.
If they see this dark sign. Right.
We had this. They did use
using a loops.
And so in the industry the standard is
we don't write a lot of comments.
Actually what we do is
we write the code in such a way
that no one needs the comments.
So this is the standard.
Write your code in such a way
that it's super, super easy to read.
Readability
is a very big issue in the industry,
so we only use the comments severely.
It can differ from company to company,
but at least the companies
that I have been working,
they they had this rule
that every developer has to use
these simple basic operations and
write the code in such a way
that everyone can understand.
If you look,
you guys are in learning, okay,
so should we move to the next task?
Okay, you guys send me the requirements
for the next task.
So some of you were asking
for the recording link.
I thought the card has already
shared the link.
Then that's why I didn't feel
I wake up at 3 a.m.
and deliver messages.
Hey, scheduling, scheduling a scheduling
event again in order to explain your code.
If you commented, I like this one.
Yeah. I also placed them
in the first class.
If you guys remember
when we were teaching you
about the comments
variable as this is a comment
that I have to declare this thing variable
and put the comment inside that variable.
Yep. I will show that.
I will check that. Now
create a set of cities.
Let me copy.
So you had to create a set of
city is not at a list of cities
why you created an ad at least
for one. Yes.
We can do this set like this.
Okay.
How many of you
watch the recording again
after class
to understand it in a better way?
Maybe.
Let's say if you have missed something or
me in
or I will share building criteria.
Actually, I was waiting for this zoom.
I was refreshing the page again and again
because sometimes
if the video is
big, it takes like 2 hours to
to process that video.
So then I and then then I saw the
how many hours in your day, guys
they don't have any life
does hash said maintains
the insertion order no time
and it does not maintain the linked link
the one maintains
the other.
It should be linked.
I said create a set of 30 then with
you want to make sure that oh okay.
Yes you guys are right.
We should be using the link sent
for selenium class forever to upload
what I will do
if you guys don't
get to your selenium class
in like 3 hours,
send me a message or tag me in.
This portion of the video
has not been shared.
I will share that with you.
And if you guys are facing
any other issues because I will now
stop teaching after now
from the next week.
So if you guys face any other issues
during your next courses or
anything like that,
you can still, if you don't get proper
response in this sport,
general or something like that,
you can always tag me or in this channel
or send me a direct message
so I create a set of cities.
Okay,
so we created a site in which you want
to make sure
the ad insertion order is maintained.
So because we want the insertion order
and that's why we use the link, dissect.
Okay.
And then what we want,
we want to remove any city
that starts with
the letter E, Right.
So if so, guys will will this operation,
will this operation change the.
It can change the size of this disk.
So what what should I do?
Should I use the enhanced
for loop or vibrator.
The vibrator. Right.
So I can go to the operator
in the same way
and I can see it greater.
I think you should take automation
as well.
I will be teaching a skill
and then at the end I will be teaching you
that in Jenkins we are.
We will automate everything from deploying
your code,
your Jenkins will convert, pull up,
it will execute your test case,
it will send you an email.
Your best guess is passed or failed.
You can just
rest that you you
you don't even need to press anything.
You would just need to push your code
and everything will be done automatically.
You will be just getting an email
whether all the task is his boss
or failed or everything has been deployed
successfully or not,
you should find the job as well.
Yes, that's, that's what I, I do actually.
And so load not worry about that as well.
You should teach everything.
Last week it happened to me a lot.
My girls
could not attend the Selenium session,
but they don't get a chance to watch.
It was posted at 4 a.m.
so you guys can. You guys can tell me.
I mean,
the syntax all we have been hiding
so many previously in this syntax.
If you are one of the course you
you can join syntax as well.
But once you have the industry experience
so like for example,
they are law and then
there was another who
just slipped through my mind.
There was another instructor
who used to be selenium.
They were previously
the student of syntax.
If we have any questions regarding job,
we can text you straight up. Yep.
So we will be creating a separate channel
for all of that.
So don't worry about that.
My girls.
So spring
and then
I Prater
is equal to
the they might be having separate groups
for the girls right daughters
I'll.
Okay so how can I get the data.
I just need to see cities that I clicked.
So now I have dehydrator
I can again same same thing.
I can write a loop.
I can say I created all pairs.
It means that the syntax will not tie
it as without experience.
If you guys can teach like for example,
we don't have any issues,
just tell me there's
actually a better way to do that.
We will tell you that we have experience,
but you have to believe us
as a group.
If you guys can pass my interview.
I mean, I will be taking the interview
and if you guys can pass in Java.
But why not?
You guys are more
than welcome to join syntax.
I just need to ask one question.
Can we call a static method inside
a non static
method right.
And all of you will fail because I
yes, I will help you pass.
So now what I can do,
I can restore the city
and I can see I create the next
and we can put a live condition now.
So if
so guys do you I
remember the method from the string class
that can help us
if they're going to help us check if a
a string is from a specif specific
character or not.
Yeah.
This starts with method, right?
So I just need to check if this city
dark starts weird
E right.
And if this condition is met
then using which method
I can remove this from this act.
You remove method. Right?
So I'd prefer not remove
so checking
if a string
with a
or not.
Right.
Removing it back
safely from db
from this act,
turn it into uppercase.
So in the requirement, if it was mentioned
only about to be uppercase dammit,
you want to include the lowercase as well.
You mean.
So you see in real life applications
you should always cater
for these conditions,
but the uppercase is fine.
So you guys can see this
two lowercase dot
and then right,
because it is a city
always in uppercase. Yep.
So you guys can also do this
first, convert everything to lowercase
and then check for the lowercase.
So city, if, if you face any issues,
you can always post in this post.
So let me, let me do this.
Okay.
And, and let's just try to check
if the city is removed
from the list on the set of Mark
I did yesterday.
So I still see that city in here. Guys,
what is going on?
Why I still see the city
this out.
Okay, You guys are north
champs, right?
So I first bring the list
that has this city, then I remove it
and then I put into that.
We can use
all clear
on. Let me check
if we are missing something from the
when you guys go through this slides,
is there anything that is confusing you?
The last task is very interesting.
Okay.
Next to solve the last task
as well, create
a collection
that will hold objects of stolen type.
So there.
Okay.
Because if you guys go to the slides
before the next class,
you guys can ask any questions
or if maybe something is confusing,
you create a set.
So in here we have to create a collection
that will hold
objects off to the side, right?
So that means
I have to create a student class
for the stars
and then create the objects of that class.
And then for those objects in this act,
in this set,
we do not care about the insertion order.
All right?
So I can use the hazard
or I can use any of this art, right?
Each student object
should have in name and the entirety
display name of each student.
Right.
So there are two simple features
inside the student
name.
I did it by constructor.
Okay, so student name.
And then
Student
I will be here to deconstruct
and then I have to
display the name. So.
So I created some kind of matter guys
or not, we haven't done it with hash map.
Do you mean
you have already learned the maps
key and value?
Okay, that's great. Today
we will discuss about that.
Then we can use that
map terms also.
Okay. So
lost the annex.
That's that's great.
So we need to print out the
the name of the office student.
So that's I'll name
right
who I have this student class
for me
and here
I'd also
know but the task
the only is about the name of the student
right now.
It's also fine
if you guys have been doing pretty
so start
what should be our today specifying
in this environment of recognize
what type of objects
I will be storing in this work.
The student of so I type
the name of that class,
I can call it student
and then new hashtag
because I don't care about the order.
So let's have the performance.
I said, Always
give me a good performance.
Okay.
So create a collection that will hold
the objects of student type.
We don't care about order.
Each student
objects have name and student I.D.
and then display the name
of each student.
Right.
So I say
I say
student, don't add new
student
Alexi
with an extra E here
and all ready.
One, two, three.
Then we have
all month
and the idea will be
poly.
One, two, three.
We need to.
And then
we have I show right
for all manual.
One, two, three.
I can do
that.
Sorry about that.
I hope you don't mind.
Okay, let me put all auto on quickly
then we have Sebastian.
We mean one, two, three.
Okay.
Two. Yeah.
And then
I have
to get the objects, all the objects,
and then I have to call the method
print name
on that object as well.
Right.
Well, I forgot about GAO.
One, two, three.
So what I can do, I can see 44 eight.
All right.
And then student
we're done
with and then. Student
And once you have
the object, I can see the student dog
came to me, right?
Because I only have to access the data.
So I can safely use the enhanced follow up
to it.
Ildiko
Break Manager
One, two, three.
Okay, so and I see big names, objects for
so this is how we can store
any of the objects
inside a list, any of the objects,
any questions that is from this
in English.
Alexey Ukraine of
So are you guys ready to move
to the next class?
Maybe Lubo. Okay.
On the request of Alexey, we have the Lubo
and let me put myself as
well.
I want to
thank you.
Okay?
Okay, then I understand that this task
is better to do by hash map.
Yes. These kind of data,
when you have to store the objects
with their identities, it's
always better to use the hash maps.
Actually, in collections framework,
the most widely used
data structure is the hash map
because it's super, super fast.
Are you guys having some kind of issues
with Zoom?
Did you all get this connector
next to the hash maps?
Then?
All right, guys.
So next class
is very easy again,
I guess next
class is on maps and it's very easy
because almost all of
the methods that you guys have learned,
they are kind of present in the map
again, easy again.
You guys don't like easy stuff
you say about back.
So now you guys know, you take
I always say that
everything is easy
and you end up are
okay.
No I think I'll do this class
it really easy you're easy to
easy difficult
the the last batch
Let let me show you something.
I don't know if that
that message is still there.
You see that student?
Like we have trust issues
because of this guy.
I forget an easy because a
previous had I always used to say,
I always used to say that, hey guys,
this class is super, super easy.
And now if any of this data,
this is that something is easy
to believe it.
All right. So
a map is an object.
So you guys want the examples first?
Oh, my God.
Like or like I like it.
Let me let.
So you guys want examples first?
All the theory
examples.
Okay.
And I want you,
everyone of you, to follow me.
So what we have been doing up
till now is first
we learned about the arrays
and ADD is they have so many issues,
they are not flexible.
And we can only if we store
the data inside an area, the only way to
if we need their data again,
we only need only thing that we can do
is either
iterate through that complete list,
check all the elements one by one.
And if that element is, we get
that element from the adding, right?
So all the data
was index based, I would say, okay
then we learned about the ArrayList right
there.
This solve
some of the issues of the arrays.
They were flexible.
They had methods to manipulate the data
and they were have different
implementations.
Great to retrieve the data.
Sometimes to manipulate that.
But still we have this issue that
if still we are looking for something
from the array list or from the array
internally, what Java is doing Java
is picking each element from that list
because they are index based
and comparing
if their thing is equal to or not.
So for example, if I create an ADI,
so can you guys tell me the syntax
for to create an ADI?
Do you guys remember the syntax?
So the for example in this Adi Right.
What Java.
What if we are doing everything
so what we have to do, let's
see if we are looking for something.
We have to.
I train through
this array
and check all the elements
and then we can tell
if that element is present inside
that array or not.
So yes, in the added list
we have that method contains,
but internally that contains
method is again doing the same thing.
So for example, if an element is inside
the list, I pick all the elements.
I go through all the elements one by one.
If that element is present,
then I can check that out.
Otherwise, I will not be
getting that element.
Then what?
Then we learned about the
array list. Right?
So ArrayList.
This solved some of the issues of
there was a
melding method here inside this ArrayList
to do the same thing.
So for example, add a list or contains
and then I specify
in there, say maybe 70.
So I get it from
because 70 is present in here.
But if I show you the internal
implementation of this contains.
So I have
I clicked on that method index off
and then you guys will see
that internally, the Java guys,
they are also using a loop.
They are
I printing through all the elements
one by one
that I present inside of that list.
And if that element is found,
then the return as the value.
So can you guys tell me if I have a list
that has 1 million entries
and the number that I am looking for it
present at the last index,
how many iterations I have to do before
I can find
that element?
1 million, right?
If that element is present
in maybe somewhere in between,
I maybe have to go through 500 key
elements.
Right. So what do you guys think?
Is it a good way
to start something in the computer? No.
So to solve this very big issue,
Java guys introduced the maps.
Now in eddies, or at
least what happens is that all the data
in the case of Arrays,
all the ArrayList, all the data is stored
internally inside adding.
So we pick the first element.
And so again,
so these are index zero one, two,
three, four, five, six.
So what we do, we
explore some elements in here.
In here, and then we search through
all the elements, starting from first one
by here, here, here and here.
So in the computer science
department there, there has been a tons
and tons of research on how to design
efficient algorithms that can help us
store, manipulate and search to do that.
Right.
So Imagine you are using the Facebook,
Facebook, have you
billions of users, right?
If you are logging into your account,
you enter your username and password
and think if you
if Facebook has to compare
all those 7 billion entries
and once all of those are compared,
then if Facebook like takes,
it will take days for the Facebook
to find if you are a valid user or not.
Right.
So in those cases,
we cannot use these data structure.
It is clear that is the big drawback
of these data structures
or is
anyone is confused If I have to do
searching,
is it clear why this ad is released
and link list are bad data structures?
Because in the worst case
I might have to go through all the entries
before I can find my diatribe.
In the worst case. Yes.
To search. Right.
So for the big data,
like, for example, Facebook, Amazon
or any other big company,
it's devastating.
So in the case of list as well.
So they are efficient
in manipulating their data.
But again,
if some element is present in here
and that is the element
that I am looking for,
then I have to first check first
check the content of this
class. I am searching for that.
If it is matched, then I do.
Then I say I have found the list.
Otherwise I go check the next,
I go check the next next.
And I keep on looking for the data.
So what? Computer science This.
They created a special data structure
that the data structure
is very, very special
I think this
this guy should be given a Nobel Prize.
So this data structure is is doing it.
He uses a special mathematical term, a
special duty,
the special maths behind this function.
It is called
the hash function.
All the cryptocurrencies,
they are based on these hash functions.
If we do not have these hash functions,
no cryptocurrency would have ever existed.
They are all based on this hash
hash function.
What is the beauty of this hash functions?
Let's say
I want to start under from this list.
I will enter this hundred
to this function
and as the output it will,
it will return me
to the exact direct
index of that and data We are back
there to is present.
So it does some kind of magic
which you guys don't need to worry about.
So I get I put in that line here
that I am looking for
and it directly gives me
the index of data from that computer.
So if
I am looking for 100, it will say
that is good. Yes.
Without searching guys, without searching
by just looking at the data,
it will say that it's good.
Yes, this data is present
and it is present at index number three.
How beautiful. Right.
So it will directly
it will tell me the index in here,
the index of this element.
If I want to search for, let's say 200,
this is not present in here.
So again,
I will input this blue 100 in here.
I will input to the data and it will
tell me that this data is not present.
It will return me minus one.
So these are hash functions.
We give them a key.
Key in our case is this data
and they tell us the exact memory
location inside our computer.
We are there.
Data is present. So you're searching.
So there is a special terminology.
We call them the in in this case
we call that we have to go through
and elements in the worst case
before we can find are elements
like an inventory check.
So using these data
and using this hash functions,
they develop the maps.
There is one more beautiful
about the maps in our real life place.
Do we have
always told me that based on the indexes
or do we use some real life information?
For example, let's say
I all
my data is stored somewhere in a computer.
I only tell them about the SSN number
and they can get them right.
So what happens is that in real life,
the entities
they are based on not indexes,
but they are based on some numbers
which have special meanings, right?
So for example, relatively beautiful that.
If I create a data structure
that instead of storing the data
based on index index zero index one,
it stores the data based on SSN number.
So maps can do that as well.
There are no indexes in MAP.
Rather, we create our own indexes.
We can use any type of data.
We can associate any type of key
with our data.
We just provide that key to the map
and it returns us that data
so we have real life.
We can use real life data
to create our own indexes.
So for example,
so for example, if I go in here
instead of always,
always storing your data
starting from index 0123,
I can create my custom indexes.
For example,
this is how we create a map, by the way.
So we say map
then Diamond operator, same as before.
And instead of one vector type
we specify two
because indexes they are
they work on two data types.
So let's say I specify integer and then
spin.
Right?
And I see
student info
is equal to new
hash map. Yes,
I will share the data.
So instead of
Alexa a new example.
You want me to do this in a new file?
You mean?
Okay, so just let me write to three lines
and then the next example
because it is related
to these things in here.
And that's why I'm doing it in here.
So instead of using always those indexes
that start from zero 1 to 3,
what I can do, I can see.
So this book method,
I used to put some data inside of the map.
I can see, let's say
maybe I want to start my index from ten.
Okay, I can do that.
Maybe the next index.
I don't want it to be 11.
I want it to be, let's say 100.
Okay.
I can also do that.
And now
so these indexes, they can be anything.
What I can do?
For example,
I can store your SSN numbers as indexes.
So for example, let's assume
this would be SSN number of Alexey.
Right?
This is the SSN number of Jimmy.
I don't need to do that.
That restriction that the index is will be
0123 is starting from 0123
and keep on going
is as the number of elements in that list.
I can put anything as the index inside
a map
and I can put the data
at that specific index.
And simply by
writing this student in for dark,
yet I specify the
index
and I get back my data.
So I get my bet, I get back my data
so I can now create custom indexes.
These indexes, they can be alphabet
or they can be numbered,
they can be integers, booleans, numbers,
whatever I want.
And now I can associate
real life information in here.
I can store maybe your names as the index.
I can use your names as the index
and as a data.
Maybe I am storing
how much money you are earning.
Where do you live? All that.
So now the final flexibility
that we are getting
with the help of this maps fast.
They are super, super fast.
Second custom indexes.
I can put anything as the index and I can
search there that I using that index.
So hash
map is just a collection of p value.
Yes. Sebastian does, it make sense. Why?
Why hash maps are back and then add is
ArrayList linked list and all that
I can will do three int and and string.
Yes yes we can do that.
So if I put printed in me
will I get four, four, five as printout.
So no, this is a one way relation.
We cannot, we, we can not pass the values.
So these are called values,
they are called keys.
So if you want to get the associated key.
We have to use some other methods
that I will teach you later.
But right now
it is not possible by default.
So give me that contains value.
It will only tell you if that value
is present, not inside of that map.
Okay.
It will not give you the key
for that value.
Yes, we can do something
by strings and all that.
So now I will show you 8
to 10 examples and then things will become
super, super clear.
At this point, I just want you
to understand the benefits of maps.
Why should you learn maps?
If that is clear,
then we can move forward.
Okay, so now let's move some examples in
then will be super, super clear.
Okay.
So let me put some comments for you.
Things
are stored based
on the indexes.
Easy peasy, hard.
Those are all right.
I have to go through
all the elements
in the
workspace
internally
contains
method is
knowing the same
and going through all the elements
who served.
I think if you to go to sleep
at least your brain efficiency
increases by 30%
more too easy peasy.
Okay,
so now let's say
physical
then it's
why Why are you guys don't type it?
It will be better for you, believe me.
Me, I just get connected again.
It was something wrong with my computer.
Don't send it
and people will start typing it.
Okay.
It's like switch case.
Yep. Yep.
Switch also uses the hash function
behind the scenes.
Yes, you are right.
That's why you should always use switch
cases instead of if health conditions.
If it is possible
actually switch and a hash maps.
They are both developed
using hash functions.
This.
So by the way, we use the boot method
to insert the data in the map
and we use the get method to get back
the data.
Let me know once you guys are done
typing this code, these demos,
they belong to 28.
Yes, they belong to 28.
We will take a break.
Let's have a break.
Okay.
So guys, during the break,
I want all of you to
either have Excel on your computer
or have that loops on your computer
or have that open office.
So let me show you.
They are all free alternatives,
all Microsoft Excel,
so you guys can install any of these.
I have only two monitors.
I think there's enough.
Alex, You want more?
Nothing is free. In the US. It's the same
everywhere.
But that open source software,
they are actually free.
I am a student, so actually free.
I want more monitors.
Can you send us an extra monitors?
I think they are super, super cheap.
I think you can get a monitor
for 50 to $60, right?
A good one.
Maybe around hundred or 120,
or you can import it from Ukraine.
Alexi much for the monitor.
$3. Good.
At least your best friend
who calls.
Yes, you can extend the monitor far too
cause
I think WPC is better.
You know, $15, $20
and do you guys remember how to know?
Google search will not work.
They can work, but it's hard.
They use different API.
We will not be learning those APIs
in Google sheets we can use,
but we will not be using in here.
Also,
everyone plays with all this website.
Let me put in the course announcements
that Excel is also good.
Actually is actually better.
So now I am going to show you something
very important. Guys
with you.
Don't get run.
See if the guy went out and today
he just leaves right?
So every one of you
have you guys open this this website
you have shared in the course
announcements channel.
You just give me one woman game. Yes.
You guys need to install the Apache
for you as well
because we will be rating the selfies
with the help of this library.
Can we just start and maybe
a project and enter dependencies
we will be teaching you maven
I think in the next week or so,
but if you know how to use Maven here,
you can,
you can do the minimum as
a you guys have to install it.
During the break
I will show you how to that
and then you have to resolve your issues
during the
break
so that we don't waste a lot of time.
So is there anyone who has still
not opened this website?
So I want you to pay attention.
If you guys don't pay attention,
you will be a lot of issues.
So there are multiple links in here.
You guys, please don't open
any of these links.
You see this binder in distribution?
This is for Mac users
and this one is for
Windows users.
Okay, so please don't make this mistake.
Let me repeat again.
You guys don't need to click on
any of these links in here.
You have to open binary distribution.
There are two links
in the binary distribution world.
Say one cheers and the underdog B, D, Z.
It is for Mac users
and the other one is their Phase Z IP.
It is for Windows
user.
Everyone has understood
which link you have to click.
Okay.
Yes, I know someone will still do it
wrong. Yes.
Binary distribution
and then zip for windows
Dart, d z for Mac users.
So now because I am using Windows,
I will click on this zip.
Please do not click on the zip.
If you are using a mac.
Okay.
I am clicking on this name
because I have windows.
Please do not click on this
if you are using a mac,
let's switch to second gear.
Okay.
And now on this website
you can have you can download from this,
this link or any of the links.
It does not matter which one works for
you, you can use any of that.
Okay.
So I will be using this suggested link
for download these files.
Yes, Nicolai.
That's why I am downloading
the downloading the zip file.
So are you guys
bear on this, am using this link
in because I have windows. Yes.
So once depending upon which software
you have to download,
it will be downloaded on your computer.
So this for Mac is then is please.
If you have Mac then then if you it.
What about static
we use we can call a static method
inside the instance method and
we can also deliver
right.
Okay.
You see.
So all right
you can click any of these links
and great Alex.
Which one do I have to click to download.
Now you are.
I have not. You are already downloaded it
said if
so now
you guys will see something like this.
So depending upon
which software you are using,
I am using ADR.
So that's why I see the icon like this
looks.
But if you have zip or
if you have anything else, you might see
a different icon.
Do you guys know how to extract
something on your computer.
It is in the zip format.
Okay, so now I want all of you
to extract these files.
Okay.
So I see, I see right
click ironically, then what I can do,
I can open it with binary
or I can click on this extract.
All you guys might not have this option
extract all depending upon which Windows
version you are using
or if you are using Mac, then
if I if this is the same
like for the last days,
how do I you on Mac Illini
you don't know how to extract files on Mac
against someone gadolinium
or if you are a mac user,
how to extract some data on Mac
I what
it's already extracted for me
so I say extract all
so you can install wind
audio from internet.
If you don't see that option
all the windows user,
they can just double click on that file
like this
and they will be able to see
some kind of pop up that shows all of you.
So if you guys are double clicking on this
and if you see the expecting
the expected data
that is not actually expected,
it is just showing you that that data.
So I explicitly want you to extract that.
Where do I go?
Go, go to New York, New York, Illinois.
There you will see a very big bridge.
I am in New York,
then go to So somewhere else
you go
give me
and anyone
else can can you please go about
that extraction?
So I say extract
and then I click on
Extract button.
And now, depending upon your computer,
it should it should create a separate
folder like this.
I want every one of you
to have this separate folder.
And if you go inside that folder
you will see Boy Bash
being or something like that.
And then you should see
this stack.
All questions about Mac users.
So next time you guys remember how to
import
the jobs in your intelligence, right?
Same as as you did for the selenium.
So now
go to file.
Now go to file.
Is everyone done
downloading and extracting the data
is the same as you download movies
could not see the extract option.
Okay.
You know,
you can just copy the all of this data
and you can place it
anywhere in a different folder.
If you guys are seeing this.
Okay, we just need that data.
Create a new folder
somewhere else on your computer and don't
forget about the part
and just copy and paste this that out
to that folder.
Can if. Are you done Illini?
Are you guys done extracting the data
to download
that is taking time want the extraction
extraction.
Are you using a Pentium three computer
you'll your guitar There is no zip on Mac.
Yes it will not be on Mac
it will be a dot b
d that
I am having Mac and it is hard.
Sorry, I don't know Illini
How did you do it for the Selenium
is the same, same
as you did for the Selenium
guy. It's the same
as you download the jobs for Selenium.
Silverstein and mine not showing this
on YouTube.
So you guys have forgot about how to do
that.
You are not showing on YouTube.
Okay.
Princes Illini,
I will buy a mac next time,
maybe before I show you something.
Same idea of downloading.
I am ready to extend my laptop to Mac.
That is what I am getting.
Okay, let me check.
Yes, this is what we want.
Go to
that for been 5.1 folder.
Yes, it is correct.
Yes, it is.
So it's actually a good idea.
Just double click on that folder.
Maybe something wrong with the mon again
and we move next.
No, Alex,
you want to leave your prince
or princess behind?
Finally.
Great idea.
And there are still prince and princess,
which we take which we need to with us.
We have a break.
People can ask at this time,
is there anyone who is still extracting
or maybe downloading data to
now 70 people wait for five people?
Yep. Yep.
Alex There is also not good.
So now everyone
get back to your intelligent
Leave no man behind.
So now click on
file, click on file
and then
project structure.
Alexia, you have noticed this
When you are talking to girls,
your English is perfect
when you have to ask our questions
that you would just type.
I don't even understand it properly.
What is this behavior?
I mean, so now click on file
and then project structure
Magic.
You have to be very clear with girls
and the girls, they are never clear
with you
so far.
And then project structure,
there was a famous dialog
in an Indian movie in which Katrina says,
Maja,
How to get to hold it on your husband.
Nadella So her boyfriend was about
to leave, and then she says, So she is.
He was in a different world.
So then the boyfriend looks at her
and then say, What do you want?
Then she says, Met you.
Get them to go get them.
You have to not.
Okay, so
this is the window.
Okay?
We are we will be importing.
So now you have to go to libraries
and starting modules.
Now you have to go to modules.
Can we get subtitles?
So there was there was a girl
who was talking to her boyfriend,
and her boyfriend
was about to leave, to somewhere.
So. And then, then, then she is
he acted like she is not happy with that.
So it's not a boyfriend. Ask that.
What is wrong with you?
Then she says, I want
you and you guys help me.
How can I say that?
Please go ahead.
I want you to walk back.
You don't go from here.
So modules
and now.
Because in the previous class
or so we created be
asked Dick Batch ten and batch 11.
In my country we can have four wives
but it's just kind of a thing
that no one can
no one will ever dare to do that.
Only one is more than enough.
So modules
and then you guys have to select as that
batch 11 from here.
Everybody is polymorphism.
So do you guys see this batch
11 option in here?
Lena It's not about money.
So now
you will see this and option.
So depending upon which word
you are using,
you might see this option somewhere here
or you might see some option
if you get it.
But look for that plus sign.
I see this plus sign.
My product has different name.
Is it okay?
Yes, it is okay.
Okay.
So once I click on that plus sign. Yes.
And if you are right,
then you have to click on jobs
or directories. Yes.
Same as selenium.
Do you guys see this, dogs or directories?
Okay.
Once I did contact,
now I have to specify that folder.
The part of that folder
in which I have extracted my files.
Usually those files that we downloaded
and the next selected.
Now I need to go to that file.
So in my case
I downloaded it inside downloads
and then
it was in compressed
and then Apache Point here.
Do I need this just for Java? Whoops.
No. You guys will be needing this
for your frameworks as well
and for your whole testing. It.
Do you guys see your dogs?
Okay, now
expand this lib folder.
Expand this little folder.
You guys will see more dos
and expand this
or x and mail folder as well.
It does not show java or directory.
That means all by
you have not extracted the files.
Or if or maybe you have
you have downloaded
the wrong jobs.
It does not
only new modules or import module.
Make sure you are on this modules option
and then you are not clicking on this.
Plus, although you are clicking on this
plus sign you have to click on.
There are two plus signs on this,
this window.
So let me go back.
Make sure, guys, if you click on here,
you will see new module on that option
that you are seeing,
although you are to click on this
plus sign this one, not this one.
Yeah.
And then make sure you are in here.
In here it is.
And dependencies.
No Bill, is it. Okay.
You see that option on
you see that option.
Okay.
Is there anyone else
who is facing any issues.
Yeah.
So click on this
plus sign.
It is not inside the or excel
and will
so jobs or directories.
Yes. I also have in a separate folder
everyone has have it in a separate folder.
So once I click on that plus
now I need to go to the folder here.
I have downloaded
my jars and extracted those jobs.
So in my case
I don't have anything in that lame
because you have not
extracting that file after
you have not expected in that file,
you are still opening the zip file
from your intelligent.
You have to go to the folder.
So this is what you are doing.
You are opening this
for door to be and that's
why you see nothing inside this live.
You have to
the folder that contains the expected
that this one not the zip the one.
That's why I told you
to explicitly extract from their data.
But I show both Laban and ExxonMobil.
Melanie open
why you have done the okay button.
I didn't tell you to do that.
Now remove those file
and repeal the steps in.
So I go inside of the folder
where I extract, delete
those jobs, okay?
And then I will see all of my jobs.
Yeah.
The lib folder, it contains the jar,
the X and my folder and all of that.
So now I want you to hold down your shift
button or control button
and then use the downwards arrow
or use your mouse
to select all of these jars
like this
to go back to the step. Yes.
And then expand the folders
and select all the jars. This
I don't know how I could do that in Mac.
Or maybe the view can be different,
but you have to select
all the docs like this down your control
button or shift,
but it is hidden now.
Well, I did it and done
full command in Mac.
Can I click on okay it? Yes.
Those will see the exact same view.
And if you guys able to select
all the jars you can click on.
Okay. No, no.
All of the other jobs as well
which are outside of these folders.
So let me show you the last sample.
So those who are bored with the last step,
I am selecting the right file.
So let me create a new file.
So those
who write Discord in
any of the job file
and if you don't get any errors,
that means you have done it correctly
and you can be on break. Now.
I have copied and pasted
because in the life questions
those who die of discord
and this import is there for you.
It means you are good
you. When we come back,
once all the issues are resolved,
maybe after three days
alone.
Well,
we'll see you on Saturday.
How many of you are getting any issues?
Click on.
Okay, Maryam, click on.
Okay. Yes.
And and maybe by quality.
Yes. After selecting the jobs press.
Okay. Yes.
So the mirror disconnect from the class
and initiate a new meeting and then share
that meetings link in the export
channel and everyone who is using Mac,
you guys can follow that link.
So the meeting
will guide you about the Mac.
So this is how you guys can be sure
if you write this line of code
and if you don't get any errors,
if your code is compiling successfully,
that means you guys are
good. Yes.
Are the remaining ones as well.
That 4.5.1
like this.
Sebastian, you are good.
You can you can leave.
It tells me one
of those doors is an empty library.
Can you share this screenshot?
You are also bold
always gaps. Yes.
When Mac users
please join the meeting shared by a link
shared by a dummy press.
Okay. Yes. Marina Press.
Okay.
Nothing. You are also good.
You can leave.
Will we get the virus
if we selected to the whole folder?
No, there is no virus.
But some of your antivirus
is or other security softwares.
They might warn you about these doors
because they can contain actually viruses.
Should I click on as good?
Yes, click on. Okay.
Don't click on me.
Mine is also I am done. See you tomorrow.
What time should we come
in? In 20 minutes.
We do. I find the link for them again.
Elena is in the
let me hear it in the course and also
our standard. I
think
there will be a video on the internet
and the.
Here we go. Okay,
let me share this with you.
So those who are facing
you shoot a very short video.
3 minutes.
You guys can follow this video.
I, I think here also on
this is the main to be the dialog one
it's find the one you
you just need to make sure that
when you write this line
you don't get any errors
if you don't
if are not getting any other thoughts,
that's fine
with you.
You you are not importing all the dos,
but until 130, maybe now
30, 20.
Not worry, I am not going on break.
I will help you solve your issues.
50% of difference you guys can post here.
The remaining 50%
you guys can post in this sports channel
and you guys can also follow that video
from the course announcement.
Seven
Please share screenshot
if you are getting any errors.
Mac users please do on the link
in the course announcement
and then we will show you how to do that.
The others.
If you are facing any issues,
please share the screenshot here
or in the sports channel.
Yes. Access of workbook.
If you're tired this don't get any errors.
You are going to
hear highlighted in back
in. That means you have done
something wrong Olga.
That means what do we do in the course?
And also questions and check which steps
you are missing.
Thanks.
I got an order on perfect.
And you guys have all installed either
WP s openoffice or excel as well.
Right?
And great. Great.
Now you guys, you guys can be on
break for 2 to 10 minutes.
I simply shared a screenshot.
Also share the screenshot of your jars
of your structure.
I think everyone has left.
Is there anyone still or am I talking to a
just my computer screen
or I think the video.
Great.
You are good
to BBC is okay? Yes.
Why yellow lamp?
This one.
This yellow lamp is telling you something
about your piece of code.
Or like for example,
if you want to replace it with a block.
Right.
Those different type of
comments,
is there anyone who is facing any issues
in a and property?
The original chair shared the screenshot.
It's fine now you're going to ignore this.
I will teach you about this
in the next class.
Yes. You are good
or you are missing.
Does that means you are missing jobs
that Andre you are missing?
Just watch the video from the course
and all sports channel
and redo the whole process.
Not not.
You don't need to download again.
I think you have downloaded
the characters,
but it will be good
if you watch the it from the start.
Okay.
I will be back in 2 minutes.
Is there anyone who is still facing issues
then near
the mean time? It's
are we ready or are we
okay?
Time?
Is everyone back.
So it's good to include the
all the libraries.
Okay I think they will not hardly.
And more thing.
Guys, please don't deliver this folder.
If you delete this folder, integrity
will not be able
to find those jobs in the future
and you will again be issues.
So the folder
in which you have expressed in your jobs,
you should not delete that folder or place
those data
somewhere else
and re-import in your intelligence.
Okay.
Because I see a lot of students
accidentally
delete the files and
when they open their project software,
some time,
nothing works.
Okay, so we were discussing about ripping
maps right?
Some maps.
They allow us to store the data
in the form of ease and devalues.
So how? How can I create a map? I Right.
So as we have three types
for this class cache set set
and then link said
we also have these two types for the maps
ash map three map
and then link the hash map.
So same behavior remap.
It will start your data
in ascending order.
Hash map will not store that
in any specific order,
but it's the fastest one.
And then we have the
link, the hash map, which will store the,
which will keep your insertion order.
So all we created the map, we write
hash map right.
And then I specified the diamond operator
and previously we were specifying
only one data type, right?
If we had both store integers
we used, we have been floating.
We have been specifying integer
if things we've think.
But in here we need to that types
So faster
data type
is treated as a key, as a string.
So let's say for example, if as a key,
if as a key you want to store
maybe the strings.
Okay.
And then as the data,
I want to store
the integers, right.
So new and then hash,
because these are classes.
So we had the add method.
So this is not a part of collections
framework,
but it is widely used with collections.
So we kind of
sometimes you in the industry,
you guys will see these terminologies
interchanging, they will use this
terminology interchangeably,
but this is not a part of collection,
it's a separate hierarchy.
So that's why we don't have backed
ADD method.
We have this put method.
So what we can do, we can see fruit
dot port
and now I can put my data.
So let's say for example,
I put apple and then its price.
Yeah.
Then maybe I save fruit and or or
mango and then I say 15
and then fruit or put
orange
in there.
So can you guys tell me
which of these two data types
are being used as keys,
which of them is being used as key
and which one is being used as value.
So the first time type that we specify
is created as key.
So apple and mango orange,
they are keys here
and these are the values
against those keys.
So the keys they can be integer,
they can be a string boolean,
any data type, you can have any data type
as key and any data type as value.
There is no restriction.
Okay?
It is no restriction.
So fruit diet
or maybe you
I show
you are still having issues.
Google this out of status
log log for there could not be find.
It means that you are not importing
all the jobs
through the output.
Okay I want
if you are facing an issue with the jobs
leave that and focus on in here
where you will be needing those jobs
after the next week.
So you guys still have time.
Let's focus on the class.
Please don't.
You can pause,
but don't be distracted by that.
So I mean, this is how I insert the data
inside an map using.
The parameter.
I have a lot of input, so make sure.
Yes, map maps are not part of collection,
so make sure or month.
If you are specifying
a string on the first place,
you are putting a string in here.
If you are
specifying and the second as the value,
you are putting an integer.
If you try to fit it
or you try to insert it wrong data type,
you will be getting in that a
Yes, I put hash start instead of hash map.
What is equal to and total same. Yes.
Then is
now as we have
building methods to manipulate the data
in collections framework
with arrays with Adel is with search.
We also have some meters
inside our to be maps.
So for example,
if you want to get the data
for a specific
so I can get the data, I, I just say fruit
or to get and here I specify the key
for which I want to get to that.
So for example, let's say the TV,
and if now I execute
my port, I get this 80,
okay, Okay.
So this is how we get the data from a map.
So if I, if you are getting null,
we make sure the case is case
sensitive again.
So if you if I put in start of capital K,
if I put lowercase square,
then I will be getting then.
Okay.
So make sure you guys are
how to make a ignore case in there.
So you have to
afford to pay that off
when you are putting the data,
you have to make sure it is
in the lowercase or uppercase
and then you have to keep
the same behavior
when you are getting that data.
So there is no thing that you can
convert your data
to uppercase or lowercase at runtime.
Why? I got this issue, it's fine.
And if you can ignore it, if
you can ignore this,
you guys can ignore all this.
Okay,
so this is how we get it in that
we specify the key
and we get the corresponding value
and they are sensitive.
No, it was not
because I specified the wrong case file.
Give me.
Okay.
And if I have to remove
any of data from my map,
I can do that by specifying the key
for let's say I don't want this
all in inside this map, right?
So what I can do, I can say a fruit
not remove.
And I can specify any of the keys
from here.
And that data will be removed,
both the keys and the value.
And it also returns
the value that it removes
so that you guys you are showed that
there was 20 against this audience.
And now if I print out of that nav
map here,
I don't see that orange in here.
Yeah, that orange has been removed.
Is it possible to get my index
We are getting by index
you mean one by one starting
from the first entry to the last one
there.
There
is no index or anything like that in maps,
but we can use the iterator
to get all the values
like three.
For example.
No, there is no.
I think the index is they are things
in our case
they are doing this.
Why am I pretty caught is first
because in hash map.
In hash map we cannot guarantee the order.
Remember, I am using a hash map.
Okay. Now,
if we are, are we now
just call back.
So we have created this map
and then
we have inserted some data
using the output method.
So I specify the key, the value, the key,
the value
given the value
question.
Make sure you don't want to be beaten
by Aisha
because she was having issues
for the last 30 minutes.
So root daughter get will return mean be
the value corresponding
you also joined right now
is is there anyone who is still
are you surprised how old they are you
so let me repeat those who have joined.
Let's move on.
So let me quickly do that.
So we have created a map
and we have specified string and integer
because we the keys to be string
and the values to be integer.
Then using the put method, we have
inserted some data inside to be map.
Let me share code with you.
So those who have joined
and then we are now learning about
the methods that are present in maps.
So if we want to get feedback now
from a map which the key for example,
give me and we get the corresponding value
like 18 in here,
if we want to remove, we specify the key
and that E is now removed from this map.
So maps, they work most of the time.
They work based on keys.
So the next method
is if you want to check
if a certain thing is present inside
the map or not.
So let's say, for example,
I want to check if in this map
contains the key
goal or not.
Right.
So I can use this contains key method
to check for keys
and now I get false.
That means this key is not present
inside this map.
If I say let's say
maybe mango,
then I read that
it true, right?
So I get it to
and I can also check for the values.
So let's say, for example,
I want to check
if a certain value is present
inside this map or not.
So let's say, for example, I can see
maybe if Value hundred is present as a
as a value or not, inside of this.
Well, so I get a false
so it
will return you
are these methods clear days
How to see the equal to Apple
is equal to ten back and how to add
so this works
because of the boosting method
that I will teach you in the review class.
So a lot
you can modify as per your needs
and if you want
to think
you can, we use ignore case for example?
No, we can not do that here.
You have to be careful
when inserting the entertainment.
And then there is another map.
Can we use lowercase or uppercase?
Not at the time
when you are retrieving Beretta,
but you have to use that lowercase
when you are inserting the data
so that you always know
that your keys are in lowercase.
So this is empty
method is also present in here
where this method will return.
Guys.
All right, It will return a boolean value
and the value
will be false.
If I have an error in another class
and it bothers me, please repeat
how to ignore.
Okay,
give me one moment.
Let me just complete this exercise.
So there is one more thing.
If You want to replace Alexa.
Obviously, if we want to replace
the value of a certain key.
So for example, you can use
the replacement in here,
so you can say, let's maybe for the mango
instead of 15,
let's say party for.
And now if we printed the map again,
we see 35 mango.
So if a file is bothering you,
you can double click
on your shift button quickly.
You can type
Explore's.
Okay, Alexa, do you see this
excludes option
double click your shift button
twice,
and then type excludes.
Then you show it again.
I did nothing.
I just double
click my shift button on on here
this list, double click on this.
Shift them.
You guys see this option?
Okay, now click on this.
Excuse
and then click
on this last button to exclude the fires
that are bothering you.
I am always using that really helpful.
What do you mean really helpful for what?
To select the files.
Oops.
So now you have to go back to your project
or my project
Eclipse Workspace
and then ask that fetch 11.
So not directly
eclipse
programs like everybody
else. I
let me find
give me a little
they are in
us journal the idea of project okay
and we were earlier point there
and then I run and then s C
and then you can select any of the file
that is bothering you select.
So for example,
this file is having issues.
So if I click on okay
then invalidate
will not include that file
in compilation.
So for example, if I click on
okay then I will not be getting anything.
I'll do I do on Mac.
It's same on Mac as well
with all the files. Alex
All files are bothering you
in in here.
Same on Mac as well.
The only thing that can be different is
how to look at your files.
That is what I see. Yes.
You have to now find your project.
Right? We are.
Your project is looked at here.
So for example,
I get the directory from here.
I was also unable to find my project,
so my projects are located
in this directory.
So you can also close that window
and you can check part.
So my projects that are present in here.
So you have to move to this statically.
And I think here is one more solution.
Tell this Mac and by Windows computers,
but is not it
better to go and put a mistake in there.
Quite. Yes. It's also good.
It's also good to correct
if you know how to correct it.
Expensive to buy another.
I think you will get better.
You will get a better one.
A good Windows
laptop or a computer.
This many.
Yeah.
Here is the third
one is ready to exchange.
Would one
take that feature out for example?
You don't want to include the files
that are the problems.
There must be.
There must be something like that.
I will search it
and I will let you know in the next class.
Okay, so
this is how we use before this
course start.
You always told told that no active
background needed, but you never said that
this course is good for people
who never saw the computer before.
And maybe, maybe next day.
We shouldn't say you should know
how to use mobile phone or a laptop.
Right.
But let's do one more example
of our thing that
is there
anyone who has shifted
from Android to Apple iPhone?
I am planning to do that,
but I don't see a lot of features.
Like for example, in my Android,
I can use multiple accounts
for Facebook, WhatsApp, I can have bought
WhatsApp, Facebook accounts
like that and like things like that.
I don't see a lot of features
in the iPhone right?
Okay.
Thank you, guys.
Okay, So let's do
one more example about the maps, guys.
So this time, let's say I want to store
the keys as the index
and then the strings
as the value.
If you have complete set party,
then go for it.
No, I don't.
I never saw a computer before at all.
Seriously, Alexi
No, I
am not planning to have because they cause
a lot of problems right now.
I have multiple monitors
and windows, computer work perfectly.
I don't have to buy those extra cables
and all of that.
I can connect with my laptop.
Three, four pair monitors easily.
No, If you just need cable.
I saw a lot of video.
The there is a ton of things
that you will be needing for that.
But if you want to do that,
yes, we will do that as well.
So guys, let's this time now.
Okay, guys, I never ask any question.
So last time let's use the link
hash map.
Okay.
And again, the diamond operator
and then I need to specify the key.
So let's say this time
the key, they are integers
and this time the data is of five string.
Okay.
Me this.
Let me find a better example for
Iran on that example.
So let's say
now I want to store the keys
as the numbers
and so let me call it as
students.
And then
they are named as the keys.
So I will say new
linked hash map.
So now, because this time I have my keys
as integer, so I will
now insert the keys
as integer and the values
of values will be like this.
So I can do that as well, right?
I can use any type of data as keys,
any type of data as values.
Just it should just be an object
of a class.
Okay.
And if I try to duplicate that data
so maps, they cannot have duplicate keys.
The keys, they should always be unique.
Okay, data can duplicate,
but the keys, they should all
always be unique.
So now
first I had let's see now I
am trying to insert a thing
down is with the same key
so I cannot do that
is there should be unique. It
and real life example again
like house keys.
Yep yep yep.
So in here let's say
we are inserting the roll numbers and the
and the names of these students
and no,
we will not be getting that on time matter
then that will be replaced.
So maybe a rendered and then with
Are you happy now?
Okay, so
now if I print out this map
or with this key, then
instead of let's see, I am
so it will retain the last value
that you have placed me.
Because because we have we are
we have tried to insert that again
with the key that was already there.
That's why you see
the key is same then and then then
so is cannot be duplicate.
If we try to insert the data
with the same key that is already present
it will overwrite that data.
Now I am not happy.
Okay, let's do this.
What are what I really get
now guys, for the key.
Then what output I will get to.
Now I get the MLC because last
I inserted Alexi with this key.
Okay.
So it will be still on the first place,
but it will be replaced.
And then
the next key is 20 we see.
Then if and then the next key is know. So.
All right.
So if I, if I put Alexi
after inserting Denis
and he know
and I am using linked the high set,
will I see Alexi still
and the first location
or will I see it at the last location.
So because the length has set
maintains the insertion order,
I inserted this key first and maps.
They work on the keys they based.
They are based on the keys.
So it will always be the first entry
whether you are replacing it
at the last in the middle or anyway.
So once you insert a key that key.
So this is how it is working.
So this is a map.
I have two portions,
one for ski, one for my values.
So I insert, I put Alexi in here,
then I replace it with
and then I again replace it with Alexi.
So this, this is not this will not change
this this location, this first index.
Okay?
It will always be first
because we we already had inserted
that key in the first place.
So it is dependent on key.
So no matter when you are replacing that,
it will always be the first one.
Then we inserted the next
20 and the corresponding data
so it will maintain the order.
Yeah, for the keys.
And then we have under
and then you know,
so when we again try to do this then
and then next
the first job I will search
if the ski is already present or not.
If this is present,
then it will replace this again.
Yeah.
So therefore all the Lingard hash
map works in Java.
All right.
Is it clear, guys, can you zoom out
so we can see the nodes on the computer
on the next line?
Actually,
what happened if we put Alexi between and
and then is
like this
still it will this key is first
if however if we do this
then what
will be the order of the database?
If I do this
the E here
so it retains the order based on keys.
Is it clear now?
Not it
is not starting with number Parliament.
It is linked to hash map.
It is returning B insertion order.
So how do we know
how many of a certainty is there?
If the list is a larger
and you are not aware of it
and this for example,
to remove repeated entries
so so how do we know
how many of a certain key
so one key can have
There can be one unique key in a map.
This cannot be duplicate keys.
And if you are trying to insert in data
with that key
cluster, you can try to check that
to using for example, contains
method or any other method.
If the data for that key
is already present or not.
Okay.
If that is present then
maybe you don't want to replace there.
Otherwise you want to place
there is one more method.
So for
example, you want to replace the net.
All right.
So now if the key for this
and if this then is already
present inside the map,
it will replace it.
Okay?
Otherwise it will do nothing
as well.
Do you know what they would go for?
It is no.
Denis, can you share this screenshot?
So guys, now
if I don't have this
then only
will I see the ten here.
Now I will not see it.
But if this data will this
he is already present,
then it will be replaced.
Okay.
So maybe you want to use the replace
method.
Maybe.
Maybe you want to use the replacement part
or your your question
is the other way around. Yes.
If we don't have the key,
we cannot replace it.
You guys will never tell me about these
special things.
Right?
Yeah. Oh.
Oh, this is related to this class, Denis.
People use these kind of things
to do magic, right?
For black magic magic.
It's very simple.
Voodoo Toy is part of Java.
Maybe there is some kind of
or there is voodoo doll.
And by the way, this, that
easy peasy.
So that is maybe you want to try this help
if you are having trouble melting stress.
This is the app for you
Voodoo is great for stress relief.
Are you frustrated?
No, I did it.
Everyone, please.
By person, by
It's a
punching bag
is also good.
So is it clear, guys, this example
support.
If that is not present,
people will install them better.
If that guy is already present,
it will replace that data.
But replace only replaces
if that data is already present.
So this is the difference between replace.
Oops.
We can only replace the value,
not the key.
No. How can we replace the key? Right.
Because keys. They are unique.
We can remove one key.
We can remove and then insert the new one.
If this is what you mean by replacing key.
All right,
so let me show you another thing.
So this class is easy, right?
Easy peasy.
It's similar to the collections framework.
Okay, Let me make it hard for you.
We will go deeper.
We are not going deeper.
You guys are not ready.
Okay,
So let's say I have two maps
and I want to combine those two maps.
Yes, it is not a collection framework,
but it's very similar to that.
So in industry, people can use sometimes
these things you.
So okay,
let me use a
tree map this time.
So tree map and then the next to
the keys will be string.
And this time let's say let's use double
U and then
bring
what is pendulum
edge device that
just keeps on swinging from here
and it's heavily
used in heavily studied in physics
of okay, so let me put some
more of these in here
to say X
and then how much for the end, Alexey
how much in the Ukraine for flags
people use as a showpiece as well.
3199 in here.
Okay.
When you
put the out for 2.5
so tomato is not for
3.2 guys
notice this in
in primitive data type
java used to convert your
primitives automatically.
For example, if I have specified double
and if I try to use an integer
now I get an error.
That auto conversion
is not applicable in here
because now we are dealing with objects.
Yeah.
So if I am specifying double
and I try to put an integer,
it will auto convert that.
Yeah,
we have to be careful about that as well.
Let me it in here somewhere.
Yes. No costing because now
we are dealing with the wrapper classes.
They are separate objects.
So I need to put this 10.0
in here.
Lola, how much
for one could Alexi
one can you put to
and let's say I have another
list.
So three map
and then
there can copy this
configure the $1.5 controller
that I see.
That's why you also have the
0.3%, right?
Give me some more things
to put inside this map.
Sweet potatoes are the
be it for $2.
Okay, so now
let's say
I want to combine these two maps.
So can I do the same with collections?
If I have two different list,
can I combine them into a single list
in a collection
using which method?
Can you guys tell me
the name of the method using which I can
combine two lists completely
without going through all the elements
one by one
there was a
add method to add the elements one by one,
and there was another method
to add all the elements
at once from one list.
Add. All right, so we have
the book all method in
maps, same as the case
with ADD all methods.
So if I say put all three of the list
one and two.
Now all the data from both
the maps will be combined
inside this third list.
Then we do that in child classes.
You mean if in here you are using a parent
that are type and in another
you are using a child
data type inside the map.
Denis
So now
I see all of my data combined
and then we put in one line, one,
then we put in one line.
What do you mean by one line?
Aleks
So data from this map
growth,
you mean like this, like this?
No, it's not possible.
It's not possible.
Is it clear, guys, what is happening here?
Is it clear?
Okay,
so we can insert the null values as well.
So for example
if I is the to
used do not put I can use.
Oh I can not actually so null
and null.
So if I tried to do this can we do like
we did add a list in analyst together.
You showed one example previous.
Can we do
like would did ArrayList
in the list add it to get the
I don't understand your question
so if we try to insert a null values
inside a tree map,
you guys will be getting this null pointer
exception because remap
has to solve to be values
and for sorting it compares
all the data types
and when during the comparison
it gets this error.
So for the
three maps
null is are not allowed.
But we can combine any map
or just map anywhere.
So for example, let's say
okay, and I want to show this as well.
So if we have the hash map
and if now here
in in three maps,
so I have this hash map
and this is tree map.
So nodes are not allowed tree map.
So let's see if they are allowed
in the hash map.
So because tree map
has to compare the values,
because it has to far
to be values in here.
So we will not be getting any issues
in here.
Yeah, but again,
when we will be combining this, actually
let me show this
null thing in a separate example.
Let's keep this example
only for the put on.
If it is clear I will create a new file
so it is allowed
that one of the maps can be hash map.
The other one is tree map and then I can
combine more null and all that.
I don't understand the difference between
hash map remember and then dash map.
Hash map
will not
maintain the information ordered tree
map will far field back based on your keys
and let's link the hash map will retain
the order in instruction
or the same as the case with search
same as the case with deserts.
You guys want to have a break.
Maps in our key values
you know
for all removed that contains
contains value.
Okay clear long contains key value.
And so clearly we would delete
all the data.
We have not discussed this one.
Let me give you some tasks as well.
We questions should be bigger before
a because three map source alphabetically.
Just give me one moment.
So it is one task.
Okay, let's let's keep it to one tasks.
What a task. So
in here
this starting
is actually not based
on the first two letters on the.
Okay, so the sorting is complex.
It is using you guys remember that
ASCII table.
So for all the characters,
it is looking for the ASCII values
behind that and.
Then it combines
all the values for all the letters
and then it calculates the order.
Yeah, right.
So that's why we don't see this before.
And it also takes the upper case
and lower case bear with lower case
E is with uppercase.
So let's say, for example,
if I put the beer with capital
B, so now beer will be at first.
So on that ASCII table, you guys will see
that the uppercase alphabets,
they are first and the lowercase ones
they are after
30 minutes initially.
So the starting is done based on that.
That ASCII table.
So if you guys see this, the value of
this is 41, right?
But if you check the value of lowercase
here, it's a 61.
So 41 uppercase letters,
they will come first
when sorting and the lowercase
will come after tomorrow night.
It's clear why we see AGs with capital E
first and B as of today.
Okay.
Do you guys want to break?
Let's be fair or
143 minus is slipping
or are already left B class
maybe enjoying the sun?
No is
all in case.
Remind me about the reporting
you read the back?
Yeah.
I want to task volatility
this time is busy
a little question
can you download that video
and convert it to and before
you create a map of buildings,
store the floor number and
its associated company name.
For example,
Google Syntactic insert seven entries
with duplicate keys and values.
Check how many entries you have
to remove and bring to your map.
So which type of map
you guys have used for this?
So let me be the example from
the map hash map.
So is the order retained.
So either
you should use the dream map or the
linked hash map, right?
If you want to retain the order
and as a key,
we should use integers
and as a values, we should use the string.
Then simply we have to insert some values
and then after inserting
update company on the fourth floor.
So instead of Facebook, now
we have matter and remove the company
on the floor.
Number seven.
So let's say for example,
how can I remove the value?
I can say remove
and then I can specify the key,
which is duplicate.
Okay, let me put it to it
and check the size as well.
Okay, let's bring this size as well. So
building or size
and then the map,
we have total six keys and six values
because we removed one.
And for the duplicate, let's say,
okay, if we try to insert Amazon,
so will we see the Facebook
or the Amazon guys?
So because we are replacing
the same company, let me put it on five
now you guys will see it.
Okay,
so we see Amazon for for an hour 45.
Are there any questions?
Okay.
So for the next example, let me
let me use this map.
So let's say, guys, now
you want to remove
some values
based on key
or value.
Now, if we try to do that,
we might
end up
changing the size of the map, right?
So when we are doing an operation
that can change this size,
what should we do, guys?
Should we use the normal for loops
or should we use something else
using
We should use the I create those, right?
So How we can get the operator in maps.
So there are two types
of three types of traders in maps.
One that can give us keys of the map,
one that new that can give us the values
and there is this third time
which can give us both keys and values.
So let's start from the
simple one they can do
that tells us the keys.
So example.
So we have this map and if we see
key said
so before the articles,
let me tell you about the
how you can get the keys separately
and the value
separately from a map.
Okay.
So if I say key sect,
the then I show you that intelligent
can also introduce local variables
for you automatically like this.
Then you guys give me.
So if a map third is returning something
and you are not sure about exactly
which
type of variable you should use the store
that you can press all enter
and then click on
introduce local variable
or what you can do.
You can also say
I create all our set and string
so it will write a loop for you as well.
So writing a loop from a key set or first
storing it inside a variable.
Okay.
Me change it
to keys.
So this key.
So it returns us a set
of all the keys
that are present inside of this map.
Why we get this guys
is it safe to have this x.
So now all the keys
will be converted to a set
and this he said to method
will return us all the keys
separately from a map.
So for example,
now I have the keys I can put in data.
Right?
So keys.
So I get
only and only the keys from this map
using this key segmented.
And there another method
to get the values.
Can you guys search
through your intelligent
and tell me the name of dark matter
if I only want be
from this sect?
Surprise me.
Dark values.
Yeah, well, you said.
But what if there are duplicate values?
So is it safe to have this set
for the values
or just only safe for the keys?
So in maps we are sure that
there will no duplicate keys,
but we cannot say that with the
values. Right.
I can.
I can have a duplicate value.
No issues with that.
So if we get a set in here,
what will happen guys?
All those duplicates,
they will be removed.
So instead of that we get a collection
and the
and the values they are off type double.
So we get a double and then values.
Remember that collection framework.
So if you want the values
you only if you are only interested
in them, in the values
from a map
you can get that.
And if you are interested
only in keys, you can also get that.
How can I get a
how can I get the keys from the map?
I can write
this key set in here
and if I want the values,
I can also write.
I can also call this values method and
it will only only written with the values.
But this key set it returns.
Give me a set.
But this values.
It returns as a collection. Why?
Because keys can never be duplicate
so it's safe to have them in a set.
But the values can be duplicated
so we get a collection
back from the values method.
Is it clear right.
Line 80.
Here we are getting
here we
are getting the values from this set
and here we are getting the keys.
So if you all, if you are only
and only interested in keys,
you can call this method
and that method will return
all the keys in the form of a sect
and then you can put into them out here.
If you are only only interested in values
of a map,
you can call the values
method to get the values.
But this values method
returns
the values in the form of a collection.
What does this collection?
You guys
remember the interface in collection
and then you can get
only and only the values.
So it's kind of separating out the keys
and values from a map and returning.
Returning you the data in separate
data structures in the form of collections
you asset returns a set view of
is contained in this map.
Yes, if you are right,
is there any shortcut you did
to get collection by help of intelligence?
No, no, there is no shortcut.
The shortcut was just to introduce
the variable.
So let's say if I delayed this, I want
if I only want the values, I will say
collection and these types of the values
if double double
values is equal to the name
of the map and dark values.
So so key is always come first
inside the bracket. Yes.
Yes. Actually you are right.
We can directly do s our growth grocery is
not value is that I You are correct.
We can also do that.
Is it paradise?
What I am doing on line 16 and on line 18
we can
use this to store username and password.
Yes, we can also do that.
What is the difference
between keys are ten and three
said we will discuss entry set as well.
Just give me one moment.
It's good time for now.
I hope I will be able to remember tomorrow
and if so, no duplicates is allowed in
both.
No values can be duplicate.
You see, I am inserting 4.3 twice
so the alias can do.
We can.
We can have duplicate values but not keys.
So if I print out this map here
in case of username
and password, if you want to store
the username and password,
you don't want to have duplicate passwords
like for example.
Nor not, two persons can also have same
passwords.
We find that
this password is
already used by star 119 to try another.
You you want to have a nice
you own the password as well,
but we need to thank it.
So once you know the password
you want to tell that he was user,
please use a different password.
We and in the two users
can have duplicate password.
Is there any harm that.
But yes, if you want
that you have to think of another way
it's not possible do using maps because
maps they can have duplicate values.
You can have a check on usernames
but not on maps
to print keys.
Why do we use a set
and a collection of our values?
So this is how it is by default
and designed by Java guys?
Because keys,
they always have unique values.
They use the asset for that
and values can duplicated
so that that's why they use collection.
I have tried to find key asset
by using collection.
It works with this way as well.
Building.
Oh yes, because the set all set is
also a collection.
Now is good. You see
they are
all coming from the collections
framework, right?
So you guys remember that.
So for example, if you want to do this
right, you can also do that.
You, you can use the collection for both
because collection is better integrate
collection is the parent parent interface
and the asset class is implementing
in the early stages, implementing it.
All the classes
they are implementing so child class
objects can be stored in the parent class.
Easy attention.
Would you just go to hash map?
I really don't understand.
I We're doing
we ending the class a little different.
Know why we should end the class?
At least let me rephrase what companies
use for storing user name passwords.
They use something called the database.
I will teach you that database
in the next month or so.
Maps can not have duplicate for kids,
but it allows duplicate for values.
Yes, you'll get that.
That's why you
you can use the collection for both
is are
clear now guys so this
variable is going to be of my collection
can I can I use the table here?
So if you guys remember
why I am able
to use any of the collection or START
or any of this because this collection
is the parent of all is parent of
is the parent of list.
So I can use collection
to store both type of objects
and I even more parent of all
so you can use the table
as reported depends on you
but do you guys remember
the disadvantage of doing this?
I will only be able to call the methods
which are present inside the table
if I stored that inside the table.
Right.
If I store that variable inside
a collection, I will only be able to call
the methods from collection
that are same in
both of those classes.
If there is a specific method,
I will not be able to do that.
All right.
So is it clear now?
So this is how we get the is
this is how we get the value of it.
It depends you in which variable
you want to store.
So let me copy this for the next demo
and let me
remove this.
So once I have a guys, once I have a set,
can I get it later from a set?
If I have a set, can I get iterator
from that set?
So what I can do, I can see out.
I tried to write
because we all know that we can have
and I can see
that now I have an operator.
So what I did
from the map, I first
got the keys in the form of a set
and on that set now I am on top of that.
I am getting the art from that.
So it clear, guys,
what I am doing on this line from the map.
First I get the ease
and from those keys
I get the operator right.
So now I can loop through the keys, right?
I can see keys not has the next
and then I can print out using the
is the dot
next method right.
So I get all the using here all use.
Is it clear what I am doing in here?
From the map I separate all the keys
in a set and once I have set
I get the operator from that set.
Can you repeat please in line 17.
So from the map
I get the keys are tracking problems.
So from map
I get a set
and from assert I got the right later
I get on this line line 17
again because you guys remember
the I table
interface is implemented
by collections framework
but we don't have
that flexibility in the maps.
So that's why we convert the maps to
the collections.
It can be a
side is can be at a established
or anything like that.
And then we get the iterator from that.
And let's say guys,
I want to remove all the,
all the elements
which contain this letter.
E So I want to those keys.
Can you guys help me
write down the logic for that?
So I have a, I have e
using
keys and next
what should I write then
if I want to remove the keys
that contain the letter E
if E contains letter E,
which method I can call from the iterator
to remove the entries.
I see.
Let me rename it to iterator
so that it is clear.
So I treated
and has next to it or not next
and I say I prefer dot remove
and now if I print my map
in here
I only get milk and tomato.
Right.
The egg, the rice, they have been removed.
So this is how we remove the entries
from a map using iterator.
I can do it separate separately for keys.
I can do it separately for values
and I can do combined
with keys and values.
So right now we are learning
how to only delete certain keys.
Then we will discuss how to delete values.
Only then we will discuss
how to delete both both of them
if we are going
how wide these keys have been deleted.
Why are these two
things have been deleted from this map?
So first I get to the keys,
then I get the iterator
from those keys
and then the this this logic.
You guys already know
the only thing that can confuse you.
It might be distinct.
So from MAP we get the keys,
these keys, egg, rice, tomato
and then we get iterator on top of that.
Can I move to the next example?
I think you guys are more tired
or better than me.
Okay. Yes.
So let me.
Yeah.
And the third part.
So previously I was injecting
a key set.
If I want to get the values
which method I should use
instead of this case,
the guys,
the values method
and what is the data type of values
method.
It's a double.
So I should change this
to double estimate. Yes.
And then it will be double here as well.
So let's write this logic again.
So I am this time.
What's the use of real life?
In the real life,
we will learn that in the next class.
And when you will be
building the framework, you guys will see
all the use cases
for all the Java that you have. Like
do you guys use
loops or methods or variables in selenium
and you guys use the variables,
insulin to interact with web pages.
You guys didn't use variables.
How you have been storing your data.
You guys didn't create any variable
to store any
anything in there.
What is what is the web driver?
VM driver is a variable.
How are you guys using the methods?
Get title.
They are all real life use cases.
I virtually knew.
No, it's cool.
I like it because of okay,
so I am getting the values
and from values I am getting the iterator
and now I can write any logic.
For example, let's say
if so, first by right double
value.
I say I create third or next,
and then I say if
value is C equal.
If the value is equal to 4.3,
then I say I pay third or three more.
So now if you guys notice all the values
which were 4.3, they have been removed.
They have been removed.
So if you are only interested in values,
you want to manipulate the values
from a map using an arbitrator.
You can use this approach
if you are only interested in keys
and you want to use the iterator for keys,
you can use the previous approach
and if you are interested in both of them,
then we have another thing
that is called entry set,
so we can use that as well.
Is it clear, guys,
this example.
So let's use the third type
to get to both keys and values
using a single iterator.
Before I show you that,
let me tell you a concept
that is called
the empty set
internally, when we create a set
here,
let me do this.
So what Java is doing internally
in Java, Dave
both of these values is
and I'll create
a box around them.
So inside this bigger box, this
if this is a map,
this inner box is called a single entry,
then it will do the same
for the second entry.
It will create an entry in here, in here
and here.
And inside of that entry,
all the data from here
will be stored in the form of entries,
in the form of entries.
So what happens
is that if we want to get both the keys
and the values, so what
will be your major in which position
you want your plan to work?
I will be an automation and I Indian
you artificial intelligence,
building algorithms and robots
that can work like humans.
After my master.
This is where I am planning to do my Ph.D.
next year.
You will control all Pakistan.
You want to teach? Yes.
Until I am done with my Ph.D.,
I will be teaching next five years
at least I will be teaching.
So, guys,
if I want to get to both the keys
and the values combined,
why do you need to be?
Because to to have my research,
you know, multiple publications.
Papers? Yep. Passion.
Totally passion.
So if I want to have both keys
and values in a single set,
I need to get a special type of printer
that is called Entry SEQ.
And basically,
if there is going to be a judgment day,
we want to know who to thank. So
they have already started doing that logo.
They have already started
doing their role both
You could see that
it was a cleaning robot.
The lady was sleeping and it took all
the scientist.
Yeah,
it's vacuum robot is sleeping.
WOMAN Here it's
and so it begins
with the yeah,
you guys need to be very careful.
Oh, my God, She is not going
anywhere else in the future.
So if I want the keys and the values
are using a single iterator,
so what I can do,
I can get a new type of vibrator,
which will give me both keys and values.
We just want to have cuddly here.
But I wanted to present.
So what we can do we can see
girl three dot entry set
here and
this entry set will return us.
It will return us both keys and values.
Have you tried
to put the microchip in vaccine?
So it's all over the world, right?
I you So in Pakistan, people in here,
they are not taking the vaccine.
They say that USA is paying $10,000
to have that vaccine inside you
and you will be dead in two years.
And all that.
Oh, my God.
They are all blaming that
the who was the creator of Microsoft's
make it about to be Steve
Jobs, not Steve Jobs created Bill Gates.
They are a whole thing that.
Gates, because of Bill Gates,
make it about to be in your side and time.
And we do a lot to protect you. So
this entry said, guys,
it will return me, assert
all entry.
And what does each entry contains?
It contains eggs which are all five screen
and the values are off type double
and let's call it antisec.
So if you are only interested in these,
we use the key.
So if you are only interested in values,
we use values.
If you are interested in both keys
and values combined together,
then we use the entries
from all to make perfect
those are more list
are too hard near the Microsoft store.
So now this will give me.
So for example, if I
if I use the for each loop
so map
so inside this sect we have this
map doc and pre
and each entry.
Yes. Let me explain it again.
Each entry consists of string
and let's call it
an entry.
And now I can get to both.
B So in this entry
there are two methods and three dot
get key
and and three dot get value.
So demo it.
We need a lot of practice.
So the maps internally, what they do there
don't store the key value appears
just like their work they do.
Each key value pair is wrapped inside
another object
which is called an entry,
which is called an entry.
So this is a map.
And inside the maps we have the entries
and inside those entries
we have the actual values.
We have the actual values.
So it will be a
and 4.5.
So if I want that entry,
if I want a set of all the entries,
I use the entry SEQ method
so we can use if but if should to both.
Yes If we need both keys and values,
we can get actually
the complete entry from map.
So so many entries around
the key
to get to the
OR to get only the keys values
to get the values and set to get both
keys and values.
SIMON Is it clear?
So now we are actually getting
all of these
with the help of this,
what is weird, right?
So here this map door entry
is actually a
and interface inside this map.
So we are specifying the data type
before this diamond operator.
We always specify the data, right?
So this map, not entry is it's actually
a Delta, a Delta type.
In our case, if the both of them,
they are interfaces actually let show you.
So if we have
our our this entry
and if we go inside this here
you will see this is an interface inside
this map interface
so interface inside and other interface.
Okay deep diving.
So that's why we use the map dot entry.
We need to hold the board to the keys
and the values to get well.
So we Java guys
created a data structure that can hold
a lot more to the keys and values.
Not only it's not an external, it's like
just like having a variable fight.
You remember, like I told you,
classes can have other classes,
classes can have interfaces, interface
skin class
is going to have meters,
variables, constructors.
So this is the interface.
This is interface inside
another interface.
We have not learned that
how to create an interface
inside, another interface,
but this is how we do it.
So this interface is present
inside another inside back map.
So that's why we are writing
map dot entry.
This is how we access
if something is present inside
and it is like those static
variables, right?
We write the name of the class
and then dock and then we write
the name of the variable.
So if we have a variable in an interface,
we would either be
name of the interface dot
and then the name of the variable.
So they are trade
demos, exposure.
Yes, let's now
do hash map and preset work.
Yes. Yes.
It is prevalent for all of them.
An interface inside another interface.
Yeah.
So we get the keys
and the values, even values
combined together
in a single data structure, which is
entry map
mapped or entry.
And again it is returning me asset.
So can I get an written over the set set?
Yes. So let's do that in next demo
and go.
So I what I can do I can send I data
right.
Like this
and now I have to replace
with the iterator
because now I am getting an iterator.
So from the map I get to be present
and from the entry set
I get the iterator.
And again now I have the operator again.
Same method.
While there can be no changes to my data,
while
I create not has next,
I can
s demo.
It is a little complicated
because now we are getting both keys
and values all together. So.
Okay. So now
what if I
say I printed out next life
I tweeted out next
what kind of values I will be getting,
what kind of objects I will be getting
from this?
And you scroll up for a second.
Yes, I will be getting map dot entry.
And inside of that entry, I have a string.
And Douglas.
Right.
I have strings and numbers.
And once I have an entry,
I can now write the
if conditions if
so let me if you need anything if
if the key inside the entry
if I get the key and if that key
because the keys they are staying
if that is
let's say may be equal to make
and and if entry
not get to value,
if it is equal to equal to 4.3.
So from this entry I can get
both keys and values using these methods.
Get can get value.
If this is the case,
I want to remove I want to say entry door.
So entry non.
I tried to start.
I want to remove that from my map.
So now maybe you are doing something there
for which you want to check
both the keys and the values
and then you want to take this decision.
If you want to remove that value or not.
In that case, we need to have maps
at this this entry SEQ
because it returns us both keys
and values together in a single data type,
which is map dot entry
if it's possible to do the same
remote in demo. Yes.
So you are creating an interface
and through another interface E.
S and a B.
Yes, you are right.
Okay.
And now if we print out
what is mean, you might expand it already.
I can get.
Can you expand learn more times.
So this map dot entry,
it's an interface.
The map interface.
And this data structure.
This interface.
What is the beauty of this interface?
This data structure is there
it can hold both ease
and values
together inside a single object.
So we
are interested in both keys and values.
Then we use this method of entry
and we get this map entry
by calling this entry set
on a map.
So you see now that million 4.3 is gone.
So now I am removing the elements,
maybe by checking both the keys
and values a
Are there
any questions, guys?
Too much to remember.
So these are printers.
You guys already know how to work
with apparatus maps.
They are simple.
We use port and and get right.
Same as interfaces.
The only thing that you guys
now need to focus is these entry sets
that we are getting from here here.
Let me
shift.
Thanks for breaking the brain therapy.
Okay.
So once you go to
all of these tasks, yes,
we will continue the reviews from where
we left.
Is it easy tasks?
So let me solve this task.
This first one in here.
Let me be in.
Do you guys want me solve this task?
Then I saved them online.
You delivered?
Are you getting any errors
lately?
You are so dangerous on the homeworks.
Don't give us ten tasks.
You guys have complete week
for these tasks.
Can you do one example for Alexey
about encapsulation?
Yep. Okay,
let's do the example for Aleksey.
We also have life.
We have a lot of things to do in
life as well.
It's okay.
Alexey Ideas still with us.
Like 400 girls.
Well,
what is life after joining this syntax?
Alexey, you with us?
I think Alexey has
okay maybe maybe next time.
If anyone know, if you have questions,
I will say it.
Let's do it at the end.
Talking to the ladies.
Okay.
So let's let's all big tasks
so that you guys
can remember something.
Why I see on my console,
which I have removed.
If you are
putting it in this out,
then you will see that entry
and they don't get value, don't equal so
and and they don't get valued or equals
the part.
So why are you are using equals
method for the double letter type.
You'll get them
why you are using it
if you guys want to leave.
So when the students they start new.
So I don't know.
Yes, I had classes.
So that class was supposed
to be taught on a week week day
and I thought that class on the weekend so
I got a lot of feedback from the student
why the instructor left us leave.
He could have taught us more.
And when I asked the same question,
when they were
in like the third or fourth
month, fourth month.
I teach skill also.
So then they asked,
Hey guys, do you want to leave an hour
before every of the Yes, please leave.
We will to go quickly, please
In this class. You
okay?
Let's let's do this task quickly.
And this is the last.
How do you guys like to leave?
No, no task.
But you guys want to end this session
here?
Maybe we can solve in in the
finish this one.
Okay.
You guys still have some patients
left in a 40 day?
Okay. Create a map of countries.
It's capital that will be stored.
Countries in alphabetical order.
But in all the key then values
from a country map using for each.
And I tried to bring all the values
And I tried to
listen to the hardest one.
Why are we doing
one of the easy tasks on the class?
Oh, good luck, guys. Let's do it next time
you guys are free, you
please have some freedom, has some life.
You said this class will be easy.
How easy was this?
This class was hard.
Or I told This class is easy,
but only I'm not talking
about the vibrators
or for away from easy.
Yes, I think the amount of information
is too much or the concepts are not easy.
Is there anything that confused you
or which is not clear if I
You guys have to remember a lot of things.
It starts easy and lots of entries
then did not enter
be my.
I need some valerian root
after this class.
What are they used for
to calm down.
Is it like some something like weird
heart and nerve?
We can also call me or down right?
You will be free flying in the sky.
No tensions and nothing
that I tried to have.
Why we installed the apartment?
Because I thought the class is easy
and you guys will be able to understand
it around 2 p.m.
and then we will be having one hour
to try the Excel files and all that.
That's why I made
you install deck.
We might understand if we all smoke weed.
Yes, it's also legal in Pakistan.
So actually you, Prime Minister, it says
Please, please, God, please,
please have some beers in your funds.
It's very good.
He says, Let's all of them.
Let's have it.
Yes. In Pakistan, it's legal.
You can have as much as you want.
No, I'm not getting it literally.
Prime Minister said that we can make
a lot of money if we have some.
If we have ears on our farm,
we can sell it to other countries.
So, everyone, let's find those.
Literally.
Okay, That's the end.
Do it.
No, no, no.
You have to be very
in every guy You said so
smart, Minister.
I think he was understood it.
No, no,
I don't need that if you have somewhere.
So there was a friend of mine
and he didn't tell me there was a dish
some of you might know about that
They are.
They are called.
I don't know.
What are they called.
So he put weird
inside this dish, brownness.
And he didn't tell me.
And he said, Do you want to have some?
They are very delicious. I couldn't do it.
So I eat a lot of reinventing
and everything was so
I was trying to get to my phone
and it looks like the phone is going away.
And every I was unable to touch
anything at all that I don't know.
It is recording. Yes, we are recording.