The Guardian.
Thank you, Simon,
for reminding me.
So there are no questions
regarding the contract.
So let's revise the concert.
Revise by submitting the homeworks
in the applet, but does not say received.
So once you submit your homework,
there should be a mark
that you should see with your app.
That means you have some better apples.
Can we please correct the homework
altogether?
Yes, that's what I will be doing today.
It says continue working.
That means that you have not submitted
their tongue.
So let's say, for example
or not, what is your username?
What is your email
that you used to log in to?
And it happened.
If I click on some regions
and if I check.
So you have
you have submitted the homework
on seventh of this month at 8 p.m..
Okay.
I have received it and
okay, so you just, you guys just have to
make sure that you submit your homework.
If I check B submission
or the second triplet.
So you have also submitted
the second homework at age seven.
It was just the first one.
Now you have also submitted
the second one.
This is what I am doing.
And if I click on View
that both are difficult,
but you have submitted
so submitted on 7th of October
and this is what you have submitted.
Math on February 13 was confusing.
Can you go over that one?
About 40 rappers.
I will go over these rappers on
review Glass.
Can you change the
due date for the next one?
Alright, I will change the due dates
for the national assignment or whatever,
but I submitted on Total.
Yes, definitely not.
You have received them
and they are automatically marked.
I can't hear.
Give me.
Maybe because of
the internet audio or my audio.
Speaker on your side.
I think everyone can hear me.
So let's let's let's revive
the concept that we told
you yesterday.
So what did we cover in the last
class length?
What do you guys remember?
So if I ask you, what are
the variables,
what would be your answer?
Grammatical operations.
And that I
So what?
What are variables?
I am doing that right now and nothing
moderate variables are boxes
that hold values.
Right?
This is the simplest definition. So
variables are boxes in the
computer
memory.
The old
values, right.
And what about the data types?
What are the other types?
Variables are a place
where we can assign the value
primitive and non primitive types.
Yes, the other types are primitive
and non primitive.
But by the way,
I was not able to see your note posted.
Only the slides and the video.
So guys, I posted b notes
and let me show you.
So if you guys go to batch 11,
then Java
and then class two.
So here are the notes.
Here is the code from class
and here are the slides
below
and you can check again
why you were unable to get these notes.
So data types are primitive
and non primitive.
Yes, the dead trees are primitive
and non primitive, but what is
the definition of that type?
Again, we're download this slide.
Yes, you guys can download the slides
so I see not all of you can define your
to let me define it.
So if you understand the definition
of anything, it becomes super easy
to understand the related concepts
and it also becomes easier to use back.
So the data type
is a mechanism
that defines
what type
of values
a variable
can store and
what type of operations
we can perform on that back.
Right.
So when we
when we use the string that are tied,
we know that we can only store strings
in that variable, right?
And we know that if we apply, if we use
that plus operator,
it will do the concatenation.
So who is defining all of this?
It is defined by the data type.
What kind of values you will store
in that box, in that variable,
and when you will be doing some kind of
operation, how those operations will work.
All of this is defined in the data type.
So most of us are very new in decoding
some time.
It's very hard
to catch up with the homework needs
when you give us this kind of homework,
give us some extra time
because always we are going back
to the reporting the market
and follow the homework.
Otherwise it's very hard for us.
So basically, regarding the deadline,
the homework that I will be giving you
during the class,
let's say, for example, I give you a whole
I give you some kind of homework maybe
in the yesterday's class or today's class.
So only the homework
that are given on Saturday
during the class are due on Sunday.
The homework that I will be giving to
today, you guys will be having
a complete week for the back directors
you have 14 days for.
Do that.
Okay, so don't rush far back
homework regarding output or something.
Only focus on the homework
that I am giving during the class.
Okay.
And it's only on Saturday
that you will be having one day
for all other type of homework
you guys will be having at least one week.
So don't worry about that.
And even even if you are unable
to complete those homework, it's fine
because again, in the next class,
each next class,
I will be showing you the solutions.
So last year, for some reason
you could not have time on.
Maybe you are unable to solve it,
so it's fine. Okay.
There are no marks deduction.
I will reduce the marks on quizzes,
not on the homeworks.
Okay, it's fine.
Even if you submit them late.
Yes. And
remember, guys, this is a boot camp,
right? So.
And you guys have agreed to spend
at least 10 to 15 hours a week.
Right.
But still, I will not be deducting
any marks just by your best.
Just try your best
for the first two weeks.
I will not put it up
being any marks from homework or
anything.
And those homework that I give.
Yes. No grades here.
It totally depends on how much you learn
from those homeworks.
Okay.
All right.
So the data types are those things
we can define
what kind of data we can put in a variable
and what kind of operations
are allowed on that data.
Right.
So, for example, if I
if I try to multiply those things,
can I multiply to string variables days?
No. Right.
So who who is defining this?
Who is defining this?
Not I cannot multiply
this thing that our type is defining it.
Okay.
It is defined entire back and that I can
I store numbers entire thing?
No, I cannot store who is defining
the data
type is defining this mechanism.
Or so then we discussed of
our the string concatenation
string
can all do calculations
to see of them as characters.
Yes, I'm with you.
All right. So.
So, so.
And then we discuss
about the string concatenation.
So what is shrinking?
Calculation goes
is kind of combining two things, right?
So is it necessity
that if I want to calculate that
both of the variables
that should be of types thing
or if just enough
if I have only one data type,
I have only one variable as distinct.
So using
it having string and generation
or you can from line
or or attach
a value with Spain
or so let's say
if I have a string variable variable one,
I have something in here.
Then if I have an interior,
we cannot compare compared
with other data types as well.
All right.
Yeah.
So concatenation
only happens with the strings.
And so if I have integer
number one
with ten and if I say string
Rizzo
is equal to
or one plus
number one,
then what will be the result
of this operation?
Great.
And and
and open result ten
and or ten
and then ten.
So those who are saying error.
Nice.
Why I will get better.
Why will I get an error
or one number one.
So I like to think
I will be getting larger one number one
as the result.
So those who are saying ETA it,
can you guys tell me why you think
I will be getting an added.
So let me take this call
go to Eclipse.
So let's create a new package
for today's class.
So new
package
and then gone out and
through your main method in here
because you didn't use the system,
not out, not put in
even if I don't use the system not out.
Still I will not be getting errors.
You are not allowed to add
those data type.
So Roman did it.
This is where you need to correct your
your concept.
Okay.
The strength and activation
we can do the concatenation.
We had an integer and double it.
Correct.
A boolean only one that type
only one variable should be off
string that type
the other variable it can be of any type.
Okay.
It can be a string integer
or any other thing.
So it will still work.
No, it's not an error.
If it's like water one number one,
then it will be added. Yes.
So not nice saying that
if we try to do minus
instead of plus,
then we will be getting an added.
Okay.
Then we will we get the name.
All right.
So not now.
I have written a complete
kind of piece of code, so can you guys now
tell me the output,
the line
that I will see on my console And here
some of you are
saying that I will be getting lot of one.
Number one as the output.
So let me execute.
So I see. Hello ten.
Why I am getting this output
because it is happening
because of string concatenation.
String concatenation.
And what I can do, let's say for example,
if I have a
boolean, right, if I have a boolean
is true, is equal to
true, can I also concatenate this is true
with this result variable.
This result variable. And I do that.
So if I say a so
Alex is saying no, Roman is saying no,
no, I saying yes
and you're saying
yes, yes, yes.
So those who are saying, you know guys
why are you think that
I can not concatenate a boolean value
with a B with a string,
while I cannot do that,
you guys mean that
I will be getting some kind of error.
We can write only one that I type
needs.
It will be a string.
The other data type.
It can be anything, right?
It can be anything.
I can combine, I can I can concatenate,
I can attach a boolean
with a string as that.
Okay.
So I can also do this.
I can also put output.
I will always
be getting the first and then hello.
Word back. Okay.
I can do that.
So now let me let me rewrite it.
And you know,
because a lot of you are confusing
with who
or phone
technician, only one
variable needs to be a
thing.
The other variable
can be of any and
size like
Boolean.
And these are
strings.
It can be a finite type.
All right.
So after concatenation,
we discussed about the
what it would discuss about after this
something congratulation guys.
We discussed about some kind of operators.
What kind of operators we discussed
and automatic operators
right.
And in from those other
automatic operators that we discussed
about the plus sign
minus sign multiplication
sign, the dividend sign and more best sign
right.
We use plus
to perform
our nation, our
in continuation, right?
We use minus bool or fault.
So action.
We use this sign for
our multiplication
and we use this forward slash
for division.
And lastly, we discuss about the
modulus operator tool
there to be.
We mean that right?
Okay.
So let's
I saw some of you are confused about
the division and the modulus operator.
So let me go through those again.
So let's say
I have in number number one is equal to
and I have okay, I have to find one
why I am getting an error based on this
number one
already defined, right?
So I have defined this number one in here
already.
Okay.
So I need to change it in here.
So number two, and then I have
three is for three.
If I do
number two by
number three, what answer I advise,
I am dividing number two with number three
one, three,
two, one,
one three and
since it's integer we get three. So
and then we have the target three as well.
So let's try to solve this.
So I am trying to divide ten by three.
Right?
So three threes are nine,
one is the remainder.
Right.
I put a zero in here. It
put a
decimal in here, I put a zero in here,
I said three, these are nine.
Then again is determined
and I keep on doing so.
I will be getting this as the answer.
Three Part three
What is the type of the number of days
integer again Integer.
Hold 31333.
So if I try to store 3.33
inside of the integer,
what what
value will be stored in the integer?
Or I will be getting an error.
So I will only be getting this three
as the answer.
And this part it will be.
You can know why Because my dad types,
they are integers and they are
indeed. Yes.
So I get three as the answer.
Yeah.
So those who are saying
one as the answer, I guess.
I think you guys were confused
about the modulus.
I'll put it up in here.
Well what will be the answer
of this module?
Modulus operation guys.
So here I will be getting one right,
because one is the remainder.
All right, We have two as well.
And delete
those saying two, remainder one.
So Angela and Anita,
we will not be getting two as the answer.
We will be getting one as the answer.
Why one as the answer?
Because in here.
So when we do the mathematical division
or the remainder with integer variables,
this part is
is the result of this operation.
Okay.
And this, this thing in here
is the result of this modulus.
Operator.
Okay, so
let me let me change it to 14.
So guys, tell me what answer
I'm going to get for Division,
what answer I will get for Modulus
or and two.
Right?
So now I have this, I have 14.
I said three, four.
Well,
all is determined.
Remember, we go in here
and the answer will go in here.
Here.
So I get four.
And what if, guys,
what if I change?
What if change it to four
and this one to find out
if I changed it to a double?
What you get now for these two statements?
Are you guys sure
they will still get the same answer?
Because I didn't
change the variables, right?
I didn't change the variable.
So let me first
I need to change the variables
right
either.
Right.
Same answer.
So now, now tell me the answer
so fast.
Answer 4.66.
What about the second one
part of this line
or 2.6 and 2.0?
So I see 4.6 and 2.0.
Okay.
All right.
Because double values,
they can hold the decimal numbers.
Okay.
But this this modulus operation,
it has nothing to do with the data type.
It's it will give
you almost the same reasons
why I am saying almost same
because in here you are getting two.
In here you are getting 2.0.
Okay,
so the only difference is off the decimal.
And then this table
all. So then
we discussed about the
and operate this operation.
What, what kind of shorthand operators
we learned guys,
can we explain the last one, please.
Yes, sure. Question
You mean this one,
the output of this line, I think you mean.
Yes, this line.
So in here.
So number four contains 14,
Number five contains three.
So three, four are well
and two is the remainder.
Okay.
But in here, because we are using double
values, this tool is actually kind
of converted to 2.0 automatically.
That's why we do this on set in here.
But this part
God does not consider this remainder.
Okay, So I will do for this part.
This is what the Java will say.
14 three So three fours are
right
with the remainder
decimal place zero in here.
These things are being
done at the end.
To the end of the end,
it will keep on going.
So you guys know about the unending
sequences in math.
So some operations,
some division operations,
they they have the never ending
decimal place part, right?
They just keep on going so much because
computers, they are limited in memory.
So computers will try and be the best
to support the results.
But once they see that they cannot fit
the mold decimal numbers in their memory,
they will just terminated
and they will just round off it.
Okay.
After a certain number of decimal places.
So that's why we are seeing this six,
seven, etc.
we will learn about this decimal places
and all of this stuff
as well.
Is it clear now?
All right.
So we learned about many different
shorthand operators.
We started with plus plus,
then minus minus
than plus equal to
minus equal to multiply two
you already thought and modulus.
Yeah.
I love this math class.
Math is very closely
related to programing.
By the way.
All right, so what does this
plus plus operator do if I have,
let's say, a variable
in the var line
and if I have the handwriting error,
if I say law one plus plus,
what will be the result
of this calculation?
So it will increment the value by one.
So whatever
we are supporting in that variable,
that value will be implemented by one.
Say if I have indeed
var one is equal to hundreds
and if I say right, one
plus plus
and so I have to do r one already.
So let's say
number six. So
and then if I try to print out
this number six,
so I am using
plus plus shorthand operator in here.
So this value, whatever value
I am storing in this number,
since it will be incremented by one.
So the answer will be
101. What?
What if I put negative number two guys?
Will I get two negative
one zero one or positive
101 or 99 or
or -99.
Okay.
A lot of you add this nice.
If I add one,
if I add one two minus heading back,
what will be the answer?
An integer be negative.
Yes, I'm on integers going to be negative.
So now I see some
correct answers looking
so negative
if I add one, two -100 will be -99.
Not positive, 99 or not
101, but not convert out like that.
Yes. It's just simple math.
Yeah.
All right. So
I mean -99.
So but then why now?
And then they will be asking questions
in your interview.
Give them the wrong answer and then say,
oh, no, this is not what I meant.
I mean, something as finite.
So and then we learned about B
minus, minus operator. Right.
So if I say number
six, minus minus
four to answer, I will write
this out
on the statement
minus under
minus one zero on.
So guys, remember I am first adding one.
So this minus under,
then I am subtracting one.
So if I add and subtract
same amount from a number,
what answer I will get,
I will get the same number again.
Right.
But again.
So it will be
-100 again.
Right.
I added one to that value,
then I subtracted one.
So I get back to same number.
Correct.
So guys, can I do can I do this
number multiply and multiply?
Can I do this
work?
Multiply, multiply.
Right.
And that's why it is not allowed,
why it is not allowed in Java.
Can you guys
tell me why it is not allowed?
Any logic you can think of?
It's not defined.
So the two things that are not defined,
they are also not defined for a reason.
Here we go.
So Alanna.
Yes, you are perfectly right.
That is, if I multiply something with one
what answer
I will get
multiplication
by one does not change anything.
Right?
It is the same number again,
so it does not make sense to have that
number multiply. Multiply it right.
Same reason for the division.
If I divide something by one there
there will not be any difference.
Right.
So I will be getting the same answer.
So the next slide,
Java guys, is going to define
these two operations.
So in Java, if something is not defined
or if something is not allowed,
there can be multiple reasons for that.
Some reasons are because some
things are not possible in programing,
some other things are they
may they may not make sense.
The other things are coming from history
and things like that.
So I will be telling you
the reasons as well.
If something is defined,
it will help you memorize.
Remember that thing for the longer
period of time
are not allowed
because it does not
change anything
right.
It's very logical.
Of course,
programing is very, very logical.
And then we discuss the other shorthand
operators,
other shorthand operators
and the first operators that we discussed.
So let me say, I realize if I do
remember
so the results
are the same for the table as well.
Okay.
I just wanted to show you
so that you guys don't
confuse about this.
So if we have doubles
and if we do, if we do number four
plus plus,
actually let me put it outside of that,
because there is something more
that I want to show you.
Actually, this
I saw it in the review class,
but we can also put
this plus plus
before the variable.
Okay.
And there is a difference
in putting the number first
and then putting this plus before
and after the video.
But okay.
So and if you guys
some of you if you have tried this,
if you put this plus plus,
what would answer
I will get right.
So let me surprise you.
I got ten. Okay.
And I want you to
hold next Saturday,
next and next Thursday.
And then I will explain why you
if you put this inside the print balance,
why you got a ten,
and if you put it outside
the outside of the standard out,
why you get 11.
Okay.
So inside system, again, if if we do,
we get ten outside or we get 11.
Okay.
I will explain the reason in the test.
This class have to come on first.
Okay.
I know.
So it has something
to do with putting this plus plus before
and after this number
so we we can do this
plus plus with the would be
with the doubles as well.
Okay. We could double data
inside your team.
I think this thing.
No, this is not the reason
actually,
I don't want to confuse you, but hold on.
I will explain in greater detail
so you can do plus plus before or not.
Yes, you can do the plus,
but before as that.
Okay.
Like this.
Okay. You can do this as well.
Plus.
Plus means anything inside the bracket.
No, not for what it means.
It means so many things
inside the brackets as well.
Okay.
But what I would explain,
though, we need to add a bracket in here.
Print with print. Hello?
Yes, we need them
if you remove you will be getting an added
no additional.
Yes, you can you can put additional
like this if you want.
But but it doesn't make sense
to put additional brackets
for plus plus in here like this.
Like this. Yes, you can do that
if we can do that.
So if you pull the brackets
and then if you print out p value.
Okay.
So still
you will be getting then
let me remove the brackets.
No. So that must be
you guys can always try different
different things.
We both have the individual
and try to figure it out.
If I put these brackets first,
if I put this plus plus
before then you will be getting 11.
Okay.
11 is the answer.
So you see 11 if you put this plus, plus
this, plus, plus, after the number,
you would be getting ten as the answer.
Yeah.
And if you put this
plus plus before or after,
if you are outside of the println
statement, then it does not matter.
You will always be getting
11 as the answer.
Okay. So 11
and then
11. Okay.
So try to make sense out of it.
Still, I will be getting 11. Okay.
Because inside the bracket
has got to go up plus plus means moving
next up and like this number
plus plus means added value and value.
The number
really?
Well, yes. Wait, what did I miss?
What statistic?
So, guys,
Java is actually something very big.
People have yesterday is in Java.
Okay.
So but we will be learning around
only 0.5% of it during this course.
Okay. So it's huge. Huge.
So number seven, one.
So I was saying
in that
the other shorthand operators
that we large were
the number seven
started eight
and let's see.
Yes, guys tried to Google
it, tried to Google it.
If you know how to use Google,
believe me, your job will be super, super
easy for you in CEUs in computer science,
if you know how to use Google,
your life is easy.
So the other short shorthand operators
that that we learned
were plus equal to operator right.
So number
eight
and then plus equal to
percent.
And if I try,
let me tell you the terminologies
as they are called also to increment
operator and pre increment operators,
if you guys want to use Google,
they are called pre increment
and post increment operators.
So now whatever value is stored
inside this box,
it will be incremented by ten.
Okay.
So I have 20 stored in here.
Quantity plus ten is equal to Typekit.
So I see it kind of thing
and if I do, if I do
minus ten.
So number eight, minus ten.
But answer I will get to
on two divided by zero
I will get
ten. Right.
And if I do 40 guys,
if I do 40 number
eight minus equal to 40, what?
Answer I will get them.
So this was my original value 20.
Then I am adding ten
to this content which makes it 30.
Then I am subtracting -40
from 30.
So I get minus ten,
I get minus ten.
All right.
And Pride is able to follow me
or you are going to stop here
and maybe you are typing some code.
Can we move on?
So I'm one.
What do you mean by ML one?
No, not me.
Today's lesson.
So no, I will not.
And we will not be following this
always in all the classes
First, all of the instructors.
They will be revising what
they have covered in the previous class
and then they will be moving forward.
So if, like you see before any season or,
or something like that, they show you.
Previously on Syntax was Previously
on Syntax.
So previously on
Friends.
So here is the Previously on Syntax
reading.
Yes, it's very important in programing.
You you guys will realize this with time.
How important is this region?
Please tell me when we need
light white, electric, white.
What do you mean by white?
Right. Okay,
so if you want, you can follow me.
If you want, you can follow me right now.
So then we discussed about.
So let me make the calculations easy party
and let me store
Andre in here
and let's make it for.
So I have us I have reassigned hundred.
Can you repeat the last part
if you don't mind?
So know which line,
which line you want me to repeat.
41 to 4341.
So this is 41 and this is 43.
So in here we are doing
whatever value is stored in this number
eight.
We are subtracting 40 out of that.
That's it.
So previously we had 20,
then we added ten subtotal last 30
and then we are subtracting -40 from 30.
Okay, Is it clear now?
So guys, some of you
you might be good at programing.
So what you can do
if you think that the repetition,
this recap is unnecessary,
maybe you can you can join the class late.
So first one are most of the time
plus one out
I will be spending on on TV again.
So you guys
maybe can do something else in that time.
All right.
And then we can do the same.
Or we can do the same
with division.
So if I have 400
and if I say number plus equal to four,
I will be
getting hundreds.
And then same with be
modulus.
So let's say if I have ten
and if I say it, then modulus four
what?
Answer I will get guys
who right, right, get to it.
So this was our previous class.
Now You guys can ask me if let's,
if still something
is not clear about the
about the concepts that we discussed.
You can ask me any questions from that
or is it all
clear?
All clear. All clear.
Mean nothing and nothing entered in
your brain are all clear.
Mean.
All concepts are clear.
So do you help us with that homework? Yes.
So now we will solve the homeworks.
Okay.
So far only tricky.
Plus plus the entire println.
Actually, it's a complete science.
That plus plus
think it's a complete science.
I will explain that in the review class.
So don't worry about that plus plus ten
the let's all the homeworks.
Okay so let's call it
so I am creating a new class
inside class three package
and let's call it task one.
So let me take online now.
Is it okay if I close this other window?
Maybe some of you are typing.
You mentioned that many people did it
differently and wanted to talk about.
Yes, I will.
We're going to talk about
you today.
Closed this other file
or you guys maybe are typing from it.
So here is one three people guys,
before you solve your programing
homeworks,
don't directly, try to call it.
Okay don't directly try to quoted
when you read the requirement first
try to solve that on a paper
on on a on a on a paper
with pencil without directly
coding and just try to make
steps
that how would you solve this problem
without programing manually video
copy intervention.
It will help you a lot.
Define those steps.
Once you have those steps,
then try to board against those steps.
It will help you a lot.
By the way,
it's a proper technique in programing
and it's called pseudo programing.
Okay, so maybe you guys want to Google it,
so try to write pseudo codes first,
then try to then then write actually code.
So if I solve this problem, right,
if I solve
this problem manually without
without writing the code directly,
what I will do, I will first divide
this problem into smaller steps.
So I have to write a program.
So if I, if I just read this part,
it means that
I have to create a new class.
That class should have
the main method, right?
And this should be my first step.
Then I have to do addition,
subtraction, multiplication
and or division
with the two decimal values.
Okay,
so I have to perform these four operations
and I have to do these operations
with decimal numbers.
Okay.
And then the third step can be my my program should say if should operate the bar,
then the
result
of two numbers,
the first number, the second number,
and then it should say is equal to
and then if should print the results
about this task.
What we need to learn scanner
all we can do with out and it's so nice.
If I have no part you about something
then yes, you guys are not supposed
to use that in your homework.
Okay.
So then you guys will learn about this
kind of class.
I guess it's in the next class then. Yes,
you can use this kind of
in your programs.
By the way,
those who don't know about Scandal, it's
a piece of code that can help
you take the input dynamically
from your keyboard.
Okay.
So right now we are hard
coding everything in our programs, right?
Hard coding the values and variables
using the scanner.
You guys will be able to take
the input from your keyboard.
Yes, one thing at
a time. Day.
Yes. Let me check
if we are missing something.
Correct.
Everything looks good. So
first I need two variables, right?
First, I need to enable.
So let me define so variables.
Number one, and maybe let's say next
or ten in
two and store again and inside.
Okay.
And now to all the results
of these calculations,
let's define more creative.
Okay. So I have to do addition.
So I will have a variable double
B, some.
And in here I will say number one.
Number two
or yes, number.
That should be that.
You must point.
Is it good?
Now we'll start.
So I have declared a variable
that contains the result of
of some now why not float.
So in
this float
number today actually
you guys will learn about it
first has less capacity than double
second every time you use floor float
you have to put that at the end.
Okay, So that's why, as I have explained
previously, that these days, the memory,
it does not matter that much.
So you can always use the tables in here
today I will show you
the limitation of floor data type.
Okay, so this double for decimal numbers
always use double
for into type of numbers.
Always use in not short,
not long, not byte and things like that.
Like they are the most commonly used
data types.
Then double maybe subtraction
and multiplication.
Why I'm getting an error on online
and in nice
there are no variables.
Add number
and that I have defined in my program.
So I am.
I will be getting an error
if I have not defined something and if
I try to use that.
All right.
So now I have to produce this output.
So to produce this output, which concept
I will use right?
Things can get in nature, right?
Combining
multiple output from multiple variables.
So with the help of string
kind of stagnation,
I need to say duh.
So I will use double quotes.
Then I will say
our nation of
two numbers.
Okay, so the addition of two numbers
then if space in here,
then I will say
number one
again plus
okay.
Plus then and
again. Space
again plus
then number two
again.
Double force is
equal to space
plus.
And the variable that contain
it is what is error?
Where is the error
word system or word system?
Oh, you guys mean this?
It should be system out.
It's there are
multiple classes in this in the system
interface. Okay.
So that's why you guys are
not what you want that.
So is it clear right.
How I have built the output.
So if I execute this
not subtraction,
it should be something.
It should be some.
So now I can simply copy this
and I can replicate it.
All the other tasks
I lost my sound far field.
I don't know if you answered my question
or not.
Last word summary
Going this way is correct.
Yes, you'll get to it is also correct.
I have just declared additional variables
to make this program a little simpler.
My question was it worked for me
without line
16 to 19, do we need to have those lines?
No, they they are just extra steps
to make the program
a little easier to understand.
Then that's it.
If you guys have used those brackets
and then if you have done the plus
and minus perfectly fine, it's
perfectly fine.
So now I will say the
fraction
is so
the other duplication
and then give.
And then when I tried to print this
different way is same result I am good at
it is not picky.
Let's not talk about it at all
now because it's this start right now.
It will be 0:00 in the future,
so don't worry about that.
But I hope you guys we've got great
how to how to fix those issues
rapidly and all that brilliant.
Not that smart.
You can easily fool.
Let's give
I think, only two problems
in the complete exercises.
There are only two problems
that might take some time.
Otherwise.
Are there any questions that I
explore?
Super easy right?
Is there anyone who was unable to solve
them?
Let's solve the task. Two
Well, I am.
My number console is all together.
Really.
Please share the screenshot
and posted in this sports channel.
It looks messy
and your looks may need
you shared a screenshot
so that I know.
So let's create task. So
are you guys following me? Yes.
Follow me.
Okay.
So Lenny, I hope I'm
pronouncing your name correctly.
So make sure that you have these spaces,
okay?
Make sure you have the spaces
before the before
the before you end of the court.
Okay.
This one that they will make your output
look better.
Okay, I am closing this this file.
Right.
So should I close it?
Why the error?
Guys, if you are facing any errors,
please post and export channel
so you are not using this plus sign.
Now you are not using this plus sign.
So when you are putting a string
and a variable
inside the system out, you need this
plus sign.
Otherwise, how?
How do I know
if you are trying to get in it or what?
What you are trying to do?
You use that plus, are there
is there anyone who's getting any errors
or issues,
even though output is correct?
A repeat test is showing failed.
What should we do
so the way some make it anyway? No.
Okay, so guys,
let's see.
Let me actually this is important. So
so let's take the example of this.
This first.
So let's say for somebody
then you have written record.
I am not writing
any piece of code in here.
Okay?
And you try to run your best.
Okay.
So your test will fail, right?
Because it is not getting
what it is expecting.
But the how how can you check
what is double
what, what is expecting
and what is your output.
So if you click this result
so rapidly,
it will show that to say that, hey then
you know what?
From this wrapper,
I was expecting it through
and it false
as the output from the program.
But the actual output
that your program is generating,
it's empty.
It's empty.
Okay.
So you know that you are missing
something now.
Now let me
So let's
say I write something in here, okay?
I write something.
I run log.
I click on Run test again.
Okay.
Still, the test case is filled and
if I click on Desert again, so this time
my results are partially correct.
Okay.
So it will again
tell me that it will say that task
that I was expecting it true.
And if I was.
But you are your program is only printing
true and you are missing a false
so the variable
it will try to help you as much as it can.
Okay.
So therefore it is now telling you
it is saying that pass that
if you put this false in here as well,
your your test case will pass.
Okay.
So I will again go
I will check if I am missing
in my program.
I may put
a false as that.
Okay.
And now if I click on Run test, this time
the test is passed.
Okay.
And if I click on reserves,
this is what I was expecting.
This is what my program generated.
And so now all good.
So that's when you are
when you are facing any issues, always.
If the test case is not passing,
always post
the screenshot of this results
window. Okay.
So I know what you are missing
and I can help you back.
I like that I am self solving.
It helps me in developing attention
to details.
Yes, I have Arab in homework in public.
I get wrong answer, but the result is fail
and you check one of them and explain
thank you
Alex,
which rapidly you are talking about.
Well, 13 and 14. Okay.
So if if we are left some time,
remind me at the end of this class,
if we are left with some time,
then I will show
you would be solution funded
appeals.
All right.
So I am closing this this class days.
I am closing.
So the second task.
All right, so the second task was write
a program to find this.
The error of number 3.9.
Okay.
So base, how do we calculate
the square of a number
in the simplest way?
How can we calculate
the square of a number
multiplied the number with itself?
Right.
Multiply the number by itself.
So let's first can declare a variable
to hold this number double
the number 3.9.
Oops.
Not like that is equal to 3.9.
All right.
And then so let me use this time,
let let's not declare a variable.
Okay.
And let's try to use
the results directly in the system.
So the program says
the output should
be split the square of the
double force,
the sphere of the
and then plus sign
number
again, plus sign.
That is a space is.
And this time I am using brackets
because I don't want
the can get nation to happen 40
these are okay
so I will the number
multiplied by
so the square of 3.9 is 5.9999.
Okay.
All right.
So are there any questions
from this place, from this task?
Pretty simple, right?
I put it so in one more thing.
Nice for each task,
try to create a new file
that looks nice and create enough.
So right click
and then task could be
this method is right?
Yes, that method is also right.
Katrina.
That method is also right.
No special operator
grading to the power of then not.
There are operators.
I mean there are complete classes,
complete methods
to calculate
sine waves and romantic romantic values,
imaginary numbers.
Everything is available in Java, but
I will show it in a later point of time.
Okay, all is available.
Don't worry.
But right now I am only trying to use
those concepts that I have showed you.
Okay, so I will avoid all other concepts
even if they are
better.
Let's solve the next task.
Should I close this task?
Have you guys type this?
Let's focus on our homework first
and then just do the next thing.
Yes. Okay.
I am closing this one.
Java is easy.
If we go step by step, believe me,
if we go step by step,
if we know a little bit
about how to use Google programing,
Java and this computer science job,
it does not have any match.
Let me tell you the benefits of
a lot
of the stories from previous batches.
Right now, believe me,
they are doing their job from beaches
and they are enjoying because most them,
they are working remotely.
They just need a laptop and an internet
connection and they are on vacation.
Some of them, believe me, they were here
in United states for five years.
They never trusted their families
because they did the jobs last
the day they were not having vacations
or something like that.
So some of them, they have visited
families after five years
and they are doing their job.
A lot of work
from Afghanistan and back here.
So they visited their families.
Now often they go
and at some of the companies
they will be like
especially like one month or two months
paid holidays are there.
I have not seen my family in six years.
They did those two schools.
They were very, very happy.
Once they got a job,
the next thing they did, they
they just went back to their families
or I am getting at of.
So, Maryam,
you have not defined this number variable.
The names are okay.
No you have that number variable,
but actually it is
the spelling mistake is number mark,
the variable that you have defined
and you are trying to use a number
I use spelling mistake.
All right.
So I have to write a program to play
the area and the parameter.
Okay, So here comes to Google.
So now I have something like, say,
I may maybe I don't know
how to calculate the parameter. Okay.
How to calculate the area. Okay.
So what I will do either
I can always use Google, right?
So I will say
you and then I see the formula, right?
They formalize.
I have to add length with with
and then I have to multiply it by two.
Okay. So,
so we can cheat the whole time
is not actually cheating in on your jobs.
Even during your interviews.
You can use Google
computer precise.
They they don't respect you.
You can always use Google.
You just know
you should know how to use your tools.
That's it.
That's what the job requires from you.
So now I know.
Okay, so let me Google the oops
the area as this area of
well,
sorry, not the triangle rectangle,
but with multiplied by length.
So now let's try to solve this problem.
So I am programed to put into
the area and the parameter
all rectangle
with with five and height.
Okay.
So should I declare the integer type
of variable guys
or should I declare the full double value
byte?
Alexi, don't use bytes.
Okay, so guys, tell me in a
can a double variable hold B integer
values as well?
But again, an integer
hold the double values.
So which one is better to always use?
Always, Always go with the doubles.
Okay,
so yes,
we can solve this with the integers.
Like doubles are better.
Double with it
equal to five
number.
I is equal to eight
and then double
and later.
So if you formula is two
is implied by
the plus
and then double it
with multiplied by height.
And now I can say
so I can copy this
double course
space then
it works.
Good.
Is it correct
if you use N in this exercise?
Yes. Yes. It's also correct.
But double is better
then you also show how to do it
in system or out line as well.
Yes, sure, I will tell you.
So if I used is it not correct?
No, but know it's also correct.
But the doubles are better.
So I see my output in here.
Let me try to do without variables.
So without variables, you're able to
this step
and do
its start.
Okay, so I get the same answer now,
but a double will take mostly
for our decimal value, right?
Yes, we are three.
We should be taking the double
for decimal values,
but the numbers as they can
hold the integers as well.
So it's always better to use double so 30.
Even if your calculations
are giving you a result
that can be a double,
you still don't get any errors.
Okay, so it's always better.
So let's say, for example,
you have to perform
the division in this case.
So although the numbers on
which I am trying to perform division,
although they are integers,
but what type of result
I will get precisely
if I try to divide five by eight,
will it be an integer
or a double?
It will be a double, right?
I will be getting on starting point.
So that's
why using doubles is always better.
All right.
So do you guys want me to go through
the rest of the tasks
or you guys want to break
or no
break and we more, please.
Okay.
So we see a message from Damini as well.
From there.
Just one task left to go on.
Okay, let's do that task as we
let me check.
How many tasks are there?
Actually, there are 3 to 4 tasks.
It's not only one task.
So let's do that.
I people do it
around 1140.
So please be back by 12
and remind me
about everybody.
How's everybody doing today?
I can take a break first.
All right. I hope you guys are back.
Will be a gem.
Of course I like it.
Yes, that is
is next
on the next task.
Can you please go to previous window
for a minute?
Yes, sure.
Scared I was.
Who is talking from my computer? Yes.
We are recording.
Okay.
So the next task
was to declare aviary.
It will and increase by hand Bird
using shorthand operator.
Yeah.
So these are number.
And here
and now let's use the shorthand operator
to increase it by our.
If I put into the value, I will see 101
So this is be sharpened.
Operator
All you make screen bigger and smaller.
So Hasim on Windows
hold down your control button
and then press the plus sign
to increase the font
and minus sign or decrease the font.
Or guys try to use Google right in
in the Google
How to increase the font size in Eclipse.
I want you to start practicing that.
It says increase by 100.
Okay. Okay.
Then we have to do this
declare variable and increase by 200
using the shorthand operator.
Is it good now?
Are we good now number plus equal to
and then it says
declare variable and decrease by 67
or ten
and remember to
under
two minus
quarter to 60.
I see practically
next task last
declared variable
increase is equal to 11.
So integer
excuse me quarter to 11
and divide
peace between
for people using shorthand operator.
Each person
should get an equal piece of cake.
I really like your teaching method.
Thank you. Right from the three now.
So guys, I have to divide something.
Should I use the modulus operator
or the division operator?
So I saw I saw in your homework.
Some of you use the
modulus operator
and some of you use the division operator.
So the task simplifies divide, right?
Divide means divide, for example. So
and when it says divide equally,
I know that I should not be using
the double data type.
Right. Right.
If I use the double letter
type can I divided equally
so so those who are saying double
if we if we use double,
then this is what will happen.
Now I will get
decimal points in my answers.
Okay.
But we have to divide complete pieces.
Okay. Complete pieces.
So if I say get
divide by four.
So yes, it is still a division,
but now I will be getting those
in decimal point.
Okay. And I have 11 pieces.
Okay.
I don't have 1.5 pieces.
12.3 pieces. 12.2.
So I have to divide the complete piece
between four people.
So if I use double,
I will be getting the answer in point.
Okay.
But I don't have 175 piece either.
How you have one piece or no piece.
So for that reason we should
after type, I should use case
the integer one, right?
So when we use the integer one, yes,
some of the pieces will be left over, but
the pieces that will be divided
between four people,
they will be complete pieces
naught half or two or 2.5 or 3.5.
Okay.
So that's why
we should use the inferior data type,
and that's why we should use
the division operator, not the modulus.
Optical modulus of the operator will
tell me how much pieces are left behind.
So let's if I want to know that,
okay, two pieces per person are divided.
And if I want to know how many pieces
are left behind, then I will use.
The modulus Operator
So modulus operator will tell me
how many pieces
are still there.
So two pieces for each person.
And then I have I am left with three.
So that was your
number three.
Is it clear? Right.
Why I am using that type, Why
I am using double.
So the last task.
So last task save
declared variable key piece.
So first step I declare this variable.
Okay.
And divide peace between seven people.
This time again I will use integer
because I want to divide equally.
I got 2.75.
Oh. Okay.
So we have two.
So could we use four triangle?
Yes. So let's try to use this
shorthand operator.
So it is
divide
by four.
Then I will see.
Okay, so there we commit this out
and if I putting this out
and are okay, so
let me make it take this one.
Okay.
For the next task.
So I get the answer to using the shorthand
operator.
Are you using double A
to hold your variable?
Yes. You are using double, right?
That's why you are important.
All right.
So let's start with last task as well.
So then I start with the player
variable take.
So I am using this one because
I already have declared this in here.
Or maybe I can be assigned the
value of looking like this
and divide
peace between seven people
using shorthand operator
and find out
how many pieces of cake left
after it was distributed
equally among seven people.
Okay,
so if I say
so, first
I have to use the shorthand operator.
Okay, so I will see it piece
and then median
time to find and I have divided this time
between seven.
I put this out.
So if I want to divide 25
in seven people equally,
so each one will get three,
get three pieces.
And then I want to check that
how many eggs
are left behind?
Right.
How many pieces are there
after I have done the division.
So what I can say.
So one thing you guys can do is that you
can reassign bigger and you can take five
in here and you can say
a these and then modulus
by seven.
Okay, So then you will know
how many pieces are left over?
Like four.
I think there is there
is this ambiguity in question
so instead of
using the shorthand
operators.
Okay so this is let me update this.
So let me remove this
shorthand operator from here
and then we can use
to find out
how many pieces of get left over after.
Okay.
And let me move this short
turn of waterfront it
so that it does not confuse you.
You guys can also point out
if something is given,
even if it is a little confusing for you.
Okay, I will update those stuff.
I can do this task are not created by me.
They are created by someone else.
But it's fine. I can do it now.
We need percentage to get remaining.
Yes, because the question asked
only five remaining. Yes.
Sorry. You are right.
If also possible with the short one.
But it will it.
Some of you might find it a little harder.
So let's just make it easier
so that it does not confuse you.
So it says faster.
It says divide between seven people
and then it says
how much is left after division.
So that's why the division
and the modulus, both of them.
Is it clear days.
So these are our tasks
and now we are ready
to start the last number.
So on next, next what is in class
three by?
Show me three. It will be four.
I got three.
All right.
So guys,
you are making a very same simple mistake.
What happens with the shorthand operator
is that it actually update it actually
objective value of original variable
so because you guys
so you guys are making this mistake.
If I remove this assignment,
a piece is equal to 20
this, this shorthand operator
it is actually updating this eight piece
original value.
Okay.
So you guys, you guys are not reassigning.
So now if I if I go to school,
I will get a different answer.
I will get a three and the three.
Well, so why I'm getting this three.
So seven threes are 21, right?
And I am left with four.
Okay.
And 47.
So you're
left me actually do this.
So when we are saying 725
divided by seven, so we are doing this,
we are taking the value 25
Let me actually try it.
So we have this 25
so seven
threes are 21 right?
So we are left with four.
All right.
So in here
let me actually draw,
put a line so that we can visually
differentiate because we are going to be
as much.
So these are the results of task one,
these are our duties are solved.
Task.
So once we are done with this calculation,
so initially there was 25
in this case piece.
I use different variable
name to close this job,
but I gave new variable piece one.
Okay, so a 25
and then I am performing this operation
with the shorthand operator. Okay.
On the shorthand operator,
this is actually what is going on.
So the shorthand operator,
it is something like this
piece is equal to two divided by seven.
Okay.
So this is what it is actually doing.
So dividing the eight piece by seven,
then splitting the results
back to this variable.
Okay.
So if we put into our T value
after this operation, we get three Okay,
so this three that
this trade
that you guys are seeing in here,
this actually gets stored
in the original variable
and then after offered this line
on this line
47, you are actually doing this
three modulus
seven So we learn yesterday
that if we try to take them
on less of a shorter number,
we the bigger number,
the answer will always be shorter
innocuously.
So this three is coming from here.
Okay.
Is it clear
those who are getting the answer three.
So you guys can maybe
use a different variable name
or maybe you can just find a value
question asks for only how many left
I think and only to calculate
division is enough.
So Aisha because chances divide
the is between seven people.
Okay so the question also says divide
this piece
between seven people
using shorthand operator.
Okay.
And then find out how many pieces of it
are left over
if it was distributed equally.
So it's fine if you have only only
calculated how many pieces are left.
It is also fine
if you have calculated both.
Okay,
I just changed the variable and it works.
It was taking the value after the. Yes.
All right, so let's move forward.
Nice.
So today we will discuss about
the side being part means
how many pieces left
of the original name. Yes.
So today's class is about typecast
if statements and if else statements.
So first, let's try to understand
what is costing.
So you guys must have noticed that
we cannot place the values
of sometimes
we cannot place the values of one vector
type into an other type of variable.
For example,
if we try to place a double value,
if we try to place a double value
inside an integer
type of variable,
what happens if I try to do this?
I have a double value with decimal point
and I am trying to store it
inside an integer.
Can I do that?
I will get an error.
So this is what I am talking about.
And there actually I have integer number
ten and and bradburn
number who.
So I can I can I can do this
if I say number two is equal to number,
I can do that.
I don't get any errors.
And even if I
point this out, I don't get any errors.
And actually actually let me do this,
remove this.
So I have a variable which is of typing.
I have another box and another variable
which is
of type double.
Okay. Yes, I am
redefining not I am not redefining it.
I am reassigning it.
So this part is called definition
defining a variable.
This part is called
assigning a value to the table.
Read.
Defining is actually not possible in Java.
So if I tried to do this, if I say
double number, this is what will say that
I am trying to redefine something
so this is not allowed in Java.
You really get that. If
I am reassigning
or assigning
this number is is actually a smaller box.
It's actually a smaller box.
This double is actually a bigger box.
So right now I am picking the contents
of smaller box and place.
I am trying to place them in a bigger box.
So in our in real life,
if I try to do this, is there any harm
or is there any problem that I get
if I try to place
the contents of a smaller box in a bigger
I don't have any issues doing that.
What if I try to do the reverse guys?
If I try to do the reverse,
if I have a double,
if I have a double unit,
if I try to place
now the bigger content in do something
now, I will have issues.
So let's say,
let's say I have this box.
Okay?
And next to this is Sebastian.
Sebastian no means today.
Okay,
so this is the double
double box
and this one
is an integer box.
Sebastian, I hope you don't mind.
They will be coming down to it,
not working.
So now if I try.
If I try to feed Sebastian in here,
it may happen that we may only.
Only see the body of Sebastian in here.
Right.
Maybe they do out
right.
So I am losing something.
Okay, so in here
I have lost of information.
So that's why I get this data.
Okay?
That's why I said. Now
I want you to focus, guys.
I want you to focus. What if.
What if
I have this?
Then now we all know this.
That this pen, this pen, it can.
It can fit into the same digit.
Right. Embrace this pen.
Now, I know it can easily fit
inside this number.
Right.
Can you please repeat defining
your assigning the assignment moment.
So Aisha and this part is called
defining a variable.
Okay,
let break it down.
It's also in here.
We are also defining
and here
we are asking, here we have assignment.
And if I tried to assign either value
to the same variable, then I will.
I am reassigning something that I type.
Share this same variable name No
one variable name.
Even if you are trying to declare the same
for integer and then double or
not, it is also not allowed.
So let's assume,
let's let's
take the example of Sebastian and you.
So this is in page.
This is double.
This is in. Right.
Let's let's make Sebastian smaller
this time.
So I know that the content
that I have inside this bigger box,
it can easily fit in here right?
Even though I am picking the content
from a bigger box.
We got a box. I know.
I know that the
the actual content, it's actually smaller.
I know it will fit in this smaller box.
So now if I try to fit this inside
the smaller box, is there any harm guys,
if I know that actual content
and is outside?
Okay, so we have to remove that
and I want to
complete account is gone.
Okay.
So if I know
that the actual content
is something that can fit,
then I should be allowed to do that.
Right. But what happens, Right.
I this that I have stored them in here
and that can easily 13 and integer
but still Java is giving me edit
okay because Java don't know
what I have stored inside of that variable
or java
going to go and check inside the box
what is stored in there.
Java only knows that I am trying
to pick something from a bigger box
and I am trying to put that
in a smaller box.
Java. Don't check the actual content.
Okay, so in this scenario,
if I have something like this,
I can force Java.
I can say to Java that Java,
I know the content can fit in there.
So how do I say
I use these two
brackets and I see integer.
Okay, I said to Java that, Hey, Java,
I know this is a double value,
but I want and I know sometimes I know
sometimes that can double
can cannot fit in an integer
but you know in here
I know for sure that this
and it can fit into this box.
So can you please try to convert that?
Can you please do this placement
in here?
Because I am sure 100%
I will not be losing any information.
There is no harm doing that. So please.
So in here I am explicitly saying,
Hey Java, please take the contents
from the bigger box from the well
and put it inside the smaller box.
Because I know.
Because I know that the contents
they can fit.
Okay, so this process of explicitly saying
that a team
can fit in a letter
box is called typecasting.
Okay, It's a very good question
why we need to do this.
Okay, so, guys,
sometimes what happens is that so
I have showed you that
you guys will be writing thousands
and thousands of lines of code, right.
To solve real life problems,
even millions lines of code.
A single person can not write
all of that code.
You guys will be working in teams.
In my previous company,
there was a team of 50 developers
and we used to write code
for 400 plus services.
So some part of the code is written by me,
some other
the other part is maybe written
by someone else.
The other part is written by someone else.
Now, it is also possible that maybe,
Alexi,
maybe you you are you are storing
some information in an integer.
Right?
But I have written my logic for doubles
because I didn't have time
to go through all of your code.
I was writing.
My logic are according to me, you have
written your logic according to you.
And now we have to combine that code.
We have to combine that code
if typecasting is not possible
and if you have used doubles in your code,
I will not be able to translate either.
I have put you my code
or you to change your code.
Okay, so this convergence
between different variables,
it makes that merging of code easier.
Let's say, for example,
you have written a code 40 years later,
four years before you left that company,
someone else divided out some code
and now you are purging that.
So Java is giving you flexibility
that you don't have to change all the code
if some part is written
using a different type.
And the other part is written
using a different database.
Now you guys can easily convert the data
types between each other if you know
there is no harm, you can convert
the data ties between each of them.
You can transfer the information
from one type of variable
to the other type of variable.
Okay, So you get this
functionality by typecasting,
just like an item costing way
force one type to other type.
You are right.
Is it clear why we needed scary stories?
Begin here with projects support.
Put hundreds more.
So that's why we need typecasting.
And have you guys seen those converters?
So you buy something maybe
that takes maybe
110 words as the input
and then you try to use in another socket
that works on 22 and we use that converter
in between or adapter.
So it is that adapter taking the one thing
and converting it to the other thing
so that these things can be compatible.
Actually, my nose is hurting from inside
when I am speaking.
I had my surgery last week
so I cannot even laugh
really.
So now let me show you
which data type.
Okay, so assigning
a value of
one type
to a to a variable of an other type.
Okay So the data type,
the data type, they are the variables.
They are all different data types.
And we are trying to move the data
between those two different variables.
So this process is called costing.
Okay, so let me repeat again,
assigning a value
of one type to a variable of another type
is known as type question.
And there are two types of typecasting.
So guys, notice this.
Notice if I have an integer
in here, I am again doing the same thing.
I am trying to assign the value
from the one type of variable
to the other type.
But in here I don't get any errors.
Java does not give me any errors.
It does not bother me.
So yes, this is also typecasting.
So moving things from smaller box
to the bigger box.
So when we move something
from a smaller box to a bigger box,
we are 100% sure
that this thing can fit in the bigger box.
But when we are doing the reverse,
sometimes it can fit,
but the other times
it might not fit right?
So this typecasting is automatic, okay,
It's implicit, it's widening.
So three names.
Okay,
then just technically, don't worry about
this typecasting.
We have to explicitly do this right.
We have to explicitly
tell the job out there, page out loud.
Don't worry,
this thing can fit in the smaller box.
Please, please fit it right.
So this one. This.
This one is called explicit typecasting.
Okay. Or narrowing.
We are picking something and we are trying
to compress in a smaller box.
Okay, so this is close.
Narrowing, explicit.
Okay, So that's why
we have these names so widening.
We think something from smaller box again
into bigger box.
So we are widening this space.
It's also called implicit
or it's automatic
format.
You you are from Afghanistan
and all out of standardizing the
you guys understand both in the Urdu and
and all the movies
and get everything right very closely
at least one is automatic.
So you tell me which one is automatic?
Which one is automatic?
Is this one automatic or one is automatic?
This one is automatic.
I am not doing anything.
It is being done automatically by Java.
Right?
So this one is automatic.
Which one is implicit? Right.
Which one is implicit?
First one or the second one?
So this one is implicit.
Implicit
I am not explicitly doing in here.
I am explicitly doing it in
which in which one is widening,
which one is widening, in which case
the size of the box is getting wider.
The second one, this one is widening.
Okay, this one is narrowing.
We are actually shrinking the space.
All right.
So now, guys, this is also possible
and this is also possible that
if we try to sum
if we
try to figure something from Maker Box,
it is also possible
that big thing
may not fit in the beta box.
Okay, so this is also possible.
And this it can lead to two
something very unexpected.
Okay.
Losing the data.
For example, if I say
in pager
number
five is equal to one, two, five, six,
and if I try to fit in a smaller box
where it's very, very small box right.
So in here again, I am trying to fit
from a bigger box to a smaller box.
So how can I tell you about that?
Hey, don't worry. This thing can fit.
How can I tell?
What is the syntax?
What should I write in here?
If I want this
for this convergence to be forced,
I need to write
brackets and I need to write byte.
Okay, so what do you guys think?
What will happen
if I try to print this number six?
I might get something very weird.
Okay.
Because now we are forcing Sebastian.
So I got -24.
Okay,
so features in September features and your
so in here we have we might,
we might lose this information
or maybe even
we would change the
actual context into something different.
Okay.
So whenever you are performing
this kind of work,
make sure make, sure
the pain can fit inside that box.
Otherwise the results can be disastrous.
Okay.
Are we often Monday?
I think. Yes, you are.
Do you guys have classes on Mondays?
I think you know, after
I guess after four weeks
you guys will be having so Romani saying,
why we go?
Why We got -40.
Okay.
So this is what is happening right now.
So maybe you
you have tried to forcefully to
fit Sebastian in here
and now it has deformed to something else.
I might be okay.
Something like this.
So it has become something else.
So that's why you got -24.
So when Java tries to perform
this calculation,
it follows a special procedure. Okay.
And when you try to fit a very big number
into a box that is smaller.
So sometimes maybe it is only able
to fit this part of this box.
So this convergence
is actually happening in binary.
So instead of this, Wolf,
I find the computer is floating
something like this. So
this is zero, actually.
Okay.
In computers, if you have to represent
a negative number,
you make it
the first bit as one, okay, As one.
And if you have to put something
if you have to show the plus sign,
you make it to zero.
So this number was positive.
So first bit was zero.
Then you try to fit in a smaller box.
Maybe you have
no you have lost this, first of all, big.
And now the remaining part
that you left with it starts with a one.
So Java is thinking that
maybe it is a -24.
Okay, this is actually complete science,
how the calculations are performed
under the hood.
Okay. And it all happens in binary.
So if you guys have not understood
this part, it's fine.
Just understand this
that if you are trying to fit something
very big into something very small things,
you you guys will be getting an
unexpected visit.
But in actual,
the results are very calculated.
They are not unexpected, but
there is a complete science behind that.
And I don't want you to get into that.
Fine.
Even if we typecast,
we still have that a lot.
So what is the use of forcing
to change that that I saw
right now?
You know the actual contents
that you have stored inside this variable.
Later on, you guys will learn
how to read data from files,
how to read data from Internet,
how to read from data from keyboard.
User can enter anything from the keyboard.
The logic will be same,
but the data can be different.
In those scenarios.
You will not be knowing in advance
what kind of data you will be dealing.
So in those scenarios
we will be using typecasting.
Okay.
And in those narratives,
we will not be knowing the results.
Yes, you are right.
So I think in the next class or so,
you guys will learn about this kind of
class, then things will make more sense.
Right now, we are we are like
you can also ask this question there.
Tell us that you know, that this
this will be five cannot fix it in this
why why you are placing this
well 5556 in here
so in here I am demonstrating
your different possibilities
in actual
when you will be solving a real problem,
you will not me knowing the
all the circumstances.
Okay, then you will be using different
different logics to make your programs
work in real life values.
But right now, because we are learning,
I need to show you all the possibilities.
So sometimes I may use dumb examples which
to show you that what can happen
if you do this.
Okay, so It's not always possible
to show you in real life use case
out of all the examples.
So sometimes you have to meet.
Okay, So, Alexi, you are trying to write,
I guess you to the Russian
is good for Russian or something
that you are trying to write in comics
so your eclipse,
it cannot handle all the languages.
So it trying to convert that Russian
to something simpler before starting.
If you remove your comics
or if you use English,
then it should work.
Actually, the file type is not Java,
and Java File does
not support all languages
and that's why sometimes
you can get these others.
Yes. So guys, so this is the sequence.
Okay.
This is the sequence in which
the memory is increase or decrease.
So the shortest data type is by.
Okay, I hope you guys remember
this, that it can only store
from one -128 to 127.
Then the next bigger data type is sharp.
So it means that we can easily place
the contents of a bite a short, okay.
We can easily place the contents
of a short inside an integer.
We can easily perform integer too long.
Okay.
So if I am moving in this direction,
am I doing
explicit typecasting
or implicit typecasting?
Guys, it's
implicit like automatic lightning.
So float is than long.
And then long applicable is the biggest.
Okay when it comes to numbers
and this is just Natalie
doing the reverse.
All right.
Are there any questions guides
from this typecasting? It's
okay. Yes.
You guys need practice, that's for sure.
All right,
Come on.
I must use only English. Yes for comments.
Yes, you can use some other languages,
but not all of them are supported.
So I don't know right now, which I guess
you are trying to use some version.
Or it can also happen
if you are trying to make
trying to store emojis
or something like that.
So if you're using this, it should work.
If you should not get any errors
and you give us more
examples about the typecasting,
you want more examples of the typecasting.
Okay, let's let's let's do more.
So if I say a short,
I'm seven, okay?
And if I say
and then if I stand by
number eight.
Okay So if I try to store number seven,
if I try to assign number
seven variable to number, nobody
can I do that Or I have to do
some kind of exclusive casting.
So if I said
number seven,
I get an added right, I get an error.
Why I am getting an error, guys,
I am trying to assign a variable
which is of type shark to a variable
which is of type by I'm getting an error.
Why I am getting an error.
We should box in the bigger picture.
It is bigger divided by it is bigger.
So I am trying to store something bigger
from a bigger box to a smaller box.
So how can I avoid this area?
Because I know the bite and tell
I need to typecast, right?
I need time part.
I need to say Java is fine.
I know the number can fit inside
the smaller class.
Okay.
And if I do, if I see in integer
number nine
is equal to 1000.
And if I say long order, maybe,
maybe float
or F can assign this number nine to float
without performing any typecasting
or I have to typecast it.
Which box is bigger? Right?
Which box is the bigger
the integer or the float
Float is bigger, right?
So I can simply say
number nine is equal to float. Okay
And if I say long
and is equal to,
can I assign this f to this l directly?
Or I have to do some kind of convergent
which boxes are bigger that
float or long.
So floor is bigger.
No, no, no.
Float is bigger, right?
Long is not bigger.
Big luminous.
And I try to memorize this sequence.
So float comes after long
it take 2 minutes
to memorize it and then we will do it.
So first byte, short integer,
then long then float and.
Then at the last double.
So forget about the decimal point.
Okay? Just memorize this.
Size of boxes.
Yeah.
So now if I try to do this,
I will get ten.
Adam and I have to explicitly type.
Oops.
What would I type inside the box? Right.
Longer float.
So the variable which is over the left
I am saying,
will convert this f to this variable.
So I will say long. Okay. Not short.
I am saying convert this flock to a long.
Okay. So I will not specify float.
I will say long.
Okay. And bucket next to this.
If I have a double
number ten and if I have 10.5 in here
and if I have indeed
number 11
and I shoot this content
inside this locked case.
So even if even if I force Java,
even if I force in Java,
even if I thought Java by saying,
hey, Java I know what I am doing,
you just try to convert it,
what will happen? What will happen, guys?
What output I will get, I will lose.
So Java will do the convergent
because I am forcing it,
but the actual results,
they can be disastrous.
They can be unexpected time.
So Java will do the conversion
because I am posting it by saying this,
but sometimes I might lose information
so I lost the decimal part.
This can happen with the other data types.
If something can fix can fit easily, go
I will fit it
if not just
your input
and the result can be something
very unexpected.
All right.
Is it clear now
to check
if we are on type of not?
Okay, Everything seems good.
Okay.
So do we move forward
or do you guys need more examples?
So if our first variable is bigger
than the second variable,
we do typecasting.
No, no, it's not bigger.
It's smaller if the first two.
So the variable in which
we are trying to store
it is smaller than you do.
Typecasting.
So the minor is fine
if you don't understand the use case.
Okay.
So once you start building your framework,
then you will understand the use case.
So right now, focus on the rules.
If you understand the rules, it's fine.
The actual use case, they will be coming
after you guys are done with Java,
then you will build your own framework.
Then you will realize the use cases.
Is there any
use case of it in non
imperative that I fahadh
you mean non primitive prototype
because there is nothing like non
imperative prototype.
Okay.
So if there are two different types
then we cannot do testing now.
Actually do typecasting
when the data types are different.
You see in here the data type is double.
In here, type is integer.
Okay, two different data types,
double is bigger than integer.
Yeah.
So how many of you all get left?
Let's do this.
How many of you understand this?
That which in.
That type is bigger and smaller,
if I ask you,
is long, greater than float or not?
How many of you can answer this question
Which data type is bigger float
or long float?
And what about long end double?
Which one is bigger
than double?
Okay, so you guys understand this.
Okay, the second part,
do you guys understand this?
That If we try to fit something bigger
in a smaller box,
we might not be able to do that
right?
So sometimes, depending upon
what we have stored in a box, right,
sometimes we might be able to fit it,
sometimes we might not be able to fit it.
Right.
So if I have this mobile phone right,
and if I pulled this mobile in a box
that can hold one box and hold 15
mobile phones and the other box can hold
ten mobile phones,
but I have only one phone in that box
which can hold 15
mobile phone, mobile phones.
And if I try to pick this phone
from that box, which can hold 15
and if I try to place this phone in a box
that can hold only ten,
will I be able to do that
or I will not be able to do that?
Can I do that?
I have only one one phone.
I have only one phone, and I am
picking this phone from a box
that can hold 15 phones
and I am trying to place it in a box
that can hold that phone.
So if I have only one phone,
I don't have any issues
putting in a smaller box right?
So if I have
if I have a box.
Okay.
And the contents of that box,
the contents of that box
can easily fit in other box.
I don't have any issues. Right.
I don't have any issues
I can just write in.
And the convergence will happen.
But if I know that I have something
which is bigger,
okay, it's not only in a bigger box,
but it can also not fit inside
this smaller box.
Then I will lose information.
Okay Then I will lose information.
What if that box already has been formed?
Yes. If that is the case, Maryam,
then we will lose the information.
Then the convergent will not be perfect.
We only use costing for numbers.
Not we actually can cost any variables,
but you will learn those in the later
part.
But right now, yes, we can.
Only you can think of that.
We can only do it with number five
for now, double was bigger than integer.
How was integer able
to hold the double in number 10.5?
No, it was not able to hold that at all.
It was not able to hold that.
You see, we have lost
we have lost about 2.5.
We have that that 50% of the information
we are only able to create.
And then we have lost that .5.5.
We lose that if we try to force it,
I think we lose that.
I would try to force it.
Is it still not clear, guys,
if we lose information, we can fix it.
No, Alexa, unfortunately,
we cannot fix it.
We have to be careful with the
with the conversion.
We have to be careful with the conversion.
But it will get more clear
when you guys will fold it apples.
And then
in the next class, I will again revise it.
And on the review session
I will again revise it.
Okay,
So if there are still questions left,
So when guys will solve the homework,
when you will solve the if oppose,
when you will attend the review class
after the review class,
we will go through that again
in the next week.
So it's fine.
So if you guys have understood,
let's say 70%
of what I have told you, it's fine.
But if you are on around 50% or 40%,
then it can be problematic.
You should ask me questions. Then
when do we need costings?
So most probably
you guys will not be needing it.
Okay.
But we need it when we have to combine
because from multiple sources
to build a single application
long L is equal to long.
F line 23. Not clear.
Okay, so line 424.
So you know
which box is bigger,
which box bigger is float
bigger or the longest bigger.
I thought it was one.
Oh exactly, actually.
Okay, let me change it to number.
Maybe
on the end of the class.
Can you send more
YouTube videos on next lesson?
Same be how you do yesterday.
Yes. I will always be sharing the YouTube
before each class
float bigger, right?
Yes. Float is bigger than long.
So because float bigger than long.
That's why I need to explicitly tell
to Java that hey Java, please try.
They try to convert this number.
I know that this number 10,000.
It can fit easily inside a log,
so don't worry.
Just do the conversion.
Yes, you have written it properly.
All right. So should we move forward
or are there any
any questions out there and there?
There are any questions why?
I am getting an added for line
19 and 20 vital changes.
Screenshot.
All right.
So so we have learned about the
arithmetic operators
today.
We will learn the relational operators
and equality operators,
the two types of new operators.
Give me what happened.
Give me why that bad face.
All right.
So nice deal.
Now we have learned about
but we have only learned about the
all the casting or all of that.
You what I have been doing
was from the previous class.
From this class,
we have only learned about the casting
you give to a man to comprehend
in general.
Yes, programing.
It requires
attention to those details
and these symbol.
And then semicolons and then this.
So many rules.
So yes, it will take time.
It will take time.
Don't worry.
We will make you learn
all you have during this bootcamp.
You will learn.
It will be easy
for people who has experience.
But so we started from zero. So sorry.
I don't know if you are coming
from regular or not.
95% of our students,
they don't have any background.
It's not that easy.
Okay, so on line number 24, Michael,
the s off that chart is actually capital.
Make sure that it is not capital.
It should be
with lowercase s.
All right.
So today we will learn how to make
our programs take decisions.
Okay. Based On data.
How Based on data,
how to take decisions,
it is easy for woman, I guess, because.
Woman
they they inherently naturally they, they,
they have more attention
to details than men.
And that's why a lot of women,
they join the testing,
testing jobs and they are successful.
So men as the developer and woman
as the test
is the best combination.
Even if you do
all of the things in your life perfectly,
your wife and your mom,
they can still tell you issues, you know,
all the things that you do right.
Let's bring people to us.
We are in different class.
And then of men can also focus on details.
I'm just kidding.
Okay. So
there are some things which are good.
Like, for example, ladies,
they can see more shared in class,
like so many different types of lipsticks
when it comes to choosing a dress.
And girls can decide for look,
they can decide
from so many colors men,
they are just simple, right?
And he showed they see from the job
they just by the end
they come home.
So today, guys, we will learn about
how to make our programs
kind of base and decisions.
Okay.
How to make our programs
big decisions based on certain scenarios
or certain data,
how to perform certain tasks.
Okay.
Or how to avoid certain task, how to
execute one part of the court
record,
how to avoid one part of the court.
Okay.
Now, to make our programs
take these decisions,
we need to learn some new operators. Okay?
And the first operator
So let's say
so now we will learn
how to make our to take the decisions.
So if the operator that we will learn
is an equal to operator.
So if we want to check that,
if something if the contents of a box
are same as of a third box,
we use this operator
and it is called equal
to equal to operator
will report the code on canvas.
Yes, I will always post the code on canvas
for all the classes to complete course
you will be having the material on canvas.
So if I have two boxes.
So if I have two boxes. Okay.
So right now I am hard coding the values
I am explicitly stored in ten inside port.
The variables. Okay.
But there will be times
you guys will not be annoying
beforehand,
but the values variables contain.
If you want, check in those scenarios.
If the contents of two variables
are same or not,
we can use the equal to equal to.
And this is how we use it. We see
number one equal to equal to
number two.
Okay, guys, if something
if Java has to represent
something in the form of Yes or
what do we use instead of yes
and no, in Java, what do we use?
True and false.
Right.
So if the contents of these two variables,
if they are same,
we like get a true or false,
I will be getting a true yes.
So if I ask you this, exclude
I get true.
True means both of these variables
they contain same thing.
Okay.
If change this 10 to 20
and if now I institute my code,
I get a false because now
both variables,
they contain different things.
Okay, so If we have to check something,
if something is same in
both the variables,
we use this equal to equal to operator.
So looking for comments as it
all is possible without using boolean.
It is possible with the help of this.
Equal to equal to operator.
Yes. Java knows without without boolean,
without variable
if it is a true or false,
why we are double equal.
So Alex in Java single
equal is reserved for assignment.
Okay,
so That's why they are using double equal.
So you guys might be thinking that
in math in the in real life
the the equal to single equal
to in a real life we use for equality.
Right.
So in programing things are little
different single equal to sign
we use if we want to assign
to a variable double equal to sign
we use for equality.
Okay.
It's it's a little different,
but we only use it to check it
and then erase it.
So we are not erasing anything.
We are simply checking if number one
is equal to number two or not.
But we are not erasing.
We are not storing.
We are not doing anything.
But yes, if you want, you can do this.
You can say
you can see Boolean
results and you can see
number one to the number.
Okay. But you can you can do that as well.
So because the because the results
of this operation, they are a boolean,
I can declare a variable
and I can stored the reserves
in that variable.
Okay. Yes.
But it's a longer B, it's a longer.
Okay.
And I can also put into this all
these items.
So both both give me false.
So this is my first operator.
Do you guys understand this, by the way?
Guys,
if you to use a single equal to sign,
I like typing.
We need to get used to typing.
Yes, you guys should be typing.
You guys should be following. Okay.
It's important.
Don't think that I
because I will be sharing all the code
and not you guys don't need to type it
because guys, it's not only your brain
that learns but your muscles.
They also learn. They also have memory.
So when you are typing something,
there are so many things
your muscles also need to learn.
Okay,
so make sure you are practicing with me.
So guys, if I see if I.
If I use single equal, what happens
when we use the single equal guys.
So if you accidentally use single value.
So now if I try to execute the score
instead of true and false, I am getting 20
y, I am getting 20
because P value from number two
variable is being assigned to number one
and number one is being printed. Okay?
And if you try to do remove in here,
you will get an negative
because now the result of this operation
is a number,
not a boolean, but you are trying to store
that result in a boolean.
Okay.
So make sure you are using
the relational operators.
So let me also show my printing it out.
If I put into B value of number one,
what about what?
I will go to guys
I am using assignment operator
or the equality operator,
what output I will get for number one,
I will get 20.
That pen has been reassigned
that then
the pen has been reassigned by this point.
B Okay.
It has been reassigned
because I use the assignment operator.
So note then those who were saying
I will be now getting 20
because I have done this assignment
operation,
is it clear to do a thing then?
So make sure you use double equals.
All right.
So the next operator
I don't understand.
Can you explain again?
So which part you don't understand
then you tell me the line
number
Boolean, please.
This this line, this one
line quantity.
Okay, so let me do this.
So Java,
execute from top
to bottom, from left to right.
Okay, left, right.
But when we have this equal to sign,
first the Java execute whatever
we are writing after that equal to sign.
Okay,
so after that equal to sign, I am writing.
I am saying Java.
And please tell me if number one is equal
to equal to number two or not. So
is it is it equal to number?
Is one equal to number two? No.
So the result of this calculation
will be false.
Right after I have gotten this
false result,
I am storing that result
inside this result variable.
It's a Boolean variable, right?
So the there are two operations
that are being performed on line number
ten, one in one operation.
I am checking
if two numbers are equal or not
and it is top
whether it's a true or false,
I am spotting that true or false
inside the results variable.
So one assignment
and one
equality checking operation.
Okay, so that's why you get true or false.
And depending
if the numbers are same or not in black
box, well, the reason is certain
when you change the position of number one
or number two, the results change.
Right?
So is it clear
those who were saying about this line ten
is an X symbol, saying about line?
I think in line I am simply printing
the value of number one.
I'm simply printing the value
of number one.
So number one contains ten.
Okay, I am printing it.
And if I execute for my core,
I get ten in here.
But if I use single equal to sign
instead of double click one double equal.
So now
this 20 from this number two
is first of being assigned to number one.
So this then it will be discarded.
Number 20 will be stored in number one.
And if then I try to print it out,
then I think about what?
But will I get ten or 20?
I have change.
This two equals to single equal.
So previously I was using the assignment
operator.
Sorry, the equality.
Now I am using the assignment operator
So the brand
you will be assigned to now
and that's why I get 20.
I made it clear
that why if I use single equal, I get 20.
And why if I use double equal signs,
I get false, I get sometimes false
and sometimes 20
because I am doing different operations.
When I do assignment,
I get the result of variable.
When I do equality
operation, I am checking
if something is equal or not.
Then I get the
rule for false as the answer
nicely.
Are there any other students
who are confused about line
11 or line ten?
Remember, guys, it's perfectly fine.
Even if you have explained something
you still don't understand.
Your questions are dumb.
You are going repeat it multiple times.
It's fine for now. It's fine. Slowly.
When we move forward in this course,
then explicitly
I will be telling you guys that, Hey guys,
you should not be asking this question
at this point of time.
Or maybe I will say that.
Hey guys,
I have already explained this thing twice.
Twice. You should pay attention.
You should not waste
your time of other class.
Because remember, guys,
there will be students.
There are students
who are paying full attention.
They are investing their time, their money
and their efforts.
Okay.
And always, if we are repeating something
four or five times,
we are not doing fear with those students
who are giving full time, full effort.
Right.
So then we be we should be focusing.
Then we should think
maybe we are not doing proper
and because a lot of the students,
they are not from the background.
If we move too fast
in the start of the course,
then it is not fair with those.
Okay, so right now it's fine.
But as we move forward,
I will be telling you that
if you maybe need to study more
or maybe if you need to practice more,
or maybe if you need to focus more
so far now, if the questions are dumb
or if you don't understand
in the first attempt or second, it's fine.
In line 11
is that when you switch to single equal,
the result will be 20 instead of ten.
Will it always choose the higher value
number with 20?
So, Catalina, it's not about the higher
values, it's about the assignment.
If I put if I took five in here
and if I, if I remove this equal to sign,
this five is being assigned
to this number one.
Now what, what I what, I will get Catalina
will I get five
or ten
by. Right.
So it's not about bigger or smaller
number.
It's about, it's about
it's about what value is stored in.
And number two
is being shifted to earth.
Number one, it's about this.
Okay, this is the logic
so it's not about
because so line
nine is over writing line ten.
So but
it's not proper to say we are
line is overriding
the values of of variables
are being overwritten.
The value of number one
variable is being overwritten by number.
So this is the proper terminology.
Yes. Is reassignment.
We are reassigning in here.
It used to be assigned.
So the double equal, if we want to check.
Okay.
All right.
So should I move forward with it
or is it okay?
You guys need to break.
Just give me maybe 15 minutes,
then we will have a break.
Okay? Yes.
Number two, value is assigned to number.
It's okay. We can move forward.
Yes. One equals to find
assigning to equal to find equality
like.
Well, actually,
we have started from this variable.
Okay, let's learn about this symbol.
This this kind of
it's called less than symbol. So
in here we are
we are checking
if if something is equal to or not.
What if if I have to check if something is
bigger than the other thing or not.
Right.
Value of one variable is bigger than
the value of the other variable or not.
If again,
I check back with the equal to find guys.
If one variable has the bigger value
than the other variable,
can I check that with equal cosine?
No, I cannot check that
indicator.
Well. Okay.
Maybe equals a typo.
Okay.
So we cannot check that equal
to sign only checks if two things
are equal or not. So.
So if we want to check
this in info that if something is bigger
then the other or not.
Or we use
this greater than sign. Okay
guys, is
the is the value
that that we have stored in
number one, is it greater than the value
which we have stolen?
Number two, Yes.
Give me the result
of all the relational operators
will be true or false.
So should I get a true or false
in this case?
Right. I get it.
So Java is telling me that,
hey, that's good.
Whatever you have stored in number one,
it is bigger
that then
whatever you have stored in number two.
Okay, it's not that simple.
Which
if I change this to 50,
what are what I will get Now?
Now I will get false.
Because number two contains
something that is bigger
and number one contains something
that is smaller.
Okay.
But we are checking for little things.
So now I will get false.
Yeah.
So whatever
value, whatever variable we are putting,
we are
we have this two two sides of this symbol.
If that thing contains bigger values,
we will be getting true
and we are over
is that there are this arrow like sign.
Whichever way we are
we will be placing there.
If it has smaller values,
then we will be getting full
and we have reversed the symbol
so we can also use the other the
the reverse arrow, this reversing them.
So now the logic will be reversed. Okay.
If now number one
has something that is smaller
and number two has something bigger,
now I will get control.
Okay.
So guys, it
is it possible that these two symbols,
they can have same values?
If I am using same variable,
is it possible they can also be both
and have blue
or they both can have false? I
think about this.
Okay.
So if two numbers are same,
so electra's same numbers are same.
So what do you guys think?
What answer
I will get for both of them now.
So they will have false
when both the values are equal, right?
So yes, they can have the same.
Okay.
Not greater, not not less.
All right.
So in programing, you have to
you have got to think
of all the possibilities.
Yeah.
Is it clear that these two symbols,
if they're just like math, simple,
just like math,
so closely related, are two next symbols
to next relational operators
that they are called
greater than equal to
or less than equal to.
Okay, so this thing, this symbol is called
called greater than symbol.
This symbol is called less than symbol.
These are called greater than equal
to symbol or less than or equal to symbol.
Okay.
So now we have this extra gap ability.
So this symbol,
it can check two things.
It can check if something is greater or.
If something is equal, this symbol,
it can only check if something is greater.
Okay.
But in this one it can check
if something is greater and equal.
Okay. So.
So tell me, guys, tell me the output.
If I put pen in both the variables,
what will be the output for this two lines
and what will be output
for these two lines?
You will be getting four outputs, right?
Those four outputs in the console,
you can just write f 44 false and two
So tell me those four answers.
All right.
So false. False.
And then
pro. So false, false.
Go through.
And if I, if I
if I say 20
now work output I will get
take your time.
Not right.
Think about it
and then tell me the output.
All right.
So for this one,
is the number one
the greater than number two, life
is number one greater the number two
false right is the number one less
then number two.
Yes. Right. So false. True.
And is the number one
greater or equal to number two?
No more.
The condition of failed, right?
Neither.
This number is equal to number one.
Neither number one is equal to number
two, nor
be number one is greater than number two.
Okay, so both the condition are feared.
So if I end insecurities, so I get false
because number one
is not greater than number two,
I get true because number
one is less than number two.
I get calls
because neither number one is greater
nor it is equal to number two.
Okay?
And get true
because one condition is passed.
This time I am getting this true.
I am I getting this true
because these two numbers are equal or
because number one is less than number
two, less.
Right.
So this this
this operator rejects who thinks, okay,
it's excluding all these operators clearly
they are these operators clear.
Okay then we have this
not equal to operator so
same as equal to
so if we want to check
if something is not equal to
or if number one is not equal to
number two,
then I will be getting it true.
Okay.
So it's the reverse of this condition.
We say, hey, let's
this is the reverse of equal to
so because these numbers
are not equal sign
group.
And if these numbers are equal,
then I will get a false
this is the reverse of that condition.
Now, let's have a break
and the break
we will learn about B,
if conditions get
worse.
Can you explain why on line 20
you get a draw
if just one condition is true
on line 20.
So in here, Catalina,
we are using two conditions.
And even if one condition returns true,
we return true for the complete condition.
So you're saying extend or condition.
Okay.
So in our
what do we say if this part is true, then
this part is also or if this part is true,
We said this is true.
Okay.
So if you ask me,
like in order to see how this works,
if let's say I have or
so I will say, okay,
if either of these values are one,
the answer is okay,
it can be first one or the second one.
It can be the first one
of the second one.
The answer is one.
If Both the conditions are one
spin. The answer is one.
This condition will only return false.
Then both the operators return
false.
So in three conditions
you will be getting a true.
First condition is true.
Second condition is true.
Both conditions are true. Okay.
Only you will be getting false
when both are fake.
Does it matter which one? We don't know.
It does not matter.
What was the last condition
if did not equal to a picture?
Please again about not equal.
So let's see if simple it checks.
If it fails, if number one
is non equals or number two
it will return you.
True.
So R is number one not equal to number two
or they are, they are equal.
So if I ask you this,
that number one
is not equal to number two.
What will be your answer?
Will you say true or false? No.
If I say number one is not equal
to number two,
will your answer be true or false?
I'm saying not equal to m.
I am.
So this condition is false.
Why it is false
because in actual numbers are equal.
So if just I am saying the reverse equal.
Okay.
Because they are equal equal.
Is it clear now
this class is not being too hard
if here we go.
Here we see the examples from Michael
and some point of time later on
maybe we will see a meme as well
from Sebastien
on Proven false.
No, we are not hungry. Let's have a break.
So I guess one thing we
saw because we have to cover a lot.
So let's have a shorter break.
Maybe 15 minutes.
No, there is no chance for 255
a 15 minute break
because we have to cover a lot.
So. 155.
Okay.
Please be back in 15 minutes
and reminding me
about the recording.
Okay.
I have started recording.
Thank you
to a new class.
So now
we will use these relational operators
with the help of another construct
that is called F condition.
So now we will write code that
execute certain blocks,
certain lines based on these conditions.
Okay.
And this is how we achieve it.
Let's say
we have one
and one or two
like this one
so we can see if.
Okay, so if
that two parenthesis
and if
frustrating it, let me tell you this,
I continue this
to parentheses
and then I am putting two in here.
Okay.
Yes, we are recording.
So if I have three lines like this
for this, if,
if whatever
we are putting inside these brackets,
if the result of that calculation is true,
the this starting bracket
and extending that liberated
whatever code
we put inside these two brackets
if that condition returns.
True.
Yeah, Java will execute that code.
If not because I will not execute
this line of code.
So right now I have placed true.
So I will see this line,
this line and this line on my console.
So if I execute this
I see before
if condition I see
I am inside of condition.
I see after if condition. Yes.
If same as of those court papers.
If I put clause in here
now I will only see this line
and this line. Okay.
This line
Java will now not execute this line
because in here we are putting false. Okay
I see before this line
after applying
and there can be thousands of lines
inside this condition, it's
not only about one line.
There can be thousands of lines.
Okay.
So if the condition is false,
none of those lines will execute.
If condition is true,
all the lines will be executed.
So this eighth condition,
it works on booleans.
Okay, True and false.
So those operators that we have learned,
what do the return, guys?
What kind of data written, what
what is the data type
that the return
boolean, right?
Yes or no? True or false?
So can I use those relational operators
inside these parentheses where?
I am using false and true, yes.
Right.
So if I say instead
of true and false, if I say
actually
actually we create a new class.
So they work on true and false. So
let me quickly copy in this code.
And at this time,
let me introduce you to.
So if I say number
one is greater than
number two,
so we will these lines on the consolidate.
If I said
no right, because this condition,
it is returning me a false.
And whenever we have a false
inside these parentheses in an F condition
are and Java does not execute the lines
which are inside the
if condition starting from this bracket.
Tell this.
So if I execute this
I see only two lines.
Why there is an added on line 16.
Please put in this portion of
so you are missing a bracket.
You are missing a bracket.
There should be three closed in
curly bracket one for this class,
the second one for this method
and the third one for the if condition.
You are missing that bracket.
Yes, I think. Sure.
Let me know once you have time this code.
But we have understood this code
to minors.
Try to understand this code.
Ask questions.
If something is not clear, I will. Yes.
Only if the condition is true,
then the lines will be printed
or any other code.
But any other code
that you put inside this if condition
inside the safe condition
starting this bracket to
this is not necessarily
to be print or statement.
Anything that you put inside in here,
Java will only execute those lines
if this part is returning a true
if the discrimination
Java is doing discrimination
or you just got back into print on
Jimmy, you are almost 10 minutes late
works the condition.
I'm not telling you about this condition.
First you have to pay the penalty.
You have to give part to all of the class
members.
Line 18.
Why is it outside? First
line is
at the line 18.
This way
it's different.
And this is with
line 16. Oh.
I am writing this line intentionally
so that you guys know
which lines are executed
and which which not.
When we started condition
just just to show you,
if we are not settling down,
then would it be the right race?
Okay, so Jimmy, we have learned about
so it does not matter
if it's outside those brackets on line 15.
So Catalina, this line
which outside of curly brackets
it is independent of this if condition,
whether this condition is returning to
or it is returning force,
it will always be executed
at face of things
which are outside of curly brackets.
They will always be executed.
Learn the things
which are inside these curly brackets
they will execute if if condition is true
and not if the if condition is false.
They they will declare bankruptcy,
giving a piece of body
to a class of 100 plus
or I will duplicate three times
I am inside of this condition.
So you're doing I just duplicate
it is to show you that we can put
more than one line inside this condition.
If you want to compute,
then we're going to look
just to show you
that we can have multiple lines.
Oops.
So, Jimmy, we were learning
about relational operators.
So focus on here. Give me
we now we
we are learning about this condition.
So how this condition works, if
we place it through
in here,
inside this, if whatever line
we write inside these brackets,
it is executed.
If we have a true in here.
Right. So if I execute this line.
So because I have oops,
I have a true in here,
I see these three lines
which are inside if condition
if I put a false, our job
will not execute these three lines
in here.
Okay.
So I see only two lines.
So they are called if health conditions.
So and instead of putting true and false,
I can also write code
that returns true
or false as a result an executed.
So if I write number
one is greater than number two
because the relational operators did it
and true or false.
Right.
So they can also
be used inside this condition.
So I am writing
if number one is greater than number two,
I am saying here Java and all these lines,
if not in all of these lines,
in all this line, but these two lines
which are above and below
if condition, they are not dependent of on
if condition, no matter if the
if is true or if it is false,
they will always be executed.
They will always be executed.
And so when I print less than it print
all as true.
So let's see, because number one
is less than number two.
So you put in less,
then it will print all the values,
but it will print
because now the condition is true, right?
The condition is true.
So now I will see all the lines.
What is this used for, Maryam?
And these if conditions are used to give
to your programs
kind of in print now your programs,
they can think they can take the data
from the user.
They can now take decisions.
They can do either this or that.
Okay, So we are giving this new logic,
new kind of brings to our programs
that they can take the decisions.
So once you enter the username
and password correctly, guys,
once you enter the username and password
correctly on Facebook, what happens?
Facebook takes you to the
to the account, right?
How how, how Facebook is checking that
all Facebook is checking if your username
and password are the ones that you that
you entered when you created that account.
Using if conditions is
the most important thing in programing.
If The most important thing.
So so Facebook is doing this great
Facebook is doing this.
So say
let's say your password is ten.
Okay, I'm just as the password is ten.
So Facebook is saying
if number one is equal to equal to ten,
then show you the pool for your account
and everything.
Okay.
Otherwise, if if the password is not,
don't let you log in.
Okay.
So can't do that without the boolean
or justifying multiple method. Yes.
We cannot do this without booleans.
This is how your programs take decisions.
You can put any operator in here.
So if the value of if is equal to two,
it prints everything
inside the calibrated of
if condition when the value is false,
it does not work.
Yes, Farhad, you are right.
So let's do one more example Case.
Let's do one more.
So let me put it in in here.
Let's do something first because
let's say
you have this variable integer temp
that has 16, okay?
And you check if if
some pressure
is greater. 60.
Okay.
If it is greater than or equal to 60
is equal to greater than or equal
to say
I am going to be okay.
And with this if conditions,
I can also have an health condition.
Okay.
So if condition, if the thing
that I am writing in here,
if it pretend stroke,
whatever I write in here,
it will be printed.
If not, I can this as okay,
I can write this else.
So if true, do this else do this.
Okay.
So as I stand out
some thought out.
I mean, go for a
walk.
Okay.
So if
whatever condition
I am putting in here, if it is true,
the code from
extracting from this bracket in
this bracket will be executed.
If it is not true,
then this code will be executed.
Okay.
So is this condition progress?
What output?
I will see.
I am going to h.
And if I change the temperature to 50,
what output?
I will see.
I will go for whatever.
Okay, so now your program
is taking decisions based on the data.
Okay?
So it can
it can take the data from your keyboard,
it can download this data from Internet.
It can start from the other files.
So you feel the data to your program.
Depending upon that data,
your program can now take decisions.
This all the websites,
this is how they take decisions.
If the amount in your balance is
is less than B amount,
maybe you are trying to do something.
If it is less than that
and they show you at the e-commerce,
if you had usernames and passwords,
they are not same, they show you error.
Yes, it is also possible
to do with strength,
but part of strength
we have to do something
differently.
So, for example, let's say
I have this
one, two, three.
So strange guys.
Things don't work
with equal to.
Yes, these brackets,
they are very important.
Otherwise you will be getting error.
So things.
Yes, we can do.
We can use equal to equal to sign,
but it is not
recommended to use that equal to sign.
Things
actually have this different mechanism
that is called equals method.
So if you want to check
if two strings are equal or not,
instead of using equal to equal to sign,
it's only four strings, by the way.
Right?
So because string is a non primitive
data type, non
primitive data types, we check non
primitive data types differently.
Okay.
But if are primitive
you can use the equal to four times.
So you will say equals
yes. So if username equals
equal,
whatever.
Let me move this part.
Let's, let's keep it simple.
Else.
So five things
instead of using equal equal to operator,
I have to write this talk.
Okay, then I have to write the equals,
then brackets double course,
and then the value to which
I want to compare compare.
So I see. Hi. Yeah.
And if I change this to
Aisha, or what I will see
is is equal to almost
no right.
Okay.
I see.
I don't know.
So this is how we will use things
on right place
next to one more example.
So let's make sure you understand
these conditions
because they are very important. Yes.
I don't normally
I will be splitting my screen.
Okay.
Don't worry about
doing so.
This is where you guys will make
mistakes.
First, you can miss these brackets.
Okay, We can lift this bracket.
Most of the mistakes you guys
will be making in this area missing out.
These brackets are putting wrong brackets.
Okay?
So make sure every opening bracket
its closing bracket.
Okay. So
meanwhile, others
who have already tried it,
if you guys have any other
any questions you can ask me?
Yes. Dot equals.
We will only be using with strength
with a double boolean
with integer with correct
we we can use the equal to equal
because string is a non primitive
data type.
So we can use this equals to this equal
to equal to all of its things.
And right
now if because you guys have asked
so let me
show you this.
So this greater than sine
is also not allowed.
So on your after your
if condition for four days
you are putting
some of you are putting semicolons in here
it will give you error
this is your error remove that semicolon
semicolon if conditions
there don't have those semicolons.
Why did you write line 19 in separate
curly brackets?
This one from line 18?
You mean curly brackets or parentheses?
Catalina?
You mean these these two separate things.
All these brackets.
So why did you write line 19 in separate
separate brackets?
No, I am not writing exactly like this.
So Starting from here. Still here.
If if the part of if condition
and starting from here till here.
So if I cannot do this
so this is as and part belongs to else
so it is not always necessary
that you put these curly brackets,
but I would say it's a best practice.
So even if you remove this bracket
like this, if you remove this,
if you remove this, yes, your code will
still work, but it is not recommended.
And the reason why it is not recommended,
I will show you that reason
under review class.
For now, all of you
please use curly brackets.
Okay.
All of you.
Because. Yes.
Okay.
So just check this out because thing is
so Maryam, you are making the same mistake
on line number nine
and you are putting a semicolon.
Remove that semicolon
on line 15 and on line
nine, remove those semicolons after the
if condition.
You have a semicolon
in here after this condition
already.
So you guys
see this greater than operation is greater
than the operator is also not allowed
when it comes to things.
Okay.
It is not allowed
this less than is not allowed.
Okay.
But this equals two and not equal to
are allowed.
So first things only equal to
and not equal to are allowed.
Okay, let's put in order.
So do you mean are they getting any output
or are you getting any unexpected
answer.
So. Right.
Yes they are.
Allow the equal to equal to sign and
not equal to saying yes, they are allowed.
Look,
they are never, never recommended to use
always use the equals to method.
Okay.
They are not allowed
the greater than less than greater than
equal to they are not allowed
this equal
to an unequal to are allowed for
things like not recommended to use.
They may produce an expected result.
So always you have this equals method.
And there is one more thing, guys.
When you are using greater
than equal to sign,
make sure you put in this equal to sign
after this this greater than fine.
Okay.
If you put this equal to sign before be
greater than sign, you will get an error.
Do you guys see this this equal to sign?
It should be after this symbol.
And if the same case
will be less than equal to sign,
it will work for less
than if you put it after the error.
If today was okay, far less than no.
It is not always, always after. And
so far less than
if you put it before you will get better.
Okay. For
far greater.
So this sign, it should be in here.
Okay.
After this this this this symbol.
So some of you might not make this
mistake.
Okay. So it should be in here.
Is this five things right now?
It's four numbers.
So it needs to look like yes, like this.
And if you do this,
it should be like this.
Okay.
So if it is greater than okay,
it is greater than sign, then
the equal to sign should be after this.
Okay.
If you look at before
that, you will get an error
and far less than sign.
It should be before the error.
So it's not actually same.
Both less than and greater
than two different okay.
Or greater than it should be
before the equal to sign.
And it should be after.
It should not actually. Yes,
it should not.
And Java guys should not do this.
They should make it different.
But there might be a reason
behind doing this.
So I will try to do a research on
this as well.
Maybe they need a specific reason
for doing this, but
common sense is that it
should not be the case.
So you guys can get errors
If you are using the
is equal to sign operators,
you guys will get errors.
You put a semicolon in here
and you guys can get errors
if you're going to place data lubricates
this.
My brain hurts.
I think the analogy from your break fast
is now consumed.
Michael Right.
Why? I am laughing at
So for us both
in this sport, you are missing a Celebrex.
Okay, make sure guys,
for every opening cut bracket
for every opening, click back in.
Do you have a closing bracket?
If not curly brackets, parentheses,
square brackets,
they always come in pairs.
If you do not have a closing bracket
for an optical bracket,
you will get an error.
Please write
it in the proper way of investing.
You mean this?
I am making so this is the proper way.
If you try to put it before the arrow sign
you will go down.
This is the proper way
show.
This is the property.
All right.
So have you guys to
all of you have to type this code now
if you knew what I mean, this
assume
you are still typing it.
Let me know.
Sorry.
Don't equals use only fast things. Yes.
Actually not only first things.
All of the non primitive that are bytes
lost in this question of strings.
Actually I don't want
I didn't want to show this.
I don't to show this but so
but someone asked this question
and now I am showing this
so is so Maryam it's
because of their student loan believe me
if you
if you think something hard has found.
Okay.
This is not because me. It is because
I wanted to show it actually later.
So you can ignore this part,
this one, this one
or now. Yes.
That's why I don't like that's
why I always want to go step by step.
Okay.
So next looking.
Well, that actually is it easy now
or is it still hard?
Is it easy now?
Somebody who was already scared
before even
even before the class was active.
So you can order that state.
But we will learn that later.
Nice gesture.
They move forward.
So we do the next example.
So let's let's do one more example. So
in your in your testing, you guys have
expected results
and actually that's right.
And then you test, test.
This is based on that.
So if let me use
doubles this time so if you
still are so
expectation are equal to 15.
Okay.
So we are expecting you
to at least 15 hours
each week. Right.
But if you are giving only 2 hours
a week to this course,
what will happen, guys, if we have
actual
if actual hours
are less, then
expected of.
So if you are doing this for
it will be hard.
Oops. Or
really hard for you
as as or in
the you
there
your job
after five
months.
I am closing this
so but I'll I will say guys
if I execute this code line full
line 12 years.
What is wrong with line 12.
No spaces.
Oh okay.
So you mean I will go to the line
pattern right?
So of course will be hard. But you.
And if you are giving more than 15 odds,
then because it will be easy for you
and you will get your job.
Okay.
So this is how if health conditions were,
let me know what you
once you guys have typed this,
we will do another example.
I will tell a lot of examples
that 15 hours
on base story
if I'm not putting don't worry
how about instead of changing the value
of double change the operator. Yes.
If you can also do that
less than double, then you have to reverse
the content of the
if as condition as that.
Otherwise the result would be incorrect.
Right.
So if you use greater than in here,
you should put this line
entirely else
this line inside this
and this line inside
that you now have same.
So you have changed the operator,
you have the change,
the conditions as well.
I try by variable, I stay by variable.
I think some of it is common commonsense.
Actually all of it is a common sense
except in that syntax.
So once we have understood
the syntax, it's very logical
programing languages,
they are very logical things.
What is else meaning?
So Eugene, what does it mean in English?
What does it mean in English means
same in the programing language Java.
If if this condition is true,
do this as notice.
Okay. As to this.
If it is not the case. Yes,
it is not that.
It's just remembering everything.
Yes, you guys have to learn that syntax
first.
I am Groot
or what you guys are talking about.
I don't understand your language, so
let me use
Google translate.
Maybe you are saying Peter is bad.
It means otherwise.
Is Hindi as in
there?
Thank God Google is here to help me
a little java.
So in the previous bad
student was saying in Brazilian
that the teacher is so bad
I don't understand him.
So I googled him in front of all the class
if I was even has thought a single line.
Okay. So I was just telling you.
I was just telling them
that we will be following this approach
and this approach and this is the students
said, I don't understand this digit.
Oh man, I have not even started putting.
So sometimes if you build a perspective
about about a person,
so it takes a lot time
to change their perspective.
So some of their stories
there can be part of them.
It's harder to understand my accent,
why I am getting of in as part
because you have a semicolon on line
number ten days.
I don't know why it happens, so
I need to at least tell the same thing
at least five times.
Still, they're asked to write,
so don't listen and make the same mistake.
So are you guys.
I think you guys are doing this. You are?
Only when I speak for 5 minutes,
you are only grabbing
the content of 2 minutes,
maybe four and 5 minutes.
Right.
And then you have to repeat again
and that you guys missed that.
I can
use this, quote, channel
to turn off and on.
So the best thing you need to write,
if something is not right again,
try turning it off and on.
I am sitting with translator to
so it
means after condition after condition.
Yes. No semicolons, no semicolons.
Semicolon.
We use semicolon when we will
when we end statement.
Okay so this
if condition it's not a statement.
This line is a statement.
This line of the statement.
This condition is not a statement.
So we don't need a semicolon.
Thank you, Mike.
So are we ready for the next example?
Let's let's do one more example.
Okay.
So let's use ten classes.
We move the two packages.
Yes, they can. We will to packages.
So, for example,
let me check if we can do in here
new and package.
So I have created a package inside
another package this one
and if I drag this class
and I drop in here
and now that class
has been moved inside this package.
Okay, so maybe you guys
want to
find out, organize your code
into packages.
For example, let's say
if conditions are okay,
so create a package
inside another package, select
all the conditions.
So if you if you want to find that,
organize your for and then
place all your
if conditions inside this package.
If you if you want, you can do that. So
I am storing everything off
to the end to this package plus three.
It keeps it organized. Yes.
If you want to create further protein,
it is also possible.
All right.
So double
five and let's
try it is 5.993
country.
And That's right.
I don't understand, Alexa.
I don't understand this.
Still
and do how you would not
you means three to choose
the video package
so if
it is in the money
is greater or at least equal to
would be the ultimate price
as I am.
I said okay, okay.
So I am I said not happy
if I execute this code base,
I insert right.
And if I have more money,
even if I have at least 5.99
or chocolate
for you. Yes.
You mean you are doing your tried
order advice.
So if you have understood this simple, if
and if you allow me, we can now
learn the next type of conditions
that has
that can check for more conditions.
So right now
we are only checking two conditions.
Okay, I'm not writing.
Okay. Even
you guys will not be able to focus.
If you are writing,
let me know what's your time type this
We can only print the
print line
in the eighth condition is true. Yes.
Only If it is true,
today is okay tomorrow.
So which class
you guys will be having tomorrow?
I mean, on Tuesday you're testing classes,
right, Manuel? Testing.
They are easy, right?
When we're testing is easy.
So as fan
for now.
Yes, all classes are easy except Java.
So don't say this.
Yeah.
Why is not hard? So
you guys can always check your canvas.
Java. It's not C++. Yes.
If you guys have to learn C or C++.
Oh man, that is way harder than this.
Are you going to be Java instructor?
No, I will be music musical instructor.
I will be teaching.
I will be teaching you how to play guitar.
I am the instructor for upcoming classes.
Yes, I will be the Java instructor.
No, I think he means permanently.
As I began to get that memory of
you also know about, I thought, okay,
but there are no exercises about it.
First condition.
No, no.
And there are so many
excited about if conditions
so if we
will, I hope you
guys don't mind my jokes.
So these conditions, they are called
the conditional statements.
All of these are starting from 25 to 30.
These nested
if y you guys have standard class first
or I think you guys
oh my God, I think you guys were supposed
to learn about this kind of class today.
And I think I have missed that
class.
Most of the class in here,
it's not present
on these slides.
Why you guys have it happens
regarding these kind of class
or this of classes in the next class. Yes.
Tangled I caught by.
You have missed something.
So you will be learning about this 10:00
in the next class.
Not all that.
That's great.
Then you go
back to the previous issue in here.
My favorite movie is
we are going to have your translated into
all you have seen in the
week from get together
the viewers are going to like
have seen this movie or not
actually I was because I was an engineer.
I was in an engineering university.
In the end, they don't have life.
So I didn't watch that many movies.
What engineers cannot last.
Yes, in the next class.
So you can just kind of class.
Where are you from,
if you don't mind asking?
I am from Pakistan.
And you can watch it now.
Yes, now I was able to
actually I am right now
taking three batches.
So ten and batch nine, That's nine.
They have their interviews.
So I will be
the one who will be assisting you
in your interviews.
So they have just graduated
like one month before.
Yes, we are.
And it was 9 minutes left.
All right, guys.
So should I move forward?
There are many Stay.
Our friend from batch
nine just wanted a job.
Yes, I guess 25 students from the batch
have a9a matched
and have got the job
and it's just their third week or so.
I will invite some of the students
from Batch ten just to motivate you.
Just one of you guys.
My you guys will be having these questions
in your mind maybe,
and my spending
and the proper amount of time this course.
I don't understand
hundred percent of the content.
So will I get the job if I only understand
60% or 70%
how much time it takes to get the job?
How much salaries are you guys paid so
you guys can ask all of these questions.
I will invite you to four
students from previous batch.
How hard?
Yes, how hard is getting a job on
how many offers they got,
how many jobs they apply
So guys can all just just
Do you work for the company?
Yes, I am working for a company.
I am also doing freelancing projects
and am doing my research for my master's.
So I am doing a lot of things. Why?
Because I don't know.
I cannot stay idle.
I, I have to do something.
Otherwise I get bored
when I get the job done.
I think not done like just like that.
I think it will take around six months
to to be comfortable with the company,
the culture,
the procedures, the policies and all that.
But in my case, when I got my job
for the first three months,
I was in training.
So I used to watch movies
and then YouTube during my training.
How is it possible to get a job before
completing the course?
It is not possible to get a job before
completing the course.
Oh, you guys mean Batch ten Also,
I meant batch nine.
Oh, okay. Okay. Yes you are.
The students are from batch nine.
Not not batch death, but Yeah.
Some of the students,
they started applying on the jobs
before they completed the course.
And three of them,
they actually got the job.
They were ready and be ready last week.
So because.
Nice. Is it
okay if I take ten more minutes?
Maybe today?
I know it's already like
5 hours class,
but just give me ten more minutes.
So guys,
up till now, we have you.
I am not going to work anymore.
Your brain is all set to programing,
so once you are a programmer,
you can continue programing.
You can sit in the in front of laptops
five, 16 hours, 18 hours.
If It's normal in the life of programmers
to just sit in front of computers
for 16 hours a day or 18 hours a day
actually, then 5 to 6 hours day.
Then they need 5 to 6 hours
to just just get started.
So if it's just just get started,
think 5 to 6 hours
when we will be done with
because do we have any certification?
So you'll get a
you don't need any certification in I.T.
sector.
You don't need a
degree in the certification.
You apply on a job.
They ask you for the interview,
they ask questions.
If you answer those questions, you get.
I don't.
This is the beauty of i.t. Sector guys.
40% of the google employees,
they don't have any degree.
They just know how to do this stuff.
That's it.
None of our students.
This is the 11th batch.
And each batch, at least
a hundred students are there in batch.
So more than 1200 students,
they all got their jobs
without any degree,
without any certifications.
Some of them are from nothing.
Background,
faith, background, different background.
It does not matter in here.
So if you have got past
multiple conditions guys,
if you have got test multiple conditions,
then we can extend the this
if health conditions.
Okay.
So let's say, for example, up till now
we were testing only two conditions.
If this is true, do this
if it is not true.
No, the other part.
Okay.
Now we will do multiple if conditions.
So let's say if I have
a variable
is equal to one, I can say if
B is equal to equal to one
does the
it will be certification help
with finding a job?
No assignment. It is not required.
It will give you an edge,
but it is not required.
Same is
the case would be Java certification. Yes.
If you do it you will have an edge.
But right now, believe me,
there are so many jobs on the market
they don't even take complete interviews.
The if they if they know that you
you are the person who can do the job,
they will just hide it right away.
If we are relocating to another company
comparing
comparing batches, are we doing
okay so far?
Actually, you guys
be how a batch is doing.
I can tell it from the sports channel
if you guys are making a lot of mistakes.
So I will look at sports Channel
after the class and then I will tell you
in the next class.
So if I have compressed
multiple conditions.
So let's say, for example,
I want to check this condition.
If today is equal to equal to one,
I fair money.
If this is not the case,
I check another condition
so I will write ls space
and other if condition ls if
there is equal to equal to two
this time go I will say
it's still there.
If I have to check another condition,
I will say
as if again
it is equal to equal to three.
I see.
Oops.
Expensive benefit.
I can add more conditions as if.
Okay, so more conditions
equal to fourth.
I see.
Firstly
more conditions.
And if is there a shortcut for typing
system brought out
and start of typing the whole thing. Yes.
If you just type this out
you press control and space
and it would automatically be entered
automatically
complete
report.
And if in the end or does not need
be in Java.
Yes we can put it.
I will show you
and the last I can see
wrong date so that if
for one
do you know any other programing language
this and this is in F hash
you're seeing python
and in other programing language we this
and if your child
so present in that Microsoft Excel
what is the language it's
F hash or or we will basic
we use the different visual basics
if we as the
but they have not that much with be
I have worked with six or seven
other programing languages
so that's how it will work. Now.
So Java starts from top to bottom
so us to check
if this condition is 2:00.
If this condition is true,
this line will be executed
and all of the remaining lines
will be ignored.
And we will jump in here. Okay.
If this condition is not true,
Java will be next condition
If it is also not true.
Next condition, next condition.
It will keep on
checking all the condition.
And if none of these conditions are true,
this last condition, this aspart
this will be executed here.
So If
if I said is equal to for work output,
I will go to this.
So this condition is true.
So we get test.
If I put ten,
is there any condition who becomes true?
If I put ten?
So which part will be executed now
be wrong by
so wrong if none of the conditions are
if I put one the first part.
Okay.
So this is how this is the bigger login.
All three false conditions
with multiple conditions.
So if we want to check multiple conditions
for the same variable,
you can use this approach.
If if you guys have any questions
you can ask.
Otherwise,
we will continue the next class from here.
Any homework? Yes, why not?
And definitely a lot of homework.
Let me post.
I guess the exercises are available, but
you guys don't need to do those exercises
they are finding next week.
Once you have learned
about this kind of class,
then you guys should follow those
if health conditions.
But if there are any exercises
which don't require results,
condition, you can solve them.
Now as well. Okay.
But the actual deadline
is in the next week.
Just give me one moment. I will show you
and show
you this clip.
Let me know, guys, if you have questions.
We have only one homework.
Yes, some response and then homework.
So this homework is due next Saturday.
So the nine nine stays the same.
This one I show.
What do you mean by stays the same?
This completely first condition
stays the same.
Only you change the value
from this variable and how replace
so you guys are supposed to complete
first 17
proposed till next week
16 to 17 I guess
is not required of this kind of class.
Yes, that's the homework.
What is the condition of line nine?
So line nine says
that if the value of Daisy equal to one,
if the value of day
is equal to one, then execute
this line.
That's what line nine says.
If if day is equal to equal to one,
if we are storing one entire day one,
then execute this line
that is inside of condition.
That is what is meant
by the first different issue. So
do we have not have enough letter?
I hope you don't mind my my don't mind
my joke.
Are you with us?
It all seems so clear
now if this can also happen
when picture is showing something
all seems simple
and when we try to do it on our own,
then we get so many errors
of the desperate.
I change the day, but they don't change
if front line nine still works.
Yeah.
Can you please show me the screenshot?
Yes. Now you guys can write programs.
So for the name of your friend
in a variable and then type
something funny about your friend
in the condition and the as far.
So this is what I did
when I learned about live conditions.
I build programs out of my friends
next to
you will learn about this kind of classes
so you guys can type something
from your keyboard.
And then based on that input,
your program will differently
than you recommend
some backside for practice writing code.
So unless you have plus you have homework,
you still need another part.
So I shot if I put
day is equal to zero,
then this will be executed.
Not the or this one.
Okay.
Wrong day.
So yes, it's a perfectly fine behavior.
You you are expecting something else.
So because none of the conditions
are true,
that's
why the devil is executing this block.
This else condition.
So let's
just go on Google and type
no practice
forms and then you will see
a very big list of the platforms.
But I don't recommend you
to start practicing in here
because the questions,
they will be harder.
And I don't don't think so.
You will be able to
follow them. But if you can
predict
at least wait 2 to 3 weeks,
then you will be able to solve problems
from these platforms.
If are coming back, then after Professor,
even if muscle comes back,
I think it's only next 2 to 3 weeks.
The last part of Java
I will be teaching you
that.
Can you please
explain the exercise for honorable?
Yes, sure.
So those who want to leave guys,
they can leave.
I will not be showing anything new.
If you guys have any questions
regarding reptiles or anything else,
then you guys can stay here,
take some rest.
So who ask this question
now, and I hope I'm pronouncing your name
correctly.
Noble.
It's noble.
Okay. So it's very simple, right?
So you have to print out
this pattern.
Okay.
So first one star, then to start, Right.
So if there's one simple, like,
for example, if I create
for you putting into one star, okay,
then you write and print statement,
you're able to start.
It's that simple.
Very simple.
And then on the same in the same way,
you have to print out this
first one star, then two stars,
three stars, then to have and then three.
And your test case should pass.
Can you review test 14 on your show?
Any assessment test given to us from.
INTERVIEWER I have a collection
of all the code in test
and all the interview questions
that I will share with you
once you are done with Java.
So don't worry about that.
So Oracle 13
Estimating operations.
I am not I'm not showing this one.
It will take like 15 minutes.
I am out of energy.
Let me read it out.
In this project it will become a magician
and I have a small program
that performs a mathematical magic trick.
It will involve performing
a reflective operation.
Activities are going to be recorded one.
Okay,
so create
my number,
set it equal to any other number.
So don't put zero.
We will refer to my number
as ordinal number.
From now on,
create an indoor variable called step
one equal to the original number,
my number multiplied by itself
and integer.
So you are you guys.
Any issues following these steps
or what is the issue
with this triple
by the way I forgot.
I forgot to say right.
I will be sharing the solutions
of all the ripples as well.
Video.
Okay, so after each week, once
you guys are done doing those ripples,
I will, I will share the expert solution
so you guys can compare your solutions
with my statement statement.
So let's do this, guys, let's do this.
I will share these solutions next week.
But all of the proposals are till 17.
If things still don't make sense,
then we will go through those efforts.
Okay.
Is it good?
Who ask the question? You'll get the
moment.
Or maybe we can do it on the review glass.
Okay. Some of you have already told them.
That's great.
All right, guys, please take some rest.
So if you are stuck on a ripple,
leave it and move to the next one.
Okay?
Don't be too much time on it. Okay.
Once I share the solution so you can
compare it and things don't make sense.
You can ask me in the review glasses.
Actually will solve the repulsive video
during the review class.
If I was thinking
maybe you put you put my face
on top of this guy's face and then say,
Thank you so.
All right, guys, Bye bye.
Take some rest.