All right.
Good morning, guys.
And then we can you guys hear me?
All right.
Good morning.
How is everyone doing this morning?
Early morning in Virginia
and doing good.
Super cold.
We have
all this here right?
Yeah. Feel a little better?
Yeah, that's good. That's good.
Thank you for asking, guys.
Right.
Or I am. Oh, wow. That's good.
I hope you are.
You have an energy now, Mohammed.
All right, That's good.
That's good. Let me ask you guys,
how was the homework?
You will go over some stuff.
You what?
That London.
Okay, you know what?
We'll look into the homework, guys.
But before that, let's do a quick recap
right.
There's already class five.
All right, So, guys, let's talk about
what did the
what did you guys learn yesterday? Do?
Well, yesterday
we looked into the scanner
and we looked into the nets that if right.
So what what can you guys
tell me about the nest of if in
so we seen that nest of eve right.
We said it's Eve inside another Eve Right.
So there is such variation
that it's available.
Right.
In which cases
you might want to go nesting
when you have one condition
that is dependent on another.
Right.
So you want to make sure
that first checkpoint has passed
and then you want to do a further
check, right?
You want to do a more detailed check
right?
Typically. Okay. Yeah.
But those conditions
that kind of like dependable, right.
So the most in that condition
is dependable on that.
Our condition. Right.
Do you have any allergies?
Yes. Okay.
If you have any allergies, let's check
what kind of allergies you have.
But if you don't have any allergies,
I'm not going to go and ask you
what kind of allergies you have.
I'm not going to do any order detail
check.
Right. So we said Eve, right.
You'll be Eve.
And here we have
a bowling ball in condition.
Right in.
Inside, Right inside.
We can have another eve
that will have its own bowling condition.
Right.
And as we said, we can place
Eve either inside,
you look right, or we can do nesting
and place it inside the else walk.
Right.
They'll squawk
then as if condition can have
just eve block
right, Right.
Then our air conditioned
can have this else.
BLOCK Right.
Or our eve statement can have Eve else
Eve and else blocks, right.
So any of those variations,
what we can do, we can do,
we can
look in this
right? And then what are we seeing?
How do we call this Eve
that stars on the line five guys?
I do.
We call this Eve.
This Eve the first eve there this
this first a what we call it in our eve.
Right.
And our our eve
always, always controls our inner eve.
Right. All in.
Only in the condition here will be true.
Only then we will get a chance
to check our most inner right.
And we will organize into nest in one eve.
But of course, we can do nest
in more than one eve.
Right?
So all depend on the condition,
but somewhere you guys can see multiple
Eve's inside.
When it comes to us, to programmers,
to automation,
engineers, this we probably not going
to go more than three.
And most of the time
if you're going to use our nest of
if it will be,
it will be to eve conditions inside.
Right. But can it be more?
Yes, it can be more. I
think that's our nest.
It if in we look yesterday
into the scanner class.
What guys
can you tell me about the scanner glass
because there it's it's a clause in that
dedicated to take input from a user right
so now is the help of the scanner.
We tried to make our program
more interactive,
and with the help of scanner,
we can capture data.
Data. No.
One we look in captured from our keyboard,
right?
Whenever we type in something, then
be able to take it to our program, pick
it up.
Tell me guys, how can I,
how can I create scanner
in? Okay, we will do import, right?
It will come from the import app.
But the line, right, The line,
the AP will come from import
and they will come Java that you
it comes from this packages
and then it will come
from the right import statement
and then
right then the
line that we need to bring the scanner.
Right.
So we'll take it with the scanner
and then in you name.
Right.
And they so here we know that
this is identifies the variable,
this is the type of the variable in
that was something new to us.
Right.
We have to
we have to do we have to use new scanner
and then identify that system therein that
will be taken input from the keyboard.
Right.
And then since there's a different
data available. Right.
Since it's since this is
the user can enter different data and
there's a different data types in Java.
So scanner is going to use different
options, right
is going to use different ways
to capture different type of values.
Right?
So if I want to capture an integer days,
what can a what I'm going to use?
So I'll take the variable, right,
that refers to my scanner
and I'll just say next integer, right,
next integer.
If I want to capture a string this right,
just one string.
What am I going to use?
I'm just going to use next, right?
I'm just going to use next.
If I want to get your boolean dies,
you try it
with the bowling.
It just we're going to be next boolean,
right?
The same thing,
the variable that refers to the spinner.
And then we will use next fully.
Right.
The same thing will be for the double
double next double.
And another one.
I don't know.
Did you guys try to capture one character?
One character, Not the line.
So if you want to capture the character
guys, what do we all do The same thing.
We will refer to the variable.
Then we will go for a next right
and then after next
we will just go char that
at an unspecified zero in here.
Okay?
Zero. Me Yep.
Because so basically what happens is look,
what happens
is this this party you guys learn
when when we are going to use strings,
okay, When we go into long strings,
you guys will understand what it means.
But for now, just think about what
next does, right?
What is the next test?
It captures a string, right?
It captures the string, for example.
Hello. Right.
And then you send Hey,
from this string that you capture,
take eight characters, take one character,
take one character and zero.
It means the very first character
refers.
That's what it means.
Take the character
at which position Position zero,
which identifies as first place can.
Right.
And once again, the scanner right in.
If you want to pick another character,
you'll just have to change this values.
If you want the second one,
you'll go for one.
If you want the third one,
you will go for two.
Right? But
the entire purpose will be to end
their specific character, right?
To enter the specific character.
Okay.
So I know once again,
guys, can we just using
for our learning purposes
are there won't be any
any use in the future
once you start going more into object
oriented concepts of Java.
And of course, definitely we're not
going to use it for our test automation
or not.
You can try, you can try it.
So remember, guys, right now
you're learning a lot of stuff.
So in your time you want to try something,
you guys can go ahead and try again,
but can you catch it early?
You can catch it right?
Okay.
And let's see our homework.
See our homework. Right.
So here now you guys saw that
the homework quiz is to
it is to come.
It is to combine our nested E Right.
And to combine it now with the Skinner.
Right. All this assignment,
you should have it.
Is this Skinner
And actually first assignment.
Let me see this first assignment.
Or you had to capture two numbers, right?
You had to capture two numbers, right?
That's what you guys had to do.
First one, was it easy?
I think first three supposed to be first.
First four, right? First four.
They were easy, right?
So what we what we had to do right.
You had to create a scanner, right.
And then ask user
to enter the loan amount.
And here
you guys could have go for capturing
next double or next integer.
And then we would throw in the
if condition, right?
Then we were throwing the
if condition. Okay
let's just look at one of them.
This out of this three.
Let's look at one of them actually,
for the first one, you guys have
to capture two numbers so we can look
at the first, second, third, third one.
Which one you guys want to look at?
This one is just the conversion.
There is no eve condition.
Let's look at this one or this one
in here.
They're all pretty, pretty
same good spread.
That's the best one.
So today is already New Day,
right?
I teach you that syntax, that
classic.
Right. Plus
homework.
And we will go over the fifth one as well.
This right. So in here. Right.
This is just a scenario, right?
So you already in the representative
you need to ask customer their age.
Right. So now what do we need to do?
We need to capture input from a user
and as we said,
to capture the input from the user.
What do we need?
We need to create a scanner, right?
We need to create a scanner.
And then after we create this scanner,
we can give an instruction, Hey,
what is your H? Right?
And then to capture
that H can you send me a code
just peek
and you'll see
I Right.
So designers have said this scanner,
it lives in different libraries.
So what will it have?
We'll have to import it, right?
You'll have to import it to our class.
Once is get imported.
Now we can use right.
And then once we
once we created,
once we created this scanner.
So this line just gives us
an instruction, right?
What we want the output to be.
So a user knows what to enter. Right.
And then since we're trying to capture
that integer value, right,
so we use it,
we are referring to the variable that
maybe we use in the variable
that refers to our scanner.
Right.
And then using the
next integer option, Right.
Next integer
will allow us to capture an integer value
and then wants to be able to enter
and capture integer value.
We storing it inside this variable, right?
And now once we have the variable, once
we have the value that we placed inside,
now we can do our if condition.
Right.
And now this is our simple Eve statement
that consists of Eve block
and that consists of the else block right.
And as I mentioned,
what do you guys need to do?
Always, always.
When you have your program,
always try to test
that your program works correctly, Right?
In this
in this,
you have to test two options, right?
Where the E block becomes true and
the word else block becomes true, right?
Sure. Yeah. Right across
customer H, Right.
So we will make it 18 oh,
I get the right output.
Yes, we got the right output right.
Then we run in the second time.
What's your age?
My age is 15. Right.
Unfortunately, we can look provided
driver's license is my program works.
Yes, my program works.
So you guys test of your own code
in your code works, right?
I think your code works fine.
Okay, So.
And this was this
this was exactly the same thing.
The only thing in here just to practice
capturing different values.
If you guys wanted to capture a next
double, you could have used an X double.
If some of you also use next integer,
it's also fine.
And then the same thing
you would throw the if else block right.
You will try. Hey eve condition is
list then 200,000.
Then you will have the money.
Otherwise you would reject.
Right?
The first
the first one you guys had to capture
two numbers, right?
So when you captured your numbers,
you needed two variables, right?
So you will call and not
you would use another option.
Scan that next integer, you would capture
the second numbers, second number.
Now, when you have two numbers,
you can easily be either, right?
So all this
first three, four are the same.
This one, the five in the six, right.
So now when you look
at the five and the six right here,
we can look at this
one is what once
we met this
I am what I want you to do this right.
What I want you to do
always, always try to analyze, right.
Always try to analyze the tasks,
the assignment before
you start doing it right.
And that's what you guys guys going to do
in the future.
Right In the future, when we work as a
automation engineers, right?
So you guys already know what is the
what is the user story,
what is the test cases, right?
So you guys will be looking
at the user stories.
Then you will be creating the test cases.
And after that, while training the test
cases, you guys will start analyzing
what kind of automation you will be doing
right before jumping into it.
You guys will be analyzing.
So the same thing right now,
what are we trying to do?
We trying to analyze the task, right?
It's like analyzing the user's story.
Okay, So create a Java program
that will ask if the user
has a credit card or not, Right.
As a credit card or not.
We need to capture the same thing
from one user.
Then you guys will need a scanner. Right?
And then
if user does not have a credit card,
then you will add up if they do have one.
Right. So now only, only right.
You guys have to think, hey,
only and only.
If a user has a credit card, you realize
then what is good balance, right?
But obviously if you don't have a credit
card,
we're not going to ask
for the balance right.
And I see
I see this demo.
You try to capture a Boolean value.
Some of you try to capture a string value.
Some of you guys
try to capture a character value.
All the characters,
all the cards, all are correct.
And then the only will be difference
based on the value like you captured.
Right.
So let's look at the first one.
If you're going to go for a bonus right.
And we said, first we need a scanner.
We already know what's going on in here.
Then we send the instruction
right now in this scenario
and we look at the different scenario.
If you want to capture a string
or if you want to capture a store,
some of you
this capture is single character, right?
So in this case,
we trying to capture a bullet, right?
We're trying to capture a bullet.
So because we know in programing,
how do we say yes or no?
We say we seen it using true or false.
Right. So in here,
a student decided to capture a bullet.
Right.
So now and then once we capture Boolean
that we check
in, hey, if the condition is true, right.
If you do have a credit card.
Right.
Only and only
only when that condition is true,
then I'll execute this block of code.
Right.
So what did I include
in this block of code now?
Because you told me you have a credit
card.
Now, I will ask you,
what is the balance? Right?
And then I will be capturing the balance.
Now, you using
your storing it inside
a double tap of variable, Right.
And here you capture a double tap of that.
Right.
And if the balance is less than thousand,
you're doing this option.
Otherwise you're doing this option. Right?
This option.
So my only suggestion probably for
this quarter will be reminders.
If your condition is already rolling,
if your variable already holds
a Boolean type of value.
Right.
You don't have to say
if condition is true,
because what are you will look in here.
Right.
So this input boolean. Right.
This input boolean will capture either
true.
Right.
So for example, if you enter true
true will be stored inside this box
right now
basically here what you're saying
if true, is equal to true, right.
So you don't really need to say,
hey, if true is really equal to true.
Right. Is true equal. So true.
Yes. Right.
And then if you're doing this comparison
and then what you want to get,
you're going to get true, Right?
So we're saying when our condition is
when our variable holds
a Boolean type of value,
you don't need to say
true, true extension, right?
So here we can just say if condition,
if condition.
Oh, and this case. Right.
In this case, when you enter. True. Right.
You already know.
Okay.
Hey, Eve. Condition holds a true.
Yes, it's true.
You allowed to go inside that
block of code, right?
Then once you go inside, then
you will start checking for a balance.
Capturing the balance,
the value that will be stored in here.
Now, you using inside your eve condition
and coming out with the different options.
Right. So
how many
times if I want to test my code guys,
if I want to test my code,
how many times should I run it?
I want to test that my eve block works.
I want to test that my else block works
inside the Eve.
I have this eve and I have this else in.
I think I think three times, right?
I think three times. Right.
So first let's test that my else
block works right less as of my
you know, you have to remember this.
Okay, If you're using boolean,
then you have to enter boolean.
You have a credit card box.
Okay. Did my else blog that I executed?
Yes. My ls block that executed right now.
Do you have a credit card? I do. Right.
So now because my condition was true
now I've been prompted this question.
Right problem.
And then what's the balance now?
The balance we will enter.
I don't know, 900, right.
To make our eve statement.
Right to make our If block executed.
It is executed.
Yes, it is.
Or I think it should be.
If the balance is right,
the balance is larger.
Right. Okay.
The balance is larger. Right.
Just logically.
So this way
we get the correct logical right.
If the balance is more than 1000,
we want to pay it off immediately.
Right. Let's try again.
You have a credit card?
Yes, I do.
What's the balance?
The balance is 900, right?
900 ls black should get executed.
Right? Go.
You need to spend more right?
Credit cards. Want us to spend more?
Do you have a credit card? Sure.
Now let's test that.
If black works right,
If black works are 2000.
Right? And they go.
So either white and I enter values,
my code works.
Right.
And as you may see,
some of you went for the bowling, right.
Some of you want to to capture yes or no.
Can you do it?
Of course you can do it now, let me ask
you guys, let's look into this code.
But now,
instead of capturing true or false,
instead of capturing true
or false, I want to capture yes or no,
How can I do it?
Guess.
And based on death, we will.
We need to fix our statement. Right?
Okay. Yes. So, no, it's a word.
So we will use it.
We need to capture a string. Right.
Let's go top to the bottom
to fix in our code right up to the bottom.
So first now I'm not capturing boolean.
I need to capture string now. Right.
So now instead of the next boolean,
I will go for next. Right.
And you guys see right away.
Right away what happens in here.
You get in the arrow in here, right?
Because your job is smart.
Your job is smart.
So your job in your Java nodes, hey,
you will be capturing
a string type of value right here.
You expecting to capture a string?
Then why are you trying to store it
inside a bullet?
Right. So right away your java knows.
Oh, okay.
If I'm right, if I'm trying
to capture a string, of course I shoot
stored inside a string type of variable.
Right.
So we will achieve this string in here.
String.
Okay.
So now
why the line 22 complains right now.
Now. Right.
Okay, let me.
Let me see if card equals
they go. Can this in right.
So now when you think, okay,
now my condition is of
which type is a value of the string type.
Now how my EVE statement works,
my issue statement works
only with a bowling condition.
So now from this string,
I need to get a bowling.
Right. So
now it means I have to compare it right?
So now what we will use,
we will use equals.
Right?
And which answer are you expecting?
You expected. Yes. Right.
Expecting. Yes.
And now let's try this. Let's try.
Do you have a credit card?
Yes. What is the balance on your credit
card? 300.
They go right.
So whichever option you get selected,
as long as you
put the right logic
in there, you exercise will work right.
Oh, that's another
that's another good option.
Dice. Right.
When we talk about the case
sensitivity, Right.
Case sensitivity.
Right now, what we look at
in this scenario
when we enter it.
Yes, right.
We in 30 years and it was stored
inside this variable right.
So now here, technically,
what are we saying?
Hey, is this small. Yes.
Equals to another small. Yes. Right.
And of course, condition was true.
That's why
then I was prompt to this question.
To this question Why?
Because I was entering my East
block right.
So now let's see what happens.
Let's see what happens
if I'm going to enter big.
Yes, right.
And you put the breakpoint in here
so you guys will see where my for will go.
We have a credit card.
I, I entered just
the first password case right.
Well,
here is the beauty also when we do in
when we doing the debugging right.
So now on the here and you guys
will see this window of variables.
Right.
You have a window variables
if you don't have it.
Remember this to bring anything you will
just type in here variables, right?
So this way
you can see their values, right?
No, in here.
Variable input. Right.
It refers to our scanner.
Now the value of the condition.
Right.
The value of the condition is big.
Yes. Right.
So now you compare and hey, is this the.
Yes. Yes.
We close to this? Yes.
What do you guys think
is the true or false?
So condition is false because everything
inside this string is matter.
Right?
So now your code book will go right away
into that spot, Right?
It will go to the else point.
So the same thing when you look right now,
a syntax is correct.
Right? There is no issues with my syntax.
But then logically
I should not be getting this output right.
Logically,
I should be prompt and ask all this
questions
that are there inside of Eve block.
Right. So now how do we fix this? Right?
So now when you comparing two strings,
right, when you compare it to strings,
if you want to ignore the case in right.
You saying, hey,
I don't care if you enter me big. Yes.
Or if you enter me small. Yes.
Because yes is what? Yes is yes. Right.
Whether you entered big or or small.
So there's an option from our string.
Or we can use
we can use option that says equals
is in our case.
Right.
So it means hey, regardless
if you enter me, big is small.
Yes, I don't care.
I will just compare the actual values.
Right.
I will ignore the keys and
and then compare those string values.
Right now, let's try.
You have a credit card?
I'm entering big. Yes.
Write them entering big. Yes. Right.
So now when I'm entering, big is right.
So in here, what is the condition?
What is the value of My variable?
Condition is big.
Yes. Right.
So now in here
you have your big years, right?
And then you say saying, hey, us
ignore, ignore any creation
and check is yes is equal to this.
And then this is
because we are ignoring the case.
Now the condition will become true.
We're going inside.
So now we will ask in
what is the balance on the card?
Right.
The next step we are expecting
for a balance and let's enter.
It's 3000, right?
So now we capture the balance.
You guys will see
right now balance also right
in you.
That is 3000.
But because now
the conversion happened again, right?
The conversion happened again.
You enter 3000, you stored it inside
the double tap of value.
That's why there is a got added.
And now we take in our
if condition, right.
In this case this if condition
became truly going inside this
if block execute
any block and exit in all my
if statements faith
why didn't the letter look
like my did you did you try
did you try is the big true
I want you to try it first
how can we are like yes, yes, yes.
All right.
Even if you're going to it, it's
it's depen Alexander.
Look,
if you want to enter in the spaces, right.
So let's see what happens.
We have a credit card. Yes. Yes. Right.
Which
will remember what is the option.
Let's does option next.
What it will take?
It will take only f first valid
before this space.
So it will ignore everything else
that you're going to have.
Okay.
Will ignore everything else that you have.
But then later
it will give you some issue.
Might give you some issue here. Okay.
But if you if you looked into
but if you looked into the condition,
you see what it did, it took only one.
Yes. Okay. It took only one.
So now you going you will get in
some error a little bit later.
Right.
You will get something
that are a little bit later.
So that's why this whenever you are,
if you want to capture only one value,
make sure you go for a next E, okay,
So let me explain it to you guys.
I'll just explain it
very briefly not to confuse you.
Right.
So let me try to dig.
So you write different notes or
or if you
want to do this,
if you want to try different answers.
Right.
If you want to enter different answers,
for example yes.
Yeah. Yep.
Then it means you will have to test
this condition for multiple values
you want to check is the condition
equals to use or condition equals to you
or condition equals two. Yep.
Whatever the values you want. Right.
You will have to put them
all in one statement.
Okay.
You will have to change them
all in one statement.
And now this is
will be our today's topic, guys.
They will be our today's topic.
Hey what if I want to test
multiple condition in the same statement?
Okay.
So for that
we need to use something different
because when you look in here goes right
We say, hey,
if condition equals two,
yes we test in only one condition.
But the news question was, Hey,
what if I want to test another condition?
I want to say
if my condition will be equal to.
Yeah.
And then maybe more and more and more.
Right.
So now we have not learned this option
yet, but we will be learning it today.
How can we test two
or more condition in one statement?
Okay.
Because so far, everywhere you look,
guys, everywhere you look, how many
how many condition between
testing inside one
if statement you test in one condition.
Here inside this
if statement you tested one condition.
But can you test to a more? Yes, you can.
After today's topic.
After today's topic, we can do it
also on the choice
between boolean versus string.
Okay.
So maybe in this scenario, this is will be
this is very optional for you, right?
This is depend how you structuring
your program in the real test scenario.
Of course would go for a string. Right.
And we will provide
multiple multiple options.
Right.
But in our scenario we could have use
boolean we could of use string.
Right.
And also I saw some of you guys,
you just use the use
that I tried
to capture one single character.
So I would go probably for a boolean
or I would go for next,
I would go for capturing strings.
So all thing in here, guys, was
the goal, right?
We always
look at the goal of the exercise.
What are we trying to practice?
This practice would as long as you use
scanner right
it means you are practicing Skinner
and as long as you understand
that you have to go for nesting.
Right? That was the whole purpose.
What whether you use Boolean,
whether you next.
That was, that was up to you.
Basic either or.
We saw in both variation either
or gives us the right output
right in
any questions?
Good questions.
Okay. I hope it's good. Right.
And this is was very similar guess right
this is was very similar.
So in here
we had to capture the years.
Right.
And we have to capture
as salary years.
Right. And eligible in salary. Right.
Yeah.
You guys can.
Right.
So we said hey only only right only
and only if you your work
for more than five five years
then we will consider a bonus.
Right.
And then we will consider a bonus. Right.
But if you as a work less than five
years, we're not looking into the bonus.
Right.
So the same thing to options
you need in Right.
You needed this Skinner
right. Is the help of Skinner.
You need you to capture a year
right You need to get the you
and you needed to capture the salary
and then we will have to go
for the next part, right?
We won't have to go for a nested part.
Okay.
One of what's for the homework, right?
That was the homework. Okay,
so this class goes to this class
we will still continuously use in our
if statements.
We will still continuously use
in our skinner.
Right.
And we will use a different variation of
if statement, whether it will be nested,
whether it will be just using
if else blocks.
Right. So we'll continue to use it.
All of that.
The only thing today
what we will try to look right
this scenario that we just look right now.
Right. Okay.
What if I want to test
multiple conditions, right.
Multi pole conditions in one statement.
Right. In one statement.
I'm not talking about
testing it in separate statements.
Right.
So in here, for example, right now
where we added
English class three, right, Right.
In here, when you look into it,
you are testing multiple conditions,
right?
Multiple conditions.
But you test in them inside
different statements, right?
You check.
And hey, if these equals to one,
you check in inside your if right here.
If these equals to two,
you check in inside it else if right
and then these equals strategic
and inside another else
if you are still testing in one condition
but do you have multiple,
multiple conditions.
But in one statement only one write
only one condition in one statement.
So you know, hey,
what if there would be scenario?
For example, I want to see
if the day is Saturday or Sunday.
Right.
Hey, if the days six or seven,
I have a Java class, right.
Okay.
If the day is I don't know.
The day is Tuesday and Wednesday.
I have no class. Right.
So now what do you want to do?
Just you want to do test two conditions
and you want to combine them
under one statement, right?
In order for us to do that,
Java have something that
all logical operators.
Okay,
so logical all platonist
right.
So why do we use logical methods? Right?
Always remember this.
Try to understand why.
Right.
We'll try to understand
why do we need a if statement one
We want to check the condition.
Why do you want to have
that ls block inside
your even when you want to provide
the otherwise conditions, right?
Why do you want to go for it?
If else if when you want to test
multiple conditions right.
Why do you want to go for nested
when you have one condition
has a dependency on the other? Right.
Or we are saying what do we want to do?
A further check
based on the true condition.
Right. Okay.
Do we take any medication? Yes, I do.
Okay, now let's do the further chip.
So now when do we go for a logical
upgrade?
Is right. So many things in there.
Logical operators we use when we want
when we want to test two or more.
Two or more. Right.
It doesn't have to be
just a two or more condition
In one statement.
Right.
Hey, if the days equals two, Saturday
or day is equal to Sunday,
then to have a Java class, right?
Our test in either days equals to Saturday
or the days equals to Sunday.
I want you just to condition
in once statement in one statement.
So in this case
we need to go for logical operators.
Okay.
How many logical operators are there guys?
Okay, so what do we have?
We have the logical end, right?
We have the logical or
or we have the logical not right.
Not so not.
It will be reverse in that condition.
We will start looking one by one case,
Right?
Logical.
Where do you go?
And we will specify using 2% sign.
Right? You want emphasis.
So now think of this when you test two
or more conditions,
there's a different variations we can get.
Right?
So think on one condition on the left.
One condition on the right. Right.
So now, because we do test
a bowling values, right,
we do take a bool invalid,
How many bowling type of values?
Bowling. How many variations bowling has
bowling?
So only two.
Right? You can be true or false.
So now when we test
two condition is right.
So first of all,
first condition on the left can be true
and condition on the right can be true.
Right then we will have one condition.
On the left can be true and the condition
on the right and replace right.
Then we will switch them.
Condition on the left will be false
and oops,
end condition on the right will be true
or we can have that.
Both condition on the left
and on the right can be false.
Right?
Both and false.
Right.
So when we check in two conditions
using and our prayer, right.
So when we check in the condition,
use and operator
you and will give you a true value only
and only
when both conditions are true, it.
So in here you will get one
big picture everywhere else.
Your end can
you and
operator if you going to check
one condition is true
and another condition is false
and then you will get big false in here.
If one condition is false, the other one
is truth, you still going to get false.
And of course, if both condition false,
if condition on the left is false
and the condition on the right is false,
then you will get one big false
thing. Right.
So now let's look in an example.
Let's look in an example, for example.
Right.
I'm going to take two variables
that will be called
by example, right?
Pick one variable.
Right. Let's take one variable.
So I will ask you. Right.
We're not going to scan that.
What we will take variable about
if you enjoy the class.
Right. Or let's
see if you understand our Java class.
Right. So I will say boolean
and this then.
Yeah. Right. Understand Java.
So as we said,
boolean can have only two options.
Tool, right.
For example, do you understand Java? This
I hope you guys do.
And remember in the class
you don't have to get all hundred percent
as long as you get it.
7675, 80.
Then you just
you'll just have to practice more.
All right.
For example, if I want to write it,
if I want to write this simple statement,
right.
If you understand Java,
then then good job.
If you don't understand it, then
maybe you need to put more efforts right?
Or if you understand,
we'll just say that is awesome, right?
That is awesome.
For example, now
I'll say Eve and then I'll say, Understand
spell right.
If you understand, you will just say,
This is awesome.
That is awesome, right?
Otherwise, if you don't understand,
then probably I would tell you that
you guys need to put a little more
emphasis right,
because we usually end
right before you.
If you do understand, then I do.
Guys believe you practiced a lot.
Or maybe this is just
naturally coming to you, right?
So in here, I'll just say I would say
you probably need to study more, to
study more.
Right.
So in here, this is very easy for you
now, right, guys?
You just one condition, right?
And based on the true statement,
your eve block will get executing right?
So now what
if I want to add another variable right?
I want to add another boolean.
Enjoy. Right.
And so I enjoy Java. So now
whether
you are in this day and in,
but maybe you're not enjoying,
but maybe you do understand,
but maybe you don't enjoy it, right?
Or maybe you don't understand,
but you still enjoy.
Could be different variations, right?
So now the best.
The best probably, if you guys understand
and then do it right.
But so now, hey,
you know what I want to say?
Hey, if you understand Java
and enjoy Java at the same time, right?
If you understand and enjoy, that's
probably the best combination, right?
So now it means what I want to do.
I want to test multiple condition.
Hey, if you understand
and you if you enjoy.
Right.
So now if I'm just going
to put two statements like that,
Java will come
and Joe will say, Hey, hold on, hold on.
I have true in here
and a half truth in here.
So now I have two conditions in there
also.
Now, if you trying to test two
or more condition
inside our one statement, right then
Java says, you know,
now I'm giving you an and operator.
And so now as soon as you going to enter
in, now our error is gone.
So now you have condition
that is on the left
and you have a condition on the right.
Right.
So in this variation,
what we're looking
hey, what is the value of understanding?
What is the value of understand?
The value of understand is true, true.
What is the value of enjoy?
Sure. Right.
So now you have to true condition
and what am I using?
Amusing and operate.
So true and true.
What is true and true.
Going to going to give me
is going to give me now
what I'm going to get.
I'm going when I come by this to condition
using the end operator,
I'm going to get one big truth.
So now when my condition is true,
can I go inside
a book?
One condition is true. Yes.
I'm given the green light.
My condition is passed now.
I will go.
And what I'm going to do, I'm
going to execute this statement, Right?
I'm going to give you this statement
right.
That is awesome.
There you go. I got the output
right.
What I'll let's say
what could be the other variation?
Maybe you understand.
You understand?
Yes. You understand what
maybe you don't enjoy, right?
Maybe you don't enjoy it.
Maybe you don't enjoy it now. Right.
So now let's check.
Okay? Sure.
Now let's see what it will be.
What is the value of understand Java?
Understand is true, right?
Understand is true.
What is the value of enjoying Java?
Enjoy. Java is false.
Now which operator I'm using
amusing the end
operator True and false.
True and false.
What is going to give me?
It's going to give me a false right.
So now what I'm going to get I'm
going to get a big false.
Now can I go inside
if my Boolean condition is false?
No, my access is declined.
So now your code will go to the else part.
Right?
So now the way the operator works,
in order for that,
in order for the end operator, in order
for the upward to give you a big true,
you need both conditions to be true,
if you will have the variation,
true, false, or for example,
false and true,
you are still going to get a false right.
Or for example, now maybe you two.
So let's run this one.
You probably need to study more.
Well, because this condition was true,
this false, and then you get false.
Now, if you going to change to false,
right.
We said, hey, if one condition is false
and another condition is false,
obviously you're going to get false.
If you work with one
but one it's considered to be,
it's a little bit different.
Operator So for the logical
the logical upgrade is this
we are going to use to importance.
Okay.
So now let's look into another example.
This let's look into another example.
Okay.
So for example, this, right,
For example, when we have a numbers, right
when we have a numbers, for example,
right.
For example, we can add this.
Skinner
So let's do this this weekend as the user.
Let's do this assignment. Now
we can say ask the user
to enter a number right
now based on the entry number, right?
Based on the entry number and the number
three
based on the third number.
Right.
We will find
the number is it number
is small,
medium or large, right.
Or extra large, whatever.
So now what is my definition?
What is my definition of small, medium
and large?
Right.
So I'm going to say, hey, even number
it number is is
between one and ten one instance, right?
Or it means my number
has to be greater than one,
but less than ten right at the same time.
So I'm going to say this number is small.
If I'm going to say if number is
between 11 and 100,
it means my number has to be smaller
or it has to be larger than 11.
But at the same time, it has to be
it has to be smaller than 100.
I'm going to say
this is the medium number, right?
And then we can have this number is
between, let's say, one or one in
1000.
Then we going to say,
this is the large number, right?
This is the large number.
And can we do more?
If number is more than right,
This number is more than
than 1001.
Right.
We're going to see the number is extra,
extra large, right.
Okay. So that is my scenario, right?
That is missing there. Okay.
So now we do analyze.
We do analyze
right before we start quoting.
You do analyze.
So I want
you ask a user to enter a number, right?
I want to ask the user to enter number.
What are we going to use this?
We are going to use a scanner, right?
With the help of scanner,
we will be capturing integer value.
Now, you have multiple conditions, right?
You have multiple conditions.
So when you want to test
multiple conditions, we will go for
if else if else if blocks right.
But now we will look okay within one
if statement.
Right within one within one e block
I want to test you conditions.
I want to test
that my number is greater than one
and at the same time is less than ten.
So it means within one statement
I have to test two or more conditions.
Now you have to think, okay, no,
I will have to use
I will have to use a logical operator.
Right.
So once you have your plan,
then we can start doing it right.
So let's create our scanner, guys.
Equal review
scanner, and then
you see this
morning, importing scanner, right?
Once it's important.
Now let's ask let's given instructions
right.
You can say please enter
any number.
Any number. Right.
This is fine within there. Any number.
Okay.
So now we will start. Okay.
I want to capture a number.
So how am I going to capture this
number?
Integer number.
So how are we going to capture?
So we will take the variable
that refers to our scanner number.
We trying to capture the number next
right?
Next integer.
Okay.
So did
we ask a user to enter the number? Yes.
We asked the user to enter the number.
We captured the number.
Yes, we are capturing the number. Okay.
So now once we capture,
then what do we have?
We have to throw the information, right?
We have to throw this condition.
And here I have multiple FS, Right?
Multiple is
how do I test multiple conditions?
I'll go for a
block.
Right.
But now within this even else
block, I have to test multiple permission.
Now what else say hey, if mum.
So what?
My condition, my first condition
number has to be greater than one
and at the same time, number
has to be less than ten right
in is just a variable.
This is just a variable. Right.
So now what
are we trying to do within one?
If we then one is statement.
I am testing two condition. Okay.
If the number is greater than one
and the number
to less than ten
to test two more conditions.
If you want to test them together,
then Java gives us
a logical operator stuff.
Right?
So hey, in this condition is true
and this condition is true,
So we're going to say it's all
paginated
means is small, but it is just so.
And then we will say the number
that you captured is small.
Do I have another set of conditions?
Yes, I do. Right.
Get me out of your course.
The point we can include one.
We can include one. Right?
We include one.
Do I have another condition to test?
Yes, I do.
How do we add
How do we test more conditions?
What do I need to add now?
Right now, we'll go for it.
Else you'll have more conditions to test.
I do have more condition to test.
Okay. What's your condition now?
My number. Right.
If you want to include you here, guys,
just decide up. Right.
If you want to include the ten
or you don't want to include the ten.
So yeah, maybe I included ten.
So now if the number between 11 and 100,
so now my number has to be greater
equal than 11 and then the same time,
less or equal than 100.
Right?
I am test
in another condition,
but I want to test two conditions.
Right. Two conditions.
So now what I'm going to use,
Can't we use more than one?
No. Again,
I should remember
so we can test two or more condition.
Two or more condition.
I say what's what's
why do you want us to stop
while the train is going?
It's raining as well.
So what exactly?
You are lost then It
goes.
No, right now, guys,
we're just listing out multiple conditions
to which that multiple conditions
we use in the elseif.
The What are we trying to learn today?
We trying to learn how to test two
or more conditions in one state.
Right.
In one state now to test one condition.
Second condition.
Can that have one more conditions?
Yes, I can add one more conditions,
but to test two or more condition
inside one statement, we're using that
and upgrade right now.
Do I have to test
another set of condition?
Yes, I do. To this.
And then the set of condition
be going for it else.
Even now within this else, if again,
what I'm doing
just in one condition
and second condition right now,
if this condition will be matched,
then we're going to see
that number is one.
Then there is also
that's more medium, medium.
Do I have another conditions to test?
Yes, I do. Okay.
If you have another condition that does
go for LC. LC.
Now within this else
if how many conditions you test in.
I am just in one and two.
Right. Okay.
Then you only try
the logical operator. Right.
So now you will see hey, if number is
more equal
than one one
and a
number has to be smaller
or equal than 1000.
Right then you've been here.
If this condition will be match,
our number will be large.
Right. For
one plus.
Okay.
You will have more conditions to test
this.
Do have more conditions to test.
Okay, so now you guys tell me,
do you guys want to go for else black
or do you want to go for it else if work?
Well, let's go.
What else
else we're going to say?
You want to say the number is
extra large, right?
It is extra.
But we want that extra large, right?
So we saying, hey, is any of this?
And then we said, hey,
if number will be greater
than all of those,
then we'll go for extra lunch.
Right.
And we will limit this.
We will leave it then,
then we will test our code.
Remember, at first,
even when you don't think
of all the variation, it's fine.
How are you going to start in and chicken
your code?
You will start doing it only only by
providing different different values.
Right?
And we will test on this.
So now to test my code, I need to
make sure that my if block was correctly,
if you want to test
this block, you want to test this block
and we want to test this block.
And then
and then we will do other things right,
because eventually we will have to think
from different sides.
Right? But at first,
we will look into all positive
cases, right into all positive
to test my code.
And then we will try
to look in some other stuff.
Right.
We'll check groupers,
but for now, just be cool.
Any time you want to test the all the,
all the positive scenarios,
not like in terms of the positive numbers
but positive possible scenarios,
you we'll call it the happy part
list lists, our happy pass scenarios.
It means something that will fit
within this range, something that will fit
within this range or within this range.
Okay, guys,
let us let us finish with this example.
And then if we have to do more,
we will do more.
Okay.
So we define
as new.
What?
Isn't there any number I want to end now?
I want to just this French way.
Let me insert ten
right.
So now let's see what happens. Right?
So now holds the value of ten, right?
Holds the value of ten.
So ten we enter it, right?
Ten we enter it
and we store it inside this variable.
Now all we're doing, we're just providing
different conditions for this variable.
Right now. Let's check.
Is the number larger than one?
Is a condition true or wholes case
condition is true.
Is the number less than ten
less or equal?
Right? Less or equal.
Look at the operator. True.
So now we're using end, true and true.
What is going to give me
going to give me true?
Can I go inside
and then go inside my block? Now
I can go inside, right?
Because now my condition has passed.
Now what?
I'm going to go
I'm going to go inside my block
and I'm going to execute this statement
saying that the ten is small.
What happens after I execute line 34?
Guess what happens after execute line 34.
So where am I will go?
Well, my code will go and check
other conditions or my code exists
even if statement
it will end right. Why?
Because you're outside of the entire
if statement
that consist of different,
only one gets executed.
Right?
So after line 34 it is.
It's your eve statement
and that's it, right?
You will stop.
That's right.
So condition became true
now executing the line 34
and then exit in the main method.
Right. Okay
now let's check another condition.
Please enter any number.
Let's end there. 77. Right.
Okay.
Now what will happen
Leathered if right if else.
If it will go one by one by one
by one to check every condition
is the number greater than one
condition Troubles
false.
Is it smaller than ten?
Oh, no, no, no.
This is the number.
Larger than one is the condition
to a false number larger than one.
I entered 77
and this condition is true.
You confuse me. This condition is true.
What about this one?
Is the number less than ten
Now we have in false.
Now we are using an operator.
Choosing false.
What is going to give me?
You will give me one big false, right?
So now we'll get false.
When I have false, can I enter the block?
No. Right.
So now what happens after this
when the condition is false?
What happens next?
Now it will go in, check another condition
like why lie to write this?
Okay.
That condition was false. That's fine.
I'll go check this condition.
Now let's check.
This condition is number
more than 11 days.
Which condition is true?
Is it less than 100?
True.
I'm using an operator.
I'm going to get one bit true, right?
I'm going to get one. Be true.
So now when I get my true, now what I can
do, I can go inside the block.
I will execute this statement right?
As soon as I give you this statement,
then your quote will jump out of your one
right?
Oh, that condition was false.
He was not able to enter.
Now check in this condition.
Condition is true
and the rest will ignored.
Right?
Not try to enter. Enter any number.
Let's enter 9000.
Right. So you figures now
out of the if statement.
Right.
So your call will go
and checks every single condition
until it finds its true right
here we have Hey is number more than one?
Yes number is more than one.
Condition is true but here is false right
it will be skip K is number more than 11.
Yes, condition is true,
but number is not less than 100.
The condition is right.
Okay.
Is number is more than one on
one condition is true.
Hey is number is less than 1000.
No condition is false in now
because everywhere we use in an operator.
Right.
In order for the end to give me a true
in order for the end to give me a true
what conditions must be true
everywhere else, it will give me false.
Right.
So now when your quote goes check, this
condition equals
it went to check this condition.
Then in the one to check this condition.
Now, when none of this condition
give me the true where our code will go.
Guys.
All good. We'll go.
All good.
We'll jump into the Elkhorn
and it will execute the state
checks one by one, goes to the else
go right.
So now what we did
as we look into the happy scenario, right?
We tried to test the happy password.
The number could fit either here
or either here, either here either here.
Now, we got to think outside of the box
right now.
We better think
a little bit outside of the box.
Yep. That's.
What are we going to try?
Marieme can, you please try to send
your code in the support channel.
Right.
So now let's try this year. Right?
So you see, now
you start thinking differently.
Why isn't there any number? Zero.
So now where are you?
Well, what are this thing?
Which block
you will go to the else block. Why?
Because this condition
will give you false.
This condition will give you false.
This condition will give you false
when none of the condition
you a true, your code
automatically goes
to the counterpart, right?
It will automatically go to the false
false.
It goes to the LS. Right.
So now we're saying
zero is extra large number.
So now when you look at the syntax,
once again,
this our is statement is perfect, right?
Our if statement is perfect,
there's no syntactical issues.
But now what we have
we have a logical right.
We made a logical mistake, right?
So now how can we.
But let me ask you guys, how can I fix it
all? We can do this.
We can do here instead of the end.
There is a multiple ways
how we fix of this.
There's a multiple ways how we can fix it.
The easiest one that I can think of,
we can instead of the ls.
Let's add elseif.
And any time you use an ls,
if you have to provide the condition.
What's your condition? This.
What's my condition?
In which case
you want to see this output? Yes.
In which case, as we
we want to give the output
for our extra large more.
Right?
LS even number is more
or equal than or one of 1001.
Right.
So of Eve right now let's Eve.
If you enter 9000 the way we did
it will go for extra large.
So now what will happen
now? What
will happen to us if I enter zero?
What if I If I enter zero?
What will happen?
What thing will happen? Right.
Nothing will happen.
If you want something to happen,
then we can add that else block
or Or what are we can do?
Guys?
Now, if you don't get out of this,
it will still get out.
Look, let's let's let's enter zero right?
And then number zero.
So because it's that ls
if it's like a log,
they will go check every single condition.
And because right now we don't have
that elsewhere, nothing will get executed.
Nothing will get executed.
So you're stuck, right?
You're stuck.
So now. Right.
We can add it at the very beginning.
Yes. If you want to guess, we can add it
to the very beginning right now.
At the very beginning.
Before we go to that.
Greater than one. Right.
Why don't we add one if statement. Right.
We can write another one.
So now what are we can say?
Hey, Eve's right.
Eve number is less
than one will know what it is.
We'll that work for zero
and for negative numbers.
It will work, right?
We can say, hey,
even number is less than one.
What do we can say? Right?
And of course, here
we will have to continue.
We can say, see, it's all right.
We can say see. So
number is
zero or negative, write zero a negative.
And then instead of here,
we will just continue
using this right for next week.
I can be done this week. Right.
So now when you think
so, any time, right.
Any time you enter
zero it will fall on there
is this if block
now if you enter
now if you enter number it's
also will fit under here
only normally only it will go this way
if the number will be
greater than one right.
This is always, always those things.
But how we were able to add that option
only normally,
only when we test our code with multiple,
multiple values.
Right? Yeah.
And once again, guys, look,
we tested multiple conditions
to test multiple condition.
We use an F else if right reason
if else if.
Now the only difference
which we see this right here within this
if you test in one condition,
we already know how to do it
within the next.
LC If you wanted to test one condition
and second condition at the same time.
Right.
So in one statement, Right.
So and then if you want to combine two
or more condition,
that's why we use the end operator
here, here and here.
In this particular scenario,
in this particular scenario,
we also had only one condition.
So there's no need for an
or any other operator.
Right.
And then again, this is what you do
after you fix your code,
then you try to run recheck
multiple options, right.
With any number zero,
they go number zero or negative.
Please enter any number -900.
They go number is zero or negative.
Please enter any number.
Let's enter 8000 variable. Right.
It is extra large.
So you're the one those who can define
whether you put the right logic
or why are you did not put it right.
Logic
little break.
Yes, guys anything I need
a little breaks for me to do.
So let me leave this
and let me
let me break it
in two classes
so this way this can keep it absolute
for all of you.
If course,
you have both examples on your screen.
So now you guys can take it.
And meanwhile, guys, let's take a break
until 1145, right?
Okay.
All right.
We are back.
Right back.
Welcome back.
I hope you guys get some recharge, right?
Okay.
So today, guys,
we are looking our logical operators.
Yep, I did start recording.
Okay,
We're looking into the logical operators.
Right. So why do we need logical?
Yeah, well, whenever we want to test
two or more conditions
in one, right.
So for now,
we'll look at the logical end, right?
For now we'll look at the logical end.
And once again,
this cannot be more conditions.
Yes, you can add.
More condition if you want.
But when it comes to the end.
Operator, in order for the end operator
to give us a true,
all the conditions must have true
value, right?
Whether it's true, whether it's free
or whether it's more than that.
Right. Okay.
So any questions for the logical end?
Any questions for a logical end
And you guys will be
given assignments to you
guys will be given that sentence.
And probably once we look into the.
All right, now,
you'll start making sense.
Right?
So now
another operator that we have
to test two or more conditions, right?
Another operator
that we have, it's a logical or
we identify using two pipelines.
Right.
So the same thing exact the same scenario
we can have.
True. Right.
We looking in the 2
to 2 scenarios, to a true
rig, what are we going to have?
We going to have
exactly the same thing.
But let me see this.
The outputs will be different, right?
Because right now,
instead of the logical
and we are going to have a logical or
logical or logical or okay
the way
the logical or works, right,
as long as you have one true condition,
as long as you have
one true condition, logical
or will view as is a true right.
So in here true or true
will give us a true, so true or false,
it still will give me true one
because at least you have one condition
that is true for so true
also, we'll give it true
and the logical or we'll give you false
only only when the both conditions are.
So the difference in here you may see
for the logical end to give you true.
Both conditions must be true
anywhere else you.
See at least one false.
It gives you false. Right?
We'll use you false.
Let's do pipelines. Yep. Two pipelines.
The way the logical world works,
the way the logical What all works in
give you true conditions
As long one condition is true.
Right?
And we will look right
now, guys, into example, right? Why?
I mean, this is how this logic
has been developed, right?
This is how those operators work, right?
So now let's look in an example. Right?
Let's look in an example.
For example, in
the previous
assignment that we've done in here, right?
The previous assignment
that we've done here.
Right.
So you guys had a question, right?
You guys had a question, right.
Hey, orders for this credit card, right?
So when we have
when we asked for the credit card
and we wanted to give an answer work
and you guys asked, hey,
what if the answer will be yes, Yep, yeah,
whatever the answer is, right?
How can we combine it? Right.
So let me copy this.
Guess I'm not going to go for this, that,
but I'm going to copy this.
Right. I'm going to copy this.
So now we will look,
what if the variation will be?
Yes, yep, yep.
Or what are whatever
that things will be. Right. So let's take
what the
and I'll give it
I'll just rename in the answer
the exercise that we had
where we wanted to have a credit card
right when you want
if you have a credit card.
And here we try to capture the answer.
Right.
So we did this scenario
here, even the answer right in the answer.
Well now I will I will not ignore
the cases because it will become too many.
I'll just say you said, hey,
the answer will be
equals
equals two years.
Right.
And we say, hey, look, there
could be different variations, right?
What if the user will say
enter equals to Yep.
Right. For example.
Or what The answer will be?
Answer will be equals.
And so
equals
equals to yes.
Right.
For example. Right.
This is just a sample. So now same thing.
What are we looking right now in here?
We wanted to say
please tell me about bank.
Right. Something like this.
We need the balance
on the
switch.
So now what do we have inside?
Want each statement.
You to check multiple conditions.
You want to check?
Hey, the answer could be the years
or the answer could be or the answer.
It could be yes.
So now it means you test
in more than one condition.
To test more than one condition,
we have to go for a logical operator.
Right.
So now.
In this case,
I am going to use the or operator
and we going to see what if we will add.
But for now, let's look at four or
I'm going to see.
Right.
So as soon as I add my logical operators,
my job is happy.
It means syntax is correct.
So it just do a multiple conditions.
You need to add logical or operator
or logical.
Right? Okay.
So now let's see how it will work. Right?
Let's see.
Do we have a credit card?
I'm going to say yes, right?
I want to say yes.
So now in here you have
I will have to make a decision.
Joe will have to make a decision.
So now Java will start
thinking in our condition.
Right
now, this element is this condition
in is yes equals to yes.
Just condition is true.
Okay.
This condition, is it true or false?
Yes. Equals to you
know. Yes.
Is this award the same as this words,
this condition, true or false
was false, right?
Yes. Is equal to years,
but yes is not the same is.
Yep. Right.
So condition is here is false.
What about here?
Is the condition true or false?
The mission is false.
But now we look
and we look into the operator, right?
We're saying, Hey, true or false, Right.
And here we're also using the logical
or now true or false,
what is going to give us?
We're using like e will give us one
be true right here.
It will give us one. Be true.
And now again, you're saying true or false
because of the logical
or now at the end
you going to get one big true, right?
So when my condition is true, Jim,
I go inside.
Yeah.
So no, all the control
conditions will be evaluated at the end.
We use as in the logical
or we going to get a
we're going to get a true condition
and now we're saying please
tell me the balance. Right.
So now the same thing. Let me see.
Do you have a credit card?
I'm going to say you right?
So no, the same thing.
We will check the condition here.
Condition is false because.
Yep. Is not the same as Yes. Right.
This condition will be true
and this condition will be false.
Right.
So now on the left side you have false.
On the right, true. You will get a true.
And then you have true and you have false
because of the logical operator,
you are going to get a true right.
You're going to get a true sense.
Please tell me the balance right in.
For example,
that's when we're going to write.
Do you have a credit card? No.
Right.
Shouldn't the conditions will
this will start checking, right?
It will say, hey, no, what is it
hey, is answer is equals three is no.
Condition is false here.
Condition is false
here, condition is false.
So your false your false
false or false will give us one big false.
And then again for false
or false will give us a false right.
So now all the conditions will be false.
Now, you cannot go inside the
if statements.
Look what you see right now, guys.
The difference. Right.
The difference between having a logical
and right
and the logical or for the logical end
to give us a true condition.
Both statements
must be must have true value
only and
only if the condition on the left
has true and condition on
the right has true,
then my condition become true.
Right?
Well, now you guys compare industry
and if you're going to enter. Yep.
Of course, none.
None of this will be much.
If you want to add
one more condition, then sure,
you can go ahead and add an extra.
You add extra as many as your task
requires.
Okay.
And the way we're looking at the logical
or or the logical
or at least one condition can be true
all others can be false.
And what is the logical upgrade
it will give me
the logical operator will give me a true
right.
You need to know it's import in this.
Yeah. All when it comes to the one,
when it comes to this,
when it comes to that one,
you can just check one.
But let me add one thing and honestly full
statement.
Statement
and maybe let me statement
and of the quotes now, because
let me put in the default and let me
support this.
Our exercise in there was to ask
if you don't have a credit card,
would you like to get a credit card?
Would you like to apply?
Do you want to get a
right?
So now.
All right, it's important, guys.
That's what I want to show.
But it's important
not to confuse with an on or
I mean, not like to confuse,
but to understand
in which scenario to go for
and in which to not to go for it.
All right.
So let's say, for example, if instead of
the war, I'm going to use end
and what do this thing will be,
the output.
What do you guys think will be the output?
If I'm going to enter. Yes.
So I enter it.
Yes. My answer is yes.
Where do this thing my code will go.
I don't forget this.
I added the LS block.
I know that those block.
So I added ls black
guys and I added the line 23.
So now let's do this. Always,
always. Right.
So now we think logically, logically
and so
is equals two. Yes.
This is a condition, Troels
is Yes, equals two. Yep.
What about this condition?
All right.
You don't have to check anything for this.
You don't have to check anything
for it. Why?
Because right now
you're using your end operator.
So now, in order for the end
to give you a true,
both conditions must be true now.
Because condition is true
and the other condition is false.
You're going to get a false
when bulling condition is false.
Can you go inside that you book?
So what happens now?
Automatically you will jump to that.
Automatically
you will jump to the L statement right?
Automatically.
Even though you should ask me for this.
Right?
Even though you ask me for this.
So my output right now is not correct.
So this is why in this particular case
we needed to use
or also guys when comes to.
All right, so always think of it.
Let me ask you,
the current the current variable, right.
The current,
how many values your variable can hold,
How many values?
Only one Your variable can not have
at the same type at the same time.
Right?
This variable can not hold. Yes.
Not a whole. Yep.
Not a whole. Yeah.
And all of that stuff. Right.
One variable if you want to it
all these different things.
Right.
It's like here if you use in an operator
what you want to say,
you technically say, Hey,
I want my variable to,
have the value. Yes.
And at the same time
I want my variable to have the value yolk.
I want my value to have year.
Is it possible?
No, it's not possible
because you have a single variable.
Single variable
can have only one single value.
Okay.
That's what we have.
We have this option right now, right?
If you want to add more, more options,
you can list them out.
You can list demand, all possible options
that you want, that you want.
You think. Right.
So in this case, logical and will give us
a logical right, logical pair.
So here we'll use or here.
That's how we are, right,
Alexia this how are of here
if the answer is equals to you.
So you just add in another condition
and to combine two condition
you need to use logical.
Operator In this case we said
which logical operator will make sense,
logical or logical
is then your option to reassign.
And when you use end or like,
what do we mean by reassign? Is
because
we can go for equals ignore case.
I just didn't want the lines
to be too longest, that's all.
But of course the best way
will be to go for equals ignores case.
I just.
I just did not use it guys,
because this line will become right
that's all.
But of course equals
ignore case will be the best choice.
I just wanted to show you.
So this way, guys, it's easier
to look for you.
Network.
Michael, can you please like
when you present it in the support
channel?
I do.
We do get the answer,
but because we were using a wrong operator
right now, if you going to say, Yep.
But if you using a logical
or then we will get the correct output.
Right?
So your execution of this statement
will depend on
what kind of operator you use.
And in order for you to know
which operator to use,
you have to understand this table, right?
Or the order statement to give you true.
You want at least one condition
to be true, right?
So this way, let's say first time,
if you go and you enter.
Yep. Right. If you're going to enter. Yep.
And this will be stored
inside this answer.
Right.
So first condition,
it will give you false.
Right.
While this condition
will give you true right.
When you have false or true
because of the logical operator,
we are going to get one be true.
But before.
But before what we did, we said, hey,
what if instead of the or
I'm going to use end now,
the end will give you a different output
when one condition is false
and another condition is true logical.
An operator always gives us a false right.
And when the condition is false
for the eve statement,
you cannot go inside like you good
and say, Let's look at one more example.
Let's look at the one more example
because
logical for them, right?
The example
that also was telling you. Right.
For example. Right.
For example, when I want you there,
we just want to see, for example, right.
You want to say, hey,
we'll take our days of the week, right?
You'll take our or we can bring
the scanner if you want to bring this.
Okay.
Can be reassigned Variables, yes
or not inside.
After we check the condition
if you to perform
some operations
of changing the values of the variables.
Yes you can.
And we will look probably later today.
We'll look into those things. Okay.
So for example. Right.
So word we will ask.
Okay, this one,
we can use a scanner as user
to enter
to these days, to these
B Right.
And now I want to say right, I want to say
Eve Bay is Monday, right?
These Monday or these Friday, Right.
What Do you guys
have you guys have no class, right.
If your days Tuesday or
Wednesday
Wednesday were the
one day what do you guys have
man all question how by the way
how's the mental classes are going
those mental
okay Interesting.
Good. Fine.
Okay.
I think this week
you guys to have two more classes, but
it does not mean that your SDLC process
or the mental process have finished.
We will continue.
I did those concepts.
Once we start going into the automation,
then you guys will have your user stories
there.
Again, in the test cases,
all all those things will continuously
practiced in more.
Once you start learning automation, start.
Okay, we'll be starting is
Do you know anything guys?
Just make sure
you keep practicing this with JIRA
because you guys will be using it
for later projects as well.
Okay.
So then you guys have Saturday
or Sunday, right?
Saturday. Awesome.
And a
lot of theory or.
Yeah, there is a lot of theories
when it comes to, especially
when you do the mental testing
and there's a lot of theory.
Then you guys have class
as most definitely
make sure you practice before the class.
So this way
you'll refresh your memory right?
Okay. It right,
always analyze it right.
And here
it's another piece and another right.
So the same thing we need to ask the user
today's date, we going to use a scanner.
We need to capture the day, right?
We will need to capture the
and then we will have to test
multiple conditions.
We want to say if these Monday or Tuesday.
Right.
Or if these Tuesday or Wednesday,
if this Saturday or Sunday,
we will be testing multiple conditions.
Right. To test multiple conditions.
You guys will tell me what do we need to
want?
So we will get our scanner and
then right.
We have system that
right there
and then we will say,
please enter today's date right.
They right or whatever.
Right.
Then how are we going to capture that
they get then how are we going to capture
the day
will be
inside is spring day
and how are we going to capture it?
Will you scan that next?
Right. And that's next.
And now, once you have the variable,
you guys can throw your
if conditions to test multiple conditions,
you go for that.
If else if now within one statement,
you test in two or more conditions.
So you will need to add
your logical operator
so you guys can go ahead and complete it
and then you guys can send the code.
Okay.
I just want you to finish
the this, this test. It
you guys type in
your you are mostly done
for the authorities.
Let me I copy one of your could
let me formatted it in
three
right so whenever you capture the day
right whenever you capture the day
now you check in.
Hey, if your days equals to Monday
or the value of the day
could be Friday if any of this. Right.
If it's Monday or Friday,
then there is no class, right?
Then there's no clause
else.
If you have another condition. Right.
You want to check in these Tuesday
or your days Wednesday.
Then you said you guys have mental class.
Another condition right here.
What are you doing?
You check in multiple conditions
using your else if statement right
within your else ease you test in that.
Hey, what if this condition is true
or this condition is true.
Right?
And then when we go for debugging guys,
right.
Let's go for debugging or
please enter today's day,
today's Saturday,
the Saturday.
Right.
So now what? We'll start happening right?
The way the evil it works.
It's a like a letter Eve right
your java will go one
by one and check condition in every block.
Right?
And now we static
and hey is day equals to Monday?
Nope. Condition is false.
Is day is equals to Friday.
No condition is false.
False or false will give us false. Right.
What way we're going
and we're going to go one more time.
We see.
Right.
So here we said conditional is false
and condition was false. Why?
Because the date currently is what?
The date currently is, is a
right then if this condition was false.
Right.
Your Geragos checks another block right
now, it checks another block.
He is the day equals that usually
means again false.
Okay is the name equals to Wednesday
conditions again false
using the all operator or operator.
Right and here he is
the day equals to Saturday.
Yes, these equals to Saturday
we are going to get true in here.
It is the day equals to Sunday
we're going to get false any right
or false.
It will give us one true condition.
Right. Will give us one true condition.
And when the condition is true,
we can go inside the block of code.
Right.
Then this statement will be executed.
And then your Java will exist.
Your entire
right.
And then you bargain once again.
Right? This was false. This is false.
Now, this will become true.
Your java will go inside
and then the rest of the code
will be ignored
and the rest of the group will be ignored.
What is the difference between equals?
N equals ignore keys.
So now if you enter small Tuesday
or if you enter Tuesday in all caps,
Java will ignore the case
and what it will compare
the actual down can does it do
in the same thing in here?
Right.
We could not go for it and right
We could not go for our end.
Right. Why?
Because for example,
if I'm going to enter, please
enter O
let's say
for example, it will be Monday, right?
Eve you would use the end operator Right.
So Monday, right.
Will give you the true
and then Friday will give you the false.
But because of the end operator
you will get one false
and then your exercise one B right, right.
Why should we hope we have
we don't have to have a rule entry.
This is like copy the code days.
This is just for this scenario.
For example. Right.
If you want choose, for example,
if somebody is going to
please enter today's date, I don't know.
I'm going to enter something wrong. Right?
I'm going to enter something wrong.
Then your Java will just execute this out.
Do you have to have it?
No, you don't have to have it.
But this way we just try to show that,
hey, you know what?
The wrong input, right?
Or we can say invalidate is into something
like that, right?
Do you have to have it?
No, you don't have to
have to remember else either.
Else is a very, very optional block.
Right But here we just added
to show the message to use it.
Right. Hey, you did the wrong output.
That's why I did not show you
what class you have right for class.
You have.
So this is what our logical order
and this is was our logical.
And the same thing in here.
Describe the same thing in here.
It's important not to get confused, right?
It's important
to know where to use the right output.
And if some of the things are confused
right now, you can easily,
easily days will understand
which operator you need by providing
and by test in your own code.
Right.
For example, let's look at this one
and then I'll give you the task is
let's look at this assignment
right when we wanted to check the number,
when we wanted to say, Hey,
the number is small, medium or large,
think going this what would have happened
now, Eve instead of the end?
I would specify all and I would specify or
and I would specify or write.
And now while running
my code, I would enter.
While running my code, I would enter
900 our 10th or 900.
So I would expect to see that
my number is large.
But because I did the role
of a logical operator, what to do?
This thing will be my
what do you guys think will be my output?
So change from
and I change it to or where do this
thing will be my output
so it will go to the 26, right?
Why not go to the 26?
Because here is 900 larger than one.
Yes, condition is true.
Hey, is the number less than ten
condition is false.
But because of using the rule operator,
your main condition will become true
and your code will execute this statement.
Right?
Instead of having is large,
that's what you should be expecting it.
Right.
But if you if instead of the end
you would use
all you will get that mistake right here.
That's where it will interact
and it will tell you that 900 is small
and everything else will be ignored.
Right. What is this thing?
Will it let's let me enter 1 million
or whatever.
What is it? 10,000?
Where? Oops.
Why is still still in me?
Small
Because this statement.
So now you can enter 1,001,010 million
because of the rule Operator
This condition always and remember you in
three will be more than one.
And then wrongly,
this statement will be executed.
Right? So that's why it's important.
And if at first side you feel confused,
which one to use just right, you call this
and try to use different values.
Okay. Now.
Oh, there you go. Now. Correct.
Right.
Okay.
So let me give you the
first two or three task.
Let me see.
So I think you guys already
saw the slides, right?
The slides weren't can last, right?
This is the same table.
And let me give this test first
and then we'll look at the logical
table and I'll paste this in the
course announcement.
And maybe let me add
one more task for you.
This, or maybe I'll give you two years
of homework
figure, which does
because it is only two tasks in there.
Okay, let's want to give you
I give you four more minutes.
All right.
Let me ask you all,
so for the first task, right
from the user to enter person's height,
you knew that
you would have to go for Skinner.
Let me ask you guys,
which operator did you use
in here?
Logical end.
Right. Logical.
And you were capturing
if you get your integer value, some of you
double probably integer will be
will be more suitable here. Right.
And then in here
you wanted to test two conditions, right.
You wanted to check that the height. Yes.
You enter it more than 60
and in the same time a less than 72.
Right.
In this case
you guys one for using and operator.
Right.
So okay this as this test actually
could be done two different ways.
Okay. So solid to ask. Okay.
So which which operator did you guys use
is or operator?
Okay.
Or okay, can you guys show me your code
because I've seen
I've seen people can do it
different, different ways.
Okay.
So this way you guys will see it as well
because of this one.
Let me see this.
And the second one, they go, right.
So let me show you.
So right now,
you guys share in the current.
I'm sure you guys
seen that it can be done
different, different way.
Right.
So let me see.
Skinner
was right.
So when we have an Skinner,
we ask in the day, then
you guys maybe captured it.
They use it
because they exercise is numbers.
Maybe some of you captures an integer
some or you could
capture is a strange right different ways.
But in this case
we went for a integer, right?
And now we're saying, hey,
that they could be equal
to one, two or three or four or five.
Right?
Because you could they can have
different values at different moments.
Right.
Okay. For a moment.
So it was a weekday
as if the day is six or seven.
It's a weekend.
Otherwise we're just saying it's invalid.
Then, of course, guess what do you do?
You just run right.
You always execute your code.
Today's day one, right
now your
Java will come and check the conditions.
Right?
This one will be true.
This one will be false.
And then false. And then false.
And then false. Right.
But you have one true,
and you have the other operator.
So this condition will give you one
be true, right?
And then you are allowed to go
and inside the statement will be executed.
Right.
So this statement will be true
for all the values anywhere.
If enter one, two, three, four or five.
Right.
So all the way you'll find then
for example, if you going to enter six.
Right.
If you're going to enter six. Right.
All this conditions will be false alls.
False. False. Right.
So when you in false and all the others
will give you false,
so then you'll go check this condition.
This condition will become true,
this will be false,
and this will give you the correct output.
Right.
And then as the last option
is the last option,
if you're going to enter anything invalid,
you want to enter ten
all forces will be here,
All forces will be here.
So your code will go to the part, Right?
So it works in the end, right?
It works in here.
So everything is correct. So in this case,
one for you is in and use in or operates.
But I saw some of you,
you guys did it differently right?
Some of you
you guys went in and used the end up way.
Right.
So let me copy let me copy this
in this one.
Oh well
remember, this is in programing.
Everything can be done
that leads to different types.
Okay.
So this is
this is another example. Right.
The same thing using Skinner doctrine.
The they first reported
exactly the same. Right?
Exactly the same.
But then for the if condition
that person
decided to use a different operator
now instead of chicken
the equality operator when for a greater
or less right, greater,
equal or less one equal.
So now we see hey Eve there weekday
that you end 30 will be larger than one
and at the same time less than five.
I'll tell you that it's a weekday.
Otherwise
It will be greater or equal than six
or and at the same time smaller
than seven.
It's a weekday. Right.
And what's this?
Let's tested
mentally, this right. Let's say
I'm going to enter one.
Right. I'm going to enter one now.
One as we said,
will be stored inside this variable.
And now we chicken.
Hey, is one larger
or greater than one condition?
12 false days
or one year?
Quote. Right. So condition is true.
He is
is the winner
may is less or equal to five.
Is it true or false?
It's also true so now true and true.
What it will give you.
It will be give you one true.
Then your statement will go right.
And the same thing,
whether you're going to enter two,
three, four, all the way to five, right.
Going to enter
five K is five larger than one.
Yes. Condition is true, K is five.
Less or equal to five.
Condition is true. Right.
That's work for all of those statements.
Now let's say you're going to enter
six right.
The same thing
here will be false. You
going even have to check everything else
because you have the end right.
As soon as you have one false,
your condition will be given six.
Then your statement will go check
the next set of conditions.
Hey, is a big day more equals to six? Yes.
Condition is true.
Is it less or equal than seven years?
So week date will work right here.
Should be with it.
It's a weekend
for people.
It will work any time.
If you want to enter ten. Right.
If you're going to enter ten here.
Hey, is ten more than one up?
So here will be true.
Here is the ten less than five condition.
It will be false because you it
and operator you will get a false right.
Hey is there more than six
Condition is true.
Eight is the weekday
less than seven condition false.
Right. And operator will give a false.
So then your call will go inside
the ls one.
So you're going to see
different operators,
different relational operators,
and because of different
relational operators.
Now here a person
use a different logical operator to write
both assignments
gives me the right output.
Both assignments have a right lot,
so you will see
what is the benefit
of when you will share in your code.
When you get share in your homework,
and what is the practice to
the practice when you do the other days?
So this way you can pick somebody else
brain
and also
try to think on different ways, right?
And by looking at others you list
can also see that oh well this assignments
could have been done
in different ways, right?
All right.
The largest number,
the largest number should be easy, guys.
Write the largest numbers would be easy.
Let me see. Largest mortgage
transactions.
Not really.
Well, that's when you start
thinking of different. That.
That's actually a good point.
Okay, that's good.
That's good. Okay.
We will look at small.
Okay.
So write
scanner write asking for three numbers
and capturing them in the form of double
values.
That's fine.
Write to that's fine.
Then we go in the happy path.
Just going happy back. Right.
Maybe we should have say
and are three different numbers.
Right.
But of course user can behave differently.
But for now, just happy, right?
Why do we comparing three numbers right
when we compared the numbers.
So a happy pair scenario
we check in that number one
could be larger than number two
and at the same time
it should be larger than number three.
Then number becomes the largest number.
Right?
Then we say, hey, if number two, larger
than number three and at the same time,
number two is larger than number one,
then two is the largest, right?
And then you do just all these conditions,
right within their numbers,
11, 12, 13.
They go 13 is the largest. Right?
Then you enter 1211.
The first one is the largest number.
Right.
And let's take the 111 1210.
So in the happy scenario, it works, right?
What do we mean?
What do I mean by happy path?
Right by Happy Party needs All
numbers are different, right?
So now the easiest start coming
when you want to enter three
the same numbers, ten,
ten, ten, right.
So then I put something on equal.
Please enter three numbers.
Ten and ten.
Oh, there's no output right?
There's no output.
So what do we want to see
when the numbers are equal.
Right.
When all the numbers equal to each other.
We want to say numbers are equal, right?
There is no largest number.
All numbers are equal. Right?
So then whenever you start
thinking of those very
because all you do is you add the same,
you add more conditions,
you add more conditions, or then once
you add that condition, then you start
think of the scenario, Hey, what is the
first two number will be the same right?
Then once you start of thinking
more and more options,
then you guys will start adding those,
right?
So now if none of the things will be much
right, we can we can add another one else
if we are lucky,
we can say else is now one.
Actually,
maybe I would put it as a first part.
This is better.
So first let's eliminate that.
The numbers not equal. Right.
And I'll show you different ways
how it can be actually.
Right. Let me add anything I want to say.
Hey, Eve, actually, we can use the next
ending here that we can say, hey,
it's no one
equals two and
now one equals to number three, right?
So we want to say, hey,
if the numbers are just the equal, right,
then we want to add the statement, right
then we want to see the numbers are equal.
Once numbers are equal, Right.
So if the numbers are equal,
do you guys want to do the comparison
or you don't want to check
which? One is the largest.
If the numbers are equal,
you do check with No,
But if the numbers are equal,
you don't want to check
which one is the largest.
No need. Right.
So there is a multiple ways
it can be done.
This if you saying, hey,
I want to check that all in.
Only when I want to check
that the number is the largest
only and only when I deal
with not equal numbers.
Right.
So what are we can do, guys,
to make it more complicated, right.
What? We can do this.
We can add the ls block
and only know only inside that ls block.
Do this. Just
order this thing
here.
Right here.
What are we going to see here?
And then we can look at different
variations right?
It can get more and more complicated.
Now, I was saying, Hey, if those numbers
are equal, right, those numbers are equal.
I'll just say they're equal
when I want to check
for different conditions only in
only when the numbers are not equal.
Right. When the numbers are not equal.
So as as I'm going to enter
what I intend in there.
Ten, ten, ten.
Right.
So this statement will become true because
this will be true and this will be true.
Right?
They will give me one, be true
and then this will get executed.
LS black will get it.
You can then. MILANI Yes, it can be done.
Can then be thrown
as a very first statement.
Yes, it can be thrown as a very,
very fair statement.
There's a different variations there.
So no, the more
so, but let's say.
But if you're going to enter guys
ten, ten and ten.
Right.
So now ten, ten and 12, it does shows me
that the 12 is the largest.
Right.
I wanted to find out that is the largest
if you're going to enter to a 12
and then the ten, it's okay.
Now it's a good one.
So let's see why there was no output
when I entered 1212 and ten, because
every time you just will have to test
the more options you start thing,
probably the more else
if statements you will look right.
So now let me enter this before
this left me and they're all equal.
And then we'll repeat this scenario then.
Okay.
It works when all equal, it works when
when you are small and
the biggest is the largest.
But now we saw that it does not work
when this 12, 12 and ten does not work.
Right.
It does not work.
Know we can think why
it does not work. Right?
So what we entered, we entered in here 12
we enter it here 12 and enter it ten.
Right
now we say Hey is the number one
equals two.
Number two,
this condition was true, right?
Because 12 is equal to 12, but number one
was not equals to number three.
This was false. Right.
So our if statement was ignored.
So our court when inside the block.
Right. You went inside the ls one.
So inside the LS blockage.
The comparison here is number one
larger than number right.
It was basic saying is the 12 larger
than 12 This give me false,
give me false.
I don't even have to check the second one
because of the end operator.
Right then it one next again.
Now it says hey, is the number two larger
than the number three?
12 is larger than is the 12
larger than ten years condition is true.
He is the number two larger
than number one.
12 is not larger.
The Number one, this gave me false.
So again in here I was not able to enter.
Then when inside the ls if part we check
and he is the number
three larger
than the number two condition was false.
And now it did not go inside right again.
So how did this thing
the easiest way to fix? No.
Or one? No, no, no.
Because the order one worked. The other
one works.
How can we go for
it. So we need to add
that we can add
one of the equality operators
or we cannot some of the else
if statements in the other.
Yes, we can add case.
But to eliminate this scenario
right where we say is the most issue comes
when you have two numbers
that are the same
and they are the largest, right?
So they may give us why don't we try
to enter the equal sign in here?
Why don't we try to enter the equal
or larger or equal?
Right. So let's say
larger or equal, Right.
Why don't you or equal now, let's see.
Let's say right.
So when I'm adding larger or equal, Right
when I'm adding larger or equal,
now let's say what's going to happen.
I have 1212 in the ten right now.
Hey, is number one
larger or equal than number two?
Yes. Condition will be true, right?
Is number one
larger than the number three?
Yes. Condition is true. Right.
So now it tells me now one, but
it does identify the largest, right.
It does identify the largest
thing, 12 plus
people identifies the largest.
Right.
And then you guys start adding more
when you add all of them, you we can try.
Let's see,
what if I'm going to enter 12 and then ten
and then once again, no output.
Again output.
Then you start thinking,
okay, where is it?
Had to have gone.
I have now one and three that were equal.
Right.
And then you guys just thought do you can,
you guys can just add this
probably one of these equality signs there
or there all you do you guys you tried
you test it
and then by testing it multiple times,
you guys will be able to do one
that we'll be able to define.
So you have two.
So you have number one
equals to number two, you have them to.
It was number three
and probably number three equals two.
No one probably.
So only right with this
one. And
I know it works right.
Changing the line between two or
but if I'm going to change the line
15 two.
All right okay
so first let's let's in here
what I did I, I equality one
number one is equal to number two
when them two could be equal
to number three and when them three
could be equals to no one, right.
When then they could be equal to one.
So now any scenario I draw
first to largest
and then ten, it was fallen in here.
Now I'm entering 12, ten and number one.
And number two
is the large number number one.
And number three are
the letters is still identified right now.
They let me see. Okay.
So what will happen is if I'll enter equal
in or in here, what will happen is
what will happen if I
enter or in here.
So in this particular scenario,
I'm going to enter 12, ten and 12.
What are you saying will be my output?
Yeah, it will tell me that. Equal right.
So number one is 12, Number two is ten.
Number three is 12. Right now?
Hey, is number one equals to number two,
no condition will be false.
Okay.
But number one is equal with the number
three condition
will true because of this Operator. Right.
This statement will get executed, right.
So now it won't show me the write up.
Okay.
So now in here we have to keep it as a
given.
And good point is with point this on.
Okay, let me use
or that wants me to run it all in 312.
Well, all right. Numbers are equal.
They're not equal.
Right.
Logically, that's not the correct output.
That's not correct.
The numbers are equal.
So in here, we will keep it as a step.
Okay. Right.
And you guys see, probably at first
I was not able to capture that either.
Right.
But how I was able to think
and add more statements
by to by thinking of different ways
and by providing
after that more and more conditions.
Right.
So on two
equals two, three.
You mean in here.
Yeah, in here.
It doesn't it need this.
If now one will be equal to two it's
automatically right.
It's automatically will mean in here
that number two is equal to number three.
Right.
And could be
there's another way to fix it. Yes.
Then there could be another way
to do it as well.
But as long as you guys will come up
to the right logic, the right output,
that's what's more important.
Okay, good, good, good thinking.
That's really, really good thinking.
As we're
we are trying to become tested right
then when it comes to testers,
in order to become a good tester,
we have to think of different,
different possibilities. Right.
And if you guys still have some questions
in here, you guys can try to do it
at home,
try to do different, different ways
and then see that
there's a possibility to do it either way.
Right? I also will give you guys,
I'll give you this assignment.
You'll find the largest number
as a homework,
but I will add some restrictions.
Three grade.
That will be your homework to do it.
Okay, this in all the code.
Remember, guys,
all the code is available on canvas.
So after the class, please, please
make sure you guys always go over your
over over the assignments
and always please
make sure you guys look at those code
before our next class.
Now that things are starting,
adding more and more.
Right.
So your knowledge will start
getting increased.
The more practice needs to be done.
And because you guys see we are more
our speed is slowly, slowly increasing.
Right?
So you have to make sure
there's your studying.
So this you don't fall behind.
Okay?
Okay.
Alright guys,
is this clear for the three numbers?
Okay.
I hope it's good. I hope it's to keep
so the break is before the break
because it will be short.
One examples. Okay.
So before the break,
we're going to at the logical,
not logical.
Not logical, not
where we
you will be using the exclamation mark.
Okay.
So what is the logical not what it does
it reverse
and mission reversing condition, right
now, when we think of
what do we think of the condition?
Right. So remember this.
When we work with the condition,
we are saying, hey,
our condition can be either true, right?
Or either either either true or false.
Right. True or false.
So what does it mean?
Okay, What does it mean?
So if it means
if your condition will be true
with then not operating,
we can reverse it to false.
And if your condition is false with
the note operator, we can turn it to true.
Right.
So let me show you. See
me. So, for example, right.
Really in
full right
now if I'm going to try to print
both right.
So you know the output, right?
You'll show me the true
what happened because the value
that are placed, the boot was true.
Right.
So now what we can use,
we can use a not operator.
So now if I'm going to use the not
and it's always added
before the condition that it's
always operated before a condition.
So what is the not operator will do it
basically say not true.
What is not true?
What is the opposite of not true?
Now your true will get converted
to the false.
Right now
what they see it will show me false right
or right.
This we will take boolean.
You don't know right?
Make it false and then
right.
It's false.
Well,
if you're going to try to you
of course it will you false.
Right.
But now as soon as you going to add
the note operator,
what I will do, you will change your false
you will change it to a true right.
You will change it to short.
So that's all it does.
This did not operate.
It's what it does make.
What is in use for the real world,
for example.
Right.
So whenever we do in the coding,
right, we'll never be doing the coding
then we want to do something.
What I want to say, I want to say,
hey, let's take a simple example, right?
Let's take a simple example.
Right now is a
I know it's sunny or whatever.
Let me take one variable boolean.
Let me take it is rain, right?
Variable is right.
For example, there's no rain.
Rain or if there's a rain does not matter.
Right.
So now when I want to have a condition
right, I want to have a condition.
If there is no rain,
If there is no rain, I'll go for a walk.
Right.
I want to see if there is
no I'll go for a walk.
There is no other conditions
I want You have
I would want to have otherwise
my strictly condition.
If there is no rain, I'll go for a walk.
Right.
So now how will you do this exercise?
Then you will say, Hey,
if there is no rain right, you will say.
You will say is rain.
Right?
No, you
you want to see if there is no rain.
If there's no rain,
then what do you will do?
You want to say I want to go for a walk.
I will go
or what?
I will go for a walk.
Right?
You don't want to have
the l'espoir, right?
You don't want to have that elsewhere,
but you want to say, Hey,
if there's rain, only then I'll do
certain action, right?
I'll do certain action.
So now let's see what I will do right now.
I said, Hey, holy moly,
if there is no rain.
So what is the value of rain?
The value of rain is true.
Now here you will have it for
then use in the not operator.
Your condition will get converted
to the false right
and then. Hey,
hey if the condition is false,
you cannot enter inside your program.
Want to be finished? There's no else part.
There's no other way. Right.
So now in this speech there be any output.
Okay. To holes comes from here,
right? That's.
But nothing comes right now.
As soon as you enter it, you falls right
now, what will happen?
Hey, the value of is rain is false, right?
The value of rain is false. Right.
The value of rain is false.
Now you have a not operator.
Your false will get changed to true.
And then once the condition is true,
you're able to execute it.
Right. We were able to execute.
You know, it says I will go for a walk.
I will go for a walk.
Right.
For example.
Right. For example.
And let me try to give you the example
from our automation.
Right. From our automation,
for example, like, for example,
when doing the automation, right,
when doing the automation,
we'll be going on the browsers, right?
We will be going on the browsers.
Now, for example,
when you navigate to the browser, right,
you to make sure that there's only one
login button, right?
There is only one login button.
So now if there will be two login buttons,
right there, all let's say for example,
you want to click on the one
only only login button, right?
All for example,
you don't want to click on some specific.
So what you will say, hey,
if the value of this link or if the value
if this button not equal to something,
only then I'll perform some action, right?
Only then I perform some action only now
only those two links are not equal, right?
Only.
Only the text on those links
is not equal to each other.
Only then I will click on the first link
and then I'll click on the second.
Right.
But if the links will be having the same
text, your code will get confused.
Then.
Then then probably there is some error on,
on the on the application.
Right.
So you want to perform action.
What do you want to perform?
The click action only only the text on
those links is not equal.
If it's not equal, then
then I will perform
some action
which I give username and password.
Yes, you can say hey when I'm going to ask
right?
Only normally right when you guys
when you this
trying to create your account.
Right.
When you trying to create a account and
you trying to enter I don't know password.
Right.
So then your valid password will be all in
only if it's not equal to username.
Right.
In which case password is that only
if it's not equal to username.
Right.
So there will be
some scenarios and probably this
once we start going more into the machine,
it will start making more sense.
But for now, what I want you to on
this thing is I want you to understand
what is the mode operator does right?
What is the not apparatus?
Okay, let's take
one more example
or second one more example.
Right, right.
I don't know.
Let me think of example this,
but we think of the example.
Right?
Okay.
Let's take let's take our
the username and password, for example.
We will have string username,
write string username, and for example,
the username will be
test, username will be test.
Right. It right.
So now we know that on our whenever
we try to create
create a password,
we have the warning right?
It's always a hey your password cannot be
the same as the username right.
Your password cannot be the same username.
You know what you want to say, right?
You want to say only lonely, right?
Online only username.
Actually let
let me add another string password.
Like string password.
Right.
Then for example, I'm
going to add for example for now also test
right now I want to say right now
I want to say only, only if username
equals right and equals to your password.
Right.
For now me just password
or I can just type the word right.
So now this will check for equality.
But what I want to say,
I want you to say all in.
Only when a user name
is not equal to password.
Right.
So now what I want to do,
I want to reverse this condition,
to reverse this condition, I will add that
exclamation mark only more.
Only when usernames are username
is not equal.
So your password
then I can say I am accepting.
I don't know.
I'm accepting your
doing this and doing this.
And you say What's to happen?
So now your username is a test, right?
Hey, is test equals to test
condition in here will give me true right
then I'm using logical not right
so now a true will be turned to the false.
Now you cannot go inside.
You cannot go inside but a morning you're
ready.
Let me read you plug in in here
you will see.
Does one go
here?
Right.
What is the username?
Username in test?
What is the password?
I entered for example.
Also test.
Right now
I'm saying hey only only is user name
which test equals to password.
And then I'm saying not
only only do they not equal only
then I will accept your password.
Right.
I'm not providing
any other match conditions.
So now you could go. So.
So now all in.
Only if I know
now. Only know me right now.
If you will check.
Hey, the username which is test
K is the test equals to password.
No condition will be false
now because I'm using the note operator.
Right.
So now my false using
not operator will turn into the true.
So now one condition is true.
I can inside
and now I'm going to get the output.
I am accepting your password case.
Maybe you can think good.
I mean, I would think more of that.
It's reverse the conditions.
That's that's what I that's
I was doing for example.
Right. Actually another example
when we looked in the application.
Right.
So let me see
if we can find any application
we have
probably not going to find in here,
but we see
there's no checkbox.
Okay.
But I want to get
think of this on our applications.
What do we have? Right.
Sometimes we have
there's something that called checkbox
write something that culture box
like for example, it will act.
It will ask us, do you accept something?
Something right? You accept.
And then we will have to select
this checkbox.
We will have to select it. Right.
But what happens, guys?
What happens
if your checkbox is already selected
and if you're going to click on it?
What's going to happen?
This if you checkbox is already selected,
then now you want to click it again.
What will happen,
what it will do, it will select,
it will uncheck.
Right?
And then of course
you won't be able proceed.
So now what we will do, we will add our
if statement we will say only in
only if the box not checked
only and only If the box is not checked
only then what I would like
to do click on that on that checkbox.
Only then I want you to click.
Okay.
That's actually another good scenario.
Right?
But if, if, if it's if it's already
checked, if it will be, give me true.
Right.
That's
how actually those checkboxes have worked.
So whenever it will be checked,
it will give you true.
Whenever it's unchecked,
it will give you full.
So now all in only when box
is not checked, then I'm going to click.
Click. Okay.
That's our automation scenario.
When we're going to use this note
operator.
I hope that makes sense best.
If that doesn't make sense.
Okay.
Right.
So if you're going to write it in
here, right.
Okay. I hope it's good.
I hope that's how it works.
That's right. So let's see.
Let's take that checkbox right.
Booleans it box, Right.
So say if it's selected. Right.
So when you saw that, it says, Yeah, yeah,
we're going to take a break.
And now I wanted to say all in only,
only or actually not checkbox
Let's make it selected.
So like, right.
So I want to say only in only
if my checkbox is
not selected right, then
that's what I will do.
Oh, duplicate.
Right.
So this way if your record will be shown
that the checkbox is selected,
which is true,
then it will convert it to the false.
Then you will never perform
the click on the trip box,
but the checkbox will show you that hey,
no, it has never been checked.
Now false converted into true.
Right?
And then what
you will perform from this click
on for the let's let's take a break
133 Let's take a break until 155.
Okay. I'm starting the spinning.
That's good.
As long as you get started this week
and then you'll do practice
and they will start giving you more
and more and
more thing.
It's 135 or 155.
Get it break.
You want 55.
I'm right.
Okay.
I hope you guys were able
to take your little break.
So we back.
Well, I hope you guys
I hope you guys are all back My car.
More coffee to your body?
Well, that's what you guys will need.
Make sure you get enough coffee, teas,
whatever you need for the next six months.
That's I can guarantee you.
You guys will need it, right?
Especially people on the
West coast.
Your Sunday and Saturday stars
at seven in the morning
right
where I am.
Mariam was taking the power naps.
All right,
guys, let's get back to our Java.
Right.
So today
we said we are looking into the logical
where logical upgrades
are given in our Java
programing
whenever we want to test write up.
Right.
Not all logical upgrades right
logical operators
and or enough right logical
and on or a given to us
when we want to test choose
or more conditions in one statement.
Right so and then the not operator right
very simple
very easy note operator what it simply
does it reverse the conditions.
Right?
And because our condition
it's a Boolean type of value.
And what is the Boolean?
Chappell Now
type of value can be the true or false.
So what is the note Operator?
Does it reverse the condition? Right?
So whenever you have a true right,
so you what your
not operator is going
reverted to the false one
and we have a false is going
reverted to the true right
and here what we did right example right
if there is no rain
if there's no rain
then I'll go for a walk.
Right. So when the value will be false.
Now we can worry if false good true,
then the condition becomes right.
And in here. Right.
Okay. Is the check checkboxes
selected? Right?
If the checkbox is already selected,
then we say.
And only.
Only if the check box is not selected.
Only then I'll do click right.
So now our true condition
will be converted to the false
and then the statement
will never be executed.
Okay.
All right.
Any questions
for any of these logical operators?
Any questions?
Okay. I hope it's clear.
So know what?
I want to show you this.
I want to show you a little
a little things for our code.
Right.
So a little enhancements
that we want to start adding.
Right.
So before we go and maybe we will test
this statement, maybe not.
So we'll see.
But I want to show you something like.
Right.
Okay So when you look into this scenario,
when we look into this scenario.
Right.
And we can look at a very simple one,
we don't have to
take an assumption. Well, that's fine.
We'll take examples. Right.
So, for example,
what if right now, guess
what if right now,
what if right now this given exercise.
Right.
I have to add something else for.
Example, right.
In my exercise right now,
the goal of this exercise is to find
the three largest numbers, right?
The goal is to find out, sorry,
that the the largest number out of the
three numbers.
Right.
So what if now I want to do
based on their result,
based on the result that I'm getting.
Right.
Whichever number is the largest, worse
than the one or number two
or number three,
based on which number is the largest.
Now, I want to check another condition,
not I want to say, hey, now,
can you tell me that the largest
whether the largest number
is even or art, right.
Even or so.
Now, let me ask you guys, how do you guys
think you will start doing it?
So now, once you find out
which number is the largest,
please tell me whether this largest number
is even or odd number.
Are you going to do it
using percentage?
Yep. So we will add that right.
And that we will add
that we will have to throw that right
actually in this
exercise because you guys said now
one is the largest, which is one, right.
Which is like the
I want to show you a little bit diff,
not different way, but probably more
preferred way of how this assignment
could be completed and how this assignment
could be completed.
I'm not going to change the logic
of using EVE statements,
not going to change the logic
of using the logical approach.
No logic in call will stay the same,
but what we will try to do is
we will try to write a little bit
a cleaner code,
because when we look into our exercises
right now, right,
we look into our exercises
where we know that
the words are
right.
So in here, so everywhere,
what we are doing right now is great.
Based on the condition
I have some specific output, right?
I have some specific
output, some specific output
by for
when it comes to coding guys, coding is,
not just about print outs.
Right.
The code is actually about
performing
some particular task right in here.
Hey, if the checkbox is not selected,
then I'm going to do
going to perform the click right.
Actually,
it shouldn't B.S. South. It will.
It should be an actual actual clip. Right.
So and we will
we will see how those things work.
Right. So now another thing, right?
What I mean here we kind of like already
did it the little bit, right?
So now we said now
one is the largest, number two.
And now if we want to define
which number is
if your largest number is equal or right.
So now you guys
probably would have to come in here
and hey, if num one right num one more
now one
more to equals to zero.
Right.
Then you probably will say the number is
equal or the number is right.
So then you will at this
and then then you'll see
now one I don't know that that one plus
in this
is the model number
and near or else
it's an even number right.
And then what you would have to do
you will have to observe even right
evening and then you would have to
do the same thing for a num to
and then you probably would have to
do the same thing for an empty
as one of the would. Right.
So now one to me and I'll look into this,
our code becomes a little,
a little messy and too big.
Right.
So now what we will try to do,
there is a way how we can start writing
a cleaner code and there is a way
how we can improve our coding in here
as well.
Right?
So any time we look into the improvement
or we talk about enhancements,
you guys will start here.
A lot of terms enhancing.
Okay, let me enhance my
let me enhance my automation in sprints.
Okay.
Or whenever you guys will be going more,
more and more and over,
you guys will hear that's very, very.
All right.
So for example, I want to do guys I want
to I'll take exact the same exercise,
but now we will try to do it
in a little bit, enhance with it.
Let me copy this.
So this way
you guys will have somewhat better look
because your largest number right.
Are it spots, largest
number of events.
Right. Exact the same thing I'll take.
But now I will start doing all of it.
So I think lots of others.
Right.
So now they all
look think I will try to.
Well, that's fine.
It will be everywhere like that. Right?
So now you know what I want to do
instead of having this results.
So it has a bit time
and hey, now one is the largest.
Number two is the largest number.
Number three is the largest number.
What is what is instead of this C out,
I actually will perform some operation.
What kind of operation?
I would perform,
I would declare a variable.
I will declare a variable, right?
I will declare the variable double
largest number I largest number largest.
As of now, I don't know
what is the value of the largest.
Right?
So now want to say, hey, you know what?
Now of the typing.
Now one is the largest number.
Why don't I initialize the variable?
And let's let's take it simple.
I'll remove this
because I want to show you different ways.
Right.
So for now, where there's a list,
we will we will pretend
that all numbers are entered are distinct.
So now I'm saying, Hey,
why instead of this out,
why don't I say,
why don't I initialize my variable?
So now, if all those values will be true,
you already find that
you know one is the largest number.
And why don't I do something that.
Why don't I say that largest number
equals to no one, Right?
So now, instead of the long C sound,
what I'm doing,
I'm actually performing some operation.
I'm performing that operation
all initialize in a variable.
Right?
And the same thing. I'll do it here.
Now I'm going to say, Hey, now two,
we already said that will be the largest.
Now I'm going to say, Hey,
I'm going to say
largest number is number two, right?
Largest number is number two
for right.
And then and then in here,
we already said that
the number three will be the largest.
So now what I'm going to say,
I'm going to say largest
is equals to number three, Right?
So now what will happen right now?
What will happen now?
Because, you know,
guess how that statement works right
out of the entire statement, Right.
If we have the look out So all we want
and if only one condition
will become true,
if non condition will become true,
your call will go to the else part right.
So this means and we will pretend
that all the numbers are distinct.
We will pretend
that all the numbers are just
now we have
we will enter I don't know, 2010 and five.
Right.
So we know that the number one
will be the largest.
So you caught this condition will be true.
Your call will match, will go inside
and what it will do,
the value of
no one will initialize value of largest.
So now the largest
will become to number 20.
Right.
And then we know that
as soon as one condition becomes true,
the rest will be ignored. Right.
And the same thing will be happening
if you will enter, for example.
Right. We will enter 1025. Right.
We will take indistinct numbers
so we know this condition.
One be true, right?
We know that number two will be true.
So then this else if becomes true, right.
And this statement will get executed.
Right is based on
we will get it is all we need right now
guys instead of the playing style.
Let's see.
Let's see that on every single line.
What we did, we initialize our variable.
Now What?
We will do this now what will do?
Well,
you'll largest will be initialized
inside this condition
or inside this condition
or inside this condition.
Right now what I can do is
I can just add one statement in here
and now I can see the largest
number is, the largest number is
and plus the largest
realized.
There will be some error,
but don't worry about it.
We will fix.
Now this. I want you to look at this code.
At first I want you to look
at the cleanliness of the code.
Now let's look at this code
that we have worried ahead.
Right.
Even if I remove this for now,
we had a lot of sea, thousands suits out.
And now look at this code on our right.
This look at the code on our right.
So what happened
out of the entire exercise?
I have only wants to start statement.
I was able to do
all we want to show statement. Why?
Because instead of having sea
cells one, two, three times what I did,
once I identified the largest number,
I assign to the variable.
Once I identify which number is
the largest, I initialize right?
And then I'll set of my
if else in blog I have only one print out.
So now let me ask you this
just from your eyes.
Just just by looking at this code,
tell Me guys, which code loops
And even if I'll remove the spaces
that way,
there is no spaces in that world right?
Which code looks more cleaner?
Second one,
right. Second one looks cleaner.
So that's one point, right?
That's one point.
Now Think it this
I added another condition in here. Right.
I added another condition I added.
I say, Hey, what
if now the largest number that you found,
tell me if this number is even or odd.
So what you had to do,
you would have to put all this
If statements for your are one,
then you would have to draw this statement
or the number two right.
And say to two.
And then you would have to draw
this statement for the number three right.
That's probably the most
if you think a little bit more, of course,
there's can be other ways to fix it,
but this is how it will come.
Right now?
You will become more and more.
And then when you look inside, Right.
So what are we having,
guys this is repetitive line, right?
Is The largest is
the largest is the largest.
So what I have
I have a repetitive lines of code.
And now the thing what I have
this statement,
it's also kind of like repetitive.
The only thing what I'm changing right now
I'm changing just the variable.
Now, one num, two and three.
But this is again
becomes my repetitive lines, right?
So eventually the goal of our
x is a coding.
This will be two
if it's possible to eliminate
repetitive lines
now by looking at this code.
Right. You complete this eventually.
Did you complete the exercise?
Yes, we did complete the exercise. Right.
We did find out
which number is the largest.
And now we did define
whether the largest number is even or not.
The task is done.
Yes, the task was done,
but can it be done in the better way?
Yes, it can be done in the better way.
Think it goes now. I'll go back in here.
I'll go back in here.
I closed that
and then we will come here again. Now,
now think of this.
And don't worry,
I'm going to add the zero right now.
I will explain why
I'm not in the zero for now.
Just ignore.
So now think of it this because in here.
Because inside this if statements.
Because inside this, each statement,
what I'm doing, I'm being a little bit
more smarter. Right?
Instead of print out what I'm doing,
I am initializing variable
now because I have a variable
that holds the value
right outside of this statement.
The largest will hold
the value of that number.
And now think what I can do
is I can throw one statement in there
and I can say, Hey, I've learned number
what two equals equals to zero.
Then I'm going to say
how you can initialize variables in here
if I want, but if I want I can just say
blah. This
number is on my
and I cannot otherwise,
if I want, I can write
or I can even observe even right?
I can make it even clean after that.
But what I to show you right now
because right now,
because right now this what you did,
you didn't just boost, it's out.
So first we initialize your variable and
then you have only once this out, right?
You have only one source out.
So this makes your code clean.
There you try
you are eliminating some unnecessary
C cells that are kind of
like saying the same thing.
Right?
And then because you did initialize
this variable,
you did initialize this variable.
Now this variable holds a value now
instead of the destroying if statements
here and here and here what you did,
you just added one each statement
and you just identify which numbers
even or it or even to make it better.
We make it even cleaner code.
Let me see.
We can make it even cleaner code, right?
We can see.
We can take a moving variable. Right?
I will explain that.
I can I can explain that we can see these
even right.
So now I can say, right.
Hey, if the number will be an even number.
Right.
I am going to say right
I'm going to say is even equal special.
Right to say is even equals to true.
Otherwise, I can say is
even if it will become too
complicated again let me no false right
and then I can have one to self oops.
I can have one two steps. Right.
So I can say largest number,
largest
number E needs
or is
even right or something like that.
You just have to come up with a
right sentences and then concatenate this
figure right?
Yes, I will repeat again this.
I will repeat again. Right.
So now first thing, don't worry
about this.
Don't worry about this.
This I will explain you after
we understand this right now.
What are we doing in there?
Inside my eve statement.
Right inside my statement.
Because our exercise was first right,
First identify,
identify largest number.
Right.
That was our first thing to do
within the same task
and set second
continuation was identify right, identify
eve largest number is
even if largest is even.
All right.
So this is important
even or right even number.
So now what do we did once we capture
all numbers inside our eve statements?
We Identify them.
Hey, if the first condition match,
then the value of the largest
will will take the value of now one.
Otherwise
it will be the value of number two
or otherwise
it will be the value of number three.
So what do we do in this if statement this
if statement identifies the largest number
now based on result,
based on the result of this statement,
we can continue doing
it. We can continue doing more check.
Right?
We can continue to do more check. Right.
So now what I did right,
we learned, right?
We said, hey, if I'll take my largest
number, if I try to divide it by two,
if there is no reminder,
if there's no reminder.
So here I took a variable.
I'm saying hey, is even number right?
Will get the value of true.
I did not have to do it.
I could have leave this size,
but to make it more cleaner, click right.
Otherwise
there will be any reminder of cause.
Then the number one be even right,
the number one be even
I'm on. Yes.
Because we we
we can do more of that stuff.
Yes, we can easily
make do that stuff. Okay.
But once we learn what is there
why do we do initialization one
we don't do, we'll come to that. Right?
And then now
my program has one output, right?
It will say, Hey,
what is the value of the largest number?
It will come.
It will be the value of number one
or number two or three.
And then I'll say, hey, is that is
this number is even
and then either going to see true
or either going to see false.
Right.
Although we will come to zero,
we will come back to zero.
So I will explain. But in this way
and this
way, what I wanted to show you,
number one, what are we achieving?
We are achieving
the cleanliness of our code.
We are eliminating
redundancy of the code, right?
We are eliminating unnecessary see sounds.
And the second thing,
what are we doing this?
Because right now
we don't just say systolic.
Number one is the largest
because we perform some operation
and now result from operation
that we have done inside our IF statement
we are using for the further
check right, not like for the chin,
but we can use it for more things.
Right.
For example,
this think of it like when think of
some application where maybe you guys
I don't applying for mortgages right
so there is a lot of information
that has been taken right
And then your information
has been calculated right.
And then for example,
when when you applied for a loan, right,
maybe the check in your credit score
and they check in your income.
Right.
So there is some operation performed.
And then if some condition is match
as the result of this operation,
you will get improved.
Otherwise you will get declined. Right.
So there inside the code,
there is no scissors, guys.
There is a lot a lot of calculation
and variable initialization is done.
And then after that, there
is a lot of statement in there, right?
If your score is this,
if your income is this,
then if all those conditions on match,
then you are getting improve.
Right? So that's
what are we trying to do in here?
We did one task
and inside this task
we perform some operation
and then the result of this operation
we using to define
whether our number is low is even
or whether our number is okay.
So and then eventually,
when you look in our entire
in various screen,
what I have have only once this out,
I have only one print out statement.
And within this print statement
I know which number is the largest
and I know whether
my large number is even or
even or so.
Now, when you guys are going to compare
this code, write this code,
this code with this code
that don't even fit on my screen right now
here you have
is even is is even is largest
large is larger.
So a lot of live repetition.
Now when you look on the code on the left,
your code looks clean there.
So now we are looking more like
it's a code of or, you know, programmers
that are doing their stuff.
Right.
All right.
So now let let I'll take your questions.
Anyone is besides zero
Michael still choose the right it's okay
you can still choose the right
but at the same time start practicing
the things of the on the on the left.
Okay.
Because eventually we will come slowly
to the solutions
that we use in on the left.
Okay, So my main question, guys,
I want you to ask me
if you did not understand
why we doing it.
Zero is coming.
The zero is coming, why we are doing it.
We're doing it to make our code cleaner,
to eliminate any redundant,
unnecessary lines right.
And also this code will be beneficial
if you want to perform from the order
or if there's any other things
you want to do
based on the result.
On the interviews,
they will look into your logic
and they will look into the clean
cleanliness of your code.
And does your Java recognize
largest of the building
your job identify is why I will show you
those teeny tiny details, of course,
because I will have to explain it to you.
And I will.
I am coming to why It's zero.
Okay.
We know size
for whatever.
I got these comparisons.
That works for you, right? Eventually.
Because you will have to come to that
site.
Okay.
I am confused.
Okay, let's do a
can focus any more.
So we're not going to look into this,
which is.
But let me do it.
Let me do this things.
Let me do this.
Let's do this assignment.
Okay. And I will come back to zero.
I will come back to zero.
Let me look at the this assignment
that I wanted to give it to you
right. You
okay?
Right. We're going to look into the task.
If we're going to look into the task
and then we will look into that.
So because I want you to show again,
how does it make so clean, right?
Oh, for you.
Right.
It will take a longer
wait and we will take a
we will look into the cleaner.
We do.
Right.
So now we want to see, right?
So we want a program that will ask user to
to to input a current time.
Right. A current time.
So time we will take in 24 hours.
Try to go slow. Okay.
I'll try to go slow, even though I am
already a little too slow now.
Okay.
So now we say based on the given time,
we will define, we will see.
Right now it's morning.
Right now
it's afternoon, evening or night.
Right. Okay.
You know, the same thing
we will be called scanner, right?
All equals new scanner.
This party,
you guys already know you don't.
You need to.
But I will ask you guys to type it.
Don't just copy it. Right.
So just call it import our scanner.
We should all go now.
All please.
Sensor
a one time
know you will have to capture the time.
It will take 24 hour format. Right?
11, 12, 15, 16.
All the way to 20 right now
we will capture this time
and we'll save your time.
Equals
in that next integer.
Right.
All those lines.
You guys are ready. Right.
So now I will need to happen here.
This is just based on the given time.
I want to define whether it's morning,
afternoon, evening or night.
How can I go for a days, Eve if what
if right, if time is
it times is more than one.
If you want to include we can include
one more is equal than one
so and or organize
and okay and
time is less.
And if we want to include
we will include for example
and let me just go for.
I see. So it's
I want to see I don't know
right now please in morning
or we can just say morning right now is 20
right.
Do I have another condition to just.
Yes, I do. I'll go for LTV. Right.
I'll go for a elseif and same thing.
So now my times
would be more equal than 12.
And then the same time, time has to me
less or equal than 15.
Then we will see.
Right now
it's like.
And then we will go for it else. Right?
I'll see.
And then they going to save time from 16
to 24, right?
More inclusive to 16 in the same time.
Time is less or than 20.
Right.
We will say right now it's only
and then we have it's
always between 21 to 24 right.
Is time is more than equal in 21,
but less than 24.
Right.
We know.
And then if nothing else. Right.
Just in case. Just in case. Right.
Eve user is 100.
Right.
User is 100.
Else we can say I don't know.
We can say
no. Valid.
Fine. And
I like this.
Something like this.
So can you tell me why didn't you
go for and instead of that or
so yeah.
When we check in the time.
Right.
For example, what if I'm entering
right now it's 2:00, so it's 14, right?
If you're going to 20 4:00, it's 14.
14. Right.
So now
when I'm using end.
Right. Okay. Is that time more than one?
Yes, time is more than one.
Condition is true
and time is less than 11.
Condition is false because of the end.
Operator You will give me false, right?
My end will give me false.
And then I'll go to check next condition.
Right.
And then I'll go check next condition.
And here it will give me true.
And my end operator will give me true.
So now if we are going to have
or right, if instead of the end
I'm going to have or right,
I'm going to have or
and my time is still 14.
So then what will happen here is the
time is more than one
use condition is true.
Time is is less than 11.
Condition is false.
Now because of the or operator
I am using, I will get one true.
And then what happened?
The statement will get exact
like we will get situations.
So if you want to use or this condition
always will be true.
This condition always will be true.
Your other statements
will never get a chance right?
So that's why I will meet with our
book.
Right.
So this is like how how can we do it?
Is there something wrong?
No, there is nothing wrong.
Yeah, I say basically,
if any time when you talk
about range right,
you you kind of like use an end.
But when we check in for specific values
we are using or okay
in okay.
All right.
So now this is how we used to do
this is how we used to do this.
Now let me just let me try to do it
with the concept of instead of that. See?
So why don't I initialize the variable
instead of the sea that
why don't I initialize the variables.
Right.
So all with me on the so
for actually here.
So now I'll take this as it is. Right.
I'll take this it as it is now.
I will one variable
I will introduce one variable.
I'll say I don't know string
of the next.
Right.
What about
I don't know the value of time of D
right now I'm going to see
hey if the time
if the time is between one and 12 right.
So what do we have right now?
What is it? Time of the day?
Guess what is it Time of the day?
If the time is between one and 12, it's
morning, right?
So now what I'm going to do,
I take this variable
and I'm going to assign the Valley
of Morning to
else is right else.
Even this condition is true.
Now of this this out I'm
going to initialize the variable, right?
I'm going to say time of the day
is equals to evening.
Right.
Then another right then another else is.
I'll see what time
is between here.
Right is between here.
All the fine.
Oh I skip the evening. Right.
Oh I skipped this one.
I skipped after that one.
Mm. Week in the afternoon.
That's right.
And I'm copying
because I'm adding the same conditions can
sometimes
1 to 11, 12 to 15, 16 to 20.
Right now it's evening
last evening and then optional evening.
I'm going to say time of the day.
Right.
Instead of this use that I'm going to say
time of the day
is equal to what is equal to evening.
Right.
So now what I'm doing inside
my every block, inside my eve block
or then inside my ls a block
instead of having C sounds what I'm doing
actually is store in the value
inside this variable silence variable.
Right.
And then you send the elsewhere right.
That's for
there's l point.
I can see the time of the day.
It means when we come to the l sports
when user will enter
something invalid, the right
one user to enter either
negative number or user will enter zeros
or something.
Here I can say time of the day.
I'll just see that for example.
Right. I'll just say in the
in norms.
And now if I want to have one C
so back into one C stop
now what I can say.
Right.
So I want you,
I can just print it and then we can have
another condition.
Right now we and I will come to me
time of but
finally.
So what are this key?
I want you to okay I added to extra space,
extra spaces for now you guys. So
what are you guys?
It will do exactly the same thing
I'll put will be exact the same.
But when you look into this code
and when you look into this right.
So now our code becomes pointer, right?
As we enter
the current time, it's 43 words.
Outputs gives me the same thing.
Right now
it's afternoon, right now it's afternoon.
But when we look into our actual code
that we do now on the line
30 code looks clean.
Okay? And eventually this,
once we start doing more
and more practice,
you guys will start seeing it
that there is actually some things
we are performing,
not just doing the principles,
but we will be doing some calculation
and assignment of variables
and different, different stuff.
Okay, so what now?
Just think
what it looks way cleaner, right?
It looks
okay.
So now
at least I hope you will see.
And let me explain you guys, for now,
just please pay attention.
So now I will explain you why there
there were zeros.
Why there was no zeros.
And see.
Okay, good. Now. Yeah, like I like that
you got this message.
So now let's take a look.
This.
Let's take a look, guys.
Why? Right?
Why? We.
We got zero before, right?
Why we had to do zero before
and why some of you are having issues.
Why some of you are having issues.
So now.
Yeah. Was the difference.
I didn't hear inside my else
I did initialize my variable.
Okay I did initialize my be able to now
show you
what happens.
Right? What happens.
So remember this our code is always
executed up to the bottom, always right.
And so now in here on the line
36 on the line 36, you created a box.
Is there any
value at the current moment
when your Java is at the line?
36 Are there any value inside this box
right now? This
there's no we did not initialized, right?
We did not initialize.
So now what happens, right?
What happens
inside Eve statement.
Inside the eve statement.
Right now your java looks at every single
possibility.
Actually there's someone before
Java looks.
But for now we'll just say Java.
Okay,
so now your code is always being checked.
So now. Okay, Right.
Eve, My code
will fall inside the eve block
and my place in the valley,
inside this box and my place in the value.
This I'm placing the value which valley
I'm placing this string morning.
Right.
So when you will go in there, Eve,
my quarter will be in here
then Bucharest, Czech.
Okay. What if.
What is her condition?
Right. One there. Right.
The code would have
the code will fill in here.
Are they initializing the variable?
Yes, they do initialize the variable.
If the code will come in here
and they initialize in the variable.
Yes they are initializing the variable.
Hey, could be this scenario
when none of the conditions are match.
Yeah.
There could be a scenario
when none of the condition match.
So then the code will go to the else
block.
Are they initializing the variable
inside the LS?
BLOCK Yes, they do.
So remember this if statement
does this selective execution.
So your code is check.
Hey, if possibility will be here or here
or here or here.
Are they giving the value of this box?
Yes, they do give the value of this box.
Okay, cool.
So now on the line 48,
you are asking to display the value
inside this box, right?
That's why your code looks fine.
That's why the code looks fine.
But what before
and what happens is the zero
get as soon as I'm going to remove
my ls block,
as soon as I'm going to remove
my LS block, my code will complain,
my quota will complain.
And if we're going to hover over
it tells that our variable
may not have been initialized.
What does it mean? This?
What does it mean?
So you could before it lets Java run it.
Okay, so there is one guy that checks
your code all the time.
Okay.
And this guy we it compiler this.
Okay, so compiler.
It's like your best friend
compile is the poly.
So your program compiler
wants to make sure
that before it handles the code to Java
to execute to execute
it wants to make sure that code is correct
okay.
So now know here it won't be zero.
Guess I'll explain it to you.
So first of all, follow
my logic. This place.
So now what happens?
Code executes that to the bottom.
Your compiler quickly checks compiler say
okay here they created empty variable.
Right now they have the eve
now they
said if this condition is true,
are they initialize in years?
Is this condition
is the initializing? Yes.
Is this condition is true.
They initialize in years
hey but there could be a possibility
when none of the condition is match.
So if none of this will match,
are you initializing
the time of the day somewhere against?
Are you initializing it?
We are not initializing it. Right.
Is there a possibility
that none of the condition could be true?
So your compiler.
Okay, if none of the condition is true,
they're not placing any value.
They're not placing any value
inside this box.
However, on the line 46,
they asking for me
to print the value of this box.
How can I print the value of the box
if there won't be any value,
if there possibility
that this things might not be initialized?
Remember,
I guess your program is not going to take
in my place and it's something to you.
So now what your program will ask?
Your program will ask, Hey,
can you give it this initial value.
Initial value.
I want to have you as a you as a program.
I take responsibility,
put in the initial value.
If you're not having the LS block in here.
Right.
Because I can look for anything you want.
So now, if you are going to click in here
right, your compiler will help you.
You will help you to initialize it.
So now.
But the only thing compiler can do,
it can initialize
only two default values.
Guess so now because we have
a different data types.
Different data types
has a different default values, right?
So if you want to click initialize,
it will show us now.
Okay.
So what what we mean in here.
So to initialize compiler in
we've only default
values to the variables to the variables.
So for example, if it sees
your variable is not being initialized
and if the variable of the integer type
it will get zero,
if it will be a double type,
what are this thing?
It will be
it will be zero zero.
If it will be string.
All our you guys will learn.
It will be for all non primitives.
It will give null.
If you will use a boolean,
it will be false.
Okay.
So if this is the default values
and this is what happens,
so now your compiler will say, okay,
so they did put some value just in case.
If this quarter will come to the support,
then I'm not responsible.
I am not responsible.
But the it has a default value.
So this way I can print it. Right.
And let me go back to the largest number.
This this same thing,
what's happening in here?
Right.
The same thing was happening in here.
So your code looks great.
Let me remove.
So here, if you're not going to have zero,
your code was complaining in here, right?
Your code was complaining in here. Why?
It was complaining the same thing.
Largest right now it's an empty box.
It's an empty box. Right.
So now your job, your compiler checks.
Okay.
If this scenario will be true
and they place in the value.
Yes, they do.
If this scenario is true
and they place in the value, yes, they do.
and they place and the values do,
hey, what if, as we said,
the numbers will be all distinct?
What will happen?
None of the cases will get executed.
So below
the box still will be empty by now.
On the line 29 you you need to check.
Use the mode Operator. How can I use this?
Operator How can I perform
any operation on the empty box?
How can I perform any operation?
Even your variable
have not been initialized.
The variable have no initialize.
So there's a two ways this.
You either can initialize it
at first, right?
You can either provide the default value
Or the way we had it in here.
If you want, you have the ls block
and inside that ls block.
If going to initialize
your variable, it's an invalid
invalid,
then you
don't need to initialize it in here.
So this way you java checks. Okay.
If none of the condition is match
my code will java code
will go to the ls block of the initialize
in there.
Yes. The place in the value
I can have the java can have you print it
as long as there is a value.
Right.
Java cannot print that something
if there is no now Lee
has been placed.
Okay. Does it make sense guys?
I hope.
I hope all the zero questions are are gone
now. Yes.
So the way to solve it,
you either add the ILS
because maybe somewhere else
combination, right?
So now we can just add it
or just initialize it before
it's the machine.
Okay.
Now it's my
but we are the one who making it smarter.
Right?
So in here because
in the year because it was an integer
value or double rate
but we know what happens with a double
write in it will add that that zero to it.
Right will add that zero. Right.
Because it's a double it at zero zero
it would be integer,
it will be just zero.
And these are what yes you can have.
But if you want to have both,
you can have it.
But I probably would not initialize it
unnecessary.
Okay.
So if you want to provide the ls
I can provide right, then
throw it.
Let's code less problems
if you put the right logic.
Right.
But yes,
when you guys can start having let's see.
So your code will still look clean.
I probably can concentrate even more.
All right.
So please practice with this.
And of course you guys will practice
more on the review classes.
Now I'll give you more homework, guys.
So the same thing right now,
we try to follow this approach, Right?
So here
you will be
asked to enter the name of the month,
right?
September, October, November, December.
And then based on the month,
I want you define the season.
Right.
If the birthday is January, February,
December, your season when you were
born is winter right in the
you born in June, July, August.
Your season is summer. Right.
So then try to use it the same way.
So here
you guys will have another one, right?
You will have another one and.
Of course you guys are going to have
ripple assignments as well.
Okay, Many questions.
What our homework is.
Jamie is happy.
I see that
homework.
As long as you guys tried to do it
before the next class.
But my suggestion guys
see one of the homework and reply.
I probably will try to do it
before Thursdays.
So this week, in case there's any issues
you have, you guys can try to.
So it might also be some concerns
you have you this can bring on Thursday
class.
Yes I'll send you an announcement
and one thing guys please please, please.
Next week will be very
important week.
Right.
And please look into switch case,
which case will be easy.
Switch case will be easy.
But then next week
we're going to start with loops.
Okay?
Loops are very, very huge an important
concept when it comes to the programing.
It's those loops,
any basics that we're learning
that's actually right now,
they do
exist in every other programing language,
but loops are very, very important.
Okay, so we will open some ripples,
but one thing is remembered by ripples.
Okay?
So because we want you to continue
studying and not just.
Oh, I'll do it later.
Okay. So over time, this ripples, right?
We will be opening up new ripples,
but the all ripples will start closing.
Not right away.
This week, after about two weeks,
we were going to start closing
those ripples. Okay, So that's why.
Please make sure you guys
practice, practice, practice.
And then next class, I will upload slides.
Please make sure you guys prepare. Okay.
Don't come on, prepare for the next class
loop.
So loops are very, very fun.
Oh yeah.
They're there will be
I think there's again will be about 16
or 15 exercises in Ripple. Okay
so everything
all the points until we learn today,
that's what you guys going to see on ramp.
All right.
Okay guys.
Then the,
uh, so when it comes to the slides goes,
the slides are not when you have tasks,
the slides are going.
I have an all mine information.
That's what the slides have.
The task are not they're on the slides.
They won't be uploaded. All right.
Okay, good.
Thank you.
And please make sure you study one
so when you enter, the seating
has two words like you, Catalina.
In that case,
you will have to use the next slide.
But actually, I forgot that some of you
you were having the easiest.
Sometimes those issue comes
when you use next and next slide.
Okay, So if you guys face
any of that issue, please ask Asghar.
He will explain it to
There's a there's a process
that happens behind when you use next
and when we use next line. Yep.
So please ask him if he will explain this.
All right.
Thank you, guys. In great work, everyone.
And I'll see all of you next week
and then hopefully,
as I should be, start
feeling better by next Saturday, right?
Okay. Thank you, guys.