Yes. Let me start today.
Farming two days.
I am just watching online.
Can't cable to sol side by side.
I just came out of dental surgery.
I will try to bill my wrist.
That's okay.
So. Oh no.
I mean, today's the day
when we will not be learning new things.
They are just kind of resilient.
So the things that we will be covering
today,
you guys have already gone
through those things.
So today's class will be very easy
to. Yes, I am sure.
Then just a few new things,
etc..
Pilot program would be job
because you didn't get that.
It is
possible.
Actually,
you guys didn't realize this, but
I 75% of the concepts
I have delivered those concepts
in previous classes,
so it will be
just a few new terminologies,
but we will be doing
pretty much the same thing.
So today's class will be actually fun.
We will see you
how much patience you guys have.
So you have been seeing my patients
till now that see your patients.
Today we are 75% ingenious.
So let me create a new package.
Let's call it
and let's clear
and find
the one
how they are stable.
All right, guys.
So what did we cover on
last class on Wednesday?
Do you guys remember something
fun sounds techni super key word, right?
Very easy or so.
Can you guys tell me in how many ways
in Java we can use the super keyboard?
If you guys remember something
not refers
to super class
variant plus
so B ways, right?
So let's, let's try to define this first.
So super is a keyword
that we use to refer to the
parent class
instance.
Yeah. And
we can use,
we focused on quizzes,
everything else is forgotten.
So we can use super
user in three
even if
we write.
The first use is
var constructor and matter.
I did not even get to play this.
So what do the first
you guys that we learn?
This quiz was easy
to expand
in grade.
Alex.
Okay.
The constructor right
to call the parent class
constructor.
This second use
all the methods from
parent class.
If we have.
Yeah.
Okay.
So even if we don't have a method
in the child class with same name,
we can still use super to call the method
from the parent class,
but it will not make sense
to call the method from the parent.
So I will only try to call the methods
from the parent class
and then to use the
fields
from the
parent class.
All right,
so let's see if I have a class parent
and if I have a weird name
mean here. Okay.
So let's take the example of
what is the name of your father.
Right. So let's say we have
this name field.
Right.
And let's see.
It is this method. So.
So what what is the that
your father like earlier?
So let's say there is this it method
in the parent class
Talk about
so as well so this is how short for
printing out in here.
Okay so I have a method in here
and then I have a cover
and let's say there are other fields
which are not initialized yet.
So let's say
Double
Century,
which we are initializing
through the
constructor.
Now if we try to clear the child class,
what can happen?
I'm not, You made me hungry.
So if we have a child
class, what can happen
is that the child class
and have its own fields
and the fields they can be.
You didn't
share the notes from the last class.
So, Alexy, here
are the notes from the last class.
And I pushed these notes to the gate tab.
You do check the YouTube.
They should be on GitHub.
Yes. They are not present on the data.
Let me check back
now here.
Alexa, North north door to the extreme.
So I will be pushing the north Speed
with the code on your top from the top.
So we went here.
So what can happen
is that if now the child class,
if this class wants to have
the exact same name field
so this child
class can have the exact same name.
FIELD Okay, So we don't have to come up
with the different names
or let's say someone else,
they find the parent class
and now you guys want to use
some functional data from this class
so you can now have same methods,
the same name methods,
and then same name fears.
And with the help of super keyboard,
you will be able to call the methods
or be fields
or the constructor from the parent class,
and then you can also call
the fields on the methods from the child
class.
Yeah.
So we can have we can have
this name field again in here.
Yes, we need the
x and schema tank is almost
just the string name
and then we can have a method
it so and not.
What do you like to it?
What about more?
So that's where we can use
the super keyword.
Now let's say if I am
putting
a board, if I have this method
okay, I can
now if I look for it,
what output I will see is
if I added and do it above,
if I write super state
and if I call the sprint
for no matter what output, I will see
the output from the parent.
And if I call this method
but but without any super keyword, then
I will see more and more for that.
And in the same way I can, I can print out
the names.
Okay, I can say
super dark name.
Yeah.
If I say super dark name,
I will see said that
I need to ask my to prepare some color.
So I said okay book.
Sorry.
And if I only print the name
then I will see
the name and
so here is one rule that
inside the constructor.
So let's say this is the child
constructor.
It is taking a field salary
and I can write super
and then I can pass this salary in here.
So now there is this rule.
So you guys remember
when we were using the
this keyword with parentheses?
Do you think you can copy and paste it?
And also I can paste
into my notes on Intelligent.
So let me go complete the notes
and maybe you can, but.
But why do you need to copy
and because I will be creating these notes
right after the class.
So as we as the this with parentheses
needs to be the first line
inside the constructor.
Same is the case with this super killer,
so I can not have anything before back.
Okay.
I cannot have anything.
Let's say I cannot put super
I cannot put any system out
or I cannot call any method
or I cannot do anything like that.
Okay.
This super, this
call to the constructor,
it should be the first line.
Okay.
It should be the first line.
And if you guys remember, if
I have a parent class and a child class,
if I clear the object of child class,
will the object of parent class
be created?
Or if the only child class
if I have a constructor in the parent
and a constructor in the child,
which constructor will be called?
And in this sequence, the parent.
So always, always the object of parent
class is created first.
Then the object of Jared class is greater
so that if we are using some fields
from the parent class,
these fields they are initialized.
The first.
Okay, so do you guys remember
anything else about the super keyboard?
I think it was super easy, right?
Super killer,
Super easy.
No respect to the parent. The.
So let me send you the nurse.
I will write more notes
from now on
because these things,
they are very important
for your interviews.
And if you want to write Advanced
Java Code.
So I would not start overloading you guys.
Watch the
I just so
I just said that I will be writing
more notes because they are important.
The conversations
that we will be having now.
So they are more important
for your interviews.
And I think this is also important
because when I speak, I think
if I am speaking 100 words,
you guys only get about 50
to 50 to 60 words right?
I think this is how humans work
and naturally they miss givers
because I'm also a student.
So I can feel that
missing and forgetting.
But I also hope that you guys
are revising the Java slides, right,
Because if the next week
when you will be starting the fun part,
when you will be using
Java in your real life
to do very fun things.
Okay,
so I hope you guys are revising your Java,
all the loops and all the
under concepts like switch cases.
If health conditions.
I don't have this large format method
over loading.
Sebastian Why?
I think I shared on the canvas
are naughty slides
present on canvas.
Mine goes to class 19
so you guys can ask in this sports channel
if something is not present.
Oh, I didn't push, I didn't publish them.
Okay.
Now they should be
relevant.
Can you guys check now if the slides on
method overloading are present?
I have it.
Bug master.
So today's class is very important.
Let's start today's class.
Let's show
us how to provide notes on an intelligent
So in should you
First you have to create.
You have to right click on your package.
Then you have to select new and then phi.
Then you can write any anything,
any name for your file
and then you need to type this extension
dot B XD.
Okay, then you should be able
to see the exact same file
as I have on my in reality
method over learning.
So did you guys watch the video
on method overloading?
And if yes, what?
What do you guys understand
from from that?
So let me create a very simple class
by adding more parameters.
Yes, it is complicated for me.
When you have two thirds
with the same name,
but different parameters
but didn't understand.
Yes, it was the easiest video
it will deal with when you have
two methods of the same name,
but with different parameters.
So let me first show you the issue, guys.
Let me first show you the issue why
we even need to be method overloading.
It's just a new terminology.
Can I ask something?
My review package
classes have read render titles. Why?
They were just fine.
So I shine Intelligent Red means you have
not added those files to the new hub.
So then we say that if you say get a dot,
add that red should be gone.
So your writing just just tells you that
in these files I'm not part of as good.
Is it possible you create
one file for your notes on canvas, please?
Kazim You want me to share the notes on
canvas as well?
You guys don't see the code from GitHub
or you don't clone it.
We want to use
or we want you to use GitHub
because it's the first thing
that you guys will be using on your jobs.
It's very important
why you guys are still
using the canvas
for files or stuff like that.
YouTube is very important.
Guys,
so they will be sharing you
a link off project.
I use GitHub to
how to find other files on GitHub lessons.
So we will be you guys will be having
more sessions on GitHub after selenium.
But you guys already had a tool.
I guess to do sessions on GitHub
right to two or three sessions
and you guys already know how to clone
something
from the GitHub
that that's what we want for now.
So I want you believe me, you don't want
to learn new things about it.
I mean, GitHub is so
big you guys can spend the next one year
just learning bigger time.
It's so big.
We just know how to push code.
You guys don't know how to clone the code
from the
YouTube.
Oh, all right. All right.
So remind me at the end of this class,
I will show you.
It's very easy.
Just copy paste.
Is push equal to.
It's very easy.
Very easy.
So, listen, this was the issue before
method overloading, let's say.
Guys,
I have to create a very simple method that
adds through parameters.
Okay?
Number one to
and this is a very simple method,
it just displays the sum
of this number, right?
So, okay,
now, because Java is something
that gives about the letter types a lot.
So if I want to have another method,
let's say
that is doing the exact same thing,
but it is dealing with different
and data types.
Okay, so let's say I want to have a method
that can not only add integers,
but it can also add maybe long
numbers on floating point numbers
or doubles or bi or shorts.
Now we know
that we cannot use one single method
to add all the stereotypes.
Can we use the well?
Can we use one single method
to add all the numbers
like integers, numbers, longs floors?
Can I use the this this one single method
to add all the data types?
The number data types?
Can I pass double value to this method?
If I have declared integers in here,
then I passed the doubles.
I cannot write, I cannot pass doubles.
I will get an error.
So I cannot use one single method
to handle all the data types.
Okay.
That means even even though I am
doing the exact same thing,
I have to write a new method.
Right.
And before the method
overloading before the method overloading
because it was not possible
to write same name meters
for different types of parameters.
Programmers,
they have to come up with different names
if they are dealing with different data
types.
So let's say for example,
if I had to write
a method that can add doubles,
I will have to come up
with a different name.
I, I might use add doubles,
although I am doing
exactly this same thing.
Okay. So the only difference
is this number and I'm one.
And then
double.
Okay.
So the only difference here is this
data type going to see.
I am doing exactly the same thing. Okay.
I am adding inside this method, adding
in that the only difference
is this in here I am using double,
but my my operation is same.
So is it a good idea
if I am doing exactly the same thing
and if I have to come up
with different different names?
So to give one more example,
let's say I have to add this time
maybe the elements
of of an editor, right? So
then I have
to come up with again
with a different name
and add a write
how can I boss
and add it to the method dies?
Or should I write
inside these parentheses?
And what is the terminology that we use?
What are these things called?
They are called parameters. Right?
Again, I am doing the exact same thing,
so how can I add the elements of an array?
I need maybe a temporary variable
to hold the sum.
I can write a law
integer number
and then I get the elements of the array
one by one
and I do some
is equal to some plus number.
And do we need. Yes.
Yes I shall when you do that.
Okay.
And then once I am done looping through
all the elements, okay,
I can print out that sum.
So again,
I am doing addition in this method.
I am doing audition.
In this method I am doing addition.
In here I am again doing addition.
And why?
Why also it is important.
It's also important because
whenever
you guys will be joining a company,
you guys will be reading a lot of quote,
not if the names of the methods.
They don't convey the sense, right?
Like, well, what is that method is doing?
If you cannot get that info
from the name of the method,
what do you guys have to do?
You guys have to open that method,
understand all the logic,
the reading through all the lines
that are written inside that method
and it will be wasting a lot of time,
right?
Maybe.
Let's say if I, if I say
lose something
with Eddie.
Right. If I name this method like this.
Now what you guys have to do,
you cannot read
from the name of this method,
so you have to open that matter.
You have to read all the logic
and then you have to understand the logic,
and then you can use this
method in your program. So.
So what happens
is that in the industry, it's
very, very important
how you name your methods,
how you name your classes,
how you name your variables.
Okay? So that's why it is also important
in now
in here, let's say we were adding
at two elements.
Okay, Now if I have to add three elements,
I have to come up with a different name
again.
Okay.
And three integers, maybe.
And then I can write another number
like this and I can say plus
method and number three.
Okay.
So in all these examples,
we are doing the exact same operation
addition.
Okay.
But what we have to do every time,
if I change the number of parameters,
if I change the type of parameter
or one more thing,
if I change the six months of parameter.
So let's say, for example, I have to add
one integer and one double.
Now again,
I have to come up with a different name,
add integer
and double right?
So oops.
So I double again.
I am doing the same thing
just because I have to
change the number of parameters
that I am passing to a method,
or just because I am changing
the sequence of the parameter
or just because I am passing
different number of parameters,
I have to come up again and again
with different different names.
Okay, so this is the problem that method
overloading solves.
Okay.
And how it soldered the method overloading
says that Hey programmers,
if you are changing the parameter
types,
you don't have to write a new method.
If you are passing
different number of parameters,
you can still use the same name.
If you are passing different parameters
in a different sequence,
you can still use the same name
and if you are posting
something totally different,
you can still use the same name.
Okay, so let's say
so let me
call these
methods and let me show how these
methods works.
Let me know once
you guys are done typing discord.
Now let's try to call these methods. Okay?
So expert quality and so.
So tell me, guys, if I want to
call these methods from this class
and I don't want to create the object
of this class, what should I modify?
How can I do that?
I want to call these matters
just with the name of the class. Yes.
So I can add
the static keyword like this right
then with the I can say
method overloading
not add.
I pass in number ten and under number ten.
Right.
I can see
method overloading
add and
double.
I can post and point five
and 10.5 so I can now add
two doubles as well.
If I have
one integer and the other one as double.
I can also do that
and if I have my turn overloading
or let's say for example,
if I have three numbers, then
and then I can also do that.
So just add
one thing at any
and if I have
and if I have an array,
I can also add that.
Okay.
And now if I execute my code,
I will see the results for all the methods
you guys also granted, it does.
So when we call array,
we put them in curly
bracket E Yes,
So if that's a shorter way
of creating and adding, are there students
which are getting some kind of errors
so say while having errors
add indiabulls.
So Silva, you have to show me this class,
this method overloading class.
So we just add into double matter.
No, you don't have that
method in your class.
Silva You have to create this method.
You are missing that matter.
Add into double.
Okay,
so in here you are having add double
only but not add into doubles.
So. So this is one of the problem.
You guys understand the problem.
So again, can you guys write the problem
if you have understood?
And so without overloading,
that's the method
name always has to start with
same word or that.
No, no, no.
Oh, it can be anything.
It can be anything.
It can be.
So now let's try to rewrite
this these methods
and these classes.
But this time, last use
method overload Me.
Okay. Okay.
Can I close these two classes, guys?
If you guys are done typing,
why we put start not public.
So can you guys
tell us why we use this static,
not public.
And if the public and static
if they are related?
Are Republicans that static
related to each other?
The first thing public and static.
They are not related.
They are not a substitute of a
for one and other.
Okay.
Just out of curiosity,
why does the import randomly pop up
when I make a different class
out of the same import
that caused the trouble on that day? It's
so you
you might be typing
something related to that class.
There might be a class in this package
and you accidentally type
the name of that class.
Then it pops up.
So first things starting and public.
They don't have to do anything
with each another.
Okay, static is a non access modifier,
oblique is a and excess modifier.
Okay.
Public means what does public mean guys?
If I write public with the
method, what does it mean? So
we can
access that called in whole package.
You got access to it
is static and private are same.
No, they are also not same.
If we write public it means that matter
or constructor or field.
If I am writing public with the field
matter constructor
can be called from anywhere
inside that package.
On the other hand,
static means I don't have to come up.
I don't have to create
an object of that class
to access that field or that method.
Again, I have static.
That structure goes, No,
we can not have static constructors.
Can you guys tell me the reason
why we cannot have static constructors?
What is the purpose of constructors?
What is the purpose of constructors
to initialize
instance figures, right.
To create an object object is nothing
but a collection of
instance fields and methods.
But static means
something that belongs to class,
something that is shared
across all the objects.
Something that has only one
value shared across all the classes.
So if we are making the constructor static
first, we will not be able to access
instance fields.
Second,
even if we are able to access the instance
fields, all the objects will be having
same values, same values.
So that's why it is not allowed.
Does it make sense?
Yes. All the objects
will be having the same values.
If Java guys are allowed
to have static constructors.
Okay,
so let's try to use method
overloading in here.
Okay.
God, we access
static fields with static constructors.
Yes we can.
But what about the instance fields
constructor
is there to initialize instance fields.
We will
be initializing those fields.
Is it clear for hard
welcome.
So let me copy these matters
and close this up
and let me be.
Can now work method overloading saves it.
Save the task because you are always
doing the same operation.
You know work.
You can always use the same name.
Okay.
You can always use the same.
You can always use the same. Right.
So I can use
because I am always doing the same thing.
I can use the same name
for all the methods.
And now if I am calling
this add method
with integer type of parameters,
which method will be called dies
in the first one bright integer
and who is deciding how it is being
decided which method to call
based on the type of parameters?
Okay.
And if I pass one integer and double
Java automatically calls
this method. Okay.
If I pass three parameters, Java
automatically calls this parameter.
This method if I pass
and every Java automatically calls
this and method
which is expecting and adding,
okay, so this is the benefit of method of.
And so you guys have already done
this when we created multiple
constructors, right?
What if we have the same types?
Which one is be called?
So if we have the same types,
we will be getting an error
here because Java is now confused.
Java decides based on the parameters
and you are passing the same parameters
to the Java.
Don't know which method to call.
Let me also show that.
So it is saying what if
we pass?
If we pass the same parameters again?
So because the parameters are same,
because these methods,
they have the same parameters.
Now we will be getting an error
so far method overloading to work,
but it is not the
this going to make your documentation
confusing is a lot easier
of the names of methods given indication
for what this method does.
So Mohammad, can you tell me
what all of these methods are doing?
They are always adding.
They are always adding just because
sometimes you are adding integer.
Some times you are adding double,
sometimes you are adding longs,
sometimes you are adding one integer
and other double.
Is it a good idea to always write a new.
Okay, so that's not a good idea.
What if you are?
You have to pass three parameters.
You come up with a different name.
What if you have to pass formatted
parameters?
Then again a different name.
Five parameter again a different name.
If you changed the sequence
again, a new method name, you
you will be running out of names.
But the operation.
Yes, the operation should be same.
Okay. Operation should be same.
So this is okay.
So the operation should be same.
So there are three things through
which we can overload.
Okay.
First,
if we change the data types, so in here
the data type was integer.
In here the data type was again
an integer on the second method.
Then I define the second method.
I change this integer to a double.
Okay, so if I change the data types,
then Java will not give me an error.
I will be able to override or a method.
The other thing
that can allow me to overload
the method is
if I pass different number of parameters.
How many parameters
I am passing in here guys
tool and
how many parameters are there in here?
They are three right
now. One more way of overloading
is changing the sequence.
If I pass the double value first
and if I pass the integer after that,
still I can overload objects in here.
I was passing an integer first,
then double in here
I am passing a double first
and then an integer.
So this is changing the sequence.
So in how many ways I can overload
the meters?
Three ways, right?
Can you guys.
Can you guys tell me which three ways?
Changing sequence. Yes,
Changing that type? Yes.
And passing different parameters.
Right.
So three ways I can overload four meters
in three different ways.
And can I also do the same
with the constructors?
Three.
So if you guys remember
the class
on constructors,
it was after access modifiers, right?
I guess this one.
Oh yes, this one.
So you guys see in here
how many parameters
I was passing to this constructor.
Zero in here.
What did I change?
How did I overload this constructor?
Guys, by changing which out of those
three things that can allow me
to overload the matter,
I change the number of parameters in here.
In here it was zero parameters in here
I passed one
parameter right?
So in here I was always overloading
the constructors by passing
how I am overloading
the constructors in this class.
Let me make it bigger.
So I am writing this same
constructor again and again.
But what I am changing in here,
how I am overloading this constructor
by changing the number of
parameters that I am passing.
So overloading the constructors
is also possible.
Guys,
someone please tell me that four fingers
does not mean three numbers.
Did I say four like this then? Yes.
It's adding new parameters.
So. So.
So let me repeat in how many ways I can.
I can overload methods.
Then is it three?
Yeah.
All right.
So I can overload the constructor
in three different ways.
Okay. Three different ways.
So there is also a dog
and a video on the internet.
So they ask you to
hold your hand like this
and put it on your chin.
But they are actually placing it
on your cheeks, right?
And the person cannot get it right.
Okay, so.
So I can also overload the constructors.
Yeah, I can overload three meters.
I can overload the constructors.
Can I also overload the
field two days.
Okay.
Do do we pass parameters to the fields
movie pass parameters to the field?
No, there.
There is no such thing for field,
so there is no assisting
field overloading.
Like if, if it was allowed
you guys will be
having this flexibility
that in one single class
you guys
would be creating a field with integer
and then the same name field with boolean,
same name field with double,
then we can see that
the field overloading is allowed.
But can we do that?
Can I read Declare a variable
with different data type in Java?
No. Right.
We cannot do that.
It's also not allowed
in other programing languages
you ask as masters questions.
We are working on
our certificate as there so
I am teaching
you how to be a master for hard.
No, and don't only learn
for that certificate.
Yes, that would mess up everything.
So now
if I have to
call these matters, but
I just pass.
I just to say
I just say
urd. Okay.
And if I pass to integers. Yes.
If I pass to integers.
So which method will be called right.
The first one. Right.
Because Java knows that I am passing
to integers
and Java automatically decides
which method to call.
If I was
one double
and one third, then
which method will be called twice
what I did.
I got an error that is not available
in this channel.
On line number seven what you are passing.
One, two, three four and five parameters.
So your matter.
But you have not defined any method
that accepts five parameters.
So you are indeed introducing this method
overloading in previous classes. Yep.
In constructors.
So you guys already knew about
about method overloading.
So posting
this for ten guys, I will help you out.
No. So. No.
And you guys can also check this out
as soon as I write the method name and
as soon as I pass the parameters.
You guys see,
the color of this method has been changed.
The color of this other methods
is kind of this.
Ladies, can you tell me
what is this color?
So, ladies,
so we we know only about seven colors.
The rest of the colors,
they are five ladies. Yes.
So what about being
a you see, like a faint
movie, purple, navy, blue, yellowish
sky blue,
blah, blah, blah.
So you guys see this deal color literally.
I'm getting this word
for the first time, black and white.
I only know
the it's kind of this deal color.
Okay. I don't know what is different.
So and the and the color for me.
And what is this
color is not it's kind of dark green.
Okay. It looks like black.
So as you guys write
the name of the method
the the in the java, the invalidate
also changes the color of the method.
And now and then you say yes, go to
you are now using this
method somewhere in your code.
But these this method these three meters
they are still not being used
so the color is also changed.
Even we execute this code
and because of this property
that Java knows, even
we before the execution of the code,
the Java knows which method will be called
because of this property.
It is also called hourly binding.
Okay, so writing a method name,
passing the arguments and knowing
before the execution which will be called,
is called hourly binding.
So method overloading or hourly binding.
There are other names
for this terminology as well.
We will learn about those as right. So
now, because I am passing
a double in here,
so large Java will do Java,
I will search this method Java with Jack.
Okay.
What is the first parameter
you're sending?
Pages.
So it's not a good match for this method.
So let's try to check the second method.
Okay.
Static binding, hourly binding
method overloading
compile time polymorphism
so there are multiple names for this.
So then Java Jacks, the next method,
the first parameter
you're targeting an integer,
but as other is passing a double.
So it's also not a good match for this
call than Java text.
The next method call.
This one is double.
Okay. If some match, then java text.
The second one is the integer.
Yes. So in here we have a perfect match.
So Java will call this method.
Okay, so this is how Java decides.
It takes all the parameters one by one.
It compares first with the matters
which are present in class.
If we have a perfect match,
then that method will be called.
If we do not have a perfect match,
we will be getting an error.
So Lubo was trying to do this.
So now Java what Java is trying
Java is checking if there is a method
which takes first argument
as the double, second as the integer part
as the double again.
So Java does not see any method
inside this class
which fulfills these requirements.
So if this is the case, we
Java will give you an error,
your compiler will give you an error.
Okay.
Is it clear, guys?
Okay, so
this is
and then I count Lubo near the break.
Why we put number two first at line 16.
Number Oh, it's just a name
you can write number one.
And number two, not nothing special.
How to call and add a there
You mean how to boss and edit
it saying its same
you declare an area right?
You're
declaring that there are new equal to
ten if the body just like this
will clear an area
after overloading or add
and then you pass the area like this.
Simple.
And now if I execute this code,
which of these two methods will Java take?
If the first parameter is double
and second parameter is flawed
since both take in decimals.
So Mohammad A you remember with the flaws
we boss that if right so
let me define one more matter
and let me make it
make it double.
Not in
and then let me make this one
explode. Yeah
go now
if I boss lastly, if I say
so, if you if you check
Mohammad if you check in here
that okay, I'm not putting any method
and you get on with it.
So let me copy this
and let me pass
by in five in here,
Okay, So
in the Mohammad, if you see
in here, actually
I don't want to go into these details,
but now if you guys have asked me,
so let me show you.
So you see
in here,
the color of this method
has already changed.
Okay.
The color of this method
is already changed because I am passing
two levels, but it is not highlighting
this one.
It is not highlighting this one.
Now, if I do this, so now what I am doing?
Mohammad.
Now I have two choices.
Okay?
I have this float and this double, right?
So remember about the typecasting and now
I have this choice.
So which one is more
perfect match moment this time?
The first one,
because at least one parameter is matching
and this other one,
although it is not matching, but remember,
we can add the up
costing is automatic, right?
The widening is automatic.
So what Java will do
because there is no loss of information,
the other parameter
will automatically be created
if there is no loss of information.
Okay, so Java tries to find
the best match possible.
Okay.
I hope it is clear. Do you guys understand
how Java desires
if there is a
there is very small difference.
So still java
be looking for the best match
and no information loss.
So you can even put an integer
inside the double plus in this case.
Yes, in all those cases, if Java can
if Java can convert it
to the data type without any loss,
Java will try to call that method
or try to call that method.
So Let me show you a more clear example.
Let's say
so let's say we
comment this method out.
Okay?
So now if you guys see this,
this ADD method
are if Java can't find the perfect method,
it's the best possible. Yes.
So now there is no perfect match for this
method.
Okay.
And now Java will not try
to convert the data type because
integer family.
They by the shark, the log.
They are in a different family.
The long and the flawed.
Okay, so now the convergent will they
the calling will not happen.
Okay, but they belong to the same family.
And if there is
a slight mismatch
and Java will up to the variable
and it will try to call that method and
there are so many variations on there.
So let let's not go there.
But it is possible. Yes.
Sometimes Java will try
will try its best to find a perfect match.
Okay.
But you guys don't need
to worry about that.
I hope.
I hope you guys are not confused.
Why are you put two parameters
and you have only one float?
And I'll just to show the example
just before the example. Yes.
Let me make your two smaller.
I hope you guys can you can read the font.
So let me uncomment this
like this.
So what we have done,
we have solved this problem.
One problem
that if I am doing the exact same thing,
I don't have to come up with different,
different names.
I can use the same name
and if I am passing different
number of parameters, different type
or in different sequence,
Java is allowing me
to have same method name.
Now there is one more,
so there is one more issue.
Can you guys tell me
there is still one more issue
in this code?
There is still more
and there is one more issue in here.
So let me do this, guys.
If so, let me move this method
in here.
So what is the difference
between this method and this method?
The data type is exactly the same,
but I am passing
different number of parameters.
What if I have to add phone numbers? Guys?
What if I have
the phone numbers?
I have to add
one more parameter.
Right?
Is it clear that if I have to add
four numbers, I have to add one more?
What if I have to add five,
six, seven, eight, nine?
And what if I don't even know how many
parameters the user will be possible?
That will pass.
I again have a problem, right?
I again have a problem.
So Andrew,
do you guys understand the problem?
So data type is same,
but sometimes I want to add two integers.
Maybe sometimes I want to add
three integers, sometimes maybe
I want to add 456.
I can add
I can add any number of parameters.
Right?
So does that mean I have to write
so many copies of this exact same method
by just varying the number of parameters?
Will it be a good approach?
Guys?
Is it a good approach?
So then if we pass an area,
if we use an editor,
can I boss parameters to that method?
Or I always have to first create an edit
and then pass
that very
problems
are never ending.
So I if I create an array,
I the user must pass an edit,
write user must pass another bar,
but a user does not want the Boston
area user either
maybe a prince or princess.
We can create them and.
Pass it so we don't have to.
Yes, I like you guys, right?
I am writing the code reading, the slides,
writing the laws,
but still princes and prince and princes
that they don't study.
Right.
So in that scenario, what we have to do,
what we can
do, can you do a loop inside the method?
The loop need to initialize
the number of data types
and it will air accordingly.
Yes. Mohammad
We will be doing something like that.
Okay, so there is something
special for this scenario.
It is called
what args variable number of audible max.
It is called lot args var sharp.
So what I can do
instead of writing
this same method
and again with the different parameters,
I can use this.
I can write the data type
and then three dots
that can make it bigger.
And then I can write something like this.
Okay, so
let me for
2 minutes second common to this up.
So the data type
then three dots like this
and then the name of the variable.
Now this name of the variable
is it is treated
as an anti. Okay.
But when you are calling that method,
it will be taking parameters
in, dividual parameters
instead of taking an edit.
Let me complete this code
so I can have some is equal to zero
for each
integer number,
which
inside the array.
Oops, not as out.
I have to do
some plus equal to numbers.
Okay.
Like this.
And then I can print out the same.
So now if I call this method
with an array,
as you see,
I have commented out this method
which was taking the array, but still
I don't get any added on this method.
Why? I don't get any
error on this method because now
this one single method
will take care of arrays will take care
if I pass
one parameter, two, three, four,
five and number of parameters.
All of this will be taken care of
by this single method.
Okay, so let's say I am passing.
Edit no issues.
I am calling the method with
with three parameters.
No issue.
I am calling it with four parameters.
I am calling it with five parameters
noise two.
I'm calling it with six parameters.
No issue.
I can pass any number of parameters
that the only restriction
now is that they should be integer.
I can pass one parameter
two, three, four, five.
I can pass an integer.
Any And this method, this dot dot thing,
it will take care of all of these matters
how much code we have reduced.
Otherwise we will
we would we could be writing so much code.
Right?
So this is called var args, right?
And even though even though
I remove these two methods, even though
I remove these, these two matters
integer float integer double double double
ambiguous method call and double in double
effort.
Okay, now remove the.
So now
actually for this example,
let me comment out everything.
Okay.
So these are taking different parameters.
So now what I am doing in here,
if we change the error name,
we can keep the other other method
or Java will be confused.
No, these names, this one,
it can be anything.
It can be same. It can be different.
Why only the we can use
no non we can use double string boolean
all the database,
even the classes
that you guys have been creating.
We can use those as well.
So I am passing two parameters
in here.
This method will be called I am passing.
123456 parameters.
This method will take care.
I am passing an edit.
This method will take care,
but all of them must be same.
Yes of them must be having cinematic type.
Okay.
All of them must be having same type.
So how useful this method is.
Okay. Yes.
Universal method. Right. And if I.
If you let me all of this
so I get the results for all the matters,
okay?
All the matters.
So whenever you guys are not sure
about the
about the number of parameters
like you don't want to restrict your user
to pass 1 to 3 and any
or anything like that you use divide out
when you are taking
the same data, type as the input
instead of rewriting the same method again
and again,
you guys should be using the lot method
if you have to deal with the areas
as well of the same letter type.
Instead of writing a separate method
for the area,
you guys should be writing a lot argument.
This.
Okay, so now let me uncomment this.
I guess there are so many teeny
tiny details
still with the method overloading
and how the resolution happens,
but we will not be going through them
because I see.
So the only thing that I want
you to understand is that if you have
if you have let me cut this code, yes,
you guys will definitely be confused.
So I will just give you a glimpse
of how you guys can be confused.
So the only thing that I want to tell you
is that if I am passing an area
to a method and if I am writing lot args,
we cannot these two meters
inside the same class.
Okay.
Now java will be confused because
actually this is treated as an area. Okay.
So either you can have an edit
or you can have a lot.
So these two, they are not allowed.
This is the only thing
that you guys should not write.
If you are writing a lot
are don't write the
same method with same name,
but with an array
being passed parameter in the dies.
The only restriction
because Java can not decide
if you are passing an A Java can not
Java can not decide
if it should call this method
or this method
or let's say it is not defined in Java.
Okay.
There could be a possibility
that if we are explicitly passing
an error, this method should be called
Yes, this is a possibility.
It could have been done,
but they have not done it.
So it is not allowed. Okay.
It is not true
and it gets confused easier than me.
You highlighted a block of code
and commented out with a click.
How did you do that?
So you can select a piece of code
and you can press control,
shape, forward, slash to comment.
And I'm to score.
Okay, let's
now there are more things
that can cause
a problem.
Okay, So if you guys notice and
I just want to tell you, but please.
Yes, don't try to think about those.
So we are getting an error on this line.
Right.
Okay.
So only
for those who want to go into in deeper.
So I have a method
that accepts the two integers.
I am passing two integers.
Can you guys
tell me why I'm getting an error?
So all those intellectual, big, brainy
students, there are two same methods
with same parameters.
Maybe it is confused in error
and integers.
So you guys are saying that
Java is confused about this ad
and this lot.
Okay, let me next let's try to
comment this out.
Okay?
Okay. So now
the error is gone.
And if
I comment this out.
So if I uncomment dark
and convert to this out.
So now
so I have commented out
this lot of okay, okay.
We have the same method directory at the
now we are
okay.
So if
this is one more rule.
Okay. Yeah.
It's not that difficult, but
it's good to know.
So now I have a method
that is taking two parameters
and I have a method
that is taking variable arguments.
You just want to think they are brain
get bored.
So can you guys tell me
which method will be called?
So if you see Java,
Java has highlighted this method.
Okay, this method Java is not calling
these matter, this method.
Aldo, Aldo.
So, so this is where the priority comes.
If I remove this method.
Okay,
Now there is this method which can take
the variable number of arguments
right in here I am passing to
in here
Now there is no method which can take
the exact same two integers.
Okay, so now what java is saying by saying
ambiguous method, call both
and into double and add a
double int in method is a match.
Okay.
So what java is trying to do
java is trying.
So this method
and this method
only the sequence is different.
Okay, so only the sequence is different.
So now we have two choices.
Either
I can convert this integer to a double
and I can call this, or
I can convert this
first integer to a double.
And I can call this method, right?
Do you guys understand this?
But don't we have over doing job
as in those same double for adding?
So yes, yes. This is my point.
This is my point. So my point is
even if we have lot args.
Okay.
So my point is,
even if we have lot of that
can handle this
this call it can handle this call.
Right.
Do you guys understand this
that these two parameters,
they can be handled by this method, right?
If I remove
in this method and if I remove this method
now this one will be called.
Okay.
So now if I say tandem,
this method will be called.
Yes, it can handle it.
But Java has priorities.
Okay, Java has binaries.
What are the priorities?
If there is a simple method
which does not take variable arguments,
which takes simple plain parameters,
even though Java has to
up, even though Java has to do
the convergence,
the last thing
it will try to call from those matters.
Okay.
So that's why what I will recommend
what I will recommend
if you guys are dealing with
if you guys are doing the exact same thing
and the parameters are same, never, ever
create again methods like this one
or this one or this one.
Okay, so this method, it
yes, it can handle everything,
but it has the lowest priority.
Let them simplify this,
even though this method
can handle everything,
but it has the lowest priority.
Okay, but is it clear?
Is there anyone who is confused
because you use a lot of memory
because of the priority?
Because of the priority
but what arguments it can handle?
Same better type?
Yes, same data type, same letter.
So when to use it, always try to use it.
Never ever look at methods.
Always try to use it.
The confusion of Java confuses me
why Java is confused.
So the simpler
because the higher the priority.
I Yes, you guys can say that.
Yes, you guys can say that.
Or this very simple.
Yes, this method can handle a
lot of parameters,
but the priority is lowest. Yes.
Before we talk Java, they are two numbers.
So it's automatically going to use that
in our targets.
Infinity in Java will choose
only when there is an option.
Yes, not perfect, but to pass to doubles.
What are the method
should be passing double? Yes.
It cannot handle double.
Be careful about your method creation.
Make it simple
just to make it clear for myself
what we lost of information
while taking the low priority.
There is no no.
Not a loss of information
now is lazy.
Java has so many rules.
So tell me guys, here's what I do.
I was planning to not.
I was planning to not sure
this call
of double
converting to in this convergence of
double
doubles this everything but everything.
I was not planning to show you
it to you guys.
So what do you guys say?
Was it a good idea
or you guys are more confused now?
Or is it better to know about new things?
Should I Sure would.
To know
all via.
So maybe I will try to show some advanced
things that always you confused
and then ask us later after we are so
so I told you the disclaimer pass right?
I told you don't don't focus on
what what I am trying
what I'm going to show you now.
So when I say something,
those who do not want
to go in deep into Java,
you guys can just be on break
or start downloading this stuff.
So let me write it in here.
Can handle any
number of parameters and
ADD is
Bert has the lowest
choreography.
Yeah, whatever you are teaching us,
I cannot ignore.
Okay, then I will not show you.
Can we do the same with the double? Yes.
So do you guys want me to do
create the method with double in here
or create a new class?
New place.
And let's.
Let's do it after the break. Okay.
Let's do it after the break.
This little confused
for the last two months,
if we are very global
all, by the way
before
you guys don't want to break you guy
you guys have been using a method
so many times,
almost all the classes
and that method was overloaded.
Can you guys tell me
the name of that method
from the day?
First, you guys have been using
an overloaded method heavily.
No, it's so simple. Give
this out a lot of fact, Alex.
You guys see in printout
I can pass two parameters.
Three, I pass Booleans double,
then page are the strings.
It never complained
how easy your life was.
So this is the benefit of overloading
you guys see this
this out This println
method is an overloaded method.
Let me show you
the implementation of this.
So if I hold on my control
and if I click on the superintendent,
you will see what intel and method of it
double play parental and method
with dot x parental method of string,
parental and method with object.
And if you guys full of parental end
with flawed
beyond with long and char
all those overloaded method,
it made your life a whole lot
a whole lot easier.
And you guys never even realized
this, right?
So this is the benefit of overloading
a real, real life example.
So all those parental methods,
all those matters
in the same exact method,
doing the same exact thing, but
with the different type of parameter
it was always with this
I have a new appreciation for.
So can you show me one more time
how to comment about one block of board?
You have to tell us
that the first class and yes,
and you guys have understood it perfectly.
What is an overload, right?
If I tell you in the first class, no.
So there are so many things
that I will tell you later,
but you guys are using them now.
It's actually a
what do we say?
There is a special word for
that when we have to criticize someone
and we would tell the exact same
thing in a different world.
You just slept with my mind.
What do we call it?
Satan.
Although a 10th
when we have to do tons.
So, Farhad, you must have hired in
in in order to do dramas.
In the dramas,
sarcasm. Here we go.
So bolus school, a big cable,
but so in, in, in, in Asia there
is this something very common
that if the mother in law
she has to tell something to her
the device of our son,
she she yells at someone else.
And but she's actually saying to that
to go
that way.
All right, perfect.
Do you guys also have this thing
Iranians do
we have that provided in Farsi to.
We don't do that with the husbands.
We do that
with the husbands also. All right.
Not only in Asia. Yes.
It's an Arabic word.
Yeah, I out you have the word.
And what I did had we settled the door,
so we all should listen.
All right, All. And there's also. Good.
So let's have a break for people to 12.
And so just to be clear, we should use
this simple overload method instead of
unless it is necessity.
No, you should always go with what water
first.
And if you are really doing
something different,
then you should pass the parameters.
Then you show me on how to comment on it.
Okay,
so this is how we select the piece of code
and then we put we press control,
shift and forward flash to commit it out.
And again,
control shift forward slash to uncomment
this, I just need to plan something.
I think 15 minutes are enough.
Or maybe let, let me check
if you guys can solve some tasks
so maybe we can have a longer break.
Oh, yes, you guys can.
Most of this in the
course announcement center
so that you guys can play as well
for we'll
these are simple tasks.
Okay.
So let's have a longer break
and I will push the code as well.
Can you guys check
if you have got the update or not?
It looks for you simple for all the work.
So let's have a break here 1220 and try
to solve as many questions as possible.
Guys, what is the area of box
you guys can google it.
It's very simple length multiplied by it.
If it is a rectangle, length
multiplied by length,
if it is a square.
Yes. Guys try to do these tasks.
Yes. Google memo at the class.
We have some question
and helping with great help, please.
Oh, yes.
Remind me at the end of the class I will
show you some tricks about your cup.
Short break.
I use a short break.
35 minutes.
And do you guys have any questions
before we go on the break?
All right,
partners, 12:00, is it what, ARG
or what are law on a r
a lot better.
So guys
try to have 10 to 15 for your break.
Okay.
And after that, guys
can try to solve these tasks.
If you try it first, believe me,
it will make a lot more sense
when I will be solving these tasks.
So I want you to try
at least go through the requirements
and try to have that imaginary solution
in your mind so that you can understand
it better when I am solving it.
All right, guys,
reminding me about the recording of my by
device
back.
Do you guys have any questions
before we start the homework? No,
we only two from. Me too.
It's fine.
That's great. So?
So let me close these files.
Yes, we are.
Yes, I was feeling a little cold,
so that's why
I took scored.
So can you guys send me
the requirements for the task?
One? What?
Is having some kind of issues?
No, these are
just tasks.
Create a class in which create a method
that will calculate
the area.
Word task.
Easy or hard
are. Yes.
So same name method.
You guys created different names
for these methods, but
I named it. Yes.
For for the volume one.
It makes sense to make volume
for the other tools.
It should be area
right? It should be the area
of the public.
Lloyd,
Calculate
calculate area.
Right.
And I named it one oh, I thought it was
the same volume for all of them.
Yes, you can have volume for all of them.
Give me if you want to write in here
we are using
length, double
or. All right, guys.
So how can I check from the length
and the weight
if it is a rectangle or square,
because the formulas they are,
what are the different
I used?
What are the
Because it will multiply in all matters
Multiply in all matters.
If they are equal, then rectangle.
And if they are not equal,
then what will be the area?
So what will be the formula for the area?
It will still be.
I can still use the land to it right?
It does not matter
if it's a rectangle or a square.
I can still
use length, length, length
and to be tried.
Do you guys understand this point
or I can not do that, but
so if it's a square
block, then think about this as a square.
So land into which the area will be
length in width, right?
If it's a rectangle in which
the length and width they are not same,
we can still multiply the length length
in the weight to get the area right.
So I don't have to come up
with different method name
because I intentionally
I am still doing the same thing
right. But
how many of you
for this example like this
just in this task
remind me high school
just so create
one class in which create a method
that will calculate
the area volume in the case of rectangle,
Square and box.
Okay, so one of the approaches is
is can be to create
a separate method to calculate
volume.
Okay.
Because for volume
how many parameters we need,
we need a third parameter
height as well.
Okay.
So, so what we can do is
we can pass this third
parameter in here and we can put
and if condition in here,
but it will not make sense because,
well, you are calculating the area
in one method and calculating the volume.
Another method I did.
What is that Correct.
Because volume of a box is lent in to
it and height.
So you created only one method.
MUHAMMAD Can you show me the code?
Okay,
yes, creating one method.
And if you are planning to use the same
method, let's say maybe you can call this
method, calculate area
or volume inside the same method.
You can name it 80 or volume.
Yes, we go and like like the AMA is right.
And then you guess, yes, you can.
You guys can create
if it's a perfect approach,
no issues that
I think it's
also good.
Yes, yes, yes, it's good.
No issues with that as well.
It should also work fine.
Okay. So
so the point of this exercise
was either create a name that conveys
all the information,
like what the method is doing, all of it,
or don't always try to use overloading
if it is not making sense.
Please don't try to use
overload overloading. Okay.
Only use overloading
when you are essentially
doing the same thing again and again
in different methods again.
So if you are calculating volume
and in one place you are calculating
idea, it's
not a good practice to call this method.
Always maybe calculate area
or maybe always call it calculate volume
and then put everything inside that method
so it will be an over use of overloading.
So you always have to come up with the
perfect portion of creating these methods.
Does it make sense right. Oh,
okay.
So in there, smile
in here.
Okay.
It's the task.
One task
one or that area
I pass.
So you guys see
I am passing integers in here,
but actual parameters low doubles.
So what is going on? Why?
I am not getting any better.
What is happening behind the scenes?
Gasping is working. Right?
So Java if there is so if I had one method
in which I had both the parameters
as integers.
What? What do you guys think?
Which method java choose
would have to
the integer one or the double one?
So let's say if I
if I create a method,
but instead if I pass
integers in here.
So now you see this one has changed,
the intensity has changed this color
and now Java is using this integer one.
So if it if it has a perfect match,
the priority will be given to that method.
If no Java will try to find something
as close as possible
without losing any information,
if that is possible.
Okay.
Is it clear, guys?
But if one of them double, then double.
You mean if you
if we put the double in here
like this.
So still, which method is, is,
is more close to the parameters,
this one or this one.
Which one is more close to the parameters.
That we are passing the first one. Right.
So standard Java will prefer this method.
Okay.
Because at least one
parameter is exactly matching.
Okay.
Still at least one
parameter is exactly matching.
So is it clear now?
Okay, so that's how it works.
So what you guys can do always,
if you are writing integers and doubles,
you can simply ignore the integers once
because doubles
can handle integers as well.
Okay guys,
that if you have to write pool methods,
one for integer and one for double,
always go with double because double
can handle the integer as well.
Right.
Okay.
Let's turn now to not make it
more complicated, but All right.
So there is one more thing, guys.
There is still one more issue that
even if I have integers or doubles, right.
But still
I am doing simply addition, right?
There must be a way to remove
that duplication as well.
What do you guys think?
So if, if I am doing this,
I am still not doing that much
different things in these two matters.
Right?
Or maybe even if I create a method
that is taking a bite or a long.
So let's say, for example,
if I change
it to a long
like this or one double silly,
there is a little bit change of parameters
So still I am doing the exact same thing
just because I have a primitive data
types.
Should I be writing
at least like 4 to 5 meters
to handle those
those primitives, those that are types?
No. There is one more thing
that is called the concept of genetics,
but that is something that happens
if we use genetics.
We don't have to worry at all.
If we are always dealing with the numbers,
if we are always dealing with numbers,
that number can be a by ten page
long short
double float.
I can handle all of these
six data types with a single method
with the help of genetics,
but that is something advanced.
If we had some time, I will show.
I will show you that.
But if we do not have time, we will not
be discussing that because that something
that those who want to have a look,
you guys can look on the Internet.
It's called genetics.
It's not mandatory, by the way.
It's not required for this course.
So we will be keeping things simple.
So there is still a way to remove
that reputation as a
we will start a petition
to get rid of invader
like perfect.
So and this was before task one.
This is one of the ways to solve it.
If you guys have created only one method
to solve all of these two tasks,
I would say create two matters
because in one we are calculating volume
and one we are calculating
Can you make smaller
to see the cause of task?
One You want me to show the complete code
like this?
Okay, perfect.
So let me know once you guys are done
writing this code
or and I can move to the next task
as the code.
You give us an example
in which the data types will be boolean.
Yes, we can have that.
So remind me
after we are done with these tasks,
I will do that.
Okay.
So in one case
I am passing a rectangle near relentless.
Then they will take 15.
In one case I am passing a square
in which to go to length
and they are same.
So now.
Now I will always be insecure
in this matter.
Yeah. So let me close this.
Can I close these files?
The task tool was
gaining a certain many tasks to
create a class named programing.
Okay.
Their area is equal to a multiplied
by two box
to and to with two hard.
And the the last the second line.
It's not an area.
I think it's the parameter formula.
No, no, no.
This is not the formula. So
idea of
rectangle
it's length into width
area of square.
So it's a square
which means I am multiplying length
with length or width with, with.
But because they are all same.
Because they are all same,
so it does not matter.
Okay. So.
Okay, there's
this surface area box
now, right?
To create a class name for programing.
Why creating an object of the class
if nothing is possible to it,
then the message I love programing
languages should be printed. Hmm.
So can you guys tell me, should I create
a method or should I create a constructor?
Because it is saying
when creating the object of that class
if nothing is passed,
no one may suggest that
that was the point, right?
You guys should focus.
So in here it is clearly clearly mentioned
when while creating
an object of the class,
if nothing is passed.
Right.
So when we are creating the object,
we are actually calling the constructors,
not the methods. Right?
So we show the door
because I wanted to have this practice
that the constructors
can also be overloaded.
Okay, so how can I create the constructor?
It's the same as the name of the class.
All right then parentheses and then.
Right.
You guys can put public as well
if you like.
So if nothing is passed
then I love programing.
Languages should be put into it.
Okay.
How many of you created methods
instead of constructors? The
the. That's
how we fail in exams because in exams
there is this slight variation
that we always ignore
and we get something different
in the
reward message.
Message?
You want an
So do you mean
you are also not overloading it
even if you have created the method
so you are still not loading
your overloading your tried
you are
you are creating a different matter name.
So then that is also not correct.
The same way I did
I methods with the same name.
So it overloads depends on the parameters.
So for the constructors as well,
the the overload
depends on the parameters.
At least I overloaded for the second.
Plus if something is passed to it,
then the in the place of programing
languages, the value of the variable
should be printed.
Right? So
this time
I will be having an event here
but in value.
Right.
And instead of programing languages,
the value of this variable
should be printed like this.
Right?
So then that was the task is it
must be a constructor in this case, yes,
because it is mentioned
while creating an object of the class
if nothing is passed or it
could mean that means I am saying
about the constructor
either clear
because in real life guys,
you will never be getting these
exact same things in the requirements
that they will not be saying.
Create a constructive
and positive parameters to it.
Whenever it is talking about.
Always create constructor
the there is and other conditions
I show which condition
if we pass java.
So I love programing language
should be printed.
If some if some string is possible,
then in place of programing
language, the value variable
should be printed example.
If we pass Java then I love java should be
printed. Okay.
So it is just an example
when you will be calling this method.
So this time let me clear the main method
inside the same class.
Let me see new
programing.
Right?
So if I write this piece of code,
what will I see on my console
guys, this
class is out
right?
I love programing languages
and if I pass something
I am creating the object.
Then I will see.
I love Java.
Is it clear
that we know once you guys are done
diving this code
there?
So all it was the person
and I closed
this file.
Let's
subtract
like that by task.
Yes. My limit.
How how, how is your wrapper going?
Is enjoying it
can be more repulsive.
Yes, there are more wrappers.
So there are around
I guess 100 or 150 more ripples.
So don't worry about that
struck me in one.
They're killing me.
Woman
You can pull starting the sport channel,
moving slow,
but removal, I mean, there's great
one. You are doing it.
It's easy.
But when it comes going to do it
and complicated.
Is it okay to load up a little
after doing it?
Yes, it's also fine,
but you should always be doing
and you should always do it.
So I will be releasing the wrappers
related to these concepts
after tomorrow's class. Okay.
So there are wrappers related to this.
No, don't worry about that.
So let's do the task three
already.
They send me the requirement for task
three
task that it will do it
in class, create a class with the starting
MATLAB, pass three overloaded
phones, then call each overloaded method
with specific argument of set.
You guys have already done it,
but let me add the boolean
or other data types to it
so that you guys can understand it
necessary for saying for example,
the next to that
are let's create a static method
and think wide
method and let's pass
a boolean in here.
Okay, I'm
getting an error guys,
because I cannot overload a method
with the same name
and same data type, same that our type.
So the stereotype must be different.
Then I can write the same method again.
Oops.
Maybe this time I can pause the double
and press three.
I It was maybe this time
and add a
numbers of things.
Yeah, I can basically pass any I type,
I can box any time
and I can do
one more thing guys.
Do you guys know?
Or you can also pass
glasses and objects in here.
So for example, you,
the class that we have just created
this programing class,
I can also pass the objects of that class
like this.
Then we can have some variations as well.
And these one and then
boolean
bool. Okay, I can also do there.
So basically any combination
of data types.
Okay.
Any of barometers.
Okay. And any,
any parameter inside that method.
So now if I have task
to be tested in here,
if I say task for the DOT
method and if I passed a false,
can you guys tell me
which method will be called?
So let me make this class
a little smaller.
But then
we like get the line
to three of the excursion before
and then four
and then six.
So tell me the number
on my console.
I will be getting one right.
Easy peasy.
All right, get one.
Because Java is now calling this matter.
Is there anyone who don't understand
why this method
being called?
Okay, index, but that's perfectly fine.
So now
what is the
type of this value
that I am passing in here?
What is the data type?
What do we call it?
It's a boolean, right?
So boolean can have bool values
true and false, right?
It can have two or worlds.
So this class
now Java will decide
which method to call.
So lower
java do Java will go inside this class.
Right.
And when Java goes inside this class,
Java is multiple multiple matters.
All having the same name, all having
the name method method method method.
So now in java is confused.
So java is okay.
There are so many matters and all of them
they are called methods.
So what do I do now then? Java checks.
What is the value
that that is passing to this method?
So Java sees that.
So that is passing a boolean value, right?
A boolean value.
So Java will say, okay,
let me find let me try to find a method
maybe which is expecting a boolean value.
So Java will again
go in here double digit.
I will say
okay, let's try to get this fast method.
Does it take a boolean value?
Yes, it is taking a boolean value
as the result of passing a boolean value.
So this is a good match.
Perfect match, right?
Deep dive.
That category is passing
I have that method.
So let's call this method.
And that's why we see this one in here.
Please explain line 23.
The parameter is an integer array,
but the string.
Oh yes, it's just a typo,
so let me make it
a string.
Adding
space.
Okay, so job.
I will call this matter.
And if I fast like.
So now you guys will tell me
if I boss, let's say of me be
a long value in here.
Okay?
If I was maybe ten and then I'll.
So which method will be called?
So these arguments
I have a method that is taking double
spin boolean string programing integer.
And will you
to the 1919
third line
the word.
Can you guys tell me I am not
I do not have
a method which exactly takes the
the the the the long value.
So so why,
why are you always calling this double.
My java is calling this type
costing.
So can you guys tell me
which data type is bigger.
The long or the double
which one is bigger.
And the double is a bigger data
type than long,
which means I can see, if li convert
a longer value to double.
And that's what the Java is doing.
Java is saying, okay, good.
I know there is not a perfect match
inside this class, but you know what?
I can use this double and I will not.
We will not be losing any information.
So yes, we do not have a
perfect match, but we have something
that can be very close
in which we can still use this method
if I do the convert again.
So I will do the conversion.
We will not lose any information
and we will be able to use this method
digitized, clear.
So it's the same case
when we pass integer n double.
If there is a method that takes integer
java, we'll use that if no
and if we have a method
that takes double,
then it will use the double line.
Okay.
All right.
Perfect.
Is there anyone who is confused
when I am passing along?
Y why double is being called?
So if I pass a float,
which method will be called
tail three?
So do you guys understand this now?
Why I always stress to why I always
ask you to use doubles
Dart double is very powerful.
It's the biggest delta type in numbers.
Double can handle long
double can handle floor integer.
It can handle by almost everything.
Okay without any problem.
So that's why double.
I always recommend double.
Okay.
So now
it is also more common.
And if I if I create an object
of programing programing new
programing, and if not, let me make it
so because the constructor is not
public and I am trying to use it
in different package,
that's why I get this error.
Okay.
Is it poor guys why I am getting this
error on this programing?
It's because of D
access.
Modify it if I assure you
we are in this task pre package.
But programing is in task tool
and the constructor of programing.
What is the access modifier
in here guys for programing
is the default one
and can access the default ones
in different
packages. No.
So what should I do?
What should I do it in here?
If I want this code to work,
I should write public.
I should write public in here.
Now the Senate is gone, right?
And I can pass
this programing in.
Now, which method will be called?
Which line will be printed,
be line fi.
Okay.
So far
the first task is the one this okay.
And I see three B this one I again
see three
And if I pass what I'm getting this line
guys, I love programing.
I don't have this line in class. Why?
I'm getting this line.
I don't have this line in class,
in this cross.
I am confused. Magic
Here we go.
Constructor.
What I am doing in here guys,
I am calling the constructor of programing
and it is coming from that constructor.
It is not magic.
It's like it's Java.
And then if I pass programing, object
to this matter
now and I know that that is trying to pass
an object.
So let's print out five.
Okay. Is it better now?
Is your understanding better now?
All right, we will do more examples.
Okay.
We've written more examples.
Are you guys done typing this code
to connect all these files
or is there anyone who is still typing
and you are magician?
I keep getting an error for programing.
Michael, can you show me the error?
Can we overload the method in subclass?
No, sorry we can do that.
Overloading happens when we
are inside the same class.
Did you make all of them public?
Michael.
Make sure the constructor of programing
is public.
It is public
and can you show me
your programing class?
Okay. And show me
where you are passing this object as well.
So then we call it It will get the s
out of both constructors and this month.
No, no.
Only one constructor will be called.
Okay. So you are
the D class, the programing class
inside the spec package.
Can you show me that as well?
The ask three test mean.
And how about your mouse over the other
D programing class
and show me the add on as that.
What is the add on that you are to?
Can you please explain why
we need to write line ten in
task three test or no we we don't.
Why don't guys can also do this
instead of this?
You're going to have to do this.
You guys don't.
You don't need that line.
Can a boolean be an object? No.
The primitives, they are different.
Click on this first first option
that says import
class, the blue one that you see.
Click on that and import this class.
So if you remove this line from here,
so if you don't import this class,
I will be getting the same issue.
Okay.
You need to import in this class
because now
we are in a different package.
Now we need to import this class.
If the classes
they are inside the same package,
we don't need to import it,
but if the classes
they are in different packages
then we need to import.
And those classes
let me know
if this issue is resolved or not.
Because
Silver, you are also
getting some kind of issues.
They come out of the semi-colon.
Michael is the issue resolved?
So Shareef
objects And primitive
data types, they are two different things.
Okay?
Objects are the objects, the data types.
They they are created from classes.
This class you can drive this class or in
this class can be from Java guys,
but primitives,
they don't have these classes behind them.
Okay, These are the primitive data types
which are created without
and they are, they are actually classes,
but they are hidden from the programmers.
So that's why we cannot do that.
That issue is at all.
But getting this error below, Yes,
you will be getting an error
because you are missing the name.
So after posting and square brackets
you need to specify the name for the array
and then after the as well, or remove
that comma and make sure that s is lower.
Then you can remove that.
Please explain.
Line it in best line
in here I am passing a longer value
Muhammad
L means long.
It can be capital, it can be lowercase.
Michael Now, so Michael,
this is what you have to do.
You are having a semi,
you are having a coal mine here like this.
So you have to remove that comma.
You have to remove that comma in there
to make it
look, Are there
other students who are facing any issues?
Look, no
genius level D, whether
it's because I have faced these issues,
but now I have spent a huge amount of time
and believe me, there was no one.
So when you are in the universities
professors, they only have like
in big, you can only meet them like one
or two are to discuss the other issues.
And believe me, if you if you issues,
they are things like missing a semicolon
or things like that.
The professor will be very angry
if you meet him to ask
to discuss these kind of issues.
So we all the students in the hostel,
we were all struggling on our own.
Can you tell it
as a comprehensive definition?
Overloading? Yes.
We will discuss that.
Okay, let's do the last task. Then I will
go to the slides
and after that we will do more examples
if something is still not clear.
So send me the last
last question.
Create a class with private matter
that has three overloaded.
So guys, these tasks when you solve them,
also try to learn the rules
from these tasks.
So now you guys know
constructors can be overloaded.
Now you know methods can be overloaded
now, you know,
private methods can be a little bit
if you guys have solved these tasks.
Okay, so this is how you will understand
the rules better.
So do you always clear new back?
It is going to engage task?
No, no, it's just to organize it better.
So this is that in general
we have these two proteins had done body.
I was feeling more comfy with the clips
but I want to use intelligent.
What do you really more recommend for me?
Let me let me show you
and then you guys can decide on your own.
Can you explain line 11, this one as well,
this line.
Okay.
So can you guys explain this
line to nozzle?
What? What I what we are going in here
is calling the constructor,
calling the constructor,
creating the object.
Now I understand how you call it.
So this is a short way
of creating an object of a class.
Now, this is a short way of,
creating the object of a class.
And when we created the object, yes,
definitely.
The constructor is called okay.
And it is related to this method because
see in method on line 27,
this method is expecting
an object of class programing.
That's how it is related.
So when we will be passing the object,
this method will be called
Is it clear now?
So you see,
we create the object of a class
we store in a variable off
type that class of type in that class.
So I am also expecting a parameter
off type.
This class
nested.
I'm expecting a barometer of type
this class
or you can see that
I am expecting an object of this
class.
Is it clear now?
What are the shortcuts of importing?
So are you guys still writing the import?
No, no, no, no, no. What? While?
No, no, this is intelligent manual.
You don't have do anything
in an intelligent.
Open this window.
Double click on double click
your shift button.
Open this window.
You let me know
Once you guys have opened this window
type auto
import, then
do you guys see this auto import?
Do you guys see this auto import?
Click on that
and make sure there this option that says
add unambiguous import on the fly.
It is clicked.
Make sure this option is clicked
and then you guys
don't need to import anything
after
this.
Let me let me show you.
So it's double click or double click
your shift button.
Yes. Not even scanner.
Nothing. A
double shift, double
click on shift button twice.
Then type auto import.
I said, Do you see this now
click on that
and then make sure
this option is selected.
Why was not that on by default?
So when you guys installed
the intelligent, you guys did not have
this option turned on.
Oh, maybe intelligent being
so that you guys feel more comfortable.
You are switching from Eclipse.
Okay.
I don't know why
this option is not checked.
It should be checked.
We are suffering from importing.
Okay.
We'll still have this issue.
No ability.
You don't have any method. So me the
task three class.
Make sure you have this method
that is expecting
programing object.
If you don't have this method
then you will be getting this issue
also.
It also sure will help you out.
So if you guys think
there is more load on the support
channel, then yes, you can pause in here.
You'll need to give it a space auto
and then in the import
there should be a space.
Third of my third programing is there.
I guess to start
it will show me your packages as well
and also make sure
that you have that import
in here.
I don't have import, but it works.
So I say it might be working
because you might be creating the classes
inside of the same packages
those who are following me
and creating the classes
in different packages.
It will not work
if you don't import that class
again.
I will let let
me know if you still face the issue. So
all right.
So we were discussing about the task
for you guys.
Can you send me to task for
are we recording?
Yes, we are recording. I'm just waiting.
Okay.
So create
one class with the private method.
Third Test three overloaded forms.
Ask four.
So close this file.
Are you guys done typing it? Yes.
Create a class with the private method
that has three overloaded volumes.
Then call each overloaded method of a
specific article and observe the results.
Okay.
How to close out north?
I tried clicking on that x button
so it is not working.
Sebastian Is not closing the nodes.
So for example,
if I have this file, I want to close this.
I just click on the text.
Okay. So
otherwise you can
you can try to close the job.
I know you need this.
You need to I open and backup.
You need to close and re-open
the intelligence.
Yeah, I know you know this. Okay.
So I let me clear this are private
method.
That's why I'm getting an arrow.
Guys.
Void, right?
I am missing the return type.
So there is one more new thing
that I want to show.
Focus on it in here
again, I overload
the method
if I just change this return time guys,
Maybe if I return an integer from this
method
and I overloaded.
No, we cannot. Not.
So the overloading happens
based on the name and parameters.
And you guys tell me why changing
the return time does not allow to overload
the method.
Galois gets confused,
maybe with parameters because
it's so.
Imagine guys you are calling your method
and you are passing the same parameters.
Then how do Java know if it has to call
the method that is returning something
or the method is not returning anything?
Okay, you are passing the same parameters.
How does Java know that the method
with the return type should be called
or the method without having that void?
The return type should be called
again.
That's why it is not allowed.
So I must pass
a number. Maybe in here. Okay.
Or maybe I can do from this
and then I can pass
a string in here.
Yeah, and
that's fine.
So I have overloaded three methods.
Can I create file and different task
for test on file for best.
These methods?
No, because these matters,
they are private and private methods.
We only call the private and we can only
call the private methods inside
the same class.
Okay.
All right.
Do I need an object to call these matters?
Or I can just write their names
and I can call This
matters
one question
we do the done with constructor,
not in method.
I am confused.
One question
we do return with constructor does matter.
No, no, no.
You are saying it were in reverse order.
We don't return with the constructors
but we return with the matters.
And if I make it static
and I call it without creating the object
just by writing its name. Now
this method, can I call it?
Yes we can. Okay.
And have you guys noticed that?
Okay, let me do this. If,
if I change
the the, the excess modifier,
can I overload the method? No.
Okay.
Having private with one method and public
with the other method.
It also we can also overload
a method with this information.
Can I maybe make one method
a static
and other metric instance instance?
And can I overload it all again?
I can not overload so overloading only
and only happens with method name
and its parameters.
Is it paradise?
Okay,
so now
because these methods they are instance
methods and I am inside a static method,
I can not directly write
the name of the method to call it.
I create an object of this class
and then only I can all be met there.
Right?
If I don't pass anything,
which method will be called?
Guess
the best one.
Okay.
This one.
So I end security scored.
I get wide.
Okay.
This one will work.
Yeah.
And now the return type is integer.
Okay.
If I pass in number like then.
Now which which method will be called
baseline.
Right.
So integer method.
And then if I pass this thing,
this method will be called.
Okay, so
access modifiers,
non access modifiers, return types,
they have no impact on overloading
only the method of name
and of these and barometer
as they participate in overloading,
there is another name for the method, name
and parameters.
There is other terminology.
Can you guys tell me that?
Can you call this string?
Can you call the string? Yes.
So let's say if we use double course
arguments,
no signature and here we go.
So overloading happens
only with signatures.
Okay. Okay. Let me put
something in here
so that you guys can see the difference.
So only
and only the signature of the method.
Words that mean with signature.
Can you guys tell now what is
what is the signature of a method?
And I will be back in just 2 minutes.
Okay.
But this written five is something ready
and it's just bare
because otherwise if I return anything,
I will be getting another.
So I just
write it and five is
useless.
Am I right with the not in java?
Overloading in method means to define it
multiple times with same name
but different method signature. Yes.
If you are right,
can you go up to see the code? Yes.
Let me make it smaller.
I hope you guys can see it now.
So guys tell now about the method.
Signature? What is it?
I will be back in one minute.
So, Nihad, the method signature
is method the name plus experiment.
So this part of a method is called
method signature.
And this part from here till here
include adding
excess modifier, non excess modifier
return type.
What is it called guys?
It's the header of the method
parameter name or parameter type.
Yes, the integer and and actually
the list of all the parameters.
And then this one
is the body of the method.
Okay.
All right.
Let's
show him over to the slides.
Like at the end. Yes.
Do you guys have any questions?
So those who are the. Yes.
I hope we will be having a second break
if you guys we can have.
But this will be a shorter one.
So those who are who are asking
whether you guys
should use intelligent
or whether you should be clips,
this is the platform.
It is called stack share.
Every tool that is being
used in the IP sector right now.
You can find out
how many companies or how many developers
are using that tool.
Okay.
So if I say around browse stacks
and if I type in fairly
dear.
Wow, any place big went to
I don't want
my freedom, then.
So you guys can compare all the tools
that are being in the industry.
Okay,
so these are the three popular ideas.
So as you guys can see
specs, So stacks mean these much people
they are using Eclipse,
The stacks are 2.1 in here.
But for intelligent it's almost 30.
Okay so 30 times more need
are 1.9 give followers but intelligent.
There are 23.9 followers.
There are three edify
words and intelligent.
We have 1.5 and then this netbeans
15 has 15 times more.
And these stairs,
they were a little in favor of Eclipse
five years before,
but they are declining very rapidly.
I don't see Eclipse after two years.
I don't see it leaves.
It will be any company
that will be using Eclipse.
So now it's totally up to you guys.
Which ID you guys want to use.
And you guys can compare
all the technologies,
everything that you guys will be learning,
all the tools and everything.
Okay, so you guys can make the decisions
on your own.
Okay?
Is not being new one.
I think the NetBeans is the oldest one.
Yes, the oldest one.
I am wondering why we were not using
intelligent at the beginning of the class
because there are still companies
who like to use Eclipse.
So we have not we do not have any choice
but to at least show you 14 classes
how eclipse work.
That's one of them.
But yeah, it's just beginning.
You guys will be learning selenium,
you guys will be learning best
and you guys will be learning
cucumber APIs all for all of those.
You guys will be needing an ID, but,
but don't tell this information.
If some instructors they want to use
Eclipse, don't tell them that
I told you not to use the eclipse.
Okay.
It depends on the state
because they can use any ID
to teach you.
Okay.
I don't want you to share sending them
as they told us.
That's what showed us this.
Okay.
I'm just getting whichever ID
you guys are comfortable with.
You guys can use.
Okay, let me close this.
Sorry about that.
You guys are telling us that.
So method overloading. Okay,
so method overloading is whenever.
Same method.
The name is existing multiple times.
Okay, so we have multiple methods,
but the name is same.
Okay.
In this same class
with different number of parameters.
So either
the number of parameters are different
or most
probably she will be doing the review
or the order of the parameters
is different
or the different order of parameters
or different types of parameters.
So either the type is different, either
the type is different
or the number of parameters are different
or the sequence are different.
Are these different from us?
Are they should not be different?
Are the different.
So what do you
what do you guys see on on those lines
this large?
They are two batches, all like us
or want them back.
There should hardly be any difference
or No, no, no is they?
This slides the method overriding
is the next class actually.
So class won't be.
I Think I shared the slides
for the next one
so I will be sharing the
I hope this slide.
They should be there.
So you guys are opening this large class.
Bronte
right now
and you'll see method overwriting in here.
Okay.
And let me check what is inside
class 19 then
19 is super.
Oh, so we are missing the method
overloading.
Okay,
I will share those slides, don't they?
I will share both slides.
Okay.
So whenever same method,
the name of the existing multiple times
in the same class
with different number of parameters
or different order of parameters
or different types of parameters,
it is known as method overloading.
Okay,
so the method should be in the same class.
The name of the method should be same,
but parameters can differ.
Java does not allow
overloading by changing the return type.
Okay.
No overloaded
matters can change the return type.
So do you guys understand this paragraph?
So. So it says
if I only change the return type,
I cannot overload method
but an overloaded method.
Maybe it is having different parameters
or different types of parameters.
It can have a different
return type.
So let's go back to this example
in here. This method overloaded, right?
It has integer, it has void,
and it can have double as well.
Okay. So if we are overloading
a method already,
it can have a different return type.
But because this method is
being overloaded with help of parameters.
Okay.
But if you try to only overload
just by changing the return type,
then you cannot do that.
Okay.
Is clear now.
So he.
No, I cannot overload.
I cannot overload a method
by just changing the return type.
That that's what it means in simple works.
I must change the parameters.
This is what it means in simple.
And then if I have changed the parameters,
I can have different return types.
It also does not work.
If you change the return type, then
you need to change the parameters also.
Yes, but you are right for our.
Do you understand this return thing now?
So I can have different return types
with overloaded methods?
What is the return?
This is the return type in bid.
Lloyd Noble.
These are the return types
of matters. Yes.
You know, in order to overload,
we have to change parameters,
not the return type,
except where no word is also included.
Word is also return type.
Word means returning nothing.
So it's also written by.
I think I should know why
we are using return type.
We are using return type for no reason.
Okay.
I just wanted to you
that you can have different return types.
That's why I wrote it.
There is absolutely no point
of these return types
and here
if you change the parameters
then you can also change returned type.
Okay, all clear.
Or is there anyone who is still confused?
So let me repeat again.
Jala does not allow overloading
by changing the return type
only. Okay.
Only this one is super clear.
And this line this.
This sentence is super clear.
Now let me show this segment though.
Overloaded methods.
So you have already a method
by changing its parameters.
That overloaded
method can have a different return type.
But if you say, okay,
I am only the return type
and that method should be overloaded,
then it is not possible.
What is the difference between
see out and return?
The difference is that for hard
when you will be calling
this method sets out
will print the results,
but return will return the results
from where you are calling.
That method.
If you don't want to print
something in a method,
if you are a courier,
if you are calculating intermediate
results,
you calculate something from one method.
That method returns that thing.
You use that thing
in further calculations.
That's when you should be using a method
that returns a something.
If you are doing all the logic inside
the same method, you can use this result.
You remember that
next integer or next boolean method
from the scanner class.
Right?
So you are taking the input
using those matters.
Then you were storing those inputs
in some kind of variables
and then you were further
using that data inside your logic.
So that's where you should using use
the method that something
when you have to further
use the results from that method.
So this is just an example.
We have a method and other method
in which I am expecting a data type.
So this is overloading in my.
Okay.
In java
method overloading is not possible
by changing the return type of the method.
Okay. So it is again the train here.
So this out is very
because you are acting as overload to.
So here is an interview question. Guys.
Think about this.
Can I overload the main method?
A very famous interview question
you now you guys know all the rules.
Apply those rules and tell me,
can I overload the main method?
Yes, I can. All right, I can.
There is no half so I can say
I can write another main method.
And this time
maybe I am not the arguments.
Right?
I have overloaded the main method first.
Okay.
I can call this main method in here
that does not take any arguments
like this.
Okay.
And I get the output twice because I am
calling the method here and then in here.
But what is the use of non parameter with
there is no use.
I am just explaining you
that how it works.
This is a very famous interview
question, by the way,
can we overload the main method or not?
So always when you have questions,
apply the rules.
If if it follows the rules,
then you guys can do that thing.
The answer is just yes.
Ah, yes.
If you guys can understand it
just like that.
If I say something in the form of
yes and knows yes, that is great
yes, the answer is yes.
But you guys always need examples
to understand things, right?
So this is another slide
in which I have written some examples.
Okay.
If they ask you to different,
it might be not.
So I have a method in which I am passing
two arguments, then pass
in three arguments and that's how
I can call these two methods.
Okay.
In here I am
passing different number of parameters.
What changes
when we overload the amendment?
Nothing changes.
It's just like any other static method.
So your JVM,
your JVM,
always looks for a method
that is public static.
It has wide return type if name is main
and it accepts
this string at a If it finds all of them,
then JVM will start the execution
of your call from here.
For example,
if I change this public to nothing,
you see that that play button is gone
because this method, it does
not follow the header of the main method
so that that is gone.
You see, as as I put the public back,
I see this play button.
So your JVM is looking for the public
and then the method should also be static.
If I remove static again,
the play button is gone
because I am not fulfilling
the requirements.
Oops.
And then if I change it to maybe interior
or something like that, let me
return
to look again.
That play button is gone
because JVM is looking
for the method that has void return type.
Okay.
We don't have class at Thanksgiving.
Yes we don't.
And then the name of the method
should remain.
If I change it. Domain one again.
Play button is gone. Okay,
I remove the parentheses again.
So JVM is looking specifically
specifically for public static
void main string and then this parent.
Okay with the adding of strings,
is it clear?
Okay.
So advantages of method overloading.
The main advantage of this is clean
less okay
of what method overloading increases
the reliability program.
Think about the println
method is a far println metadata.
You have to use different different names
when you are passing
different different parameters.
There will be a lot of
methods with different names.
It gives the flexibility, right?
So we can have same method name
but with different
overloaded methods.
Give programmers
the flexibility to call similar method
for different types of backup.
If you are working on a mathematics
program, for example,
you could use overloading
to create several multiply classes,
each of which multiplies
a different number of types of arguments.
Not integer A and B then multiplies
to integers more complicated.
Multiply three integers,
one double, two integers.
Yeah.
And you guys can keep
on having these variations
so you don't have to come up
with different names.
But instead that class will be on Monday.
If it is planned for Monday, it will be
announced in the course on version of.
So that said about today's class,
because I got a good response from you.
So now we will be learning two classes
in the same day because you guys are smart
and intelligent now
and now you understand more. So
we will be doing the method overloading as
is there anyone
by the way,
confused about method overloading?
I told you guys it is very easy.
I need now you need more examples.
Not giving more examples.
I am teaching you about method overwriting
right now.
You guys know you are more smart, right?
So let's have a 15 minute break.
After the break we will discuss about
by the way, we are not
I am not teaching two classes
in the same class.
This class was planned on Wednesday,
but because you guys had one day off
and as a was speaking, you so guy,
this class was planned for 2 hours
and you guys took 4 hours for this class.
Okay, so now you guys can
not ask me
if so I am not
we are not learning new things, but
we learning some part of the new class
master has out mastered us once again.
So now you guys.
You guys know better
if you are smart or intelligent.
Or maybe because we we in this class
were supposed to be completed in 3 hours.
You guys took 4 hours.
I'm just kidding.
But we said,
Let's have a break.
And after the break,
we will learn about overloading.
By the way, you guys have already learned
about the overloading.
Okay,
so it's just new terminologies.
So it will be just new terminologies
we learn.
And the issue for getting so fast,
you guys, by all means
literally, they help, believe me.
They help.
They help a lot.
Like you have to put them
in water at night
and in the morning
before you eat anything.
Try to eat 8 to 10 of those
all that you put in water at night.
Believe me, they will help you
know, you guys don't believe me
and the thing will work. What?
It will never work.
Smart classes, only learning,
even implements.
It's scientific fact that they did
studies.
So, you know, it is true.
It's a joke.
No, it's not.
I have been eating a lot of those.
When I was in my graduation,
and believe me, the GPA was
I got 90%, many of them.
Can you please push the code
after the class?
I did not copy more code because my five
my daughter is sick and I have to hold.
Okay, It's fine.
Yes, I will push that.
All right, guys, please be back
and reminding me about the regarding.
I think I again, you almost you are smart.
So whether eat or not,
it does not make sense. So
sorry.
This is how I am calling it in here.
The snack here in spirit
parent is it okay now
reject it.
No, no, no, no.
This is not a new topic.
You guys have already covered this
in the super
class.
We used to caramelized with sugar.
Can you show me Task for, please?
Yes, actually, let me push it
and then you guys can have a look at it
on your computers.
Okay.
So I have pushed it to the top.
Weird.
So all elements and apricot seeds
help with memory, not fish.
Gallbladder bang.
I was like this
I can cancel of my Amazon or
so I have heard something about these fish
and gallbladder as well.
Chinese did they use them a lot
and they are very expensive right
there is special fish
whose gallbladder does they use?
It's very expensive
and it's very beneficial for health.
So it's like I think, yeah,
8 to $10000 per fish.
But the gallbladder of that fish,
that there is some special type of fish.
Okay.
All right, guys,
because today my mode mode is different.
So let me give you a different example
of method overriding.
So let me create a
I hope you guys will understand
this.
So let's say like there is this parent
class, okay, no dogs, really?
No. I am in a very different world today.
So let's say there is this parent class
and the parent
like,
where is Emmett?
Emmett This example is for me.
So the name is
said that.
So this is the parent of
the father of Emmett. Right.
And we have a word method in here.
There C is putting name.
My name is
right.
Okay, let me put.
Okay.
Apologies for that. Yes.
Maybe that's that's why I look
s that
the name of.
Yeah.
And then there is this method
or so
I will
get Mary
my choice.
Okay, so, Emmett, this is a method
that is defined
in the parent class.
Okay, so now what can happen?
So let's say this is
okay, This is something,
you know,
and if this child class is inheriting
from this parent
with.
So what happens
is that when we inherit from something,
we have to accept those meters
from the parent class as it is.
Right.
But what can happen
is that the child classes,
they can also have their own
wishes, right?
And they can also have their own methods.
Maybe they don't like the method
from the parent blasted the methods
that are coming from the parent class.
So what can happen?
Emma can see
the Emmett
can define its own method inside
which class.
And now what Emmett is doing.
Emmett is over writing.
So the terminology is
terminology is overriding.
Okay, so we can override the method.
So there is something that is defined
in the parent class, child class.
It does not like it.
So what child class can do?
It can override that.
Okay, so what will happen now
if we create a
an object of the Charlie
class, The child
class will be having its own behavior.
Okay.
So what about whatever you guys
are, You can't imagine
in our programing
we read something that anybody
would like to see.
So now
the overridden
method from the child will be okay.
So you guys also notice this
in the super example, right?
Same name, apparently independent class,
same name at third in the child class.
And you were calling
the when
we call the method, the method
from the child class was being called
because child class had overridden
that thing.
Okay.
And now if Emmett is naughty,
he can do one more thing.
Okay?
He can have one more method.
And what he can do,
he can Mattie.
Both for both girls, right?
So what Emmett can do,
Emmett can say is super.
Yes. Pop up.
I, I am getting ready.
Okay.
So you can get ready to
the girl is parents like
and then he can also Mattie they go
that he likes it
okay so with the help of super keyword
we can also do that.
So now if we call
this let's do something crazy.
I will be getting both the outputs.
Okay, both the outputs.
Okay. So Emmett will get
let me fix that.
So now we are calling both the methods.
Okay, so this, this overriding thing, this
having the exact same name method
in, I think that's a good smoke
something during the good.
I don't smoke anything.
Now let's have the party.
What I must
if you have to.
I may.
You should be happy at the moment.
Just screaming.
And he didn't share.
I only drink water during the classes.
I don't want you.
I don't want to be teaching something else
in the class.
Believe me, it's just what
must be holy water.
Something so right.
And this.
This phenomena of having.
Okay, and this phenomena of having
the exact the same methods
inside the parent class, exact same name,
method
inside the parent class
and inside the child class is called
method overriding.
So what happens is actually this
is what happens in the real life as well.
You are inheriting from a class, okay.
And maybe you don't like the from
that class.
Okay.
So what you can do,
you can define your own method.
And whenever you will be calling that
method.
Now the method from
your class will be called
Does it make sense where it can be
useful guys
method overriding
only makes sense, but I'm not.
So when we are inheriting
from a class, yes,
we inherit all the matters
we want.
All the but
sometimes we don't want all the methods.
Okay.
Okay. So let let's come back.
Let's get back to class.
So we are having a method in here
inside the parent class.
Okay?
And then the child class
is extending from the parent class.
Okay.
Now, if the child class does not like
the behavior from the parent class, then
we can override that behavior.
We can define our own methods.
Okay,
So that is called method overriding,
but which if we did it before.
No, no, we did the same thing
almost in the super example,
but we didn't use this
terminology of overriding
and what we can also do or we can also do.
So method overriding,
Do we do that at the beginning of the code
or the other not method.
So it only it is only required
if you don't like something
from your parent class.
If all is good from the parent class,
then you guys don't need to override it.
So let's say your.
And the best case example is that whenever
there is an update
in the JDK or in the methods,
when whenever
there is this performance improvement
or whenever you are introducing
new features, So what do we do?
Because changing something
inside the parent,
you guys remember changing something
inside the parent can change everything
in all the child classes.
So what do we do instead?
We create a new class.
We include use those new features
in the child class.
We improve the code, we write new code,
and then we use the written code.
We combine these two
and then we release new features.
I need that override in your life.
Is it really overwriting?
If we are calling the method
from the class we like
is not it over redone, but rather
we pick the method we like.
So what happens is that Mohammad,
if there is no method present
inside the child class
and if now I think you the score
I will be getting the results,
both the results from the parent class
when I write my own method.
Now I have overridden that method and now
I will be getting the results
from my own class if I don't use super.
So that's why it is called overriding.
So when we use method override, it takes
the child class but not the parent. Yes.
So if method is defined in the child
class, call it from there.
If it is not defined,
call it from different class.
Does it make sense?
Guys?
I mean, the example is very simple.
Well, it's very realistic.
Now, what is this line 15?
This one.
Okay, So this override here,
these are, by the way,
these are called annotations.
These are part
A called annotations and notations.
They are extra pieces of information
that you provide to your compiler.
Okay.
So let's say, for example,
if we write this,
if we remove this override,
we will not be getting any issues.
Okay? But what happens is that
if you oops, if you write this.
So sometimes let's say
you are making a very small mistake.
Okay?
Let's say you are you change this m2m
And if you use this override annotation
now at compile time,
you know that you are making a mistake.
You are not overriding a matter. Okay?
Because there is no method matching
this name in here.
So this override annotation,
it is helping you
by telling you
if you are overwriting in actual or not.
If there is something in the parent class
or not that you can override.
But if we remove this annotation,
you see I will not be getting any errors.
So if I write this override
Java performs this extra checking for us.
It makes sure that there is a method
with the same name
in the parent class, in the child
class, the arguments are the same
and it is following
all the rules of overwriting.
But after in the next class, maybe
we will learn the rules about overriding.
So this overriding make sure that we are
always, always following all the rules.
So these are called annotations
you guys will be learning about
these annotations
more in the selenium and testing classes.
We didn't write that override.
It was system
generated, intelligent is generating this.
Okay, intelligent is doing this.
If you don't need it,
you guys can remove this.
So it's just an extra step to make sure
that everything is is good at compile
time.
Oh, it's to explicitly say
the method needs to be overridden.
If it was not there
and spelling of the method was different,
the code will compile.
But yes.
So even if the spelling are different,
so let's say there is no more method
in the independent class,
so there is nothing to override.
And if you are still thinking
that you are overriding
something, you are making a mistake.
So what will
intelligent will still?
It will still give you an error.
So it does not matter if the only spelling
are incorrect, if you are not following
all the rules of overriding
it will give you an error.
I will teach you about
the rules of overwriting.
Yes, we will do one
more example, but let me quickly show
you more things.
Okay, so string name is equal to
omit.
And if.
Yep, yep, it's fine. It's fine.
We say print name
and let me make
one more
I hope is not married in real life.
Well, I might be his last class with this
stage name.
If thief
but I brand is waiting for you
so we cannot overload
fields.
But we can override fields time
So let them create
actually a test for class.
How many of you don't understand this?
That if we have a method
defined in the parent class
and if same method is defined in the child
class,
then you will be calling the method
from the child.
Always
the child class method will be called.
And the difference We will discuss.
The difference
is that anyone who don't understand this
and you guys also understand this, that
if I don't like something from the parent,
I can override it.
I can provide my own method,
I can provide my own implementation,
I can write my own method,
which is also possible in Java,
and it is called overwriting.
Okay.
Uh, and, and if a field
is present in the parent class
and if same name field
is also present in the child class,
again, the priority will be given
to which class guys
child class.
The priority is given to the child class.
So this example will make it more clear.
Okay, so let me declare
the GI
child is equal to on male.
And if I say child not
put into
name, can you guys tell me the output?
So I am having same name field
in the parent,
same name field in the child,
same name field in tied the method.
And then I am writing three print out
statements.
First, I am simply writing
the name of the variable.
In the second, I am using this keyword
and in the third
I am using this super keyword.
Don't execute on this code.
Tell me the output from the rules
that you have understood.
And not to show Eve and said that
Sherif will be the first output.
Okay.
Remember all the rules that we learned
about the variables, instance
variables, local variables, super keyword.
Let me execute the score
and then let me explain
why we are getting this output.
So you guys remember
the use of this keyword
and b so the difference
between local variables.
Yes. Niyaz answer was correct.
So guys,
if I have a local variable
and if I only use its name
always, always
the local variable gets the priority,
but always, always
the local variable gets priority.
But in the same second line,
I am explicitly saying this dot name,
you guys remember what we're about.
What do we do with this keyword?
What happens when we use this keyword
with the variables?
Which variables are always referred?
We refer to the instance variables, guys.
So this in this case,
this is the instance variable, right?
Because yes,
we have this field in the parent as well,
but because we have defined our own field,
now the priority is given to that field.
The priority is the child class.
It can be a method, it can be a field.
If A class is defining
its own variables or methods.
Always, always.
The property is given to matters.
Okay?
And when we explicitly say
a super dot name, what does it mean, guys?
Super facility parent class.
So that's why we get the sheriff
first, then them
and then the student.
I talk to this only for constructor.
No, no. And this can be for peers.
I think we spend
more than one hour on that.
And is there
anyone who still don't understand why
we getting these three outputs?
Okay, so let me know this
if I comment this out.
If if I comment this out
now, tell me what output
they will get.
So animate animate
and then saw the
so now
let me execute this.
So now there is no competition
between instance fear
and a local field, right?
There is no local field
so it does not matter if we write this
or if we write the field name
without this right,
it will always be referring
to the instance field.
Okay.
And then in here
we are explicitly, explicitly using super
so that that's why
we get this sort of in here.
Is there anyone who don't understand this?
No, not will.
We will not be getting null
because now the name will also
refer to the instance field.
Okay.
And if I comment this out
as well, now what I will get
all products right?
Because what happens, guys,
when we expand from a class,
all the features
which are not private, they are kind of
you remember the inheritance class,
they are kind of copied to the child
class, right?
So this name and this
and this doc name,
they are referring it from the child class
and this is coming from the parent class,
but they are all same.
Okay? They are all same.
All right, All right.
So now you guys understand
how all the writing works
a little bit right?
Okay. So and you guys.
So let me instead of this crazy let me
let me
also make it clear
how methods look.
So right now,
the name of the project
should be overriding
or I wrote overloading.
Let me add refactoring.
So if I have to change something,
I go to the effective
and then I write.
Okay,
so this is how I refactor team.
Okay.
And then it will change the overriding
here, here, inside all the classes.
Okay, we will.
So do it.
We don't have to go inside the classes
and have to change it
if we use the developer.
So guys, now
I have this parent class
in which I have this printer method.
Okay.
And then this. Sorry, not this.
Get it get married method.
And I have the same method
and my frozen.
Okay.
So if I have same name method in parent
and in child
and if I create the object of child class
and I call that matter.
So which method will execute?
Which will which method will get priority?
The method from there.
I like someone
so the method
from the child class will be executed.
And if I don't have
that maternal and child class,
then the parent class
method will be executed.
Then in exit.
This is overriding.
If you have something
same inside the parent parent child
priority is for the child class.
If you don't have it,
it comes from the parent.
And this be this this phenomena
of having same name method.
It's called.
We can override a field,
we can override the method.
Are we going to cover this same class? No.
Model? Yes.
It is required for the next class.
Is there anyone who is still confused
about the overriding why we need it?
How it works?
Is it important for now?
So don't worry.
I will try to show you at least
maybe three more examples on overriding.
Okay.
But overloading is good, right?
Overloading is good.
Having same name method
but different parameters so far.
Overriding.
We will do more examples.
All right.
And then we can always use super keyword
to prioritize things
if we don't want to use something
from child, mainly
for advising a privatizing
child class methods and variables. Yes,
if we have overrides parent class
with a lot of child matters,
can the parent override all the same?
If we have overriding parent class
with a lot of child class methods,
then parent override.
So he knows
this.
This question is not correct.
Only the child can override
that and the classes
can never override something from child
classes first thing days.
And then it does not matter
how many methods there,
you can always override all the methods
that participate in inheritance.
So can I override private methods?
Nice.
Very famous interview question
can override private methods?
No. Can I overload private methods?
Can I overload private methods? Yes.
Can I override constructors?
Override?
So first everyone was saying yes.
Now no, because I emphasize doing that.
It's it's those things
which do not participate in inheritance.
We cannot override them.
So constructors,
we cannot override them because they don't
participate in inheritance.
And this is from inheritance class.
Can I
overload the constructor?
Yes, I can overload the constructor.
Right. No issues with that.
And on
okay.
Everything looks good for now.
So let me.
I have one error please.
Now is not you are available.
My mind is overriding
and overloading today.
Let me check what
What is the error that you are getting?
So now you are trying to define the child
class inside of the parent class.
This is not possible.
So this giant class,
it must be outside of these parentheses.
These these in brackets. Okay.
That's why you are getting this error.
All right.
So let's discuss.
I know, I know all of you
are waiting for this keyword, right?
If Java is the best option for execution.
Actually, to me, the third thing
it is to use Java two, two of methods.
Yes, you
can. It's
so on.
But I am married with my lovely wife.
I know.
Because your wife is standing right
behind you and she has the right planning
to handle.
That's why I will never show this class
to her partial.
My parents of the word
is I am not.
You don't have to say this to class.
Everyone understands.
We know that you are saying it
to your wife,
but you are showing it to us. Right?
So I guess
this the
I don't know why my my mood
is totally different today,
although I have to submit
so many assignments
know they are not all means.
So whenever same method name
is the existing in both base class.
No, it's 20
as you a bad idea to do brain for. But
how can I be so happy if I am married?
It's it should be obvious, man.
Literally.
Believe me, I have seen married people
when they go out with their friends
and if their wives they
they can hear them laughing with friends.
The next thing that then
when they will come back they will say,
You never laugh with me.
You, you talk with me like that
with your friend.
You are very happy, always smiling.
Because all of the members
my, my, my brothers and sisters,
they are married.
So I know
every single thing is being noticed
when you get married.
That is what I would talk about too.
I just.
I don't think so.
I can even one single.
You will have that question too,
as I am, I am observing everything.
I would make sure
that this never happens to me.
So whenever same method name is existing
in both the base class, I remember
all writing happens in,
in, in the classes where you
you have that parent child relationships.
Okay.
But overloading
happens inside the same class.
Okay.
There is no parent child relationship.
There is no inheritance.
So this is the one of the biggest
difference are overloading
inside of the same class over writing
parent and child relationship.
No, no.
I can not be happy by getting married
and I would class
with the same types of bad meters.
Okay.
So in overloading
and overriding always
the matter name should be
okay.
So the cluster name, it's
so far
overriding
and overloading the method name.
It should be same.
So method name that should be same.
But in overloading
bad on meters
shit, there always be different
but in overriding
they should never be different.
Focus on this
for both method
overloading and overriding method.
The name should be same
for overloading parameters
should be different
for overriding parameters.
It should be exactly the same.
Oh okay.
So whenever same method
third name is existing
in both base class and derived class
class
with same type of parameters or same order
or of parameter
is known as method overriding,
so which was not required
for the overloading
is not required for overriding.
Okay,
so do you guys understand this which was
which was required for overloading
is now totally the opposite.
If we do the same thing in here.
The overriding yes, completely opposite.
The overriding will not happen in here.
Parameters should be exactly the same.
They have sequence, they have numbers,
they are tied.
They should be exactly the same.
The return type in overloading in
do not have any effect in overriding
it should be exactly the same.
Okay.
If subclass general class has the same
method as declared
in the parent,
we are already scared and as good.
If if subclass has the same method
as declared in the parent class,
it is known as method overriding.
Okay.
And remember the small guys
without the inheritance
method overriding is not possible.
Okay.
The overriding concept is only
when you have the parent child
relationship. Now,
as we have the benefits from overloading,
we also get the benefits from overriding
method.
Overriding is used to provide
specific implementation
of a method that is
already provided by its superclass.
So method is already there.
But for some reason we don't like that
method.
We override the variable
in the same class.
In the same class, No,
overriding always happens in full classes
and there should always be
this parent child relationship,
this inheritance relationship.
Perhaps
there should be a subclass.
Yes, there should be a subclass.
The private methods cannot be overridden
but can be overloaded.
Yes. Moment.
Right. Right.
This code you are declaring two variables
with same name.
It does not allow that inside
same class or inside same method.
Right.
Is there anyone else who is confused?
So method overloading is used
for compile time polymorphism
and method overwriting
is used for runtime polymorphism.
Okay.
Your favorite topic
without inheritance
method overriding is not possible.
Why are you doing this to yourself?
Yes, I know Mohammad is very responsive.
He always participates in class
and I can tell from my previous experience
the students who participate in the class,
they are the
they are the students
who usually get their job in fast
one or two weeks
because it only makes you like.
If you are not doing anything,
just sitting and watching,
you can be super, super lazy.
You can go to sleep,
but when you are active it also
you kind of get
involved in the class as well
so you don't feel sleepy
and things like that.
So yep,
I slept for 5 hours.
So advantage of method overriding.
We can have our own implementations.
Yeah,
that's good
because when I get stuck in something
I, I have brother
is not only he will be helping you
in your jobs in during the classes right.
And doing the assignments
the sisters the
they always have this benefit
from the brother so rules
for method overriding
so three more minutes
so first rule very simple must be
it must be is a relationship.
There must be inheritance
method must have the same name
as in the parent class and child class.
Okay, so same name, same names,
method must have same parameters.
Well, while this condition
also there are overloading guys,
should we be having same parameters
for method overloading as well?
What was the condition
about parameters in overloading?
They should always be different.
They should always be different
either in numbers
or in sequence or in type
method.
They must have the same return type
lost this condition,
therefore overloading
or overloading.
We don't care about the return type,
but in all the writing
we hear about return type it must be same.
Okay, so this is just an example.
There is this walking class.
The man is extending from walking
and he is giving his own implementation
the method signature.
That is the method name
and the parameter list and the return type
have to match exactly in super
and subclasses for overriding.
Also, there is a restriction
about the excess modifier.
Was there a restriction about
the excess modifier in overloading guys?
The no
and there was no restriction
on access modifiers,
but in overriding excess
level can cannot be more restrictive.
Okay. What does this mean? It means
if I have
public access modified in here,
I can not make it to default
or private or protected.
I cannot make it more restrictive.
But if I have default,
I can make it public.
So I can increase the visibility,
but I cannot decrease visibility.
Okay.
Is this point player guys
perfect?
The access level
cannot be more restrictive. Yes.
If parent has public
child must have at least public,
then the overridden
method of access level.
For example,
if superclass method is declared public,
then overriding method in some class
cannot be private default or work after.
So I just wanted to complete this slide
so that I can give you some tasks
and we will cover the differences.
What is not possible in overriding
and then the difference
between overloading and overriding.
We will we will be doing two more examples
and then we will start
your favorite topic.
Yeah, thank you.
So I have shared the homework
in the course announcement.
Oh, it's not that difficult.
I was just kidding You
are. You guys will see it.
It's very easy.
No, no, it's not that hard.
Like it is very simple.
Only I'm in three slides, I guess.
So it's very similar to casting.
If you guys understand
the casting in primitives
that is actually casting in objects,
there's
there's the difference.
I am not really single.
I am dating myself.
I take myself out,
I buy myself clothes, I love me.
I am awesome.
Sandy slide please Overwriting.
Yes, I even send the slides from the class
and I will share the video as well
and I hope to have us to this class.
My manager.
You are not cannot override my really
if she is not accessible.
All right.
Take some rest and I will see you to model
and hopefully my mode will be same
tomorrow.
Thank you. Bye bye.