When I
start teaching, I start to feel good.
Hello. Hello.
So today's class number 22.
And from the next week,
your selenium classes are starting
and I think Moslem is Moslem.
We will be teaching the Selenium classes.
So are you guys ready for that?
Yes, we are recording.
What's up?
Sorry I'm late.
Meeting specialized. I only have just.
We just started.
Hello.
Ask Country two.
What happened to you? Nothing.
I don't know, I.
I heard some.
I think it's because of the orange juice.
I have some orange juice
and some burgers before the class.
They don't take his jello pills. Oh,
okay.
Or in, guys.
So let's discuss your favorite topic
one more time
as a revision, as a recap,
and then I hope you guys will feel better.
If not, we will do
more examples today about the polymorphism
and I hope it will make some sense.
So we went through the overloading
and overriding part already, right?
We realized we had all the nodes as well.
I was not not gonna interpret that.
You are also sick like so here
so far this year.
The quota is done for me to be sick
and I hope all the rest of the year
I will be fine.
Yes, you may be at me at most,
maybe one day.
So where do you guys
what is dengue fever?
Is dengue fever, not mango fever.
It's a kind of virus in in Asia
and Sri Lanka.
Pakistan. It's common.
Yes, India,
Nepal, Bhutan, in this this area.
So, yes, yes.
It's spreading through mosquitoes.
And it happened last year as well.
But the government there responded
very well to it.
But now we have the government
of Imran Khan.
So there and then
they're not special efforts this time.
Are you see, it's
kind of like the symptoms
are nearly close to malaria.
So after that overriding
thing is we discuss for how
we can cost the objects as well.
Right?
So there was a casting that we discussed
when we were
discussing the primitive types.
So if you guys are trying
to compare this
casting to the primitive casting, it's
a little different
because now methods are involved.
Now we have the properties as well.
Now we have the
parent child relationship
that's going on.
You I was sorry, I was,
but I am not enough.
So that casting thing, guys,
if I am trying to cast a parent
object, okay, A parent object
to a child object,
can I do that in objects?
Can I cast a parent class to a child
class?
So, for example, let's say
I have.
So let's take an example, okay?
And mother is ready for the example
left to someone else this time.
What is ready?
Who has
one or two brothers maybe
who have a
different one?
Borrow?
Okay, so I sure you are ready.
So let's make your further class.
And what is always ready is to ask again.
So it's just to give you an idea that
what a
how how the casting worked in Java.
So let's say we have this parent class
then brother, he is not interested
only vice role me Mohammad
the let's say
we have a string filled.
Yeah brother is not interesting.
We have this name field
and then there is this constructor
through which I should initialize
the spirit field because constructors,
the only purpose the constructors exist
is to initialize the instance fields
and even the expected fields of a class.
So this is the whole purpose
of constructor.
So whenever we have to initialize
a field of a class,
we should always write a constructor. So
school nurse initialize
and this field for the constructor.
So this dot name is equal to name.
So anyways,
tell me why I am using this dog name.
Well, why can't I do
this name is equal to name? No.
Why? Why?
Why? I need this keyword guys.
What is this?
This keyword is going in here
not repeating to differentiate
I to the instance will be able
to be confused
or you need another name. Yes.
So if I am writing this
line of word, what I am
technically saying, I am saying
get b value from this name field
and store it again back to the name field.
Okay, so whatever value is coming
through this constructor
inside this name field,
I am picking that name field
and I am assigning it back to the same
variable, same local variable,
which means I will never be
using this name field,
which is an instance field of this class.
Okay, so this will never work.
This the value will never get extra
inside this name field.
So if I want to use the instance spheres,
I need to write this keyword.
This refers to the current class object.
You can do it,
but it does not change instances variable
if you don't use this here.
Yes, you guys are right.
So let's say
there are two behaviors in here.
Okay, so
who is ready
for the example?
Having some siblings, Sheriff is Steve.
How many are your father like to sleep?
I am now.
8 hours.
I like to sleep.
It out.
Okay.
And then ward it.
And what does he like to eat?
Six or 7 hours.
Reggie? Everything.
Eric's a selfish.
Okay,
so we have this parent class now,
even in our real life
and in Java, as well.
What happens is that from the parent
class, the things they are.
Hello, guys.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Did I miss anything else?
So what happens
is that we inherit something.
So our children, they inherit
the properties,
the behaviors of the parents.
But it does not happen in the reverse
order.
Right?
The parents,
they don't inherit anything from children.
So it's a one way relationship. So
and it
it acts like same in the Java as well.
So let's say, for example
and now if I have a
child class, so what I can do,
I can inherit from this father class
and as soon as I do, I get pissed at it.
There is no default constructor
available in Father.
What does this mean?
Guys?
You need father
and then parentheses Constructor
need for constructing father
we can inherit only default constructor
job or cannot create
a default constructor.
How can I resolve this issue?
So one way is to provide a
no argument constructor
inside the father class,
but I want to use this field.
So what should be my approach
if I want to use this name field in here?
Should I create
a default constructor in here
or should I create
some kind of constructors in this class?
We need a constructor to initialize
be variables because if child classes
they are planning to use
the fields or masters
from the parent class.
They must create a matching constructor
and then they should
initialize those fields.
So for example,
I should do and I should do this.
I should say, Son, because I have a field
inside the parent class
that I must initialize.
I say a super.
And then I was listening
and you guys tell me,
what is this super doing in here?
Yes, Constructors.
They don't participate in inheritance,
but we can use
a mechanism in Jala through
which we can call the constructor
of the parent class,
and that mechanism is super
with these parentheses.
So when I super end these parentheses,
whenever the object of this sunglass
will be created, it will fall.
This son construct.
And inside this some constructor
I am calling the constructor
of the parent class
that we in this field will be initialize
whether I am creating an object of child
or if I am creating an object
of dependent or directly.
So now I am always sure that
no matter if there is a child class object
or there is a parent,
a class object, I am always
initializing this to name field.
Now what can happen is that
my methods
inside the parent class, they might be
using this name field right now.
And if I am also planning to use
these methods from the parent class
because they will automatically
be inherited in the child class.
All right.
So I should always initialize this field
because these methods, they are also using
this field field and they are now
part of this fun class as well.
So when I am using
something from my parent class,
I should always make sure that I am
initializing those things as well.
Is this super following the
father constructor or is it calling
the superstring name variable?
It is calling the father
constructor moment,
so I will do even that code as well
so that you guys can see
the flow of information.
And now with the help of polymorphism
and with the help of overriding
what I can do, let's say following sample,
I have a slightly different behavior,
right?
So let's say
Shareef has a slightly different behavior.
So me how much you would like to sleep.
So let's say Shareef liked to sleep
maybe 10 hours.
Right now it's a different behavior
from his father, right?
So with the help of overriding,
I don't have to come up
with a different name for this method
because essentially Shareef
is doing the exact same thing, right?
The the Shareef is doing
the exact same thing.
So with the help of overwriting,
instead of coming up
with a different name,
maybe a sleep one or something
officially or something like that,
and creating the confusion,
what I can do,
I can define the exact same name
method in the child class
and I can customize that method
according to me.
Right.
And sorry, what do you like to eat?
Kabob. You guys are all fan of kabob.
I'm starting from turkey to Afghanistan.
Everyone likes kabob, so
in Libya and
even in Ukraine.
So you guys also have the same name.
What about you?
I also like kabob, biryani,
chicken, mutton,
almost everything
you can arise.
There are hardly a few things
that I don't like.
Vegetables, fish, mutton, chicken,
everything I eat, everything.
All word, loves, kabob, Anybody, any
of us. Quarter Pounder.
My mom is making beef biryani now.
Almighty God,
you guys are still making your moms
and dads dares to cook for you.
Okay. Okay.
So what is happening in here?
I am using something from my parent
in this example, the name string.
Okay.
If I have the same behavior
I can inherited directly,
if I don't like that behavior,
I can change it.
I can override it in my child class.
Okay, so this is the power of
overriding.
Let's parent under class.
No, there is another class.
And inside this class,
this class is more,
let's say maybe 50%, same
as in the parent
class.
Well, I'm getting analogous.
So even if I try to initialize
this name field,
which is coming from Father,
I still get an error.
Okay.
And I am getting an editor
because they're always saying their task
that this is not the proper way
of initializing this field, this name,
not field.
You are trying to initialize
this fear of this sunglass.
Okay, so if you want to initialize
the parent field,
you must focus.
You must say
super name
because remember guys inheritance.
What inheritance is doing
is kind of copying
all the code except constructive
and private fields are methods
inside this child class and this keyword.
It always refers
to the members of this current class.
It never
it can never
refer to the name field of the father
class.
Okay.
So if we are planning to use
these methods are filled from the parent,
you must initialize them
through the super,
not using the this keyword
or any other method.
Okay.
So this is for child
class and super is for father.
Father class? Yes.
Let's say
there is this another son of this father
and he he like he likes to sleep indoors,
but he likes to eat fish.
Okay.
And the rest of the things they are same.
So now we will try to.
Maybe I can do this.
Guys, if you guys are comfortable,
maybe I can copy
both the classes inside this same class
so that you guys, it's easy for you to
read these classes because there is
nothing much that is going on
inside these classes.
So let me put it in here.
And guys,
don't try to change the code on your own.
Let me send this code.
So keep this package in.
This package might be different for you.
And let me show you the rest of the code
who are getting any issues.
You guys can use the code from here.
Let me know once you guys are done.
But in the real world,
it should be in a different file estimate.
Yes, you are right
at work.
We will also call you to copy
paste your code.
Yet 90% of the time
you guys will be copying
and pasting the code from the internet
because
there is a high
probability that the problems
that you guys will be facing,
the solutions that you guys
will be looking for,
they are already solved by someone else.
So you just need to be good
at sucking skins
and then integrating the code
from different sources.
So that's why these concepts are
important for you, because on the internet
you guys will find the examples
of using all of these concepts.
And if you don't understand
how that piece of code is working,
you will never be able to integrate
and writing all the code from scratch.
It will take huge amounts of time.
This need to learn how to make 10 minutes
of ruling and 30 minutes of modification
seems like 6 hours. But yep,
I mean, literally if
you are if you observe a developer
or a automation engineer
who are doing their job,
you guys will find that
there will be 200 tabs
open on their laptops.
And essentially what they all they, they,
what they do, they just copy and paste
and then integrate.
It is all the errors that they get.
Fix the issue with the subject.
Again, check if it is working fine or not.
So troubleshooting,
searching and integrating the code,
it's it's rare that you guys
will be writing the complete classes
and all the code and everything.
So now let's try to understand
disgusting guys.
So you guys understand
this part
very well that so if you guys understand
this concept, the casting will be
will be super easy for you.
This parent guys,
everything that this parent has
that is available to this child
and this child right.
And initial the screenshot.
Nice.
Everything that this parent has
is is available
with the help of this external keyword
to these child classes.
That's why when we try to store
their slime
and we try to store a sun
inside the parent class,
we don't get any at us.
You have to father classes.
Okay, just give me an
so that's why when
whenever I try to store the object
from a giant class
inside the variable of the parent type,
I can easily do that because this father.
So whatever the son is inheriting
from this father, father
already have those properties
and those behaviors work.
Is it true father, son guys?
Is it true father son?
So if I say a son is equal to
father,
New, No, it's wrong.
It's a one way thing, right?
So one weird thing because inheritance
happens from parent class
to this child class, not from the child
class to the parent a class.
So this son, the son,
it might be having something different.
And that's why we cannot store
that information.
So let's say, for example,
this son has something additional.
Maybe Ward play
video games.
Yeah,
I can play
video games.
Okay.
So what happens
is that when we say the son
inside the memory, inside the memory
media, inside the memory,
because we are extending.
So there will be a name field in here.
So a memory
location of our name will be reserved
then.
And remember, location of our sleep
will be reserved
for it will be reserved
for play, video games will be okay.
And when we are saying the new father job,
I will try to fit these things
from the father class.
So it will successfully
it will be able to create this name,
it will be able to create this sleep.
But now Angela does not know.
So because it's a one way relationship,
does not know
about the sleep method
that exist inside the father class.
Okay.
But because we are extending
so it's possible
inside the child class
because we all
we inherit everything from the parents.
So this class has the information
about this matters
and then we override these methods.
So what happens is that
in Java they have defined the inheritance
and the casting like this.
So right now, if I out of my mouth
it says required son provided father.
But if I try to store this son class
inside the father class,
I don't get any errors.
Okay. Now
what is also possible
So this is not possible
that we can directly store
an object of father class
inside a variable All son class.
But what is possible is this.
So I have initially stored this Shareef
inside a box off type father.
And if I want to get back
this Shareef,
I can get it back with the help of casting
so I can see son
and then son.
Yeah.
So it's a capitalist.
So now in, in this example,
what I am doing.
So let's, let's assume I have a box,
okay?
And this box is a special box.
Okay?
Although the type of this box is farther
to people.
So these classes,
they are also called types.
So this father type.
So I put Shareef inside this box,
and this box is designed
in Java
in such a way that it can hold this one.
So I put this on in here and later
on, on this line
I am asking Java to give this son back.
So now I have a different box.
This box is of type son.
Okay?
So these variables, they are they are
treated as like boxes, memory, location.
So this, this is the son box.
And what I am saying,
I am saying that this box please
give this son back from this box
and try to fit it inside in here.
So I will not be getting any issues
because initially this box
was big enough to hold the son.
And the only thing that I am doing on
this line is I am getting back this son
from this box. From this box. So
storing the object
of one type in inside
another type is only possible
if we are storing it inside
a father class, inside a parent class.
Okay, Only this is possible.
And if we have this scenario,
then we can do this thing.
Otherwise we cannot.
We will be getting in it
now. And I know this, guys.
I have this son class in here
and then I have another class
which is a son to now
the son to use a different class.
Right.
It might be having hundred
different methods in here.
Can I say this that in Italy
I put the son in here,
but on this line I get back the son to
know.
Right?
And even if I try to do that,
and then if I try to do that,
then I will be executing my code.
I will be getting this class cost
exception.
Silver dollar is trying to do
why you don't have it.
How will you get it
when you don't have it?
How? Yes.
So initially I had son, right?
And now I am trying this a son.
I am trying this son to convert it to in.
Okay.
And then I'm trying to store it
inside this object.
So there is nothing wrong
with this part of the core in
I am just declaring a variable often
to I'm giving it a name Sharif.
But the problem is here
because I am this variable horse,
this son, and I am trying
to cast it to the son to variable, okay,
which is not possible.
So the only thing that you guys
will be doing in Java
regarding this casting and sun
and all of that thing
you guys will be using this
to achieve the polymorphism.
And for polymorphism, the only thing that
you guys will be doing, you guys will be
creating an
array or you guys will be storing
the objects
of these jali classes
inside the parent class or.
If you guys have understood this part
that we can store a child
class object inside a parent or variable
we can create
ADD is of parent type variable
and we can put all the child class
object inside that.
I can look through it.
I can call all the methods.
And if a specific method is available
inside
a class, inside a special child class,
I cannot call it that's enough.
If it was possible,
it would be nested polymorphism.
So let me repeat
if you guys have understood this thing
that I can store
Egide class object inside A
and let me also write this so we can
store a
jar class
object.
So let me repeat, let me write
rules for busting
objects
or classes.
I think we need another example
from scratch.
We will do anything.
We can store a child class
all go inside a parent
or type
inside a parent type variable.
Okay.
Because
inheritance
is one way
from better to die
so we can store the child
class
object inside a parent class variable.
Or we can view the year
areas of type
parent
and can store
all the
objects of the
child classes
inside that adding birth
have the same type notes as last class.
Okay, sure.
But we all alone or override in here.
So this all of these examples in here
we are overwriting.
So you see in here I have this statement
little snippet tossed in here
I am overridden.
That would be what I, I can write, Lou,
for any of those statements
or any of that logic inside this method,
I am really finding the same name
method inside the tile class.
So this is all the overriding problem.
Is it clear
if I don't override guys,
if I don't override any file,
try to use polymorphism.
What will happen
this override
that that
that that annotation is optional?
No, it will work.
It will work like like for example,
I am saying this
if I don't override these matters,
what will happen?
The exact same methods
from the parent class.
They will get inherited in here. Right?
And the exact same letters will
will get inherited inside
this one too as well.
So there is no point of polymorphism.
Right?
Because what we are essentially doing,
we are calling same method again
and again.
Right.
I can just write,
I can just create the object of this class
and call the method from here
because I am not providing
in any different implementation,
then what's the point
of creating this child class
if I am doing exactly the same thing
inside this child as well?
Right.
You get paid in a class method
if you don't override them.
Yes, I get the parent class method.
Exact the same method right.
Then what is the point of writing a loop
and then
storing all the objects of the child
and then calling the same method
again and again and again. Right.
I will always be getting the same output.
There is no point without the overwriting.
So that's why we override.
Because in child classes they want to have
some different functionality.
Think about the testing right
then we are testing
on Firefox classes, on Google Chrome
classes, on safari.
These things,
they don't exactly behave same.
There are differences right there.
So I would create a matter in the web
driver class and all of these classes
this slightly differently implement
those matters
and that's why we use the polymorphism.
Right
Because they are different things. So
that's where you should be using the.
And then polymorphism, if,
if you have to do the same thing,
then then there is no point of overwriting
or anything like that.
So we can create
add as of type parent and again store
all the objects of the child classes
inside that and
then we can
override
loops to pull all the
matters
from all the classes.
So our days to pass database.
So you guys have done
the homework on days to pass.
I showed to example in the previous class.
Is there anyone is still confused
about these 2.0?
Okay.
So the third thing is or we cannot score a
parent
class
object, we cannot store
or cost a parent class object to the
child class. Okay,
So and
neither we can store a parent class object
in a child type variable,
nor we can bastard.
Okay. But
if the parent type
variable.
But so I am using different things in here
focused in here guys in here I am saying
storing or costing it being in the class
object in here I am talking about
the parent type variable.
When I say parent type variable,
I mean this, I mean this.
This is a variable.
And this type is parent.
Do you guys understand this parent type
of variable for parent time?
This is the I am calling a class as a type
because in Java classes they are types
I am storing.
So I am having a variable of type parent
and then I am trying to store a child
class object inside that variable.
Okay.
So from child to parent,
it's possible, but from
parent to child it is not possible.
So for example,
I cannot have a variable of type
child, son and I cannot store a father
object inside that.
So this is we are this
this third warrant is referential
or we cannot store or accost a parent
class object to a child class,
child class
variable.
But if parent type already
already contains
the child object,
then we can get it back
by casting it.
So if the class
already have a child,
objects
or if a variable already have a child
object inside it, then I can get it back.
Okay, then I can
throw.
So if a variable already has
directly, it is not possible.
Yes, not even even
indirectly is not possible.
Even indirectly is not possible.
So let's say, for example,
instead of this one, if I try to store
a father in here,
okay, still I will be getting an error
because what I am doing technically,
if I ignore the is to ignore this,
ignore the cell
and get all this variable in here.
I am kind of trying to store this
this new father inside this object.
Right?
This is just an intermediate step
that I first proposed this object
inside this variable.
And from this variable
I try to get going back.
Okay?
If just an extra member location
that I am using,
it's like temporarily variable, right?
But still I am doing this.
I am trying to store a father
in extra steps inside a son variable.
Is it possible? Goes
no. Right.
Because I cannot store a father
inside this variable.
Okay.
So again,
I will be getting a class cost exception.
So only one way is possible.
Storing child class objects
inside of parent type variables.
If this is only this is possible,
the rest of these things,
this costing out all of this,
you guys will hardly be needing this.
But yes, it's possible.
Okay.
Up costing it is required in.
You guys will be learning a short
framework, a small framework study
on different data structures is
it will be I think after
two weeks all for
so there you guys will you
you guys might want to do that
this up costing or down costing
and before that you guys
will be using this up costing and down
costing in your
in your very first selenium class.
So you guys will be creating a web driver
element
web driver class object variable,
and then you will be storing Google Chrome
or Firefox inside of that.
And then you will be opening Google Chrome
or Firefox on your computers
with the help of some methods
that are present in there.
Okay.
Let's do one more example.
So let's say I have a person class.
The article is done typing the code
of the classes and the notes as well.
And can I start the new class?
Let's say this person has a name for you
and I am
leaving this name field again
through the constructor
I guess on
what is available in this four channel.
And then I have
an employee
note from the person
and now I am getting an error.
What is this paradise
again?
Because I am extending
and I have a constructor
that takes one argument inside the parent.
I must provide a matching constructor
inside my child class,
so I need a matching
constructor in here for the in here
and this constructor
here should not only match,
you should also call the parent
class constructor
with the help of super keyword.
So I have another class
that has a slightly different behavior
for this perform daily task.
So what I do, I override this behavior
and I provide my own implementation.
But for one of the matters I don't have,
I don't mind if I have
the exact same implementation.
Right?
So which concept I am using in here guys?
Overriding, not overloading, overriding.
And then I can have another class
student extending
person.
So again, need a matching constructor,
right?
Then the student can have
a slightly different behavior.
Right?
Then I can have another class.
So now you guys are getting this point.
But if I am having, if I want to use
some functionality from one class
and I don't like the
I maybe the other piece of functionality,
maybe I like two matters
and I don't like maybe five.
My third from the parent class.
I have this flexibility that I can provide
my own implementation for those matters.
Right?
I don't have to change the names.
If I am essentially doing the same thing,
I can have my own thing, but
and at the same time
I can have the same name.
Okay, please
repeat line 23 to 25.
And so in here then this I am calling.
I am writing a meeting constructor
inside the child class.
I am writing a matching constructor
to the parent class.
So I have a constructor
inside the parent class
which takes this argument off by string.
So if I am allowing this inheritance,
if I am extending from this class,
I must have a same constructor
inside the child class
and that constructor
should call the parent class constructor
so that the first of the parent
class can be initialized properly.
So it's mandatory from Java
to initialize the fields of the parent
if you are extending from a feeder.
So if there is a constructor
in the parent class, you must
have a matching constructor
in your child's class.
So that's why I need matching constructor
in this class of
because I
if what happens is
if I don't have the matching constructor
as the parent class constructor,
what can go wrong?
So whatever the parent class
has, each alternate is the same. Yes
or writing
will not work.
You will not be able to inherit
the methods of the parent.
Okay, so let me do this guys
inside this person class.
Let me comment on this line.
Okay, so all of these constructors,
they are calling this constructor, right?
And whatever I was doing in here,
I have commented that out.
So technically,
as if I am not calling this constructor
or if I don't have
this constructor anymore.
Okay, because if I try to remove it
completely, I will give me an error.
So I am trying to show you the
benefit of having this super in here.
Okay.
I cannot remove it completely
because I will be getting an error.
But instead what I have done,
whatever I was doing in here
because the super it calls this
in the class constructor, right?
So I have removed this line here.
I have removed this line.
So now you guys will be able
to see what happens
if we don't have that matching struct that
the name will not initialize the instance
variable in that case.
Yes. That's that.
That's exactly what happens if we don't
call the parent class constructor.
So let's say, for example,
if I am using this name field in here
right
inside one of my methods
and if this is not there to solve
the instance
variable is only the instance.
So if I am using these instance fields
inside my methods now all of this matters.
They will misbehave by misbehave
I mean I will be getting a null value.
Okay.
Because the same method
is inherited inside this employee.
The same method is inherited inside
student, the same method is inherited
inside this teacher.
Okay, so now if I say
so, if I say, is this what you do?
Is there
if I'm
just giving
this So
let me open side by side
and a guide.
Are you done typing it?
Yes, I did.
Here,
actually, there was this store and my
I hope you guys all know. So
it was so let me show you is missing me
and so I was supposed
to teach the school classes
what I could not
teach in this picture.
How can I open that?
Okay,
I hope you guys can see the
then I had here
similar a similar to his
because he was missing me badly.
He was the mean guide.
And you tell me please in case we need
your static award performed activity.
So mostly Alexa, you guys will be
creating the state a static methods.
So if you are not planning to use
the instance.
Feels like for example, this one always go
with the static method.
Someone is asking
the price are let me converted.
I guess it passed $3 $3.
But it's still expensive, right?
I mean $5 a call
in Ukraine versus $3 here.
If so, now
if I now
create the object of, let's say, teacher
or feature is equal to new teacher or
pupil, my like Pakistan and Indian barber,
weird, incorrect.
Okay, so if I fall oops.
If I say teacher dot it
what I what I will get
or why do I forget to tell you
I had this official as well.
It's official playing card
and all that into dollars.
So if you ask me if I execute the score
you see only is eating.
Yes, only three is eating.
This is the problem that happens
if we don't use
the super keyword the fields,
and then I am using from my parent class,
they will never be initialized.
They will never be initialized
if any of the method
from the parent class,
if they are using those fields,
they will never work properly.
There's the
that's the use of the super keyword.
Okay.
So I have not removed this
this super from here
because we will be getting an error.
But what I have done,
I have commented this
in this piece of code inside that matter.
So technically, same
as if we are not calling the super dot
and these parentheses,
if I am not calling the super constructor.
So if I put it back.
So because I was, I was using this method
from the parent class and that each method
was using this instance field
and this instance field
must be initialized
if I want this method to behave properly.
That's why I call the super from here.
So even though if I am doing it
from the child class,
still the parent class feels
they get initialized.
Is this clear now?
The use of super keyword.
So now if I execute the score
now I will get escalating.
Yeah.
Now the fields of dependent
class are properly
initialized.
Super. And this in the main class.
What was the rule number three
in the note, please?
The rule number three was this.
And so
if we are trying to store a child class
inside the parent type variable,
I can do that.
But if I am doing the reverse
storing a parent object
inside the child variable
that I cannot do,
okay, directly or indirectly,
that that was the total number three.
Anyone ever tried to fool go?
I will be getting a runtime exception.
Class casting exception.
Okay, so now guys, tell me.
So this was about the super key
were not telling me how can I,
how can you please that an example.
So yes,
I can explain that in an example as well.
So tell me guys is so
this also relates to real things.
Okay is it
feature is it is is is a teacher
a person also?
Right.
So I can do that.
I can say a person person is equal to new
new teacher.
Okay, I can do that
because this is how it works
in real life, right?
I can do that.
Yes. This subclass and
now tell me,
are all these persons are their teachers
also in our real life?
No. Right.
So I cannot do that in Java. But okay.
I cannot do that.
I cannot say teacher Oops.
Teacher,
teacher is equal to new person, right?
Because this is not how it works
in our real life.
And the same rules
they apply in Java as well.
So I hope now you guys can remember it.
If something is, it can be categorized
under something else,
then we can do that in Java as well.
It same in in our real life as
okay so that's why.
Because
the whole purpose of this object
oriented programing,
guys, is to translate the information
from real life,
then build the rules
against those objects and classes.
So you guys are kind of literally
creating everything that exists in
or sometimes a portion of a thing
from our real life, right?
Think of the banking applications, right?
They virtually did they they created this
that there will be an account
inside the account.
There will be funds inside of the funds
someone can deposit
or someone can withdraw.
So it's all about translating things
from real life to the these computers
inside this virtual world
and then defining the rules
around those objects and classes.
Now, if these things like like if how
they work in real life,
if they also work almost
the same way
in the virtual world
on inside the computers,
you guys will be able to write programs
easier and in a much better
way, Like so which our guys have done.
They have
they have also
almost same rules
as we have rules in our real life.
Okay.
So that you guys can easily
translate the problem from from real life.
You guys can build applications
around the around the real life
solving any issues or like that because
programing languages,
these object
oriented and high level languages, they
they were not created right away
when the computers got invented,
it took them 15 to 20 years,
actually more than that.
So they started building
programing languages in 1968
and Java came into being in 1995.
So almost five years.
So they have slowly learned these things.
They have slowly learned
how we can solve real life examples
in a better way using this programing.
So so they they did it.
That's why they have almost similar rules.
So this is not possible.
Yeah.
So you guys
you guys going to have a very quick check?
Just check for that.
Is a relationship
like you even that exist.
You guys can do that.
If that does not exist, we cannot do that.
Who was asking about now?
And I think for hard.
No, not for hard.
Is it clear now who ever.
Well, ask most of our.
Okay so I cannot do that.
All right.
So can you guys tell me now,
can I say this?
Can I say
so? This equal to sign.
This equal to sign is
it is is pretty much
saying if the thing that is
to the right, if it is same
as the as this thing that is towards
the left of it
or if it has this is a relationship
okay so again I say maybe I'll give
tell me this if you guys have understood
this and I say student
who is equal to new person
and I say that
no, Why?
Because not all the persons
in our real life,
not all of them, they are, they are.
Student Right?
Some of them
they might be right, but not all of them.
But if we do the other way around,
if we see one
person, person
one is equal to new student.
Is this logically correct?
Right.
So I can see that, okay,
Java will not give me any errors.
All right, guys,
back.
So can you guys now tell me,
how can I use polymorphism
in here
at the bottom of it?
Is that a right and for the array,
what should I should be this type
of that addy
brings strings, string
strings.
So tell me guys
if I so so a lot of you are saying string
and then
area is equal to New York New
York New
maybe let's say student
are students
are all these students are this things
are these things
to organize for this
to represent inside strings thing at
any type of this
it should be
the logic should hold true for this
part of the add is as well.
Right.
So now this is logically true, right?
Only this to all the students.
They are percents.
That's why I can create an area of persons
and I can put inside that person.
I can put student,
I can put employees, I can put teachers.
And because logically,
they are all persons, okay?
That's why I can do that.
But I cannot do that with string, right?
Because implies they are not strings.
Right.
Okay.
And then I can say
yes, it's like a train so
I can send you employee
and I can put it on me line
things.
String, string.
And then you
feature right?
Okay. All right.
And now how can I call all the method
from all of these classes
loop.
Right.
Can I use this simple for loop
will that I variable
is equal to zero
I less then and then I plus plus.
Can I use that loop?
No clue.
Better law.
So yes, I can use that loop as well.
Okay.
I was just checking if you guys have
revised the concept for selenium or not,
but the advanced one, the enhanced one,
they are recommended
because if we are only accessing a value,
we should always go with the advanced one.
Okay. It's more clear.
It's more easy to read.
So I can say for each
here and then a version with
the type of the variable in here
person, right?
The first person and then
adding okay.
Or maybe less.
So most of the time
you guys will see this terminology first
since
they already have this variable.
So let me make it person two
and now I can say person to God,
perform daily tasks.
Okay, so now I will see all the methods
from all of these classes
that I am storing and
all that comes in here.
Now tell me, guys,
is there anyone who is still confused
about casting or polymorphism?
What if we have specific
method for teacher class?
We cannot do that.
Yes, we can argue that.
So let's say for example.
So you'll get
I saying if let's say for example,
there is
special method in here.
So now this method
is only available inside
this feature, this person class.
Yes, we can do, but this person
class has no idea about this
design class
and the variable time that I am
using to call all of these method,
what is the type of this variable?
Is this person to
this person?
Right? What does this person know about?
This specific method?
No. Right.
So now if I try to say
person to dot
design class
or something like that,
I will not be able to do that.
Okay. Or about.
But what we have something
or I forget I forgot about
what do you guys going to do something
that is with the help of another keyword
that is called instance of keyword.
Okay, so let's say
you want to call a specific method.
So what is happening in here, guys?
Firstly, object
of new state, new student is created.
It is placed inside this variable.
This method executes right
then the object of the symbols created.
Then it is placed inside this variable.
The method on that object is executed
and then we do the same.
How many of you understand
what I have just said?
So not me.
Okay, let me repeat from this area.
From this area
I am getting the object of student
with the help of this loop
and I am calling this
this method on that object.
Then I get the second objectively
second element of the array.
I executed the method on second
object, then I get to the third object.
Then I execute this method on the target
of how many of you understand
this?
This is this is what this loop is doing.
So there is there is another keyword.
We with the help of that keyword,
we can actually at runtime we can check
which object
this person two variables contains.
I did that to that object
that the keyword is
we can say if
person to
instance off
feature.
Okay,
so with the help of this keyword,
if this person contains
and object of teacher class,
this will return true.
Okay.
This condition will return true
if this person do
contains on which I appreciate this
condition will be true based
on which our duration of the loop
This condition will be true.
Yes, we are doing the same thing
in the loop.
Maybe it would be more clear if we put
name inside, perform daily tasks.
Yes, we can also do that.
But give me one more.
And so when the last hour duration
will happen, this person two will contain
this feature object
and this condition will be true,
then what I can do?
I can convert this person to object.
Can I convert this person to object
back to the teacher?
In the last citation?
So is the same example I book the teacher
inside of the person box
and now I am trying to get them back.
The person from that box included.
I pulled the teacher
entire parent type variable
and first I check
if that box contains the teacher or not.
If it contains the teacher,
I get it back from that box.
So in the last iteration
I will be storing teacher inside person to
I check in here
if this box contains a teacher
and then I am trying
to get the teacher back.
And I know that
yes we can.
So what I can do,
I can convert it back to a teacher
right in the last iteration
and then I can call
these line classes.
Okay.
And I will not be getting any error
and the code will work fine.
By the way, if you guys don't understand
score, it's all because of your data.
Okay.
I was not planning to show this.
I'm just kidding.
So it's a good point.
She reminded me about this.
So now if I execute this code,
you see, create wrap and design classes.
Okay, so giving homeworks after that,
it has printed this.
Now, if if I don't put this if condition
guys, if I don't put this
if condition we'll do this thing
what will happen now.
It will not get executed.
It will show for everyone.
So from the first I tradition,
what I am putting inside the box
student But what I am doing in here,
what I am trying to get from that box.
So I put this to order.
I try to go to the back.
Teacher Is it possible?
So we cannot I will get
the famous
class cost exception
here because teachers and the students,
they are not equal fired.
They are not equal.
So that's why I write that if condition
I only try to get back teacher
if that box actually contains the teacher.
Okay, therefore this
if condition is important,
do you guys understand
the importance of this?
If condition and how it is working?
But there are so many things.
I mean, we
can spend the next five years
just learning Java.
There are so many concepts,
so many things.
But and then because we will,
we are training you
for an academician engineer.
So we only try to show you that part.
So I think we can throw if and else if.
No, I, I'm in total.
It depends on you.
If you want to use if you want to best
for multiple conditions,
then definitely you need if as if
if you are only testing one condition,
then you only need one if condition
can you scroll down on the person class?
Exact max.
I cannot scroll down further.
I think we need to do
so. If you guys are not comfortable
with polymorphism overriding,
maybe we can spend more time on that.
Yes, we can go to break
and after the break we will do.
I think Lobo is not present in here,
so after the break
we will do an example again,
break, break article, The Colonial Break.
And on the first week,
I mean on the next week you guys will be
starting your selenium.
And in the very first class
you guys will be using
this concept of polymorphism
if it is not clear,
you guys, you guys can tell me
in the next week in class
and then I will show you more examples
from automation as well, because by
that time you guys will be familiar
with selenium and automation.
Can you explain
if as one more time, please?
So this if is, if as if.
Okay,
so if ls means if I'll do the required
when we are checking multiple conditions
if only a single if is required.
If we are only checking
a single condition.
So before we go on break someone,
someone was asking to debug
discord.
Do you guys want me to label the score?
Okay, so let me do this.
Let me put a label point in here
and in here.
So those who understand
how debugging works and
how this all is
working, you guys can on
what can be on break.
This is the only thing that I will showing
and then we will be having a big.
So let me put it in here and let me debug
so I have this step over button
and then step into button.
I want to go to the next line,
which button I should click guys
over button.
Right.
So the object person
one is declared, right?
And then we are declaring in it.
So the of persons
it has three elements.
The first element
is a student.
You guys can see that in here.
The second one is an employee
and the third one is a feature.
So now I have this person variable
and I want to focus.
I want you to focus on this person
to actually see it's very important.
So as the moment I say
next going to see from this area,
the first element was student
and it has been copied
to this person.
So you see it now contains student.
So this person is right now
containing a student object.
Okay, then I call this perform daily task.
So what will happen?
The method from this student
will be called, right?
Because I have the object that student.
Right.
So I say next.
Then I check if person two
which right now contains a student,
if it is an instance of teacher
So this condition will return me false
because student is not an instance
of teacher class, right?
So this will be false.
And I go,
I go to the next iteration of the loop
and as soon as I execute
the next iteration,
you go see this time
this person too, it contains an employee.
So again, we perform daily task
from the employee class will be executed
and we will see this output.
Then again, this is condition text.
If employee is an instance of teacher,
is it an instance of teacher?
Guys? No.
Right. So
this condition will again be false.
Then a teacher will be placed
to the last object.
This this one from the area
is now placed inside the person.
So to execute the perform the task first,
then it checks.
If teacher is an instance of teacher
or not.
Is this condition true now?
So now it will enter inside in here.
Okay.
So and from this person to box,
I am getting this teacher instance back.
Okay,
I'm getting this teacher instance back.
And now the design class will be called.
Okay, So if I have a specific method
inside a class,
I must have the object
in its original form to call that method.
That's
why I am writing this piece of line.
why I dislike this part of the code.
That's why I convert the person back
to its original teacher form
so that I can execute this method.
Because executing this method
when the teacher is stored
inside of the parent type box,
if not possible,
we have to convert it
to its original form.
Well, I'm getting an error first person so
Michael,
on line 16,
you have given the name to your array
as array, but on line nine
then you are using person.
So either change the line
number 16, Edit 2% or change your line.
Number 19 to a
or address.
So is it clear now
how the shifting of objects
from one box to the other box happens?
We can call specific method
and how we can execute all the meters,
how casting works, why it works like this,
why we cannot store one type of object
in another type.
How, how, how the logic works.
Why it is logical to
divide and does all of this.
Okay, so now let's have a break.
After the break, we will solve the task.
And today's class will
we will start today's
class back
so we can spend more time
on polymorphism and overwriting.
And this if you guys don't understand it
after the next week as well, don't
worry about it.
So three for P and then
to two
for 52
it will be 15 minutes, right?
Or 15 minutes.
Yes please.
We should stay on polymorphism.
So if you don't want to
complete this bootcamp,
otherwise please be back by 853
and remind me about the coding.
All right, guys, I hope you guys are back.
Three. Thank you.
Okay, we are already recording.
Look at my profile picture
it. It's
the Western Now I have to have a haircut
like you.
Next time, maybe.
Or I can gain weight like you.
So if it great.
Let's have the work.
Oh, by the way, I forgot.
I forgot to tell you that.
That today's class
is actually the easiest class.
It's about the final keyword with the you
final? Yes.
Finally,
we will learn about the final keywords.
You always said this.
So now you guys know the truth.
Well,
I know this setup, okay?
It's.
It's really
it's really it's really the easiest class.
So, again, you guys send me the
statement for question
and we will expect it hard.
The hard part is gone.
It was polymorphic ism.
It was hard, right? It was actually hard.
I mean, as compared to
other classes.
But not too much. Yep.
Can you guys send me this statement?
I need more explanation about this.
Yes. Now,
on your job,
you will only be needing the polymorphism.
Nothing else.
Right.
So let's spend all the classes on that.
We have already spent three classes.
Don't worry, I'm just kidding.
We will spend more time.
If you guys want to create.
This work already
you covered in your review class.
I told us all to go about to go through
the polymorphism and all that as well.
During review class as well.
Access modifiers
at here.
So next time I will ask Suhail or ASL
to spend more time
on polymorphism
or create
a class store that will have pre subclass.
See that as syntax student quality.
Our schools
define common behavior within parent class
and override some of the matters
in this child.
Classes.
Define
some methods specific to child classes.
Great example of achieving polymorphism
or so
let's define a behavior study.
Right all the disorders this fairly
to you look in our homeworks.
Yes I do.
So when I see lot of people
they are making same mistake.
Then I try to incorporate that feedback
during the during
the class
and I am thinking of
actually picking the homework
from any one of you
from the next classes
and then maybe trying to fix text
so that you guys can see
how we're where things were wrong
and how we fix them.
And you guys can define any methods.
I am defining these methods.
You guys
can have any methods in here. Now
let's have a syntax class
class syntax to run experience
and the student.
Okay,
so now let's try to override
some behavior.
Is it okay to study 25 hours a week?
Is anyone angry?
Yes, I am
enjoying hurting.
Is from parents, right?
Attending the classes.
I am so happy I am not hungry.
Otherwise I would walk after
class.
But in the picture world
they are playing game, right?
They are not studying
or doing like something like that.
Right.
Question Question.
Still, it's a good
good use.
So syntax student must do
additional reasons
and then we can have the class
college students.
And then I don't want to override
these methods
for the student, but
only, only let's override
one of the methods.
So two of the methods they will be
same.
And then
class
will student
and not override
any of the methods in here.
But we need to write override at all.
It's just a recommendation.
It's just an annotation.
Yes. It's good to write. It's
good to write.
You should always like it.
Let me actually follow the best.
Represent me
back in here.
It's always good to have
because it will tell you
if you are making a mistake or not.
You see, if I if I put this override
on study and homework,
I don't get any error.
But the moment I put it on to do research,
I get an error
and it says method does not override
method from the superclass.
Or what does this error means?
It is saying hey is good.
There is no new research
method inside your parent class.
If there is no method
presented inside the parent class,
you cannot override it, right?
You cannot override it.
So that's how these override annotation
annotations can help.
It's always good to hear.
So now let's have
so guys
quickly write the code
to achieve the polymorphism
or the code that you guys have written.
To achieve the polymorphism.
Quickly
send that in the IntelliJ questions.
Jenna, Let me let me see how you guys
have written it.
Student to college.
Student Senior Student
Okay, so Elena has written
this piece of work.
Oh, I think you have already.
You'll be casting in it
and all that pre tutorials.
All right, perfect.
So I have this study method,
I have this homework method,
and then this
practice method
already.
So I will be able to call these
three methods
without any costing right.
But drive decode
if I want to for inside the same look,
how can I execute this?
Do research as well.
Right. Right.
That piece of code. Yes.
With the if condition otherwise
we will be getting an error right.
Because we are inside the loop
and that will try
to convert every object
to the syntax student object.
Yes. According to today's class, if
if first instance of syntax to run.
Yes. Next.
After that, what should I do
if I want all this new research
Student
One instance of syntax class to index to.
Student one And learn or this is great.
Alex So your guitar,
your code is not correct
because I cannot
this is not a static method, right?
So I cannot call it on
the name of the class, no collaborators.
And then you are missing
that name of the object as that.
Okay. Okay.
No, no, no.
So you this is the object, right?
So as yes, no other then?
That is correct. Yes, it's correct.
And then that.
So if s is an instance of syntax student
try to convert their S
and then try to call this
new research
and execute for
and I get all the output from everywhere
and I get this output, but
any questions from this task
based.
Yes, maybe as defined
the variable differently.
So this is how you guys
are supposed to solve this homework.
Okay.
Just going.
Okay, so no questions.
So we move to the
today's class.
Okay, so
look, we did a long way,
but I wondered only not research
of how to do that.
Technically, this is I mean, this
let's say I,
I have this
class, and inside this pattern,
I have a field.
How many of you know about the value of pi
or the value of gravity?
The value of g gravitational pull or not,
or any other constant?
Are you guys all aware of gravity?
No, not me. So
those who are not aware of the gravity,
can you guys
tell me if we throw something to
in the sky,
why it falls back on the earth?
It's because of the gravity.
So our earth is always putting a force,
kind of attracting everything
with the force of 9.8 meter per second.
So in simple terms,
due to gravity, we all stick to earth.
What goes up must come down.
But this does not happen in this space.
If you throw something in this space,
like, for example,
if you are in the middle of the
I mean, if you are not on any planet
or moon or something like that,
if you throw something,
it will keep on moving indefinitely.
Okay?
Because there is no gravity or no other
force or nothing that can stop it, okay?
It's not like it does not work.
Like on like
with like it works on the earth, okay?
It does not come back.
It will keep on moving in that direction.
So everything stick to earth because of
this gravity, all those C and everything.
All those waves that we see in these
in C, they are
of the gravitational pull of the moon.
So when we have to right,
when we have to really find
some mathematical classes
we are doing,
when we are defining some classes
that will be dealing
with these constants or,
or if also there is something
that we never want to change.
That is something universe that we want
to define their thing inside a variable
and we don't want anyone
to change in their thing.
Okay?
To change the value of their thing,
then we will define their thing as final.
So for example,
we all know that on the earth
the value of gravity
will be 9.8.
Now, we don't want to change this thing
in any of the classes, okay?
We don't want to change this thing
inside the business class.
Okay?
Because if we are allowed
to change in this thing,
this value of this variable,
and if other matters
or other fields are only using this value,
we can get a wrong result
for all those matters.
All those matters, they can be here.
So when you want something
constant in your code
like laws, universal constants
or values of your variables,
you make their thing
final and you store their thing
and the value inside of that thing.
There is one more benefit
of defining these final variables.
Do you guys know there is
another paradigm, the functional paradigm.
In that paradigm, every variable is final.
When we do that what happens is
there can be hackers.
They can try,
they can go and check your memory.
So all of the programs
and they are executing inside the RAM
right on my computer.
I can write a program
that can that can go inside
the memory of other programs
and it can change the values.
But if I define if I declare
the variables as final,
those those things, they can never
be changed or not even inside of memory.
So it's very good practice
for security reasons as well.
If you know that something is going to
make it fine, it declared it final. Now,
how we can achieve that?
We achieve that
with the help of final keyword.
Now let's see if I have a method.
Maybe
strategy can be changed.
Yesterday can be changed
starting again,
but just starting means something.
Sure, across
all the objects, static does not mean
a thing that can not be change.
Okay. If you define it.
So maybe the naming convention
is confusing. You.
That static keyword
is coming from a special memory area
inside our computer that is called static.
That's why we call those variable
that static
because they are declared inside
that static area.
So I am now writing a method.
Okay So I am writing a method
and I see
if I say gravity is equal to 10.2,
I will get an active okay
and the error save
can not assign a value
to final variable and gravity.
These final variables,
they are only assigned a value once.
Once you have initialized the
these variables.
Once you have stored something inside
of these final variables,
you cannot change that.
Okay?
You cannot change that.
So I cannot reassign it.
I cannot change it. Okay.
I can now only replace.
All right, now,
what are the other uses of the
final plot?
The final fewer.
So right now,
every class inside Java, again,
inherited from the spin class.
If you guys don't want this behavior,
if you don't want the others programmers
external from your class, use your code
and then develop on top of your code.
What you can do,
you can make your class final as well.
And now the moment you you do that
now, any class
that now tries to extend from your class
will get
an error
cannot and added from final period.
Okay no one now
can inherit from your parent class
because we have declared
that class as final.
This is the second use
of the final keyword.
The hard to use of this final keyword is
will be matters
ready programmers will love that
the term
to use the tanios is will be methods.
So you guys have learned how
well what happens
if we put the final keyword
with variables?
What happens
if we write final keyword with class?
Now if I put final with the method
now, I cannot override
this method inside.
My child class.
Okay,
so now I go to Sara, blah blah blah.
Cannot be override in blah blah blah over
method is final.
Okay,
so now I cannot override that method.
So for example, for example,
if guys want something now,
if you know, if you don't want your child
classes.
No, no, it does not work for the overtone,
only for override.
Okay.
Only for override.
So in the previous example, if I am not
is is trying to marry someone else.
What the father of four I am not can do.
He can make the method as final now
and what cannot override.
Okay.
And if I'm still trying to find new method
it is Father
can even make the whole class as final.
So now he don't get any inheritance?
No, No property.
No money from Father.
So these are
the three uses of the final keyword
when we put it with the variable,
we cannot change its value.
When we put it with the method,
we cannot override that method.
When we put it with class,
we cannot inherit from that class.
So then that was for this class.
I hope you guys have into this.
Thank you so much.
Joining and by
so this is the third
use of the final key
or let me put it on the nose as well
so there is one one that you guys can do.
Last thing is if
if let's say
I don't know the value and this time
I am writing this class, okay,
so what I can do,
I can also give initial value
to this gravity variable
inside the constructor.
I can also take this value from outside.
So this is possible, but it is allowed
only inside the constructor.
Okay.
Only inside the constructor.
So this not gravity is equal to gravity.
And once you call
the constructor of this class
and you assign the value,
now that value is fixed.
Okay, so we can only assign the value
to this variable inside the constructor,
or we can initialize it right away
when we declaring that variable.
Okay.
And now we must
have a matching constructor
inside the
class as well.
The is it?
Is there anyone confused
about these three uses of the final
keyword
is here.
So that is straightforward
and that's all about it.
So let me put it in the notes.
Final
keyword.
So what is the first use of the final
keyword?
Right?
Or one of the uses
will be during the homework.
As always, yes,
I will try that fight with the variable.
Right.
If we write final with
variable.
And let me show you one more thing.
So let's try
to have
so what we can do,
we can really clear this variable
in inside the child class, but we cannot
change its value from the parent class.
Okay, so this is possible.
So don't don't get confused
that we cannot also really declare it
like like, for example,
we can not really clear this method,
but we can redeploy
clear this variable in here.
Okay. So different from this one.
Okay. So
if we write the final with variable
rule,
we cannot
change its value.
And there is one more restriction we must
dangerous value.
Either we should
initialize it
right away
or through the constructor
when used with the method.
What happens is if we use it with method,
but about uppercase
name of final variable as we will or
Alex will do or is not right.
What about uppercase name?
Oh yes.
So someone is going to remind me
there is one more best practice guys,
regarding the final variable that
when we make something
constant, when we declare
something called the SO convention
in Java, that we declare it
in all uppercase letters,
okay,
Like this, It's convention all caps
just for the final variables.
You will not be getting any errors
or something like that.
It's just a good practice.
All perfect. So.
So what type of guys, when we
when we write this
final keyword with the method,
when used with
method, we cannot
we can't
override that
method in the
charter class, when used with
class.
What happens if we use the final keyword
with class?
No class.
Then explain.
And from
from that class
class can extend from class to
so let me check if we are missing
something. Oh,
you guys have done this.
And if you.
You were
so final variable
to create constant variables.
Final method to prevent the method
overriding final class
inheritance.
This is just another example.
And that example and third set.
Okay, so how many of you know
want me to start with abstraction in Java?
And how many of you want to add to
this class
in here?
I'm not fast due to
this class was super, super short.
And what, you guys are all tired
so I can you write
in English,
see the song, start
I'm in.
Google is unable to even understand that
it's enough for today.
Okay, so let me give you a little bit.
Let me give you an overview,
kind of overview about the abstraction.
I focus have so many.
No, no.
Easy to remember when you do. Yes.
Put too much to order.
No. 933 We still have like 26
7 minutes right.
Okay, let's end the class
because I'm also not feeling well.
And tomorrow
we will learn about the abstraction.
Abstraction is also not that tough,
but actually nothing is an alternative.
After this class
from this polymorphism
interfaces
encapsulation you guys already know
about again those same.
So try decrement thirds
in here.
You guys will be getting another project
regarding the videos,
explaining the concepts writing code open
and this is my favorite part,
the collections framework.
These are the things that that you guys
will be using the most.
Any push people to become.
Yes, I can do that.
I hope you build them well.
Thank you, Nurse. Please.
They will be pushed with the class.
I will share them with you on abstraction.
So try to watch that video.
I will share the slide.
Try to have a look
over the slide as well.
Can you tell me about your watch here?
Say a galaxy, I think pool. What
android? If
Thank you now said
homework.
I have posted the homework in course
and also our standards.
Your new talk just happen like in 3 hours
before
I was feeling well I think just need a hot
cup of coffee.
Can you look at the calendar?
Yes, I can take calls.
I can make calls and text.
I can watch videos verify, hey,
everything is available on this one.
There is a complete Android phone, kind of
those watch is so scratchy.
I think this one is not
because it's been more than two years
and it still looks shiny
and it's like new.
I have the same one.
I don't know.
I don't know how you use it, but
I don't use it on a daily basis.
So it might be
this is because because of this,
it looks good still.
Garmin 66 and it's 99, 99.
If we have time,
can you look the calendar on canvas? Yes.
You guys can leave.
I will not be taking anything new
because I my my throat
is kind of done
speaking for today
and kosher
last.
Is there anything wrong on the calendar?
If one.
Yes, we have the calendar
next Saturday.
EPA class
next session
Review class.
Oh, you guys are on but 11 or ten
group projects
collections,
abstraction.
You mean on
here?
Sorry, not me here.
You mean in here? It is.
It looks good.
Next sensitivity class.
Okay, so this is the Saturday.
Sorry, This friend collections
bring the certain interface.
It looks good on December 3rd.
So on December 3rd.
You guys a review class on Friday.
And this is what you want me to tell.
But then I guess they will be starting
in 15. Check.
When is the best first starting
and they will be having
their first class on
orientation.
It will be on it off. Generally
not doing it on
Friday.
I'll it should not be on Friday.
Let me discuss it with the cell
and it should be actually on Thursday.
So if there is nothing special,
is there anything special on on
2nd of December, some kind of holiday or
something like that. No.
Then it should be on Thursday.
But I will discuss it
and I will let you know in the course.
Question
Honored guys take some rest.
Bye bye. Good night.