You hear me now?
I'm. Your
life is not working today.
But if I can hear you,
I'm doing it.
How are you guys?
Oh, look what you just.
Just word to leave
this file today.
I think someone's
loved your days
and their.
We already checked it.
This thing is better. From what?
Not as well.
I share some videos on.
On regular expressions
that you guys watched that video
in the war time.
Did it make sense?
And what about the types of variables
that a
it is stuff, right
now as easy
peasy now.
All right.
So yesterday we discussed about the Spain.
I just made much of the export testing.
It's known
they're importing on paper
to deal with.
It's a bit complicated
but almost there are
there's just give me just 2 minutes
and I'll be right back on.
Let me
think.
You'll see.
So let me just
go. So
we're discussing about the 10-Q.
We discussed our the this method
and we discussed about the replace
all method.
Can you guys tell the difference
between replace and replace all?
So we discussed toolmakers, replacement
replace or
service train
here.
Replace will replace.
One of the ones was replaced.
All will replace everything that's been.
So if we have the strings.
So you got the new guys?
I'm saying that the replacement third
player only
replace one occurrence.
Right.
So I said
replace.
So this first occurrence
should be replaced, Right.
Will that occur with new
and this should stay the same right.
This is what the replace method
is for.
No, just bought
when we replaced.
So what is the difference
between replace and replace or
replace?
First method only first. Yes.
So that's the difference
between replace and replace.
All is that.
So if you hover your mouse over the method
name,
replace all we can do.
We can add range.
What we wanna replace.
Replace each substring of this string
that matches the letter of their sequence
with specified letter and replacement of
the replacement. Here.
From beginning of this
change of the end, for example,
this will be the best blah blah blah.
So this replace method in here,
we cannot pass
the regular expression in here.
It does not take the regular expression
there that replaced all method.
It works on the
regular expression.
So you guys can also see the arguments
and replace what we are passing appendix.
So these are regular expressions.
They are also bar radicals
and in the replace method
we are passing the target sequence,
the sequence that we want to replace
and the string
with which we want the replacement.
So this is the difference in here.
We pass that regular expression.
Most of the time
you guys will be using the replace
all that
because it supports the
functionality of the place as the
and then it also support
provided of expression.
So if we have
the same display are two plus ten years
long month.
The output of replace and replace
all is the same. Yes,
yes it is same.
The it should not be same thing.
What is the difference again
between the two?
Okay, so the difference is so let's say
if we have to use regular expression
in here,
you may be remove
these special characters.
So can you guys
tell me the regular expression for there
if I want to remove these regular these
special characters from here,
what can I write?
Not off
a capital air capital Z.
So we don't want to replace it.
Capital to Capital Z, All the letters
in between, including the C and see,
we don't want to replace
the lowercase letters from A to Z,
and we don't want to replace the numbers
from 0 to 9.
Other than that, if we have anything,
we want to replace that
right?
That's
something wrong.
Learn did not work with C line D
or do not want because
we will have to replace
with something well,
so it should be in here.
Which would not be SDR.
Replace the word SDR. Yes.
So we were trying to replace with this
SDR to.
Okay, go getting it now.
Let's find
who will be seen with
the replacement.
So you guys see the difference
The moment you replace all method,
it takes the regular expressions, okay,
It can replace it.
If we don't want to replace
special characters like this,
then for this code will be
no need to have the type each.
Then yes.
So the regular expressions.
They also work like the all conditions.
So one way of doing that is to specify
all the characters that you don't want
to replace with this hex symbol system
out as they are to this world.
So we are to make the
you guys see this replace on method.
It takes the regular expressions
and it replaces the values in here.
But if we try to post this
regular expression to this replace method,
we don't get the expected output.
It is not doing the replacement because it
does not work on the regular expression.
It is still looking for this string
inside this SDR variable.
Okay.
And it only replaces the letter,
which means if to see
is the exact detector
that we boss in here,
then only it will do the replacement.
While it is replaced by the method,
it can take the regular expressions.
We can pass different backgrounds,
all the rules that are appeared
in the regular expressions.
We can be used to.
All right.
So and then we started discussing about
the string builder in this train class.
So you guys were asking, for example.
So let me show you an example.
So let's say
I have a variable that specifically
with empty like note
and I have a loop.
And if would try to change the
context of this SDR
three, again, I am just using the slope
just to make changes
to this thing again and again.
And then I print out
the value of a static.
Yes, I get this zero one, two,
three and four.
So can you guys tell me
if there is any issue
with this code?
So the concepts that were discussed
about the string builder
and string class, it is related to that.
It is related to memory.
They are integer string
and integer.
Think about what is happening
inside the memory when we are trying
to make this variable
start again and again.
I think I do. Often.
Yes, we can apply an integer twisting
using this string definition,
which was using one variable.
So the type of the
variable is starting, right?
So what happens?
What happens is when we try to store
something inside is being a variable.
So what will happen?
It will check if something
so strings they are immutable, right?
Means they cannot be changed.
But what I am doing in here
I am changing the value of this SDR
to the again and again inside the loop.
So what will happen
Every time we update the value of
SDR geometry,
it will first go inside the memory.
It will check
if there is any variable which contains
the content that we are trying
to store in this SDR tree.
If the contents are already
inside the memory,
no new variable, no new memory
location will be declared
and this SDR tree will apply to back
memory location
that already contains the data. So
this is it later does not that are lost?
Let me copy this code
and let me paste
it inside of the intelligent
interior.
It can detect these kind of issues. Right?
So if I hello to my mouse over in here,
it says
spring concatenation inside a loop
convert to variable
SDR tree from string the string builder.
Okay.
And with the help of one click
it will automatically change
the string the string builder
because it can do that.
What we are trying to write
and it can detect
which types of classes
we are trying to use for that purpose.
If it finds an issue,
it can tell you the issues
and it will fix those issues also.
So in that it is saying that the operation
that you are trying to perform must,
if you know what string
builder is more appropriate class.
But this type of operation.
Okay, because what we are doing,
we are changing the contents of this thing
variable again and again
and when we change the contents
of this string variable again and again,
it is not the command IT operation, okay?
If we have these kind of requirements,
we should always be going with string
builder class and this is how we will
distinguish the class.
We like String builder,
same as we created the objects
like any of the class,
we are the name of the class
object name
equal to sign the new keyword
and then add the name of the class name.
Then these parentheses
and then instead of deck
plus sign.
So soon you guys going to be,
I think, this setter that we will be
starting using intelligent.
How dare you ask us
to iterate on opposite Eclipse?
So we thought we were using
string incorrectly.
We were supposed to use string builder.
When we use things that need to have
the information cluster and change. Yes.
So you use the variables
if they are constantly,
if distinguishable is constantly,
you are updating it constantly.
You should be use
string builder class
instead of string, which
and that is because it's self memory.
So it's not because it saves memory,
it's because the code is not
is not.
At least this.
If you try to roll this operation
with string, it will take more time.
Okay?
It will take more time.
Append means and calculation.
Append means concatenation.
So this down for you as.
But when you have the
image, the
you or
the variable
always to
string is not
rendered in here.
Returns
every time
we're
going to be memory. The
that when the
would expire
when we are updating the variables
again and again, we should always be using
distinguish good plus
nice things normal connections traveling
while this schools
so it will be back
if you guys get the job
in a good company good companies
they some of the companies
they will be paying you
two months paid holiday
and you guys can enjoy
anywhere like two months in FS
and IP sector use only five days a week.
So and if you guys are working
accidentally,
you can use two months,
you can do the tasks.
So they will not be watching
most of the time.
They will not be watching.
You are given the task you have completed.
You you've been completed
during your job acting night on the
on the week and you can set every
we have most of the jobs.
They are online so
never had more than three weeks we do that
so I disagree it's a little different
from other sectors.
So is it clear days
when you guys should be using this thing
and when you should
be using this finger? This
is so let me
show you some
some methods.
I'm just speaking with turbulence.
So if we press stock
so we have this open method in this thing
builder task.
Now this the brand method
is exactly the same as you guys have that
didn't get method or, or the plus operator
that you guys use in this thing.
Builder class to append
multiple things to a string variable. But
and it can also work with features.
Does booleans and any other type of
then we have the job act
method is the exactly same name.
Look, it's not you, it's me.
I just have something
I need to work out a place.
But we had good time.
We don't really do that,
but it will be doing
much more
than the single classes like that.
So the started method is exactly the same
as the dark matter from this string class.
And you guys don't
need to worry about this code.
Why these input screens?
So in the single class
we have that equals to method.
But sorry, in this thing
we have the equals method
equals the method and here we have
this compared to method.
Okay.
And then we have some additional matters
in here.
Like for example, in distinguish
in class,
you can delete certain characters from,
from a certain index to a
certain index.
And then you were going to get the jobs
index of
and as we can delete
some characters from in between,
we have the insert
method that inserts the characters
in between these two letters.
They are very useful.
And one more thing that
the substring method again, same
size, same.
And we want one more thing that if
if you guys have a string variable,
let's say for example,
if for some reason you are given a string,
but then you want to use
the methods from the string builder class,
or if you are given
a single class object and you want to use
some methods from distinct class.
So how we can convert
between these two classes.
So let's say for example,
if I have this string for
the I
will put it inside
my don't show that option
Master String Builder because
so assume you are
trying to use the name of the class,
right?
Right. SDR for the name of the object.
Remember, if we have the quality methods,
we use the name of the object,
not not the class name.
So just type SDR for not string band.
Is it in here?
Because I have given the name to my object
as String builder.
I will.
I encourage you guys to at least
read the description of delete
and insert
method from this string builder class.
All right.
So let's say, guys, that if I have this
string and I want to convert this thing
to a string builder record, maybe I want
to use some methods from this thing.
We're a class,
so what I can do, I declare the
object
in and
we have anyone on sport channel
what should be there
that's hard and interesting.
Some issues
you can post in here
if you are not getting good response
single string.
Well, until
single or append,
that's it.
Then you have a little mouse
over this, over this append,
and then you tell me
what kind of energy you are getting on.
You. Can you guys tried this quote?
No, no, it's not eclipse data. The
this this class is available
in Java eight.
But then you guys tried this code
in the method append
in this undefined
father die string builder.
Okay, so
for hard
have you given your class
the same name as String builder
by creating the class?
What was the name
that you guys gave to your class?
And you have like for example,
I have you on this recap or column.
What is the name
that you guys have given to your class?
You guys must be using this. Yes.
So for how do you are now
if you guys should not made this mistake.
So remember, this has happened.
This happened with
this a scanner glass as that.
Remember, if we have a class
defined in JDK
and, if we try to define our own class
with the same name,
we can get this conflict right.
So now Java is trying to find this
method
from the class that you guys have defined.
And because there is no append
method in that class
now it is giving you that added.
So make sure guys this name of the class
is something different
and different
than the string builder class.
And you guys can.
Instead of creating new class,
you guys can quickly
oops,
right click on it
and then you can refactor and you can name
and are you you also are
you are also making the same mistake.
Make sure guys we don't define the classes
that are already defined in the JDK.
Otherwise there will be a conflict. And
in Java, preferably classes that you guys
are creating over the classes
that are defined by Java base
statement.
So what we can do
if we have to convert this thing
object listing builder,
we can simply pass this
inside these parentheses like this.
Okay.
And now we can use any methods
from this builder class.
Like for example,
there is a building method
to reverse the strings inside
string Google class.
Okay, so we don't have to write any loop.
We don't have to do anything.
And now if we put in
SDR, there is
and you're going to see
everything has been reversed automatically
because there is
a building method in this thing where
the class will be worse than the strings.
And same is the case with other methods.
You guys can use many, many different
useful methods from distinguish
or class.
You guys.
What would replace the shortened spin?
Let me
then move this to this
thing.
Is it better now?
Literally just through word by word.
So what it is doing,
it is fixing this last character
and it just pressing it in here.
Then it is picking this word
displacing in here.
So it is not only reversing the class,
but it is also changing
the position of those words.
What are the most useful methods?
Last thing that you suggest.
So most of the time
you guys will be using this
reverse method
that those delete and insert methods.
They are very useful
because if you try to do
the same operation with String Glass,
you guys have to write a lot of both.
And I tried to matter.
Guys try to write the method
in which you can insert the characters,
add specific positions, and you delete
the characters explicitly position
doing my homework.
So as
I have told you guys in your real life,
everything, almost
everything is already built for you.
Okay, you guys just are.
You guys should just know how
to use that code that is already there.
How to decode, how to use the libraries
and how to integrate those.
So it's very rare
that you guys will be writing methods.
All of you guys will be writing new book.
If most of the time it's integration.
We just need to pass the interviews.
No. Silva After passing the interviews,
if you guys don't perform,
they will never fly. Too
likely to go there.
So reversing the lines, words
and position. Yes.
So the homework was something different,
right?
In the homework this the Java.
It should be at the last position,
not on the first position
and getting put into it.
So if you guys have any questions
you can ask.
So I will encourage you
to explore this thing,
build the class
now, otherwise
we can start the tasks,
just log period on that or
we go over all of this.
So this one, your task number one,
the testing that will hold a sentence,
write a program to get a new stain
and without any spaces.
How would you reverse this thing
that occurred back then?
It would be reverse
that string word by word.
So this was your first
task, right?
You're just doing that to reward
a sentence.
Write a program to get
a new string
without any spaces.
It was task number seven.
This is not the task number one.
Then you guys and the requirements
podcast number.
Once you know I'm in total
reach at this thing.
Okay, so
let's say I have this string sphere
fixed.
Number one, what I am doing string.
So should I use the replace method order
replace all method.
I can use the boat.
Okay, I can use the boat.
I can use replace.
I can use the replacement.
Okay.
Because
that's where to use the replace
augment and I get all
of these standards.
That is both hard work. Okay.
But most of the time you guys will be
using the replace all method
that my produce overall more powerful.
And you guys tell me if I
if I bring this out,
will I get spaces or I will get
the original sentence?
So will I get a new sentence
without spaces
or with spaces?
Let me let me surprise you.
I am still getting the
sentence with spaces.
Why? I am still directing the sentence
with spaces
Because strings, they are immutable.
The value.
Once we have stored
something inside a string,
that thing can not be changed
unless and until we reassign that string,
I think.
But if so,
if I have a
thing very that
it's being built.
It is not immutable
that needs
to connect. Lost this one. Right.
This is five.
Can I close this one?
But if I have a string builder class
and if I say
do you start in the and
let me try to sign
and try to find
either retrospectively change
the let's use the previous matter.
Okay.
So in here again, I am trying to perform
an operation
but it won't will be replace
all method for me.
Look,
it took hours but no it will not work.
You guys must be doing something wrong.
So let me also do this.
This or method.
So if I have replace all method
so I get
this first full output
and still I am getting original contents
with spaces
get noise.
It will not even work
with double backwards.
Less than this. Yes.
Let's try to print out the original value
of SDR like I am doing in here.
Try to print out that SDR value.
Then you will see these spaces.
They are still there.
Maya, you are also doing the same mistake.
You guys are not printing
the original variable.
You just tried to print out
the original variable in which you are
trying to make these changes.
Look new with the same new.
You guys are not printing out it,
you are only printing out
the output of this replace all matter.
Yes, SDR is still
same because it is immutable,
so I can show you the difference in here.
So if we try to call a method
on a string builder class.
So I want you to focus in here.
Guys, this is important.
If I try to call in method on the string
class,
that is changing the output
of that variable, the regional variable,
the changes, they are not made
to the original variable.
It still stays the same.
But if I am trying to do something
with the string builder
class, the changes
they are made to the original variable.
Okay. In case of singular. Why?
Because string builders,
they are mutable, means
they can change
in the values of their variables.
So you guys see in here
I declare this variable,
but this time it's a string builder
I call a method in here.
I am also not reassigning the value,
right?
I am doing the same in here.
I am calling a method
I am not reassigning.
But when I try to print out
the original variables, value
the contents for the string distressing,
but the context for the string
builder date changes. Why?
Because the strings they are immutable.
That means they cannot be changed and
is a very important interview question.
They will ask you What is the difference
between string and string builder class?
So your answer should be a string
is a immutable, strings are immutable.
Then you guys should tell.
Then you should be using this string class
and then you should be using
the string class.
The thing builder can build
the original string again,
you you can say the
changes
they are made to the original variable.
Then think of this thing
builder are immutable,
but strings without string building
spring in the string will
that are immutable,
but strings
without string builder is unstable.
So for having simple ways,
you can say this string class is immutable
and the string builder classes mutate with
does that mean and is immutable.
So yes, the in all the primitive types
they are mutable,
but as the primitive data types,
they don't have any methods.
So you will not be able
to check the mutability
like I am showing for Distinguish
the class.
Yes, we can change multiple times there.
The whole reason
the string builder class exist.
If we have to change multiple times,
if we have to change the value
of the variable multiple times.
Always, always.
We distinguish class still string builder
pretty much every year since the value.
And that value does not change.
So the string builder
pretty much really assigns the value.
That value does not change.
No, we we say we
we explain this concept like this that
the string builder class is mutable means
any changes
that we are performing on this object,
they will be reflected
in the original variable.
Okay.
But distinct class is immutable means
it cannot be changed.
So once we have declared something,
it will always stay the same
unless and until we re assigned the value.
Now you guys can also say this, right?
You guys can also.
Maybe so you guys can can say it
that what if
what if we do this
so this is one
more type of syntax
will replace a string sustain.
Sorry. On this basis
they can also be represented with this
to backwards slash it.
And as in regular expression,
this is how we represent
a string space.
So what if I am explicitly
assigning the value now
the contents of the original variable,
they will change, right?
So what I am saying is things are
immutable.
They cannot we change then how the value
of this SDR tool got updated, right?
It should not be updated.
It should still be having these spaces.
If the values of these
things cannot change.
Can you guys
can you explain what is going on in here?
Reassigning and changing?
So this is this
is what is happening in here two days.
So when we
when we declare this thing a memory
location inside,
the computer will be occupied
and it will be placed
this string will be placed
with spaces inside that box.
And now that variable
is actually pointing to that box.
When we say the strings are immutable,
we mean that
the contents of this box
can not be changed again.
But what can we do?
We can create a new box.
So when we are removing the spaces and
when we are actually assigning the value,
what is happening behind the scenes
in new boxes being created?
Because now the contents of this box
and this box, they are not same, okay?
Because the conditions are same.
So Java will create a new box
and then this new box will be
we are pointing to this new box in here,
but we will need to note box.
It will always be staying unchanged.
Okay, so this is what what would we say?
That settings are mutable,
strings are immutable.
We say once a memory box for a string
object is created inside
the computer's memory,
that box be contained.
Inside that box is never change.
If we are trying to change the contents
in new boxes created in new memory.
Sally created and then the variable binds
to that new box.
But in the case of this thing builder
only one box is declared
inside the memory.
When we said string builder SDR
to only one box was declared.
When we call this reverse, the changes
were made to this original box.
Okay. No, no, no new box was created.
That's why we see the changes
in the original variable in here.
So that original box will be a store
consuming more memory that is unused.
Yes, ma'am.
So in this string,
so that's why intelligible saying
when I was changing the value
of that string again and again,
I was creating each time
I was creating a new box
for each iteration,
I was creating a new box.
That's why.
And DeLaria told me in their task
that this is not the most efficient
approach that you are
using in here.
Okay? You are.
For each iteration,
you are creating a new box.
Maybe you should go with the String
Builder class to save some memory.
Is it clear now which
So I saw this
two times during the interviews.
So they asked a student
to write a piece of code
and they said that this piece of code
should complete this
task in in this time
and time was in millis and in microseconds
and when I was solving that interview
and when I used the string class,
the test cases for that question
were not passing and the editor lost that.
This code that you guys have written,
it is taking more time.
Then I replaced this thing
with String Builder
and then the than we did
wasn't much so of the components
they will be explicitly asking you
to write more efficient code
which one is recommended to you.
So Shareef if you are not planning
to change the contents
of this variable again and again,
always, always go with the string class.
If you are planning to change the contents
of a variable again and again,
try to use distinguish the class.
Does the string builder
reassign the string
so it does not reassign the string
hallmark?
It actually the changes
to that original box.
So if we are making changes
to the original box,
then we don't need to do anything right.
We don't need to reassign
whenever we have a new box,
then we need to reassign it. So.
So can you guys now explain the difference
between string and string
builder glass
if someone asks you so keep things busy.
It's about saving memory.
I Yes, spinning
it can save a lot of memory
because every time you declare
a new string variable, it checks
if indeed the content that you are trying
to store in that variable,
it will go inside the memory
and it will check
if that variable is already declared
or not.
Okay.
So if that variable is already declared
and memory location is already there,
that contains the exact same string,
it will not be creating a new box.
It will be reassigning that box.
Yes, it is similar to yesterday's example.
Lots of accidents.
So you guys asked me to show an example.
That's why I'm showing this example.
String Builder.
If you need to keep reassigning. Yes.
If we need to keep reassigning,
that's when we should be using this thing.
The class is all about memory.
Interesting.
And the reason that is why I'm focusing,
why I'm stressing so much
this spring class
is the most widely used class in Java.
You will not find any real life
application without the string class
and it can greatly affect the performance
if you are not properly using
the string or string class,
why would you run to the singular before
alone?
You mean when we were showing
the simpler examples for you guys
in classes? No.
So most of the time
you guys will be using the string class
only when you are changing the contents
of the variable again and again.
Then you will be using this singular
class.
Testing is still
the most widely used class in Java.
Okay.
It's not that it's now useless
and you should go always with this thing.
Builder.
Remember guys going to use this thing
and when to use this finger class.
Can you guys quickly tell me
when you should be using the string class
and when you guys should be using this
finger to class?
Remember, things happen, guys.
Remember Android and iPhone, iPhone,
the things that iPhone can do
in six gigabyte, It cannot it shouldn't
do that even in 12 gigabytes.
So this is the reason behind.
Yes, iPhone users distinguish the
thing with the
base system, which is
I don't remember fastest boom
greenglass glass. We ordered one.
We don't change the code
while we use Angular one.
We change the code constantly
so that instead of saying change the core,
you should say change the contents
of the string variable.
When strings keep changing,
we use Angular.
Yes, perfect answer string.
When you are not planning for changes
in the contents
of string. Yes.
And are you guys doing
some kind of sessions
with your group methods?
Do they teach each other
or to try to explain the concept concepts
to each other?
Remember, guys,
I have seen students, very good students
all doing everything on schedule,
performing very well in the class,
but because they lack
the communication skills, it takes
sometimes one or two months for them
to get a job.
And the students
who are even below average or average
because they have good
communication skills, because they know
how to explain something to others, they
they can get their jobs in within weeks.
So interviews
they will not be knowing your background.
They don't know what you know
or what you don't know.
It's how you explain this is how they will
be checking the way you explain things.
Okay.
So try to focus on that.
Okay. Here's my problem.
It is very important.
Very, very important.
In a single event,
you want to make changes
and we
bounce ideas off each other
and turn to each other for help.
There.
So this is how we solve the task. One
Are there any questions?
So my communication skill is below
zero negative.
I am good.
I think so.
I do two or three interviews
already for different different jobs.
They explain on average disorders.
They will say like 8 to 10 interviews.
So before they get the job,
but only because you guys
have to learn so many things.
In the interview, this gentleman.
But if you're if your
communication skills are good,
you guys will be very, very good.
Soft skills are important.
I am my native language
and you do the place
all with the string builder class.
So this will replace all methods for Hunt.
I think the replace out
method is is a little different
in this finger class.
Why is it not working in single class?
Yes. Look, it's different. Okay?
So these replace all matter
to the regular expressions.
It's only available in the string class.
So that's why I have told
you guys how to convert back and forth.
Your finger instinct, the classes
you guys remember.
So in the last example, let's see,
you want to use some matters
from distinguish the class.
So you take your string,
you place is inside these practices
and now you have a string builder and
once and now if you want to go back to the
string class, what you can do,
you can see
thing builder dot will spin.
Okay,
so this boasting to convert the string
builder object back to a string.
And if you want to convert a string
to expand builder,
you step inside these band and tissues.
Okay?
That's how you convert back and forth.
So use the method from both the classes.
I asked them, maybe ones that I could not
graduate.
Will will learn more about string builder
like string functions. No,
we will not be learning
our P functions from this thing or class.
So I hope you guys can use the methods
from the string builder
if they are needed.
Right.
You can just hover your mouse over
the matter, you can read the description
and you can figure it out.
And if this is how I want to do
of how to solve
the problems related to these classes,
let's say you have to reverse something.
Let's say you have to replace something,
you have to search something or whatever
you guys are planning to do.
Try to search that function,
try to search that on the Google fast.
So let's see, for example,
how to reverse testing,
using using distinguishable class.
The moment you type,
you will be able to find out
if there are any methods that can reverse
the string or not from this single class
or you guys can press this,
you can type the variable name
and then you can press start
and you can go through all the methods
that are present inside the name.
But honestly, even though I suck at Job
and I keep applying for a job
and speak with my confidence, there's
a lot of different scenarios differently.
There are like rules. It
is it clear days
how to convert
is being a twisting builder.
Interesting thing that
works on the task.
Number two
appeared
right in front,
but we are testing
that should be combination of letters.
Number and special factors.
Find out how many characters are there
in a string.
So here it is.
Is short for alphanumeric.
So Thursday I have this thing
that's on
me. I
guess the above is some numbers
and some special characters,
and I want to find out
how many
alphanumeric characters are there.
How can I do that, guys?
Which method I can use to find this out.
So first I can replace so.
So what I can do?
I can replace these to
I can remove these three characters
from the string
and then I can use the length
method to call
how many alphanumeric characters
are there.
Okay.
So I can say
replace everything,
but not uppercase
and lowercase letters.
Sorry, lowercase letters
and then numbers from 0 to 9.
Okay, So don't replace these
and replace everything
with with nothing,
which means they will be removed
from the string.
And then I can use method
of chaining means
I can multiple methods in a single row
on a string variable
and I can the length method in here think
so. Now I get the answer.
No matter you think about this,
we should.
If yes, this way is also good.
But remember, guys,
these are regular expressions.
They are not very powerful,
but they are also super, super fast.
The Loop series that you are writing,
it will be way slower
than this regular expression.
So if you are looking for something
of something that also performs
well, you should be using
the regular expressions.
But if the task is to just
get good results, then it's also good.
Why numbers?
So that's what if you guys have done it
only for four letters.
Okay, we can remove this.
So in here
alpha means alphanumeric characters.
But the idea
if you guys have solved it,
only four letters,
it's out of.
So let me answer
this.
Characters.
If you guys search on the Google,
you see Alpha means alphanumeric.
So alphanumeric,
also known as alphanumeric, simply refers
to the type of Latin,
blah, blah, blah, 0 to 9 and then A to Z.
Okay, so do you guys search on the Google
or you just
thought that maybe Alpha means
only B characters?
So that's why I am writing
the numbers as well in here.
Is it good now?
I understood it wrong.
It does includes a few special characters.
It also includes a few special characters
and deliver.
Which one?
I don't think so
concludes the special characters.
What is it?
Okay.
Some common symbols
such as not a terrorist.
And this
I search 0029 is called alphanumeric.
And what we did the idea was this okay,
so how could do know certain characters
and then how to coin, how to count
which characters are left behind.
If I feel home task, it's easy 100%
sure I do something wrong.
We find a good time.
You guys will be playing now.
You guys will be good.
It was a bit confusing.
So if something is confusing guys
you can post in this for channel,
you guys can drag
me and I will help you out
inside of
characters you specify
if you want letters on
those
insert characters, you specify
If you want letters now
and then you rephrase the question.
Then you explain this one more time.
So Abdul, in here
we are first replacing
everything.
So this is the not similar practice,
correct?
Means not
this, this this means the not that.
So I am saying replace everything
other than uppercase here
to the location
to the and numbers from 0 to 9
with nothing.
Which means if there is anything
other than these three things,
it will be removed from this thing.
And after that task has performed so off.
So once I get the results back from this,
replace all methods,
I am calling this length method on that.
So this is what is going on in here.
First, I am removing
the special characters from this meeting
and then that
I am counting the remaining letters.
So once first I remove this, this one,
these three things
that I am left with the numbers
and I personally.
And then I am counting those pins
and four equals to alphanumeric in Java.
I'll Yes, actually
let me do this
this slide, this is my understanding
and someone says programing is easy.
All right, let's solve the next task
is a player Abdul,
the person that did not come
and say that to me, I would say
so should
we move to the next task
based on all questions
all good, then we do it after debate.
So far, yes, we can do it after the break.
Do you guys want a break?
It was fair.
So, first of all,
I know that your time would be
well, you both discussed solutions. Yes.
I always hear of the board after the class
on the YouTube
that both.
Yes, I will share this solution
as often happens as well for the year cup.
So right now
I am posting the solutions on the canvas
so and I forget
to upload the solutions,
find it at oppose this week.
So I will share the solutions
after this class.
This a man manager is saying
get more winners
before we go on break.
Let's let's quickly you solve this fast
so you have a sitting
Saturday.
Is it raining? We have a Java class.
All right.
And how would you find out
how many sentences are there
industry.
So can you guys tell me?
I can use the split method, right?
The split worker.
I won't work.
What should be my condition to split?
Only question What?
What about this thought sign?
This is also the indication
of a sentence, right?
The sentence can end on a period
on a exclamation mark on a question.
Question mark.
Right now we have something
which which notes doodles for English
was posted.
It was question mark in the
in the question
for. Okay.
So let me appear that
so all question marks one question
and then we're going okay,
then we can use the question mark in here.
But in real life,
what will be happening, guys?
You guys encounter
a period, right?
And this exclamation mark, right?
So I if I want to find the sentences
and I want to write genetic code
that will work on any type of paragraph,
then I should be looking
for these three conditions.
Okay, so the split matter
where the subject method will return,
we guys,
it will return me and then add it.
And how can I find the length of an edit
document?
All right.
So I also have this length method
on this thing with the parentheses.
So can you guys tell me
in this thing we use these length,
but in here we are using this line.
So what is the difference? Yes.
So there are three sentences in
this weird integer call, this split node.
Yes. It's also fine if you are planning
to use that variable in the future code,
then you should be storing
the results first in a variable
and then you can display the contents
yourself.
So it's absolutely.
Are there any questions?
Great
for everybody.
Can you enough
for my use for this task.
So guys always,
always try to avoid flawed laws.
They are
they are not good for performance.
If we have a break open recap class,
please be sure.
Why were you why
we don't use length and then parentheses.
So can someone tell now why
we didn't use the land?
So now I think in here why we are using
to weed out those bad entities.
Can you guys tell me the difference
between land with been
and without benefits?
Yes. Okay.
Yes. It's also good for this example.
I think it's awesome.
So this land is a property.
It's a fear.
You guys remember the how it class.
What does the what does this thing work.
What are the things that a class contains?
If you ask and have matters and
a class can have properties three years.
So the this land is actually
a field on the add a class.
That field contains the number of
elements that are dead in an attic
while that land with these better pieces.
It's a method on the string class.
So whenever you have to count
the number of characters in testing,
we use the land to be the parentheses.
But whenever we have to find out
how many elements are there in a string
in, an in an edit,
we use this length field
and because this split method,
because it is a returning, it's an attic.
So that's why we use to this land in here.
Okay.
All right.
This placement, please remind me
about the recording when you guys are back
in there. 70
after recording
and less notes.
All the next problem.
How would you reverse this thing?
Is it cold there in your city?
No, not that. Or
so let's bring this stream.
SDR. I heard in Tajikistan
it goes to -20 or 30, right?
This in winter
will not go below
minus one or minus four max of minus two.
And I am from all
see you. So,
so let's figure we have a state
and I want to reverse.
So I don't want to
change the positions in here,
but I want to reverse
the letters in each work.
So this the position of this
will states same
now three degrees centigrade.
So how can I do that days
What should be my first approach?
So first I should get each word
from this sentence.
I did with low,
but if I start, approach would be bad.
But I think the first
I split and I get
the entity
in here.
So I say ASCII or split,
you just defy these space.
So after this I will be getting an area
with individual
words. Okay?
And then I can do I can start a loop.
Okay, Get each
word one by one
from this addy
and then I can reverse it.
I can reverse it.
So let's try
to use the method
from the string builder class.
So all if if you guys have a method
for something, always try to pressure
that method because these letters,
they are written by experts.
Okay,
so whatever code you will be writing,
there are chances that the code
that is written by Java guys,
or if you are using some library
that will be more efficient,
can we reverse using our gloss bottle?
Yes, we can
bring B for I learned C++.
Yes, we can also use that.
And so how can I convert
is spin boosting builder nice E
Let's say you want to use a method
from this thing builder class
that reverse method.
So how can I can work this word spin
twisting builder.
So I build the
string
weird word or new
and then
import
and I pass
this word
in here.
All right.
And then what I can do, I can do
we have use string word
so you guys don't have to use this thing.
Builder I'm using String Builder
because there is already a method
present inside the string builder
to reverse a string.
Okay.
And we should always,
always prefer the building meters
to solve these problems.
Well, can I request nice line
we are converting to array.
So if we don't convert it to any,
then how can I get these words
from this
sentence? Now?
Because remember, I want to reverse this
string word of dialog.
I don't want to change the position
of this word in here in last.
So if you are only writing the reverse
for loop, the position of this,
it will be in the last of the Yes,
it will be reversed,
but the position will be at the last.
So that's why I am getting a letter.
I am reversing it
and then I am appending it.
So what I can do,
I can apply a loop in here, right?
I can say it's string builder
or replace
or reverse
meaning.
Then I can print out
the spacing here.
So what I am going in here,
I get this, I reverse it.
I printed, then I get is
I reverse it I printed without finger.
The class can be reversed
using only a gloss loop or with word
no. If you want to replace.
So if you want a reverse loop
you cannot use and are lost.
What looks like that.
But instead of putting
lazy basically
is reversed by the position of this word.
This is not changed.
It's still the first word in the sentence
and in the paper.
Guys, I am sure you guys have tried
to build atomic bombs for this example,
for this task right.
And we just two words.
What do you mean just do words?
Check this, please.
If we use land without that
and to see is in reverse.
Correct inherit.
We use land without that indices
into reverse.
Now, what do you mean?
Can you leave your question
String Reverse word
thought is
so said if this is not correct
because you see, the position of the
world today has been change.
We want to change the position of words.
If this is the first word, it should stay
the first word.
Instead, I understood the problem
as reversing the order of first Berkeley,
having that
in fact
ordered it for
no work.
Nothing is wrong.
And let's see,
you are getting the expected output.
Expect something else
on line nine. Why we use.
So if we don't use this,
there will be no spaces between the words.
So the let's say if I don't do this,
then there will be no spaces.
Or finally I
buried specification
inhumane.
Okay, so let me do this.
So it
for example is in
this auction
here this in me up to the last
the slides
so that didn't express the all the
you did better now was
probably has been is this is
variance
I believe this word is an understood
reverse so
no I would remove to the next guys go to
is is it possible we learn you guys
I believe this was
all right it's fine
so if something is not clear.
That's why I asked you for your feedback.
So that we can update things.
Maybe adding some examples, but the tasks
if there is an extended tasks, but
and you guys see
the same problem in ripples,
maybe if some ripples are there,
you guys want more examples.
You can also point those out.
I will fix those.
The How would you check
if this thing is wrong or not?
Yeah.
Corrective for loop and I used to
pull matters but the result is different.
I will be reverse is being
or loop and booleans
is is
the this all of this nice.
Can you tell me which words are palindrome
and which words which ones are not?
And it does tell me the definition.
If you reverse the word,
it will still be same.
So you guys already know that.
So the simplest definition
is that if you reverse testing
and if this thing stays same,
that word is a better drum, Right?
Can you read?
You can read from both sides. Yes.
So it's very simple task, right.
Have it string.
Right.
Are you the Spring Builder class?
Like macro is equal to
because that is.
But it didn't matter
what they were assisting.
So let me try use that
is after the reversal.
If they are
or it was just to be
I see
use string for string
but what is also good
but then you guys are dealing with
with the class.
Okay otherwise
if you compare the performance of string
builder and string buffer,
this thing builder is faster
string buffer slower
and we use sentence for example.
Yes, we can use the sentence
as I used to fall
open, made it so it can check sentence.
Okay.
So yes,
you guys can use the sentences as well.
No lemon normal and
how would you check if a string is wrong
or not?
I used to place or to get rid of spaces
and then check into reverse.
So we need to convert that I so to YouTube
Google and I could not find it
and use use sentence. So
if we understand the logic yes this is
give me some sentences that you guys want
to check
your full years for.
No non one.
It's not wrong because of the spaces.
Let's so if we reverse this thing
this thing is not same
because of the spaces.
If we remove the spaces,
maybe then it is same.
And for that the approaches
that the other students are mentioning,
like they moving the spaces
and then special characters
from in between,
maybe you guys can use that approach.
Okay.
For all these approaches,
they are also good.
Could you please copy paste your code,
make sure
that is God.
Please explain on line one.
So in here we are trying to compare
escaping with the string builder object.
Okay, so because the singular object
is something different
and a string object is different,
so we will be getting a false.
So I am converting that string builder
object to this thing back
before the confetti. It
is. Is not this a very wrong?
Says you're smart. Yes.
Ignore this is so you guys can
get these kind of small issues
like converting
uppercase and lowercase things
before you do the comparison.
So we use this string builder only
for the last method
and then return it to anonymous thing.
Yes, ma'am.
You're right.
Are there other questions
or should we move to the next task
I would use where those things
without the temporary variable
are we doing preference for model? Yes.
So tomorrow, do you guys know?
So here.
Have you guys
attended any session with Serial? No.
So Suhail will be teaching you the review
and to review,
and you guys can discuss the wrappers
or any other things that you, based on.
Does he like means?
Oh, yes, he likes means
on canvas.
I only have rapid solutions,
but I will share the remaining solutions.
Does he go fast?
You guys can ask
if the if any instructor is going fast,
you guys can ask the instructor
to slow down.
What did I do wrong?
I am getting the wrong output.
Now you're going to just give.
So you show me the output
you'll need to.
Newbold Looks good.
Starting with Then you are reversing gear
and then you are comparing it.
Yes, I will.
That last one? Yes.
So you are missing.
You are not forcing this string
to distinguish your class.
So you are checking an empty string
against this thing
and that's why you are not getting the
as the use of all his means.
I think
nobody.
No, don't worry.
I will bring you any experience thing
for maybe any task.
So I saw one this thing before is used
when you guys will be
and market ready for it because
we will not be going over market ready.
So that's why we're going to extract
from the after.
If you guys want to learn
something special and if there are
enough students invested,
maybe you guys can
maybe we can arrange a special session
on those things.
If you guys want to learn expressions
or any other thing in Java,
if there are students interested,
then I can arrange these sessions on that.
So let's say guys, I want to the place.
So inside this SDR,
I want to place this on one
and in turn this SDR I want to place
without needing any
other variable
or add a or something like that.
If I'm to do that.
Guys,
you remember the problem for the integers.
So that would be just without needing
any other variables.
So the same problem.
So first we say SDR is equal to SDR
plus SDR.
So once we do this, what will be stored
inside the SDR
request?
And what if we use yes,
you guys can use to replace
as well. Yes.
Can you replace as well?
So we are missing them.
So start acting out
values of
be. So this is how we replace it.
Be like just saw the time
we are running out of time.
So let me quickly explain things
so we have this thing in here
then we combine these two strings.
So then we will be having this
and on this line what we are doing
to get back
the SDR to I, we are saying
replace the contents of this SDR,
so remove the contents of SDR to Okay.
So right now the SDR to it contains
is sort of all right,
after we replace this old one
with nothing inside the SDR,
we will be left with this bottom right
and then we are saying again, replace
on this SDR again, replace this time SDR.
So replace this one.
So you will be left with this one.
And then we are picking SDR and SDR one
that's German or substituting zero SDR.
This approach is also good,
but this one is easier
to understand.
Using this updating
method, it's a little harder to understand
over two days.
So did you
guys have any questions from this task?
All right.
So are you doing. I'm going to go class.
We will be using that class again
and again and again.
So today's topic is about the types
of variables at the end.
It is one of the easiest topics.
Again, one of the easiest topics.
So you guys learn
how to that are types, right?
And based on those data types
you do find different variable
that's like strings,
boolean, blah, blah blah.
Today
we will learn about the types of variables
with respect to their scope.
By scope I mean if I declare a variable
in a class or inside a method
where I can access that variable,
where
I can not access that variable and how
the memory is consumed under the hood.
So let's say, for example,
I have this name.
So then you guys tell me how many types of
variables are there?
Three types, right?
Any guy's name?
No, they start date, local and instance.
So the variables,
the variables which are declared
outside of the method,
but inside a class of this class,
it starts from this bracket scale,
this bracket.
And in here we have this method
and then we are declaring some variables.
Okay, so the variables
which are declared outside of methods
or a block of code, you guys will learn
about, say, a block of code.
Is this using these parentheses in here?
Okay, so a loop is a block of code
a suitable block of code.
A constructor is a block of code
and method is a block of block.
So if a variable is declared
outside of a block board,
but inside a class, we call that variable
as the instance variable.
So this is an instance 50,
because an instance.
But if we declare a variable
inside a law or a switch case statement
or inside the metadata constructor,
you guys don't know about the constructor.
So those variables,
they are called local variables.
So let's say
if I declare a variable in here
because this variable
is inside this method,
so this variable will be local
to this variable.
So let's say, for example,
you fly, you have another method.
So what I can do,
because this name of variable
is an instance variable,
I can use that variable inside any method
which is inside of this class,
but the local variables
which are declared inside a block of code,
we cannot access
those here but outside of that block.
So for example, if I see
the value of time,
I will be getting another
because this variable
is only only available to this method
starting from this can bracket
do this calibrate.
If this is the second type of variable,
they are the local database,
local variables
before we can use them.
Before we can use them,
we should initialize them.
I think we must initialize them
before we use them.
But the instant variables, we can use them
without the initialization as that
kind of thing here.
So local variables are only local
to that specific block of core.
It can be a loop if you're declared
a variable inside a loop,
that variable is only accessible
inside of that group.
If we try to access it
outside of that group,
we will not be to.
And then
as the line is
that time is a local, we
associate
a false
method
and then we have something
called as static variables.
Now statically idea
they are same as instance variables.
They are outside of a block of code,
but with a static feature
like this, it's
not so you guys
can you guys now identify
if a variable is local static
or instance?
Okay, now let's discuss why
we have these three types of variables
and, why we are learning them again
when we should be using
which type of variable, which
these instance variables are nice,
they are available
starting from this curly bracket.
So this curly bracket.
Okay, if you have thousand meters in here,
these will be available
to all those 1000 letters.
We can access these instance variables
and the static variables
by creating the objects of them.
Okay.
But we cannot do the same
with local variables.
Now, these instance variables,
they will stay in the memory.
So let me
f we created subclass.
That's what's.
And it is a static ever used inside
what not We can not have a static method
inside a method.
So for example, if by state
starting in here I will be getting in at
not positive.
If I said go no, this is for
new or
no name
pending.
There's definitely a name for
local inside public static wide which
local inside public static one. Yes.
So the method can be anywhere.
It can be the mean method.
It can be a static method,
not strictly methods
or all variables
that would declare inside methods.
They are local variables.
So let me debug this code
and let me show you why
we have these different types of variables
and how the memory under the hood
is declared
for these types of variables
and how it is contained.
So the best approach that guys,
if you are solving a problem
and if you have to create a class for that
always, always try to avoid
these instance variables.
The reason is that the instance
variables are and until this object dog.
So as far as this dog object
stays inside the memory,
these instance variables,
they will keep occupying the memory
inside your computer.
Okay.
But on the other
hand these local variables,
the moment the
this sleep method is executed,
these local variables,
even if you have million of variables
inside this method.
So once the execution for this
method starts,
those variables will be declared
inside the memory.
And as soon as you guys are done
executing this
method, as soon as Java is done
executing this method,
all those local variables
are destroyed and the memory is free
to be used by other programs.
But the instant variables,
they will be staying in the memory forever
as long as we have this object
inside the memory.
So let me show you that.
So let's say, for example,
if I debug this program.
So right now
we are inside of me in a method
and no variable is declared
inside the method.
The moment I execute
this line of
core, now we have this dog
and you guys see inside this dog a color
and the name variable is declared.
Okay.
Even though
if I don't have to use those variables,
even though I don't
all the methods on this object, the moment
I, I create the object,
the variables, all the variables,
all the instance variables
that are there inside this class,
they will be declared
inside the memory
and they will start occupying the memory.
Okay, If I execute the next line,
the variable is there.
But watch what happens, guys.
Right now in here
we don't have this times variables.
Okay.
But I watch what happens
when I execute this method.
Okay.
If I go inside this memory method.
The moment I go inside this method,
the times variable will be declared.
And as soon as I am done
executing that method,
that variable is gone.
That complete stack press
for that matter is gone.
But but that our desktop
will still have this color and name inside
the memory.
These local variables.
They are
always, always recommended to be okay.
They only occupied memory for the moment.
Your method is in execution
means when Java
and it is for microseconds.
Okay.
When Java starts the execution
of your method or any block of code,
these variables
they are instantly declared
and once Java is done
executing that block of code,
they disappear from the method.
Okay,
so they are super, super memory efficient.
But these instances variables
and they will stay in the memory
as far as the objects
out there in the memory.
And even if you have million variables
in here, the moment you create the object,
the memory for all those 1
million variables will be occupied.
Even if you are using
only one of those videos.
So these instant variables,
they are highly, highly discouraged.
But when I should be using the instance
variables,
does it mean that instance variables
they are useless?
No, they are not useless.
So you should be using an instance
variable.
Then you have to share something
between your methods.
So you guys see this name
inside the stock class.
This slave
method can access this name, right?
This method in objects of this name.
But this times it is only only accessible
to the sleep better.
So what if I have to share
some information
between my class matters?
If I have these kind of requirements,
then I should be going.
For instance, variables.
Otherwise, always, always local
variables are recommended.
Is it clear this?
Can you give a practical example?
Yes. Yes.
Java Economics.
Yes. We Will do the example the last.
Now what about this?
These static variables?
Okay.
When we should be using the static videos.
Now to
understand this
whenever actually let me
let me create one more.
I have created two.
There are two objects from this class
I haven't added on in bigger times.
Okay. Yes.
I need to update.
So when I create the objects from a class,
this is what happens inside the mapping
or this dog to
in name variable will be declared
and a value of this. Yes.
Right.
Will be stored inside that way.
Then a color variable will be declared.
So this is dog to object
and then another object
created inside of the memory
that will called a dog.
If it's one.
And again, a copy of the instance
variables will be created.
And in this time in here
we are only storing
Jasper, and inside the color
will only store in black.
The black instance variables
each time we create
a new object is separate copy of instance
variables is created for each object,
and then we can store
object specific data inside of that copy.
But when we declare a static variable,
then we declare a static variable.
There is a separate memory location
that is called static area.
So these all of these objects
and these memory locations,
they are being created inside the heap.
So inside the event there are five
special memory areas inside your RAM.
When you execute a Java program,
there are five special memory areas.
We will not be going into the details.
So one of them is called the static area
and the other one is called the
heap.
So all of these objects,
they are created on your heap,
but these static variables,
they are declared inside the static area.
And even if you create a 1 million objects
of a class,
only one memory location
will be declared
for this static variables.
Okay, For instance, variables.
If you create 1 million objects,
1 million copies will be declared.
But static variables,
only one memory location is
and that memory location is shared
across all the objects, all the objects.
So if
if I say
so, let me, let me.
So just to show.
So if
if I say dog dot
number of flags
and if I say four in here nice.
I am setting the value
using dog object to this static variable.
Okay. But watch what happens if
if I try
to bring back to using the dog
to object,
I will be getting the same value,
but I will be getting the same value.
So I get four.
But for instance variables.
If I store something inside
an instance variable.
Okay, so in here
I am setting the value of this name again
using the dog dollar object.
But if I try to get to that value
using a dog tool object,
I will be getting
nothing. If
so, I get.
And so the values of this static
variable static is
something is common
for all the objects of that class
one object
and stored the value inside that variable.
All other objects will see the same.
Okay, Only one memory location is shared
across all the objects,
like for instance variables. Each
gets a
separate copy of instance variables
from that object.
Okay, so whenever you guys
have to share something across
all the objects of a class,
then should I use the instance variable
or the static
variable?
The static variable. Right.
And if I know that
something will spare same
for all the objects, so should I
indicate a static variable for that
or an instance variable?
If I know that something will space
same for all the objects.
Should I declare a static variable
or instance
variable?
So all the dogs,
all the healthy, not affected
dogs, not defective dogs,
they will be having four legs right.
But if I try to store back
inside an instance variable,
what will happen
for each dog
in new memory location will be created.
I don't want to do that
because I know all the dogs.
They will be having four legs right?
Then why should I declare separate
memory locations for all the objects?
Why should I declare instance variables
if I know that a piece of information
will be staying the same
for all the objects?
Right.
So then I should be going
with static variables.
But if I know that
the information can change
object to object,
then I should be declaring an instance
variable for that.
I know that one
dog can have maybe Casper, name
the other dog and have Casper
skied the other dog.
Another dog maybe can having another name.
So I know that the information
is changing.
Object to object.
Now I should not be going for instance
variables.
Now I should be declaring a sorry,
I should not be going for static variables
and now I should declare
an instance variable again
because I know each
object can have a different value.
Is it clear, guys, when we should be
using this static variable,
then when we should be using the instance
variables
and the use case for local variables?
It is always, always recommended.
Always, always recommended. Okay,
so let's do an example.
Let's do an example.
Then I will write some notes for you
and I hope
it will be clear
that this advanced part of Java,
it is more related to
how you write better programs.
Okay.
How you manage your code,
the basic concepts that you guys
have learned in the first part,
they will be staying the same.
In this.
We will only be learning rules
that will help write better programs.
Okay, so
let's say I have left
you have this syntax order right?
And I have this variable spool
inside here.
So can you guys tell me,
should I go, for instance, variable
or static variable?
Yes, sure.
Because I know for all the syntax students
this school
will be staying the same right?
So I should be declaring
this variable is static
variable.
What about the name guys?
What about the name?
Should it be spectate or insurgents?
Because each student
will be having most probably
they will be having different names.
So I should be going with so static
variable are not changing.
Why every variable in the first place?
No. No. Not me.
Yes. So a lot of teachers,
they will try to confuse this concept.
So they think that static means
not change.
But in Java this is not what it means.
Static means static is a special area
inside of the memory of your computer
that holds the values
which are shared across all the variables.
Okay.
That's why they have these static name.
Yes. The real word meaning of static
is not changing,
but this is not what we mean in here.
That will mean that the memory area
where this variable will be declared.
Okay, So yes, it can change its values.
That's why we speak of quality video. But
those
things which can not change their values,
they are the constants in programing
because they are constants in programing.
So don't don't confuse this static name
with the with the variable
that cannot change
because its value.
Then we have more than one static variable
and one plus yes,
we can have as many static variables
as as you guys want
to be.
One illogical thing of Java.
So to you guys,
it might look illogical because.
You guys don't know
about the memory structure of a computer,
so that's why
it might be confusing for you.
Why don't you also do to Java on YouTube
simpler than what do you send us to watch?
Okay, I will try that.
So right now I am super busy in
my masters, in my research in
in the areas
of blockchain and artificial intelligence.
So maybe once I am done
with my research, maybe then I would think
about creating a YouTube channel.
The content of variable
cannot be changed with static.
No, no no.
This is what I am telling the context.
They can be changed.
What I work
on, softwares that can act as humans.
So we would in in artificial
would try to build softwares
which can replace humans.
So the things that humans can do
would try to write softwares that
differently.
A computer can also do those tasks
then will be instructed by robots there.
So I am thinking of creating a robot
to answer your questions
in this syntax or channel.
Maybe I will do my take on bad. So
the name it
can change for all of the instances.
So I will declare an instance
variable in here.
Okay.
And what about guys?
If I have a variable
duration?
Of course.
Or should I declare it?
Instance?
A lot of ifs and escorts.
So yes, people, they think that the EIA
is about a lot of conditions,
but this is not how it works.
So again, this information,
it will be staying.
Same for all the students
in all the student.
So I should be declaring it as static
and what about the ID?
So students in the in the colleges
and universities, they have IDs, right?
So should it be static or instant?
It should be
okay.
And then
let let's try to have that
made up method
or calculate speed.
Okay. So
let's say maybe
media
or on
the property
that is required to only be one.
So I am just trying to do calculations,
just just to show you
the use of local variables
and then maybe recalculate the fee
when we are
trying to do some calculations
inside the method.
And for that
we need to declare some local variables.
Okay.
So if you uncover that face
other than these,
if health conditions, you will find it.
There is a lot of math
going behind the scenes, so there are
no if s conditions in AA
there can be.
I mean,
but if you if you really look at the code,
you will find that 90% of the times
these are derivatives and
other under
concepts from the Met
author, it's super hard finally.
So maybe current one multiplied by 1000
and then plus
1000 multiplied
by maybe six or something like that.
Okay.
Maybe because calculations
they super complex.
So this is how we calculate 50.
So I can see
it's just a made up examples
like this.
Let me clear professor class
you for you
and on the
I believe me
even though I was
the position holder in my district
if and I got
I done my
I did my bachelors on scholarship
I got a scholarship
from the prime minister of Pakistan
but this I and this master's on that,
as I have
thought many times to work
very hard,
very hard.
All right.
So next fight to declare
when all of this for the next slide. Yes.
So in real life, you guys will be creating
separate files.
So that's
why I try to use the best practices.
All right.
So let's create some objects
then.
Let's try to pull
in names.
And just any idea
want to
not there
how these guys find you.
So syntax there they used to have
child companies
in different countries, India,
Pakistan and other countries.
So I was basically hired
with one of those companies and then
I switched to syntax.
There is one more recommended
approach, guys.
So although if you guys see so
if I execute
you guys there they are both.
So although the static variables
they can be excess just by writing
the name of the object
and then the variable
in, but it is not recommended
to use them like this.
Instead we have it different syntax.
So what we can do as we know that
the static variables
they will always be having
same value for all the objects.
So what do we do?
What we can do?
We can use the name of the class
and then we can directly call
these static variables.
Okay?
And this is the recommended approach.
And they are also called
class level variables, okay?
And because they belong
to class to objects, so they they should,
if you guys have to access them,
always use the name of the class
and then the name must be very different.
Okay.
And as we have the static variables,
there are static methods,
but we will learn about those matters
later on.
So this is the recommended approach.
If are there any questions,
guys, we are left.
We only have 5 minutes.
Simon typed in notes for you
in the next class.
Let me
just.
Okay, So is there anyone
who can take this responsibility?
So I will add that student
to the previous batch.
Batch nine.
Right now they are applying on the jobs
and they are sharing
what kind of questions
they are getting in their interviews
and in the coding class.
So if someone from
you can take this responsibility,
I can add that student to the channel
and he can collect
all the interview questions
and and share those questions
and then test
with the rest of the solution for us,
maybe in the form of this Google doc
or something like that, or one
is my suggestion
any of the task again, please.
So I want a student
to take this responsibility.
There.
He collects the questions
from previous batches,
the interview questions, decoding tasks,
and he shares those solutions,
those those questions
with dispatch students.
I shot it already.
So again, I already.
Okay.
So naturally, student from previous batch,
he collected some questions
and he has filled this repository
and these are the names of the companies.
These are the interview questions.
Let me share this link with you guys.
I sure you can continue
adding to this repository.
Maybe, or maybe you can create your own
so that we don't mess up
the questions from
previous batches within me share.
You can do it.
So we have another repository
that we will be sharing with you.
The official index repository.
But what happens
is that with time companies,
they keep on adding
new interview questions, new
new order in desk.
So that way we can we and these
I think they are also
Celexa for example
if you open up this question
so they asked this how do you rate
yourself in Java I said 2.5.
So the previous best students, they also
share the of the answers
that they have given back.
And at the end
you said I will rate you as 4.9.
So we both meant
all the conversation has happened.
After he
learned about
a student that he she knows
better than he did learning
how to execute slap statement
in Java at the same time using Java.
So you guys will be learning about these
all of these things later on,
maybe in around three weeks.
So if you guys at this point,
if you guys don't understand
any of the questions,
you guys can ignore them.
Next, you guys will be starting
operatively when we start doing selenium
and then Jenkins and expert.
So all of these questions,
they are formed here.
So those questions
which make sense at this point,
you guys can just go through them
so for example brain tired
non repeated correct in a string.
Okay, so you guys can solve this one.
Okay.
I suggest you do not look at this solution
first.
Try to solve this problem on your own
and then you guys
can check out the solution from here.
Okay.
These are the interview questions
that these out of it and this mapped out
entry, blah, blah, blah.
You guys can ignore them for now.
Okay.
Soon everything will start to made sense.
And then I want you to
I just want you
to keep an eye on this as well,
because who really
we really get this from.
So I will be adding new questions
and things to this repository. This
are there any questions?
Right.
So I have to share the rapid solutions
with you
and I hope you guys are doing the quiz.
I will share this board and the recording
will be available tomorrow morning.
Then you should be.
It's a yes or
are these questions
accessed on Google, right? Yes.
And these can be accessed on Google Drive.
Extended articles, seeing
already.
So I have recorded this video and I
have tried my best to edit it.
Maybe I should send that
to those Sebastian so I will be shared.
I am recording the video for the Mac users
in both of the videos.
They are ready.
I will share those videos
before such this class
and then you guys can install
installed intelligent and hopefully
from the center this class will
you start to use the intelligent.
So will I be added to their channel?
Yes, I will add you build the agenda
so when the students
they start to apply on the jobs of the
are separate channels
like technical jobs for interview
application are lost
Java and things like that.
So I will add you to those that
older days
if you guys don't have any question
since you're excluded
today, take some rest.
Good night.
And I.