Not so many messages today
as Thanksgiving made you lazy.
Good morning.
Enjoyed Thanksgiving.
Hello. Hello. Yep.
I am feeling perfect.
This morning I'm feeling great.
As in, thank you.
How was your two days off, guys?
You guys revise your java.
Good morning.
Morning.
Good morning, old man.
It's good to hear you are feeling better.
Thank you.
Morning, Katrina.
Good morning.
Give me your feeling.
I am feeling great, Linda.
And thank you.
How are your Thanksgiving, guys?
I hope you guys had a great time.
The fact.
Good morning, everyone.
Hello, Sebastian.
And how is your prep for Selena?
You have tried
my first television programing.
I should apply and Google
it further.
A holiday for me.
No night
and get out while it was still giving
me giving out like this to each other.
So today is class number 23.
Somewhere at both
and then some PowerPoint slides.
So I kids
day three.
You guys watch some
we do don't on on YouTube
or the Selena.
So your first class will be on Tuesday
from now on weekdays.
You guys will be having
your selenium classes
and on weekend
you guys will be having your Java classes.
What do you guys think?
Are you guys okay?
If we host Java reviews on Mondays
and Selenium reviews on Tuesdays?
Will you guys be joining
or you guys only want one
review per week?
It will only be for
for like 2 to 3 weeks.
Yes, because you guys will be starting
the Selenium
and Java side by side from next week.
I feel
like we do reviews before every Java
class.
And you.
Yes. Simon, you are right.
For those who are strong
and in programing on Java.
You guys might feel this repetitive
because almost in
every class I go to the concepts,
but I think for every student
and for most of the far
most of this class, what we have to do,
the reviews that they are,
they're really helpful for others,
especially the latest classes.
Okay,
so I will post about this in the course
announcements
once I confirm it with other instructors.
Who is teaching Selenium Muslim?
Most probably will be teaching selenium.
Reviews are good for interacting
with instructors.
It's good for those
who are missing classes.
And I think I will
be doing the Selenium reviews
and I guess
Suhail will be doing these Java reviews
and regular classes of Selenium
will be taken care
of by Muslim and regular classes of Java
will be taken care of by me.
So this is a tentative
for now,
but I will personally course announcement
once I it is confirmed.
So I mean could you a file.
So do you guys remember from the last
Java class we were discussing
about the final keyword,
how many uses we learned
of the final keyword?
Three. Right.
So first
final
is a keyword.
And in Java
that we can use
with classes
for years
and methods.
Good morning, everyone.
So is it a
is it an access modifier or non
access modifier?
It's a non access modifier, right?
The final is a keyword
and it falls under the
category of non nexus modifier.
So what happens is
when we use the final keyword
with the class
final classes cannot inherit
final classes can inherit
the class which is final,
cannot be inherited by other classes.
So if a class is final,
that class can actually inherit
from other classes, but no other class
can inherit from this class.
So it will be good if we see it like this.
Final classes cannot be inherited.
It's specified this class cannot
be modified for the right.
We cannot have this flexibility
that if someone is trying
to use some parts of our class,
some methods are fears.
If we don't want this, we we can.
What we can do, we can restrict this.
Can you guys think of any benefit
of doing that? Why?
Why might someone want to do that?
Preventing hacking
that to.
Okay, so
no one can change
prevents people
from tampering with perfection
where security guards might use it more
so the first thing is,
is if you guys remember,
there was a disadvantage off inheritance.
Do you guys remember the disadvantages
of inheritance
to protect?
If we want to hide?
So final keyword is actually not
allowing us
to have that inheritance relationship.
So the disadvantages
that we discussed about the inheritance
are the reasons why someone
might not want to use
inheritance.
And for that reason they can use the final
keyword depending from each other.
If we change it in a class variable
that will affect all other subclasses.
So there was a specific keyword for that.
There is.
There was a specific terminology
that we use in the industry
when we have this problem that classes,
they are closely related to each other.
When we inherit from one class
diamond problem.
I know you are always late.
So there we have.
We will discuss that.
We can have it tightly compiled.
Are are we going to have two classes
at Berkeley?
Couple. Right.
And we we make some changes in one class
that severely
can effect
and be dependent class the Jared class.
Right.
So classes they are tightly coupled
when we use the inheritance
relationship between them. Right.
What was the other disadvantage
that happens in multiple
it happens in all types of inheritance is
when there is a single child class.
If you are making it independent
class, that child class, you got affected.
But the effect is more
when we have multiple child classes
decreases
speed, change is all dependent classes.
There is one more issue
with the inheritance guys.
If you
observe
when we create the
object of the child class and if there are
hundreds of parents or grandparents
or all the ancestors in that hierarchy,
we will or will be object
before all those hundred classes, will
they be created before the actual
object of that class is created.
So let's say there are 100 ancestors
before the class and now you are trying
to create the object of that class
which is on position number 101.
So when I create the object
of that class, which is acquisition
number 101, what happens to those classes
which are about in that hierarchy?
We use the final keyword in a method
to indicate
that the method cannot be overridden
by a subclass
the yesterdays.
So all,
all the, the, the,
the object for all those
ancestors first
be objects of all those hundred classes
will be created.
The constructors of those classes
will be called.
The fears
of all those classes will be initialized
and then add the last
the object of the child class, the
the child which is at position number 101.
The object of that class is created.
So when you have this deep hierarchy,
the object creation,
it can be super, super slow.
Okay.
And if you don't want this behavior,
but you can do
maybe you want to restrict
the further inheritance, maybe offer
three classes or four classes
or five classes wherever you find it
comfortable. Okay.
So to to break that chain that someone
don't keep on inheriting
from the classes in a very deep hierarchy,
we can use the final keyword anywhere
to to avoid that behavior
so that the object creation is not super
super slow.
So that be so that someone
is not trying to overuse inheritance.
So for those
reasons we can also use the final fewer
so when used with subclasses,
when used with classes,
those classes cannot be inherited.
But can we use implement schema
to use methods
if that class is final.
So I show first thing implements
is not used with classes.
Implements is only used with interfaces
and if you are making
and you cannot have an interface
as final and implement at the same time.
So technically this,
this question does not make any sense
because interfaces
they are always there to be inherited
and the methods
they should be implemented.
If you are making that final,
that means
no one will be able to implement
the methods.
Then why? Why?
Why should we create the interface
on the first place?
If we can select,
we will be discussing today.
So once we have gone through them,
then then maybe these things will
make more sense
to different things.
Then the other question how can we use
matters if the class is final?
We cannot.
That's why we are making the class final.
Private and final methods
can be overridden but not overloaded.
So if you are saying it
in a reverse order, private
and final methods can be overloaded
but can not be overridden.
Yeah.
Okay. Okay. You.
You guys are always right.
My mistake. My bad.
I just make.
Thank you so
it cannot be inherited to
prevent
all the use of
inheritance.
We are your students. Yep.
Yep. No, no. You are my boss.
Actually, we do not.
Students. But
I'm just kidding.
So our use of inheritance
final matters cannot be overloaded.
No, they can be overloaded
to choose from.
We final.
Final can be overloaded.
Okay.
Can we act like a boss?
You guys are always like bosses.
Your Highness Nikolai.
Okay. Okay.
But they cannot be overridden.
Okay, So. And then we.
Yeah, there was a movie also on this.
I think it was maybe Boss
did the name or something like that.
It was a good movie.
So what was this
second use of the final keyword
that we discussed? Guys
with the methods, Right.
So what happens when final methods can
or can be overloaded?
Final decision? Yes.
So usually with the methods,
with the method, if if we use the final
keyword with the method,
can we overload that method
and can we override that method
when used with
matters?
That method cannot be
overridden in
style
classes.
Okay.
And the third use was certified and
the third use was will be phased
by when we use the final keyword
with fears
in. I override that fear
then I have same name field
in in general class.
Oh my God.
Well, yes we can. We can.
We can.
We cannot change the value of that field.
We cannot change the value of that. We
so I think we need to do a small demo.
So when used
with fields,
we cannot change
the value of their period
because
let me show you quickly
a demo.
The expert.
I said,
can you show me one more example? Yes.
So let's have a
let's try to check.
So basically,
when someone is using final in class,
we break the chain of inheritance.
Inheritance and obtain.
But if that class is not final, but just
the method is final, we can use it.
Yes, we can use it.
No, no, it's fine.
Ask as many questions as you guys want.
We can declare the value in child
class, correct? Yes.
So let me try
to declare a field as private
and let me try to declare it as final
and let me specify the data type
and then
the name of the activity.
Right.
And let's let's let's call it
let's call it.
Okay. So there is no issue.
I can have a field as private and as final
and the same time, no issues with that.
Then I can can I use public or
private or are protected
access modifiers with the final fields?
What do you guys think? So
I can have a protected
final age.
Sorry. Indeed it is.
Is equal to done.
All right. No issues.
I can have a public
final
double.
We is equal 30.
No issues.
And finally I can have
final
double.
I fight for that.
Yes or no issues in that.
I can use final keyword
when I am having
any access modified with the
fields, but
not static all because it's non access.
So let me let me declare it a
static final
number of
legs.
Oops is equal to the right.
So no issues
because they don't contradict feature.
The right static
means something that is shared
across all the objects of that class.
Final means no object can modify that.
So if you want to share a constant
and sorry,
I should be capitalizing all of these
because they are fine.
So final variable is a
convention
that we always kept oops,
always capitalized them.
And let's say if I want to have two words
in a variable,
then I use underscore, underscore.
So then we are declaring
a normal variable.
We capitalized the first
letter of the word in the
case notation,
but if it's a constant
means we are using the final keyword,
then we
before each word starts,
we put back underscore
if results with convention.
So let's say if I have to write something
like this,
we are of
and the definition.
So I don't have any issue issues when I am
doing this thing with the feared.
So no issues with the first.
Now let's try to understand
the use of the final
keyword
with the method.
So what do you guys think?
And I have a method as
private and final.
Can you please repeat the capitalization
use so
when we are declaring it
constant noun means we are.
If we are using the final keyword,
that means
I have to start.
So all the letters,
they should be capital.
And if I am having multiple words
in a variable name.
Previously we were using the camel case
notate notation.
Each letter of the friend in the first letter of each word was capitalized, right,
other than the first word.
So in here we use these underscores
if we are having multiple words
in a variable. So.
Right, we're fine.
But you didn't capitalize last two ones.
Oh yes.
Sorry, I should
go for it.
So private final, let's say,
and then obviously be written by and then
print.
Let's say maybe name.
So if we are using the normal
family association,
we capitalized the first word, but in
constant, all the letters are subject
and we use underscore.
Do you have to do this?
If you don't want that, give you an error?
No, no.
There's just a convention
in created the readability of the code.
The yes when we capitalized
we need to use the underscore. So
right now if you guys
your if you guys have
your mouth over the final keyword
intelligent is
is showing something entirely
do saying there Tasker
you are declaring a private
method as final
is there a need for them guys
because for private matters
they never participate in inheritance.
If something is not participating
in inheritance,
still someone can not still
someone can not
override of that, right?
So I can have the same behavior
by just specifying
only the private field.
I don't need to specify the final keyword
with private variables. Now.
It makes sense, guys.
If something is not participating
in inheritance,
there is already no way
for the child class to override that.
Right.
So making that final as well.
So guys, just give me one moment.
Otherwise I will be destroyed
for the rest of my life
because she is asking me
if I am busy right now.
So can I have 2 minutes from you
now? The next message will be,
Is the class important to learn?
Me and my answer definitely will be no.
The class is not important.
Then you write it.
So I'm just getting it so
best practice
class is nothing is
okay.
So if I am already it is early morning.
What's going on with.
Okay, so now you guys are asking
who is most important?
Okay, so if I am having a private
and final at the same time,
actually there is no need
to use the final keyword. Okay.
Because I am already having that behavior.
All right, now, now let's try to use
this with
default access modifier.
Right?
So I don't put any access modifier,
I make it final
and then maybe
put in edge
and then I put oops aging here.
Right.
So this time if you guys notice
intelligent didn't highlight
this final keyword in here
because this time it is making sense
because defaults
they participate in inheritance.
And if something is participating
in inheritance,
yes there are there are chances
that may be the child class.
It might want to override that
or it might not like override that.
So I can use the final keyword
with the non
access modifier
and the default access modifier.
And then let me quickly show you how
what happens,
if we will, there be an issue if the word
final is that beginning of the field
or step in line,
you mean this is after this word
like this.
So yes, if it is a competition between the
return type of the method, then yes,
it matters.
But if the bulk of the keywords
they are non access modifiers,
then you can change their position
and then you can change their position.
And if one word is X,
one word is excess modifier
and the other one is non access modifier,
then again we will not be having issue,
but the best practice
is always specify
the access modifier first
and then specify the non access modifier
to increase the readability of the board.
But technically
there will not be an issue.
They will not be.
It will not be a big problem.
No, we need to follow the same rules
for capitalizing variables
with the methods.
No, with variables. We don't do that
because there
is no such thing as constraint methods.
Right.
This terminology,
it only belongs to fields.
There is no such thing
as constraint methods.
So now let me use protected
and then final and then Lord.
And then bring it to maybe
a height.
And again, I don't have any issues, right?
I don't have any issues.
And then I can do it with the oops
and weird.
So no issues with this.
All right.
There is one more thing.
What about the constructors guys?
What about the constructors?
Can I use the final keyword
with constructor?
So if I write final and then constructor,
I will be getting an error.
Can you guys tell me why?
Why it is not allowing me to have final
with constructor?
Okay. So constructors.
They belong to a class,
They belong to a class.
The purpose of the constructors
is to initialize the instance fields.
Yeah.
And because they don't participate
in the inheritance,
so neither we can have
a static keyword in here.
Actually no
non access
modifier is allowed with constructors,
so they are the non
excess modifier givers
that we will discuss today.
They are also not allowed
with constructors.
Okay, so you guys now know all about.
Is there anything that you guys
want to add to this example?
Any question? So
all types of fields, all types of matter?
Oh yes. There is one more thing.
A static method, right? So
I have this static fear,
so let me try to have final
sorry public
spirited final.
Are print
and little flags
and obviously I need to metatrader
and type.
Okay.
And then
can I use this double filter?
Can I can I print out the double field
as well in here base?
Base? Yes.
Why not?
If I say weight of human. Mm.
I got an added
I get an error.
The error stays non static.
Fear cannot be referenced
from a static context
and we spend around
I guess 20 minutes on this.
Can you guys tell me why non static fears
why instance feels cannot be used inside
static methods.
Can you guys see
the red faces on my phone.
Static here.
The same value
if I am already there
it's because static is here
but it's instance are not.
I guess
totally different memory locations.
So guys tell me if I have
100 objects of this class,
if I have 100 objects of this class,
and if 100 objects of this class is
can they have we can all of them can
they have under different values,
for instance, fields.
So for example,
let's say the example of this hard field.
If I create 200 objects of this class,
can all the objects,
can they have different values
for this height?
FIELD Yes.
Now, if there are 100 different fields
and you guys remember that
static and fields, they can be called
by just writing the name of the class.
And then that method.
So if I am writing the syntax,
the name of the class,
and then I'm calling the method,
can you tell me out of those 100 objects
we two value of which object
should be printed inside this method
because static is same across
all the objects, right?
It's something that is shared,
but the instance means
each object can have its own value.
Right?
So there is this competition
out of 100 values
and we have only one variable
inside this static method.
So now starting to lose.
Confused that from which object
I should print out this value
didn't make
sense right.
Okay.
So if it is clear, tell me I have
this non static method.
I have this and I'll start again.
I use static field inside this
non static method
and again
I use instance
field inside of this instance
method. Yes.
So instance matters because
static fields,
they are shared across all the objects.
So there is no harm
because always this value in the variable,
that variable will always be containing
a single value.
Right?
So for instance, method knows that
it has to print out that single value,
but static method because each class
can have thousands of objects.
So Java does not know
from which object it should pick the value
and should print out the value.
So far this static method,
we cannot use the instance fears,
but we can
the static fields like, for example
this one number of flags.
So let me put
not allowed
because
it's a
an instance
we okay
and I can
I can write a see how to print out
the static radius and no issues with that
static only works with static once
static
method only works with static fears.
All right.
So okay,
so I was saying that again, internally,
they're saying they're telling us
that you don't need to this method
as final.
Can you guys tell me
why is thinking
that this final is redundant again
and with the non static motifs
with non static we can use
both. Yes.
Can you tell me
why intelligent is thinking
that this final is redundant
with this method bringing number of flags
because they are static.
We are not going to change the values.
Same rules final is already static. No,
because they're a static field.
Okay. Why?
Why? Why? Because it's the start.
If something is starting,
what happens with that
is a method, by the way, not a field.
So what happens is if a method is static
because you already declared in the weird
so fine
again can override
static matters in general,
we can only declare a static method,
but we cannot override that method.
Remember those two different terminologies
when we discussed about overriding,
we discussed that static method,
although they have
the exact same behavior,
but we use a different terminology.
We don't say
we are overriding a static method.
Say we are declaring a method
because static methods
can be accessed
by just writing the name of the class.
They are different from the instance
method.
They work differently from the instance
methods and the instance features.
So therefore saying their tests,
they do not need
to specify this final in here.
Okay.
Because if you don't read declare this
method inside of the child
class, the method from the parent
class will be called.
Can we go over differences between
overwriting and the clearing place?
So Simon,
there is absolutely no difference.
Technically,
The behavior that you will be getting
with an instance method,
you will be getting the exact same
behavior with this static method.
Okay, But we don't use this terminology
of overwriting in static matters
because they work a little different.
We use this overriding terminology
in the instance fields,
an instance matters because remember
instance methods and fields.
There there will be thousand copies.
If you are creating thousand objects,
but static matters and static fields,
there will always be one single memory
location and only one single method
when you will be having a static field
or static method.
And so did did they?
They are just different terminologies.
Okay.
Because even if you have a
actually let me do that again
so that you guys
can have kind of a revision from this.
So if I have a
child class
that is extending from
parent class
and then I have
a pastoral class in here
and a main method in here.
So let's say guys, right now
this is a static method, right?
And to, to show this concept
I need a method
which is not final. So
let me declare the field
and let's say
or shear color
like this, it should not be fine.
And it is this method
which is not final
and I am using this method
simply
We didn't count this color.
So I have an instance method
and I have a static method
now inside my child class.
If I don't override the instance method
or if I don't read clear the static
method,
I will be getting the same exact
same behavior.
So for example, I can say child.
Child is equal to new child,
but and then child dot
print here color, right.
And then child dot
print
number of
flags.
Right.
So what happens in here
if I have a static method or
an instance method in the parent class,
if I don't really clear that static method
or if I don't override
that instance method in the child
class, the method from the parent
class will be called right?
Exact same behavior
actually looking to
assign some value setting
so that you guys
don't see no.
Okay. So black and to no shows.
And if I read declare this method
inside the child class body
because I am declaring the static method
and and
let me override
the the the instance method.
So now to fast
okay again
let me know once you guys have typed this
and let me harden this window,
let me make this font smaller
so can you please share the code here?
I just heard Andy, don't frighten you.
Sure, I just make sure.
Okay.
Oops.
Please make the entire window.
Okay.
I don't know if you guys will be able to
let me put this test on class
in a separate file.
Oops.
I hope you guys will be able to see.
So this is an article
of a certain log on display
is incredible. This
seems like you have your.
But there
I think a lot of my classmates
there said you always carry a fire
extinguisher with you by this thing.
Actually,
it looks like that for more of that
messages
he is getting working as rentable
for him. Yes.
I think there have
let me check how many messages I have got.
Okay.
There are 2000 red faces
and then there are 27 new messages.
But I will look into them during the break
after class.
Here is the test of class.
Maybe, maybe the experience
people can tell me how to
how can I be?
How can I avoid these situations?
And the experience person from the class
mean I know one thing that works.
Always just live with it.
You are in trouble. And so now
no, no.
I know
one thing that that that always works.
Okay.
I will start in one sentence.
This is all my fault
and everything will be fine.
So here a little method is overridden
and a number of like
things that yes, yes, I'm on your right,
but technically, if you see
there is no difference if we don't have
these methods in the class, the methods
from the parent class are called.
If we read the clearer override.
So the different terminologies,
then the letters from the child
class are called
are you guys and I'm writing
nothing
nasty.
Imagine that's how I thank.
So I hear you.
Are you all to understand
I don't want to be dead.
Oh, my God.
You guys are multilingual, multitalented.
This is a recording, right? Yes.
So you are to make a video clip
out of that
and post on the Internet.
Now, to understand. Don't do that. It's
all right, guys.
So you guys see the difference?
You guys see the difference?
Actually, there is no difference.
It's only a different terminology.
Okay.
And then the final use of the
final keyword,
if we put it with the public, if we put it
with the classes, then
no class
can inherit from this parent class.
Yeah,
no class can inherit from this class.
So that is all about the final keyword.
I hope it is clear now.
So there.
So then why can't we have
final and static?
We can have Simon. We can have.
But if you check, actually
there is no edit.
It's just a suggestion
from the intelligent.
Okay, it is not related to compiler.
It is not related to any rules of Java.
It's just a suggestion
from your intelligent.
All right.
Are there other questions, guys
here?
So do I show?
All right.
So today's topic is
again, very simple as you guys
all always know.
Interface.
Yes, the abstract.
Did I give you any homework
in the last class?
Okay, let's go to that homework first.
We're sorry. In the common third phase.
Final start date. Not allowed.
Let me check.
Where did I put that
final start?
It not allowed.
Oh, here's constructor assignment.
It's constructor custom built constructor.
It is not allowed.
Create a class computer that will have
four subclass pieces of Apple. No.
Okay.
Close task one
and create
you guys done typing discord.
Okay. Which class now was good?
The parent class. Why?
I have error here
start date ward is this
is this number of flag length failed
either instance?
Where is it an instance?
Fear.
You guys are having error in here
so make sure
it's a static field.
It's static field and still error.
You guys are extending from here
and it's inside
the number of flags.
Can you guys show me
the complete screenshot
of your class?
And you guys are also extending it, right?
Are you guys
also extending the parent class?
And let me
import the input
from the child.
So I'm gonna show me in the parent
class as well.
Just let me push it to the get as well.
Sure.
Then you do find the video, the review
class number eight on the YouTube.
Was it uploaded?
Parent one
Let me know.
You have given the name
to your parent class as Parent one
But you are extending
from only the parent class.
That means there are two classes,
two different parent classes
and yes, please post an export terminal.
She was she was there to help you out
and let me know.
Was there anyone from your family in bad?
I guess six or seven.
And named Mohammad
Best seven years.
Okay. Is the issue resolved?
You have to inherit from the parent class.
Then you please repeat what line is read
declaration
here.
This is a declaration.
Just re declaring their comment exact
same as we do in the instance methods.
Is your issue resolved
and are there other students
who are facing this?
I am.
So the lessons for people
who have someone in previous batches.
Yes, I got it.
Okay, perfect.
That is from child two and in the console
who is coming from
this variable number of flags.
Okay.
Which is
declared inside parent and from child
is coming from the child class.
Welcome.
Should we move to the example?
Okay, so let's take the example
from any of the students
who are here to the homework.
I will do the rest of the class.
Then you go to send me
the requirements again,
create a class computer.
Okay, let's have the
creativity from semester question.
So create a class computer
that will have for
some classes as per Lenovo XP, Dell.
They find common behaviors within
and some fears in the parent class
and override
some of the matters in child classes.
Right. So
so in this model here
operating system
new internet
Apple uses was
okay so
Sebastian has declared a field as model
and is using
the best practice to initialize
this field through the constructor.
So this model is equal
to a model.
And then
the wide
operating system.
So ward
operating system
and then almost all the computers
we can have
live video functionality right
now let's try to create the child classes.
So Class
Apple
into extending from the computers
and now I am getting an error.
Can you guys
tell me why I am getting an error?
So you need to do
you need to test to page as well.
Yes. That will be good.
Import import, deconstruct.
Yes I so
in my parent class I have a constructor
which is taking one string type argument.
Now if I want to use these features,
these methods from the parent class,
I must provide a matching
constructor inside my child class
so that in this model
field can be initialized.
When I amusing which child class.
So once I see Apple
string model
and one side are super and bypass model,
now the edit is gone.
Okay,
the edit is going
in. Then let me override
this method operating system.
Okay.
And let me draw right
the the MAC has the
iOS operating system is not the iOS
for only part of mobile phones.
What is it?
It what what is it called?
It's for the Macintosh.
This Mac os.
Okay MapQuest.
And then I don't need to override this
because.
This is something common in here.
Then I can clear the other class,
the Lenovo class.
So subclass
Lenovo.
It is also extending from the computer
class.
And again, I must provide a matching
constructor.
So the screen
model.
So and then I need to pass the model
and then
I can
override this behavior in here as that.
Okay.
So little so the the Lenovo has the
Windows operating system
and then I can create another class,
let's say XP,
which is extending from the again,
computer.
Again, I need a matching constructor
and then I can override this behavior.
I can in here. Yeah.
Well,
for the sake of this example has maybe
didn't.
And now we can create the test
for class in there.
And again, let's use
the premise
polymorphism.
You also created Dell
or some specific method as well.
That's great.
Let me copy that.
Yeah. So.
So Bastian created one more class Dell
operating system which is he
see he's overriding
and then especially
method services has good
reputation of the products and services
And then there was
this specific method inside
the Lenovo
class.
Inside here
it was laptop
you know has a large selection of laptops
and then Apple had this behavior cost
special method inside here.
Maybe it will be more appropriate
if we groups
if we rename it to
put in cost
because methods are something
that that perform operations.
Right.
They are not the names of some things. So
we choose the names of the meters,
something like this.
So maybe
bring
an external
of Apple
Play video that it looks good.
We have an issue in XP that is brand
I'm using right now.
The shortcut shift takes to refactor
this code.
It's been
at various because of records.
We need to remove this to
and they should be inside the main
method right?
Yeah.
Okay.
It looks good.
All good.
When done,
can you send the code for both classes?
I was going to say not by choice.
Part of the.
Okay.
So is it okay
if I push this code to the GitHub?
Is it better you guys maybe copy?
You can copy from there.
Okay. So
I took Sebastian around.
So some version is going on this line six,
but he created the object of Apple
class boss
Apple inside the constructor.
Then Lenovo class.
He bought the Lenovo inside in here
actually.
And then that class. Yeah.
Then he wrote a loop.
So he is using computer variable
in here because the anti is off
type computers, which is the
parent class of all these classes.
So from polymorphism and from object
casting, you guys remember that
because all these brands
or this Apple
you know what they are all computers
so I can create a variable of time
computer
and I can store the objects
of these classes.
Other way of saying use
because this is a parent class,
it can hold the objects
of all the child classes and because
now we can hold the objects
of all the child
classes in a single variable,
it can be an array.
And now we can write loops.
Now we can write much more flexible code.
So what Sebastian is doing is using
an enhanced for loop,
just a variable name,
and he is taking these objects
one by one and checking
if that object is instance of Apple.
So this print operating system,
because it is present
in all the child classes, it
coming from the parent plus.
So we don't need to check for this method
because this method is available
in all the classes.
But this print cost laptops,
brand services, these methods,
they are only specific to the world class.
The brand is only specific to HP.
The laptops is only
available inside the Lenovo G4.
First, we have to convert that
computer to variable from computer type
to that specific apple type.
And then only we can call
the specif methods from the child
classes on this variable.
Okay.
Is it clamcase?
Is there anyone who is confused
and maybe want me
to debug the score?
I hope every one of you has
done this homework.
Okay.
Perfect.
So most of all,
if you are having a hard time,
I have pushed this code to the github.
Try to debug it
if still it does not make sense.
Then after the break you can tell me
and then I will debug it for you here.
No, don't be.
So let's have a break guys.
And after the break will start
the abstraction.
The abstraction, the third
pillar of object oriented programing.
So we have already discussed
the two pillars of the object
oriented program and the main two pillars.
Then you guys
tell me the names of those two pillars.
So inheritance, yes,
and polymorphism, perfect
artifact.
So let's have a break
till 1140.
Okay. Abstraction. Next one.
Yes And please
remind me about the recording
when you guys are back.
I started recording
manuscripts of encapsulation.
All right,
so today's class is about abstraction
and tell me the meaning of abstraction.
What do we mean in real life when say,
something is abstract,
the hidden meanings, right?
The meanings behind something, outline
and very general.
So in Java we use this abstraction
in terms of finding
the implementation of a method.
So, for example,
a method is doing something, let's say
the method that you guys use to take
the input from the keyboard, right?
The next boolean of next digit method.
Now you guys didn't hear how that method
was taking this input
and how every piece of logic was
was executing.
Although I was working to get the input
from the keyboard
and to store that input
inside the variable.
So in Java when we abstract something,
we are almost doing the same thing.
We Are writing a method, but we don't care
how that method will be implemented.
We just write the input
and the output of the method.
We tell the name of the method,
the input and the output
and the rest of the things are taken care
by someone else.
And once those things
they are taken care of by someone else.
We will simply be using that
method our code.
So think about the real life guys.
When we when, when the companies
they release some mobile phone
or they are these cars
or anything in our real life.
Right.
Well, what other companies do they
they just produce the spare parts
they get the
data shared all the
all the instructions on all design.
What will be the the how,
the will look like they will fit that.
Let's take the example
of the mirror of a car. Right.
What will be the dimension
of the mirror? Right.
And what will be the interface
is how that will be connected to the
MCU of
the car
to operate or to operate it properly.
And then these companies,
when they take this information,
the input, the output, and then the design
and everything about their thing,
they design that part and later on
we can replace those parts.
We can use those parts
with our main machinery, right?
So what we are doing
and even if you guys think of the B
construction all fall for anything, right?
So let's say, for example, laptops,
the memory is built by someone else,
the processors
and the memory is most of the time
it is built by Samsung or,
Kingston, Kingston, the CPU.
They are built by Intel or AMD, right?
The motherboard
they are built by maybe AGP,
Dell, Lenovo and, these kind of companies,
they're displaced.
They are getting most of the time.
They are built by Samsung cameras,
they are built by some other companies.
And at the end,
what these companies they are doing,
they integrate all of these parts
to make the full product.
Right now, Samsung does not know.
So Samsung is only designing that memory.
It is defining
the number of inputs and outputs
and how their thing will be connected
to the motherboard.
Right.
And then the CPU guys they are
only getting about the CPU is defining
once they know the information
about the input and the output.
Right.
How the CPU will take the input,
how it will process
and give back the output,
the design, their CPU.
And that way everyone who is
kind of perfect
in that field
takes care of their specific part.
And at the end, because we have all,
all of these companies, because
we as the
as the if you guys
think of the company Edge or Dell,
the HP guys or the Dell guys
because they know the specifications,
they know the input output, so they get
these pieces from different companies.
They put it together,
then they build very complex, huge things.
So the idea behind this abstraction
will be divide
a very big problem into different parts,
define
the input
and output for those specific parts.
In our case, that these will be met first
and then whoever it is
is kind of has more knowledge
about those things.
Those guys will be implementing
those matters
and at the end we will be bringing
all those methods together
to achieve something bigger,
to build something complex.
You guys can also think about the coffee
machines right
as a end user,
I don't care how everything is working
inside that coffee machine,
how the electronics is working,
how the temperature is being controlled,
how the heating mechanism
is being controlled.
We just press simple few buttons
and then the coffee is ready.
Right?
So far the end user,
the benefit will be that
the end user is just need my coffee.
So the end user will be benefiting from
from this abstraction.
The end user will only be calling
those matters in our case,
and he will be
using those meters in in his code
or maybe achieving or maybe
combining so many different methods
to achieve something bigger.
So abstraction in abstraction,
what do we do?
How something is actually working.
We don't care about that.
We hide that information, okay?
Or we leave this information.
We leave this piece of code
to be taken care by someone else.
We only define the input and the output.
And then once that implementation is done
from the other guy,
then we can integrate the scope
to achieve something bigger.
So Silva, remember about the ladies?
Oh, yes.
So remind me, you you should have
reminded me during the break.
But when I do the next break, remind me.
I will invite them. Okay.
I have already talked to them
so they are ready and but I have not
shared the links with them,
so I have to share the links.
I have been invited them in this meeting.
So remind me
before the next break.
So abstraction is a process of hardening
implementation details
and showing only the functionality, right?
When we use our mobile phones.
Let's say, for example, if we have
we have to take a picture, right?
We press the camera button and then
we select the view, we take a picture.
We don't care how that camera
is internally working,
how the photo is being saved
inside the mobile memory,
how all those pieces,
they are linked together.
Right?
We only care how to use those things.
I think of the think of the cards, right.
We only care how the steering works.
We only get how to press the better, how
to use the brakes and things like that.
No one cares about those super,
super complex and integrated tangle
inside the engine or everything.
So all details,
they are kind of abstracted for us, right?
They are hidden from us.
Only those guys
who have good grip on in those areas,
the guys who knows how to build engines
and all those mechanism on everything.
They are the one who is
who are taking care of it right?
So this abstraction is this this
this idea is actually coming from this.
These
what should we say?
So how
how the other companies in real life,
how they build super big complex systems.
So this idea is taking care
from there right in
whenever
we have to build something complex.
We all know that one single man cannot
do everything.
So what we do,
we hired the experts, right?
We tell them how the parts will look like,
right?
We define the inputs.
We define the outputs will do what we
tell them this size or things like that.
Then they, the experts of those areas,
they they design that specific part.
Then we integrate that part into our
main system.
Then this is how in real life complex
things are built.
Is this like backend action?
Yes, it's kind
all happening in the back end.
So we will try to achieve some things
same, right?
We will try to give something, Sam
using this abstraction.
So right now
the idea is looking super, super complex.
But it's really simple, really simple
because what we can do
using this abstract keyword
so you guys already know
how to hide
the implementation details, right?
When we define a method in a class,
we write all the logic in there.
We have hidden those details.
When we are calling that method,
we are actually
only getting about the input output
and writing the name of that method.
Right? So we have been already doing this
for many, many, many, many classes.
But now we will impose some more
on how those matters.
They are defined in tired big classes,
how one class should implement
or what are the rules.
So the in this implementation,
hiding the implementation
and only exposing the functionality.
We have already done it so many times.
When we define the method
we are providing the implementations.
When we are calling a method,
we are only getting about
the functionality of that method, right?
We passed the parameter, the
then if that method is returning something
that is our output, right?
And if there are wild methods,
they are simply printing things.
But now we have this extra extra power
off of this abstract keyword
that we can use to enforce these things.
Yes. Kind of access modifier.
We have a special keyword
that will help us to enforce
some new rules, but the idea is same
idea is very simple, same writing method
in a in a file
provide implementation in a different file
and then call that method
whenever you need your tried.
So for example scandal class
implemented by Java
expert wise, they know how to take
the input from the keyboard.
Well, we don't care.
We simply write the next boolean method.
We get the output from that boolean method
and we use it right.
But out there in the back we made
many overloaded, overloaded methods. Yes.
Yes, you are right.
So abstraction is a process of hardening
the implementation details and showing
only the functionality to the user.
Right? So when we create
public methods, then we create
the default access methods,
then we create protected method.
We are already this thing.
For example, it doesn't end of that
example sending in estimates, right?
We don't care how Google mobile phones,
they are connected the over the network.
The console is an abstraction interface
for the user.
Yes, ma'am.
And you can say that. Yes. Yes,
you are right.
So and we don't care how two mobile
phones,
they are connected over the Internet,
right?
One mobile phone, maybe using the SIM
card of a different network.
The other might be using the network
from a different company.
One might be using the iOS,
the other might be using Android.
All those details, how
all the communication will happen between
different companies, networks,
operating system,
all that is hidden from us, right?
We just write the message.
We press this button next to
the message is gone to the next person.
Usually no
as our part right after extract part
we will discuss about that note.
So for example, sending
SMS, you would just type text
and send the message.
You don't know the internal processing
about the message delivery, right?
There can be super, super complex
algorithms behind the seems scenes
and this can be super, super
complex technology behind the scenes,
but we don't get all of that.
Now about text.
Abstraction is the process
of separating ideas from their action
again, implementation
and then calling a method.
This is just another example
when we use data, same machine, right
the and then we insert the atrium card
inside of the atrium machine.
The atrium connects us
in the atrium, checks the balance
from our bank writer, sends sensor
request, and the balance is ratified,
the password is verified,
then we withdraw something,
then we get the cash and all those
calculations, how everything is happening
behind scene, we don't care.
We insert the card, enter the password,
enter the amount that we want,
and we get back.
I'm all right if we have that
in our balance, in our account. So
this is again, there are so many things
which are being in here, right?
How the atrium, the internal electronics,
how a
how the Internet protocols,
how these machines are connected.
Look banks, how verification
is being happening automatically
all that is hidden from us, right,
is, again, something similar to methods.
A method can contain
thousand lines of code, right?
Maybe million lines of code.
It may be calling other million meters,
but we don't care about them.
We just write the name of the method, past
the parameters, get back
the outputs of the string methods, base
string method.
When we have to get the character
at a specific index right, there
is some kind of logic that is happening
behind the scenes, but we don't care.
We just tell the index and we get back
the character at that index.
So that is also abstraction.
So like why is an object oriented
programing?
Abstraction is a process of hardening
the implements and details
from the use, right?
These are just technical documents.
They're don't, don't worry
about an abstraction.
This is very simple.
Only the functionality will be visible
to the user.
Abstraction lets you focus on
what the object does
instead of how it does.
Right?
There is an object, let's say the object
of this kind of class.
It tells us, take the input of different
types from the keyboard.
Right now, what this object is doing,
it is helping us
get the input from the keyboard.
We don't care
how all the logic is implemented
behind the scenes.
Abstraction is nothing but the process
of giving a set of guidelines to the user
who are going to implement
these guidelines
based on their needs.
So we define the input output.
The end user knows how this method works.
It gives the specific input
and gets back the specific output.
So abstraction is the concept of exposing
only the required
essential characteristics and behaviors
with respect to a conscious context.
Right.
Expose some features if you want, expose
some methods if you want,
and the others can use those methods
and fears
to get the information from your
to to
have this logic from your class
to perform different actions.
Now, as all the pillars of the programing
object oriented programing,
they have some kind of benefits.
So this abstraction is also
one of the fundamental principles
of object oriented programing.
Abstraction
helps us reduce the complexity.
So how this complexity is reduced,
think about this, right?
So if I if I show you, look me
actually create a new class.
So if we take the example of the standard
class,
because you guys are familiar with this
standard class.
So right now,
let's say if I have to take the input,
I only write this left next line, right?
But if I open this method,
this next line method,
so I am holding down my control button
and I am clicking
on this name of the method
with my left click.
So once I open
I see a lot of if health conditions
and at the and the other keywords
like through blah blah blah.
And then there are other matters
inside this method, right?
If I open this, find within horizontal,
then I again have super super complex
logic part.
There are so many things that are going
behind the scene inside of this method.
There is another method
find running buffer.
Again, so many things going on inside
this method, so many methods, right?
So think of this guys.
If you have to take the input
and if you guys always have to write,
always have to write this much code again
and again,
you want to take an integer
input from the keyboard
and you are writing all of this code
how hectic it will be, right?
It's kind of it will almost
be impossible to program. But
the programmers in nineties,
they those who have been programing in
in binary
or they used to write all of this again
and again
those combinations of ones and zeros.
Then we had this programing language
called the assembly programing language
in which we had the concept first time,
the concept of routines in which we write
the code that is being used again
and again, and we can only simply
refer to that piece of code
instead of rewriting of that code.
So in here it is,
we are only writing these few words,
and in just a few letters we are able to
get the input from the keyboard.
So this is how it reduces the complexity.
So abstraction helps
to reduce the complexity
and also improves
the maintain maintainability article.
Now if someone has to make changes,
he can make changes inside of the method
and that change wherever
we are using the next line
method that will be reflected
automatically there.
We don't need to
go in all the places
and we don't need to change the code
wherever we are calling this next line
method.
So that's how it helps us
reduce the complexity
and also improve
the maintainability of the system,
combining abstraction
with concepts of encapsulation. So
we will be discussing this encapsulation
in next week and polymorphism.
It gives more power to the object
oriented programing.
Yeah. Really?
You guys have any before we move forward?
So in Java
there are two main ways
we can achieve the abstraction.
Okay.
Yes, I will still be teaching Java,
so reviews will be taken care of by here.
So there are two ways to achieve
abstraction in our
one is using the abstract classes
and the other is using the interfaces. So
there was a big change
in Java eight before Java eight.
This is how things used to look like.
So if we have to achieve
partial abstraction,
we had to use abstract classes,
if we had to use a solid.
So I have changed the slide.
So it was before
and this is how it was
much like an alternative.
So before Java here,
if we had to achieve 100% abstraction,
we had to use interfaces.
Yes. Now we will do an example.
So abstract classes.
Now we can
we can use abstract classes or interfaces
to achieve this abstraction.
So in Java programing
we have two types of classes affect
and grade classes, and abstract
class is one
which is declared with abstract keyword
and cannot contain
defined and undefined.
Okay, now let's do an example
and before we do the example, let me in.
Wired
The students from previous batch quickly,
are they going to be with us today? Yes.
So one of them will be
the honor.
Give me road
to death on which but they are from about
eight or nine because that then is they
they will be hitting the market around
two months, 1.5 or two months,
I guess.
Okay. So
let's do an example.
Let's have a phone class.
So let's say a company
is trying to build a phone, right?
So what happens is there
there are themes, maybe a set of people
taking care of this play and adults
taking care of the
sound systems, the others
taking care of the operating system
and security and all that.
Right. So what will happen
from the perspective of design?
First,
we will have something that will define
all of these things
that our phone will be having, the things,
how those things will take the input
and how they will give us back the output.
So that class in which we will define
these requirements,
that class is called abstract class
and we use a special keyword with that.
So let's say
the person who is designing
the lesson,
we are defining some matters in here
and we are not sure about
some of the matters, so some of them are.
Third, we know how these
and how this method will be implemented.
So we will define those matters in here
and for the methods which we don't know
how to implement, we will
leave those methods as
unimplemented.
Okay, So we will say
abstract, and this is again
in non access modified fields.
So this is the third keyword
in that category that we are learning.
It's first one was static.
Then we learned about the final
and now we have this abstract proposal.
Abstract Why do we define the output?
In our case, there will be no output.
This method will only be printing
something to keep things simple.
And then we say display
maybe.
Yes. Yeah.
And this method
will not be taking any input.
And this time
I don't provide the body for this method.
I said this method is abstract.
I don't know how to implement this.
I only know that my formula
should have this display pictures
method again, please.
Someone who has expertise in this area
again, can you please implement
this method so that I can use this method
with other methods in here and now,
as soon as I declare
the method as abstract.
Now this class,
it must also be
an abstract class.
Otherwise we will be
getting an error.
So as soon as we have
a least one abstract
method in our class
now that class must be abstract as well.
So it's like you're only listing
the blueprint of the class
and then the experts will come in
and quarterly.
Yes, ma'am.
And you are right.
Perfect.
So we are only listing the details.
The other phone company
is maybe Samsung, Apple.
They implement these matters in ways,
but whichever company wants to implement
these methods, they implement the method
and then we can use those methods.
And now so Nabeel asked me in this dark
task there why it is important
that we should care about the output,
the return type of the method
when we are overriding something.
Okay, so now you guys will see
why the output is also important, right?
Because in overwriting in overload
as the output multiplies
and I overload the method by
just changing the return type.
So most of the time
Maryam and I are the first to answer,
but they always answer it wrong.
Always, Almost always.
But when they at first glance.
Right.
So no, we cannot overload them
by just attending a certain type.
There's happened only two times.
Okay, so
we cannot overload by just changing
the return type.
So we.
But again, can I,
can I change the return type of a night?
Or when I am overriding a method
or the return type
should be exactly the same.
It should be same now. Why?
It should be same.
It will be clear in here.
Okay.
Because in here
we will be using the override mechanism
to provide the implementation details.
Right.
So let's have another abstract method.
So abstract, maybe
avoid
unlock for one.
Yeah.
So now again, you guys tell me,
how can I provide
the implementation details for this class?
And any idea then a guess is
inside the parentheses through child
class.
You said override. Ding.
Yes. What is required for overriding
inheritance is required for overwriting.
Right
So now
once I have these abstract details
of how the how phone will look like now,
I now I create the actual fonts.
Okay, So I pulled the requirements.
I put the kind of
the design design in here.
Now I actually create the default, right?
So let's say, for example,
I want to create an iPhone.
I say extends font
and as soon as I write,
this is the point of being abstract
using it inside of classes. Yes.
So as soon as I write expense,
now I get an error
because now Java is enforcing
this always saying their task.
There you have to abstract method,
you have to
abstract method inside
and therefore in class.
You know what?
If you want to inherit from that class,
yes, you will be getting these
to implemented methods.
But for this one
you have to provide the implementation.
Otherwise this class
should also be an abstract class.
If you want it to be a concrete class,
it should be.
It should implement those two methods.
And what is the difference between
abstract class and a non abstract class?
What happens
when we have an abstract class?
So when we have an abstract class,
we cannot create the object of this class.
And you guys tell me why it makes sense
to not allow
to have objects of this class,
the asset class,
while why it makes sense
to not allow the objects if one class has
unless one
abstract
matter, then it must be named abstract
because it had errors.
Because we are giving information,
we have non implemented to meet
fact perfect answer and yes.
So guys, if I allow to have
the object of this class
and if the creates the object
of this class
and tries to call
and try to try to call this method
a how do I know what to do in this case,
these matter.
They don't have anybody right.
Then how do our knows
if someone is creating
the object and trying call this method?
It's an unimplemented method.
It is something and complete.
So you're saying like this
half of the card is built into
it only has two front wheels.
And now the driver is saying,
I want to drive this car right.
So if something is not complete,
how how we can use it, Right.
It has unimplemented things, right.
It needs to complete
if it is not fully designed yet.
It is not fully built yet.
You cannot call the bike.
Okay, Sebastian, in that case, you have to
you have to drive that bike with only one
will always one.
Really. And
so now
we have two rules, right?
You do not have something to execute. Yes.
A you right. So
as soon as I have one abstract method,
I must declare the class as abstract
because now I
something in my class that is not complete
right now, it is incomplete.
If you want to create object, you have to
complete methods and create the yes.
So how can we implement the method?
We use the overriding mechanism
to provide the implements?
Yeah.
So we see ward
on display picture same as we override
and we see
like we say, let's say
I form, he uses
photos to
display the pictures
and still I get an error
because I still have to implement
one more method.
So I try to avoid
unlock phone.
And now as soon as I arrived, the second
method, then the error goes right?
So I can say
you face harder to unlock default.
Right?
So now this icon class
has implemented all the requirements
which you are mentioned
inside this phone class.
And now I can create
the object of this iPhone
and now all the unimplemented method,
they are complete.
Now I can start using class.
So in here I provide the requirements.
In here I only tell about the output
and the input.
This class is written by someone else.
That person provides
the implementation details
and once the implementation
details are complete,
then I can start using the actual complete
concrete objects.
I can have another
class, for example, let's say
Samsung.
So only one class is abstract yes.
In the inadequate example,
there is only one class which is abstract,
but we can have two classes as abstract
as well.
In the next example, we will be having
two classes as the abstract class.
So class Samsung,
it also expands
the phone.
And now again, I get asked why
I am getting an add on guys.
I am trying to create a Samsung class
that is extending from the phone class,
but I get the errors because
because I must provide
the implementation for these two methods.
Right.
And the same thing about implementation.
Yes. So
this is how we define
the requirements.
This is how we
implement those requirements. Who
we detect
for the subclass.
Okay.
This face and fingerprint
reminded me of movie
Red Notice.
It's a good movie. Yep.
It's actually a prank at We had
so so nice
if I tried
to create the object of the form class.
So if I say phone
phone is equal to nil
phone,
I cannot do that.
Right. Okay.
Because this class is abstract. Now.
This class is abstract now.
So I cannot create the object
of this class.
And this is also a very famous interview
question.
Can we create, the object
of an abstract class?
All right,
So now I can use all the concepts
that I learned in my third override.
Can I use polymorphism in here, guys?
Yes. Right.
All all the same, I can call this
I can have specific methods inside
this class.
I can call the common methods
which are coming from this class.
Right.
No, no, no issues with that.
So I can say
iPhone, iPhone
is equal to a new iPhone.
I can see iPhone dot
display picture of iPhone on log phone.
I cannot call this make phone calls
and send text
method as well.
Yes. Right.
Because we are extending these methods.
They are having default access it
and there is no harm.
We can also follow this method right?
I can get my
let me know once
you guys are done typing, why not?
Perfect answer for interviews.
Not perfect answer for interviews.
What do you mean then is
you do everything. Why?
We cannot create an object in test.
So class of the of this phone class now
we can't say Why not?
The answer must be no. So
no, we cannot create the object
because abstract classes,
they contain something
which is not complete.
Why do it?
There is one more thing
nice that you can do if.
You don't want
the objects of your class to be created.
What you can do,
you can have an abstract class
even without having any abstract methods.
Okay,
there is no abstract matter.
Then you can still have
that class as abstract.
So That way the the object will also
it will not allow to create the object
if you want to restrict it.
If you want that,
the person will be
using the materials
or fields from this class.
If you want him to always first inherit
from this class and then
allow him or her to create the object,
then you can make this class abstract
even without having an abstract
and abstract method inside this.
So no requirements piece.
Okay. In abstract class.
Yes, it is as if the dog
without the head in the class
when we try to create an object.
Yes, you are right in the work place,
each group
will focus on coding
and method that are listed in the class.
Yes, Mamadou, you are right. So
and then
the even the bigger use case is.
So let's say, for example,
you are trying to build something of
something very generic, right?
So for example, think of
the Selenium.
The Selenium can test your websites
in Google Chrome, in Firefox
and Internet Explorer and other IDs.
So the guys who created the Selenium,
they created these interfaces
and abstract classes.
They defined how the methods
will look like the input and the output
and all the guys in Google Chrome, Firefox
and in other other ideas.
They implemented those matters
because they were
the experts of those ID,
Those are those browser, right?
Google Chrome guys knows how
how everything works inside the Google
Chrome, Firefox guys knows better how
those things work because we will be using
all of these things inside
a single selenium library.
Right? So
we use these
concepts of abstract classes interfaces
so that you guys, the end users
can use polymer or freedom to just change
the object of a class from Google
Chrome to maybe Firefox
and then test all of your code
in a different browser.
I am so sorry.
So loop is allowed here or not.
I start out to give my kids
their clothes. Yes.
Loops Are allowed.
All those mechanisms,
all those things that you guys
have been doing with polymorphism,
all those concepts
they are allowed here.
How many type of abstraction do we have?
Abstraction does not have types,
but there are interfaces and classes
that we can use to implement
this abstraction.
We can implement the abstraction
using interface in an abstract,
abstract classes.
And in the same way I can.
Right. Samsung. Samsung is new.
Samsung,
Samsung door or clear picture
Samsung door unlock for Samsung.
We got Centex
and Samsung gold
make phone calls
we get for the art
and how can I achieve polymorphism in here
and you guys quickly
write the code and send it to me
if have to
use polymorphism in here
through which I can call all the methods
with the help of a loop.
Maybe how can I write code
so that I don't have to repeat this
method calls again and again and again.
Each object
can rewrite form Samsung new Samsung.
Yes, I see. Yes.
Because phone is the parent class
and Samsung is the child class.
Right?
So all the Samsung
devices, they are also phones.
So we can see that inside of one variable
can quickly write the code
for polymorphism focusing. Yes.
Phone phone and your iPhone.
And then how can I write the loop?
So for each
because I am only accessing the elements,
phone, be it inside
first call it phones
and then I can say be it or display
because he said or
make phone calls.
We talked on a lot call
the pictures.
Well it's already text
so I get my output voice
on with the help of loop
and the other one with the help of
simple method calls.
Yeah, let me know once
you guys are done typing this code. Yes.
Let me push it.
Okay.
So should we move to the next example
or now?
Maybe.
Let's go to the pity a little bit
and then we will do another
example after that. So
class that is
declared with abstract keyword
is known as abstract
class, and abstract class is one
which may contain some defined methods
and some undefined methods.
Okay, that class can have undefined
methods, defined methods,
combination of those two types. Okay.
If all of it is possible,
I can have all methods as abstract.
I can have all the methods as implemented.
I can have some implemented,
some unimplemented. Okay.
No restrictions on that class is declared
abstract.
It cannot be instantiated,
cannot create an object off.
In this point it's clear, right?
It is important for your interviews.
And there is one more interview
question that
if there is a there is an abstract class,
is there necessity that
that class should have
abstract methods?
iPhone is not abstract
and does not override abstract matter.
Unload, unlock phone
So Muhammad
on online 24 inside your phone class
that matters should be unlocked
phone not unlock phones.
So the question is
can I have and again,
I have a class as abstract class
without having any abstract matters.
Yes, I can have a class
even if I don't have any abstract methods.
Okay.
Very important interview question
In Java programing
undefined
methods are known as unimplemented methods
to utilize an abstract class.
All we have to inherit from another class
and provide implementation
for the abstract method
is it needs to be extended
and it smethurst implemented.
Right.
So we create a child class,
we extend from the parent class,
then provide the implementation details,
and then we are going to rule
if we inherit an abstract class,
we have to provide implementation
for all the abstract matters inside those.
If a class as abstract method,
that class has to be abstract.
Yes, but then after class can be
without any abstract method.
Yes. And you're right.
Yes, you are.
So this
is just an example of an hour of a class.
This class is declared abstract.
And then we have this
another example, a right.
This is also an abstract class.
So and then this week
the class is a having an abstract class.
If any class have any abstract matter,
that class becomes an abstract
class, an object of abstract
class cannot be created directly,
but it can be created indirectly
with the help of J class.
Right?
Because you guys know whenever we create
the object of child class,
the object of all the parent classes,
they are created, right?
Do you guys remember this?
So it it can be created indirectly. Okay.
Just a simple point.
It means you're going to create
an object of abstract or derived class.
You can see in the above example
vehicle is equal to neo by right
parent type is equal to
new and then child type. So
if you are extending any
abstract class that have abstract
method, you must either provide
the implementation of the method
or make that class abstract as well.
So if child class is not providing
the implementation child class
has another option, that we can declare
that class as abstract,
because now that class contains something
which is incomplete right.
So that class can also be abstract class.
This is just an example.
An abstract method is one which contains
only declaration or prototype,
but it never contains body or definition
In order to make any undefined
method as abstract, whose declaration is
must be predefined by abstract keyword.
So if you are not planning
to provide the body weight,
you have to write that abstract keyword
before the method.
So abstract. Lloyd Some often dependent.
This is we pull
the semicolon ward different
if if there are any parameters
that we need inside this method
we specified parameters
and again, the semicolon
at the end.
This example will help
you understand it in more detail.
So let me share in the course
announcements
and let's do another example
after that
I hope you guys will be able to solve.
So after the example, we will go
these requirements. Then
you guys will be having a longer break.
After that I will go to the cost
and then hopefully
the students from the previous batches,
they will be here
and we will discuss
and you guys can discuss your questions,
you can ask your questions.
Okay. Can I close these two files?
Are you guys done?
I'll if I have an abstract
method in a child
class, yes,
I can have for our next example.
In next example, I will show you that. So
let's say I have this.
If you have an abstract
method in the child class,
you have to make a class. Abstract.
Yes, you are right.
Abstract is only
and only with the methods.
Yes, but you are right.
So for example.
Okay, let
let me do it in the next example.
Okay.
Let's let's keep this one simple.
So let's say I have some fields in here.
Last in this field is
the we are in number one
and if I say
abstract
with this field,
I will be getting in it right?
And the error will say modify
not allowed right?
Because fields,
they don't have this concept of body
and head and the implementation
and something like that.
It doesn't make sense
to have abstract with fields.
So let me write it down.
Can you give me recall to Oriana?
So then you ask her
to register for the link
and if she can be available
by go to entity.
So we are in number and then let me try
to have this static field as well.
In here and
then in constructor, be abstract.
So what do you think about that?
Yeah, no constructors.
They participate in inheritance.
If they don't participate in inheritance,
can we ever override those
constructors? No. Right.
So the is no
so static and
total
totally goes.
And then now
let me try to have a constructor in here.
So we call
and if I say
abstract in here, do you guys want me
to put to comment on this piece of work?
So there does no that it is not allowed.
Okay, so in this class
we are having a an instance field.
We are having a static field.
Abstract allowed with fears, abstract
not allowed with constructors.
Now let's try to have a
structure weaker.
So can I access this static fill
inside this
vehicle constructor right.
Can I accept this totally goes
for you inside this constructor.
This is a very important interview
question question
I can access.
Well, why do you guys think that
we cannot access it?
Well, why are you guys thought that?
Well, why we cannot access this
this static field inside the constructor.
So static is something universal, right?
I can access it inside.
Inside static matters.
No static methods constructors
because constructors are to initialize.
Yes, they are to initialize,
but we can put other code
as well inside the constructor
because there is no hard right.
Maybe sometimes you have to write
extra logic to initialize your fields.
Maybe you have to calculate
intermediate values
before you assign the values
to your final figures. So.
So there is this flexibility.
They are not expecting
you to only and only
initialize the field.
You guys can pull print out statements.
Almost any logic that you guys want,
you can put that
inside the constructor.
Okay, so I'm saying why
we need to put it in there.
So When I put this variable in here,
every time the object of any Jala
class will be created,
what will happen to this constructor?
Guys?
Every time
any child
creates
and the object of any child is created,
this constructor will be called
and we will be incrementing this value.
So it will.
It will be this, this total variable,
total vehicles variable.
It will have the count
of how many objects of
all the classes of display
in the class have been created till now.
So sometimes it's very useful to keep
track of the count of objects there.
How many objects are there
inside the memory?
If we make the vehicle class, abstract
and constructor is pointless.
No, no, no, no.
Simon Department.
The constructor will still be.
The constructor will still be called.
The figures will be initialized.
The only thing that we can not do
is we cannot access.
We cannot create the object of this
this class directly, but everything else.
We can do it with the children
to all classes.
Yes, you can use use to it
to keep track of your children.
So in near school,
practical sense, too many lives. Yes.
Especially when someone has to use
in they start we are using
is equal to when we are in.
Yeah,
well, I'm getting another great
different. I
no empty constructor.
No, no, no.
You you ask
if someone can confuse you guys
really quickly.
Okay.
They are two different data types.
Like we cannot assign
a string to a integer.
And let me also put out a line in here
so that you guys can also see visually
how the constructors are quite
so inspired this class.
Till now we have created the instance
field, static field.
You guys now know the concept of static
and all starting
fields, how to use them
inside instance or static methods.
And then okay, it will also cover
how the object creation is
have a happens.
Let's say we have this method Public
award
for doing
and I call this total vehicles
variable inside this method guys. Yes.
No. No. Yes.
Now I see.
Why why did they ask this question
in the interview?
Yes, I can call it Yes, I can call it.
It can because it's a static field.
I mean, I think we have repeated this
in during today's class
at least 4 to 5 times.
Right
But still, it is confusing you
so keep asking
and hopefully it will be printed
inside your minds.
So I'm going to ask a question by default.
We think no,
I am still confusing it to
it will be fine.
I think not very
so who implemented the methods?
Now I have to implement the methods
and now
there is one way only to make titles
with right answers. This
one and let's have
another common method
in now let's have a public abstract
ward.
Start
quoting here.
So it says abstract method in non
abstract class.
What does this mean, guys?
It is saying abstract
method in non abstract class.
Can you guys guess the error?
It's giving me an error in line says win
number is an integer.
Yes. Now it should be string.
Now I have at least one abstract method,
so this class now must be
abstract as well. Hmm.
I still get data
so this time the error says abstract
method cannot have a body.
So if a math 30 is abstract,
I cannot have it.
Body. Right.
I must remove this line.
Okay. Now all the arrows they go.
All the arrows they go.
Okay,
now let's have a
class.
And inside this car class,
this class is extending
from logical.
This time
I don't want to implement this method.
Or how can I ward this error?
Guys if I don't want to provide
implementation for this method?
Order to remove error from abstract.
So far I removed the brackets from
this method.
I removed the body of the method
so I can create
this class.
I can also create.
I can also have this class as abstract,
but I still get that
out of the atmospheres.
So class.
So the this time the error says
and there is no default constructor
available in vehicle.
Yeah, well Sebastian,
in this channel.
So now because I have a construct
the inside the parent class
which expects
one string by field to be passed,
I must create a matching the constructor
inside my child class as well.
Yeah.
So let's say I has been
bar type
and other field inside my child class.
So what I can do,
I can take these pool fields
from outside string
car type, string.
We are in number
and I can call super
and I can in number
and I can see oops,
this car are equal to cart
by ID like this.
So now all the arrows, they are gone.
And let me also put out a statement.
Parent perspective is called
so can I override this behavior?
Guys, can I override this
drive behavior inside this style class?
Yes, I can have
I can still override non
abstract methods,
still non abstract methods.
I can see God is driving.
All right.
So this is also clear.
And can I have more abstract
matters inside this
car class?
He writes of public abstract may be
toward speed.
Yeah.
Then this child class will implement.
So I can have a class
with abstract matters.
Another class inheriting from that class,
not providing any implementation details,
but adding some more abstract matters
and then maybe overriding some define
methods and all defined method.
So all is possible that you guys
have been doing with overriding.
Okay, you are using
static fields
non static fields, static methods,
and starting all those rules
that you guys have learned previously.
They are still valid.
Okay.
Now let's try to create the actual object.
So let's say class we have w
expands from God.
Okay.
So now
how many methods
this BMW class should implement?
If I don't want this BMW to be abstract,
how many meters it should implement
at least
1 to 2.
So I have one abstract
method inside of the car,
one abstract
method inside of the parent vehicle.
So how many meters this BMW must implement
if we don't want any errors
to matter?
Right.
One is coming from grandpa,
the other one is coming from parent.
So it says Class
BMW must either be declared abstract
or implement abstract
method speared in the guide class.
So as soon as I say
speed, so
if I still get any error and error,
it says class BMW must drive that to be
blah, blah, blah or in the vehicle.
So it ask us to implement
this start method as well.
And so as soon as I start
now I can start
I can
I can provide the implementation in here
and I
still get errors this time out of sales.
There is a known default constructor,
which means I must provide
a matching constructor
and I can have some of my own fields.
Right? Me
model
and then BMW, right.
So I need to take for VIN number
to pass to grandpa
and then I need to take car type
or parent class
and I need the
make and
demand. So
super
car type
and we let me know once you guys are done
typing this, you
let's clear
to one more class.
The class
Toyota. Oops
extends
from R
and oops.
I have to again provide the implementation
for these two methods.
Otherwise I will be getting an error
and then I must provide a
matching constructor. Yes.
Jamie.
Sure.
You mean did you call Arianna?
You you ask her to join.
Okay.
Perfect.
The simple part
I am getting error in car type
and you show you got in car type
the car class.
Here is the car class.
What does the error say?
And let me have a specific method
for Toyota.
Okay, but
already guys, so I am inside the third.
I am entitled to charge class.
Can I access this total vehicles
inside in here
inside this display for method
so daughter overheat girls
so I can access it.
And can I also access
maybe this car type and we are in number
from the parent class
like make
yes, yes
and no issues with their parents.
You can access all these things
on are
you guys
are you guys done typing all the code.
So we need to do
we need to do this talk may distort model
also or not.
Yes we should be doing this asking me.
All right.
So we should say
this not make is equal to make
this or
model is equal to one.
Yes, we should do that
what I am getting and Adam guys.
Yeah so but it should be on line
number one.
Is there anything else
that you guys want work
all now?
Okay.
Is this Spiderman movie released
on? It will be in December somewhere as
on the not here to seven being
contract.
How is the COVID situation
in the US right now
because I heard of new variant in Africa
some in Britain,
Africa, Italy and somewhere else
there is new variant
to okay better than started things.
It would be better
if people actually got vaccinated here.
All right.
We are still wearing them masks.
We did.
But it is also having that
polymorphism property, right?
Every time you
it changes your cells to something else.
If new variant,
we need to have a booster vaccine
if it is going
when we grow.
Okay.
So let me actually push this code
so that everyone can come here and check
if there is anything needs to be done.
So the Greeks, well,
now they are asking to have that on me.
Only grown vaccine I am
and no one is wearing,
including me and my family.
After vaccines.
What if someone has already got COVID?
Is he or she is also not safe
from this new.
Oh my God.
I mean, we just have to
keep on taking new vaccines.
And you scroll down a little bit,
please, is the maximum I can scroll down.
And I said, Oh, you mean scroll up?
Here we go.
Yeah.
So this year in September, I got COVID.
Even after getting to go of Pfizer.
Oh, my God.
The Pfizer was famous everywhere.
Still
copy and paste.
So those who are having a hard time
understanding the
first book, there is one more book on
Java that is called,
I guess, but are you scared, sir?
And our lost one.
Remember now? No.
I hope you guys will be able to understand
Everything is called effective Java,
so try to read the back
effective Java
non effective Java
third edition.
Yes, the latest addition will be good.
Learn but not try to teach those lambda
expressions functional, programing
and all that
because you guys are still in beta phases.
I mean initial phases.
You guys are not for production,
but the course is complete.
Then maybe you guys can start learning
about those functional programing
and all that.
Yep, step by step.
But hopefully half of the book
will now make sense.
At least half of book will make sense.
Then you scroll up to the car class, see
if you guys are having a hard time.
Maybe
I can split these classes in two files.
Do you guys want to do that?
No, I didn't just write Impact in
Java book by job
or with whoever is the author.
What I am sure on
only 5% of you will be reading it.
Would you please copy and paste?
Yes, I can copy paste as well.
Actually, let me split this
into two different classes with
give me another one.
Let's put vehicle and card in here
and export BMW.
We split it in two, so
I hope
now you guys can see
what completed for
all these examples help you guys in.
So I'm trying to put everything inside
a simple inside inside the same
but that with the examples they get large
so are they helpful or are smaller.
Hard to understand these this way
it's good overload.
Yes. Okay.
Let me know once you guys have
this is already old issue
so that we can test these classes.
Is it intelligent?
Shows us abstract.
Yes. So if you guys noticed
you see
you guys see this arrow sign in here
that that tells you that is this method
you are trying to write in for.
There is this another
kind of symbol which is implemented in BMW
to try and things like that.
There is another symbol
with the icon of glass
with those two vertical that tells you
that this is an abstract class.
Yes. Or what they're telling
is this a multi level
in had multi-level inheritance.
So what do you guys think?
Are we using multilevel inheritance
in here on multiple inheritance
going to here, multilevel,
multiple hierarchical,
I would say a multilevel,
modern, hierarchical.
We have one parent and multiple times
BMW and Toyota. Yes.
So we are using all types of inheritance
is in here
except in this single inheritance.
Multilevel is being used
and hierarchical is being used.
Multiple is our in Java. Right.
Multiple is not supported in Java.
All right.
You guys already know this.
I can not have multiple parents.
So what we are doing,
we using a hybrid type
of inheritance, multi level
because I have this level
first I have a he called and,
I have God, then I have BMW.
So there are three levels in here
and I have hierarchical as well.
Right.
So Mahmoud Abbas was correct, hierarchical
because God has two titles,
BMW and Toyota.
So more types of multiple
is not supported in Java Java.
Are you guys done
to do
we created that so class now I have at
oh where do you guys think will
it be better to create the main method
inside of this class in here
or create inside
a new file,
new separate new file?
Well, I was asking because now
you guys will not be able to see
all the classes.
And let me check if we
I hope
it's readable.
Okay, So now, if I say guys, if I say BMW,
BMW is equal to new BMW, don't rush.
Take your time
and tell me if I just prior to this line,
how many outbursts
I will see on my console.
Okay.
Near your download
If I only read this line,
how many outputs I will see
and which lines and in which sequence.
If you guys can tell me
that it will be great
new. Can you change
phone file for vehicle file?
Oh, you, me
only this parent constructor is called.
I think it will be three
so let me execute this code
and let me explain why we will be seeing
these two lines.
So if.
So you see,
even though I am
creating the object of the child class
first of all, the constructor
of the grand card.
So if you have hundred classes
in a hierarchy,
all the objects for all
the classes will be created first,
then the object of the child
class is created.
Okay, so first the constructor from
the top
more variant is called okay.
And even though
we are creating the object of child, okay,
we are creating the object of child First.
The object off top.
Most parent is created,
then the class
which next in the hierarchy.
Then the constructor of that
class is created.
So what is going on behind the scenes?
Technically, Java
is creating the objects of all the classes
which are in this hierarchy above this
BMW class.
Okay,
so that's why we use the final keyword
to restrict these long hierarchies
if there are any.
Okay, so that we can improve
the performance. Otherwise,
all those hundred classes
and the structure of those classes will be
created, appears will be initialized,
memory will be reserved,
objects will be created, and then only
the construction of the child will happen.
Okay.
And if I put air and s out
in here saying BMW
constructor,
and if now I had security code,
can you guys tell me the sequence
in which sequence I will get three lines
and how many lines I will see
and in which sequence.
So this is on line number 13.
This is on 33 and this is on 11.
BMW last child class preferred
grand parent and then BMW.
Yes, Right. So
child will be at the last
the last thing.
So that's
why it's not good to have long hierarchies
of inheritance.
All right.
So I have created the constructor
so you guys know how
the constructors are called.
And now I can say BMW Dot
print where you can count what output.
I will see if I say print vehicle count
based.
Yeah, I will get to count one. Why?
Because this constructor,
which I am incrementing the value.
It is only being called once.
Okay.
For this can create a BMW object.
Yeah. For this concrete class.
So if I say let's say maybe
BMW, BMW two
now word count.
I will see you guys.
So now I will see
because now I have created two objects
inside this main method.
Okay. Okay.
Let me remove this.
Okay.
So you can call all the matters in here.
In here, BMW dot
weird,
BMW door
start,
BMW board.
I'll try.
We work.
Stop.
Oh God is driving weakly stopping
BMW can start is angry mode
and then execute all that
and if I say
can I say this guys
can I create an object of type
variable of vehicle?
And can I say in New
York to like this?
Yeah.
So I am simply
I am simply
having a variable of pattern
and I am storing the object of child.
There is no harm doing that.
So I can do that.
I can do that.
No issues in the.
All right.
And can I also say car instead of
instead of a car?
Can I also say car in here?
God is also a parent class, right?
I can also say that I can also see that.
Perfect.
So are there any questions or so does
not matter.
How about abstract?
Yes. No. No, abstract does not matter.
We Can store the child
class is still inside the parent classes
even though they are abstract.
But we cannot create the object
of of of legal.
This vehicle is an abstract class.
This Toyota is a
is a concrete class.
All right.
So let me go through the remaining slides
and let's check if we are
forgetting something many
you did a mistake and just third time now
it is my my third class has an error
that Toyota
will use is fine.
This is how we learn.
We use abstract classes
when we know only method,
but we don't know how will be implemented.
So this is where you guys should
use the abstract
classes.
No, no, you're not discouraged.
Again,
I see the code one more time, please.
Even though if if you guys are answering
it wrong, I still want you to respond.
Or you have a quick question.
Maybe I missed it.
Can we create an object for our class
being?
That car class is an abstract.
So what do you guys think?
And you guys are not.
Can we create the object of class?
It is an abstract class. Yes.
We can not create the object
only because it's an abstract class.
But the.
Yes, indirect right?
Yep. Yep.
It's fine. It's fine.
If there are any doubts you guys can ask,
always ask.
And I move to the slides.
Okay.
And you do this car garden input.
You can do this way,
but it is not an object of class.
Yes, I'm not.
All right.
Can we take a break? Yes.
After going through those slides,
we will be having a break.
So when to use the abstract classes?
We use abstract classes
when we know the methods,
but we don't know how they would be
implemented in every abstract class.
Participate in inheritance.
Abstract class of Java always contains
common feature.
So good.
Try to put common features in here.
Abstract Classes of definitions
should not be made as fine.
Can you guys tell me why
the abstract classes should not be made?
The final
dares in how to?
What does the abstract mean?
Guys?
Abstract
means something incomplete, right?
Final means something complete.
I'm not contradicting each other,
so that's why
we can all have
abstract and fine all at the same time.
All right.
Because they are opposite things.
Or an object of abstract
class cannot be created directly,
but it can be created indirectly.
The next thing is the interface,
but it's the only clearly
it will not make sense.
So let's discuss it tomorrow. Okay.
I will discuss this interface tomorrow
and then we will come back.
But let me just go through
if it makes interfaces similar to a class
which is collection of public static
final variables, will it make sense?
Guys, if I just read the slides?
Okay, let's not do this. That's not good.
So remind me that, we we didn't go through
these three slides in the next class.
I have I posted
this question in the course
and afterwards then it
Okay so let's have a break.
And after the break,
hopefully
the students from the previous batch,
they will be here
and we will quickly
I will quickly solve this task
and then we will have the discussion
with the seniors for breaking the law.
Nerd, feel good.
And I hope you guys will be able to take
rest.
Plus, you guys will be able to do
the task in 15 minutes.
Is that okay?
And please be back
and remind me about the recording.
All right, Good.
Yeah, we would.
Yeah.
Well, whoever was here
this whole time is looking
at you guys.
Have any more questions?
Oh, yeah.
Everybody knows that.
Not just these guys.
They're not special this way
we create an emoji
with those guys face
because we were procrastinating.
So. So, so.
But I'm not sure what kind of question is.
If it's a full time
job, you'll be working, you know,
five, 9 to 5 every like Monday, Friday,
with all the holidays.
So it's going to be like 40 hours a week.
You know, I don't really know.
Maybe some some is all perplexed ability
this kind of, you know, time wise.
But most likely you will have to stick to
the schedule.
Best advice is study.
Listen to us Go very carefully
Listen to everyone else.
That's index and just soak it all
and do your research
and on your free time,
you know, just repeat everything.
You study, practice,
you know, just go at it.
That's that's your best investment.
The place right now
for the course for you.
The course. Oh, it was hard.
It was very hard for me.
I mean I didn't have
any technical experience and it was hard.
I didn't sleep.
Sometimes I would be studying
till like three or four in the morning
and I would work.
But at end it's worth it.
You guys like whatever you guys,
you know, don't get bored.
Just continue doing it.
I'm telling you guys, it's
going to change your life.
Like when people
when used to be the student
and then I would have people from previous
batch tell me, Oh, you know, it's
going to change your life and be like,
Oh no, it is like I work.
Yeah.
Now my schedule is pretty flexible,
so just study you guys.
And if you think that you don't know
anything, you know, or like you're like,
want to give up,
don't like it's just continue and you guys
are able to do it so just don't give up
but listen to ask our
honestly he's the most out the instructors
he's the he's the best
like he was very very very patient
even with our batch like
I remember we had a student
I'm not going to say any names
he would have asked the same question
over and over and over again
and ask our reply to him
every single time.
Even the students were like okay,
you know, like we just learned this.
But yeah, you guys just about
we all know though.
So yeah, 100% what she said.
I used to look at the people
who would come in like me and Ariana
are here right now and listen to them say,
Oh, this changed my life.
I was like, Yeah, whatever. Just
give us, give us the good stuff.
And as as it sounds like
it's 100% true, I used to be a bartender,
and as soon as COVID hit,
I was out of a job,
I was out of money and it was just ugly.
And here I am now.
I don't care what's happening.
I don't care how many cases are out there.
I've got my laptop right here.
I got my Wi-Fi connection
and I've got the money.
So and I love my job like I really do.
It's I'm having fun doing it.
I'm excited when Monday comes, you know?
So, yeah, just put in your best effort
based on your performance.
I know you choose the years of experience
depending how how you feel about it.
I only I went with three years
in a house of experience, but it varies.
Veronica
She said for those people that I've done
five, there's people
that have had no experience.
It just all depends on how,
you know, you feel pretty much, but
it's like
in retrospect, I'm thinking
if you've got good knowledge, you can go
as far as put like a year
or two years of experience because
if you can back it up
with solid knowledge, you know, you
then need to like pretend
that you've been out there for four years
because like I've been working
for six months now and realizing
how much more I know now and how much more
like practical knowledge I've got.
And I'm like,
Yeah, four years of experience is
bullshit and like, chances are
they'll know.
So just try like, try to be humble,
but confident
in your knowledge.
So in my place
we've got a bunch of testers.
I think it's like
five of us now, but like everyone
kind of does a different thing.
But we work
multiple projects simultaneously, so
in my
team we have so my team is pretty big.
I think we have about 16 people
on my team.
We have a lot of developers
and we only have three testers,
including myself. Why?
So we have one
that does automation, just automation.
I do both automation and manual,
and then we have another girl
that does just manual testing.
I know we help each other.
When I first started, I didn't know.
So my application is pretty big.
We have about 14 domains, so I always ask
questions to the other testers.
I've been there longer and like I said,
they're very, very I mean, for my
my team, they're very helpful. So
And I think just in general,
they if you don't know anything,
they'll they'll help you.
They're not going to be like,
oh, you know, not answer any questions or
I haven't seen anything like any one
competing in my company, like,
you know, testers,
they're always just helpful
because at the end of the day,
they want to,
you know, be able
to deliver to the client.
And you can't do that
without pretty much being a team.
So I don't think you have that.
But like I said, it
depends on your company.
So I'm not sure.
Yeah, because they all work on
the same project, you know, most likely.
So it's, it's in your best interest
to help each other out and make sure.
So, you know,
you're on time and everything's good.
And if you ever encounter people
who, like, you know, tell you to piss off
when you ask them for help,
then just leave that place,
you don't want to work there.
Hopefully you'll never see that.
But yeah, the developer and investor
relationship, is it
relationships or right ratio?
But relationships are good, you know,
when they're not being difficult.
But Yeah, no, it's good.
And you want to be on good terms
with your developers because there's
going to be a lot of back and forth.
Like if you don't understand
the application, they might help you,
They might help you, you know,
because I have a lot of backend testing
which, you know,
syntax didn't teach us that and chances
are you're not going to need it anywhere.
But it's just the way
my application works, right?
So a lot of times
developers will help me out,
like how to even understand
what I'm testing, like how to test it.
So yeah,
you want to be on good terms with them.
Regions.
But in a job I applied to a lot.
I applied to quite a few jobs and total,
I believe I got four job offers
and I think I went into like
maybe 10 to 15 interviews.
But yeah,
I, you you just apply, apply, apply.
And you know,
we have a girl from our batch.
She used to apply adding to
like 50 to 100 jobs a day.
So once you are
that started, just apply apply.
I would remember I would be
it would be like two 3:00 in the morning
and I would just be applying on my phone
just every time
and you'll you'll get those calls.
You get even till now, like
my email is full of like, hey, you know,
we want to save
if you're interested in a job
like you just continue getting
and getting those emails.
So there's jobs there a lot.
Now you guys have to change your email
and mobile.
You can have like a throwaway email for
the job applications.
Are you nervous at all during your.
Yeah, the nerves during the interview.
It depends how you know how
you are as a person,
but most likely you're going to be like
shaking there a little bit.
But yeah, just
drink some camomile tea. I don't know.
Just, you know, do something
to keep it down, have a glass of wine
if you can handle yourself off, you know.
But yeah, just the fear.
Yeah.
Like come up with something that helps you
with this, with the shakiness.
As long as you got the knowledge again,
you should be good
in the sense
of all these companies in your city.
They care about you.
Out of how many required
showing up in the office.
Everyone's different.
I'm based in Florida
and my company is actually New York.
And when they hired me,
we had an agreement that I'll relocate
as soon as they want people in the office.
But it's been like half a year and they've
been pushing date and pushing it more.
And now it's like,
I'm not
even sure that it's ever happening.
Like, I'm fine here.
I'm not looking forward to moving.
But you know, it's a ten.
So you might be getting offers
from all over the country.
Now, the pandemic kind of changed the
like the workplace situation.
So you might find something near.
But the good thing is you can apply it
anywhere and still be able to, you know,
work remotely.
So you just have like
more more room to play.
If they ask you
why you want to change your job, it's
the kind of field where you can jump jobs
like every few months, basically.
Well, let's say six, eight,
you know, every year, because you want
a personal growth, career growth,
it doesn't matter,
you know, your contract and you'll get
all the answers down the road
from your possible.
Yes. I don't know. It's possible.
We have international students working
from almost all the countries to the it.
It will depend on the company.
So we don't need our lecture.
For example,
if you want to move back to your home
country
or you want to live in the United States,
so do they require you
to stay in United States?
I mean,
do they have some kind of check and
balance on you can maybe visit the U.S.
maybe twice a year
and then you can stay in your own country
or something like that.
So with my particular job,
it probably wouldn't happen
because they're pretty it's a business
to business payment platform and they work
with banks and it's just not good
for their taxes, I think, or something.
So yeah, that wouldn't happen.
But there that, you know if you have
what's it called the job
if you can work in the U.S.,
you know a lot of companies won't care.
You know, it really depends.
A lot of companies like outsource
and you know,
like we have people
working from England and stuff.
So it really I'm also not lucky,
I guess, with Russia as my home country
because I wanted to work
like take my work
laptop with me on vacation and trip home.
And they were like, Yeah, Russian
hackers, We're not risking that.
And they just didn't want me.
They were like, You, you just take
your vacation, you know, enjoy it.
So yeah, I I guess
it depends on where you're from too.
But like, even if you don't,
if you move back to your country
and you don't work for U.S.
company anymore, there's still
you know, salaries are good everywhere.
And it's a very like needed
profession.
Probably not that, too,
but they're not famous for hackers,
at least, you know, companies.
If you guys want to work
in the United States
from outside,
I can guard you if you guys want,
because there are special companies
who are looking for these kind of people.
So if you guys want,
I can guide you for that.
You know, for our budget,
we've got people from all over
didn't give us all the information.
They're. Yeah.
So you see how nice he is.
He's just doing your job
but willing to help you with like,
future job opportunities.
Hold on to this guy.
I was going to ask.
So besides salary, you want to focus on
kind of the personal part too.
You know, you want to see how
how you communicate with people
who are interviewing you
if there is, you know,
a good report and everything,
because you're going to be working
with those people, you know, all the time.
So you want to have, you know, something,
something going there.
You you you want to be interested
in the application itself.
So find out what the company does,
what tools they use
because, you know, some like maybe
some of you will want to learn something
new once you're done with Centex,
maybe some of you will be more sticking
with your stack like Java, selenium
testing, G, cucumber or whatever.
So those like
there are a lot of things to consider.
Salary is just one of them.
And like almost
every place will offer you a good one. So
look at the benefits.
Remote work, work, work at the office.
You know,
I think it's more difficult for women.
Yeah, I don't think it's more difficult
for women to get this position.
I mean, honestly,
I think they want females more
because there are more details
and that's something that you need
in order to tester no room for a woman.
So they always want that cutting.
How long after you finish
did you find a job
that it took me?
I think after my second week on the I'm
looking for a job.
I got my first offer,
but I wasn't happy with it.
So I continue applying.
So it took me probably about 3 to 4 weeks
to get my job.
And even then when I had my
when I was in my current job,
I was still in other rounds
with other company.
So I still got
I like job offers well in the company, but
I decided to stick to the one I'm
with just because it's just at the time.
It just know works best for me.
Yes, you need to be very detail oriented
as a tester,
especially if you do manual testing.
Very right now.
My job, I'm very detail oriented
and sometimes they'll be like,
What do you mean?
Like the developers
just like sending messages like, No,
but this and this and that.
I'm like, No, you're missing
this, you're missing that. So
they'll just like Veronica said earlier,
like, they'll be like, Oh, no,
there she goes again.
Send me a message.
It's like, Oh, no, not her.
This is what you want to be like.
I keep laughing at it
because when you know, when someone goes,
Oh my God, when are you going to stop
recording blogs?
I'm like, when I'm when I'll stop looking
and I'll just
provide the that they're going
from.
For me, they provided everything for me.
They gave me a keyboard or a screen,
a laptop mouse.
Yeah.
So most companies, they provide everything
for you, especially.
They don't have to pay for rent
for the office.
It's much cheaper for them.
Do you mean if we were forgetting
things while being a student?
I mean,
and you know, bugging as GA
like many times was the same question.
So you're the guy whose name thing.
If I ask them something
about like two weeks ago or one week ago,
and then they don't remember that
sometimes.
Well, they're asking, I've got good,
pretty good memory, I would say.
And I was, you know,
putting in work to study
and like like I understand things
not even necessarily remember,
like you have to understand them.
So, no, I didn't really forget things.
Well, being a student
in general,
I had a part time job during
while studying and I was also full time
college student and they still are.
So yeah,
sometimes those days, not weeks, B.A.
sometimes it's 5 minutes.
Like you'll say something in 5 minutes,
you don't know it. It's
how you
rate your knowledge, why you finish, how
well you rate your job or knowledge
while you finish.
How will you rate your knowledge?
I don't think I mean, from from my
like talking to like from my perspective
would probably say
maybe a seven.
There's always things you need to learn.
So you would never be 100% like,
well unless your are, then maybe,
you know, you'll know everything,
but you will never be ten out of ten
because there's always something new
to learn.
Always like
sometimes they'll be like,
Oh, look at this code, you know?
And I'm like, okay, let me go back.
I still go on my notes.
I still go on YouTube and watch videos
like there's, just always, there
are things to learn
hundred percent
or 1000
out of ten or
no, you're asking the right questions.
So about a thousand.
So but imposter syndrome is a thing.
And I actually I did feel like an imposter
because I was like,
Oh my God, who am I kidding?
Four years of experience in my ass.
Like, Come on, you guys.
Like, I barely understand what's going on.
They're like, using, you know, the slang
that's going to company specific
and you just trying to fit in so hard
and, you know, and you see people
who actually have like many years
of experience and you're like, like,
yeah, it's, it's a thing, but
it's just you make the best of it.
You get, you say, yeah,
and the best you can do.
Yeah. You'll sit
and you'll get used to it.
But like knowledge,
you don't have experience,
you won't have it
when you start your first job.
But what you can is knowledge. So
even if you
have experience, you leave that job
just like maybe for one month or two month
and you guys will be same.
You, you, you have to start from zero
when you will be joining a new company.
I don't think I could just pass
an interview like off the bed right now.
I would have to study for it.
Yeah, she had to study,
came here.
And even if I am applying on a job,
I need to study.
You need to study
under percent?
Yeah, that depends on your English.
I would say
it can be sometimes, but like it's
the English barrier issues
more in your head than other.
Oh, you'll have those companies
on your resume.
We have links in the FBI.
Yeah.
You know, they pay the right people
for the background check.
And yes,
you work 40 hours and sometimes more.
And Mohamed just stopped looking
for shortcuts.
Sebastian, They're both.
So they when you go on the field,
you'll see a lot of full time
and contracting jobs.
It all depends what you're looking for,
but there's both.
Okay, well,
when you reach your goals, level
and remember that before before that
I spent seven years.
Yeah. I mean
then you can and he's teaching
like every day
you see how
it's it's
it's the same problem from badge to badge.
I think like we
because we were having the same self
doubt and everything
and we were like we'll never find a job.
It's not real.
All those people who just came and said
that since it's changed their lives,
they only lying.
They paid them.
They're not paying us, by the way,
just I
know,
but yeah, now you guys will be.
You guys will be great.
You're in good hands.
You know, all the instructors are great.
You think we're actors?
Thank you.
Yeah. You
just put in the effort and,
you know, it's like, take it seriously
and don't look for shortcuts.
You're getting a shortcut.
We kind 100%.
Hardest question an interview
any question related experience when I was
I had a one hour interview where there was
they were asking me like on my resume
and they would go, Oh, this job,
what would your supervisor say about you?
What was the most interesting bug
you found?
What would this person say about you
and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah?
And they went from,
you know, every job on the list.
They went and asked the same questions.
And honestly,
I'm not just that imaginative
I ran out of answers really fast,
and by the end of it I was like,
Yeah, So like, I think so much will,
you know, we'll let you know.
I'm like,
you know, how to, like, get all ready.
Now, there are some interviewers
that they will drill you down.
I had an interview.
Oh, he just it was with a developer.
He just kept asking questions.
I was like, Oh, Mike,
I don't know what else to say.
Like, you just kept drilling and drilling.
And I was like, Oh, now he's like,
But why this?
But why would you do this?
Why would you do that?
And I'm like, Oh my God. Like,
I don't know what I'll say.
I just want to, like,
shut down the computer.
I'm like, I'm done.
Yeah, They'll be those interviews
when you're like, Can
we just stop this thing?
Do we have like, it's
obviously not a good fit.
Let's just wrap it up.
But yeah, it's,
it's all, it's all experience.
So from what I heard, if you
to get into like Amazon or Google
or all those, you know, like
big companies, they'll be grilling you
with experience and everything.
So just be you of that
if you're good in your feed.
Yeah quick on your feed your music sounds
so I'm fine
No I think I'm okay from what It's me.
I have friends that have done this before
and they actually went
with to six years of experience.
So I did talk to them prior to me
putting the experience on my résumé.
So I think I, for myself I did,
I chose a good amount of years
of experience because sometimes, you know,
the more you have, it all depends
how you feel about your knowledge.
You know, if you feel like you're
very strong, go for it, you know?
But at the same time,
you're always going to learn.
So even if you put two, three, four
or five years of experience,
there's always learning involved.
So don't afraid of, you know,
how many years you put on your resume,
but then a good chances that, you know,
even if you put like four
years of experience,
they're still seeing you as a very kind of
junior person because four years of
experience is not that much
because, like,
you'll be working side by side with guys
who've been there, like for 20 years
or more than that
and it'll be like pretty obvious
where, you know, we're 20
and we're four is
you guys ask me the,
can these students
graduate from university
once they, have three years of experience,
Then they start to learn the things
that are used in the practical fair.
So even they have to spend
like three years before they have
a little bit of practical knowledge.
Hey, if feel like being a tester,
you know, it's not, you know,
like kind of a low position from
you have to move
to move up to manager or developer,
it's it's a
you know, if you're a good tester,
they'll pay you good money and Yes.
And you can be working there for 20 years.
You genuinely love it. And
why not?
Do you guys
beam during the night from the day of.
Yeah, when there was a student.
No, I didn't have no no one.
Like I didn't know any programing,
nothing.
I came from a health care field,
so It was completely different to me.
Everything. Everything.
And, you know, you just. Just study.
Just study.
That's all I can say.
Study and I'm I'm in college
for a computer science degree right now.
And I'm telling you, the way
these guys here give you information,
the way they teach you, you won't get it
anywhere else because college is a joke.
And I've said it many times
and they'll say it again
because the classes I'm taking,
if I didn't have any knowledge,
you know, from thank you, Oscar
and other guys, it's in books,
I'd be like, Oh, this isn't for me.
You know, this is too difficult.
This is too whatever.
So I'm seriously
they're doing a great job here.
They are
manual testing.
It's never boring.
By the way, but
it can get, you know, pretty late
when you want to code,
but it's never boring.
And I'm getting a degree
because their work
because I don't have any degree.
I the highest level of education
I have is high school and
if already have a bachelor's degree,
you're not going to run into this problem.
But I've been shut down on interviews
and recruiter calls where they'd ask me,
Oh, do you have a bachelor's degree?
It doesn't matter and what?
And I'd be like,
Oh, I'm working on one right now.
And they're like,
Oh, so you don't have it? Okay, bye.
And that's why her
and maybe down the road,
yeah, I'll have more opportunities
with, with a degree
like computer science degree
that but
mostly just
you know, to like to have some bachelor's
degree like to have some kind of higher
education. Yes.
Thank you for having us here.
It's to be on the other side.
Yeah.
Worry about studying anymore.
Just give it a few months
and you'll be visiting next batches
and giving them, you know,
they'll be on this side of the computer.
It's fun. Here.
Come join us
online, guys.
If you want,
I can invite some more students and I hope
this is enough for today.
Okay,
Now you're getting us girls
best treatment.
You know, usually pulling students for you
and everything.
Don't forget to post the code.
Oh, yeah. Her.
All right, Veronica already.
And I thank you so much for joining us.
Thank you, guys.
Thank you, guys. A lot of fun.
Yeah.
Good luck on your journey.
And please study you guys a lot.
All right.
Thank you.
Good weekend.
Hey, guys.