Good morning.
Good morning. Theme.
Hello. Hello.
How are you guys?
I know.
That's good.
Well, listen, there's been a
you know, I cannot say it was bad, right?
I always have to say it was great. It's
Alec Costello.
Well, because is.
I'm doing great.
I mean,
so we didn't do this task last year.
Let's start from this task.
And before we start,
if you guys have any questions,
ask me where I can ask
one morning and all.
Do you guys can you guys see
videos from other groups
as well on Flipboard?
Try to watch the videos from other
especially from, you know, Sebastian,
the way they have explained things
slowly, peacefully and with examples.
It's good
if you guys are explaining in this way
it will be good.
I saw from Alan.
Okay, so I have only watch
the videos from the group
and all and all that belong.
But I will try to watch
the remaining videos
and then I will share the feedback
with you guys.
But why do they.
We are
you have seen it like 8 to 10 people.
It was it was great.
As compared to the previous videos
that you guys
recorded.
Good morning.
Morning.
I want you to feel worse
so that you guys keep on improving
slowly and Carmen does not work with me.
So let me let me put the
this last task as well in here.
I saw I a great improvement for
Illini as well as compared to last time.
So I will share the feedback.
Personal.
Okay, let's do this
task inside this class.
25, the last task
task for you
and in the
task find you guys had to
create a web driver interface
to create driver interface
and define
matters like open floors and open.
So wide open
or with
inward.
Then we have to create another interface,
big screen shortcut interface.
So let's create that in here.
Interface
is not a string title.
Oh yes, you are right.
Next you
the screenshot
and get screenshot.
The method here.
What is the return type
for this screenshot?
Is it wide in real life?
They will give like this pictures job
or not in real life they will give like
this picture in
Can you can you do you face your question
interview maybe
Oh no in on your jobs.
If you are building a framework,
there will be a requirement document
as authorities.
There are many different types
of documents
and everything will be clearly explained.
And if something is not clear,
you guys will be having team
leads and architect and you will
be is.
So you can always consult with those.
If some requirements are not clear
and if your team is small,
you can directly ask the client as well.
You can also ask for pictures
or further explanation.
You will be having meetings
that will not be a problem.
Don't worry about the requirement.
And then we have the remote web driver
interface
and under the interface
the remote
web driver, and it has the navigate
method,
avoid, navigate
In this remote web driver,
it is inheriting from web driver
and takes screenshot.
So what is the key word
that I should use guide
if I want to inherit
from another interface
extends right.
So extend the screenshot and then extends
subscribe.
And then you guys had to create
three classes Chrome Driver,
Firefox and Safari Driver
in which you guys had to implement
all of these methods.
So last
grown driver.
And now if I have the implementing
methods, should I use the expense keyword
of implement?
So chrome driver implements
which interface I should implement?
Do I need to implement all of these?
All three of these?
No, I only need to implement
the remote web driver
and if I press all to enter on Windows,
I can implement all the matters like this
because it has everything.
So let me put some printouts
was the shortcut.
Sorry I didn't pay attention format.
It was options and enter
it. Is
it okay if
I created the next class as well in here?
But finger title do
we need to give parameter in our or not?
It's a simple
exercise to practice the inheritance
and interface implementation.
So don't worry about giving parameters
to this method
because even if you see in this picture,
there are no parameters
that are being passed
to any of these methods.
So you guys had to implement this picture.
So that's why
we don't need to place any parameters.
So class
Firefox
Driver Welcome,
implement.
Let's bring more private
new You guys explore the methods from Top
end our classes.
Actually let me copy
the matters from here.
You pass
Safari driver
which also implements
a little
or then yes try to explore them
because they are really helpful and
copy these methods are being
let me replace
Firefox
with Safari
because
now we have implemented
how to replace word shortcut.
It's control are Sebastian control are
okay.
So can you send me the
polymorphism implementation
for this task?
Create the driver
that's for the class
you mean
method?
Are you guys able to follow me?
Is anyone following me?
That means you guys are now great
at typing and coding.
Was this task homework? No, it was.
It was
in your group project
in group project.
You are too fast.
Do you guys want me to slow down
or. Yeah.
No, we will.
As the all email is
using
these
the cloud.
It looks like you
in this issue for yourself.
Okay, so you guys can always stop me.
Let me know once you guys are done typing
and let me know
if you guys want me to scroll down a lot.
Because this shortcut so far worked.
Not good.
I just don't feel good.
That's why I am not responding as much.
No, no. I want you to.
I want you to respond
and I want you to follow.
Whenever I am typing something,
I always want you to
follow.
Option Enter does not look good.
You are using Windows or Mac
and no Hartmut, I don't want you to copy.
I want you to type with me.
Yes, I can scroll down
to the fast.
Anyway, please share this when you finish.
No, I don't want you guys to copy me.
I want you to type with me.
That's what I was trying my.
Why are you guys the desktop? Me
in a YouTube videos?
We have option to play fast or slow.
I have met so it will be options
and enter. Yes.
We have so many
in your time.
Don't right. Type it.
I want you to type it all
using the shortcuts, copying and pasting
using be replaced.
But all of these skills
they will be very very helpful
in your jobs when you guys will be dealing
with large projects
and you guys will be writing the code,
you will be much, much faster
in typing and writing the code.
If you guys know all these tricks,
I means copy, I will write them down.
Okay, so you are one of those format.
So for example, when I used to copy paste
assignments in my bachelors,
I was one of those who used to understand
that assignment
as well, not just copying and pasting
for windows. It's
old and enter
that.
Are you Officer?
Look,
are you guys done writing Bill Line 40?
Is there anyone who is still writing
this piece of code?
Okay, let me scroll down then
and try to use the shortcuts.
Guys.
By the way, I didn't
I didn't understand what you said
at the end of your
at the end of the recording.
I think it was in the native language.
How do you replace that
word on multiple lines?
By different ones.
Control are
so you have to press control are
then you specify the word
that you want to replace.
Whom did you not understand?
Oh, I was talking about the recordings, so
I re now
said something in her native language
at the end of her video.
And then the words that you guys
want to replace this word with.
And then once you fill these two boxes,
it will highlight
the words that will be replaced.
So, for example,
I hear Katrina, so
so then you guys can
press this replace button.
I guess I start adding maybe,
maybe there is some kind of network issue.
So and if you want to replace all of them,
you can replace this.
Replace all or replace
will start replacing from here.
And it will replace
all the highlighted words.
And if you don't want to replace anything,
you can press this downwards.
Arrow
to replace the next one.
So you see it has moved in here.
So now it will start replacing from here.
And if you want to replace all of them,
you can select based
in, then you have the options
to replace in only commands
and string literals.
Accept commands,
accept strings frozen all of that.
And you guys can also
learn about this from you.
You guys aren't typing this code.
All of it.
Now in here
we are just creating three objects
of chrome driver Firefox and Safari
and we are floating it inside
the remote web driver.
So why you have written this?
If health conditions
is an order,
the same method
that is available inside all the classes?
I don't think so.
I don't think we need this.
If health conditions
because put parameter in title
just to use it for practice.
What?
So I see the output I do the same
or from all the browsers.
Are there any questions from this task?
Guys.
All right then.
I closed these two files.
We create a new
26 or 60.
So in the last class
we started learning about,
can I ask
name of the class cannot be released?
Yes, it can be released.
You can have this name,
but then there will be a conflict
because Java always prefers
the classes that are created by you.
It will always look for the methods
from your class
instead of the classes
that are in JDK from Java guys.
So you will not be able
to call those matters.
But yes, yes, you can create.
But this is the problem that you will get.
So keep it simple and board.
Call it dog. Yes, Sebastian
Alert guys.
So we
started learning about the wrapper classes
and you guys tell me, what is that
upper class.
So object
type of primitive variables.
Okay, but
upper
type of primitive variable assignment,
do you mean by upper type
way to use primitive types inside and use?
We have now
it's a class for each primitive variable.
So wrapper
wrapper classes are
object classes
around
primitive
types that have
building
methods
and are used
as objects
where
necessity.
So they are simple classes
that are built around
the primitive data types.
Wrapper classes are object
classes around primitive
that are type that have built in
returns are not used as objects.
We are necessity.
For example, in
collection.
And what are the what?
What is this
concept of boxing and unboxing
wrapper classes provide us
provide us
a mechanism
to use primitive data types
as objects.
The automatic convergence
of primitive data type
into its equivalent wrapper
or third
boxing
is the
automatic convergence of primitive data
types into its equivalent wrapper
is filed.
Boxing is not automatic.
Yes, it's not automatic.
You have to punch someone first,
then the boxing starts.
Right?
It's not automatic.
So because of convergence
of primitive data,
type into its equivalent
wrapper class is called
boxing
or belt.
If we type
integer
I equal to narrow in bigger
and then we pass a primitive.
Then it is called
in boxing.
But in the art of boxing
is they
are called pneumatic
and virgin of primitive are type
into execution.
Purpose
is called
R2 in boxing.
So for example, instead of this
we simply stay.
I is equal to kind still we are doing
the same thing, exact same thing.
But in here we are simply assigning
this primitive to the wrapper type.
So this is called
auto boxing,
so you can think of it like this.
So this is a wrapper class.
This is a box.
And inside this box
we have this integer.
So when we are placing this integer
inside this box, it is called boxing.
And when we get back out of this box,
we call it
unboxing
like this
is the conversion of wrapper.
It will turn to primitive Dada type
is called
Unbox can ensure
the result of previous task in console.
Well, it's already in console before
to make it
so I hope you can still read it.
The conversion of equivalent wrapper
to primitive data types
is called unboxing.
So for example, if we said
and I is equal to
I got the value of what we had
is the title.
I didn't call the title, let
me check it.
They call that title.
I was expecting that
I would see the output here
and did I miss something
or because I didn't print it out
the string. Right.
So you have to put it inside the printout
of the
let me know. It's
in the title now.
This is why he had this.
None on. This is there.
That's not the reason
you guys take decisions very quickly.
Very easy to confuse.
You guys
have faith in your concepts. No,
that was not really that
you guys are lightning fast.
So if I ask something twice
and if your answer is yes,
you quickly change it to no.
Okay, But
when I say no, I am rejecting
it is not right.
What I said. Yes, it is not right.
But this adviser, I
hope it is not going to
happen in the interview.
So if I have already placed a value inside
a wrapper class, you see the
how I get back the value
from that after the power of editing
and deleting our customers.
So this is how I can get the value back,
the primitive value back from me
wrapper, part time.
I want you to have this confidence
in your interview,
that interview
that you are born for this job.
At least this is the interview
that I have read about.
I am giving an interview to the companies
and I stuck to the devil
when I was five.
Can you comment out next to the code
and when you were born, you
by the way, I am having a severe flu.
We might have two days class
ugly.
Let's see how far I can go.
So it is boxing.
It is boxing happening here and it is
unboxing.
My son is getting interested
in forwarding.
Okay.
What do you think the age.
Thank you.
My mom tells a story about the job
and she pregnant
with me. It's
may and make him land
and he will never do easy.
He will never ask you for anything.
He will just ask you to give.
He will be frozen
is it
will give your girlfriend to make a food
since you are not willing will
she will say make two soups, one for you
and one for me.
We all started together. You can get good.
Do you guys remember the tears in scenes
like this bird to get a lot of money?
But. All right,
let me put.
And it is auto unboxing
and the awesome number of their dog class.
Okay so this talked about thing
not unboxing.
Are there any questions arise from this?
Yeah.
So then we started about the collections
plain look right.
Well what is this? Collections frame rate.
A moment please.
Yes. Dennis, do
you guys want to scroll up?
Do you have any question
or do you just want me to stop?
I don't know.
I think the little ones, they are
all they are always more smarter than the
elder ones.
Right?
It just look like that.
Learn fast.
You know, we definitely
already.
Guys, can we move forward now?
You mean five years old?
Well, reliable.
You have started discussing
how to family days.
We are learning daily.
Please come back
with the
Everyone is now.
It looks like
everyone is from the government over to us
All the paintings right.
How many people working day
what are their ages and all that.
All right I'm just kidding.
So collections framework, guys.
I am.
I am still against that if I have kids.
27 year old kid.
So what is collections framework is
collection framework.
Help us reduce programing effort
and give us data structures
that are easy to manipulate. Yep.
So. Yep. Yep.
I am 27.
I think I got I got this flow from her.
I will call her after the class.
Looks like
let good give you a long
collection.
Provides architecture to store
and we have all the recording
and they manipulate the group of
objects that are represented
as single unit.
We have many interfaces and
classes
inside the
framework to
achieve this.
Thank you.
Okay,
so there are many classes and interfaces
and we started learning about one class
in the last class gaining guys.
Name that class,
the ArrayList class.
Right.
And we also learned
about the diamond operator.
And you guys tell me, what is the purpose
of that diamond operator. Yes.
So it's called diamond Operator
And why do we use them to diamond operator
It is used to specify the
data type in
collections
framework.
All right.
So let's say we want oops,
we want to create this
ArrayList.
We specify a string.
Okay.
Have you asking to match so many times?
So let me use double
unit export numbers.
What was the other name for this
genetics is this syntax for genetics.
Genetics is a mechanism in Java
that we used to generalize.
So for example,
if you want to use the same class
and same method for multiple data types,
we can use the genetics.
So for example,
if you guys want to have a look.
So for example, for example,
if you open the analyst class,
you guys see this E if angle bracketing.
D So this E means
when I will be creating the object of this
class,
whatever data type I specify in here.
So for example, while creating the object
type by specify a string
java will replace
all of this is with string listing.
All of this is distinct
and this class will start
behaving as if this class
was built to handle a string data type.
If we specify integer,
it will start behaving
as if this class was built for integers.
So these genetics, you guys remember
when we were discussing about overloading,
I told you how to reduce
the that you guys have to write
if you are dealing
with multiple data types.
So we learned how we can use
those warthogs
to handle multiple parameters.
We discussed
how the automatic convergence happens
and this was the last
last piece of the puzzle.
So if you want to use the exact
same method for different data types,
you guys can use the genetics.
It's an advanced concept.
If we had some time, we will
is still speaking English.
I am speaking Java, so we can we
we will discuss about about this genetics.
Okay.
Public boolean and object element.
Why is there method boolean?
We are adding an object.
So how to manage or falls
that are done by the element.
So if you look at this
add method, it takes this e.
Now this e when you specify inside those
that diamond operator, if it is a string,
it will become a string.
The integer, it will become integer,
but the return type is always boolean.
This return type tells us
if there was enough space
on your computer
and your Java was successfully able
to store that element inside your RAM,
if the guy was unable to add the element
on. If you are to come
to if there was no error,
there was enough memory
on your computer,
then it will return true.
And if anything goes wrong,
then defaults will be returned from here.
So that's why
we have this proven false.
Yes, I am vaccinated. It's just a flu.
But I think I should also
I should also not
so and also not getting the flu as well
if I am.
No, I don't think so.
I am vaccinated for flu.
I thought I have enough vaccinations
for this year,
so let's not have another vaccination.
So I had
a B injections for hepatitis
and then Corona, COVID and all that.
I think that's enough for this year.
That one is good, too.
Yes, maybe next year.
I will have that one.
I think that too many vaccinations
are also not good, right?
I heard we need to take
the booster as well.
Oh, my God.
They did their booster shot, too.
Okay. Yes.
They both tried out for this label.
Vaccination does not mean
you will not have a disease.
Put flu against the building
or is equal
to nil.
At least in.
So we learned about some matters as well.
It's all fake.
Like you still think it's all fake.
All right.
So do you also believe that it is flat?
It's not round.
I have two shots and I am giving a scale.
And then you my you must also believe
that there are non dinosaurs
and nothing outdoors or dead also fake
and on die in total with that effect.
And then there are aliens between us right
until around.
But COVID is fake.
Okay, so there are still people
there is a big community of people
who still thinks be
ultra still flat.
I don't know, whatever is this, it's
not good.
So can you guys tell me the names
of the methods that we learn from this
in this class
and how we can use those methods?
So we learned about the ad method, right?
And what is the purpose? This method
add the
element to the
ad at least right then
I think these
methods are self explanatory.
Do you guys want me to write this inside
the notes?
They are simple, easy, right?
Let's Google.
Okay.
There are
so as we can store multiple element
different types of objects
in array with the help of polymorphism
there.
We can also do that with the added.
So for example, if I have a class root
and then I have a class
apple X and root,
just the name, it's
okay.
It's a very simple example
just to demonstrate that we can also use p
polymorphism in here.
Right now
the world is having so many problems.
There is this go weird and then all of
these political situations,
storms and global warming temperature
and ladies day, they're still there
they are still looking for diamonds.
It is we did
yes men went out also are
there is a complete series of
ads on on Indian period about the
about both men's the men's will be men
so if I me in matrilineal what I can have
like an event at least
I can write fruit in here
and then I can see through look and
apple
fruit dot and oops
you know orange
and then guys looking for beer
and so the polymorphism is good solution
for these problems.
Would you,
would we please do a simple example
with the red list and standard letters.
Yes. Remind me and deliver.
We will do the example which kind of
I think you guys are always
been having this problem
with scanner and add a
then loops right.
So as I can look through
an area
I can also look through
the ArrayList are using any of the loop.
So for example I can see for each
where electrolytes specify
as the data type in here life
inside this for each.
So fruit
Loops.
And then I should write fruits in here
and then I can say
not putting to name
all either
categories is there and here we are
adding whole class.
In the early years
we have always been adding whole class.
You'll get the string you
the class integer in the class.
So you see,
that's the reason why the collections
framework only works with classes.
That's the reason why we learned
to wrapper classes, because collection,
they don't allow primitives.
So we will always be adding a class.
It will always be a class
in the only difference is that here
we are creating our own class.
Previously we were using the class
that is created by dialog
life. So
quick question inside.
Why don't we have string?
Because we are not dealing with strings
anymore.
We are dealing with fruit now.
Why should we have strings
I used in class when I have to store
sequence of letters, write
fruit,
which is the parent is the whole class?
Yes. How many of you think
that I should be putting string in here?
Or maybe at least before this example,
you guys were thinking of putting
a string in here.
Okay, So I will.
I will show more examples.
Don't do that. It will be clear.
Or should I specify in here
I am sitting here thinking that the fruit,
the word fruit looks wrong and weird.
This will did.
This should not go.
It's already a rule of right.
Sorry English champion.
It's already okay.
Thank you.
I just type good so many times.
Looks wrong now. Yes,
but now we know our classes which we have,
which we create.
It needs to go there too,
so we can use class names.
Esther.
No, no, we are.
We are always using a class name.
If this thing is a class,
we passed on for this thing
after thinking for a second, banded fruit
string was a class
integer was a class boolean
or they were all classes.
We always specify a class inside
the inside of this diamond operator.
We always specify a class.
Is there anyone who is truly confused?
What do we specify inside?
In here we specify the type of object
that we want to add.
Inside this,
at least we specify the name of the class.
And here
anybody eat fruit?
Now, after this task, it
could drink
a lot of orange juice use to enter.
Here in Pakistan,
we have so many types of citrus
citrus families very famous in here.
And it's very cheap.
One one big glass of
of a good citrus family.
A juice will cost you around
around 70 to $0.80
as cheap as cow in Ukraine.
Yes, We are so loyal to building classes
we still didn't get back
much used to our own classes.
I think that that's why
that's why I have showed you this example.
I will show more
again.
Can we move to the next example?
Is not this faster?
The new fruit.
Fruit in. Yes, Mama. There it is. Faster.
Yes, it is faster.
But remember then you cannot perform
all of those things.
Removing a certain object,
inserting an object in between,
searching for an object.
If you are using arrays, you have to write
all of those matters on your own
and you will lose that flexibility.
Yes, it is faster, but there's the
that's the issue.
Yep. Yep.
No matter.
You said we will be afraid of Pauline.
Now see, everyone is in love with one.
Oh, it was a trick so that you guys don't
know to ask too many questions
from polymorphism.
I need to tell you about my tricks.
Okay. Can we move to the next thing?
The apple guys?
By the way, which topic you guys find
the hardest in this advanced
part of Java?
I think it's the overriding
or overloading or what is it?
Okay, so
let me check
if we are missing all Java.
Okay,
so we already discussed about
where do we start?
Okay, don't please
don't start.
So, so
in this these are the blue ones.
They are the interfaces, the green ones,
they are the classes.
So today we will discuss about list
a red list
and linked list
the you guys already know
about the URL method
because used to insert an element at all.
Well,
what is the difference between an add?
All guys.
Yes, I think you should.
Yes you you guys don't
you guys have these slides on canvas?
I think they are.
They are available in the.
So if I want to add only one element,
I use the add method.
If I want to add entire list inside
another list,
then I use add all metadata.
You ask static question already.
Static question then is
what do you mean by static question
and then the
remove is same.
We are, if we want to remove one element,
we use the removal method.
If we want to remove a set
elements from a list,
we passed that completely as to the
removal method and all of those elements
which are in this list
will be removed from the other list.
Now let's discuss about this retain
all match code.
So the question you always ask
and we are still not sure.
Oh, okay.
Okay, now I get it.
So can I use static
method inside of the instance
method guys?
No, don't ask.
Oh my god.
I am still getting.
No, I seem like still No.
Come on man.
Oh my God.
Okay, you guys will be fine. At least.
At least you guys will not.
I hope
At least you guys will not make a mistake.
If this question is asked
in the interview,
Just observe the expressions
of the interviewer If you said yes
with Google it
and you know if you see these expressions,
they use static.
So it'll be at least
and you guys are masters of this, right?
Can you do no and no do. Yes.
A cleaner can use this one.
So let's say nice
and then you realize that you changed
your answer to the wrong one.
No, no.
You have to observe the expressions first,
then only change.
And so let's say, guys,
okay, the way you need to use the Neo's.
So if you have the right way to do a
so let's say, guys, I have these two lists
and these elements.
They are also present in here.
So. Okay.
And then there are some elements
which are not present
inside this list right now.
What I want are we on Demo six already
know are we are on demo number for hard.
If you combine the demos from previous
class, we are learning new methods.
We are not repeating the old ones.
So let's say guys
from a list
you want to retain
all the elements, all the elements.
So now it's kind of more practical,
more and more practical.
Java will now be more and more practical
from this collection framework,
less concepts, more practicality.
So that's why
we will be having thousands of demos.
If you guys want,
I can just explain it like without
trying to demo.
Yes, in layman's tips.
So if you guys want to remove everything
from this list, nice focus in here.
Everyone, please pay attention.
If I want to remove everything from this
and only want to retain the elements
which are present in here
and in here,
then I use the retained all method.
Can you guys tell me
before a security score or
which elements will be left inside
this list are Australian
security retain all method.
So if
you guys have understood the explanation.
So I am doing this
subject.
One note
retained all and I am passing.
So what's object to in here?
And after that if I put in subject
one word output,
I will be left with inside this subject.
One. So let me repeat again.
Let me repeat it again.
Those elements
which are present in here and in here,
the elements
which are present in both the lists,
only those elements will be retained
inside of this list.
The rest of the elements,
they will be removed.
Can you guys tell me the output now?
Just tell me the line number.
For example, will I see in this line
number if that's a BLT or not? So
let me check.
Is this ls SDLC present
here?
That means it will be retained,
right?
Because it is not present
in both of the lists.
Right.
Is this manual testing present in here?
In both This
it is also not present.
It should also be retained.
Is dollar present in both of the lists?
It will be retained.
Is it present in both the list?
Is selenium present in both of the lists.
It will be returned is test
and you present the yes
test and is present here and in here.
So it will be removed.
Is cucumber present
and more delicious Removed
is still present in both
the list is removed.
Is a paste pattern in both this? Yes.
So I should have left
with this element.
Do you guys understand it now?
So today I am having a flu
and you guys know when someone has flu,
half of their minds don't work.
If we the opposite opposite results.
When I hear the score, please forgive me.
Let me
go to put.
Okay, so we
see the opposite result, right?
I was just kidding.
Let me explain.
So Java
Java will scan this completes
complete list.
Okay.
And Java, let me make it some other
things up.
Now you guys can see it.
Don't play with my
So guys, what does this written word for?
Written keyword means
retained means.
So I am saying subject one to retain all
and then I am passing subject
to which means
I want to retain all the elements
which are President inside
this list of tool
in here.
That means if best n d is present in here,
it will be retained inside of this list.
And if it is not present, it will be
removed yes, it will be removed.
So that's ten D is
present inside the subject to please
retain it.
Okay is present.
Please return it.
A skill is present.
Please retain If API is present
please that it then it so
is the opposite of remove
all in Remove all We remove the elements
which are present inside this list
that we passed to this matter.
Okay.
And in return all we remove everything
but retained those elements
which are present in here and in here.
Okay.
Is it clear why we see this test
and you will see this test and in here,
because it was present in here.
Why? We see this cucumber.
We see this cucumber
because it was also present in here.
Why we see a school Because it was present
in here and in here.
Why we don't see our SDLC,
because it was not present in here.
So it will not be retained.
You just played with my little brain,
but waiting for another plot twist.
It will keep those elements
which are present in both the classes.
Yes. So whichever is the
is the easiest way for you
to memorize this, but
I hope this will retain all this discover.
This itself is conveying
the logic behind this method.
Not enough fluid actually means remove
and remove means that
retains means.
Retain those elements
and remove everything.
As you remove everything.
So remove means remove these elements
and retain everything else for opposite
these methods to matter.
They are opposite of each.
Okay,
so just.
Just to
make it more clear,
let's have one more demo
because these classes,
they will be heavily
used in your real life problems.
So I want all of you to be super,
super clear
about all the matters
you guys will never be using.
I don't want to say this.
It's very
rare that you will be using arrays.
You will always be using edit lists,
so it will print out every.
Can you share the code for this demo? Yep.
Yes. Written means keep safe.
We will never use arrays.
Translation
You will use nothing but arrays
arrays.
Okay, so let me do this guys.
Just just so that we are clear.
If I say subject to
not retain all and subject one
and if I print out subjects to tell me
the output
to date is they are super, super real.
No, don't worry about them.
We only have two days
so that you guys learn about the nested
loops.
It is the same.
It will be the same output, same output.
Okay, so now we are saying from subject
to in here, remove everything but not
what is present
inside the subject. One.
Okay, so let us check.
Is this best and is it present inside this
list? One Yes.
So it will be retained.
Is this cucumber present
inside this list? Yes.
So almost
everything.
No, this this mobile testing.
It is not present
in here.
Right.
So it will be removed.
No, it is that present
mobile testing.
So I can use manual testing
on what I am having flu and no.
Do you
to this mobile testing
it is not present in here
so it will not be retained.
Right.
Are you guys sure?
You sure you will not be returned?
How many of you are sure that I will see
this?
I will.
I will not see this
mobile testing in my output. So
let me at least
I think I need to complete
box issues now.
It is global,
so let me execute this.
Okay.
You guys see mobile testing
is not present in the output, so
I hope it is now clear.
Okay.
All right,
Your Highness, we will have a break.
Prince Lobo of Java,
can we have released Lupo?
Break is equal to note.
Yes, we can have that.
All right, All right.
Kings and queens.
Let's have a break.
Initial media shortcode to change.
Subject one to subject to shortcut to the.
There is no shortcut to change.
Subject end subject to.
I just copied and pasted it.
You guys are always looking,
but yes, it would be mouth.
Oh, you just need to double click
to select the complete complete word
and then you have to press control C
and then you can double click in here
to place that word.
I am worried about your health.
I think you need more break time.
Okay.
We will see.
We will see if we are able
to cover enough contents.
Maybe we will learn D class or Tool 30.
Maybe we will see.
I will try to drink some
something, coffee or something
asking if there are any solutions
for our double cropping.
For example, if I want to copy this
and that and then choose what to pay for.
Yes, actually there is a complete shortcut
which will keep
you can copy 15 things and you can paste
which one of them you want to do that
which one of you
you want to paste from on that.
I will show you
after the break how to do that
all plus choose
Oops.
I want to copy what is in your brain
and demanded a reading shortcut.
Elon Musk is working on Medium.
Maybe we will have that in future.
All right guys, please be back
and reminding me about everybody.
I hope you guys are back.
I mean, to how do you do this when I ask?
Oh, you're old.
And then you can select things
vertically all down your all the button
or options button on Mac,
and then you can edit vertically.
All right.
So you guys already know about this size.
The Clear Method
player
just removes everything from a list.
Contains your text
if something is present.
Yes, we are recording.
Thank
contains instruct if something is present
inside that list or not.
And if you if we want to check
if a complete list is present inside
another list or not,
then we use this contains all.
Okay then we have this iterator
method is a very special method
for that.
How many of you
do we
and you guys will not face, you know?
So I want every one of you
to pay attention.
Now, this is something important
we. Didn't put anything in demo two.
Okay?
You know, we have something in here.
Or if just about the size.
All right, All right.
Copy this
and remove rest of these.
Okay.
So, guys,
if I do something like this, if I see.
So I can also
access the elements of
and edit list by index.
If so, what I can say
I can see subjects dot size
and then
I can print out the elements
by saying subject and item get.
So this get method.
If we pass the index to this matter,
we will be getting the element
at that specific index.
So for example, before I
go to this code,
if I say subject started get
and if I said three, what
I will advise, I should get it
because index is the start
from zero.
Here we go.
Now this is history.
First answer always the wrong answer.
Now don't worry, I'm just getting No,
don't stop this far, okay?
Don't get discouraged.
That's how you learn.
That's how you will learn.
The more mistakes you make anymore,
you guys will learn.
All right.
So, no, for it does not matter.
Let me. Let me tell you why.
Yup. It's.
I just don't want you to get discouraged.
And I always tell
that I keep on making door to door to do
and during the classes and all that.
But some of the students get serious
that why instructor
is always just making jokes on us
or like that.
What you can do.
You can make jokes on me,
but don't stop responding, okay?
And you can tell me that
I don't like this.
Please don't make any jokes. Okay?
Okay.
It depends who you are.
Just joking with it.
Some people will get mad.
So, guys, let's see.
Okay, so first, let me show you this.
So this is a simple
program in which I am
printing out the elements.
Okay,
So now, guys, I have this requirement.
I want to remove
all the elements
which have more than four characters.
How can I do that?
No, it will not say.
Just give me one moment.
It will not change to an envelope.
So we write. If
we write, if.
And then what
should I write inside of the if?
Well, I write some dark start.
Get it, boss I
and if the length.
No, no it will not be subject or size.
Remember
I am now accessing when I say subjects.
Note that this method
will return me a string.
Right?
Right.
So I now can call all the methods
which are present inside the string class.
For example, length.
And if length is greater than four,
I want to say
subjects not remove.
And then I write
This is how I can remove
an element, right?
Is there anyone
who don't understand this code?
If I want to remove the elements,
we are having more than four characters.
I will write a loop
starting from zero,
less than the size of the list,
accessing all the elements one by one.
And then because the first element
they are off type strings.
So I can call the length method
from string class.
I can if it returns more than four.
If it is the case,
I call subjects, not remove and I pass
that I in here.
So that specific element will be removed.
Right?
So now let me execute this code
or I have to print out this list as well.
After we are done
removing the elements.
Okay, so this is the output that I get.
Is there anything wrong
that you guys see inside this code?
Take 2 minutes, observe the code
and check if there is
anything wrong in here.
Okay.
So this best Benji,
it should not be in here right?
It should not be in here.
It should be removed from the list.
So if I remove.
Okay So let me do this.
Let me.
Let me run it again.
Okay.
It will.
So what is happening in here?
If the last element
so it is not checking the condition
of our last element.
Can you guys explain me what is going on
in here, why we are having this problem?
And let me you the hint
areas,
they can digest their size at runtime.
It is in our digest
and their size at runtime.
They are dynamic.
So yes, this logic is correct.
I am starting from index zero.
I should not be going more than five.
But what happens is that because it is,
they can adjust to their size at runtime.
We never use for loops
or for each loops to perform any operation
that changes the size of an edit list
because it can be dangerous,
it can lead to bugs.
And if you guys try to use a
for each loop, if you guys try to use
it for each loop to do this,
you will be getting an edit.
You will be getting an error.
Why? You are getting an error.
You are getting an error
because of this same issue.
Because it is
they can adjust their size at runtime.
Java is saying their task.
You are trying to perform an operation
inside this list
and you are trying to perform two parallel
operations,
one operation to access the element
and the other operation
to remove the elements.
Now how internally loops are implemented,
they are implemented for static data
structures, right?
The data structure
which don't change their side.
If something is changing your size,
it can lead to bugs
that can lead to arrest.
So that's why we go to this exception
that stays concurrent.
We will be getting the same issue
with the Y loop as well.
Loops cannot be used safely.
Sometimes they will work,
sometimes they will not work.
And it can be super, super frustrating
for you to find out about the issue. No.
So for each loop is not restricted at all.
So let me
show you why why this is happening.
So let's debug this code
that's debug this code
to find out why we are facing this issue.
Yes, that's why we have operators.
We don't use loops with collections,
but we always press for iterator,
especially in those cases
which especially for those matters
on those operations
which can change the size
of your regional list.
We don't perform these operations
with the loops.
So let me let me show
you step by step like this.
This Adam is happening.
Okay?
How this change of size at runtime is
is changing our logic,
how it is leading us to bugs
and why we should not use loops.
So let me just move this up in here
so that you guys can see
the complete picture.
So let me put a debug point in here.
Okay.
And then let me debug
application.
Okay.
So you guys see right now what is the size
of this ArrayList?
So arrays,
they are fixed in size at compile time.
So areas are
fixed in size, compile time,
not at runtime.
It is.
Come on.
Okay.
Not this time
is and we can give this size.
So once this size is given to an area,
the size after that is fixed,
you can give their size at compile time
by encoding the value.
You can give their size at runtime
by asking the user, by asking the user
for the size of their data
and then placing that inside a variable
and using that variable
as the size of the area.
This is how it works.
So right now
decide this six we execute the next line.
So first we will be getting the SDLC
right.
SDLC has size four.
If I want to check out the output
of this part guys,
during my debugging,
I want to go a little deeper.
I want to check over this subject
computer and I get I is returning me.
How can I do that?
Maybe there
are multiple operations on a single line
and I want to check
the output of each of them.
Do you guys remember what we can use
in this kind of scenarios?
So no.
Yes, we can use this step in,
but there is this option off what
and what if.
So you see subjects dot
get is returning SDLC
subjects don't get to not learn
is returning me for
and subjects don't get
the talent is greater
than for
is returning me false
so I can check the output out at each step
with the help of this,
what are you guys able to create this?
What is okay?
So if I want to have a detailed
look at the execution steps
and if there are multiple steps in
a single line, I use this. So
what the
first element did is annihilation.
This.
If condition will be false,
then we will be getting the second
element, which is manual testing.
And now the size is 14
and this is condition will return me.
True.
You said a lot. Yes.
And they are called what is what
like this one.
So this time the condition
to still decide is six days, right
So this time the condition will be true
and this element will be removed.
Right.
So what is the size now?
This size has been reduced to
five now.
Okay.
And next time
we get geared to no change in size,
next time we get selenium, no change size.
Oh, sorry.
This time again,
the size will be reduced to four.
And then
we get the best ending, right?
So right now the size is four,
the value of Y is three.
So is three.
Less than four.
So the size of us four.
So four is a four less than four, No.
So this loop, it terminates
because if this size was fixed
so the I was incrementing one by one.
Let me let me do it again.
You guys did you guys observe the change?
Why the last condition was not executed,
By the way,
let me show you one more trick.
So let's say you are executing a code.
You executing a code.
And that code, it involves
many, many loops
before you reach your specific case.
Does mean
that you have to go through all the steps.
Like, for example, in our case,
we want to see the result of our test
and yes, we do that Position number six,
I have go through first
five iterations of the loop
during the debug process
and then only I can check out the business
for our test ending.
So here is a neat trick.
If your iterations
the involves thousands of I feel loops,
they involve thousands of iterations,
what do you guys can do?
You can right click on your debug blank
and you can place a condition.
So when you want to stop this loop.
So let's say, for example,
I want to stop this loop when,
when the value either
equal to equal to two.
Now I don't need to go through
the first two steps to check the results.
And now this loop will stop,
will be stopped at iteration number two.
So we don't care.
We can skip thousand
first thousand vibrations.
I want to skip and I want to check
the results for iteration number 1001.
I can also do that.
Does it make sense, guys,
if you are debugging a code
and that would
involve a thousand self iterations
and you want to check out the result of of
maybe the last vibration.
If you are not using
the debugging process, let me show
you first,
let me show you by doing it manually.
So let's say if I wanted to check the test
and you result, how can I do that?
I have to go through first vibrations.
So I have to do this, this, this.
I have to wait.
When will be the test and you coming?
Okay. Selenium. Selenium.
I have to click multiple times.
Multiple times.
Finally I see testing right.
Okay. So
and then if I don't want to do that,
I want to directly jump to this iteration
when the value I is three.
So what I can do, I can right click,
I can say there, take out intelligence
only stop this loop
when the value of I is two.
And now if I debug discord
you see I directly start my debugger.
This is starting from gate.
It has skipped SDLC,
it has skipped manual testing,
it has skip to Java
and now I see my debugging in here.
Why too?
Because I want to check the results
for digression.
How many of you have got a
how many of you have understood
the benefit of this?
Okay, I will show again. Don't worry,
it does not matter.
You can stop it at any iteration.
Yes, we tell where to start the debugging.
Skip the first 500 iterations.
Yes, they will be skipped.
You don't have to click
multiple times the end and again and again
to reach the iteration number 5000.
It's very useful.
Very, very useful when debugging loops
and why to
to go to class and because it is adjusting
your size dynamically.
Hasim Because the list is only testing
So the will be all acquisition
number, iteration
number two,
I will show you it with another one.
Okay.
Let me do it manually.
The longer we're
there is nothing and we cannot skip
any operation.
Let's do it. The manual.
Let me skip this
for for good guys.
Whatever I have showed you in last
five units, forget about Netflix. It's
I will show you
the benefit of this debugging.
What if it is about asking the interview?
So I will show you it with another example
here.
This size is being understood dynamically,
so it will be harder for you to grasp
this concept.
I understand that.
Don't worry,
I will show you with another example.
So okay,
so I get the SDLC can't be forgotten.
It is recorded.
Okay, so I take the next iteration.
Okay.
Right now the value of AI is one.
This size is four.
So this size has been reduced to five.
If you guys see in here
again condition.
So we get it.
And now
for the next iteration.
So let me show this this subject
and dot size
is four, right?
And the value of AI,
you guys can see it from here.
The value of AI is three, right?
So, okay,
it is not showing that last step.
So this size for this selenium
after this GitHub
it it changes to three
and then three is not less than three.
So it terminates the loop
and it never checks
for this best ending. So
you guys might ask this that, Hey Oscar,
why don't you put less equal
to sign in here?
And if I do this.
Yes. Third place.
If I do this, I will be getting
an index.
So an index out of bounds
if I try to do that.
Okay.
And if I don't do this,
I am skipping this last element.
Because for this last element,
the value of AI
and the condition that this this objects,
it is returning.
They don't match
and the loop gets terminated.
Okay.
How many of you have understood this,
that why
this last entry is not being processed?
So let me let me try it and try to draw it
for for this iteration.
This size will be five or 30
and decide
this, this this less than equal to
so the size will return me
six the 1 to 3, four,
five six sides will return with six
and the value of I will be zero.
Right.
Let me try again here
then it be fixed?
Yes, there are so many ways to fix it, but
you guys will always be in trouble, right?
Because once the data changes,
your loop will break.
So maybe less.
Let's say at the last position
if I put an element
so add the second last position.
If I put an element
which is which has an size less than four,
then this loop it will work perfectly fine
because
for the last element,
the size will not be changed.
So let me first.
Right.
Okay, so I is zero in here.
Total sizes.
States, right?
Can we do a subject?
I so try to do all of these things
on your computer.
Okay.
So I am trying to teach you
that don't use loops.
Then you are changing this size.
Okay. Simple.
How many of you
just believe me that using the loops
when you are changing this size,
it cannot be problematic
and you should never use it.
That's what I am trying to explain this.
All I want you to say
if you guys believe me,
you guys that okay, we can move forward.
We believed until today is
So let me try one more time.
I was about to say
so after this iteration, the value of
I will be one
and the total size.
So after this iteration, guys,
the total size will be five, right
after this
I will be to
total size will be five,
I will be three.
Total
size is still five for this operation.
This is where the problem happens.
I will be four
and size will be reduced to four.
Also for this last element,
this condition will not hold true
because I four is not less than four.
Look, I still don't understand this.
Why this last element is being skipped
because now I is not less than four.
Right? Four is not less than four.
This condition is not holding
true anymore.
The loops they keep on iterating unless
and until only
if this condition that we write in here,
if this condition returns true
as soon as this condition returns
cause the loops they break, right?
They loops, they break right.
So that's
why the last element will be skipped,
because size is changing at runtime
and we
we didn't
change our condition with that size.
So what you guys can try
you guys can try one more thing.
Maybe you guys can try this.
Maybe store the size
in a variable first
and then use their size
inside.
This condition will change size and
we will be really size change at runtime.
Now. But really,
will this code work now?
No, it will not work
because is there any element
which is present at index number five?
I if I remove these two elements there
will be no element at index number five.
Now I will be getting an exception
index out of bound.
Let me let me show it again.
It's important guys. Let's try to focus.
So you see size is six, but in actual
the size of the error
list has been reduced to five four.
So when you will try to get to the element
index number five,
you will be having no element
at index number five because elements
have been removed
and the size is already being shrink
to four.
Okay, so you guys now understand
the frustration.
So it's not even easy to understand
why you why in this call is not working.
Well, that was my whole point.
It's not even easy to understand.
Now, you guys can imagine
debugging this code and trying to fix out
your behavior issue.
So the conclusion is please don't use lose
when you are changing this size.
When you are performing
any operation on the error list
that can change its size,
it can be adding the element.
If you are adding element inside a loop,
it can be problematic.
If you are removing an element,
it can also be problematic.
Whichever operation changes this size,
please don't perform
those operations inside the loops.
Okay.
And I
hope you guys will never try to do that.
I should say no.
And as in the sports general related
to these these these issues.
Okay.
Well, I am sure you brought the point home
with that
hour and half explanation.
So what do we do now?
Right.
I can not use the default loop.
I cannot use the Y loop.
I cannot use h loop.
So what can I use, right?
Or what can I use?
I can use something called iterator.
Okay.
I can use something
called as I played this.
Now what is this iteration?
So this iterator,
it's again an interface. It's
not closed for sure.
So this iterator,
it's an interface.
And we again
use the diamond operator in here.
We specify the data
type that we are dealing with
and we can create an object of this.
We can get an object of the class
that is implementing this iterator.
So if you guys look at this picture,
you see this table interface
early is super, super, very, very top.
That means this iterator will be present
in all the interfaces and classes in here.
Okay.
So for collections,
whenever you are using collections,
always, always to use I
if you are changing this size
so this hydrator,
it will be available everywhere.
So don't worry about this availability.
It is the topmost line in the hierarchy.
So and how can I get that each class,
like for example, this analyst class
they are implementing this iterator
interface which means to whichever method
I present inside this iterator interface,
they are implemented by all the classes.
So I can simply say
I can see
some dark start.
I and I will get the object of our trigger
from this method.
Is it okay guys, here's the top interface.
All the classes are implementing
this interface so I can get the object
of this iterator from any of the class
and I can float inside this interface.
Is it clear?
Okay.
So now how this iterator works?
This iterator has three methods.
So the first method is
iterator.
Dot has the next word.
This map meter does
iterate through.
If there are elements
inside this ArrayList.
So for example, if I have your discord,
I will be getting a true
okay.
And if I want to get out the ops,
if I want to get out the elements,
you with the help of this iterator,
I say our iterator dot
iterator dot
next.
Then it will return me the element
which is present at first allocation.
So I get through.
There are elements. I get SDLC forward.
This has next to again, it just tells you
if there are any elements
inside the iterator download.
So what what is happening in here?
You guys can think of it like this.
I treated yesterday from that structure
and when you call this iterator method
all the elements from the list,
they are kind of copied.
They are not copied in actual,
but they are kind of copied
inside of this iterator.
Okay.
And the pointer,
it is index number minus one.
This is zero. And this one.
So initially the pointer
is at index minus one.
When we call this this next method,
this pointer is mode one location ahead
and it returns as the element
that is present at the location.
Therefore,
why we get to this SDLC, because it was
first element
and if I call the next method
one more time,
the pointer will be moved in here.
If I call the next method three times
we should get any elements.
Guys.
No. Right.
Because I have consumed all the elements.
So if I repeat this code
so I am
I am taking if the if the pointer if it
is still at the last location or not,
if there are still elements left or not,
it will return me to.
Then I call the next matrix.
The pointer will move one location ahead
and then I again check
if there are any elements. So
can you guys tell me what this hasn't
last has?
Next will return me
once I have consumed both of the elements.
So the table true Still true or false?
So I get through.
I get the SDLC again, go through,
I get malware testing.
But last night try to check
if there is a third
element present or not.
Is there any third element?
No. So I will be getting it false.
So can I write a loop with this?
Has an extra method
with this has an X method.
Cannot write a loop.
So as far as there are elements
in the list, I will be getting through
and add as soon as I am,
I am done consuming all the elements.
I will get that false
so I can use this as a condition
inside a loop.
Oh, I am not immune to that.
Don't use the loop without the iterator
with the iterator you guys
can use the loops because that dynamic
or adjustment of size,
it will be taken care of by this hydrator.
Okay, so it's kind of that
that structure that is
that is handling this size
dynamically at runtime.
So let let let's let me first complete.
So if there are no elements
and I tried to call this next method
again, okay, if there are no elements
and I try to call the next method again,
I will be getting an error.
Okay. No such element exception.
So is it here how this treat
how these two methods are total?
They are working.
So let me do this. If
if if
I say let's say maybe.
Oh okay.
If I check
that there are any elements or not.
And after that, if
I try to remove an element, okay.
If the wide type
so I checked
if there are any elements or not,
after that
I call to remove the element.
Okay.
And then I am
calling the next method again.
Will I get any other guys
if I execute the code?
So I got the first element,
so I to one element
and I remove the other element.
So I have already consumed two elements
and there were total two elements, right?
And now I am trying to get the third one.
Okay, let me check why we have.
Okay.
Sorry, sorry, sorry, let me do this.
So what is happening in here?
I got this SDLC in here and this
were testing in here.
So this next method,
what the next method is doing.
So initially the pointer is in, here
it is index number zero,
and it is index number one.
When I call the next method,
you can think of it like this
when I call the next method
in here,
it will move the pointer in here
and it will grab me.
So in this SDLC will be stored
inside this, this, next.
And when I check
the has an next
because there is still one element in here
I get true when I call this remove method.
It is actually removing SDLC. Not.
Yes it is removing the the the element
which was previously stored inside it,
not the menu testing.
If I have to remove the men were testing,
I have to call this next method
one more time.
Then it will move the pointer in here
and this will contain manual testing.
So I think it will be clear
in this way. So.
So what I am doing, I am calling
this has the next returns through.
I got the next element, which is SDLC.
First element first I am calling the next,
then checking has next returns be true.
Then I am removing element from this list.
Right?
So now if I execute this code,
I should still see manual testing
in my list because the last element
that was stored back was grabbed by next
and next method was SDLC.
So there is still one element
present inside my list.
So this removal method,
it actually works on the memory off
next method,
whatever is returned by the next method.
Last time.
If we call the remove method
after the back,
it removes that element,
not the current element.
Is it clear days?
So if I want to remove the manual testing,
let's say
if I want to remove the manual testing,
what should I do?
I should say
I prefer
not the next one more time.
Now next element
will grab the manual testing
and it restored it inside in here.
Okay.
And now if I call the remove method,
which element
I should see in my output guide?
I see SDLC because last time
I called the next method
it was manual testing.
So so this line to start from minus one.
It gives every time we call
the next method, it
moves to the next location and it stores
the previous element inside it.
Okay.
Well, you can you can say that it keeps
the pointer at that location still.
And when we call the police
this next method and remove method of
they are interlinked.
Whatever you have
got from calling the next method.
If you call the remove method
after the back,
it will remove that element.
So grab the element from the operator
one by one,
whichever is the element
that you grabbed last from the list.
And after that
if you call remove, remove that element,
it is clear
yes has an X
and does not remove the pointer.
There is no way to and the pointer.
There is another type of iterator
which can move in both directions.
You can move it forward
and you can move it backwards.
So let me
I don't know if you guys will be confused
or not.
It is called
I think it is called a list Hydrator.
Yes, this one.
So this list I created,
it can move in both directions.
So it is only for assignment guys.
Notably it is only for assignment.
So string or typewriter.
You see it has a previous,
so it has a previous next index
and a previous and previous index.
The method to move in
more to do that actions.
So we did.
We do not discuss this list. Right. Okay.
Imagine we never did this. So
let me let me show you more examples. Yes.
So this has a next it tells you
if there are any elements
left inside this iterator,
this next method.
On the other hand,
it goes inside of that typewriter,
one by one, grabs the elements and move
the pointer one location ahead.
And this remove method,
it actually keeps track of that pointer.
So let me explain.
I think it will make more sense
if I explain
all of this in terms of pointer.
So guys, let me try one time. So
so this is my list
to remove.
We should always call
after calling be next.
Yep, yep, yep.
You are right.
So if I say so, I have.
So let's say if I am not calling the next
and if I directly call the remove
I will be getting
an add of the addresses.
Yes. Let me read this
look and fail for multiple reasons.
It depends on the data.
You are right.
So If I try to call
this illegal state argument,
if I try to call remove directly, we
we are about the pointer guys
in the first vibration.
If I have not call the next method,
the pointer applies to index minus one.
Right.
Is there any element present
at minus one? No.
Then how can I try to remove that element?
Right.
How can I try to remove that element
first we should move the pointer
to proper location
by calling the next method.
Then only we can remove this element.
Right.
So when commented this out,
the next method
and I directly called to remove
the pointer was at minus one.
So I got an add. It.
I got an active
if I want to remove
the element on index float
so I have to call the next four times
then say remove.
Yes but hard.
You are right.
Yes. Yes you are right.
So if I want to remove.
So now you guys will tell me
if I want to remove SDLC.
SDLC which code I should write?
No index.
The next
method should be called four times.
So you see
when we call the next method once
we are will be deploying. Right.
So let me explain.
Give me just one moment.
Maybe you are right.
So when I called the next method
and here we are will be the pointer.
The point
at which index the pointer will be
it be in here, right?
It will be in here.
And now if I call the remove element
which which element should be removed.
The element that is present at location.
How many of you are confused
with this example?
I can look
actually let me do this.
Okay.
Is it clear now
let me remove this as well.
Okay.
So as the next.
Okay, let me now try it again
in this is manual testing, okay,
blah, blah, blah.
So initially the pointer is in here
and you guys just have to keep
you guys just have to understand
one thing.
This pointer is only
and only moved
when you the next method their state
and at whichever location
this pointer will be.
Once you call the remove method,
it will remove that
and it always starts
at location of minus one.
Yes, yes. Just focus on these two points.
So this pointer is only moved
when we call the next method.
So right now the pointer is at minus one.
So if I call the remove method in here
after this line, will I get any other
or I can show you
the value of our territory as well.
Okay.
Okay you guys, let me let me show you
the value of our territory as well.
The pull the value of pointer.
I didn't It's a good point, actually.
You guys will be able
to visualize it more.
So if I debug this application, you guys
will be able to see any blind as well.
So if I expand my window
and you will see
once I move to the next step,
the iterator is declared in here.
So in here
you guys see this?
This minus one,
the last odd oddity.
You see this?
Observe this. What happens to this one?
No, no, no.
It is actually
the iterator is internally actually
implemented in the same way
the way I am explaining it.
Okay.
You see this last read
minus one. So
focus on this.
This what happens.
So if I call head next, you see,
nothing has changed.
Last check is, still minus one, right?
Expected mode count is still two.
Right.
And as soon as I call this
next, you guys see
the last threat has changed to zero,
which means the pointer
has moved to location number.
Okay. Does move to location number.
What is present at location number zero,
guys, DLC is present.
Right?
So when I will be calling
the remove method,
which which element should be removed?
The SDLC. Right.
Because it is present at location
number zero and my right is at zero.
So if I call this remove you guys see
the size has changed at runtime.
SDLC is gone
and now I only men who are testing.
Now tell me if some of you are still
confused about this next or has next.
I remove.
So I should tell me the line number
which is confusing you.
So when we say next
so remove has a dependency on next
remove has a dependency on next.
So if I draw this,
my operator has two values
and the pointer
starts at location number minus one.
When this this pointer
which is pointing to minus one right now
it only and only changes
it only advances once.
I call this next method
and add whichever location is pointer is
is present at that moment.
If I call the remove method
at whichever location
this pointer, it will remove that element.
So if I call this remove method
right now, right now I am on location
index number minus one.
Which element should be removed
or should I get an error
by understanding SDLC?
Why is your understanding SDLC
at index number minus one?
What is present
index number two minus one?
This is the index zero.
This is the index number one.
No, no.
I am saying if I don't call this next,
if I don't call this next.
If I don't call this next
and I directly try call this move.
And if I call the next method first
and then I call the remove method.
So this next method, it
will also ask the pointer to this location
and then it will remove SDLC.
So I show will tell us the call.
Now what should I do
if I want to remove testing
and not SDLC?
What should I write?
I want to remove SDLC after removal.
Next again
before, before remove or after emotion.
I call the next method
before remove or after remove.
If I want to retain SDLC
and want to remove manual testing,
so I should call this next
slice.
And now the pointer will be at location
at index number one.
And now if I call the remove method,
it will remove the element
at that location location.
So now I see
SDLC and manual testing is gone.
Yeah,
when we're testing is gone.
Is it clear now?
Is there anyone who is still confused?
Okay, now let's try to use this operator.
Now let's try to use the typewriter
for the last example.
So in the last example, I guess
it was this one. No,
it was this one.
This one. Right.
And here
we were trying to remove best ending.
Now let's try to do that
with the help of left.
Maybe I should remove this.
Let's try to do that
with the help of our iterator.
Well,
no, no, no.
Okay.
So what I will do, I will always whenever.
Right.
I will be changing the size of the error
list.
Whenever I will be performing an operation
that can change size, I will always use
iterator and I will always use iterator
with y loop.
Yes, Farhad, you are. You are right.
So what I can do, I can get in idea later
virtualize specify inside Daniel bracket
s model and let me show you
how we can use that next.
And it has an x
spring, right?
Because my list is of types things.
Right right.
Later is equal to
how can I get the iterator
subject got.
I tried the
and then I can write a y loop
so I can say why?
What should I put inside
the condition? Guys
remove next on has next
as an exit.
As far as there are elements
present, keep on iterating
and if I want to get
the element which method I should call
next, remove or has next.
So I should say iterator dot next.
And if the size
of element
is greater than four,
how can I remove that element? Guys
by saying I prefer not remove?
And after this,
if I print out the size
I will be getting
only SDLC java
and you guys see the difference.
When we were trying
do the same thing with for Loop,
we were not getting the proper results
when we tried before each loop,
we were getting an exception,
but we use iterator with the y loop.
Now the results are but a fact.
We don't care about that dynamic size
changing thing.
And let me you one more beautiful thing.
It is lambda.
The next thing that I am going to show
you, they are the lambda expression
you can replace all of this code
with a single line
with the help of lambda expression.
Oops, you guys still needed.
So I am planning to show you
lambda
so this whole line can be replaced.
You don't need to confuse about this
at all.
Fine What is happening in here?
A press all can enter
the first one comment and show the short
one please.
If not make problem again.
Okay,
so you guys can do this as well.
You can.
You can solve this in single and
this is the beauty of Lambda expressions.
So I will be getting the same results, but
with a single line of code,
Lambda expressions can reduce
your complete classes to a single line.
In some cases.
So if I had time, I will show you
how to use Lambda expressions.
And if you guys have patience,
patience, all entries always so always.
Whenever intelligence
giving you a suggestion,
let's all enter and intelligible write
the code for you
the proper code that a good professional
developer should write intelligible
show you that code
if you are doing something wrong.
Same format just options. Enter
then you do the same.
Does it make sense now?
Okay, so
this is how we use iterator.
So only use our operators
when you are performing thinking of it
when you performing an operation
that can change
the size of the edit list
in those scenarios,
use purpose
to do it.
Move to the next example.
Or do you guys have any questions?
I think it is simple.
Now, once you understand that
how to remove the elements,
I think we need a break.
Okay, let's have a break
and remind me about the recording.
If I forget
to repeat what is the why condition
and if are doing so while is checking
if there are any elements
left in the iterator
and if condition is checking
if the size of each element
that we are getting one by one in here
if desired.
If the length of the number of characters
are more than four, if it is the case.
So remove that element.
Otherwise keep on looping.
You you guys can convert
to lambda expression.
If you have your mouse over this
yellowish line,
it will say replace loop with collection.
Start remove work.
Eliminate which one?
So right now I will recommend you
to use this approach later on once
I have taught you
about lambda expressions,
then maybe you guys can start
using lambda expressions.
So. Right, right.
Now let's use this one.
Eliminate which one?
The elements
which are greater than which are having
a let's get rid of them for.
So with the help of lambda expressions
and collections, you can eliminate
completely almost in every scenario,
you guys can remove the loop
loop conditions
if health conditions and all that,
and you can convert your five
or ten lines, 10 to 1520 lines
in a single line, you can convert
your code in some scenarios.
So that is
why with
three elements in that output, yes,
it is the same example that we were
trying to do with the for loop.
Are there
other questions?
I am only confused why maybe men
were testing it and aren't there?
What is this kind of manual testing idea?
How many characters are there
in manual testing?
Have you got it?
If it is more than four characters,
I am saying remove those elements
right?
I think No, no, no.
We are taking the side of this.
These characters,
even they are more than four.
We are removing them.
So Assignment
B, the purpose of Lambda Expressions
is to reduce the amount of code
that you have to write.
SIMON Is it clear the purpose of Lambda
expression is to reduce
the amount of code that we have to write?
I will.
Once I teach you about Lambda expressions,
it will be more clear, don't worry.
Right now, just
just think about this
line is not for this time.
There is no line.
There is no line
for you in here.
Okay, so
58, Let's come back by 15. Yes.
Pretend you guys don't see.
It's only for those who understand.
Oh, let me check
what else we are missing.
13 all contains I tried to clear.
All right,
Now, the point that we were discussing
yesterday
get our collection was non genetic before
JDK 1.561.5.
It is generic Java.
New generic collection allows you to have
only one type of object in collection.
Now this type save.
So typecasting is not required at runtime.
So now let's discuss
some properties of list.
So this
time this list interface.
There are these three classes at alias
link place
vector instead and the edit BQ
well which are implementing
this list interface.
So what will be the properties?
These
these classes
will get from this interface?
So first the list it allows to store
duplicate objects
you guys will learn in the next class.
Or maybe to date there are data structures
which don't allow us to store duplicate
objects.
Well, we have a week last fall on Monday.
Yes, I will do the review
so at least
we can store the elements inside the list
and the list.
It maintains the order.
Engagement of the order.
The order in which
I am inserting the element when I will be
printing out the element or I will be
getting the elements and using a loop.
I will be getting the elements
in same sequence in same order
list may contain duplicate elements.
Elements can be inserted
or accessed by the opposition
in the list using a zero based index
listed in order to collection
that can contain
duplicate elements.
I think we are required. Yes.
List is one of the most
to use collection type,
so these are some classes
we will be discussing these two classes.
So what is the difference
between these two classes?
So in ADD is the element.
They are stored
in consecutive memory locations, but
in this second class that we are,
we will now discuss
this is called the link list in here.
The elements, they are not stored
in consecutive memory locations.
So let me ask you this, guys.
Let me ask you this. If
if in a society
I let's say
you do the need addresses to be called E.
S moment.
So let's say in a society
I have maybe let's say 100 houses
and all of these houses,
they are consecutive to each other.
And there is this label
outside of their house that
this is house number one,
two, three, four or five and so on.
And they are all in a straight draw
connected to each other.
If I know the address of House number one,
can I reach to House number 100
without asking anyone
if they the items I could do each other?
Okay. So it's super easy, right?
I can go to any house number,
but if I have to insert
a new house in between,
what do I have to do?
Can I do that?
Only if I have to
demolish.
All right.
And then reconstruct all in all the case
in areas once we have stored the data,
the data is stored
in consecutive memory locations.
And if we have to insert a new element
in between, we have to shift
towards
the right
and then only we can insert the data.
In simple words, we have to demolish,
let's say we want in certain
and new house at location number 50.
I have to demolish all the houses
from either side.
Right?
And then I can insert the new element to
build the houses again, label them again.
So this is same as inserting an element
inside the added inside to be added.
But we also get a benefit from
this add is right is super easy
to find some hard some any of the houses
but what is the drawback?
It is very very expensive.
Insert something in between
or to remove something from in between.
Now these are linked list.
Then they follow this approach.
The houses,
they are scattered all over the society.
And if I have to go to house number two,
I can only go to house number two
if I know its exact location
on some kind of map or if I know the path.
And that part it is
in house number one.
So I have to go to house number one.
I have to call them.
I have to ask them that.
Hey guys, can you tell me the location,
the the location of house similar to once
once I know the location, number of two,
I can go to house number two
and then if I have to go to house number
three first, I have to go to house
number two, I have lost the location
of house number three.
So the locations, they are remembered
by the previous houses.
In the second case, this link list,
it exactly follows that approach.
If I have to reach to the element e
first I have to go to element,
then I will ask element E about element B,
then element C and D,
and then only I can go to E.
But what is the flexibility that I get,
I can now insert any element in between
and I just have to upgrade the House
member.
Let's say I want to insert
element number Z in between.
I only have to read out,
I only have to obtain this information
back, Where is this house?
So I only have me there.
Tell me now
if someone asks you about the next house
instead of telling them the address of C,
tell them the address of Z.
So I get this flexibility.
I can now insert any house in between.
I can remove any house from in between.
The only thing that I have to do is to
and just the point of
is to re address the addresses
that make sense.
But now the traversal is slow.
If I have to reach to the last element,
I have to go through all the elements
before back and then only I can reach
to the last element.
Right?
If I want to go to the last house,
I first have to go to house number one.
No, there I have lost the address there.
Hey guys, can you tell the address
of the last house?
They will say
we don't know about the last element.
The only thing that we know
is the address of the next.
So at Max, we can only tell you
the address of next house.
Okay, Then we will say, please
tell us the House address of next member.
We go to the next member, ask the address
of the next member to that.
And then we keep on doing, doing,
doing this again.
Eventually we will be at the last index.
So link list, they are super, super good.
If we have to insert something in between,
if we have to remove
something from in between,
but then downsize is down
is they are super super slow to traverse.
So linked list is more flexible
but slower than a normal list. Yes.
And you are right.
So tell me guys, if I am
if I know that I will
never be inserting any element in between
and I know that 90% of the times
I will be accessing the elements
from a data structure.
Should I use a link list
ought to be at list, Yes.
So I should always use the array list
because they super, super fast
when it comes to accessing the elements.
And if I know that 90% of the time
I will be inserting
and removing the elements in between
and only maybe 10% of the time,
I have access to these elements.
So I use an ink list, or at least
then I should use the link list.
Exact same methods
which are present in charge.
The list list.
They are also present
inside the link list.
The only difference is
how are implemented internally.
Okay.
And and I have explained that in here.
So all the methods
which are present in the array list,
they are also present inside the link
list.
But the only difference
is in how they are implemented internally.
So if I say
link list
or demo one, so this is how I can
I can declare all English.
So link list
or let me actually copy this
from the previous one.
So I only need to change this class
to link list.
And that's it.
That's it.
I need the main method.
Okay, here we go.
The exact same from top, same
same results, everything.
You say them, but they will differ
in the way how you are using them.
There can be a very bad performance impact
if you are not using the proper
data structure.
So first you should have the knowledge
that to how your program will be here.
You should have the knowledge of domain,
the type of data that you will be dealing,
and then you choose the proper
data structure and then you write
the program using back
and data structure in the database.
So normally whenever we have to access
the elements more,
then updating those elements
whenever, we
have all of the elements
still stored from zero one.
Yes, everything is same indexes,
same all the same
The differences in because you see
the both classes, the link list
and the analyst
they are both implementing.
They are both implementing this list
interface
to all the methods that you guys saw.
First, they were actually coming
the list interface, but this linked list,
it is additionally implementing this BQ
and this you as well.
So you see additional methods as well
inside of the linked list.
Okay, I will show you.
Let me first check how much
we have before level.
So add remove index
all if you guys already know that in
SA it contains the you guys only
you guys only don't know
about the first method.
So let me show that as well.
So let's say
I want to replace this job
with something else.
So this is Java.
Presenter 201 second index, right?
So if I
print out subjects,
you guys will see.
Okay,
so Java is present at index number two.
If I want to replace this java
with something else,
I can use this type
method, I have to specify the index,
the index
at which I want to replace the element
which
so let's say next number to it.
And then the element
that I want to replace
may be by a ton.
And now if I print this out, Lazy
Java has been replaced
with Python is a clear case.
You see.
So still I am using a
I am right now using a link list.
So let's check if all the methods are
present inside of the link list or not. So
it is.
But I learned settings descending.
I don't need to worry about add add
all clear size
so we have this additional
method does not add first and last.
So if you want to insert an element
and add the first location
of the list, you can call the add first.
How can we achieve this
same thing inside of the earliest days?
If I want to insert the element add
index number zero, can I do that?
Java is on index number, but
when you put in it is index number three.
How not?
No, it is still on index number two, SDLC
index zero, manual testing
number one by tone index number two.
But how do you see it at index
number three?
Okay, link list, behave the same way off
and edit list when you use the shared
method inside the list. Yes.
So from the perspective of writing,
because you guys will not see
any difference.
The difference is in the
in the final performance.
So if I have the element or the location
number first,
I can call the add overloaded
method
in which I can pass the index to that.
Right.
So it's just they have created
a separate method in here.
Contains again, same exact pattern
element is present or not.
Got to get the first get last index off.
So they are all so many methods.
Start out by the end here.
Okay.
But all the methods that we have learned
in the Analyst Day are also present
in dealing for the list.
Okay. It is just because
how to look at it.
As you guys already know, our iterator
identity is used for protecting
the classes in the collection framework
we use.
And I tried to create the elements
of the collection classes.
The effect is that an interface
arbitration can be done only once
if you reach the end of series it's done.
If we need to iterate again,
we should get a new art.
Now what does this mean?
This means
there,
this arbitrator that I am getting in here.
I can only use it once, once
I have used it
after
if I try to reuse it again.
So let's say I petered out next.
If I try to do that,
if I tried to do that, the pointers
and all that, they will still be behaving.
They will keeping this history
and I should create a new arbitrator.
Is it clear, Dave Thereby I am saying that
I should, if I want to start
the arbitration from beginning,
I want to perform some more operations.
I should either I should
get a new
straight up.
Okay.
The three methods in the iterator has an x
and x
and remove
these audio or tasks
in order to start the process class
so at least works as a link list.
ArrayList is the best
alternative to add is in
Java as ArrayList is dynamic
data structure.
So right now
we are discussing Arrays and ArrayList.
It is are they starting data structure?
And it can contain both primitive,
primitive objects,
but ArrayList can only
objects.
No primitives are allowed in case of
ArrayList, you can use length variable
to calculate the length of an array,
but size 30 is used
inside the additive,
and it uses the assignment operator
for the assignment
and those square brackets
to access on up to the elements.
But in at least
we have add or remove method
and it can be multi dimensional.
While the error list is always
single dimension, but we can have areas
of arrays.
Do you guys want to learn
how to the arrays?
Looks like?
Okay,
if the array inside
and another a yes,
sometimes you guys might need them.
Okay on the request of
same and dummy.
Here we go.
Are you as ready to get confused
as everything to confuse us
till the end of the course.
Okay.
So if you have
so many lists right, and you want to store
instead of floating string or number
or boolean or character,
if you want to store a list inside
another list,
so you write array list
and diamond operator.
And then inside the diamond
operator, you again write
array list and again diamond operator.
And then you write the actual data side.
This will be in
and this will be an array of ArrayList
like this.
And now instead of adding a string
or a number or two,
you guys can do a list of early start,
and now you can add a complete list
inside another layer.
So for example, subject
oops depth
to three.
I think it's easy is not an easy, nice
list of lists like to date is
it? Sales marketing.
What I am just stating.
So this is how we can create
a list of list
and we can create a list of list
of list of list of list.
We can go as deep as we want.
Is it clear, guys,
or should we get back to this nice.
Not clear.
Okay.
So it was only if I made nested list.
And who else asked about this?
It was only for possible
and the meet and see.
Okay.
This has never happened
for the rest of you.
So think of
just so let's
say you have a box and inside
that box
let's say
there is this box
previously what you guys were doing
when you were creating the list,
you were placing strings.
The inside of him in here, right?
String one string, two.
But now what you guys are doing
instead of
putting strings directly.
So this is this is one that
at least it contains strings.
Then there is a lot
less than if there is a list.
Then there is another list.
And now you are putting all those lists
inside and other list,
and you can put those lists inside
and other list as well if you want.
Like this.
It's a nesting list inside
and one another.
Once you show us there is no going back.
Okay,
I will not show you as well from now.
So link list is a class so question.
We are just jumping from one to another.
It makes us confused.
Jumping from bear to where?
You mean drying and slides
and the
end to use for loop for that nesting.
So question how long list are structured
is a structure assumed
by adding a second ArrayList to be all
you guys want to check the structure?
They are
structured with the help of
Node North.
So in the link list we have a special data
structure that is called.
So this is how to link list
and they are implemented
internally.
So inside this middle box we put the data
in for the first element.
Can you possibly edit list inside
another list code or so it again is like
just give me on
the first element will be null.
The next element will find
to the next block.
In here we will store the data
and then this will point to the next block
in here again, tie in here.
Then it will point to
this is how it is structured. Mean
with the help of nodes.
Okay, here is the list of
another list.
Next lists.
Are you guys good?
Should we move?
Don't worry too much about the
about this
nested is
so link
list to the class which implements
the list interface of collection framework
like at least link list also can contain
duplicate elements
and also maintain the insertion order.
We can declare the link list
same way as the ArrayList
and perform operations
like insertion and deletion.
There they are. Same as ArrayList.
The only difference in
at least in English, is the list.
All the elements
in a doubly linked list of data structure.
The data structure
that you have just drawn.
While
ArrayList
stores the elements in a backing adding
so array uses internally and added
but linked list uses
a separate data structure for doubly
linked list
so when to use which
arraylist internally
uses dynamic area to store the elements
linked list uses doubly linked list
manipulate with arraylist manipulation
with the array list is low
because internally uses arrays,
one element is removed from the array.
All the birds are shifted in memory.
Remember that example of how
you have to shift everything?
Indicators of arrays
Manipulation
with the linked list is faster than arrays
because it uses the list of no base
shifting is required.
We just reported yesterday point us
ArrayList
can act as a list
only because it implements implement list,
but linked list as list and a Q bullet
because it is implementing
most the interfaces
array list is better for accessing data
linked list is better for storing
and removing
adding It maintains
index is an element that are linked.
List contains elements
that bind to pointers for neighboring
north
and the memory is high in the linked list.
Comparatively.
Okay, these are your next tasks.
Now this first
serves.
They are very simple.
All is a all is very simple.
Okay.
Not simple.
So the on the three can use
trendy calls for the link list.
It is better if I push this code.
Will you guys be able to
get the call from GitHub
etc.?
Simple will start
and then you can feel this.
So the first class we discussed
was ArrayList.
Then we discussed the list, same
as the released
only difference in the performance.
The next class is the
hash set.
Okay.
And this hash set
the now we are discussing these classes
start interface.
I started certainly a certain precursor.
So Head Start Diamond and operator string
I certainly towards the new hash sec
so hash
said dot add.
So this add method is also available
inside the high set.
And let's say I inserting a file
has said not add
and then
mangle
hash cert
not add dv
asset not add
epilog in
set not add
apple again.
So the property of self is that guys
they don't allow duplicate elements.
Okay.
If I tried to print out this hash sir,
I am trying to insert the apple
three times,
but in the output I will see it only what?
Yeah.
So first was apples
right to make it.
That would.
Yeah.
So Apple TV and mango.
So start link list we can store
duplicate elements linked list.
They maintain the order.
You see
the order is also not maintained in here.
First I inserted the apple.
I see the second I inserted the mango.
But I see added position number three.
I should see it at in here in link list.
If you are trying to insert this element,
you will see it in the same location.
So for example, if, if I change this to
link list
how many elements
I will see you guys.
All of them.
Right?
Because in list
I can store all the elements.
No issues with the list.
So Apple and you do see the order.
If I am inserting the apple first,
I see the apple first.
If I am inserting the mango second,
I see it as second position.
Give me kiwi, apple, apple.
But these two properties,
they don't hold
for the hash effect.
And this is the difference
between a certain and increased
link list maintains
the order allows duplicate
why I start changes the list order does
set prints in alphabetical order.
Let me change you.
They really want to learn
why the order is not maintained.
So it is not maintained because
internally this hash
that is using a special type
of data structure that is called hash.
Now Latasha is doing hash
stored
the elements inside your memory
in such a way
that once you give the input for hash,
either function
in which you give some kind of input
and the output, it will give you
the exact memory, location of that element
where it is stored.
So for example,
if there are a million memory locations
inside the RAM and I want to search,
if is present inside the memory or not,
I will adjust inside this apple
to a special function
and that function will return me
a memory address.
I will directly go to the memory location
and I can check
if that that is present or not.
Does it happen
the same way in the address guys?
Or I have to look through
all the elements in the areas
if I have to find an
element is present or not inside the area,
can I?
How many elements I have to compare?
I am how many elements I have to check
all right there.
So I will buy three.
So this hash function
and these hash cells,
they have this special property
that something is super, super fast.
And we will combine this searching benefit
with another thing
and we will learn about maps
that if you have to perform searching,
you will be those maps
and those maps,
they will be super, super fast.
So each data structure
that we are discussing,
whether they are hash search
link list or released,
first, they are implemented
differently in the memory
and they all have some kind of benefits
over the other.
Now, choosing proper data structure.
Now what what you have to do
as a programmer, you have to as per
your needs, do you have to choose
a proper data structure
and then the program
using that data factors.
So the performance is good.
Otherwise you can almost achieve
everything with this.
Simply simply with the atlas.
Does Does it make sense?
Great
to have says super, super fast
if we have to search something,
but what is the downside?
They don't maintain the order.
They don't allow duplicates.
Disorganized, yes,
but they are super, super fast insulting.
So if you know that your data
will never contain duplicates,
you can store them inside a set
and you can send to them very fast.
Genius, but just organized.
The issue is to understand
which one to use.
Yes, depending upon your needs, which one
we should use
link list, prep prints, all the elements.
But it does not. Oh, it is.
It is not printing because in
it is not storing these two elements.
As soon as it sees a duplicate element,
it will discard that.
It will not store that.
But there are other variations
of the high sets as well, which allow
many different things.
So let's say, for example,
if you want the order, if you still want
the benefit of fast searching,
but you want the ADD, then you can use
another type of
another type of set,
which is called link to the hash set.
So still, how do you print?
Because I change it to two linked list.
So if you guys want to maintain the order
and still don't want duplicates,
you can use
link the hair six.
They are very simple.
Right in link
bisect order will be maintained.
No duplicates.
These are it hard guys.
It's very simple.
So apple, mango and then kiwi.
Now you see the older guys in here,
the order is maintained.
For me, it's simple.
I mean, what is hard in this?
If you want the order
and not duplicate your list.
If no order not obligated to the high set,
if simple, I'm not ready to die.
And if
you guys want those for your elements
in alphabetical order,
we have a third type of set
that is called preset.
Right?
Again, very simple
to reset
what preset will do.
It will sort all your elements
in a specific order.
So if even if I insert elements like the
then if I think the last one,
the last one is six.
So if I say the x here
and if I print this,
what was the benefit of labor?
So it maintains the order.
It maintains the order.
So you see and it s enforced
and it don't allow duplicate.
So all the cells that you say linked to
the three said
said they will not allow duplicate.
This is the property
that is coming from first
now has
no order linked to high start order three.
I said 13 for example in here
we are sorting the elements.
I inserted that first text, then
and then there.
But in here I a z
with my vertical order in place after.
Yes, if you are splitting numbers
they will be sorted in numerical order
and you get a few regions right.
That suit that well the class.
So certainly the collection
that can't contain duplicate elements
there three main implementations of hash
linked hash and set.
So can I see certain demo two. Yes.
Yep. That's all.
Let me know.
And also once you are done
so third class
that implements that interface,
it does not allow duplicates,
does not guarantee any insertion order.
You just let me go through the
slides then you guys can go.
It allows null elements
or one more way
we can insert of the nodes as well.
Link the asset
class that implements
that interface does not allow duplicates.
So all these are will not allowed.
Okay.
And order is in the elements
is based on the order
in which they were inserted.
So if you are inserting something first
you will be getting that thing first
and then we have preset
is similar to hash start,
except that it sorts
the elements in ascending order.
While I started does not maintain any of
so I started the class
which implements certain interface
so it does not guarantee
any insertion order.
So it can be used in place
of at least to sort objects.
If you are require no duplicate
and don't care about insertion,
anybody else is confused or it is just me.
No me.
I am also confused, but
so assert
is the class we to implement
this self interface in java
have certain does not allow
does not have any additional methods
beyond those found in this set interface.
Now is the language
we are confusion about is
said does not guarantee
any insertion order
why we need high start
because laying to start looks perfect.
No link that is low in performance.
Head Start is more fast than the length
of the haystack.
Okay,
so it can be used in place of
do they?
We are all has said can be used in place
of at least to store the all elements.
If you don't care about the insertion
and you don't want duplicated
as there does not allow duplicate
the same thing
and later start
it maintains the order.
It is simplest implementation
of start interface again
same methods
which are present in this set.
I need to bring this again
on my computer screen for be working
all to be concerned.
Otherwise I will be lost.
When in doubt, throw a hash map
if yes.
And then you are right. Oh my God.
I don't like things that
that look like each other.
And then you show.
Then you should never visit China.
Because in China
everyone looks all Chinese.
If they are,
they are saying brothers and sisters,
right?
Hey said does not allow
duplicates and does not maintain the order
Link maintains the order does not allow
duplicate things at source
the elements alphabetically.
Yes, you are right.
And again, no duplicates.
And that's why they don't pay.
That's why they don't like.
I lived in China for three years. Wow.
I've been doing Java for link to high.
Said maintains the insertion order
Elements get started
in the same sequence
in which they have been added to this.
Checked
linked start achieves good
performance
by using a hash to store the object
in this part of the hash allows fast
lookup. So
this is just another example.
Restart
is simplest implementation of third place
does not allow
any additional methods of same thing.
So it does not allow
no and so is similar to start,
except it sorts
the elements in ascending order.
Bangladesh going to
this is an example.
These are some tasks, simple tasks.
Piece of cake
for you guys.
Okay, let's go to the next class as well.
How many are we giving us?
It's a lot.
They are just 20 to 25 slides
in the next class.
I need rest.
Very funny.
Not ready.
So, guys, to do your tasks, there is
one thing that you guys will be needing,
and their thing is
you can convert any collection.
So any class you inside,
inside their collections,
you can convert between one type
and other type by simply passing
that data to the constructor.
So let's say, for example,
if you want convert to this
hash, start to an error list.
You would just create an error list.
You will be requiring this in your tasks.
You you mention the same data type
and inside this constructor
if I boss hash said this has said
this is a
will now have all the elements from this
this has set and it is now
converted to it to an analyst.
So now I can use
all the methods from the analyst
and if I have to convert it
back to an asset,
I can create a new hash cert
like this,
a search tool.
And I can pass this ArrayList in here
so you can convert one type and other die,
but by just passing it inside,
the constructor
should be done before tomorrow's class.
Yes, try to do it,
but if you guys are unable to do it,
we can do it during the class as well.
If we continue in this space,
we will be able to cover
the rest of the Java classes today.
Yes, tomorrow.
And preview.
Yes. Oh.
Oh my God.
My mind is
is really not working to Sunday.
Okay, then you have the complete week
to complete this
task.
I talked to day Saturday
and we will be having
another class
tomorrow on Sunday.
So. All right.
I need to eat some fish
and take some medicine.
So sorry guys, if I have confused you,
but I will.
On the next feature it is class.
I will revise all of these concepts
and then I will give you more examples.
And you guys, by that time you will be
have gone to the tasks as well.
So everything will make more sense
for from in the next two. And
if something not clear in the next class,
then you guys can tell me
and we can spend more time on that.
But don't worry
if something has confused you today,
I hope it will not confuse
you in the next week.
Today was all about confusing us.
How you also confused
Too late.
All right. All right.
So a lesson D today
you are confused
about everything around me.
I don't remember to whom I am talking,
what I am teaching.
I don't remember anything
but tomorrow, Selenium
tomorrow is Java review.
And yes, it will be done by me.
No, that was not confusing.
Okay, I'm just getting in the next week
we will revise everything.
So don't.
Don't worry if something has confused you
or I am in love
for the last seven years, I will not.
Don't ask me what happened.
I feel better.
You learn, guys.
Take some of Bye bye.