They make any sense.
So I started and got bored.
Yep. Yep.
The students from previous
previous batches,
when they joined the companies,
believe me, they their brains.
How how,
how much they stood out from syntax.
Didn't know about Java and the industry.
So if you guys are
grabbing like 80 to 70 to 80% of Java,
you guys are doing great.
One thing about me,
I will be honest. Lied to lie.
Yep. Yep.
Is this last Java class the Sebastian
last regular Java class?
And now you guys will be
building the frameworks,
the actual products, the actual
meat, the actual heart of automation.
Let's do one more on January.
January 2nd.
Yes, Because of Christmas holidays,
I talk to the Apple guys,
but they are on vacations, so
they will get back to me on Monday.
No more baby boys and baby girls. Yep.
This should never end
like an infinite loop.
A new open calendar
review year.
They should keep Java at least once
a week.
Yes, I agree.
But there is no review class to model
for to be here.
Oh. Okay.
So this
today's drunk sex drive.
So we got the review class and we're in.
At what time all the David Review class
the same 710.
So time is missing.
I will update
availability time.
Is there anything else
or not by will you be not typing
because you will definitely be
writing code
if you are planning to work as back
engineer.
So we were discussing the exceptions.
Not like developers. Yep.
Actually the base is same.
The basics.
They are same for developers and testers.
It is the tools and the frameworks
that differ.
So for example, a developer might.
So for example, from here
you guys will be learning the best
indie and cucumber
a developer would learn.
For example, Springboard
or something like that from here. But
before this,
the basics, they are the same for both
developers.
They write a lot of
this topic.
We just stared.
Yup. Yup.
So can you guys tell me about exceptions?
What are they?
Why they are important.
They are classes
for atoms.
Knowing about that.
Can I ask you about previous class?
Yup. Can be built in.
So exception is.
And even that
the distro the
normal flow of
all program.
Right.
So can you guys tell me
about the normal flow of a program?
What do we expect from a normal floor?
Mean to
try and catch helps not point.
So even if let's say for example
if I have written maybe 100 lines of code,
the normal flow should be executing
all the lines of code
starting from line
number one to line number one.
Right.
And if anything goes wrong,
let's say maybe on line number 50,
then whatever that line 50
is doing,
that functionality should not work,
but the rest of the code,
it should still execute right.
So we discussed about the examples, like,
for example, if we are using Slack
and or some reason internet
gets disconnected, right?
So the slack should only show
maybe internet is not available
or trying to connect or any, any
and any simple error message
that everyone can understand.
Right.
Instead of showing
no point that exception
or some some kind of complicated error
that does not make sense for normal users.
What do we do
when we encounter any situation,
when we encounter these exceptions?
We convert them to simple error messages
that everyone can understand.
So the purpose of exception
handling is first to avoid
that abnormal termination
of the complete program.
So let's say, for example,
if we are trying to upload a file
to Google Drive using Google Chrome.
Right.
And if there is any issue with that file,
instead of completely
shutting down Google Chrome.
What do we say?
Maybe that file is not
the format of that file is not supported.
Or maybe there was an issue during the now
upload process of that file
or any other any other issue.
So we only
we we make sure that the
code that is causing the problem.
It does not
it does not make the complete program
shut down or terminate abruptly.
Maybe only that piece of functionality.
If that piece of functionality
is not working, then maybe we can just
show a simple error message
for only that specific part
instead of just
shutting down the complete program.
We created an Excel file with one value
How create with menu values,
for example, with Skynet.
So with scanners
for one, as we use the loops
to read multiple
rules and multiple columns, we can again
use a loop to create the multiple
all columns and multiple rows.
So for example, using the scanner class
first, do you have to store that data
or you can
insert it directly inside that Excel file.
So I will show you an example if you want.
So let's say, for example.
So let's do it
at the end of and end of today's class.
I think we will be done
with the exceptions around 2 p.m.
and then remind me
and then I will show you how to let's say,
for example, using the extender class,
we can insert
multiple rows of that.
Is it okay?
Prince Alexi No, no, no.
So these are exceptions.
They are more important
because you guys will not be inserting the
that in Excel files
using using this kind of classes
in your frameworks and everything else.
So let's do this part first
and then we will do that part as well.
Everyone is scared of rappel,
so that point to zero
nine is only for the mid Sorbonne
and omitted and anyone else
I like, for example, Allie.
We can do that, right?
Test out your lemurs.
It's not.
Not for you guys. Okay?
We already finished 209.
So an exception is an event which occurs
during the execution of program.
So they are the exceptions.
They are not syntax add as they are kind
of errors, but they are not syntax error.
They occur only at runtime
and when your application is in execution
and no offense, but this is rude,
I know we already finished 209
now what is the rule to zero nine?
You guys want to
unpublished
or make it easier?
Or what do you guys want instead?
It's fine.
So. So whatever. What is rude about this
that only the mirror
and for one can should cancel it.
This is rude.
Yes, please delete it.
Everyone has their own capability.
Yep. Yes.
It's.
I took a screenshot.
This is a reminder of what we do not know
about our knowledge.
So. And I have
what is rude about this. Yes.
Everyone has their own capability
as part to me.
You can't compare this students.
This is to be moralizing.
Oh no, this is not demoralizing.
So what do we do?
Let's say, for example,
when we created the exams,
when we created the quizzes
or everything else,
we divide it into different portions.
So some part of that portion of Apple
is for everyone,
then some is for the students
who are above average
and some are all fit
are for exceptional students.
Okay, So it does not mean
that anyone is inferior.
It's about how much effort and time
you guys are putting.
It's just funny. We all first, they're
not doing it.
So all the exams, quizzes
and everything,
they are purposely designed in this way.
Okay,
so don't worry about them.
Definitely.
There will be some parts
that everyone will not be able to solve.
The last bit Philosopher.
When he grew old
he said, I know, I now know that
I knew nothing.
All right,
so maybe
next time I will try to add some hints.
Maybe many of you were able to solve it.
Maybe a couple of people.
It's fine.
So there is one similarity.
Then we add these things so that you guys
don't tell in the interviews.
Hey, we know everything about Java.
We can solve everything so that we know
what we know and what we don't know.
To be celebrating this with this.
Apparently many. All
right, guys, then don't worry about it.
It's fine if you guys are unable to me.
So an exception is an event
which occurs
during the execution of the program.
So they are not syntax errors.
Yes, they are still type of errors.
It disrupts the normal flow. So what?
What do we mean by normal flow?
If we have written thousand line
500 lines of code, all of it
should execute normally line by line
starting from line one to like
the last line
of the program. Exception.
So exception is an event.
So exception
they are not something different.
Again, everything in Java, everything
in object oriented programing,
programing, languages,
they are all at the end of classes
and then we create the objects
of those classes and then we call
the methods on those objects
to achieve different functionalities.
You, you guys can control.
And the hardware is you guys
can connect to the Internet,
download files, build
games, control
your computers or laptops, hardware.
So they are all done
with the help of classes.
Okay, Everything in Java is the class
and there are
then methods inside those classes to maybe
say take the input from the keyboard
to let's say, maybe you play a video
on the screen to play a sound.
So everything
in Java is also a class.
So exceptions and the arrows,
they are also classes.
So when we encounter
a specific scenario in the code,
let's say we were trying to read a file
and maybe
the user didn't specify the correct part
or maybe the if someone deletes the file
from that part.
So then Java will go inside that folder
looking for that file.
It will not be able to find that file.
So in that scenario,
look, Java is supposed to do right?
So if you guys have not provided
any backup code
in the catch block
that follows, you don't mind me thinking
I know some Java.
So when you guys will realize
how much you don't know, then
I will prepare you for your interviews.
You guys will be surprised. So
what happens is that if we are
having that default the behavior
so the piece of code
that is trying to read that file,
all the code below that line,
it will not execute
the application, will terminate
right after that line
when he's trying to get that file.
And it is
it terminates the complete program.
So this is the default behavior
and we don't want this behavior.
So let's say
if we were trying to read a file
and that file is not found, maybe
we should print a message to the user
that,
hey, please
provide the correct path for the file,
or maybe the file is not found,
or maybe our application can try
to create new files, or maybe he can try
to download the file from the internet.
So depending upon your business
requirements your business needs, you guys
might have different backup plans.
If the plan work
plan is not working right.
So we want that behavior
in our applications.
So what do we do?
How do we tell the user that
something went wrong?
We have created so many different classes.
The exception handling and building
exceptions are also part developers.
Yes, but for our testers as well,
because in real life applications
there are so many things that can go wrong
right now.
You guys are executing your code inside
the IDE is intelligent, right?
So anything goes wrong.
You guys can just look at the error,
you can fix it.
But when you isolate your program
from intelligent execute in real life
environments, there are so many things
that can go wrong.
So we should be we should tell our
Java program how to handle those issues.
Okay.
It should know what to do
in a certain scenario
instead of
just completely shutting itself down
and just throwing at us
that no one can understand.
Easy.
So how do we tell that we encountered
an error in Java?
We could here
we have so far all types of errors.
We have
special classes in Java.
So for example, if
a file is not found,
there is a special class in Java file
not found exception.
The name of the class is file
And then we create the object
of their specific class
and we throw it using the throw keyword.
If we are trying to call a method
on null point, that exception on an object
we have null point the exception
separate class for that type of error.
If we are trying to access,
let's say maybe an index
and that index is out of bounds,
we have special class
for index bound errors.
If we are, let's say, trying
to give negative size to the address,
we have negative size
exception.
So all scenarios
they are thought well by Java guys
and they already
have created separate classes
in case those scenarios are encountered.
Why they did so make so that they kind of
have standard error messages.
And by looking at those error messages
so everyone is on the same page.
If you guys are getting an error of file
not found, they use a standard
and everyone knows that.
Okay,
something is not good about that file.
Maybe the box is not correct or the file
is not present on that specific part.
So what they didn't allow
is that everyone
just creating their own error messages.
Let's say maybe I am a developer
and maybe I can just simply print out
something went wrong with the port
and other developer.
He might print out.
It is not good and other developer
he might print out.
File is not wrong.
So instead of everyone having its own
error messages,
Java guys made it a standard
so that everyone is on the same page.
Everyone can quickly know what went wrong.
So when an exception occurs, the system
generates.
By system here we mean the Java.
Okay, the Java runtime environment
I saw system generates an error message.
We can manage this using exception
handler.
Now, they didn't only create the classes
for the errors,
they actually developed
a complete mechanism
to propagate that, add a right.
For example, it can happen that
I have written some piece of code
and then there is another developer
who has written some piece of code
and I am using his code in my code.
Right?
So if the piece of code
that other developer has written,
if that code is throwing error and error,
they have this mechanism
that that error can propagate.
It totally depends.
If that developer wants to handle that
data.
It totally is totally up to him
or he can also propagate that error to me.
And maybe then I can handle their data.
Or maybe I can have the default behavior.
And what is the default behavior?
Completely terminated.
I can terminate the application.
So they designed a complete mechanism to
generate these errors. To
handle these errors.
Standard error message is standard
class is a complete mechanism,
complete ecosystem.
So there is this other definition of
this exception handling.
It is the process of converting system
error messages into user friendly error
messages.
Now, why? Why we want to do that?
That's why we want to convert Suspender
to system error messages
into user friendly friendly error
messages.
Well, how can be helpful?
So let's say for example, for the next
to the steps of solution to the user.
Yes, we can also do that.
And this is the
best approach.
Instead of just showing the error, please
build your framework for your develop
your code in such a way
that you guys don't only show the problem,
but you also tell the user
how to fix their data.
Okay, so it's comprehensive.
So let's say, for example, to understand
and follow the issue.
If I am getting an issue of something
like this right,
if I get this kind of issue,
if you guys print this, add it
to a normal, normal user,
like, for example, when you guys
didn't know anything about Java,
and if you guys see
an error message like this,
it will make
it would make no sense, right.
To the normal users
who don't know programing.
They don't know much about the IP.
And if we are showing these
that are messages to those users,
it will not make sense.
It will not make any sense to them right.
So we don't want to do that
insert of these error messages
which Java is generating by default.
We want to convert it to something
simpler.
Right?
So when let's say, for example,
you guys are trying
to connect to the Internet
using Chrome or
any other browser,
if there is no Internet,
then if if Google Chrome
is trying to show
something like this to the end users,
they will not be able to easily
figure out what is going wrong, Right?
What is going wrong.
So that's why we want to convert
these complex error messages
to something simpler
that everyone can understand.
Yes. Instead, Chrome lets
you play a dinosaur game, so this is one
main goal of exception
handling other than avoiding
that abrupt termination of program.
And the second thing is that providing
alternate solution.
So let's say alternate
is the ultimate solution.
In the case of Google Chrome,
if it is that can dinosaur game, right?
If there is no internet,
you can play that game.
So it is the alternate solution
that they came up with.
So I hope you guys will be doing the same.
Right.
Something funny or that don't like, for
example, the end users there don't just
uninstall
your application or just break it.
They are laptops or something like that.
They can have some kind of enjoyment
or alternate or if it is a server side
application may be
you guys can develop Terminator Solutions.
For example,
let's see some of your test cases.
They are failing, right?
So what you guys can do,
maybe you can generate an email
and put all the information
about their test case
inside that email
and I can send it to yourself.
Right?
Because you guys are commission engineers.
You guys will just
start your testing framework
and you guys will not be looking at it
all the time.
When it is executing.
It might take off days, weeks.
So instead of what you guys will
do, you guys maybe will build
those frameworks.
Like for example,
if everything is going well,
it's find test
cases should keep on executing
if something goes wrong,
maybe you would generate an email
and send it to yourself
so that you know what went wrong
and what a lot of companies there do.
Let's say, for example,
your application is executing on a server.
Something goes wrong with that server.
So what they do, they generate emails
and send them to the I.T.
guys, the guys who are responsible
for taking care of those servers.
Let's say that server runs out of space
or it has internet issues,
or maybe some files are not found on,
maybe some framework is not working.
So they generate emails
and then they send that to corresponding
employees
so that they can fix those issues.
So this is also a backup plan.
Most notably, you guys will be doing
something like this.
How are you guys doing?
How we can do that?
So, Alexey, what we can do
so you guys can write it,
write catch block like this for the back
can be problematic.
And inside of this, Kurt
So I am writing the name of the class
whose error
I am expecting that this code will throw.
So I write the name of the class
whose added I am expecting.
So I know that
what kind of issue this code for control.
So I write the name of that sender
error message
and then the variable name
which can be anything.
And in here, Alexa, in here
you will write a piece of code
that will generate that
image, sending an email to
Alexa is both.
He is not working hard.
Okay, Something like that.
So inside this cache block,
you guys can write any piece of code
and when this catch block is executed,
it is only executed
when something goes wrong
inside this try block
If there
if everything is working perfectly fine
and you guys are not getting any issues
or errors in here,
then this
catch block will not be executed, okay?
It is only executed
when something goes wrong inside
the try block okay.
So, guys, is there any word or any term
which is not clear from this slide?
This is clear
what is execution of program?
What is normal flow,
What are objects, system
generated messages,
what is easy can be anything.
It's just the name of the variable. Right?
So what happens is that when we declare a
when we
declare a variable,
we can give any name to that variable.
So in here
I am declaring a variable of this class
so that whenever the exception, whenever
the object of this class is thrown,
Java can store that object
inside this variable.
Right when the null pointer
exception occurs, that
class name you got from the console,
the pointer exception.
This one is the same
that I specified in here.
So for every type of error
there is a special class
and if you are expecting your code
to throw that specific error,
you specify that class name
and the variable name.
So later on I will show you that
we can have multiple catch blocks.
I can have exception,
I can have
index out of bound exception.
So if you guys are not sure
that what kind of error that your
your code can throw, you can specify
as many catch blocks as you want.
If your code close and null pointer
exception this block is executed here.
If it throws out of index out of bounds,
this code is executed.
If it throws a general exception,
This is like overloaded catch.
Yep. Yep.
So only thing is different arguments.
This kind of overloading the moment is
omni you've and this mistake variable now.
But we should have at least one try know
at least one catch.
We will try
to try it.
They are optional
if you want you can have.
If not you, you can avoid
works like if false. Yes.
Can I play it safe and right? If you
can I play it safe
and right?
If you like.
Can you can you rephrase
some by safe? What do you mean place?
If for insurance
like this?
And sometimes I feel like I'm
talking to my girlfriend.
Your words.
They don't make any sense at all.
Playing insurance is safe.
What do you mean?
And if it's
from where this insurance comes
in, I think it means just in case.
Putting many options,
insurance Sparks House.
Yes, I agree.
We can put as many good blocks as we you
you can write in your native language.
Okay.
If you can write in your native language,
someone will translate it to me.
Yes, fine, fine. I'm just kidding.
Don't take it serious.
That is, don't take anything from me.
Hideous.
I don't know why.
And I took it
serious about that wrapper to zero nine.
I am never serious.
Please don't take your policy.
It has any of my words.
Easy peasy is including Java.
Please
don't take this Java as a serious. But
I never meant to hurt anyone.
Just.
Just so that I can put some smile on
your face is best All yet.
So it's not easy to hurt us now
because you guys are already so
in that movie.
He says, I warn you,
I, I break or no word
but that that special movie
and that the other guy said
I am already broken.
Life is hard on this is
so I hope this slide is clear.
So every word
and every sentence on this slide,
it should be super, super clear to you
because after three months
when you guys will be revising
your concepts,
you will not have time
to watch those fireworks videos.
You will be referring to these slides
to revise these concepts.
And I want to make sure that everything is
clear that is written in here.
So if something is not clear, you guys can
always ask me in the next class.
So for example, Nabeel told me, Nabeel,
can you tell me this slide?
Oh, good. This one. Right.
Glasses on.
So it should be
classroom
map in here.
All right.
Okay.
I think it looks good now. Yep.
After three months
are the year
your third month, right?
Or 3.5
third,
the fourth month, actually.
So you guys will not even realize
how these six six months fast.
It will be just like a blink of an eye
and you guys will be sitting
in your interviews
with the face.
No, no, no.
You guys will not be sitting
with blank piece.
I can tell you when when we prepare,
we will be preparing you
for your interviews.
So our students, believe me, if you
like, for example,
the knowledge that you have for Java,
you can ask these questions to a person
who is working in the industry
for five years, and believe me,
he will not be able to answer those.
You give them the their to do it online.
They will not be able to solve it.
So don't think that you guys know nothing
or you are lagging behind something
you guys are you guys will be much more
prepared than a person
who is actually working in the industry
because what happens is that guys,
if a company
gets more business or more profit.
So for example, if you are just opening
and closing a file on a daily basis
and that is profiting the company, then
they will never bother you to teach you
something new or they will never ask you
to learn something new.
If that is the only thing
that is profiting that company,
they will always want to do
the exact same thing again and again
and again for for for tolerance
go obvious.
So what happens is that in the industry
you will be working on
a very, very specific part,
on a very specific problem.
And that's all you will be knowing
about that thing.
Only you will you will not be knowing
all that you are learning in here.
Okay?
You some of the persons they don't even
know about the complete picture,
how the best cases are executed
on servers, how servers are set up,
how much to open and close the file simply
under keeper and 2128 per annum. It's
so they don't bother much about learning.
Believe me.
So some of our students,
they are still doing manual testing.
They have not written a single piece
of Java code or anything like that.
Still doing manual testing there.
So although they are hired as automation
engineers,
they are still doing
the manual, just checking the manual.
If those textbooks are working
fine or not creating Excel files.
So something like that,
you guys will be surprised to
know that you don't mind their job.
Believe me, you guys will like
when you will be repeating the same thing
again and again.
Believe me, you guys will get bored
so quickly and you will
you will say to your managers,
Please give me something new.
It is so boring. Yes.
You guys don't have to know
all three topics.
I like worrying.
Yes, I yes, obviously it depends on
what kind of person you are.
Some of you might like it very much,
but I cannot do that
if they are asking me something
to do again and again.
Believe me, in around one week
or so I will write a software application
for that.
To automate it, to do it automatically.
I can I can never do manual work again
and again, more more than one week.
But even I think one week is more
like,
did I tell you I watched the video,
I watched movies and played
video games for three months.
So in my previous company
they gave me a task, a manual task,
to correct the records in database
application.
I developed the software for that
in 15 days and I enjoyed it three months.
And believe me, I offered that solution.
It's not like that.
I didn't want to do that for the company.
I offered that solution to the manager
and manager was like, Ask
what if we introduce more issues by by,
by taking your software
and letting it fix all the issues?
Okay. I said,
okay, it's totally up to you.
Like, for example, if you want me to do
is using a calculator manually one by one
all the calculations.
I can also do that.
You could do that and have another part
time job or another source of income.
All No, I learned a lot
in those three months as well.
All those lambda expressions
and all I took like of courses from
Lynda dot com and other
other websites.
So our company was following this culture
of make a mixture of development
and best of Facebook they
they also all the same
all the developers,
they are also the testers.
So sometimes I am writing code,
sometimes I'm
testing the code, but
I never offered their solution again.
So an exception can occur
for many different reasons.
Right?
There are many things that can go wrong.
Maybe you guys have developed
an application
which takes the input from the user and
so Facebook does not need testers.
I mean, if you are a good tester,
I don't know.
But they have this mixed culture.
They don't have separate teams for testers
and separate teams for developers.
It's the same team
who who does the development
and the testing work.
So for example,
you guys have developed an application
which takes two numbers from the user
and it tries to divide those numbers.
So what? What can go wrong?
Maybe the user can is zero
for the denominator, right?
In that case,
the division is
something
that is not defined for integers.
Okay, So let's say for example, the
you guys know that if we try to divide
something by zero, what do we get guys?
If we try to divide something by zero,
we get the infinity, right?
So my math guys, they call it infinity.
So if we say number one divided by
number two, so can you guys
tell me if I execute this program,
will this project
be able to handle this issue or do still,
I will be getting that response,
that default response
in which the application will terminate.
So, for example,
if I have some lines of code in here
and some lines of code
in here, will I see this line to
when I execute this program?
No, I will not be able to see it. Why?
I will not be able to see it.
What kind of error this piece of code
will throw guys?
It will throw
it will throw out
automatic exception, right?
Divided by zero.
What kind of error?
And I have written inside this
catch block.
I have written null pointer exception.
So this catch block,
it can only get the null pointer
exceptions if so, this will not work.
I only see line one.
Then I get to this
an automatic exception divided by zero.
So I must write another catch block
that should also
take these arithmetic
exceptions.
So now I have a proper catch block
which can handle this issue.
So now if I execute this program,
now I see line one.
So no issues. I still see line one then.
So then Java, execute this line,
then this line.
And the moment
Java tries to execute this line.
But if we use exception,
it is universal. Yes.
Why do the universal?
Because the exception is the parent class
of all the issues
that can occur at runtime.
So you guys remember from
polymorphism and inheritance
the variable of parent
can hold the objects of all
any of the child classes, right?
So we can store the object
of any of the child classes
inside a variable
which is off type parent.
Right?
So their slight exception,
if we put the exception,
it will be able to handle any
kind of issues, but then you will not know
what went wrong in your code
if there's something to genetic right,
So you will not be able to know
if, let's say
there was a no pointer exception
or there was another automatic exception.
So that's why we want to be specific.
So I see we call divided by zero
and then I see line number two.
All right. So this operation
is not defined, but what if
I tried double numbers?
How come? Sending email to print.
Alexi, Boss, print out where
it will only be printed
when we encounter the null pointer
exception.
Is it important for speed?
No, it is. Didn't print out.
Okay. Why?
Because we didn't face
this issue, this null pointer issue.
If I if I now execute this program.
So now I get the infinity answer
because for doubles it is defined.
For doubles, it is defined.
So when it tries to execute this,
it gets infinity.
And then and other issue occurs,
which is null pointer exception.
So this line of code was executed
successfully.
We got the infinity as the answer.
Then when Java tried to execute this line,
it encountered null pointer exception
and then this line was executed.
This time Java ignored
this catch BLOCK okay.
And we see the line number two.
So yes, we can have multiple catch blocks,
but which bet, which
catch block execute depends
which kind of order
we are encountering. And
if we encounter that
specific type of error
and we have a cache block
for that back at block is executed
and the rest of the code
execution normally.
So it's like the effects conditions,
which is specific condition, Max, only
that part is executed and the rest of the
if blocks, they are ignored.
Can you please repeat what changes
you did to get infinity in control?
Oh, I can't do that. Types.
So remember guys,
all the operations they are defined on
that are types of data types.
So for example, what is meant by
plus it is defined
in size to be that type
and what is meant by plus
in case of the strings is defined on
in this string class.
So is it better
to use
a unique try catch block
for every issue? Yes.
So this is something like that.
And you are having a fever.
You go to doctor and doctor
gives you antibiotic,
you have maybe headache.
You again go to doctor again antibody,
you have something wrong in your stomach,
you go to doctor.
Are you an antibiotic
having a genetic block?
So it is something like that.
You should only do so.
For example, if something is not good,
we deal with your stomach.
You should go to the medicine
for that specific issue right?
You should not always get something
generic
normal practice back home
or antibiotics for everything.
Yeah,
but I don't go to doctor
because my wife is a doctor.
Oh, my God.
And that is it.
Good back to have your wife as a doctor?
I heard it's not good to have your
wife as doctor.
Is it true
you are not feeling well?
It is a big injection.
You are not going to work.
Here is a big injection.
You are not in a good mood.
It is a big injection.
It's dirty
between two other doctors already.
I still didn't get.
How would we know which catch block to?
Right.
Okay, so we have to kind of guess this
which call which block to right.
We're going to have to guess.
We have to guess
what kind of issues are called again. Two.
And then we have to think about
these scenarios, about the get blocks.
But generally speaking,
if you don't anticipate to have an ATL
in the first place,
how can you be specific in advance?
Yes, it comes from experience,
from practice,
from knowledge, and that's where
I was trying to find so I can write.
What I am like.
If you see is it's bad to have a dog
throw a big injection.
Yeah,
it's if, if he if she knows
animal B is trying to marry another girl,
it is a big injection.
What will it ever do.
Allow not feel anything about because
all you all
it is
whatever is
so yes this is
this is something that comes
from practice,
from knowledge, from experience, and
for example,
if you are writing a piece of code,
usually, you know, with the practice,
usually you will.
I could not see for three days
when she learned it.
I don't know.
I it's so code,
but we know what kind of issues
the code again can, can encounter.
So that's how we anticipate it.
Are there other types of cat blocks?
Oh yes.
There are thousands of types of cat blocks
for every possible error that can exist.
Java guys have created
a class for that inability
to index out about negative high
skill exception class
not followed for all the possibilities.
They have kind of written these classes
and if none of those classes are working,
then yes, you can have this
genetic catch block
and it will catch
all types of exceptions no matter what.
Okay.
So you you guys see some
some applications.
The true this had a something went wrong.
So this and this is where they write
this piece of code
when they don't know
did they write this exception block
at the end they just write something.
You throw something went wrong.
So you guys can also do this.
The last remedy I get that a lot
is there's the best word.
So, yes, professional developers,
they also don't know
about all the possibilities
where what can go wrong.
So they write at the end of the right this
catch block Oops, something went wrong
or go back and catch
after getting that data. Yep.
And because you guys are our testers,
maybe you guys can put try restarting
your application.
Need to have internet on again.
Was not there a way to print
towards the exception left?
Yes. Yes.
And there is a way.
So I will teach you about those methods.
So for example, instead of printing out
this, you can say e dot.
You can first of all, just directly
print this E
system, dot, dot, print causing
is making a good
Oh my God.
So now if I
if I get
if I execute this code,
which kind of arrival you guys,
I am trying to divide two integers
and the denominator is zero.
So I will get other traumatic exceptions.
So will this catch block
execute or
this one or this one.
This one will be executed. Right.
And in here I am directly trying to print
this error message directly.
So let's see what happens.
So Simon, you see dialog or planned or
to this magic exception divided by zero.
So we can we can do that or we can see
got to message.
Now I will only see the message
or the class name
divided by zero
or you can only get the class name
or you can,
for example, you can
instead of this
you can say you don't put into step three.
So there are many possible.
It depends on you.
Whatever you want to do with that.
So I get the error messages,
plus I get the lines of code
so we will see what is the
best way to handle these errors.
So an exception, guys.
Everything is making sense to law
or you guys are lost,
confused.
All good.
All our errors make sense now.
Yes, they will make much more sense.
You guys will be able to figure out
the exact lines
of code, exact
causes for the issues
after learning about exception.
So you guys don't have to
now ask are in the sports channel.
You guys will be able
to figure it out on your own. Yes.
So an exception can occur
for many different reasons.
Right.
So for example
the user is trying to input wrong
a wrong data, right.
The data you are trying to read
from a file
maybe that contains invalid data.
A file that needs to be opened
cannot be found.
So you place some file on your computer.
You accidentally delete that file.
And if now you try to run your java code,
our code will try to read the file
from that part.
But it will not be able to do that.
So it will throw that error
in the middle of communication
B gave him has run out of memory.
So can you guys tell me
who is responsible to execute
your Java code on your computers?
Who is doing all of this stuff?
Core processor,
nor specifically about Java.
Everything is executed by processor.
All right.
But what about Java?
How do Windows know?
What is Java?
How do Mac Operating system knows?
Who is translating
all of your requirements
Is the Java which machine, right?
The compiler, the Java ecosystem.
Now what is that?
What do you.
So JVM is a program, okay?
It is a program
like Google Chrome, like Microsoft Word,
like intelligent, like Zoom
as any other program on your computer.
Now, these programs,
they can also get issues right?
They can also have problems itself.
So now the guy who was executing
your Java code,
who was translating your instructions
to the underlying operating system, now
it itself get to some issues, right?
So what happens in that case?
Again, we will be we are
program will not be we will be executed.
For example, you have written
a piece of code that reads their file
of maybe 20 gigabyte, but on your computer
you only have 16 gigabyte.
So you your your JVM will run out
of memory while trying to read that file.
So this is what it
what is meant by this code?
What is it clear.
So the virtual machine
yourself can have issues, right?
And virtual machine
is the application that
executes your program
on any of the computer.
So one is the
clearly third point.
All right.
So work Java guys have done
depending upon the type of errors
they have divided
all the errors in in three main classes
where is done
it has been is is three main classes.
So they have divided all the errors
in three main classes.
So math teacher
So now let's discuss about these three
main types of issues that we can get
in Java.
So exceptions are objects
and objects are defined using classes.
So they have created this
rule class for exceptions, which is called
Jala or Lang God pro IB Okay.
And then
we have a class called Errors Error
and another class called Exception.
And then there are multiple classes
which are
extending from this exception class.
They are
divided into
two types.
This, these one,
they are called jacketed exceptions
and these one
they are called unchecked
exceptions, iron selenium
input output exception.
You guys go this input output exception
in selenium.
Okay, So now you guys will be able to
avoid these issues
in selenium.
So you guys have used the thread
dog sleep in selenium.
Right.
Which type of exception.
And that method it throws
now is different.
That standard sleep.
You guys add something
to the method signature
when you write a third or sleep
dollar Longs
belongs to you about a type of adult
that get that
this piece of code
can cause interrupt to the exception.
Right?
So that is also a type of exception.
But you guys have noticed this
that less so for
example, that you guys notice this
for some types
of exceptions, GOA
forces us to ride the bike at block
for others, Java does not for us.
For example, if I ride
thread, dart sleep
in here,
if I don't try,
if either I have to add this to method
signature in here, which means that
I am saying to Java that
Hey Java, you know what?
I don't want to provide a try catch block
for this piece of code.
Yes, I know this can cause problems,
but you know what?
If anything goes wrong,
yes, just terminate my program abruptly.
I don't care. Okay?
This is the default behavior
that you guys have been doing until now.
All that the exception
to the whoever
is calling this main method.
So who calls this main method is
here C on the JVM, right?
It's also compiler translation C
or a source code to the bytecode.
You guys must you guys know you guys have
this all followed in here.
So if you open this out folder
for all the classes
you have kind of this replica.
What is this replica?
This replica is actually if you open this
so you see this D compiled from blah,
blah, blah.
Right.
But if I go inside this directory
opening explorer
and if I go inside this folder
and if I open this with not bad,
you guys will see something like this.
Do you guys see these weird symbols
and all that
is the bytecode
is the code that your JVM understands.
So what happens
is that when we click on that plus button,
all the code that you guys have written
in playing Java that
humans can understand, it is actually
translated
to this byte called super clear.
So for every piece of code that you write
in this intelligent, any other idea,
there are two versions of code
one that we as humans can understand
easily.
And the other one is the bytecode
that JVM can understand easily.
So all that code is actually converted
to the bytecode before Java, before
JVM can execute your
for your compiler alien language.
And so this is the job of compiler
converting the code
that is understandable to humans
to something
that is understandable to JVM.
This is the job of compiler.
JVM, on
the other hand, is a piece of program
that takes that bytecode
and converts that to binary code
your processor,
your operating system can understand.
So there's the difference
between JVM and compiler.
There are many more differences,
but this one is the major one.
So what I was saying
sometimes you guys must have noticed
that when you guys try to write
some matters
lot to us, to our content,
yes, this is what I am explaining.
So the type of fairness
for which Java will explicitly force you
to provide a catch block,
they are categorized as
jagged exceptions, like,
for example, this piece of code
can also call a was an issue right
this division by zero.
But in here
Java is not forcing me to provide that
try to block Java
is not giving me an error at compile time
if I don't provide the implementation
for this piece of code,
these type of errors
which are not caused by Java,
they are categorized as
unchecked exceptions.
So what is happening behind the scenes is
Java is not checking this piece of code.
Sorry I stepped out for a minute.
I though we
I thought we have to use implicit
we cannot use thread or sleep any more
because that was them.
And it also said yep,
you guys will be using the specifics.
So again, please
Alexievich line you want me to show again
from read
from thread? Yes.
So if I remove this
right, get in here and compile time.
Java gives me an error
if I don't provide the try cache block,
but in here I don't.
I am not forced by compiler to provide it
like at block.
Now why is this important to why
Java is forcing me here and why
Java is not forcing here to provide it
like all kind of why we have these
two exceptions
and until the exceptions, can you guys
guess why?
Why is forcing mean here and not in here?
Let me give you more examples
if I try to write, if I try to
open a file input spam
in here, the dialog enforces me to provide
again
say me their task
good either provided they try that block
or add it to the method signature.
But in here, let's say for example.
So in both cases
I will be getting an error
if I try to execute this program right.
But in some cases Java forces me to either
add it to the method signature
provide provided break at block,
but in some cases Java does not force me.
So in the cases
where I am explicitly forced
to provide a broadcast block,
they are categorized as jack exceptions.
And in the cases where I am not forced,
although this piece of code can also cause
the issue,
they are called untargeted exceptions.
Time to take a break.
So think about this, guys.
I will explain after the break.
Also tried to Google it.
Why we have jagged
and untargeted exceptions.
Yeah, though
I cannot check
everything for you.
All right.
But please be back in 15 minutes
and reminding me
about the recording.
All right,
so these two main categories
are all jagged and uncheck the exceptions.
They basically exist
because of two main type of errors
that can occur in programing.
One of the arrows,
one of the type they occur due to bad
programing practices.
Okay.
And you can avoid these issues
if you write your code properly.
So let's say, for example,
if I am trying to divide by the zero,
what I can do, I can first
declare, let's say maybe
two numbers.
And then before I try to divide these
numbers, I can write an if condition.
I can see if number two
is not equal to zero, then only
I want to do the video.
And if this is not the case,
I can
simply print out some error messages.
Maybe
like this.
And in this case I can check
if a variable is null or not.
So if name is equal to null,
so it's up to you guys.
You want to handle these errors
with the help
of write catch blocks,
you can use the try catch blocks
or if you want to avoid these issues
with the help of simplified effects
conditions, you can also do that
so only if the name is not equal to no.
Then I want to print this out. As
I can see
that name
variable able
is not like, okay,
so these under exceptions
or the exceptions
which are not forced by Java,
these exceptions you guys can think of as
these exceptions as something
lightweight exceptions,
these can be avoided with the help of
if the if seems more easier
because we do not need to know
the name of exception.
Yes, but you are missing a very important
aspect.
Mohamud, for example if you use the
if conditions,
you will not be able to get a bad
press like this
imagine there are thousands and thousands
lines of code
and you are getting an error.
And the error only says
I cannot divide by zero.
Now the first thing that you have to do is
you have to set
your complete code for this added message.
Then you have to find out
which line is throwing
this, add it,
then you have to find out the issue.
But if you use the try at block,
you will get to be standard exception
plus name.
You will get that standard error message.
You will get the exact line number
that is causing the problem.
You will get the exact name
of the method, exact
name of the class,
and the complete information about the.
So finding and fixing issues is way
easier in the case of break at blocks.
Then the if health conditions.
I hope it makes sense,
but actually
it is easy to see the type of exception
just to make the mistake
and copy it from the output.
Yes, you can also do that.
For example,
just write the first condition.
Once you get the ETA,
you guys will not be needing
to know about these errors.
You once you start cracking the code,
you will know what kind of issues
that piece of code can throw.
So don't worry
too much about these these exceptions.
Zoom out.
Okay, I did better now
there are famous 10 to 15 types of issues
which you will be getting
most of the time.
So I will teach you about those issues.
Okay.
Is it possible to specifically show
the line that we made errors
when we are
using the printouts in Oak
Line 20?
Must be number number divided by Yep.
Now. Now it should be
number divided by
numbers. So
yes, you are right. Yes.
Like that of compiled it.
So for example
so guys in Oak is saying their task to
this line number
that we get with the help of exceptions.
Well why can't we also like
I can also do that
I can put on line 23 right.
I can also do that.
It's also possible
to put into the exact line numbers,
but still, you know,
are you getting this information
out of method name,
class, name, package name?
And even if you put all of this
information inside a false condition,
the moment you try to change your order.
So, for example,
even if you accidentally hit an enter, now
this line moves to line number 24
instead of line number 23.
So adding a new code to the same file.
So for example, if you are adding
some line of code in here,
all the information that you insert
about the line number,
the entire to the 6 hours it's gone.
Now it is on line number 25.
So you cannot make changes to the code
again and again.
It's a very big problem.
You understand why we cannot put line
numbers in here.
I mean, automatically.
So this is automatically.
This is automatically.
That's why they have created,
with the exception exceptions.
I don't think so. There is a way that.
So for example,
you want to write extra up.
So for to get to be exact line numbers,
class numbers and all that, then why not?
You will do the exceptions
which are providing you all of that info
but would not.
So then why not do exceptions?
They are doing the exact same thing
for you.
Yep. So then that's not a good idea
to print out the line numbers
and everything on inside this house.
And there is one more thing, guys.
In professional applications,
we don't use this house,
we don't print things on the console.
When we execute the code on servers,
there is no console.
So we use these loggers.
You remember that log for there
that caused the issue on the Internet.
That's
actually the alternate of printouts.
So there is a huge
kind of virus thing
going on over the internet.
So these applications
for professional applications,
they use a special program
to print out these all of this info,
all of this info inside of the files,
instead of printing out the
because there are no controls
on the servers servers, they don't have
screens attached to them all this.
So we don't print out information
because there is
no one looking at these errors
when the applications are in execution.
Instead, we create a file
and we put all the lines, all the issues
and errors inside that file.
We keep on putting the data, we keep on
putting this out inside that file.
If anything goes wrong, we just
we just analyze those logs.
They are called the log files.
If you guys know, for example,
when something goes wrong,
your software is like chrome
and they ask you to send the report
to the developers
and those error reports.
So they are actually sending
all those logs to the developers
I knew that we will miss as our clients
wonder.
Yes, so professional applications,
they don't source
why mine is different.
Okay, I will just call you the
so what I was saying
that we don't prior to the line numbers
because changing
the code will be difficult
and we always try to use exceptions
so that we have complete information
about the errors.
So previously were discussing the code
and the exception,
so the exceptions which can be avoided
by just writing good code
or can be avoided
by writing false conditions, or
we can also use the
at blocks they are called as unchecked
exceptions.
Okay,
compiler is not checking these exceptions,
so compiler is not checking if
the will be able
to divide this number by zero or not.
If we will get the null pointer exception
or or not.
This highlighting thing is coming from
it is not from the compiler,
but the exceptions
which are checked at combined time,
which are not in the control
of a programmer,
which can not be avoided by
just writing if false conditions.
They are called
jagged exceptions.
So for example, if a file is not found
on a specified location,
can I write a piece of code that
maybe magically generated that file
and all the data are inside that file?
Or maybe can I write a piece of code
that checks if that file is not present
there to that location
before that specific line is executed.
So for example, you guys might ask
their Tasker thought widget
if a file is not present
at a specific location before
writing the file.
Not false claim is not.
There is a way.
So yes, there are ways, but still
we cannot do that.
So for example, why? Why?
Java is forcing me
to write it,
I guess. BLOCK
So if there is a part
let's say, guys, I am trying to read
this file.
So what is
what is special about this error right?
Can't I just check before I say
filing for the same
file in perform
your file in extreme.
So why I is forcing me? Why?
By saying that there either
like to try to block
or write this exemption
to the method signature.
Can't avoid this
with the health condition.
What do you guys think?
Contain avoid this check first check
if this export is
correct or not.
Nice.
What do you think?
Like I avoided the arithmetic exception.
Like I avoided the null point of exception
by writing.
If health conditions contain avoid this
exception.
So yes, the answer is no.
We cannot avoid
even if I it.
So there is this
file class in Java the file file new file
and what I can do,
what I can do.
I can say if
dot exists.
So this method it tells me
if a specific file exist
on a specific location or not.
So I can I can count.
I say this if file exists, then only
execute this code.
Otherwise
maybe print out file
is not president
export.
So yes,
I can still try if health condition.
I still have classes.
I can still have this mechanism
to make sure that
if this file exist
on the drive, then only
maybe I can say
yes file exist
will not be
getting any errors.
So what this this method is doing.
So let's say for example.
So right now I am adding this map,
this exception to this method signature
in here.
In other words, I am saying, Hey, Java,
I don't care
if this file is just told the error.
I made the application abruptly.
I don't want to handle the setup.
Okay.
I don't want to provide a backup code.
I don't care.
So let's say for example, guys,
if I delayed this file
and then if I execute
this program,
I get
the file is not present error this part.
Okay?
And if I undo this file
and then I execute this code
so it
says this file
exist, I will not be getting any other.
Is not this condition
working perfectly fine?
I am able to check if a file is present.
Then only I am reading.
And am I not able to avoid this error?
Right.
What do you think? Alone?
I'm Mohammad Moreno amount Now Google
Allo.
So it's a tricky one.
I think it's a tricky one.
So no, actually I have tried my best.
But you know what?
I can still react to this issue.
Let me show how.
So what happens is still
things can go wrong.
I am not able to completely avoid
this issue.
So what can happen
is that at the moment Java
is executing this piece of code.
What can happen
is that the file is present on the system
and the moment this,
if condition is passed it, it is possible
that someone deletes this file
at that specific moment.
So if let me slowly execute this code.
So what can go wrong still?
So this condition
is still not perfected. So
I am sorry.
Let me put this.
I am on this line right now.
The file is present.
So will this condition pass those are not.
It will pass. Right.
But watch what happens right
the moment This
If condition is passed.
What if someone deletes this file
right after this?
If condition is passed now,
if I execute this code now,
will I get error or not?
So when when Java execute in this piece,
the file was present,
but right after that line,
someone deletes that file.
I deleted that file
and if now I execute this program,
who can be faster then?
And if health condition as there can be,
I will get an error.
Now, back in the moment.
Java now tries to execute this file
file is gone
and now I get this added.
So I tried my best
using all of my java skills
to avoid this issue,
but there are still chances
that things can go wrong.
So what I conclude
is that in all the cases,
if first condition is not sufficient,
in some cases,
if health conditions are sufficient,
I can avoid the issues
completely, but not in all the cases.
Some cases they require
try cache blocks no matter what.
Does it make sense, guys?
So if I have a piece of code in here
and if I am using
if conditions not,
this code will not be executed.
Same issue.
But after termination of program
because I didn't have like x blocks.
So let me repeat it again.
Those issues
which can not be avoided
by just writing proper code
or if those conditions
which are beyond the control
of a programmer
are called jack and exceptions
and we must provide
dry catch blocks
to avoid those issues.
But the doors are issues
which can be avoided by writing
proper code or by writing
if those conditions are called unchecked.
The exception is,
and it is not mandatory to write it,
try catch block for those errors.
So and Java knows about these,
which you can not avoid completely
by writing it false condition
that's why java forces you devastated
hey is there I know.
I know you are a very good programmer
you can use the file path class.
You can check if a file exist.
But you know what?
I know.
I know better than you.
You can still get to this issue.
So please try.
Please write a blog.
You can still get issues. I am not.
I will not allow this.
Please please user try catch block. Okay.
So the proper way to avoid this
issue is to use. Yep.
In Java is 25 years old.
Java at least knows what is possible
and what is not possible
by writing
in false condition.
So Java Sea is hence the
please provide a dry
catch block
if you want to avoid this issue.
If those conditions.
Yes, you are a good programmer,
but I know better than you.
You cannot avoid this issue by writing.
If health condition. So write it.
Try a block
and write a proper
catch block.
Stop drinking coffee Night Programmer.
How does no coffee
night?
Hello.
You were also browsing the Facebook
during the break.
I just here this on my Facebook
is what I do all the time.
One bucket.
So advice is it clear now
why in some of the cases
Java forcing us to write.
So let me let me do this again. So
so let's say for example again,
let me do the same thing.
So I write
I again.
So this time I am writing at blocks
and let me
try to build that file
right after we enter
the try.
BLOCK Okay, let's see what happens.
So previously my program was terminated
abruptly and I was unable
to execute this line of code.
Let's let's see what happens.
Now I am using try get blocks.
So when Java was this
line file vice president
file was present.
We end.
We are inside the API now let me delete
this file. Okay.
And let's let's see how the how they try
catch
behaves.
So if I exec you to this line
file is not present
at this specific moment, I will be getting
a file not found exception
and the cache block will be executed.
And then after that all the code
will be executed as per norm well.
Slow.
Okay.
Previously on
this class are different episode.
So you guys see how. How I get blocks.
They are avoiding the issues
no matter, what happens?
But if those conditions were not able
to avoid the issues
in the case of try cache blocks,
the moment we encounter an error,
we enter inside the cache block,
leaving everything inside.
We try, but we are still able to catch
that specific issue.
So that's why
try catch blocks.
They are better than if those conditions
and that's why
Java forces us to write
a catch block in certain scenarios.
And they have created a separate category
for these errors
and they called it checked exceptions.
Does it make sense,
guys? Jack towards it unchecked
and then
there is another type
which are categorized as errors.
So adders are terrible things.
For example,
your Java program was executing something
and your processor fails, or maybe
your real program was in execution and
someone unplugs
power supply off your computer,
your program was in execution
and your JVM crashes. So
is is there anything
it can try catch?
BLOCK Avoid someone
unplugging your computer from power
can try to block do something.
In this case, if your processor fails,
cancel Java program or as a programmer,
can you do something to avoid that?
So those type of issues which are beyond
all beyond are Java's control.
They are categorized as errors.
Okay, so neither we nor Java
can do anything
about these type of issues.
So if your program encounters
these are situations
memory failure, hard drive, failure,
complete computer is destroyed,
someone unplugs
you from power or someone just crashed.
Something crashes the auditorium,
all of these issues, they are
called errors
and there
is really nothing we can do about them.
So we never try to get them
or try to do anything.
It's like someone is already dead
and he had maybe a kidney issue
or something.
Something, something.
And now we are trying
to replace his kidney.
So if that person is already dead,
then there is nothing we can do about it.
Right?
So those issues which are totally,
totally beyond our control.
Okay, well, we cannot do anything at all
about those issues.
They are categorized under address. Okay?
So we don't care when we encounter that
and we say, okay,
this is something that we cannot
we cannot do about anything.
So this is the target category
of our types of error.
So there are types of errors
which can be avoided by writing back core
if health conditions
or using breakage blocks, what are
what are they called guys,
what type of exceptions
they are called, which can be avoided
writing better code if health condition
or breakage
they are called unchecked exceptions.
The types of errors
which can only be avoided
by writing dry cache blocks.
They are called jacketed exceptions.
The errors which can not be avoided
by doing any of these things.
They are called attacks in Java.
I hope it is clear so both error
and exception are derived from Java
or landlord variable.
So as per the hierarchy.
And there is this true
which is parent of all
the errors classes.
So as per hierarchy,
the errors and the exceptions,
they are both derived, they are both child
classes all through it, but
But the main difference between error
and exception is the kind of error
they represent.
So for example, Avatar error errors
are serious issues and abnormal conditions
that most applications
should not try to handle.
Why be because there is really nothing
that we can do.
When you are there
that you don't know you are dead,
then pain is only felt by others.
The same thing
happens when you are stupid.
This so error defines problems
that are not expected to be caught
under normal circumstances.
This by program for example memory
at the hardware that a JVM matters.
We we cannot do anything about that.
And what are exceptions.
So exceptions are things
that we can handle and we should handle.
Are that a reasonable application
might want to catch or conditions
within the code?
A developer can handle that.
They are a lightweight at that.
What we can do, we can do something about
such conditions
and take necessary corrective measures.
Right?
Maybe file is not.
But why not check or over the internet
still not found?
Maybe we want to send an email to a
person who is responsible
of taking care of that file.
And if internet is not found, maybe
by printing a user friendly
message on the console
and something like that.
So errors can't be handled.
Example out of memory error. Right?
You cannot go to your Java code,
cannot go buy some RAM
or and then install it on your computer.
If you faced this out of memory error.
But if you face error index out of bound
exception, you you can actually check
Jakob that index before you
try to access the element on that index.
So these are errors and exceptions.
So what we can do about exceptions.
Well why use exception
and what is the benefit of that.
We get the first thing we can again
convert system
and over into user friendly error message
by using exception
handling feature of off Java,
we can easily
find a big complete set trace of the error
and then we can fix that.
Add it. Think
this picture Alexa.
You know it was sold for
thousands of dollars over the internet.
This This girl, it is very rich now
when we divide
I like to try doing something like this.
Blow up a petrol pump
and take a smiling selfie with that.
Maybe
you can be a millionaire in the future.
Do you know about updates
when we know that if one of their heads
it is overriding of some metadata,
just replace some files,
replacing the file
and overwriting the methods, but
it's have fun calling the help desk.
I unplugged your computer
just to achieve this fixes.
Someone will write the code for
when we divide.
But don't tell that you blow up
the petrol pump or something like that.
When we divide any number by zero
and then system
generates by zero exception.
So this is not understandable by a user
and we can convert this message into user
friendly error message
like don't enter a zero for denominator
or something like that.
So why, why learn exception.
Why we should know about exceptions
converting
complex
error messages to something simpler
getting the complete
stack press of the error by stack press
I mean getting exact line
numbers and method
names, class names packages and name
package names to find and fix your issues.
And then third, providing a backup core.
So that is the primary code fails
the backup code or takes
care of that failure.
So it's like you are going on a vacation,
you you have a flag tied
and now you have maybe a
maybe some kind of guidance in your car
or an extra by and you replace that tired
and you continue your journey.
Right? So this is something like that,
having that backup mode,
making things a simpler,
finding and fixing your issues easily.
So this is, again, the hierarchy.
So exception
a class is for exceptional conditions.
That program should catch some exceptions.
We should catch we should fix them.
We should convert the error messages
to something simple.
This class is extended to create the user
specific exception classes.
So for example, Java
guys created this automatic null point
that are other unchecked
exceptions, you guys can create your own
exceptions as well.
And today
we will create our own exceptions. That
runtime
exceptions is a subclass of exception.
So from exception
we have another class
that is called a runtime exception.
And then we have these all the
unchecked exception.
So these are runtime exception exceptions.
They are only at runtime
they encounter only runtime,
but these Java will will warm new
compile time as well.
If you try to write a piece of code
that can have these issues.
So that's why they are called the runtime.
Runtime
exception is a subclass of exception.
Exceptions under this class are
automatically defined for programs, right?
You guys don't need to provide
cache block.
You are not forced and it is
are typically ignored in code.
You can't really do anything
about an error.
Example out of memory
error will arise in this type of file.
It is not possible to handle in code.
So types of exceptions.
And now this is the difference
between tagged and unchecked.
So let me repeat again
the except actions that are mandatory
to handle in code
by providing take X block
and are outside
the control of program
but are called checked exceptions.
It's a very famous interview question
guys.
The difference between tagged
and unchecked exceptions.
So please, please
let me know if something is not there.
They are forced by compiler.
What do I mean by forced by compiler?
We will be getting an error
if we don't wrap
discord with the try get block
as the compiler checks them
during compilation to see whether
the programmer has handled them
or not by writing a trick at
then the other type
which are not mandatory to handle in code
and are in control of a programmer,
can be avoided by writing good code.
We're writing if those conditions
are checking the index before
you try to get the element
that that index are called unchecked.
Unchecked exceptions comprise of time
exceptions like for example
runtime and its subclass. It
will be had to also ask
like this question.
So these are some examples
of the exceptions
and it might be no point
at index out of bounds thing
index on the fall.
Negative side that is so all of them,
they can be avoided
by simply writing a false conditions.
But these ones class not found exception.
Do you guys remember this exception?
Guys, do you guys remember this class
not found exception?
Where When did you guys encounter this?
When jobs were not present. Right.
So can we write a piece of code
to create those jobs
or to avoid this issue in any other way?
No. Right.
So we can not do anything about
this class
not found exception by just writing.
If as conditions, for instance,
you will really be getting
to the exceptions, the most famous one
will be a school exception
and file
not found exception in the chapter. Once
this is just
an example.
So 50 dividing.
We are trying to divide by zeros
arithmetic exception.
If We have null value in a variable
and try to call any method
on that null pointer exception.
If there is an area
which has a size of five.
But I am trying to get an element
at index then.
So I will be getting an array
index out of bound exception
because I am writing bad code.
I am trying to get an element
at index ten
and that index does not exist,
so it's too bad for doing
so. This is again the same scenario.
We have thousands of lines of code, some
exceptions, other occurs in the middle.
If exception is not tangled,
then the rest of the code,
the moment you encounter
that issue, the code
after that line, it will not be executed.
Program will be terminated
right after that.
If we don't it
if if we don't handle that exception.
So if exception is not handled by
an exception execution abrupt forcefully.
If you handle exception,
then exception will be reported
and next code will be executed normally.
So how can we avoid these issues
using cache block?
So we have at this new construct,
this new block
of code that we call try and get.
So now the background is good.
You guys now know to add.
So what are exceptions?
What what are the types of exceptions?
Why we should avoid them.
So now let's try to learn a little bit
about the nitty gritty details about these
how this strike team works.
Okay, so we like to try keyword
then these curly brackets
in here
and the code that we think
can cause problems.
We put that code inside this try block
and we write if that code is throwing
only can through only one type of error,
we only write that one catch.
BLOCK and we specify the name of the added
the name of the class
that whose object will be torn
when we will be encountering this issue.
So if we if the code is controlled
multiple alias,
we can write a multiple get blocks
and which block executes
depends which kind of additive
we are getting.
So try
cache is used to handle the in Java.
They are also present in other programing
languages like Python and C++
inside
try and we tried block of statements
which causes execution at runtime.
In other words,
try block always always control
in the problematic code.
We will have a real for this.
Yes definitely. Definitely.
So we put the problematic code
inside the try block
and then we write the backup code
inside the cache blocks
said, Hey, is it not clear?
Are you confused?
Or maybe it's because you are seeing
this things for the first time.
You can ask
if something is not clear. Yep.
Yeah, it's always better, you know.
Right.
So these are some of the rules, guys.
Some rules about the gate block
Try BLOCK is used to enclose the code
that might throw an exception.
A try block is always, always.
So we cannot just try to we try.
It must have at least one catch.
BLOCK
So try block is always followed by a catch
or finally block this finally,
something else that I will teach you.
So which handles the exception
that occurs in the Associated Try to block
it. Try block must be
followed by a catch block
or finally block.
So let me first show you
some examples in here.
All right.
So we should always write it.
Try a block
to catch the issues
that are for control.
So, for example,
like this, if I am,
let's say, declaring an anti
so I can get
negative at a side
exception, if I am saying,
let's say
so, this is how I write
the catch blocks
and all of them can have the same name.
All Yes, it's just a variable name.
Here's a local variable
so you can have same E
if this is only visible
inside these brackets,
it's like the parameters of the methods
you remember.
We can have the same variable name in
all of the methods inside a class
because local variables
are only visible inside of that method.
So I have intentionally introduced
problematic
for I have written problematic code
and this is in my lines
above the
right.
Actually let me do this
so that you guys can easily answer
your line one is to
could be
who or you?
The 1a9
and and
let me make it smaller.
Is it reliable guys
in the three. Okay
so now let's try to figure out
the nitty gritty details about this drive.
So can you guys
tell me if I insecure this for
what output.
I agree that.
Then tell me the line numbers
eight.
Let me actually remove this for now
and I like minimal this one now.
Okay we will discuss what this instead.
Methodism,
just tell me the line numbers.
If I execute this piece of code
so I will be getting one.
I will be getting to
one two.
So seven
and 11 days.
Everyone, please try to answer this
1 to 711.
Let me execute this.
So we got one, two, seven and 11.
Why we got this
this output. Right?
So this line is outside of the dry block.
It is not causing any problem.
I will tell you. Why not why nine.
So I will get this line eight.
It doesn't have any issues
writing in all the cases.
Then Java enters inside this dry block.
Java is the key of this line. No issues.
So it is printed
in here.
The second line no issues
if it's printed in here.
When Java tries to execute this
line, Java encounters a problem.
The moment Java encountered the problem,
all the lines
below piece of code are ignored
and Java starts
to search for the proper catch block
and we get the first get block
that it encounters from top.
Again this handle
the adult that occurred above.
Yes this catch block
can handle the issue which occurred
in the prior block so Java will execute
to whatever is present inside
this catch block and ignores
the rest of the catch blocks.
And then this line, it is outside of the
try guys, so it will again be executed.
Okay, no issues. Exactly.
And now guys why we got one two, 711.
So if
if I comment this out,
can you tell me now?
But instead, Trace, I will tell you
you'll get to what this print trace
is doing.
Yes. It's the best practice to write
separate try
catch block for separate type of issues.
If you can.
One, two, three, eight and 11.
So I got one, two, three, eight, 11.
Is there anyone who is not sure
why we are getting one, two, three,
eight and 11?
Is there anyone confused about this?
Me Rena So we are getting this one
because it's above the catch block.
There is no issues in here, right?
It is not causing any type
of exceptions, this line of code.
So that's why it is executed
without any issue
then dollar and translate bycatch.
BLOCK So what do you think?
Which number
should not be printed in here?
Which number should not be printed in here
or which should be printed
instead of one, two, three, eight, and 11?
What should be printed instead
is the E is shortcut for exception.
No, it can be anything.
It can be not.
It is just a standard
to write E for exceptions.
So the problem here basically try
can only see the first letter
and then does not care
about other E Yes. So
so the try block should have one
problematic code
as the other lines are ignored. Yes.
Yes, you are right. I do not.
Can you tell me which line
should not be printed in the console
or nothing is making sense it all of it.
Why we are getting this one two,
three 811.
Are you with us? It's fine. It's fine.
If you don't understand
what is going on, All of it is not making
sense. So
let four we put in
on which line?
This one
or I'm just intentionally
trying to introduce an error and
size can be in negative.
Right.
So but I am trying
to give a negative number as this size.
So what will happen?
I will get this exception
negative area size exception.
So this catch block,
whatever code is present in here,
Java will execute that piece of code when.
It encounters this specific issue.
That's why I have intentionally done this
to to show you guys
that how different errors can be handled
in different catch blocks is there to work
like in peer
yes Audubon one so far this out of this
did this exception
appear for this type of error?
This is the exception.
So let me do this, guys. If I do this
well, what output
I will see.
So I have written this line
outside of prior block,
so I will only see one
because it is outside of try.
So only one then. Edit
I am because it is outside of the try
right outside of the problem.
And what if I do this?
What if I put this line of code
inside of the cat?
What dating what output I will do now?
Yes, you guys are right.
So because there is a no catch block
to catch this issue,
I will go to one, two, three
and then adder.
So if I am writing a problematic code
inside of the cat again, I need a separate
dry cat
to avoid that issue.
Okay.
It also possible that I can get issues
inside a cat block and it is also possible
that I
can write nested predicate cat blocks.
They are called a nested private blocks.
Okay.
It's like if health conditions
if if conditions inside the if condition,
I can have nested x blocks,
I can also have.
Yes nested.
Can you guys tell me the output now?
So me put looks and maybe well in here
they were fun.
It's also fun.
I show
it will get funny once
I introduce more nested
catch blocks in here.
The selecting minimize this
so this will be executed no issue one.
I will be getting one.
This will be executed. No issues.
I will be getting know issues
three in here.
I will be getting an error.
So code will check if we can handle this
here in this sketch block
cannot handle this error.
So the next block will be kept.
But inside the next block, once
this is executed to encounter another,
So we will be getting it well.
So one, two, three, and then I'll offer
that if it is executed,
they are ignored and then we get 11.
So most of your answers, all of these
request
one, two, three,
12, eight and 11.
And if I introduce it right, get in here
inside of the try,
maybe try, get like this
and you guys tell me the output. Now
one noise,
you have two noise, three noise.
So one, two, three.
And then we encounter an issue and then
five is printed one, two, three, and five.
Then four is printed.
No issues but this one.
Yes, this one is also printer.
Three, five, five, all issues.
But after that we get an IT
so this is ignored.
Then we
can discuss
block, handle decision
and this one handle this issue? No.
And this handle
yes nine one can handle this issue.
All right.
So we go inside the nine, then ten
if ignored
and we see the 11,
So we get one,
two, three, five, four, five,
nine and 11.
Is there anyone who is confused? Yes.
Let let me not make it more complicated.
Okay.
And let me show you this example.
So you guys get you got the basic idea.
That's all I want to do.
So now let's get back to the slide.
So important point about prior block.
If any exception occurs in three block,
then control comes out to be or comes
out of the prior block and executes
appropriate catch BLOCK.
Does this make sense nowadays, the line
which is causing the
issue the moment that line
executed that line,
even if there are 100 lines below
that line, all will be ignored
and Java will look for the appropriate
catch.
BLOCK Is this clear? Right.
This line.
Okay.
After executing appropriate catch block,
even though we use the runtime statement,
control
never goes to prior block
to execute the rest of this statement.
So often executing the
it will never go back to try and execute
the rest of the code.
Not this is not what order does.
It will then come out of the traffic as
block and execute the rest of the court.
It never goes back to do try
each and every prior
block must be immediately
followed by a catch block
that is no intermediate.
The statements are allowed
between try and catch.
Yes. No, we can do loops,
but control never goes
back to the line which caused the problem.
So this line is saying that after
they try,
we should immediately
have the catch blocks out.
Like, for example, I cannot do this.
I cannot just make some space, declare
some variables in between
or something like this or not.
This is not
they are attached to each other
and we cannot work any code between
where they try and and where to get start.
Okay, no code in between.
So each and every try block
must immediately be
by catch block.
There is no intermediate
statements are allowed
between try and get
each and every prior
block must contain at least one catch.
So if you are writing it right,
there must at least one catch block.
But it is highly recommended
to write multiple
catch blocks for generating multiple user
error messages.
Okay.
So instead all suggest printing all
the time something went wrong
either you should
create separate catch blocks for the
that can cause problems
and you should print separate
out of the messages or provide
separate fixes for those issues.
Okay.
One try blocking contain
another try block that is nested or inner.
Now I want you to read these containers,
read all of these points
and let me know if something is confusing.
You let me know once
you guys are done reading
and all
looks good,
let me move.
Here's a little bit about quick break.
So try getting used to handle exceptions
inside.
Try it inside catch block
after block of statements which generates
user friendly error messages
and it will contain our backup code.
So put the problematic code inside.
Try in number two, saying
almost saying would not go back like loop.
Yes, yes. You know
yes you are right
it it's not like going
to the code above the line above.
Once you pass through that line of code.
Oh my God.
So you saw some important points about it.
Get blocks
catch block will never execute.
Exceptions
occurs in the prior block,
so catch block will execute the exceptions
that occur.
That's how I feel that.
So we can write multiple catch blocks
for generating easy peasy.
Right.
I like for Java just four
and 85 flies and around 250.
That was easy peasy, right?
And you guys will be good.
So still it's a lot to
then you guys will be revising,
but when you guys will be revising,
everything will make much more sense.
And will be way easier
to go through these slides.
Now, once you guys are done
building your frameworks,
everything will make much more sense.
And once you I recommend actually
when you are on your jobs,
once you have spent some time,
go to three months.
Please go back and
and read these slides again and everything
will make perfect sense.
I am trying to read
at least one lesson for that.
That's good.
That's very good, though.
Yes, we can write multiple catch blocks
for generating multiple user
error messages
to make your application strong.
What has told us about your two easy,
easy peasy?
Third,
how to survive back three first month.
You guys have already survived
those three months
plus three months, right?
No one is dead. All of you are alive
at that time.
Only one catch block is executed.
Even if we have multiple cat blocks,
Easy has its own implementation here.
I don't know how I am alive
or dead from inside.
She probably mean that he meant three
months at job or they will be easy peasy.
Most of the companies,
they will be kind of providing you
trainings, giving you
some videos or a resource will be assigned
who will be walking
through your different projects
of their company
procedures.
Policy
is how everything work in that company.
It is.
This scares me
days here is that if it is a tape,
find the most patient person in your team
and please be that the best friend
of that person of your company
in like this one week or so okay.
Please have a very good friendship
with that person
and make sure that person
has it has a lot of patience.
You guys, you guys will
be in much more good condition
if you get lucky.
You could even be waiting for
two plus months to get your equipment
and get paid to do nothing.
Usually companies first one or two months,
they will not be throwing
the tasks at you.
They will be providing you
some kind of training
the you can offer or hey,
why not offer that
20% to me, man I can help you out
in your issues. Feel
three months of practice,
then two months PTO,
then something else sounds great.
Yeah.
All right.
So at the time, only one
catch block will execute
out of multiple cash blocks.
In cash rock word,
declare an object of subclass,
and it will be internally referenced
by JVM.
Yes two It actually good set of all jokes
result in execution of more than one
catch block.
No, it's not possible at one time.
Only one catch block
powder, one try block.
I mean, I'm not talking about nested ones.
If we really try hard
to an interesting error, a mix of things
at ABC, the error that you encounter
first year of the
the dollar will everything after that
and it will try looking for appropriate
catch blocks it never gets the next line
not even the next operation.
For example if you try putting
multiple operations in the same line line
and then they are causing the moment
first error is encountered,
it will stop everything off contact.
So this will be called without breakage.
We have a variable.
I am trying to divide it by J
and we are not finding the exception.
This is the code we use right blocks
we have try.
We put the problematic code in here.
You guys need a break
and then we have the cache block.
So just give me 2 minutes.
The next slide is
about this task and I will give you a task
and a longer break
so that we can have some practice as well.
So let me just go through this slide.
A method to control
more than one exceptions.
To handle these exceptions,
we need multiple
catch blocks associated with a single try.
So, for example, instead of writing
this code in here,
I can also have a method.
Instead of all of this. Yes.
And my code.
Let me move this for now.
So now if I call this method in here
guys inside this try
all many types of adders or exceptions
this method can throw it
can throw multiple types of issues, right?
This method.
So I must have multiple catch blocks
if I want to avoid
all the issues there. What
I mean in here a method to control
more than one exceptions
and the code
welcome manner method
you'll get a What do you mean?
By main matter you mean can men can main
through multiple errors?
Any method, any method.
For example, in here I am.
I'm simply executing a method right now.
If let's say this method is coming
from a library
like selenium or coming from a library
like Apache Point.
I don't know what code
they have written inside that method.
Right?
So I can have multiple blocks
in that case as well,
or maybe a generic one in here.
In here.
So if I know what font, what kind of
what kind of instructions
this method is executing,
I will have an idea
what kind of issues it can probe.
So if this is the case, if I have a method
that is trying a more than one type
of exception
to handle these exceptions,
we also multiple case blocks,
a single try block can have multiple
catch blocks.
This is required when we try.
BLOCK had statements that generate
different types of exceptions.
Okay.
Although this is not recommended,
you should not attach
multiple catch blocks
if you are the one
who is writing that code
for each try catch block.
You should.
This is this.
This is this is a rule of thumb.
It's not actually mandatory
for each break.
BLOCK You should create a separate method
and inside of that method, right,
that specify should write, that specify,
try and get block and then call
those methods inside that file.
So if first catch block contains
the exception class
object, then subsequent
catch blocks are never executed.
The moment the dowel finds the appropriate
catch block, it
ignores the rest of the catch blocks.
The last catch block and multiple
catch blocks must be an exception. One.
So this is the last.
This should be the last one.
So that if you are not handling
a specific area,
if you don't have a specific catch.
BLOCK and by any chance
you encounter that error,
you still have something
that can catch that at it.
This is because our compiler
gives an error saying that subsequent
catch blocks have not been reached.
Now, some of you can try this as well.
Instead of putting this exception
at the last, if you try to put this
catch block as the first block
now you will get an error.
Can you guys tell me why?
Why did Java complain
when I put the exception clause first
and the rest of the classes after that
and by the way, error says
exception has already been caught. Yes.
So now I am putting more generic class
on top and specific ones later,
but the java looks for the catch blocks
from top to bottom.
No matter what kind of error we encounter,
this exception can handle all of them.
Right?
There's the parent of all the errors,
all the exceptions.
So what will happen
every time this block will be
the dollar will never be able
to execute these blocks
because exception can handle
all their issues.
Is the parent of all.
You will never never be able to reach
that those specification blocks.
So that's why you get an error.
If you try to put a more generic exception
on top of a more specific exception.
So these should be in proper
order in in proper visibility.
I should not put more generic
ones on top.
Yes. The exception of all
the exceptions must be lost.
Okay, here is your task
and let's have a break.
So at work we will use the exception
mostly or none of them.
Plus two more specific ones, then
more generic ones.
So let me tell you how to handle
input mismatch exceptions.
Input mismatch exception occurs
when user tries solve.
Let's say for example,
you are using the scanner class too
big may be an integer as the input
and if someone to enter a string
dialog
will throw input mismatch exception.
So you guys have to write a piece of code
that's going to avoid this.
Okay.
So is this problem paradise
declare and
try to take the triangle big
and integer
as the input using the scanner class.
But instead of entering the integer
in your console, try to enter this thing.
Then you will get this exception.
Now you have to write a to at your block
that can avoid this issue.
And then you have to write
piece of code that can throw
multiple types of exceptions
and you have to store
those exceptions in a list
and then you have to return that list.
Okay.
How much time will be enough case for this
15 minute for the tasks and.
15 minutes for the break are enough.
BLOCK Yes.
And I said we only have 1.5,
three months.
Okay.
I will show you how to do that.
So then let's have a break for containers.
Okay.
So at least try one problem.
At least try the first one. Okay.
And 15 minutes for break.
5 minutes for the first task.
And the other one.
I will show you how to do that.
And please remind me about the reporting
and please be back by
143. Thank you.
So let's see if we have this piece. Poor
that is taking the integer
and simply printing it out.
And so if I try to execute this code,
if I enter integer eight, it looks fine.
I entered and I get back then. All right,
so you have designed
your application to avoid.
But let's say
what if So user enters maybe a string.
So if you try to do that,
you will be getting input mismatch
exception.
Okay.
So what we can do,
instead of simply writing these scanner
programs, now we can use
the exception handling, right?
So what we can do may be
we can see, try
and put the piece of code
that is causing the issue inside.
We try block
scan or x integer,
and then in the case we can see
input mismatch exception
and then we can print out anything
but a message.
Maybe
only numbers are allowed if
does enter the number I entered,
then all works fine.
If I tried right or anything else.
Then it is only numbers are okay
and you guys can try
to prepare the input again
and you can make the program more robust.
This is how you guys do it.
Yeah, but first
you create a static method
that will return a list of exceptions
inside your method.
Create objects for exception classes
using private blocks
and store them inside your list.
Call your method inside the main
and print the name and or details
of all the exceptions right through to.
By the way,
let me tell you a little bit about this.
Look, do you guys know how I am?
How can we write our own shortcuts?
So, for example, I am writing, writing c
and if I
hit enter, it drives public
static interior.
Or if I am writing public static void, it
drives the public static word.
I promise to tell you the right.
Okay.
Remind me at the end.
Long time ago.
Let me finish the exceptions then we will.
By the way, it's called live templates.
Okay, so public static void
and instead of void.
So what should be the return time, guys?
I didn't promise.
I just said that I will show you
at the end of the class.
I never made a promise
right?
So the requirement said that
it should return a list of exceptions.
So can I return a list of exceptions
if I have void?
Would be List of what, guys?
What should I put inside
the diamond operator?
Yes. The parent class name.
Right. Because that class
can handle can store
the objects of all the child classes.
Right.
So get
exception
list.
Okay, so I say list, I say
and it is
the exception
listing of new
entities.
Then I write it. Try
and inside the try.
I see.
Let's say
are you creating method outside? Yes.
It's the method outside of me
being name is equal to all
name dot
lowercase.
And if I do that with the exception,
I will get guys
starting
which type of exception
I will get null pointer exception.
So null pointer exception and e
and once I get to that exception,
the object of that exception
will be stored inside this variable.
So I can say at least dot add and E
right then I can write another try.
BLOCK and then maybe
I can see
and they are required
continue in the minus five
and in here this time I will be getting
negative at a size
exception.
So once I get the exception again,
the catch block will be executed
and insert the catch block.
I am simply adding
that exception to the list
and once I am done, I will return
the list. All right.
You guys can create more predicate
blocks in here.
So writing different bycatch
blocks, intentionally
introducing inside the retry blocks
so that Java executes the catch blocks.
But this time, instead
of printing out the error message
or something like that, the object
that Java is throwing,
I am adding that to a list.
And once I am inside
the main method,
I can get back
so I can write a loop for it.
So I can see
that exception.
He is equal to that exception list
and then print out
using the.
So this is not but in the place
if the method will print out the details.
Okay.
So printing details of exception.
So I get past the details
about null pointer exception.
Then I get the details about negativity
and you guys can add as many as you want.
Is it clear guys, that
more examples? Yes.
I will be releasing more apples today.
So these are some of the rules.
You guys want me to share the code,
therefore, if you guys want, I can
like, for example,
if if it is not clear, you guys can ask me
and I can explain that
line of code, that's way too
nice to go through this code
and let me know if something is not there
there.
Good.
Or it can be anything.
You can you can call it E.
There's just a variable.
So why do we need this just in practice
to make sure that you guys understand
that inside of these variables
we actually get the objects
of these classes
and we can store those objects
and can pass through other
methods and can get the details
in other methods as well.
So let's say, for example,
if you guys are not to show
the error messages inside this method,
you can take these objects for stored
the list and pass them to another method
and can handle the errors.
There.
I do not understand why we are doing list
because we want to return
all the added lists
can hold multiple objects.
So I am returning a list
and I am adding all the objects in here.
Can you send the first task to your
is just
a practice
to make sure that you guys understand
how these objects can be used
in other methods as well.
So this is again the same thing at a time.
Only one exception occurs.
And at the time one
catch block is executed.
Okay.
Yes, I will release the happens
and all catch blocks must be ordered
from most the specific to most in general.
I don't put more general blocks
on top
and then Baltimore specific after that
because that way
Java will always execute the first one
and the other ones will never be executed
and you will be getting an error. Then
now they finally block.
So as we have the catch block
that handles the appropriate error,
we also have the finally block
that we can write with the try.
BLOCK It's not mandatory,
but sometimes if let's say
you are using some resources
in your prior block,
you should
always close those resources in the cache
BLOCK You guys remember,
we worked with files
and the files in in files.
I told you to write.
So in our framework, we'll.
Is that those back in here?
If we go inside of the accelerator?
I told you to write this file.
Import streamed or close?
Yes, we are finally done with Java.
So I told that it is important.
Why? This is important, guys.
Why we should close the input themes.
Because if that file is left open,
others will not be able
to perform operations on that file.
Right. But what happens, guys?
So you are opening that file
when you write this line of code.
And if you get any of the exceptions
in between, if any of these
if any of this code is throwing any add,
it, will this line be executed
and the file will be left open.
Right.
So that's why I told you that
when we learn about API cache blocks,
we will fix these methods.
So instead of throwing this exception,
what should we do Now?
I am removing this
and I am placing this code
inside
a prior block.
So I take this code
and I put it inside the right block.
Okay, Next we make it smaller and then
I add. Right.
So now
if I want to make sure
that this code is accessible, this this,
this variable is accessible,
I should declare it
before the try block
So I wrote this try now,
I should drive proper cache.
BLOCK And I should.
So if a file is not found,
I will be getting file
not found exception right?
So in that case
I can write it dot
but in stack place, right
And if let's say
there happens an input output exception
I think they are same
inspector's file.
So let's say if they ha
if there is an adult deal
if files present.
But there was an issue
reading that file again,
maybe the hard drive is crap.
It is unable to give you the data
or anything goes
wrong with the operating system
and you are unable to read that file.
So you will be getting
input output exception
and you can also get this input output
exception.
Let's say there is not
there is no enough disk space
and you are trying to create a new file
on the disk.
So then you will also get
this input output exception.
So it's good now
that we are using the deprecated catalog.
So anything goes wrong, our complete
framework will not be stored,
the proper cache block will be executed.
But what about this closing thing? Right?
So I want to make sure that
no matter what, if the error occurs
in here, in here, in here, anywhere,
this code, I always want to execute.
So for that I have this.
Where this finally block
does is it is always executed.
It is always executed.
And we need to initialize
this variable in here.
Where is this
excellent.
We need to initialize
this as well outside of the car.
I closed this
so I again use prior catch block
because this can also throw an error
and I checked if it is not null
so that I don't get another exception.
Okay.
Then only I want to close this.
So now my method is perfect.
How it is perfect
if let's say I am trying
to use the filing for name and,
the port is not correct.
I will get the error right on this line
at this line party.
Okay. In here.
So nothing will be executed from here.
I and the improper
catch block will be executed.
And then this finally block is executed
and inside this, finally I am checking.
Your filing system is not null.
Then I am closing it.
But let's say everything goes good.
Everything goes well.
I execute all the line
then the cache block is aggregated,
but still finally block is executed.
So no matter what,
if your catch blocks are executed or not,
or no matter if you encounter
an added or not, if everything goes
well or if everything does
not go well, this finally
is executed.
Always the moment you have entered
this try,
go make sure that it
this finally block.
So whatever important operations
are there in my code,
where should I put them?
I should put them inside the final block.
Because why?
I cannot pull them inside the try block
Because if I get an error in on this line,
nothing below this line executes.
So it's not safe to put them in here.
I cannot put them inside the catch block
because catch
blocks are only executed
when we encounter error.
So it's also not safe to put them in here.
But this finally
is a block.
No matter if all the code executes
or no matter if none of this is executed.
Java makes all this is always executed.
So backslide.
This finally block is the right block
where I should put
the import code cleanup code.
So let me first
show you with another example
why it is important.
I will tell you first, let me show you
and show that in law seven
So we have this
five block.
So I have written this code, guys,
and we zoomed to Java
after a few review classes.
I was back to normal.
It will be fine, I think,
because I didn't give you a short demo.
That's why you guys got lost.
So the right now
can you guys
tell me if I execute this code which lines
I will see on output?
So if I execute this code, I get seven
and 12.
Let's say I got an ad,
I have written something
that is causing the error,
which lines I will get now
let me replace this with the numbers.
One, two,
three.
Now please.
Back three and four.
And now tell me one,
three and four
after the output of this.
Finally, guys.
So if everything goes well,
still finally block is executed.
If I get an exception to still
finally block is executed.
If I get an exception
inside the edge,
what are what I will get now?
So what we understand from this example
that once
Java has this try block,
no matter what happens in this area,
Java, all these always executes this part.
So what does this mean?
It means if I am opening
some critical resources,
which should be closed
before so that others can use them.
I should close them inside the final block
because I know
no matter what goes wrong,
Java will always execute
this finally block Do you guys understand
the point of finally why?
Why finally is important?
Like, for example, I can put some
I can try to close the files
inside the try block, but I can
I don't understand why not?
Three Because before three,
we are getting an added layer.
Because three, we are getting an error
the moment we, the added
Java does not execute anything else
and it checks for the proper
catch block and there is no catch block.
That's why it is not executing.
So what happens is that
no matter if anything,
so what is finally here?
In our case,
we are closing the file inside
of finally
why we are closing it inside the finally,
because know if we get any issues
during the process of reading the data,
we are still sure
that the file will be closed.
If let's say there are no issues,
we are still closing the file.
So no matter what happens,
we are always, always closing
the critical system resources
and that's why
we should use the final block.
This block is always executed.
And no matter what, no matter
if we get an exception here, in here,
in here, anywhere inside the traffic edge,
no matter where we are, the exception.
This is always executed.
Is it possible then to put finally on
the top with good cause and then try get.
No, no, this is not possible.
This is not possible.
Finally. Must have a try. BLOCK
Finally must have it right below.
So why Java guys created this finally?
BLOCK Java guys created this finally block
so that we can put important code
in here in the case of exceptions in
get in try anywhere.
We are always always sure that
this code is always executed.
So in here
we are getting an exception in guys,
we are getting an exception in try
but still Java execute.
They finally block.
So how how
we should use this
Finally BLOCK How I am using this finally.
BLOCK So so I wrote a piece of code
in which I was opening a file,
an Excel file.
Now, this is an important system resource,
which we should close
as soon as we are done using it
so that others can use it on
our computer can finally use without try.
No, we can use.
Finally we try.
Like for example, we can automate
the catch block, finally try.
And right after that
we can have finally block
for example, we can do this one.
I can remove this catch and here
I can have it.
And then finally, this is possible,
but you ask me that again.
We have the finally block of
without the try.
This is not possible.
So I was using a system resource,
a critical one,
an important one that I should close
always. Now.
So what I did, I created a try block.
I placed all the code inside in here.
The code it can cause issues, right?
This file is not found.
So let's say let's assume we have
this scenario.
File was found.
We we we read all the data, we read
everything we're storing.
Tired of the Excel.
And if everything goes well, these two,
they will never be executed right.
But this finally will still be executed.
So we come in here and we check
if that file input stream object
not null. Why?
I am checking this
because in some scenarios it can be null
and it will cause a null pointer
exception.
If I blindly try
to call a method on this object.
So it's always a good practice to check
your objects if they are null or not.
So I am checking that
and I am closed in the system.
Resource this file. Interesting.
Now let's assume there was an error
in here, right?
I was reading that something was wrong.
So this part is not executed.
So we get an error on this line
so this part will not be executed.
Java is the appropriate catch block,
but still this part will be executed.
So by putting the code that is closed
in that system
results in final, I am now sure
that in all the scenarios, my
important system
resource will always be closed.
Okay,
that's why we are doing this
and we should always have this
generic exception as well.
At the end
like this.
So is it clear right now?
No. Ask me if something is not clear
now, ask me why I am using finally
or why I am doing something like this.
Finally is a block
that is always executed.
So I put the code that I want to always
execute inside of the final block
when you guys
will be opening database connections.
That clause is just a regular clause.
It's just a method.
It is just a matter.
It will just close your file.
Yes. Disclosure Fine.
So finally is not mandatory,
but good to use if try. Yes.
Yes. It's good to use. Yes.
Database connections in school.
They are also very expensive resources,
so we should
also close them.
Why would then rechecking
if it is not empty?
So we know if our file is
what to keep know.
So let me let me show why I am checking
if it is not null.
So not just closing. Finally. Yes.
Eskil, is this topic cardinal?
It's very easy.
I mean, you guys will not believe me,
but this is way
easier than Java. Yes.
Let me send the guys told me.
What can I do?
APIs.
They are a little hard
as compared to good.
But what if we have error in file in
we still have file import stream in.
Finally.
Yes. Perfect So if we have an error
in filing for stream,
this returns in null value.
That's why I am checking for this
null condition in here.
So let me show you why
I am checking.
So let's say guys,
I provide a
wrong bar ten here.
I don't know why,
but my friend spent the most time
learning a skill,
then learning basics of programing always.
Because
as school guys, they have a separate job.
They are called database administrators.
There is a separate to in the industry
for just for school.
If you know school well,
you can get a separate job.
It's like a developer and ask that,
no, it's not that it is used instead,
but it's a separate role.
Yes, it is used in aspect.
It is using
maybe she is doing back and testing.
That's why she keeps on learning school.
So yes.
And just to observe the lesson,
you guys can also do that.
So, guys,
let me show you how that method is
is improved now.
So I am providing a wrong part in here.
Yesterday we only updated the accelerator,
so let me
right now I am providing a wrong path.
If I don't use try, I catch block
inside that accelerator.
What will happen guys, if I
if I provide wrong
path in here, will
I get the normal flow
or my program will terminate abruptly?
I am trying to use that create method
and I am not using
catch blocks
it will terminate abruptly.
Right.
So we don't want to do that at any cost.
So we wrote the try catch block.
So let's understand how that try
catch block is helping us in here.
So I debug discord.
Let's go step by step.
And if I want to see how execution,
how I executing all the code line by line
inside this method,
should I click, step over
or step into, step into.
Right. So I go in here
inside of that method
which we updated with try get block.
So now Java will first
create these variables.
Right now what is the value is null right?
And because we have provided a wrong path,
Java will not be able to find any file
on this spot right?
So lot of work will happen.
Nothing will be assigned
to this variable,
this file in pristine right.
Nothing will be assigned to this variable.
And guys see is null
and the Java has jumped
right after that to the appropriate
catch block.
It is clear up till this point.
So I got an exception
because I didn't provide proper path.
Then you last repeat last
then you last part, please. Yes.
So I didn't provide the proper path,
so I got the exception
file not found
because my path was just a random string
and I have bad actually jumped
to the catch block right.
So now
in this scenario, I never opened the file.
So do I need to close that file? Right?
If I have never opened the file,
do I need to close it?
No, I don't need to close it.
So Java will execute the appropriate block
and it comes inside the final block
and I am checking
if file theme is not null,
then only close.
But right now
it is not really to execute this code.
Close code, it will not execute it.
Right. So that's why I put this condition.
If I never open the file,
which file I should close.
Right. I don't to close any file.
So that's why I write this if condition.
And now let's imagine the happy scenario.
Okay, so we go back
and then let's say maybe this
time we provide the proper part.
Let me copy this
and let me debug it again.
So I press step into
and then I execute line by line.
So this time file import
stream is not null
and it has something in here which mean
the file has open file has been opened.
And this time after doing everything,
I get some kind of exceptions.
Right. But file was opened.
So again I an exception
and I get this time
in null pointer exception
so appropriate cache block is executed
and now
I again check if the file is open.
So file was opened this time but
we got an exception later on.
Right.
So should I close the file now, guys?
Do I need to close the file? Yes.
So again, check file is not empty,
so I closed that file and I
pretended did that.
So if file is not opened,
I check it with an if condition.
If I don't open, I don't need to close it.
If file is opened and I got an issue
later on,
that means I need to close that file.
So I should write it inside
the finally block.
No matter if all the code is executed
properly, no matter if I get errors,
no matter at which point I got the errors,
I am always making sure
that my file is closed.
It's a critical system resource,
so that's why I used
they finally
because finally BLOCK is always executed.
Does it make sense now
why we updated that file, how we used?
They try catch block, so that's why we
updated this
reader industry.
And let me check if we can
also do the same.
So tell me, guys, which so
let me right
so I am here I am again opening a file
this file input stream right.
So the code that can cause problems,
I put it inside,
they try, then I write
catch for example like edge file
not found exception
and I simply put into the error.
But at the same time
I don't want my application
to terminate abruptly.
And then let's say maybe I see a final.
So now to make sure
that I can access this variable,
I must declare it outside of this.
Try a block.
And that's why
I have to declare this in here.
That's why I change this code
like this.
So I access it inside of the.
Finally I checked if
I file import theme is not equal to null
then only I want to close it.
Then only I want to close it.
And I can also not access
this property file.
This property object.
This should also be outside of
right block
and I can not really clear a variable
and all my code looks good.
I have now incorporated catch
and finally blocks inside my code.
And I can also put this condition in here
like this
using this shorthand operator.
So now my please share the code,
but it will not be better
if I push this code
or you guys want to share it in.
Cool in like ten.
This was about to finally block
the code inside.
The finally clause will always be
even if an exception is thrown from
within the try or the catch block.
If your code has a latency
it won't entirely try or edge block.
The code inside of the finally block will
then get executed
before returning from the method.
So even if you are writing
the written statement, be you guys know
after the written statement
Java executes nothing.
But if you have written statement
still Java executes.
They finally block
the main usage of finally block
is to do cleanup job keeping cleanup.
And finally, block is always
a good practice when no exceptions
are that guard.
And even if the exceptions occur,
it's still good to.
Execute your code inside of the it,
but it's optional.
Sometimes you guys will be needing it,
sometimes you will not be needing it.
You can
finally block the entire program
or for each try block
There can be zero or more catch blocks,
but only one finally.
So I cannot have multiple finally only one
finally.
BLOCK
So there are only
this this this is the only scenario
where we are finally.
BLOCK is not executed
if we explicitly try to system or exit
or by causing a fatal error
that causes the process to abort,
which means your JVM is crashed.
Something has happened in that case.
Java will not definitely
will not be able to execute.
Right?
Because Java itself is kind of now
destroyed from your computer.
So in that case, obviously
it will not be able to do that.
It's just an example
finally block in here.
So this is an important interview
question.
The interviewers might try to confuse
you between final and finally.
BLOCK because they look similar.
So you guys
know, finally the keyword use
with the method
variables or classes.
And for example,
if we don't want any other class
to inherit from our class,
we'll use final.
If we don't want the method
to be overridden in the child classes
we use final.
If we don't want the value of a variable
to be changed, we use final.
But finally, on the other hand, it's
not a keyword, it's a block.
Finally is used to place important.
It will be executed well.
That exception is handled or not rendered.
Okay, so you can have try and directly
finally, finally the block.
And while final is a keeper.
So let me and
let me show you one more thing
so that you guys don't
get confused.
What do you guys think?
If I get an error before this try.
BLOCK
We will.
Will the
final block still be executed or not?
So this time
I'm having an issue outside of this try.
BLOCK
Yes, this time, finally.
BLOCK will not be executed
because we never started to try.
BLOCK We never entered the block.
So it is only executed once.
We are inside the try.
If anything is going wrong, the
above my piece of code,
I cannot make sure that my finally block
is still executed.
Okay?
It is only executed when one site entered
retry block because it makes sense, right?
If I am not executing any piece of code
that can cause problem,
this has been why I should execute
the finally block, right?
At least one
line should be executed inside the try.
Then it makes sense to use the finally
so if something is happening outside of
my, then it is not executed
and then
finally BLOCK will not be executed.
Is it clear right.
Only when I entered the applied block.
So then we have this throws, keyword and
literal keyword.
So let's say
let's say, Guys,
I am writing a method and what I want.
I don't want to write the prior
catch block inside this method,
but instead instead what I want
is that whoever
also this method should provide
should write the try again.
So, so.
So I am not sure how to handle this
exception.
So what instead I am doing
I want to do that once
the error is thrown by Java,
I simply hand that
over to the caller of that method.
So if I want to do that, then
instead providing the traffic edge,
I have this upset
option add exception to method signature
like abstract.
Yes. So I
don't want to provide the implementation.
I don't want that catch block.
I don't want to write it back because I
maybe I don't know how to handle that
exception
or may be someone who will be calling.
This method has better idea
how to handle this issue.
So what I can do, I can use rules, keyword
and the name of the exception
that is
that can be thrown by my piece of code.
Now, whoever will be calling
this method has to provide it.
Try as block.
Yeah.
So whoever is calling this matter
now, he must provide a prior block right.
So it's like I gave you some homework
and you gave that homework
for someone else.
So this is also possible.
How this is possible with the pros given.
And after that,
I write the name of the exception
and then whoever will be calling
my method.
Yes, temporarily.
The remedy will have will be providing
the implementation for that error.
Okay.
So when you guys will be working in teams,
maybe you guys want to
handle all of your issues in one,
so every one of you will be throwing
that exception
with the help of this throws keyword
to the caller and then the will combine
all those exceptions
and will write all the catch blocks
and will fix those issues.
So if you want, this is also possible.
So that's what you guys have been doing
till now.
You remember you have been adding this
clause to this method signature of main.
So you are
giving
this responsibility to the Java Dark Java.
I don't know how to handle this.
You handle it
and how Java was handling it by simply
throwing error message on the console
and terminating your program.
So this is how Java handles it.
And so let's say, for example,
if you don't want
to handle in here as well,
you can go again, maybe throw it to start
to add someone else and you can write
clause and again file not so.
So now Java will handle it,
but how has this default handle?
It? Simply trolled the error message
and closed your program there.
How Java handles
it just so there are all the possible.
So I will keep trying until unless finally
someone put trying to code.
But the program is executed
in case of thread or slave.
The time will be executed totally. Yep.
Yes. Throwing the problem at each the.
So how about the program is executed
in case of third or slip
the time will be executed to sleep? Yes.
So back to Trader Dart slip it throws
a very special unique
exception
and it's very rare that it occurs.
It's very rarity.
That's why you guys never had any problems
executing that predatory.
Yes. And under special case,
it happens when your processor
so your trader sleep
what it actually doing
it pulls your thread or to slip.
And if you have written
a piece of code inside the thread slave
which will continue slipping all the time,
then out for some time,
your processor will go and check,
Hey man, you have to wake after some time.
It's been very long.
You, you, you are sleeping.
Then your CPU will throw that
exception so that you don't
write to such programs.
We just keep on executing always and doing
nothing just to sleeping.
So clause is a keyword in java language
which is used
to throw exception,
which is raised in the call.
The method inside the calling method
throws keyword
always followed by a method signature.
We write this clause,
then the name of the exception
and then the name, then the brackets.
Pro's keyword is mainly used for handling
jacketed exceptions.
Okay.
But you can also use it for uncheck
and exceptions. So
it gives an information
to the programmer
that there may occur an exception.
So it's better for the programmer
to provide try get.
BLOCK Okay,
So this was a simple piece of code.
You wrote another method
and inside that matter now you use true
schema in a you are trying
this input output exception.
So now whoever follows
this display method has
to provide breakage.
And finally we have the true keyword
being baby D'Aloisio.
Back to
who? Let's say guys,
now you you are champions, right?
Professional as that ingenious.
Qualified as that ingenious. Right.
You guys can start testing
nuclear reactors
and they will just work fine
example So
and now you want to build
your own exceptions.
We will of the world.
Okay, So if you want to
write your own exceptions
like Java guys did like
so for example,
this file not found exception
if we go inside of this file,
you see this through new Let's say
you want to do something
like this,
you are building a new framework.
You want to have a standard mechanism
to handle data.
So you want to also throw the errors
like Java guys have done in the JDK.
Maybe you are working
or writing your own custom exceptions.
Then you can also do that.
You can create your own exceptions
and you can use this
through keyword.
So let me
create an account class
with this simple account class and
inside this account class
we have public
static word
method.
So how you can create your own exceptions
to create your own exceptions,
you guys, it's simple.
It's like inheritance.
So you create a class.
Let me created outside in here, let's say
insufficient balance.
And it's a kind of
standard to put the exception keyword
after the exception plus.
So insufficient balance exception.
So if you want to create your own
exceptions, you can do so
by extending it from the
exception class.
And then can we create on simple
custom
made seems with the Java after school.
Yes. Or one you can.
Yes. Yep.
So I write the constructor
and I simply call
and pass this message in here.
So I have created my own exception.
It's very simple.
You just have to
inherit you.
You just have to create a class,
make it inherited from exception class
and that's it. Who?
Now I write this
that this.
That's a good draw method.
So I take in number out
and I check if
if the user
is trying to enter in negative amount,
I want to throw an exception right
like java.
Guys are throwing exceptions on us
and if file is not found
and we encounter null pointer
index out of bounds.
So we we are also now want to build
that mechanism inside our framework.
So what I can see, I can see through
new and then the name of the custom class
in sufficient balance exception.
And I can write, render or
sorry
I'm all
got the
negative.
Yeah.
Like this.
And now
because I am throwing an exception,
I must mention it
inside the body clause
and then in sufficient badness.
Right.
So now I have also developed
this mechanism inside of my framework.
So what will happen now
if someone is using my code,
my API account
to withdraw
if it enters the positive amount?
I don't get any shows.
But you see
now my code is also giving an error.
So this is how this Java guides
have developed these APIs
and it says
surrounded with dry at block you see.
So I have created my own exception.
My own exception.
And now if anything goes well,
I get no issues.
If I say
I, if I try entering
negative numbers.
So I get the on the exact same pattern.
You see, this was the message
that I specified amount got to be negative
so divided by zero
file is not found all of these messages
how how they are based in here because
once so
once I encounter that specific scenario
I specify the message that I want
this name of the exception
glass is automatically taken by Java
and all this information about the ad
or the line
number, the package and all that.
That's what I was asking
earlier, showing the lines.
Okay, so this is how you guys
can create your own exceptions
and you can use the exact same framework,
exact same mechanism
like dialog is are doing in JDK
to avoid the issues.
So you're showing the lines of all or not
all one exception. So
so how can we create our own custom
exceptions, create a class,
make it extend from exception,
and then all the
this the super and pass
this method inside the constructor.
Now the template that is writing
and then how to use those exceptions.
Wherever you want to use those exceptions,
use the true keyword, create
the object of that class amount, be active
and throw it
using the pro keyword
amount account class.
Yes, this is the account class
and that's the task team.
You guys can call down your brands
after this
demo. 11.
So this is good demo 11
This would be the account,
right?
So in here
I am creating the exception in here
am using that exception and in here
someone is trying to use my code
and he is getting that exception.
So this is how I can use pro and throws
keyword and I can create my own
exceptions.
Are you guys alive or dead
right from inside?
Are dead
fully dead?
Okay, so no more Java from today.
Yeah,
you guys did it alive, but completely.
You guys.
You guys can be very good actors.
And the days of you is
now I will be on your Monday is as well.
I am sad you are to Java class.
Don't worry.
We still have classes.
I still have to use guys. No, I can.
I can better reunion review classes
than the normal classes.
Right?
I don't know how to review all Java
the list of.
I also don't know.
Maybe you can try reading the slides
if it's
working that
how to begin.
So let me quickly go through the slides
and then then I can
I can see your drama.
So in Java,
throw keyword videos to throw an exception
explicitly using true keyword,
we can throw Jack unchecked
and user defined
so we can basically throw anything.
We can start from the first class.
Actually, it's a good idea
to start from the first class. Now
at least maybe one class per day.
And I think a little bit of code
karaoke word is mainly used to throw
the custom exceptions.
Only object of deployable class
or subclass can be thrown.
So let's say for example, if you
generate yes, we can start all over again.
It's the
we cannot throw any other objects
like for example, instead of this,
if I try to set through a new account,
I cannot do that.
Okay.
Only the exception.
I can only use
this keyword with exception classes
program
execution
stops on encountering true statement
and the closest catch statement
is tagged for a matching.
So let's say for example, if there was
a cache block inside that specific matter.
Plus java will prefer that one.
If not, will check
who who called this method.
So if a proper cache block is present over
there,
it will throw that exception in there.
If not, then it will to check
whoever called that method.
Throw the Mac into the window.
Please don't do that.
We have saw and saw.
One can take that Mac and
so when someone is throwing the Mac
from the window,
please be outside of that window.
Your chance
program execution
stops on encountering the pro
awkward always should exist
within the method of body.
I can not use that with classes or const.
I can use it with constructor
but not with classes.
Okay.
Whenever anybody container stroke ever,
then the call
method should be followed by it
throws keyword.
Yeah.
So inside method we use true
with the header of the method
we use to rows
with s
is just an example,
but only work by the way you can throw
already building exceptions as well.
So it's not mandatory that you always have
to create your own exception.
Right.
We can throw arithmetic null
point about anything that
these are some thoughts
for you. Yes.
And I just give me one more method.
So throw is used inside
the method body and truth
with Astrobee
that is used with the header of the body.
So throw is used to explicitly throw
an exception.
Throw is followed, an instance
throw is used within method body.
You cannot throw multiple exceptions,
only one at a time.
True keyword can be used
in which case using java
proceeds user to declare an exception
to tell
that this method
can throw some kind of exceptions,
It is followed
by the name of that Class B,
whose exception can be thrown
through is used with the method signature
you can declare multiple exceptions.
For example, a single method
can throw multiple types of exception.
For example, I can write
comma and then
maybe null point of exception like this,
so I can specify multiple.
Last year I bought MacBook and I got
two laptops instead of one by accident.
Oh my God.
What is it?
Are you serious?
Inside the same box
rules.
Keyword cannot be used anywhere
except on method of declaration.
Lying to a different.
And here we go.
All for 180
485 slides.
And you guys are still alive, private
and ready
to learn the frameworks and all that.
Finally.
So two different boxes or two deliveries.
Also, guys, if you have any suggestions
this Java course, please,
please send me those suggestions.
You can send me a direct message.
What does that mean?
It means dancing and party
and having fun with your friends.
We are flying
moment.
Do you feel better now?
Just so you guys can send me the.
Where is Alexa?
Alexa, are you with us?
Glass bottle.
Does you guys still need a glass for us?
He was encapsulated two boxes
and one delivery.
First, I thought in one box, left
open opening, second one cable and so on.
But when I opened two boxes, I was like,
Come here, we will give you a party.
Is definitely if were.
Where is the glass for steams
that glass on streams
I will share of that as well.
That was really a perfect candle
for your drama glasses.
This glass should be
thought at least three times.
This section once.
Please display the three pages
before you end
this one.
You know this one?
Oh, I say it's simple.
It means you just have to watch this video
If you are video three
times, you can start working on it
right after I upload it.
Watching is different.
You you are two best.
If you were to go through that painting,
you let me to also go through that pain
three times.
The video. But
I'm not doing it.
That's why we have recordings.
But percentage of DOA and Java we do and
it's like ABC.
It's like alphabets of English, the Java
that you guys know.
I mean, using this knowledge,
you guys cannot build anything real
that can solve any real problem
if just know how to write code.
I mean, you guys cannot build anything
real, right?
Using This knowledge.
Can you guys build
anything that can solve a real problem?
Anything like Google Chrome,
Java, slide web
side side.
So it's just the basics
to know how to use libraries.
So the next steps from here are
if you really want to good applications.
The next steps are learning
about your data structures,
then learning about design
patterns and databases,
and then some frameworks which will help
you develop your applications and then
deploying and all that.
We definitely know how to create a dog
with pink
color.
How many percent did
we learn from the whole our language?
It's not even 1%, Nikolai.
It's just how to read our code.
The thing that you guys have learned
is it's just how to read
a little bit of Java.
Java is Java is huge
and very motivational.
So you guys are champion.
You guys can now work
with any library out there
and can start using that
and you can develop drawn to using Java.
You can program your microwave ovens,
you can build websites, games
and desktop applications
because the basics are clear now.
So you just now
have to learn some APIs, some libraries,
and then you just have to call
some specific methods
that those methods
will do all the stuff for you.
And that's how the applications are good.
At least we know how
to search on Google.
I mean, you guys can read Excel
files, right?
If if something very big reading an Excel
file, Right.
Great reading,
opening some websites on the
on the web
and then clicking on different buttons.
So you like you are learning selenium.
Now you can learn other tools
and with the help of Java, you will be
you will be able to do a much more
with the help of Java and that too.
So what is Matrix?
You told us we can work in nuclear reactor
and you said we only know zero
point to two.
Yes. To destroy a nuclear reactor
you just need to know
0.001
at least I know that
I don't know any Java.
Are you talking Gladiator Dog Day?
You serious now or not?
Please don't take me serious. No, no.
All of it was joke.
Despite learning you guys has Now
I am serious.
Let me. Let me be serious.
You guys done a marvelous job.
Please let me be serious.
Guys.
You guys, don't let me be serious
the way I always try to be serious.
Yeah, And we say that we know Java
now or it's not.
Yes, Yes, I am serious.
You guys know a lot.
He is bored at home,
so he is just making some fun with us.
So you guys know. All right.
Thank you very much.
You are a wonderful teacher.
You know how to explain
what to do in a good mode.
Thank you. You the three now
making fun of us, you mean?
No, no, no.
You guys are great, by the way,
you guys to ask me that?
How did compared to the previous back.
So you guys have done a very good job,
believe me.
Seriously.
And you guys can also
ask your other batch mates, like,
if you know someone in previous batches.
Believe me,
when they were done with Java, they were
barely responding to my
messages and these last class.
So I can see
still some of you are very active, happy.
Do we have review class?
Yes, we have a review class.
What about next class?
Which classes will you teach?
School classes actually, training.
You are amazing instructor.
I did not get bored at all.
Thank you.
Take some rest, guys, and we will
meet tomorrow.
Bye Bye.