Oh, All right.
Good morning, everyone.
Good morning, friends.
Folks, guys. Right.
I see you guys already active.
It is good to get good.
All right.
That short term, short term break, guys,
right from the classes.
Back to back classes. We have.
All right.
So how is he?
Actually, guys,
I don't think I ever ask students.
Right.
So how is it do you guys have enough time
between Saturday
and Sunday to adjust to the material?
No, Michael is being honest.
Not really.
I really need more practice.
Not that much time.
Okay, I see.
And because probably the classes
are long also.
So there's a lot of information.
Sometimes, yes. Sometimes no.
All right.
I see. Well, just one thing, guys.
We have I think we have today. Tomorrow.
Oh, sorry. Today.
Tomorrow we have Today
we have about three or four classes
that left to cover our Java basics. Right.
And then you guys will be moving
to the completely brain new concepts
and oops concept.
Very beautiful concept. Right.
But what I always suggest, guys,
I know that
because the classes and
especially probably Tuesday and Wednesday
right now,
you guys been spared in manual classes
but because they in the evening
time back to back
and because you guys have some work,
I'm sure.
So that's probably gives
you even less time, Right.
So but that's one thing does please,
please, please make sure you try to find
that time because we do hear from students
that they fall behind,
not usually, not at the Java part,
but only later when the concept starts.
Right.
I know it could be tough,
but try to put that time and effort
because what I always say,
if you look at your calendar, right,
if you're going to
look at the calendar days and
I have all of them, one moment,
you know, they go this way.
So this is your schedule, right?
This is your schedule.
So now when we're looking right,
we have a Java class.
So next week, on Tuesday and Wednesday,
what you guys will be starting
you guys will be starting with
get right to now
this class has become
also a technical right now.
So from next week
guys from the upcoming week
all your weekdays
and weekends will be very technical.
Okay.
And then after we learn this,
maybe we will.
So basically after that, guys,
Java starts for one month.
But good thing tomorrow, guys,
that it's still Java, right?
You are still learning only one topic.
But then what will start happening
guys later in December.
Don't look at the time time
we want to fix it.
Sure. 630. Don't worry about it.
We'll fix all of this.
But what will start happening is
you will start learning different topics
besides Java, right?
Besides Java, there will be more topics
and then these different things
that you guys will start learning.
So what will start happening besides Java?
You guys will be learning new things,
but you will have to remember Java
after Java, you guys, your testing tool
after test until there's more things
and there is more things, right?
So then the knowledge becomes a lot
and the speed will be the same.
That's one thing this year.
That's why the course is very intense.
That's what you guys, I heard from
your friends that it was a tense ride,
but it was all worth it.
So that's I guess please, please
make sure you guys put a time
and effort right This maybe between
Saturday, Sunday classes.
There's not that much time.
So try to put your practice on Mondays
right there.
Try to put your practice on Mondays
and please make sure you guys do
study additionally.
Right.
Don't just don't
just depend on the class coming.
All right, then try to watch those YouTube
channels and everything.
Just very quick.
Ten, 15 minutes video. Right.
And I promise you guys,
that will be very, very helpful to you
as well.
Hopefully, hopefully
guys for a little time with you guys.
So we'll have to put that effort
and sacrifice.
Right.
And usually then of the six months,
what we tell you guys before you go
in the market, Right, Because usually
students will have a full time job.
So it's hard for them to look for.
So we do tell you. Right. Be confident.
That's why you have to study.
You have to have the knowledge.
And usually students towards the end,
they do quit their jobs.
By then they put the effort right
within one or two months.
I have to find it.
So but that will all depend
on your knowledge.
Okay, so try and make sure you guys please
study practice
as much as you can right now.
I know there probably a lot of repetition
for you, but still, you know, repetition
that what makes it better yet
this very cool thing guys also
for give that
will give you installation
videos today or tomorrow.
So to make sure that you guys have it
before the class.
Right. Okay.
But that's all in the future, guys.
Well, in the future, right.
So today we are having our Java class
practice makes a perfect day go, right?
Yep. That's what happens.
And because it's a coding, Right.
It's a coding, guys.
It's something that you were most of you
never done before, right?
And now you have to do it.
So if you don't do it for a couple of
days, you'll be forgetting stuff, right?
But once you start doing every day,
right, then
it will become more
and more and more better.
Okay. All right.
That's good. Okay.
So today
we will continue looking into our loops.
And I hope you guys did your homework.
I hope you guys did a practice.
And as usual,
what are we going to do, guys?
We just going to have a quick question.
Why do you have to pass the plus seven?
Write a seven to be
have a question.
All right.
So let's go over what did you guys learn
yesterday?
Switch case.
And we started with the threads.
We did introduction on them.
So I can you tell me, guys,
what did you learn about this?
Which case,
I assure you, is always there
in which situation.
This verse.
Let's understand
why do we have switch keys
and when I'm going to use it right then.
Then we'll go for it.
Limitations in there.
Right?
Which case is faster than if else.
If else if.
Right.
Switch is clean and more clear. Right.
So whenever we want to check for equality
so we talk about the switch key switch
cases, another statement that be a part
of the conditional statements.
Right.
It it's it's a great substitute for
if else if
what do we use if else if one
we want to test multiple conditions right
so in here
what we want to check for multiple values.
Right.
So we're saying the switch case is a value
based statement.
Right.
So whenever we want to check the value
for the
value of providing multiple values
for the variable, right,
then it's a good choice to go for switch
case, Right?
When do we go for a switch case?
When we are checking for the equal ready.
Right. And it's a valid base.
So switch case with it.
It's a cleaner, it's
a faster version of the if.
Right.
What do we talk about
if we send if as a condition based,
when we talk about switches,
which is a value based.
Right.
And of course, there's no great things
that works for everything, right?
So each case
will have its own limitations, right?
It will have its own limitation, right?
It can work only right.
It can work
only with some of the data types.
Right?
We can work
only this by short integer, right.
Any can work with the charge and strings.
Right. Char and strips. Right.
And they are.
We cannot use operators such as logical
and such as what?
What kind of operators? We cannot use
relational.
Right.
So then when we look at the switch syntax,
right switch syntax.
Right. So we have a switch keyword, right.
So every single key words
have a meaning for Java, right?
Have a meaning for Java.
So what happens?
Basically guess what happens, right?
So whenever we write some code, right,
Whenever we write some code,
so Right,
so our code when we are clicking on safe.
Okay.
So when we clicking on safe, right,
our code is being compiled, right?
So that's why in case
if there's any issue, right,
in case of any issue,
if I'm trying to click on safe right
here, even before clicking on Safe,
it shows me the error, right?
It shows me the error
and the machine who shows us the error.
It's a compiler, right?
So, for example,
if I have an issue right now, enough,
if I'm going to try to run my code, right.
So what we will get we will get some error
that will be saying
unresolved completion problem.
So it means there was some
syntax issues, right?
There were some syntax mistakes and that's
why our call was not able to compile.
Right. The uncle was not able to come.
So only normally
after a code being compiled.
It means there is no errors, there's
no mistakes.
Only then this code is given to Java,
right?
Only then this code is given to Java.
So whenever you try to click on Run,
then what happens?
Java actually takes your code and the
start execute in line by line your code.
So by during
while we type in who checks all our issue,
it's our compiler checks
that issues things.
All right.
So whenever Java exec use the code
right it's
it comes to the switch right switch
is a keyword so Java knows okay switch.
So now I have to do what I have to do.
I have to check for this
here.
What do we specify inside?
This switch gets
or what is we just doing?
The review.
So what do we specify
inside the switch base?
We specify variable, right?
We specify a variable. Right.
So then our switch block starts, right?
Our sweet book starts
and inside is switch.
What do we have?
What do we have? This
we have keys is right.
This is the key says
What do we provide next to the cases
values.
We provide that value one
and then whatever the code we want.
Right?
Anything else is needed.
And then if there's more values,
more value we want to provide
for this particular cases,
we list them out with the please.
The reason is the keys right now we two
and then the same thing.
We will provide a code, right
what we want and the break.
And then when we are
done, what do we provide this
equal rights and equal?
Do I do I have to put it, though?
I don't have to put it.
It's an optional right.
It's an optional that we provide
the default by default.
So optional keyword
that we want to provide.
And usually it's provided
at the end of our switch.
Right?
So this is a block of quote
is which block of.
Okay,
so that's why you're saying switch cases.
What is a value based? Value based, Right.
It's not like our
if statement we're in parenthesis
with specify a condition, right.
To specify the condition.
Very beautiful statement.
Right Very beautiful statement.
In is as similar
as another conditional statesman
and right out of the entire block,
right out of the entire switch block.
What will happen?
Only one case write only one case
or if there's none of the cases match,
only one statement will be executed.
Right?
There is no way that all of them
will be educated.
Right.
So similarly, what do we do?
We do it as selective execution, right?
The execution
right now was for a switch, right?
That was for a switch.
And then what? Last class?
Oh, actually, that's.
How was the homework for a calculator?
You guys do it.
Let's see, because that's
where you guys used your sample.
Oh, there's supposed to be
two weeks, right?
So let me create a package
from that
new class
and because everybody wants a.
Okay,
can you guys send me your calculator?
So two different ways
we could have done it, right?
we could have done it.
Let's say, Oh
yeah.
So in here,
what we bring in, we bring in our scanner
right in the given instruction,
please enter first number here.
Capturing the first number.
Right
this line, please enter the second number.
Capturing the second number right in here.
What are we doing?
We are trying to capture the operator.
Right.
What it will be
Plus minus multiplication division.
So how do we calculate?
Capture that, Operator.
We captured this using that chart, right?
We store inside that chart
and then I see what are we doing?
We are initializing one variable in here.
Okay, cool. We'll see.
What is that for? Right.
And then what do we have? Right?
And then what do we have?
So we bring in our switch statement right?
We bring in our switch statement in here.
So in the switch to which variable,
what does this variable refers to guys do?
Which variable
we try to provide matching cases.
Operator Right to the operator. Right.
So now I said, Hey,
if the operator that you entered
will be multiplication right then.
Oh I see.
What is solve or
okay, so what is so so then
a solution
will be you do it multiply by B, right?
In case if it's division,
you do A divided by B in case of the
plus you do
plus in case the minus, the minus.
And in case of none of the if
none of the cases will be mentioned,
then you want to say entry is invalid.
Write entries in them. Okay, good.
And what you knew best
after that, you just try to run your code
and see these different variations.
Right?
Please enter number eight nine
and what you want to do.
We want to do a loss of
function loss right now.
So give me a result of the addition.
Right.
And that's all you do. You run after that.
You have things one number 90,
the other one, number 80.
Right. What I want to do,
I want to multiply.
Okay, go it.
It works, right?
So you guys are able
to test your own code.
How are we able to test it?
By providing different,
different values to see that all
my cases are matches
and at the same time let's see
that our default is working as well.
Right?
We did the number 112
and the number is 13.
And the operator,
I'm going to use a percentage sign ago.
Go says entry is invalid entries invalid.
So that was with the.
But if we give one positive one negative,
we can do it -19.
What kind of operation?
What kind of operation you want to do?
Please enter
second number for operator minus.
So it gives -23.
Let's see you guys.
Let's see what happens.
Then within the first number ten,
please enter for a second.
Number minus five.
Please enter your operator.
You get -36 minus, which shows me 15.
Okay, let's see what happens.
Good. So let's see what happens.
Let's see where our code posts right.
I don't think actually try to use
the negative numbers, but let's see this.
Let me put the breakpoint in here.
Right. Let's do debugging.
Please enter first number.
So we have ten second number minus five.
Right. And your operator minus.
So now let's see where it goes.
I'm going to select a switch. Right.
So what is my operator?
My operator is minus.
Oh, okay. It is correct.
Okay, good.
So right.
Does it finds the minus?
Yes, it finds the minus. Right.
That's it finds the minus
and then it takes ten
and then minus and then the gain again
minus five.
Minus at minus. It gives me five. Right.
Let me see you guys,
because I did the first one as well.
Let me try.
Okay. Yep. Minus, minus.
Excuse me.
You use me a plus, right?
That's why it gives me that.
But let me try
the first. Negative goes first
within the first number minus ten
and then second number five
within the you operator minus.
Right.
So my operator is minus.
Let's see where it goes.
It still finds it.
So what is the value of a value of a
is minus ten.
What is the value of B, Right.
Minus ten. Minus five. Right.
And then it gives me using T -15.
Now I think I think no, I think it does
work.
Correct. Right.
Yep. Minus ten. Minus five.
So you will give me 50 as purpose.
Okay.
So only guys only if,
if you here would want to go deep.
Right.
Only if here you would want to go deep.
There's one issue.
We're going to have this
there's one issue we're going to have
in which we can solve it. Right.
Let me show you guys
what could be the potential issue.
Right? Please enter number one.
For example, I'm going to enter ten
and I'm going to enter number two zero.
And I want to do the division right.
And I want to do the division.
So now, based on the math, we know, right,
that, hey, we cannot divide by zero.
Right. Will my switch case
go to the margin?
Yes, it will give to the match.
Maybe I'll go to the division
right by now.
What will happen?
You will try to divide ten by zero, right.
So now what will happen?
Java will run into some error. Right.
So it will give you some some error,
some exception.
Right.
Which we will be learning
is what you will be learning.
So it will tell us
that we cannot divided by zero.
Right.
So in here, this in here, what are we can
do You guys can throw additional
if condition if some of you dig that
a little bit more deeper
so you guys maybe can fix that.
Right.
So maybe inside here we can say hey,
whenever you want to divide, right.
We will.
Whenever you want to divide,
let's first check.
Right. Can we throw any condition is here?
Of course, can be thrown.
How do we I want to say, hey, all we know
only if the number is not equal to zero.
Then I'm going to do division.
Other than that, let's throw
some let's throw some message saying,
Hey, can you divide by zero?
So. Right.
So what do we can say?
Hey, if we trying to do the division
keys, we try to do the division,
let's throw this condition in here.
We can say even now we're going to say
all the only
my be right, my second number,
not equal to zero.
Right only and only my second number
is not equal to zero.
Only then I am going to perform
this operation right in the other.
Yes, we can either do a hand up which.
Oh so thing
you guys still talking about that?
Are you
guys still talking
about the minus minus in there. So a
so in here. Right.
We saying hey
if the operation will be a division now
as soon as I find the matching cases,
what is the code I'm put in I'm putting my
if statement is B is not equal to zero,
then I'm going to perform division, right?
Only then I'm going to perform a division.
Right?
If you want, you throw another value.
Yeah, sure, we can throw another else.
BLOCK And we throw the block.
We can throw the workers
in. We can see it's
all innocent.
You cannot divide us correctly.
You cannot divide by just put it this way
then.
Now let's see what's going to happen.
Right?
We've done the number one
9%, the number two zero.
And then please enter your operator
division.
Right. So now what happens to which
to which
variable we are providing
and matching cases
we providing for the operator
at the current moment.
Operator is a division, right?
So what will happen when we do step into
Java finds the matching case right away.
Right?
And then once it finds the matching case
right away,
we know what is going to do
is going to execute this code
that we specified inside
from this case to this case.
Right.
So now while it enter,
it sees the if condition.
When we see in this condition,
Java knows, hey,
what I have to do, I have to check on
the condition is true or false.
Right. Then it checks.
Hey, if be not equal to zero,
no condition will be false.
Right?
Because zero is equal to zero.
So it will come to the else part.
So there's no calculation will be done.
It will give us the message, cannot divide
by zero, and then it will see the break.
It will get out from our switch. Right.
But this is only
there's
a little if you want to add that,
how do we close this?
We close this by having the variable
that refers to our scanner, right?
When the variable that result
goes to our scanner.
And then what
we'll do will just use the cost,
because that's what this is,
how we can close
our once you guys are learning,
once we start learning objects,
right, and classes,
then you guys will understand
what does all those things means
because eventually what we can do
is we can go inside all of this things,
but we cannot go right now
because we won't be able to understand
what's going on in here.
But once we start learning,
there's there's every single explanation
you guys can find out about
what is a print does, about what is the
what is this part does everything will be
because we will be able
to go ahead and read it.
Okay. Okay.
So that was for a switch.
You are
that was for the calculator using switch.
Right. Okay.
So can you guys show me a calculator
with the eve statement
this year thing you list?
I see mostly cases, pieces
of it right there.
Right.
Copy this.
So all need
copy or while you guys use the
this in your bill in here.
Let me see
string
operator on the top
you very quickly
made me right
so another way doing that
and using the eve statement right
so the same thing
bring in scanner right here we asking hey
can you enter two numbers in the operate
two numbers and the operator.
Oops.
Right.
So in here I see right
you guys capturing double
which probably is a good choice
to go for a double because you guys
want to perform a division, right?
You guys want to perform a division game.
So in here, right, Capturing two numbers
in here, capturing the operator.
Right.
The only thing in difference in here,
I see a person captures it using a string.
Right.
Using the string, which is fun, right.
Which is fine.
And here the result, I'm assuming.
Right.
And initializing to the default values.
Right to the default values.
So I'm here.
I'm saying, hey, if operators equals
two plus, then you do addition.
If it equals two minus B, doing this right
for all valid operators plus minus
multiplication division, you you listen,
you list them out, use it else
if if none of the condition match,
we see a wrong operator, right?
We say no wrong.
And this is so think
I'm assuming that the
thing copied from someone who is it
in Turk is right So now let's see
let's test them right
Let's as them isn't the number one nine.
I'm present the number two eight in what
I want to do I want to use plus Right.
Oh let's see what happening here.
Oh, I think I only see this.
What happened in there?
Where did we get stuck?
Okay, guys.
So whenever
this type of issue comes right,
whenever this type of things come,
what do we have to look in here, guys?
Eventually we will have to learn
how to read our errors.
Right?
So we have to look into where
we got the issue right now.
This is the name of my class
that I created, Right?
Homework.
This is the name of my class, right.
And my java.
Right on which line? On the line.
Right on the line.
Let me click on it.
Let me see what happened.
Okay. So it got stuck in here.
We got stuck in here.
Thanks.
Double it says, See
this and I can follow nothing.
And then
boom, Because this is a fact.
Okay, let me do the debugging this thing
and because some of the switch statement
in there, we see
the puts next.
Oh, because next. But it shouldn't be.
Yes, there is a scanner,
I think because in here
it just grabs this single character.
That's what happens.
And then but this Yeah,
this can let me see.
Guess what happens.
If not, I'll just take it to different
class
debugging. This
wasn't the number one.
Nine wasn't the number two
eight and three operator minus.
Right, focus.
So now where we going?
We are going, okay, So it does shows us
in there, shows us a D it does solve,
right?
They chose one A queens now
creating the calculator in here.
Right.
Please enter two operators.
Okay now.
Okay. It's
okay. Yes.
Let me just take it to the other class.
It's it comes with the issue
because in here we had a scanner
and we use it next chart.
Right?
Like this.
We just take it to another class
first.
More confusion
is X.
All right, let me try to beat.
No, no, no.
This in here right?
We're close in a scanner.
We have closing the scanner.
The one that we opened in here. Right.
And for the
if we are having another scanner.
Right.
It's a completely brand new scanner
is the issue.
Because in here, when we are going
I think I've got explaining to you guys
what's the difference
between Nixon? Next line
and what happens in there?
You know,
let me just go debugging in here.
It's okay.
Let me do running here.
Please enter to number and the operator
right to number nine eight
and the upgrade minus.
Right.
So it gives me one. Right.
It gives me one.
So now why in here probably
go for a
double was a better choice, right.
Where for a double go is a better choice.
If I want to go for, I don't know, 89
and then second number
67 and I want to do the division right.
So what will happen
because we're using double right.
That's why
we are getting all those decimals, right.
If I'm going in here
for the case.
Right, If I'm going to for kids,
what will happen in the number one
8967 division?
Right.
So what I'm going to give, I'm
going to get only one right
then you guys are ready.
And that's why we get in only one
because we are working
with a integer type of values
and integer type of values.
You can load
all those decimal points, right?
So that's why in here you will get one.
In here you get one point,
whatever, whatever, whatever.
Right.
So that's why probably probably
for calculator if, if you guys want to go
more into details probably using a
double will be will be a good choice.
Right. Will be a good choice.
All right in here guys.
In here. Actually, there's
that you see
right. Oh,
when it comes to integers, guys, integers,
there's just don't hold any any,
any values.
So I there is no,
even the question happens
because integers cannot hold, cannot hold
those decimals in know hold those this
well you can think of.
Yeah that's it. Just corral that change
you can think of.
All right.
So here
maybe I would capture this value number
eight in number number
B, I probably would capture it inside
and can
what what you see right now guys Right.
What we we talking about the switch right.
So we said okay whenever exercise you do
is this switch
exactly the same you can do with that
if right.
The only difference
what happening here. Right.
what happened in here on the switch
you guys work in with the char inside.
If you guys I see you guys
working with the string right?
But good of you.
They try in here.
Of course we can use the char, right?
Of course we can use the char
if you want to compare chars.
Right.
So what do you guys would use?
You would just use those
relational operation like you could have.
Say if operator equals right
equals equals to the last.
Right.
So but both solutions are good solution.
So you get c whatever done with the switch
got to be done with that else.
Right. Would it be damaged because
in this situation probably
if you really look I probably would go
for a switch case as well.
I would probably go for a switch.
It's like it's going there.
It's it's easy to read also, right?
You guys have to think of
where readability becomes easier.
Remember when I told you this,
you will be working with other automation
engineers, right?
So you guys want to make sure
that whatever code you are writing right,
whatever you do,
your writing, it's understandable
by you and others, right?
Can we do a double use?
We can do that double because
remember this in this situation, right?
You're variable your variable that you are
providing matching cases is of which type.
This variables, those of which type,
the variable of the tri type.
Right. You're not looking a case.
A case B you looking at what you looking
at the operator in here right.
Only inside you performing the operation.
But that's just regular math operations.
So we said inside switch
we can work with integer chars
strings.
Right.
And then by and then
short. Right.
So all of variable is of that char
type, right.
Yeah.
But we are not,
I'm not, I'm not putting the switch,
I'm not putting A or B right this way
if it will be a double it doesn't work.
What is my switch is about.
My switch is about providing the match
values for a char type of variable.
So even if I'm going
to change to a double in here, right,
let me change it to double,
which was changed to the next double
or change to level
and I'm going to explain it so
you are going to change anything?
That's right.
It's not going to change anything.
So we're at the
you have to multiplied by B,
maybe that and we will happen.
Oh, okay.
So now let's see, guys,
What happened? Yep, that's it.
That's a good point. Right?
So you were not
do not catch it right away.
Right.
So any time you guys have the issue right,
when we have an idea.
Right.
It's always always
compiler is a great, great friend of ours.
So what now compiler tells you here right.
It tells you that you should say
cannot convert from double to the integer.
Right. So why?
Because when you're doing
some operation
on the double type of values, your result
or it also should be a double right
here.
That's all right.
So why did not affect that?
Because this is just a regular.
Could we please inside
my switch is still looking at which
variable my switches to looking
at the variable of the chart type on which
and then present the number one, two
and three.
Number two three division right here.
So we getting three, three, three, four.
Because of that, probably having a double
will be a better choice.
Better choice
because you doing it at my operation.
Okay.
When the double wouldn't work,
which scenario.
The double would not work if right now
inside the switch you try to provide
a values for this variable
for the variable E Right.
For the variable, that's when you switch
is going to complete, right?
That's where you your will complete
because hey, what are you switch
and you trying to switch a value
that has a variable that holds a double
check, a valid that's
when here you going to say
that cannot switch
on the value of type of double.
Right.
So but as long as it's
char type of variable and the good
where it does not work
only if you're switching
long double fluid
where inside inside your switch of and you
locaters that was
or you could switch it A or B
even if you go and to put this right
because they are double
type of values it's not going to work
even if you would actually never Trevor's
counter but listening to work.
Okay right.
That was was our homework right.
That was a that was a for a homework.
Right.
So if you get confused, try
to debug your code, try to debug your code
and see how your code executes.
And that's all actually does Also
will help you clear a lot of things to
write this.
And thus in that last class
what we started,
we started with the loops,
okay loops in Java.
But I mean because if you are entering
minus two and then if is doing
the negative upgrade, it becomes minus
minus two, it will become plus, right.
And then it will be minus eight plus two.
That's why it shows minus six.
Okay.
You see if you if you are entering Right,
if you want to enter
first number you said you enter minus
minus. So
you can
minus eight.
Right.
A second number minus two and you
operate is minus then what it becomes.
And because minus eight minus minus
two equals
two plus,
that's why it gives you minus six
gives you minus.
All right.
The minor. We just cannot use double.
We cannot use double where inside
your here inside a switch If your variable
will be of the double type of the float
type you cannot put next to the switch,
you cannot sit next to the switch.
Okay, let's let's let's talk about
let's talk about loops.
Right. Let's talk about loops.
Okay.
Let's talk about loops.
So why do we need loops in Java, in
okay, so we use in loops.
So whenever there will be a situation,
right, Whenever there will be a situation
when we want to repeat
this same block of code.
Right.
What do we want
to repeat the same block of code Java sees
as, Hey,
don't write the same code over and over
to eliminate the code redundancy, right
to eliminate the code code redundancy
and you repeat this pain block of windows
says, Hey, go ahead and use loops.
Right? Go ahead and use loops.
So what the loops will do
loops will repeat
with this same block of code,
whatever you put inside the body.
Right.
What do we put inside the body and
number of times based on that condition.
Right. Based on the condition.
And then yesterday,
look how many loops we have in
Java, guys.
There's a
for loops. What are those loops? Gates
We have four.
We have while we have do while
infinite, Infinite can be infinite,
they can be either for a loop or why loop.
So infinity
just means non stop in loop right?
Or we have advanced
for those for loops that we have.
Right?
Unless we start looking with a simple
a loop.
Right. So let's
while little things x right
so will be the syntax for our why
look this
what is the syntax for a while loop
so we have a key word Well and in here.
Right in here.
What do we have inside the parentheses
commission.
Right. We also have a bowling condition.
Bowling condition. Right.
And it's it works almost similar
as if statement.
Right is a similar statement.
And then in here
or to repeat, right click to
put repeat.
Right. So
the way that our well works, our well
repeats block of code
as long as what
as long as the condition is true Right.
So your Java while executing
your code is is while so it knows okay
I have to repeat, repeat, repeat repeat
how long I'll be repeated
as long as my condition is right,
as long as my condition is true
and yesterday one of the example
that we started right here.
What if I want to say right, I want to say
good morning three times, right?
We said I want to say good morning
three times.
How are we going to say
good morning three times?
We will be adding increment decrement.
But what?
Which things do I need right now?
Just say good morning
three times and four.
Now I know only look,
I know only while loop, right?
I don't know any other loops
I know only while loop.
Once we look into all of them
then we will decide
in which situation we'll go for four
and each station will go for a while.
But for now you
guys only know one, right? So
I have to have a variable, right?
I have to have a variable.
And let's say I'm going to put one right
and then off there
I have a variable, right?
I have that variable.
Then I'm going to bring my while he
what right while
and have the condition.
If the condition will be matching, then
I'm going to open up the block of code.
Right. I'm going to open up.
This is the body of your while.
Now what will be the condition?
I want to say three times. Good morning.
It means I have to make my condition
to be true three times.
Right?
So I can say times is what
was it less or equal than three?
Right.
Let's where equal Then we will then be.
Then we will be saying right, I'm
going to write system
that are that print line of them
going to write a shorter is in line
and I'm going to say
good morning in good morning.
Anything else I have to add this?
Anything else
Now what I have to do,
I have to add the incremental issue.
Right.
What's going to happen
if I'm not going to have
the implementation,
my loop will become infinite, right?
My loop will become infinite. Why?
Because variable got initialized here,
but my code will be stuck
between this cycle, right?
That's where my code will be stuck.
That will be stuck between this cycle.
You will be running,
running, running. Right.
So that's why inside the loop body
what we need, we need the variable, right?
We need this variable
that will be incrementing my
my that will be incrementing my variable.
And by incrementing my variable
I will be able to change my condition.
Right?
I will be changing the condition
that's now all while works.
And I hope you guys look at this slides.
Right.
So we already seen hey,
whenever we want to repeat black ops code,
we'll go for loops because you repeating
the same lines over and over 20 times.
That's not a very right approach. Right?
Right.
And as we said, loops are exist in
everybody
in everybody in every programing language.
Right?
So what then? Loops.
They run a certain
block of code. Right.
Piece of code multiple times. Right.
When do we use it to perform
the repetitive execution?
Why do you use it
To eliminate the redundancy.
Right. And also, it's time
consuming, right?
Instead of here,
what if I want to do right here?
What if I want you repeat this
block of code 300 times, right?
So what I do right now,
I can just change the condition now.
My code will run 300 times. Right.
Very quick and very easy.
Instead of repeating one morning
300 times.
Right.
So right in here, different type of loops.
And this is the order that you guys will
be learning loops, right?
So what is the loop statement?
Do it allow us to execute
group of statements multiple times.
So this is our way a loop right.
So of while loop always remember this
while loop first checks the condition.
Why? Because after well, what do we have?
We do specify a condition,
right before we are able
to enter the block of code, the loop body.
We always, always check in the condition.
We always check in the condition.
And if the condition is true,
we allowed to go inside the block of code
inside the loop body.
If the current condition is false,
we are not able to interpret.
If the condition is true,
I'm going to enter my loop by
write my block of code with the condition
is false.
I cannot write
this.
So you had some tasks, right?
You had a you had some just
preparing numbers from 1 to 100.
Okay.
So did you guys use increment
or decrement in here?
Increment?
What about in here
in your decrement.
Right.
Because you're starting from the highest
value going to the smallest value.
Right.
I think even numbers
we are locked in here, right.
I think we looked in the class,
but we can look one more time.
Right. Even an odd will be very similar.
But there's just one little thing
I want to show you this scale to show you.
Look, meet up with this
and you guys, you'll send me
your code right?
Your code homework.
So as we look less
class goes right as we look last class,
this assignment code could be done
two different ways, right?
Two different ways. Okay. So
the easiest way, right?
The easiest way. Probably. Right?
Probably would be using an increment,
right?
Right.
This is probably our easiest way. Right.
So what we have, we it
we started from 20 right.
Then specify our condition. Right.
So starting from 20
will be printing all the way to 100
and then we'll be printing the print
in the value of variable
and then doing increment nation by two.
Right.
So what I'm going to run here,
that's what I get.
That's what I get.
So all the values,
all the even numbers from 20 to 100,
Right. Dude, I completed a task.
I completed the task.
And there is another way.
There is another way.
How is it that we can do it right
not to
send on
a wave so we can do it another way,
but using our
if statement. Right.
But using our if statement
right.
So another way what we say hey,
I can have my variable right
I can have my variable.
Then this will be my condition.
Right?
The same condition all the way to 100.
The only thing right now
what do we throw in here?
We throw our statement, right?
We throw our statement and we say, Hey,
I'm going
to print the value of my variable.
See all you.
Only if this condition
will be matched right.
And in which situation
this condition will be matched
only when my numbers is equally divisible
by zero.
Right.
And now let's try to run it.
Let's try to run it
normal.
And so now what are we getting?
We get an exact exact the same answer.
Right.
Well, either use an implementation by two
or throw into each condition
what it give me give me 100.
Right.
Give me 100. Right.
So now this it's a very, very important.
Right.
It's very important that
you guys put the increment right. Why?
Because only by putting the increment
we can make this condition become false
at some point.
Right.
So now, guys,
I want you to look at this screen.
I want you to pay attention.
So what I'm going to do right now, this
what I'm going to do,
I'm going to pull it.
I'm going to take this instrumentation
and I'm going to place it inside here.
So now, guys, by looking into this code,
by looking in this quote, can you guess?
Tell me what will be my output?
Will my output change?
Will my output
still going to be this same or
I'm going to get some errors
or I'm not going to get any errors?
Tell me, guys,
what will be the output by looking at
this code, then change
20. Okay.
One output
20. Let
me put another statement in here.
All of this
me wanted same
only one time just 20
saying okay, okay people
now they're saying 20.
Okay so with this same
okay I see some people say same for people
that say 20 time
you guys are going to print one time
and Don or one time an infinite
and then a done done nothing else.
Okay, let's see, guys.
Let's see now.
Done.
Okay, now, guys,
I don't want you to run it right.
I don't want you to run it.
Then look at the output.
I want you to analyze.
I want you to analyze it. Right.
So you guys will be telling me, right?
So we are
so we are not looking at the previous one.
This is the only this is the only where
we're looking right now, Right?
It's only now here.
We know we declared in the variable.
It's right in the variable here.
Java goes up to the bottom, right.
It runs the code
until it C is the statement or now
until is going to see the loop.
Right now Java sees you while it knows.
Okay, while it's a keyword.
So what does a keyword means?
In my language
it means I have to repeat block of.
Okay, cool.
So now what is the value of C guys?
What is the value of C
one at the current moment?
At the current moment it is 20.
Okay, 20 is a 20 less than 100 condition
truffles.
Condition is true. Right
Condition is true.
Condition is passed.
I can go inside my little body.
I'm going inside.
Tell me guys,
from where my little body ends,
on which line my loop ends,
biting my closes the block of good
meaning. Yes.
This will be able
so that's
it ends up w it ends at 33.
It's 33. Right.
So this is where my little buddy starts
this is where my little buddy ends
right at ends of the line. 33.
No. Who said condition was true?
Okay, cool condition is true.
Now, when condition is true,
I'm able to enter the loop body.
Right. So now, as soon as Java enters,
it is ease, right?
It's just. It knows. Okay,
What does it even use?
I have to check the condition.
Okay, no problem.
C right.
Which holds the value of 20.
What two? Right is the condition Truffles.
This action
is true.
Okay.
One condition is true.
I am able to enter my if statement. Right.
I'm able to enter my if statements enter.
And as soon as I enter if statement
I have this statement C's out right.
I have. This is out.
So what is the value of C guys?
What is the value of C
20? Right?
At this point it's below 24
when you print it.
No problem. Right.
I am printing it one time.
I'm printing it right one time.
Okay, then what happens this?
Then what happens?
Implementation happens.
My C becomes 21.
Okay, but what happens after that is
So then when my code goes bad guys,
where am I?
What goes back?
You will go back to the line 23.
But look, guys,
this is where my F body started.
This is where my F ended, right?
So then once that condition was executed,
your code will exhibit the if statement.
Right?
And there's no more lines for the wire.
Then it will go back to the while.
Right? Because it cannot stop by itself.
Now, what is the value of C guys?
A value of C right now?
21 Right.
The value of C right now is 21.
21 is the condition truffles.
Condition is still true.
Can I go inside my wild body? Yes,
I can go.
This is where my well body starts.
This is where my wild body ends.
As soon as it enter my wild body,
I'm seeing the e statement right
Jarvis's eve.
Okay, now I will check
what is the value of gets.
The value of c is 2121 mod two
is there any reminder?
So now condition is false, right?
So now my condition will become false.
When my condition is false,
can I enter the body?
No, I cannot enter the body.
And where my f body starts,
my body starts from here.
It ends in here.
So if I cannot enter my body
where my plot will go.
Guys, now
my how it even is the eve.
It can spend the eve, no problem. Right?
Because It cannot do right.
So now what? What happened in here?
Because my C right,
Because my C is equal to 21.
Right.
I need you to pay attention
this to where the body starts.
Right?
Condition for a while was true
because it's 21.
21 is less than 100 now.
As soon as we emptied Jarvis's
eve value of C
is 2121 more to go.
There is a reminder, right?
There is a reminder here.
So this condition will be false.
When condition is false,
I cannot enter my body.
This entire blog that's ignored
now when your java cannot enter
is no problem.
Now you're could it's still where you
could you could was not able to enter E
but your code is in here
you code is still inside the world body.
This your code is still inside
a world body and then what happens?
You code will go back
guys you will go back.
Java cannot spell by itself.
So now what happens?
It shows the condition.
What is the value of C?
A value of C still 21.
It did not give increment
that why it did not get incremented
because we were not able to enter
the eve body.
Right.
So now 21 is the condition is true?
Yes, condition is true.
I'm still going inside my wild body.
When I go inside my wild body,
I'm chicken.
Hey C what is the value of C?
The value of season
21, 21 month to condition is still false.
Condition is still false.
I'm still not able to go inside.
It means I'm not able to print
and then I cannot increment.
And then your code goes back again
to the while it's still 21.
So now what will happen?
We are printing 20 only one time,
but then my code does not stop my code
continuously, continuously running.
Right. So let's put into debugging, right?
Let's put into debugging mode.
I see.
What is the value of C?
The value of C is 20. Right?
Okay.
Cool condition is true for a while now.
Condition it will be true for
if if condition is true for
if I can go inside
and print in C and then what I'm doing
I'm incrementing right I'm incrementing.
Okay, fine.
Now I finish with the eve,
I'm going back to my
Well now what is the value of C analysis?
2121 is still less than 100.
Okay, now I'll go inside my if statement
21 more two condition is false.
I cannot go inside the body.
He is my where my f body.
So it means now I will never ever be able
to enter my eve block.
And now because I put the increment
inside guys.
So now what I'm going to get, I'm
going to get my infinite loop.
I'm not going to see any output, but
my loop is continuously running this.
You don't see it, but it's running, right?
So now what we got because we placed
a we placed our increment
inside the wrong block,
inside the wrong block, right.
So that's why now what we have,
we still have our code running
because when there was still
did not reach this line. Why?
Because our code gets stuck
somewhere in here, but it keeps looping,
looking, looping
because the value of C is still 21.
It's never get changed.
So we got an infinite loop, right?
So that's why it's important
as always, always pay attention
where you put in your increment.
If you are using the while, right?
So that's why you increment
your increment.
Always, always
should be at the end of your well body.
Right.
This is where your well
body starts, this is where your world body
ends, right.
So you have to make sure
you always have this increment only, only
because if you're not going
to have the increment at the end,
then your implementation
will depend on the if statement.
Okay.
Yes. Implementation
still have to be inside them.
Of course.
Thank.
Think.
Okay.
I hope that that's a little thing
that I wanted to show you that
it is difference if you place it here,
if you place it here and of course
if you place it outside the loop
of course this the difference
in why
we need a 25 and 21.
You want
this curly braces 25
and 27 We're identifying that.
What do you mean?
This is blocker.
This is block of code that belongs to the
if part.
Right?
This block of code that belongs to the
if right this is fairly braces right.
Always highlighting this this curly braces
identifies the opening of my
while loop right
and this is closing right this is closing
so this is our curly
braces that identifies
that this is body for our okay
so all eat
this if you don't want it put it.
Yes, that's fine.
Remember, guys, we already look into this
that if you have only one statement,
you don't have to put it.
But I always, always suggest you to put it
because you just
visually guys, easy for you
to read the code.
Right?
By looking at your code, you can read it.
You can understand, right?
What do you have to have it?
No, you don't really have to have it,
but it's preferable to have it
most of the time.
You guys will see that people,
even if it's a one line tool
as people are still
people are still putting those,
okay.
Okay, guys, I hope I hope you guys ready
when we are going to get to the
nested loops.
Okay.
So for now, it should be easier, right?
This should be easier. Okay.
All right.
So let's do one thing.
Is today, of course,
we're going to look into more loops.
What? For example? Right?
For example,
what if I'm going to have this task?
I ask,
I want to have it, for example. Right.
What I would like to do, right,
what I would like to do, right.
I want to ask. Right.
And it goes simple, right?
I want to ask a user
to name
his or her name, whatever
their name, write their name
and for example, age.
I don't know. This might five times.
I like.
So five times now you have to think, okay,
would you ask the name
right To ask the name?
What do we need?
What do we need to ask in the.
We will need this scanner, right?
We will need this scanner
and then to make it
five times to repeat the block of code
five times.
What do we need?
This. We.
We'll need our loop, right?
We will need our loop.
So I have you probably a little bit ahead.
So for now, we don't know any other look.
We just know, Right?
Okay, so now you have to think, okay,
I need to have two things.
I need to have scanner
and then some piece of code
I have to put inside the loop.
Right now, you will just have
to understand which piece of code.
Right. And remember guessing.
The task is a little bit is a little bit
too long.
Right. You just do it one time first.
Okay? Find it right.
I will need a scanner.
Scanner.
Scanner equals new scanner.
Right system.
Then the very
import our scanner
and then I'm going to states is all
we can say.
Please
enter your name and age right.
For example, little captured all together.
Right.
So now to capture the name,
to capture the name or we will opt system
that out to capture the name
or will you scan that next right
we will store it inside the name
and then we will capture the
H right integer H will equal.
And then next thing to enter
integer.
And then we will build out right.
Your name is and let's under name plus.
And you are and let's
h and plus
years old right?
Most of
with a simple code that we already know.
Right So we have in this scanner
we the instruction right
then we want to capture the name.
We captured the H and then we
and then we just print, right?
So we test our code.
Please enter your name.
My name is John.
I am 45 years ago.
Your name is John.
And you are 45 years old, right?
That's my code work.
Yes, my code word. Right.
I was able to capture a username
and the age, right?
And I printed up the only thing.
What happens? Right.
My quote was executed only one time.
Only one time. Right.
So now we're saying,
hey, whenever you want to
a same
block of code, we can use loop, right?
We can use language. So now tell me this.
We do this thing,
we should start our loop.
I want you to just analyze. Right.
We need to capture I want to ask the user
five times and I want to print it.
So from which line should start
from the line 19.
From the line 17
1317,
19, 13,
13 after scanner
15, 13, 20.
But how are we going to
how we going to before
this is up 13.
So now let's do this right.
I want to repeat block of good Gary
I need a loop.
So now would you block of code
I want to repeat
do you guys just want to print
user name and age five times
or you actually guys want to ask
and you guys actually want captured
five times?
We want to capture it five times, right?
I don't want
just print out five times, right?
What I want to do, I want to ask the user
their name and age five times, right?
Yes. We are asking,
I don't want just Ukraine unit.
Your name is John and you 45 years old.
I want to capture five different names.
I want you capture five different ages.
Right.
So now that's
where you have to think, okay, which
block of good I want to repeat, right?
Do we need to have five scanners, guys?
Do we need to have five scanners
to capture the name?
No, we don't need to.
We know that one
scanner can do a job. Right?
So then this line does not need
to be repeated.
Cool.
This line does not need to be repeated.
Do we need to repeat this line?
I think we should write it
because we have to give an instruction.
So it means right? This line.
I want you repeat this line
because capturing the name and the age
I have to repeat,
and this one I have to repeat,
then what part of code I have to repeat.
I want you repeat this piece of code.
Right?
So then whenever whatever the quote you
want, you repeat what, we will have to do.
We will have to place it inside the body.
Inside the body. Right.
So for now, we just know while.
So what do we all do?
What do I guys, first, what do I need it?
Okay, sure. I can have my while.
Okay, well,
this is where my body will start.
This is where my well, body
will end, right?
So you identify the wild body.
Now, what is the my condition?
H No, if you look my condition, I'm
going to define in my H Right.
So what is my condition?
I Just wanted to say five times.
So now what?
I have to make sure
that I have my condition.
That is,
I have to make this condition to be true.
Five points.
Right.
Well, now that way we learned
we need a variable, right?
We need a variable.
So let's initialize it right.
Let me put it five ways.
Let me put it five.
So now how can I make this condition
right?
How can I make the condition
to be true five times
based on the value of
my I, I should be What
I want my condition
with the current value.
Let's say I did not put one.
I put five this.
Can I put five? Yes, I can put five.
Can I put 50? Yes. Can put 50.
How do I make my condition to be true
five times.
Okay, we can go back to five.
This can go back.
Well I is what my value
if I is five, this level of
I is five
I less or equal
than five. It's
more than one more than equals.
The one.
Okay,
well, I more equal than one.
Okay.
And then what do I need to use
if I'm going to use.
So you see all I'm sure all your or all
your condition is true, then I guess
you guys need to tell me, am I going to
use an increment or decrement
if I have five and condition is one
increment decrement.
Okay.
I guess first let's look at Michael.
You probably maybe
your value is different.
Maybe you operate as different, right?
That's fine. Okay.
So integer equals to five, right
integer equals to five.
If you put in the condition
I is more or the one, then in order
for this condition true to be true
five times, what do we need to do this
I What are we going to do with the
I going to do it decrement.
Right.
So we're going to do it
right.
So now first let's go back to our body
and then we can change the operator.
Based on the operator.
We will have to change the condition
as well. Right?
We will have to change that.
So now let's see
what's going to happen. Right?
So we know that we need only one scanner,
Right?
Variable declaration
also happens only once.
Right now we have the condition
while I more than equals in one
case, five more or equal than one. Yes.
Condition Is to someone inside the world
body.
This where a world body starts.
This is where a while body is, right?
So now, right inside the body
I have to repeat a block of code
while the condition is true.
Right?
So condition.
What's true? I'm going to ask.
Please
enter your name. Right. And then. Here.
Capturing the name,
capturing the age, printing.
Then what I'm doing is my
I am decrement in now five minus one.
My I will be equal to four right then.
My driver does not stop cannot stop
Don't have a permission to stop
until it finds the false condition.
Right. It goes back
now it's saying here is the four right.
Because the values I was decrement
that is for more than one.
Yes. Four is still more than one. Okay.
If the four is more than one
right, or is more than one,
then or more equal than one. Yes.
Condition strong.
Going back
then I'll execute the second time.
Second time. Second time.
Right then four minus
one will give me three Java.
There's no stop.
It goes back to exact condition.
Now I would say here
is that three more than one.
Yes. Condition is true. Right.
And then printing this third time.
Right.
And then you will get incremented to two
and then they will get incremented to one.
Right. All this time
it will be printing it, right?
All this time it will be printing it.
And then whenever you condition
would be one, right.
Whenever your condition will be one.
Hey, one is more or equal than one
condition is true.
That will become your number.
Number five time.
What are you going to print it then?
You I will still get decrement it,
it will become zero.
Then where it goes, it goes back, right?
It goes back.
Now it says he is zero more or equal,
this one.
No condition is false.
All in only one condition is false.
Then Java not going inside the
well body right?
Only then.
So now let's try to run a quiz.
Enter your name. My Name is John.
My age is 45.
Your name is John and you?
45 years old.
Twins. Enter your name.
My name is Jane.
The age is 34, right?
Your name is John.
And so then what happens?
Our block, of course, is getting repeated.
How many times?
So what? Right.
So now I am inside the right scan.
I get created.
You guys can see in here, right?
My I got initialized.
You see it in here.
Now what we are repeating,
we are just repeating the block
that we put inside a well,
please enter your name H Right name
Jane. Right.
And then age 34
right now you will print it right?
You will it and then go back and then
this thing process will be happening.
Enter your name.
My name is John.
Please enter your age.
I don't know. Ages. Don't know 67. Right.
And then it will this block of what will
be keep repeating and repeating Repeating
it in
Give me give me increment.
Okay guess.
Now let me ask you.
Let's
think of different variations. Right.
So what if
I want to increment this,
what should I change them to?
If I want to increment,
let's think of different variations
I want to increment.
How should I fix my condition?
Okay. So right.
If you are want your increment,
then you have to fix this, right?
You have to fix this.
Well I less lesson
equals than five. Right.
We can then this way we can change it
to one input less or equal then fine.
Okay. Without Work.
Yes, that would work. Right.
We will be starting with one.
Then you will get increment
the two and then three.
And then four. And then five. Right.
So what if I'm going
to give my equal to ten?
I want to keep my incrimination.
I want to keep the value.
What what can I change, guys? Them.
I want my I to be equal to ten.
No, I'm still want to increment.
I still want to increment.
I still want to have ten.
Then what should
I change my condition This
I should
you just change it to the 15, right?
I should change it to the 15. Right.
So you guess you it can be different
incrimination, discrimination
as long as you know
how to make your condition right.
As long as you know
how to make your condition.
But usual,
of course we will be starting from small
go into larger right
or from the large going down to one.
So but cannot be done with the using ten.
Yes, it can be done right.
But the main thing in here, guys,
what are we doing?
We are repeating right now,
you don't have just one single line.
What you have, you have a block of code
right inside this block of code.
What are we doing?
We are giving instructions
and then we are capturing
values using string
and then again printing the statement.
Right.
So what we are repeating,
we repeat in block of code how many times?
Five times Based on what?
Based on my point, we should write
this block,
the block of code that we want to repeat
where we please.
We just play skip inside my well body,
right inside my box.
Look this right.
So this is how our
points already 1133
okay this is how well loop right.
Just always remember
so the way we have for a while,
we have a condition first, right?
We have a condition first.
Our well, first checks.
The condition
and only know if the condition is true.
Then we can go inside the little body
where my little body starts.
It starts from this curly braces
all the way to this right on the edge.
Or I guess. Yes.
We are going to take a break.
1130 elastic or break until 1150, right?
Yeah. Time goes to find this.
And then after the break,
we want to start looking into our another
right column and break below.
1150, keeping this in here.
So it's going to have a look right
of right.
So is
that there there's other loops in our
which we are going to look right
so once we look into all the loops right.
Not all but three, then I'll tell you
this wide Java gives so many variations
and in which situation
we will go for one or another loop.
Right.
So bye for now.
What we will do is we look into
our other look, which is do loop, right?
So this is our
this is was how
well while work right.
This is how our while loop looks
so now and that the loop that we have
we have something that call dual right
so do look will be a very very similar
to our one right
do well will be very similar
the only thing they will have
its own keywords right.
Of course we will have its own keywords.
So the way our do will work
it has a do keyword right
then without any condition.
Our due body will be open in its own
block of code, right?
It opens its own block of code.
And here, whatever code we want to repeat,
we will Voice is breaking thing.
It should be fine.
No, it should be fine.
This should be fine
by check.
I have a good connection. Right?
So we will be starting with the do
and then whatever block of code
we want to repeat,
we will be placing inside a do body.
Right?
And then outside of the do body
we will be having our while.
And then we will be having the condition.
Right. Condition will be it
while.
So this is a syntax.
What are our do? Well, right.
So now let's see how
it will look into the coding
and what will be the difference between
while in whatever there will be difference
between it do. Wow.
Right. So
what I'm going to do
because
you will
know them
so when they met that
so right so let's go let's first
so in order for us to see the difference,
I'm going to bring my way to look.
Right.
So, for example, I'm going to see it right
or individual A equals two one
in the regular code that we already done
this up with this addition.
And then the way we said while works,
well, first what we do, we are checking
the condition while we use less
or equal than three, for example.
Then I'm going to see see, All right.
And I'm going to see what.
Right.
And then our increment or decrement.
Okay.
Right.
So we know or I'm running something.
So we know in here what happens, right?
My code will be executed three times.
Three times. Right.
Because the condition was true
three times.
Right.
So now exact the same code.
This I can write using my
using my dual right.
So the same thing.
I'm going to have a variable.
I'm going to say
integer B equals to one exact
the same code, exact the same condition,
but in the dual format.
So what I'm going to do
when specified do right
is you guys see it's a keyword, right?
It's a keyword do.
And then I have a block of code
which is body of my dual loop.
This is the body of my why loop.
This is the body of my dual. Right.
So inside the new I'm placing the code
that I want you repeat, right.
I'm going to say for example in here.
Hello.
And then outside of the do body
what I'm going to provide, I'm
going to provide the well and my condition
will be less or equal.
Dempsey will be electronic Olympic.
So using
my body
while doing my body right.
Okay.
Now let me try to execute.
Let me try to. Exactly right.
Oh, wait, what did it.
Oh, I forgot what happened, you guys.
What? Why? My little pillow? Right way.
Give sprinting.
Hello?
Non stop this.
I forgot the increment or decrement.
Right. Sorry.
Okay, so be plus
the plus plus.
Right.
So now if I'm going to execute it right,
if I'm going to execute
it, output is exact the same right.
Output is exact the same.
So my y loop gives me a high three times.
Why do I loop
gives me a hello three times right.
So now then what is the difference? Right.
How it does not germinate here.
It stops based on the condition, right?
It's based on the condition
when my it becomes four
and then when we check condition
for less than three condition,
because that's how we are not able
to enter the inside the world body.
That's how we are stopping the right
that we notice.
So now here, while the condition is two,
we don't see the difference, right?
My while runs three times
my dual runs three times.
Right.
My my my do runs three times. Yes.
Instrumentation
always happens inside the body.
Guys, this is the wild body.
This is the Dubai always always happens.
And site implementation. Right.
So now let's see
then what is the difference.
Let me change this condition to be false
now. And let's just look at the code.
This let's look at the court.
When Java starts looking right
when Java starts,
look in top to the bottom, right.
So now Java sees a while.
It knows it has to repeat block of code.
But before before repeating
block of code, what your Java see is
your Java sees a condition.
Right?
So now we have to check the condition.
He is one
is more than equal then three condition.
True or false
condition is false.
So one condition is false.
Your java can load and the block of code
which belongs to the wild body.
Right? It cannot enter.
So your code will be ignored.
Now we going to see this outcome.
So now when it comes to a do body
dual loop,
so depolarize version of variable,
now your java sees a do keyword, right?
It sees Dukie.
What do you guys see?
Any condition to enter a new body?
To see any condition
before entering this block of code?
There's no condition, right?
There's no condition.
So because there's no condition.
What? Your joke.
They did not want any condition.
So I just do.
So do your java sees also do.
It means I have to repeat
the block of code to it knows it.
Right.
So there was no to enter this block of put
so your java easily enters
it will execute.
Hello.
Then what it will do?
It will increment.
So what they did will become this?
What they be will become
your B will become two
Then after in the body the loop.
Now what it does, it gives the condition.
It says while B is more than three.
Hey, I want you repeat this block of code.
Why B is more than equals.
The three Now at this point
condition will be false.
One condition is the false.
Your loop cannot continue.
It cannot continue. Right.
So now what do you see the difference
between wow and do while right?
While all in
do while they're very very similar loops
what they do
they run while condition is true
that only difference between why loop
and do y loop when the condition is false.
When the condition is false,
do while will still execute
the block of code
that you put inside the body.
Why it still executes
because do allows you
to do the action once right
and only then it checks the condition.
Right.
So the way do does do think of it
it trust you.
But then checks right.
I trust you one time.
Then I check the condition. Why?
When we talk about the why,
why Loop doesn't trust you.
It says, Hey,
you know what? I'll verify first.
If the condition is true,
then I'll trust you. Right.
So what happens once
first checks the condition?
Only.
Only the condition is true.
Then it allows you to go inside the world
by when it comes
Do, do, do says, Hey,
go ahead and execute this block of code.
I care about the condition.
I have no condition to check. It
suffers. Right?
I'm going
allow you to execute the code first
and only and only have to execute the code
at least once.
I'll check the condition.
And if that time is the condition of us.
Of course I cannot go back right.
Let's first do has no condition.
You guys at first do has no condition.
But after executing one time only,
then it checks condition only.
Then you check the condition. Right?
So let me check
does me when back check to the true right.
Let me check again. That's right.
So the way do it works exact same thing
this it's a cycle it's
repetition of the code right so the way do
works right up to the bottom of this.
Always top to the bottom B equals one.
Okay.
B, initialize to one. Now what happens?
Do no condition to check.
This will be executed one time.
B will incremented
one one by one equals two to right.
Then it exists the body and then after
that it chose the condition.
I will repeat block of code what I want y
condition is true
hey is due less than or equal then three.
Yes, condition is true.
One condition is true. Your code goes back
Now again he
says do right now
we going to print second time,
then do implementation by one
it will be equal to three right then
after executing this code it will check
is three less or equal than three?
Yes, condition is true.
It goes back again.
It goes back to do again
is going to print.
Then three plus one will be equal to four.
Right.
And outside of the
well now it will check the condition.
Hey is for less than three.
No. Now condition becomes false.
So you cannot go back
and repeat that cycle.
Right.
So that's the only difference between
while and do well this
and let's take a look
Oh, let's take a debugging
debugging in here.
We like
so declaring of the will be
what is the value of is one right
so we will go over when do we go for
well one of you will go for the key
so be right the value of these one.
So there was no condition
to enter the body.
So now I'm execute and hello
then I am incrementing might be
you can see became two
and only after I executed
first code then I'm checking the condition
Hey is due.
I will continue using the while
the run block of got
well condition is true.
He is due less or equal than three years
condition is true.
Okay.
If condition is true ongoing back. Right.
I'm going back printing.
Hello incrementing B right while I after
I increment the B now check the condition.
Hey, is three less or equal
than three years?
Condition is true and you shouldn't.
It's true.
I'm going back like I'm going back
repeating the same.
Hello now incrementing now B
became equals to four
or is not less than three.
Now condition becomes false.
I'm stepping right?
I'm stepping it.
Why? It's not all the same. If B
is equal to two.
Genius.
I don't think I understood your question.
Right.
And let's change my condition to be false.
So now,
when the condition is false. Right.
What happens with our dual right.
What happens is our due, right.
A B is equal to one first.
I don't check anything.
I trust you, right?
I trust you.
I'm going to execute
this block of code Right.
Then I will do implementation.
Now after I did, I do at least one
institution after execution.
Now I check the condition.
Condition becomes false.
I cannot go back and there my Dubai.
Right.
So now we're one of us.
Now we will look.
So now those loops you go see very,
very similar right so you're while and do
very similar loops they do work
while condition is being true right.
While condition is being true.
The only difference first
look at the difference.
Right.
And well first check the condition
only then execute
block of your do executes block of code
in only checks the condition.
So this way whenever a condition is false,
your while will never execute
block of code right
will never body will never get executed
compared to a do.
Even if the condition is false,
your do will execute at least one time.
Okay, so now out of this two loops,
right out of the tools
because they are very similar, right?
Because they're very similar.
So now out of this loops,
which loop will be more popular?
Why loop is way more popular
compared to do
right while loop compared to more to do.
It's more popular.
But then why java users do they will be.
There could be some possible scenarios
in the way we might use a do right.
For example, let's look at this scenario
right
for example.
Right. What we will try to do this.
We will try to bring this our scanner
and everything, okay?
In which cases we will go for for example,
that's for example, Right.
So let's think of this scenario.
Let's think of this scenario.
So what we will do,
let's
create a secret number.
So I'm going to have my secret number,
for example.
Right?
It can be a number from 1 to 20,
for example.
Right?
1 to 20, 50, 100, whatever.
Right.
Whatever the image or example,
we will create a secret number.
Then what we will do, let us.
Let's ask user
to guess my secret number.
Right?
So now I will have one number right?
Then I will ask user to guess
my secret number.
Right.
So now guys, do it.
What do you guys think? Right.
Let's say from one to, I don't know, 1000
from to 100 don't matter.
Right?
Let's say in my mind
I have a number 77 right now.
I will ask my user, Hey, do you
hey, guess my number.
Do this know how many times
it will take a user to guess my number?
Do you know
your guess?
My number 77.
We don't really know, right?
We don't really know.
But what I want to do,
I want to keep asking.
Right. I don't know
if it's going to take ten times.
I don't know.
It's going to take 20 times
or maybe one time or 100 times.
Right.
So now I don't really know
how many times I have to ask,
but what I'm going to do,
I'm going to ask, continuously asking.
I'm still until a user guesses
the number, as soon as user enter 77,
then I will check is
the 77 is the number that I'm looking for
as long as the number.
As soon as the number becomes match,
then I will stop asking.
Right.
So now you have to think, okay, first,
first I have to ask a user.
It means I need a scanner.
Then I have to ask.
I have to I have to ask a user. Right.
Then I have to repeat a block of quote.
I have to keep asking.
Keep asking, Keep asking. Right.
It means I need to look right for now.
We to lose. Right.
So now let me ask you this first.
First, are we would you ask for a number
or we already can check
if the number is equal to my equal
to my secret number or not equal.
Can I come, Pierre, before I can
I check my condition
before I ask for a number?
So first right.
So first what I have to get.
I have to get the number right.
I have to ask the number from a user
and only then I compare.
Right?
So first
I will have to perform the action, right?
So let's try to do this right and then
I'm going to and then hit keep asking
for more number
due to user.
So user gets the secret.
So user guess
that's because number
two, we will have two things.
Okay.
So first, right, so first
what I'm going to do,
I'm going to have a secret number.
So what is the secret number?
This secret
winning number, Right.
I mean, that's fine. Let's go for 17 now.
I guess it's like a lottery, guys, right?
So the lottery has once won.
Lucky number, right?
So now what?
I said, I have my secret number.
Now I want to ask a user.
It means I need a skin scanner
and equals new
scanner.
The right.
So now what I have to do, I have to ask
a user to gift my secret number,
but I have to keep until he guesses.
So it means I will have to repeat
this same block of code.
Write this same block of code so
repeating the same block of foot,
I have to place it inside that.
Why do I have to put inside the loop
now in order for me to use a well,
I need to have a condition.
Right at this moment,
I don't have any condition.
So what? I can go
I can go for a dual right.
Hey, what I'm trying to do, right,
what I'm trying to do.
Let me ask a user to guess the number.
Right.
I'm going to say this is all in here.
Please.
It's my
secret number.
For example.
It is a number, for example, from 1 to 1.
Right?
So now you have to capture it.
You will have to capture. Right.
So now let's capture it.
So we are going to say, yeah,
that's next.
We're going to capture inside integer
user number
using number.
So what did I do wrong?
Oh, now I have my condition, right?
So now
or next in future, what is the future?
Right?
So now first what I'm doing,
I'm having my action.
Right?
Okay.
Give me the number.
Now, when you as a gives me the number
now what I have to do,
I have to check, right?
I have to check.
And I want to continuously ask
until a user gives me
until user gives me a valid number,
your user gives me a exact
the same number.
So what will be my condition?
Guess what will be my condition?
How long should I look?
Give me the condition.
Or maybe it's going to take me three
times.
I'm not going to go.
One, two, three, four, five. Maybe.
So now I want to continuously looping.
I want to continuously loop
while my number.
Now you guys will tell me what it's equal
with.
It's not equal. Wow.
So what will be my condition?
My condition will be I'm going to loop
until the number that you enter it.
So now you guys tell me it.
Should it be equal
or should it be not equal?
Which operator should I use?
Equal or not equal?
Equal.
Okay, let's do this before running that.
I want you to run this. I want you.
I want you to understand.
Okay? We have to okay.
We have to take it outside
and I'll explain.
You guys,
we have to take it outside. Okay?
So let's declare this variable.
This let's declared
this variable outside of the due body.
Let's declare this variable.
And inside we just going to.
Inside we just going to initialize it.
But let's do it outside
and I'll explain you one.
So on the line
20, let's declare
a user number inside the line.
24 Let's do it initialization
because
now we will go line by line
and don't be confused yet.
We're going into finalizing
the now let's go line by line
right after bottom.
Do we know what happens in here, guys?
Do we know what happens in here?
Okay, guys.
And please
make sure you guys are all active
right now
because I see the same people Keep typing.
I want to make sure guys understand
loops is very, very important.
Okay.
I want all of you guys to tell me
whether after explanation,
if somebody is confused,
I will repeat again. Right.
But as of now, I hope you guys know what
first three lines means, right?
Just first three lines.
That's where we look right?
Okay.
I hope
you guys all put your weights right.
So now what do we have
yet? Is above the scanner, right?
First, it's
kind of like in my mind. Right?
So now we will see.
We will see guys,
we will analyze it. Right.
Remember, even at the first time
we did it with the mistake, that's fine.
How we can we saw with we can solve it by
analyzing our could see what's happening.
Right. So first okay first lines.
We know what happens now we see do right
do do while repeats block of code
repeats by the code.
Welcome. This is true.
But first what it allows me.
It allows me to enter the body
without checking the condition.
Right.
And first I don't even have the condition.
So I'm saying.
Hey, enter your secret number.
This code will be executed.
No, I'm saying.
Hey, enter it.
For example, guys,
my secret number is 7 to 8.
I'm going to enter, for example.
I'm going to enter 13.
Let's think I'm entering 13.
I want to store 13 inside here.
Right So now after I perform
this action, what I'm doing now,
I'll check the condition.
What is my condition?
Well, user number.
User number is 13.
Now I'm saying equals.
What is the value of my secret number goes
78. Now tell me this is my condition.
True or false?
It's a false right.
But did I guess a number
I did not gives the number yet, Right.
I want to continuously get
until I actually get the valid number.
So now how can I make this condition true
that how can I make this condition true?
It's false right now
can then make it true this
now let's change it to the not equal.
Let's change it to the not equal.
And let's see, guys, this right
now the same thing.
New pape. Give a number. Take a guess.
I'm going to enter 13
entering 13 store in here
now after I exited my do body Now
I'm chicken Hey well 13
is not equal to 78.
Is the condition true or false? This
condition is true now.
When the condition is true,
my code goes back.
My code goes back is going to ask me
second time now again,
I'm going to capture the number.
I'm going to enter 55 right now, 55
will be stored inside user number.
Now I'm chicken. Hey,
what is the condition?
While 55 not equal to 78 now
condition again.
True.
Now my code will keep be repeating,
repeating, repeating.
I'm due until what days?
Until when?
My call will get repeated.
Now, when you going to enter 78.
When we're going to enter 78.
Inside
now we're going to see, hey, is 78
not equal to 78?
Now? What is the condition?
Now? Condition becomes false.
And can I continue running the look, one
condition is false, guys.
No, that's it.
Now my loop cannot go back.
It exists. My new well body.
Right.
So first of understand
that there should be a right condition.
Right.
Okay. Please.
That's my number. 11.
No quiz.
That's my number 1266.
No, 67. No.
Now 78. Boom.
It stopped right now outside.
Maybe we can add some sequences
or you got it, for example.
Right? Something like that.
You got it right. Now let's run
11. No. 12.
No, 67.
No, 78 right now.
78. Is it not equal to seven?
The condition becomes false.
Now, I cannot go back inside my body.
I will exit right
and outside of the message.
You got it right.
So First of all, this first of all,
this is a perfect example of where
we should go for a while
or do a while, Right?
So usually we go for a while and do
well when we don't know how many times
you want to repeat the code,
but we know we
to repeat the quote
while condition is true, right?
We were repeating the code all the way.
Well, condition was true.
Now why do was the best choice to go?
Because first we had no condition to run.
First,
we wanted to ask for a number in only.
Only after capturing the number
we were able
we were able to use it as our condition.
Right? At first there were no condition.
Only then, hey, what if the user will be
entering seven need from the very first?
Right? Could that be possibility? Yes.
But what will happen?
You will still run in here.
Please enter your guess number.
It will enter 78
and here 70 is not equal to seven.
Need no condition will become false
and you will exist right away.
Right. But until you enter 70,
you quote continuously repeating,
repeating, repeating.
Right.
Could be this same scenario.
Okay.
Could it be the same scenario as done
using the y loop?
Yes, it could be done.
The only thing why loop?
Remember?
Because there we are similar now
based on our logic.
Can we make the C?
Can we make look?
What if you Of course we can make
the only thing using the Y look
there will be repetition of code.
Let's think of this.
How can we do our well?
So us
guess
number one
while you
so in here right
this is was exact the same thing
So we've done the same thing
now the way we said
for the well condition will be
the same condition will be the same.
Now the only thing for a while
I have to have already a used in number
in order for me use it as a condition.
Then which one should I have first
before I bring while this
which which lines should I have first.
So I will have this line. Right?
Because of course
I need to give instruction
and then do I need to grasp,
do I need to grasp the user? This
a question
is I'm trying to do exactly
the same scenarios in the well, right.
And trying to see
what could be the difference.
No. If this is will be my condition, guys,
I have to have
I have to have some value, right?
I have to have some value.
So I still need to get this number.
I still need to get this.
So first, this is what I will do, right?
So now what I'm doing, I'm checking,
but I'm putting it outside of the block.
Now say, Hey, I'm capturing a user number
now only
and only after I capture a using number,
I can use it as a condition.
Now I can see user number,
not equals to the
number, right?
So now it's
only my only if this condition is true,
then what you guys want to do?
What do you guys want to do?
So in here think it gets right?
So in here at first you ask
and then I'm going to enter 55.
Now you check 55,
not equals to 78.
So now condition will be true. Why?
It's true
because my number is not matching.
I want to keep asking.
I want to keep asking until the number
not matching.
So what call will go inside my while guys.
So do I have to ask again?
Yes, I have to ask again.
Do you guys think
I need to capture a given or no?
Or are just I just going to print
and I need to capture it?
Right.
Because if I'm not going to capture inside
my wild body,
then my loop will become infinite, right?
So then again, inside,
I will have to repeat this block of
like I will have to do it again.
So now let's try to run my while code.
Let's try to run my wild.
I'll put my breakpoint in here
or maybe just in here.
I'll do debug
what it is.
Guess my secret number. Right.
I'm going to enter 90.
Let me close this for now.
Right. So now what happens?
Secret number is 78.
User number is 90.
Now I'm checking
he is 90, not equal to 78.
Condition is true. Okay.
You still did not guess
because you did No guess.
I'm going to continue asking again
right now.
My skin again.
Okay. Condition was true.
Please guess my secret number
I have to repeat. Right?
I'm going to say 88
right now. 88.
I have to capture it. Right.
So now what will happen?
90 will get replaced.
The 80 they go right.
And now when I capture a new number,
now again,
what I'm comparing right
now, again, I did.
Yes, I did. It is not the same as 78. Now.
I have to keep asking again
and I have to capture it again.
Now, I'm going to enter 78 right now
after I entered 78 does not step.
It still has to go back.
Now it says, hey, is 78 not equals 78.
Now condition becomes false.
When condition is false,
I am keeping the body right
and then outside we will just
we will just add.
Got it right. So
you think
we through a number, right?
Is this line 13 is getting executed 89.
Right.
So now after capturing 89
now I'm checking my condition.
Right.
Because for the while,
in order for a while to work,
first I have to check the condition.
Check in
The condition 89 is not equal to 78.
Right? It's not. Then I'm going to enter.
I'm going to repeat
and I have to get tricky.
Like 99.
99 is not the same as 78.
Condition will be true.
I'm repeating the same block code
I am capturing 78
now once my user number
78 is equal to the second number right?
So now condition becomes false.
When condition is false,
I skip an entire wild body
existing
while body outside the world body.
I have that without
that right.
So good to see
both of the things could of be done
right could be done using
either while or do well with my
right
finger. Right.
Both could do the same thing right
with this.
Right was going to work.
But now when you go
like logically for the right
but now when you look right
when you really look
so this is the code using do while this is
the code used in the wild.
So What do we seeing
we seen repeated lines.
Right.
And what are we saying
when it comes to our coding?
What are we trying to eliminate the
we try to redundancy.
Right.
So in this case
a dual was a better choice.
Why new was a better choice
because first we wanted
do something in only
then we wanted to compare.
Right? We only then you wanted to compare
the main difference
between wild and do what right do first
does the action
and only then checks condition
Well first checks the condition
only then repeats the action.
Is there any questions?
This any questions?
And I'll give you or if you want to,
if you want a lot
or if you're going to win, I'm afraid
I'm not going to see you in the class
after that.
Yes, I'm going to leave a guess.
I'm going to leave it.
You still will be here. Okay.
That that's good to hear.
Next, we are going to the next one.
But I wanted to give you
just a couple exercises exact
the scene that we did with the while.
So this way you guys will see right then.
I just want you to practice with the duel.
This way you guys will see that exact
the same thing
you can do with the do.
A little bit confusing,
but understandable. Okay.
I hope it's like 10% confused.
Right.
Okay.
Well,
some of you type in what I'm going to ask.
This is just for practice, guys.
This is just for practice.
I want you to do a quick tasks case.
They will be repetition,
but this way you will practice the
dual.
Right?
I just want you to do the same thing.
Praying numbers from
I don't know, a little bit
prime numbers
from,
I don't know, 30 to 70 use and do what
I just want you to practice that
and maybe let's do the same thing.
Odd numbers bring numbers
from 99 to 1
using dual right then example.
But you guys will see that exactly
the same thing can be done as a duo.
Okay, so try to do this quick and
then we going to move to the next look.
Okay?
All right.
All right. I hope you did it right.
And now you guys, no more slopes.
Just make sure you know when to go
for which one right?
You is in both,
you can accomplish the same task.
But we say, Hey,
when do we go
for it, When do we go for a dual?
Right?
What do we know?
At least we want the code to be executed
one time, right?
Well, even the conditional before.
So you want to execute code
at least at least once, Right?
So when do you use dual ready word?
When you want to repeat the block of code
at least one time? Why?
Because do right?
Even by looking at that,
we went by looking at that code, right?
Just by looking at the code,
you see the do
don't have any condition
before the block of code.
Right.
What are we going to look for? E Right.
The way our if works, he has Eve
and then the same our Eve has a condition
like Eve has a condition
and only then allow us to go inside
while has a condition
only then allows to go inside.
When you look at the do do it
don't have any condition at first, right?
First it allows you
to execute the block of code.
Only then we need to check the condition.
Right.
So that's the main difference between
while in duo
and once again guys out of this two loops
out of this two loops
while will be more popular
while will be more popular.
And this example this
and this example of while
or whether do
well it's actually the best example.
When should we use while and do well.
Right?
Because what are we saying in here?
Hey, we want to keep asking a user
for a number until you guess it, right?
You want to play a lottery
until you win it, right?
Do you know how many times
you have to play the lottery? No.
But what are you going to do?
You're going to buy the tickets
until you win, right? So.
But you don't know how many times.
But you will be repeating this
same action.
Keep buying and buying and win
until you win.
Right?
So when you don't know how many times
you want to repeat a block of could you
while or do while always always
the best looks to use the best
which to use now
you're giving us another loop
and this loop is actually
very very beautiful
look and you guys going to allow it?
Probably than before.
That's what that one.
Then the while that's why we show you.
Well, first, but for a loop, it's
a very beautiful loop.
It's a very well nice structured loop
and the for loop compared to the
why loop is actually more popular.
Okay maybe probably more more times
we will using it for loop.
Right.
So now in which cases do we go for a for.
So now you guys are learning
that third loop,
the third loop
that you are learning, right?
So now Java says, hey,
I am giving you a loop.
Very beautiful, very well structured loop,
which is for loop.
Where do we go for a for loop?
All loop we go when we know in advance,
when we know in advance how we need times
we want.
You repeat this same block of code.
For example,
when we look at this scenario, right?
I want to say good morning three times.
Am I doing repetitive action?
Yes, I'm doing repetitive action, but
I know in advance
how many I want to repeat this action.
Right.
So again, this be done means that
while yes, it can be done with the well,
but now we are moving the four.
So what the for loop says hey, when
you know in advance
how many times you want to repeat
the block of code, go for the for loop,
go for four.
Look for loop
always will be the best choice.
Why the for loop is the best choice
because the four
look this very nicely structured.
Okay so the why the for a loop works it
has you probably guys already saw it right
or loop.
It's very nice.
So we have a four
which is a keyword right.
So right away is four.
I have to repeat the block
of good number of times.
Right.
So the way the for works,
what do we look at in here guys?
What do we do?
We have a variable that we initialize.
We a condition that we check
and then we have instrumentation by the
you guys see they're all somewhere
in different places, right?
They also way different places.
Initialization happens
outside, implementation happens inside.
Right?
And this happens in the condition
right now.
Think about
when you could become as large.
Now when you code becomes large and here
you have multiple, multiple lines.
Then It's complex.
Sometimes it's hard for you
to see where you are incrementing right.
For example,
there will be 20 or 30 more lines.
Right.
It's kind of hard for for you
where you increment and it's kind of hard
to see how many times
you will be repeat and block of clock.
Right.
So now when it comes to the full loop,
everything you find is one line.
So right away, by looking
only in one line, you don't have to scroll
it left right to look at all the things
by looking at one line
that's, you know how many times
this loop will perform the action.
So what happens in here?
Inside a follow we're doing initialize
right integer.
I for example, equals to one
we the condition at this same line.
Right.
I'm looking at the scenario
where I want to say
high five times, right?
So am I doing repetitive action?
Yes, I'm doing repetitive action.
Do I know how many times I want to repeat?
Yes, I know. Okay.
We can do it using the for loop
and follow will be the best choice.
Right.
So integer I equals to one initialization
now condition I less or equal then fight
right I less or equal than five
and then increment or decrement
also happens on the same line
I plus plus right
and then inside
and then inside the block of code.
That's where we're going to repeat
an action like for example, system
that out that gray line right this way.
So let me just say the shorter way for
system there are the print element, right?
And I'm going to say hi in here,
right?
So what is the beauty in here?
This initialization condition
increment or decrement happens
all at once, right?
It's always will be in that order this.
So now you as a programmer,
by looking at this code, you know,
right away, you know right away
how many times you could real be repeated.
Right. And it looks cleaner.
It looks cleaner.
It looks more organized. Right.
And they know right away whether you need
to increment or decrement.
Right.
And then a block of code
that you want to repeat you place inside.
Right.
So for a loop,
where do we go for the full look or look?
This same thing this repeats block of code
and number of time
based on the condition
all loops work exactly the same way.
All loops run your code
while the condition is true.
Right?
So now the only thing okay
now are no three loops.
Which will do I go?
So we say go for a loop.
We use for loop
when we know
in advance
how many times
anchors we want to repeat
block of point.
What do I know? Yes, you told me.
I want to say high five times, right?
I want to say high five times.
When do we go for a well, we use while
when we don't know
in advance,
when we don't know how many times,
how many times
we have to
keep block of code.
Right.
All right.
So the example
you guys can can think of the scenario
that when we did a guess number right.
I will continue asking the user
until he guesses the numbers.
I will continue by the lottery
until I'm going to win.
Right. I'm two. I'm going to win. Right.
So in this particular scenario,
you'll go for a we for a while,
but when you know in advance
will go for four.
Right.
So endless unless I want to repeat,
I want to say high five times.
Right.
Let me go for
it was three for gain.
Four is what Four is a keyword right.
As soon as you click on Run, Java enters
you inside your main block.
Right.
The event is inside your main block
and then it's used
for as soon as it's important. No.
What is the ID for this keyword?
It's a loop.
What is a loop loop?
I have to repeat block a fourth
as long as the condition is right.
So the way the for loop we have to
initialize the variable integer.
I set equal to one, then semicolon
right after the semicolon.
We have a condition.
I have to meet this condition to be true
five times next week.
Then and then I. Plus. Plus. Right.
And then when we say we're saying hello.
So any works exactly the same way guys
if you want to try to double right
you're to try to block
so what happens right initialization
condition and
right so
first our variable will be our initialize
then we're going to check the condition.
And as long as the condition is true
based, can you enter the block of code?
Yes, we can enter the block of right.
We enter in the block of code. Right.
Integer equals to one condition was true.
That's why we printed Hello.
Then after that, we're happens
and after that implementation happens
after implementation again we check.
And the condition.
Condition
is to print in that. Hello. Right.
So it gives you very nice and very clean
loop.
Right. Everything is set in the one line.
You don't have to scroll up and down
to look for variables,
to look for the increment. Right.
It's a very beautiful.
That's very beautiful.
Very popular. Right.
So now I want to show you guys
how the logic,
how it could actually in CI.
So this way you guys understand. Okay
so how the code ups
that people just extra squeezed in in here
so I can okay
so so which action first happens first
first we initialize in the variable right
We are initializing the variable.
Guess how many times overall
when we when we just started
learning course, how many times do
we have to initialize the variable
initialization hope once, only once.
Remembering this right then
assigning the value,
reassigning that happen many times,
but initialization only once.
Right declaration integer
I What are we doing via
declaring the variable
and then the initial initialize.
And yet this process this happens
only once.
Right?
Then what happens after that? Right.
What happens after that.
After that as a second step.
This as a second.
We are checking the condition
as a second step.
And please make sure you guys remember
this. Pass this.
Then we check in the condition
this process happened.
Second Now, after after
the condition is true,
we are going inside the loop.
We are going inside the right.
So then the code that we have, the abort
the code
inside the loop body,
right inside the loop by
will be executed.
So entire code, entire code
that starts from opening blueberry and
closing the little body right.
So after we execute your code,
this after we execute the code,
when the Java goes back
all in, only after it goes bad,
then they do incremental.
So after number three,
this process happens,
implementation happens first
and then after incrementally
shouldn't happen.
Then again, what we are doing,
we are going to check
for a condition, right?
And then because instrumentation happen
next time,
it will be will check
if tool is been sliced by two or three.
Now one condition is true again,
we are going back,
executing the block of code
and then again we are going back.
Remember, guys,
the loop cannot stop by itself.
Right
loop done Java do anything by itself.
We as a programmers instructed it right?
Then it goes back again.
It shows the condition of the checks,
the condition.
So after implementation again
the checks condition
after check the condition
if executes block of right.
So this cycle continuously,
continuously repeating.
Okay, implementation
happens
only after the existing block of code.
So this way when we go back.
When we go back only then implementation
happens and then condition it.
Right.
And this we can see,
we can see it while we debugging.
Right.
So I guess see when we at the first line
incremental tation checking,
the condition happens right away.
Right.
So this way because conditional was true
now you I
you could see still equals to one right.
It did not get incremental
because implementation did not happen
first
it's going to execute the block of code
after is execute block of good
only then it come back, then it goes back.
And when it goes back
it will get incremented.
And right away. It checks the condition.
And if the condition is true,
then it goes inside.
That's where you get to to right
then goes back.
Implementation happens, implementation
happens, taking the condition,
running the code,
going back in fermentation, the condition
running code, implementation
chicken condition, running the code.
You guys see now the value is five, right?
The value is five.
Now, Java does not stop.
Java cannot stop.
It knows its inside
before it's repeating the cycle.
So now it goes back.
Now It will do increment
and it will check the condition.
Now condition will be false.
When condition is false,
I cannot enter the loop body and.
I'm going to miss
weeks
because because we still increment red.
Because we still increment.
Yeah. First
you think that this all happens at once.
But no, this happened one time right away.
Check the condition going inside
and after that only these two lines.
Repeat increment check.
Condition increment check.
Condition.
You only modify it.
Now, of course, guys,
remember what we're doing in the loop
to repeat black of code,
to repeat block of code that we have right
to repeat block of code that we have in
the Let's look at more things
like we're going to repeat
what we've done before.
So let me see.
I want to print
numbers from 1 to 20.
So how are we going to do it?
Are you going to do this right?
So now, right away,
when you think right, right.
Well, when you think I want
you pray for 1 to 20,
do I know in advance
how many times I want you print?
Yes, because it's from 1 to 20. Right.
I have a starting point.
I have the end point. Right.
So most easiest loop to go
is a for a loop.
Right? Right. Along is 34
your I
equals two.
What this
one right.
High less or equal then 20.
Right.
Because I'm looping all the way to 20
and then I
and then
which variable they are printing is
we are printed by that we are printing.
Right.
And let's print maybe all in one line
so this way we can see it.
Nice, like
from 1 to 20.
Right.
So somewhere this right
somewhere what we can see.
Right.
So the way I did your description. Right.
So first initialization
we knew
was then
right, first initialization happened,
then condition was specified.
Specify look not what happens
this condition and then we have increment
decrement like increment
increment slash decrement
like chrome.
Right.
Okay.
Now where that is,
so where maybe you can hear about our
for loop for someone,
it makes it easier because what we know
need to know how many times we are right
somewhere.
What you might hear
is a first we put in our starting point
start point
right start point.
Then we should have our end point
and point
and then third increment decrement
the same thing.
So some of you can think of this, right?
So what is my starting point?
My starting point is one,
What is my Indian point?
My Indian point is 20, right?
And then from 1 to 20, what I'm doing,
I am going increment in.
Right, I'm going,
I'm going to increase in the numbers.
That's
why we're using that increment. Right.
So this way, let's say
I want to bring the numbers right.
If I want to print the numbers from,
I don't know, 100 to 20.
Right.
So now what is my starting this?
I want to print from 100 to 20
integer I equals to 100.
Right.
So what is my Indian point? Right.
What is my Indian point?
My ending point is 25 and 20.
Now you just have to figure out, oops.
Now you just have to figure out
the condition, Right?
How do I make this condition to be true?
What's more equal, less or equal? Right.
And now when you really think now
going from the largest number
going to the smallest, right.
So what are you doing?
You are decreasing the values, right?
So now what you do, do I French minus
one. Now
we can print our.
Oh, what happened, guys? Why?
Why then why am I.
Look, did no work.
Why am I no what?
My condition. Right.
My condition So and you guys see
works in the back this thing we're right
variable got initialized
now we check and hey is 100 less than 20.
No condition is false.
One condition is false.
I cannot the block of quote right.
I cannot enter one.
So now we have to change for a greater or
it changed for the greater or equal Nagel.
Now we got all the numbers right.
We got all the numbers.
Not all at once.
Okay.
Now, I think, Alex, you asked
what if I going to ask you right
now, guys, I want you print
numbers
for one 250,
but I want you print only
human numbers.
So how are you guys going to do it
with the My
we control is condition.
Okay,
that's good.
Okay.
Right. So first, right.
If we're going to go
the way we were going to solve for right.
What is my starting point?
My starting
point is one right here are equals to one.
Then how far in my loop in I'm open
all way to 50.
Right? All the way to 54, 1 to 50.
I am incrementing right.
I was like,
wow, if just going to print my equal,
if I'm just going to print my I.
Right.
So we know what happens
if I'm just going to print
I without any condition what will happen.
I will just one, two, three, four,
five fold the weight of that eight
I want you print only and only
when my is an odd number right.
I have the condition right?
If I want you print only only if the
I is even number
then listen through the conditions
for the condition. If I
want two equals equals zero, I am only.
That will be the case
when I'm going to do my output.
Only then I'm going to do my system.
Right.
So this is one way.
This is one way. Right.
And let's let's look at
let's look at the logic, right?
Let's look how this works, right?
This code that we are looking
integer equals to one one is less than 50.
Condition is true.
I am going inside as soon as I enter
my full body.
Right this where my full body
and you go see everything is aligned.
This is where my full body start.
This is where my full body.
It's right As soon as I enter
the body of my for loop,
you will see if notice here
if one more to add, the first iteration
condition will be false.
Right.
And you guys see
you don't worry right now.
You don't worry right now
about where's your instrumentation,
what course
your instrumentation is all in one line.
So now implementation will happen.
So Now one, one plus one will give me.
Q Right, will give me two.
Now check in the condition.
Hey, is two less than 50
Condition is true, right?
I'm going inside now.
I'm saying here is two mod two.
Yep it is a condition is true.
Now I'm going to print, I'm going
to print two things and that same thing.
It goes back repeats two plus one.
Right? Two plus one will be three.
Three is still less than 50.
Condition is true.
I'm going to inside now
inside I have if statement three
my two condition will be false.
I'm not printed right I'm look pretty.
So now let's see.
I guess what would be the other way?
Right?
We know that we can also know
implementation, right?
That we know that
we can do incrimination by
exact the same
thing, but we can do incrimination by two.
Right.
So now let's think is
what should be my initialization
and condition in in everything.
Right.
So at first right
we're saying, hey,
you know what I want to do?
I want to increment by two.
Can you increment by two? Yes,
you can increment by.
But first you have to
initialize it into your I equals two.
Now the only thing you have to think
I want only even numbers.
And if I'm going to increment
by two, right.
If I'm going to increment by two
now what should be my starting point is
we can start with that.
You no problem.
We can start with the two
or we can start from the zero, right?
Or we zero.
We don't need zero free.
I'm going to start from two and in here.
What's my condition? This
by less or equals, right?
And then it is going to frame my
what or why did we need
space
figure.
Right. Exactly the same footprint.
Even numbers from 1 to 50 exact
the same output here.
Exactly the same output in here.
Right.
So this is how our or
for loop works, right.
Oh, let me ask you one more
and then I guess
I'll give you I'll give you the task
and what will be the output of that
or I can do
this one
I lost or equals 40
I will come in What will be my output?
This.
Okay, Let me make it less.
Let me make it less.
You guys already execute, right?
The best way to execute it.
If you know the logic, how it works
inside, then all this makes it right.
They initialize into one
take in that condition.
First I'm printing one going back Now.
What are we doing to this?
I would say one plus five right now.
One plus five will give you six
because incrimination by five,
hey is still six less than 20 years.
Okay, then I'm printing I going back six
plus five will give 1111
still less than 20.
We want to print 11 going back again
plus five.
This will give us 16 and so. Right.
And so the only difference what happened
in here, just my increment, right?
I'm incrementing by five,
I'm incrementing by two.
And before I was just increment right.
It's always,
always this p attention to the condition
because condition must be true
before you enter the body.
Right.
And just look at your implementation
in documentation.
Right.
Right. So let me try to run it.
What is the output?
This is the output
that we got right. Once it's
I will be myself. I
yes. So
let's look at our slides
and I'll give you the task.
I'll give it the time
for loop.
Right.
So they don't go for loop
exactly the same way
it uses to execute this same block output
several times.
Right.
The only thing when we go, when we know
the number of repetition or we call them
the number of the iterations is fixed,
right?
It's fixed means we know in advance.
That's how we'll probably see. Right.
And when you look at this index,
we put it to different ways.
Initialization, condition, increment,
decrement or somewhere maybe we'll be
you guys will see starting value in in
value and the same increment or decrement
and of course what we have, we have block
of code that we want to repeat, right.
That you want to repeat.
Right.
So initialization happens first,
then condition
after the condition, right,
a body will be executed, right?
The bodies, the loop is executed
and only then increment
and decrement.
Here, two different examples
you guys will see.
All right.
And I'm going to give you the tests.
This the task is similar.
What we've done like now
it will make more sense.
Use them the for loop. Right.
For example. Right.
I'm going to give a next time
task a pre numbers from whatever right
you know the range
so now because you guys know three loops
you should be if you know in advance
how many times you should look
you should go for a or look like
you should go for the performance.
Okay let me give you the task.
And after that, guys,
I will be showing you more stuff.
Right.
So let's send it in that,
of course, announcements.
And one thing is,
even though it's a repetition, try
not to copy and paste this.
Try not to copy paste. Okay.
Try not to copy and paste.
And you guys can do them right now.
Yes, we'll do them right now.
Enough
that guys will be a break time. Right.
I'll give you 10 minutes for the task.
I'll give you 15 for break. Right.
So let's be back.
But please
make sure you complete the task. Right.
Because after that,
we will be looking at more things
completely.
Third and revised by right.
It will be 1525.
By 148.
I you to do all of this and just come back
by 140.
So copy and paste.
Guys, I want you to do it because for look
we actually will be using a lot of the
for loops, right So I want to make sure
you guys understand it.
But I think after a while
it looks pretty pretty easy
and pretty, pretty clean for you now.
Well, I guess I'll be back at 140.
Are the tests that they are in.
It's in the course and that's them.
Okay.
All right.
They were you. You, you.
You did not get a chance to get a break,
will you?
Will you want to have a break there
very soon?
Too many tasks.
Oh, that's a put a little extra hour.
So and then the you
then you can take your break right.
You neither
are I guess
you guys going to have a break soon right
then then you guys going to have a one day
break from us.
Okay.
All right. Is right.
So let's look again.
So what are we covering today?
We looking into our loop concepts, right?
So we say loop concepts in Java exists
to repeat a block of code.
Right?
So now Java. Now we just run three, right?
Java use a different variations
of the loops using different variations
because there's a difference scenarios
where we have to use each particular loop,
right?
Regardless of kind of loops,
they will repeat block of code
as long as the condition true, right.
But Java gives a different variation
because we should use them
in different scenarios.
Right?
So Java sees, hey whenever you guys know,
when you know in advance how many times
you want to execute a block of code right.
You want to repeat block of good.
Then please
make sure you go for a for loop right
when you know, hey,
I want you to do something five times.
Hey, I want to I don't know.
I want you the calculator
that we execute it right?
I want to make that program run,
I don't know, five times.
Why five times?
Because I want to test different
conditions. Right.
For example, for this, Which statement
was our homework?
Right. For this switch statement.
I want to run this task
five times y five times
because I want to provide value
for multiplication value
from value for addition, subtraction.
And if there will be invalid write.
I want this particular script
to be executed at 510
so I'm able to test my OC,
then go for a four, go for a four.
Look right here.
What I would like that I would like to do.
I want to guess a number, right?
I want to give the number.
I want you to guess a number. Right.
I want you to play a lottery
until you win.
Do you know how many times
you have to play?
No. You don't know when in the scenarios
when you don't know how you how long
you want to repeat a block of.
Could we go for a while?
Loop. Right.
So now what do we go for?
Why loop?
We have two variations, right?
We have a two origins.
We have a while
and we have do what we have.
Well, and we have a new well.
So now when you know that you don't know
how many times you want to repeat,
but you want to repeat,
as long as the condition is true right
now, just I do well.
Oh, well.
So what is the difference?
Well, we'll check the code first.
You will execute the code
first only, then checks the condition.
Right.
So now, based the particular scenario,
you guys will be able to see
which you want to complete.
Right. Which task you want to go right.
And anything.
All those stars, guys, they were very
they were very similar
to what we have done before.
Now, the only thing where we seem that the
for loop is a more structure train loop.
Right.
Although this is a cleaner code.
All right.
So just by looking at one line,
you as a programmer can define
how many times you quote will execute,
right by looking at one line y
because initialization, condition
and implementation or documentation
specified all in one line.
Right?
So quite easily, easily.
I can read my work.
So I bring an example of this
where we can actually very easy
right where we can see a benefit of the
what the benefit, what a little.
But I can bring it exercise where
we can see how powerful loops are right.
For example this right
how we want to
create a multiplication table.
I want to create a multiplication tables
multiplication table.
We know those table, right?
For example,
I want to create a multiplication
table of ones or twos or threes or force.
Right.
So what I want you
to see in multiplication
I want to see one flow one by one equals
two one, right.
One by two is equals to two
and one by two is equal to three.
Right.
So all way for example
I get one by ten equals to ten.
Right.
And then if I want to change my table
we still then the same thing
two by one equals two,
one two by two equals two two.
Right.
Two by three equal absurd to for us.
Two by three
equals to
six all the way to by ten equals to 20.
Right.
So now this multiplication
there's we can easily do with our
for loop.
Right.
So now do I know how many times
I want to print.
Yes I know I want to print,
I want to multiply from 1 to 10.
Right. From 1 to 10.
I want to multiply right.
And then I want to multiply one by one
by one,
by two, by three, by four by five.
Right.
So which variable do you guys think
be holding this values?
Which variable.
Our I. Right.
Our variable
that is keep getting income centered.
Right.
That variable
that keeps getting incremented right now
let's see how we can do it in our code.
Right. How we can do it now
for now, just simple one right
where we just
can multiply only one number, right?
So let's say I want to do
multiplication of once, right?
And then if you want to do this right,
so I have my number integer num equals
to one right y
because I want to do multiplication
or once I want to do multiplication of one
from one all the way to ten.
Right.
So now what will be my starting point
this integer
I equals to it.
We starting from one
because we want to do one by one, right?
One by one equals to one.
And then how far are we going
this time last week was then turn
and then incrementing or decrement in days
right.
Right.
And then we are going to say here
we can just do print,
but now we can print out what is it?
What are we trying to do? We trying to do?
I multiply by nothing.
So in now let's go.
Now multiply by point nine.
Right.
So this way.
And now look. Now it's a constant
daily, right?
It's not changing.
What will be changing in Malawi?
I will be right
First time, which will be one by one,
then one by two, then one by three.
Right.
And if I'm going to run here,
it gives me all the weight of ten, right?
If I want to have a nice output,
let me add some things right.
I'm going to say now, plus multiply right.
Multiply by I
words. So
those
okay num one
multiplied by one right equals
so num
multiply by i
which is one equals
none multiplied by right.
So now let's see
what's going to happen next.
Right now we got our table.
So now ac1
multiplied by
O are missing by multiply by nine.
And now what do we get? Right.
So one, it's a constant value
that comes from our now.
But what is changing
because our I inside to get an incremental
and this y value of I is changing from one
all the way to ten, right.
Yeah.
There are two different variables, right.
Because you have to multiply,
you have to multiply one by all of this.
Then if you want to change to two,
we will have to multiply to
for all these values
and then three, right.
So now what we can do, we can change
nonselective right now what are we getting
get we get all the twos right,
we get all the tools.
One day multiply by all the little ten.
Right now you want to do
the multiplication table of nines
with you, click on it.
Now we get a multiplication of nine.
Same. So now it is the help of you guys.
We can easily, easily create
those multiplication tables right
then how we are able to do it because
our marbles keeps getting incremented.
And here we just using
our theory, just using our
arithmetic operation.
Right.
Or to make
any questions those any questions
and I'm going
to show you so subjunctive for you.
You are very active.
Okay. What about? Okay, guys, let me ask
who has a question.
This tell me who at this
point has some questions.
Okay.
I want I want you best to before we go,
going to throw more stuff, right?
Okay.
Alexander, you have
you just mentioned the concatenation
operator, right?
Alexander
Because look here, you have a variable.
You try and content.
You made the variable
with the string, right?
You concatenate your variable
with the string, you need a plus sign.
Yes. Now, when I have different variables,
that's two different variables, right?
The problem when is a test?
Yes, but again,
so one thing when I give you all the task
and for example, when the time was up.
Right.
If you're not able to complete
all of them, it's okay.
So just make sure you don't leave them,
but complete them after the class.
Right. Because I know for some of you,
for some of you guys,
it might
you might need some time to think, Right.
Because some of you are very quick,
some of you for you, it takes a lot of
some time. It's okay. It's okay. Right.
So it just do it right there.
Go Get it right.
So it does not matter
how long is going to take you from point
A to point B, as long as you go in there.
Right. As long as you go.
And that's what's more important
because my my guess.
And then you'll be looking for Jeb.
Maybe somebody will get a job
in two weeks,
maybe somebody will get it in two months.
Don't really matter what's matter
that you're ending point, is that right?
That's well, we all have our own piece
of the programing background.
Yes. That that probably will help.
But majority of you guys are not right
in know it will be helpful guys
make sure you can practice in practice
and because I'm sure
some of you guys did not have a
programing background and I'm
sure you guys are doing them great.
Okay, so let me just write one more quote.
Very simple, very simple. Put.
So let me do that.
For example,
I want to print numbers, right integer
I equals to one I let's equal then 20.
And for example,
I just want to print a numbers
and then I'll do I plus equals two.
Right?
And then I'm just going to print it all
by. So that's one of your exercises.
That's right.
How to print the numbers right.
It's no different.
Right. I'm going to run.
You guys know what happens, right?
So we are printing all the other numbers,
all the ones I know.
I have a question. How think is.
Remember when we said,
hey, why not have a variable, right?
When we have a variable here
we have integer num equals to nine.
If I'm going to create
another variable integer num,
I'm going to say equal to my compiler
completes.
Right?
So you guys know who is complaining
right now.
Your compiler
shows you that there's an issue, right?
So what it tells you, it tells you
that there's a duplicate variable, right?
So we already know in this case, right.
So that we cannot have two variables
with the same name within one,
I would say right now
method within one main method.
Okay.
So this will give us an arrow
as a duplicate right.
But now
when we go into all of this,
then how is it
I am able to I have to declare a variable
I in here and to declare the variable
I in here.
Right.
So why my compiler is not complaining
right now?
Why am Java is not getting confused?
Okay, so now let's
when it comes to variables, right?
So now it's important where you
right where you declared this variable.
Okay.
So now when it comes to declaration
of variable num,
you guys see I declared my name.
Okay.
Inside my main block of code,
our main is the method.
So it means this variable right now
this is visible to the entire block.
This block
Now, when we are declaring the variable I,
we are declaring it inside our for loop.
So it means this variable, this
this variable
right now is visible
only to this block of code.
That's where it being created
and that's where it release.
Okay.
So the same thing, this variable,
I only belongs to this block.
What is the what is this?
Let's say I don't know where is that
where it starts leaving the word in
and it starts
where are you using your for loop
and the variable ends
at the time
when you are exiting your form.
Okay.
So that's why guys,
we are able to create the variable in here
and be able to create a variable
I in here.
Our java is not complaining. Why?
Because this variable I
it lives inside this block
and it's not visible to this variable
I that lives inside this block.
Okay.
So this variable belongs to this for loop.
This variable.
I belongs to this form.
Okay. Why?
Because it has been declared
inside this for loop
and this has been declared
inside this form.
So that's why I guess now when it comes
to creating these variables, we can loops
we can easy easily declared this variable
here and e declare this variable here.
Right. So no,
we will
look at this example right
first time when I
first started, when I wrote this code,
the number of days
before I did not declared right,
let me remove this line.
So at first time I did, guys,
I declared my variable inside here, Inside
here.
Right. So what happened?
This is why my compiler in here
complaining right?
Yes. Yes.
So that's what it happens. Yep.
So once it exists, that block your
variable, get in remove from the memory.
Yep. That's exactly what happens. Right.
So exactly this same exact
this thing happens in here guys.
Right.
So where we declare error
in our variable user number where we are
declaring a variable, use a number,
you are declaring it inside your do body,
you declare it inside your do body.
Now, this variable
E was not visible outside of this block.
It was not visible outside of this block.
That's your compiler tells you in here,
Hey, use a number.
I cannot resolve it to a variable. Right?
That's why here it tells you
that you have to create that right.
You have to created Y
because your code is not seen
because this variable was created
inside this block.
Okay.
So and this variable
you guys will be looking more into them.
This variable,
we call them local variables.
They are local to the block
where they have been declared.
Okay, you guys are going to have a
complete, complete separate class on that.
But this is just to explain you,
why is it happening?
So that's why what we did,
we did a declaration in here, right?
We did a declaration outside of do block.
We did it
where we're this variables declared.
Is this variables declared inside my name.
So once I declared inside my mean
this variable is e
is invisible to or everywhere
invisible to all the blocks.
Right.
So now when we declared inside the line
20, that's why on the line 25
what we seen is seen shows
that s as a duplicate
Y, because now
you declare this variable inside the mean
and if you declare it inside the name,
it's visible to every single block.
Lulu that we use in, in our code.
Okay. So that's why I'm here now.
Once we declare now,
we can be neutralized.
That's why we created this place
in space.
So now if I'll go back in here,
I'll go back in here.
Now, look this.
If I'm going to print out this out.
All right, so now where am I to start?
What is the difference between this?
It's out and what is it
difference between this isn't right
so this is out is seen variable I Why?
Because you are still inside your body.
You're still your full body.
But as soon as you take it outside,
as soon as you're taking it outside
of your loop right outside of you,
you're variable eight not visible.
If that's what compiler tells,
you can not resolve to a variable.
Right?
You cannot resolve there. But why?
Because this variable I is visible
only for you for look.
Okay, now here
all my guys trying to explain it to you
why we are able to use integer R in here
and declared
the same integer variable in here. Why?
Because they're declared inside
two independent loops.
Right. This is loop works by itself.
This is a loop that works by itself
you're variable.
I lives in here and as soon as you exist
for loop, it does not leave anymore.
Right.
So let me show
you actually in the debugging to this
you will see if in the debugging
you right.
So you will see what happened.
My code, right?
Yes. It's local foods block Right.
This local voice.
So you may see
as soon as I'm entering my name, right,
as soon as I'm entering my mean job, Java
executes the top to the bottom, right?
Until it sees either if condition, until
it sees either for either loop, right?
Because now when it sees
and if it has to do this
selective execution
or when it sees the loop,
it has to do repeated execution.
And now I want you pay
attention to the variable.
So you see you declared a variable name
outside of any block, right outside of
when you block, it belongs to you.
Me, it belongs to me. That's
why it's in here.
Visible, right?
So variable.
I still did not get created. Right?
So now it gets created only normally
when you go into enter your right.
When you enter your for,
let's say, your variable.
I comes up in here right
now, I'll be executing my for loop
ten times one one windows
and right
then right So what is the value of I
the value of my is right now ten.
Right.
I am still inside my four body. Right.
So now what will happen?
I will be going back. I'll be going back.
I am incrementing my I now my
I will become 11.
11 is not less than a ten.
Right. So now you guys practice.
What happens is my
I as as I'm exit in my for loop that's it
my variable either disappear
okay my variable either disappeared
so it's not there any memory anymore
a get vanished right
as soon as you exit in your
for loop variable I is vanished.
Right.
So this way
when you go to the next loop here,
it looks like a complete brand
new variable that is getting created.
And this variable going to leave
as long as you were executing for it.
That's why I this they are this variable
that we've only inside this block.
This item is only inside this block.
Right.
That's why are able to repeat
the exact same variable.
But now when it comes to variable nine,
it stays there in the memory
all the way until you've finished
execution.
Your Me Why?
Because it was declared
outside of any blocks
anyone's
right now again, when you create it, I'm
the only one
and your variable is to exist.
Big needs, big needs exist all the way
until all the way into executing
you loop right now, once you go
back, 19 will get changed to 21.
21 is not less than 20.
Now you are existing for loop, right?
You are rainfall.
So that's why you variable either
disappeared.
All you do you you do all of this
the number and once you exist you mean
and then of course the thing
there's a little thing
that I wanted to show you
why we're able to have integer
I integer I in
both of those.
Okay.
It's I'm going to write
what is there really
there's not really relationship guys
this one variable and this is another able
to see the only thing this variable
is a variable that belongs to the main.
This variable is
it belongs to your for or that's okay.
More details you guys will learn in
in the future classes.
They are actually different
type of variables we have.
Okay.
So now we're just using this type later.
They will there will be some variables
where you can declare else
outside of your main and there will be
different name for those variables.
Okay.
All right.
Let me do more examples.
So now we will do more examples
just to practice
on developing our logic and,
you know, to analyze in the quote.
That's what we're going to do.
Now. I'm just going to create
what I for.
Now let me just make it more for loops.
So let me give you a
I'm going to write the code
on the right B code.
But my question is my question is
I want you to give the output
so you guys, not you guys not running it,
but I want you to look at the current,
analyze it what is the output?
Well,
I'm going to have a loop, right
for Going to say it.
I believe you are equals to one
integer.
I I for example less or equal then
and as both
we actually know when you're 20
let's go 51i want maybe six.
We'll go for six. Right.
And then let's
And now what?
I want you to do this Now
what I'm going to do, I am going,
I am going to introduce one variable.
Okay,
we're going to introduce one variable.
I want to say integers. Some
actually I have
two interesting integers,
some equals to zero.
Now, inside my loop,
I'm going to write a code.
I'm going to see them less equals.
And now outside of do
I want to print the value of my variable.
So now by looking at this code,
guess by looking at this code
without running, I want you to tell me
what will be the value of some
21. Okay.
One, two, three, 456 21
six plus seven divided by 218
118 one, 234, five, 611, eight, whatever.
So in the 1118.
Okay, one, two,
three, four, five, one,
two, three, four, five. Okay
620 161 and four.
Okay,
four.
We are not running the core guys.
I just want you to analyze it. Right.
So I'm going to ask you why.
Why 21 Why seven Y6
You would say six.
Okay, now we are
let's look at select analyze, right?
It's important to understand
what happens in our code.
Right? Okay.
So first of all, guys, can you tell me
how many print out statements
am I going to see?
How many print out statements
am I going to see
one way?
One because my print out statement
is not inside loop, right?
It means it won't be repeated.
We just single independent speak, right?
So it will be printed once.
Okay. Okay.
So now let's analyze it.
We're bringing this up.
Let's write something new.
Looking for the variable.
This variable has a value of zero for now.
Right?
So now we know what happens in a year.
Declaration check.
And the condition is
the condition is true. Guess
condition is true.
I am going inside.
Once I entered inside.
What are we doing in here?
This are we doing
increasing some by one.
Right.
But what are we doing?
We are incrementing we are adding right?
We are in the value the variable
I so basically what we're saying is saying
zero plus one, right.
Zero plus one.
What it will us it will give us one.
So now what happened?
A previous sum that was zero.
We take it out now
the sum the value of some equal to one.
Right. Okay.
Then what happens with our loop
goes back,
implementation happens one plus
equals two to
check in the condition.
Condition is true.
Now, when condition is true,
I'm going inside now what are we doing?
Is so what happens inside?
So it takes a value of some
which is was one.
And now what it does, it adds the of I
what is the value of
I is two one plus two will give me three.
Right. And then cycle repeats. Right.
It goes back to plus
one will give me three.
Three is still less than six.
Right.
Okay. Condition Is true. I'm going inside.
So now what I'm doing, I'm
taking the value of some
and adding the value of I.
Right. Three plus three, right.
013 plus three equals to six.
Right. Plus equals to six.
Now going back three plus one is
four is four still less than six.
Yep. Four is still less than six.
Right Condition is true.
Now what was the last value
of some less value of sound was six
and now six plus I is four.
Right?
And then get ten
and then we will have ten plus five.
Right.
Because I will get incremented
by one right.
Condition of five is still true.
Ten plus five people will get 15 right.
Then next time going back,
I plus one will give a six
weeks. He still than six.
And then we get 15 plus six
plus.
That's
where we going to get what 21 right.
When get one.
So what is going to change.
Okay.
What is going to
change is if I'm going to have
some in here,
what will be the difference this.
So now,
instead of the having one print out,
it will print out some every time.
21 times.
That is my condition to 21 times.
How many times my condition is true. This
thinks so.
What you will get
you will get six times condition.
It will be true.
So your print out
statement will be executed six times.
So now what will be printed
six times at first time?
Write it first time. Let's take a look.
And always, always guess.
And you think confusing just the right
angle, right?
So variable sum has a value of zero
for loop, right?
Initialize our AI. Now
what is the variable?
I is one.
What is the value of sum is zero zero
plus one.
Now you will see that your sound
will get changed.
Right now our some change.
What is the value of
some is one going back.
Hi, I got change Rhino.
Let's see that yellow. Right.
So now what we do we doing two plus one
will give us the sum will be three, right?
And so on. But now every time
we are calculating the sum because now
we put the six out inside the body,
now we will be printing some every time.
Right? So now how many times
Sum will get printed?
We will be printed six times three
times six.
Why is six times right? You know what?
Because six times you
your condition will be true, right?
Six times that condition will be true.
So now let me see this.
Let me another similar example.
So you guys will know
what will be happening now right?
So let's do another variable
integer result results to make it
right and
integer and make
or right
is I equals you.
All right, let's record and four
and then I plus
right and now want to say result
multiply equals right
and I want to print result.
What will be my output based.
Okay, that's good. It will be zero. Right?
Because what happens
my result is equal to zero in here.
Right?
And then anything
multiplied to a zero, right.
Anything are multiplied
to zero will become zero.
Okay, let me ask
what if all do result equals you want?
What would be the output?
This one or zero
or four
eight.
Let's take a look.
Let's take a look for
the neuron and then you guys will see.
So it shows me zero, right?
It shows me zero.
Now let's understand what happens.
So here we are
initializing the variable, right?
We are initializing the variable.
So what is the value?
We put We put it value of one.
It goes inside.
Right now we have our loop, right?
So How many times
the condition will be true this?
How many times condition?
Oh, now I have different increment.
How many times condition is true?
Four times.
Two times three times How many times?
Three times. Right.
So first I initializing to zero is zero
less than four years.
Condition is true.
We are going inside now.
What are we doing? Our result is one.
What are we doing?
We're multiplying it by zero.
Anything will multiply by zero equals
to zero.
Right?
So now when we are going back,
what happens is I zero
plus two will give me two.
Is two less than four years?
Two less than four condition is true then
you multiply zero
by two is will give you zero.
Then you going back to plus two.
Four is four less than four? Yes.
But even if you go to multiply by four
still will give you zero.
Right.
So condition was true
three times zero when I was equal to zero.
When I was equal to two.
When I was equals to four.
However, the result. Right.
So now what happens at first iteration
you had one
as soon as you did one multiplied by zero,
you got zero guy.
So now your one got replaced with that
zero, right?
Got replaced with the zero.
And we know the bottom, the last value
will be stayed
inside that variable, right?
So now what if I'm going to change to one
this model will be the result
or what?
413331.
This is one days 313111.
So the same thing first.
First of all, that's
how many times we print in our result.
And we need to be printing the result
only once. Right?
Because we did not put this statement
inside the loop.
Right?
So it executes always once
if it's outside of the loop with things,
if it's only once right,
and then you can do
the same thing, result is equal to one.
I is equal to one.
So what we have one
multiplied by one will give us one.
Right? We are going back.
How we're multiplying, how we incrementing
and we incrementing two.
One plus two will give me three.
Right.
Hey, is that three?
Less than four years.
Three. Less than four Is condition True?
Yes, condition is true.
What was the last value of the result?
The last value of the result was one
one multiplied by three.
Right.
And then stored in it
back inside the same variable.
Three. Right.
And then going back now we had three.
Three plus two gives us five.
Now becomes false.
We cannot enter inside, not enter inside.
So now we're told
you will get three right?
So don't forget about the incremental
you know,
forget about the implementation part.
Okay. All right.
So you guys see there's different things
that we can do inside our loops, right?
This is like all loops.
Okay. This I'm going to give you.
There will be some homework based, this
based on this current.
Yeah.
You guys see, once you know a logic, logic
how your loop works, right?
Once you know the logic behind
how the works, then then it's
will be making more sense
how your code is actual actions
execute right.
Right.
Are we paradise or we are good. Hi.
Good. Okay, now let's see.
Let's see how to tag. Good, good. So good
brain hurts the brain.
We we do shake in the brain,
which is good, right?
Guess it's always good
when when some new information
comes third time you want to go home.
Are you not taking class from home?
Another cup of coffee
for detailed
loading time.
Hard brain. Okay, so let me see.
We have.
Right?
Because what are we going to have?
So we will have the
break nested loops right?
And then your house
call.
Okay.
All right.
Then I'm going to give you a more
because
I'm going to give you
probably more homework.
Okay.
And then what I want you to guys to look
what I want you to give us to look
for a next class.
Next class.
There's
no more things that we going to look. So
I'm going
to give you just the intro right now.
So this way you guys will look like
actually are easy.
One is going to do the introductions
for you and then you guys,
I'll explain your homework
and then I'll let you go.
Basically. Now,
whenever we work with the Loops desk,
whenever we work with the loops,
there are some key words
that we can use inside, right?
There are some keywords that we can use
inside, for example, right?
And it can be any type
of any type of right.
So for example my form, right,
my follow up integer equals two zero.
I like that equals
then I don't know or right
I plus plus.
So based based on the current condition,
how many times conditioner
will be triggered? How many times
four or five
zero.
One, two, three, four.
So it will be
it will be true five times, right?
Because I'm starting from the zero
and I'm including for.
Right.
Just always look at the operator. Right.
You know, if I'm going to run,
we know that my works
well works was given the natural condition
five times, right.
So we it we did expect of our loop
to execute it five times.
Okay.
So now there's some keyword
that we can add
in our inside loops.
Guess what we can use?
We can use some keyword that we say break.
So we already use this keyword.
Guess what is this keyword used to do?
What is this keyword used to do?
Is this key word
to use to observe and black of code?
Right.
It gives out from the block of quote.
So where we use the before
we use that inside our switch,
right inside our switch.
So what as soon as it would see break
what it was doing
it was breaking out from what
from the block of code.
Which block of code
because we declared inside the switch.
So it was getting out from this switch.
Now break works exactly the same way.
Guess what a break will do.
It will get out.
Where would you clear it?
Inside part
we declared inside our for loop.
So what we will do
our break will break our loop.
Right. So what will happen?
What will
happen days and what will happen?
Right.
So your Java initialization checks
the condition.
Condition is true.
Goes inside execute this court.
But then top to the bottom.
Right now it sees a break world.
It is a break it not.
Okay, I'm going to get out.
I'm breaking what?
I'm breaking.
I'm breaking this block.
All right.
So now Java sees break and what it will
do, you will get out from your phone
right?
So this way, your Java just executed
your code one time.
Right?
And this break guys can be used inside
any loop
in the used inside a well look. Right.
So while let me just make this I'm
just going to type right
in so I'm going to say
hello. Right?
So by looking at this look, guys,
what kind of look we have?
What kind of look we are going to have?
It look will be infinite. Look, right.
It will be infinite.
It will be could continuously print in.
Hello? Why?
Because our condition is true, Right?
But now, if I'm like
you are the great keyword, right?
What Happens with my look.
Why look, we'll break. Well, we'll break.
So let's see if we are near the book
and of code
for right
so declaring our variable i0i was was
then for condition is true
that's why I want to happen
we're printed almost done
then you java so break you got out
you broke your for
by writing from bronchial
the thing thing you will do inside a well
hey while condition is true
well condition is true right?
I want to print Hello.
Hello.
Get pregnant
but then your java so break it got up
think got out
and then it printed something right there.
Now is it important guys?
They will be right.
So to me, using the break
does not make sense just to use like that.
Right.
So we will be using break
only only when will be some condition met.
Okay.
So this break you would
usually we will put inside if write inside
our conditional statement because having
this does not make sense to me.
I if I need to print printed one time
I'm not going to place inside a break.
So usually this break keyword will be used
in some set inside some condition.
Right.
As soon as the condition is met, then what
I'm going to do,
I'm going to exit the right.
I'm going to exit the game.
For example, I'll give you the scenario
when it comes to our automation.
Right.
So let's go again to our word,
our application, right?
So as a part of the automation,
guess what is the automation
you guys will be doing?
Automation is
we will be automating browsers,
Okay, any application
that we have on the browsers.
Okay. So this is the application.
And when it comes to testing, as of course
there will different different scenarios
that will be given you in the form of user
stories, right?
You know,
what is a user, for example, right?
So now what you will have do
once, once
you guys start learning the selenium,
you will be able to capture
all the links, right?
You will be able to all the links, right?
Once you capture all the links,
now you have to click
only on one of them, right?
So for example, once you capture one,
two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight links. Right.
So out of this eight links,
you will be looping through
every eight link through every
and you will be checking for a text
as soon if the text, for example,
you want to do enroll
if the text is equals to enroll,
what do you want to do?
You want to click
and then you want to break the loop. Why?
Because what happened?
You found the link that you're looking
for, right?
You to talk through all of them.
Maybe think of Amazon and Amazon
have hundred links, right?
So now you have to go through all things
you have to look through of them
and to see eight is this link has this
text is the next week's link has this text
is this link has this text right.
You will continue looping
until what happens until you find the link
that shows enroll As soon as you find
the link that shows enrolled,
what are you going to do?
You went to click right because once you
then you want to break you'll look. Why?
Because the rest of the links,
something will happen with them, right?
So I don't know if it makes sense right
now, but that's one of the good examples
that we're going to have
right on the application.
We might have links on the application,
we might have ten links.
Right?
But what we have to do,
we have to go to single link and grab
the text will be,
Hey Link, what's your name hailing.
What's your name?
As soon as I find that name,
let me break them.
Let me break them.
Okay, so this
I'm going to finish in early
because probably it is
a lot of things, right?
But what I want you to guys I want you to
look into the break and continue keyword.
Right.
So are they very popular?
Some cases, yes. Some cases no. Right.
Sometimes we'll be using this,
sometimes We want we won't be using them.
But it's important to know
that this keywords can be placed
inside the right and make sure you
you look into another important thing,
another important thing
for our next class.
What I want you guys to
I want you guys to look into nested loops.
Okay.
So what are
this thing will be in the loop.
It's a loop inside another way.
We had Eve inside another Eve, Right.
And of course, this.
In order for you to understand
those loops will be working,
you have to make sure you understand
the logic of the one single right
when it comes to nesting as we can this
anything we can have, we can have four
inside another four, right?
For example, integer equals to one
and then I or equals three
and then I plus plus.
Right.
And then inside we can miss another week
in this two force.
That's fine.
For example, integer J to zero
and then G less than three
and then J plus, for example.
Right.
And then right.
It could be this variation.
Could it be different?
Variation is yes,
it can be different variations.
We can have four, right?
And we can have integer I equals to one.
I literally equals then three
and then I plus plus.
And inside of this we can have while right
instead of this we can her once
and then another block of course.
Right so or we can have while inside
the tree does not matter
right so when we say any but nested nested
loops it's
loop inside
another look loop inside another.
So please make sure guys
mostly we will go for this variation
sometimes in our automation
will be using this variation, right?
But in order in order
for us to understand.
Right.
It's like before we went to the nested,
if we saw how the regular if works.
Right. So the same thing.
Please
make sure you guys practice on the loops.
Okay. Practice on the loops.
So this way. Next class we will touch.
We will touch
this part right in real guys.
So when you use
when you use
let's do
bowling.
I think I got confused a little bit
in the question for a loop
storm we use. Plus
no, we depend on the value, right?
Catalina will just depend on the value
on which value
multiplying and doing the things right.
So that will be for you guys to look
to look for a next class.
But here's the homework. Homologous.
Let me see if I have it.
Then you have to type it for you. This
I'll give you more simpler
Then you guys will do this.
Okay, I'll.
I'll send this. Okay.
So there's one. The task will be.
One of the task will be.
I want you to write.
I want you from your one.
The task explaining.
I want you to calculate, calculate
sum of all.
And in all odd numbers.
Numbers
from range
from range.
For example, one to, I don't know, 100.
Right. 100.
So what does it mean from the range?
From 1 to 100. Right.
From the range 1 to 100.
I want you to calculate this sum of all
even numbers two plus four plus 90.
Right. What will be the total sum?
And at the same time,
I want you to calculate
the sum of odd numbers,
right from 1 to 100.
I want you to do one
plus three plus five, seven plus 99.
What will be the sum, right?
So that is one of the homework.
In another little more days,
I will ask you another homework
we will have write in.
So you guys will should differentiate
what kind of fluke you guys will be using.
Right.
So another homework I'll you
you what I want you to do guys
I want you to ask user to pay
for I don't know let's say soda right
You buy a soda right or whatever thing
you're buying, right.
Ask user to pay it for soda and continue.
Continue asking
you pay until
the user gets
the right amount.
Right amount.
Right. The user gets the right amount.
But this time I'm going to make it
a little more complicated.
This a little more complicated, right?
So what I want you to look into, right?
So if user gives you right, if user gives
if user gives
extra money, X
one money, I want you to give change
your change.
If user gives less money, ask
how much more you need,
how much more unique.
Right.
And I want you to keep asking
until you get the right
the month, right
until you get a right amount.
So I will
I will put it in the more writing by.
For example, I want you to ask
I think I made it
actually will make it pay for an item.
Let's decide which item will be right.
I want you to ask a user to pay
for an item, whichever item
you guys will decide.
And then I want you to keep asking
until you get the right amount.
For example, item will cost $10.
If user gives you 20,
I need you to give them a change.
Right?
If user gives you five,
I need you to for five more
and I want you to keep looping and looping
until you actually
will get a right amount,
until you get actually ten.
So I will write in more detail
and I'll give it to this.
I'll give it to you. Right.
So this is will be
and the only thing you guys
will have to see
what kind of loop you can use.
Right. What kind of loop you can use.
And I think there's a more ripple
will be coming in.
Guys, please don't forget
don't forget about your quiz
And don't forget to look at those
those key words.
Break and continue in the book
for the next class.
Okay.
So I would send that I will
I will make it a little more detail.
Okay.
I will make it a little more detail
so you guys will know step by step.
Okay.
How many replies?
So I think we did not release
logical switch and there will be loops,
so there will be good
amount of ripples too.
Okay, so let me have a look.
So you guys will have a lot
a lot or a lot of homework.
Also guys, the less thing. I'm sorry.
So tomorrow, tomorrow,
what are we going to do?
Because you guys are starting
with the new class, right?
You guys be starting this Google.
This will be starting with Google
and sorry, Google
you you guys will be
starting is get on on Tuesday.
Right on Tuesdays.
What are we going to do, guys,
whenever the new tool comes, Right.
We need to do the installation right.
We are going to do the installation
and installation guys.
We usually don't do it.
You were in the class.
Okay, so installation, we always,
always complete outside of the class.
So when you guys come for a class,
you're ready.
There is no distraction.
Okay, So tomorrow, guys,
we are going to release an instruction
how to install the geek.
Okay So please, please make sure
you install it before to use the class.
Right.
And the same thing guys
we will be doing for our future models.
For example, before you guys will go
start learning selenium.
We will release instructions
how to, how to install selenium
and you guys will have to do it
before the actual class.
Okay, so I want be the instructor
guys who will be teaching gear
for every single module unless we have a
different instructors who be teaching you.
Okay.
But I promise you guys it will be amazing.
Instructor
He will explain you everything in details.
You did not see him yet,
but you guys will see on Tuesday class
and it will be very detailed
class step by step.
And you guys will
known a lot of things, Right?
All right.
So I'll send all of that once again.
But please, please, please
make sure you this practice,
because we have left for Java for basics.
We left with very you know
super complex background
like complex topics.
So make sure you guys prepare yourself.
Okay. All right.
That's to actually will be
will be teaching you Java as well.
So all right okay
a recording the class guys
whenever a zoom gives it back for us right
Zoom has its own mind.
Its own sometimes
takes one hour, 2 hours to give us back.
All right.
Okay. Thank you, guys.
I'll post the whole work
and once again, guys, good job, everyone.
Just please, please much.
Make sure you guys continue
practicing more.
Okay?
All right, guys.
Enjoy the rest of your Sunday,
and I'll see you next.
Okay? Thank you, guys.