Let me start by recording
that. Good.
Good morning.
I'm sorry, guys, for a little late start.
My computer didn't want to start today,
so I don't know what have happened.
Okay.
Is this something
that's something or.
I guess I don't know
what you were talking about,
but I hope you guys are all doing good.
I hope you guys are all excited.
You guys had a good week with us, right?
And overall, you guys had a good week.
That's good.
I am feeling better,
guys, compared to the last week.
I'm feeling better and I hope.
Are you guys also.
None of you get sick
or somebody gets sick.
Get sick too. A little bit.
All guys, please make sure take
take a lot of what I mean. See?
Then just try to stay at home
and get some rest, I think.
I think that's the best medicine
these days.
Whether you get cold weather, you get
cold, eat whatever that is right there.
And I hope you guys feel better
and I hope we can distract you
for the next 5 hours.
Right.
So this way, you don't focus too much on
your sickness, but you guys will be busy.
But if you guys can practice,
please make sure you do.
If you don't, just you guys can
pay attention and just listening.
All right, That's good.
That's good.
All right, guys.
So did this class, right? This class.
We are obviously going to continue
with the topics
right today is already our class number
six, right?
5 hours, right. At first
it sounds a little
a little scary,
but then that time goes fast.
Very fast. Right.
And I guess we are already
on the Class six.
Right.
And let's just as usual, let's do a
quick recap on what did we learn?
What did we learn? Last class? This
time is going fast.
Years, guys, even six months.
We'll go very fast, I promise this.
But if we look on Saturdays, right?
And then we introduce our scanner,
and then let's class,
we start
looking into our logical operators.
Right.
Okay, good. So what can you tell me?
Why do we need those logical operators in
logical operators there?
That allows us to test
multiple conditions.
Right.
But multiple conditions in one statement.
Right. That allows us to.
To test it in one statement. Right.
Because no guess to test
multiple conditions
we have if else if blocks right.
Remember when we said
let's say when we are going to take
let's take a string, right.
When we talk in a string date right.
For example. Right.
Let's say we want to say Saturday, right.
And then we said based on the days,
we want to discuss
which topic we will be covering or which
which I don't
know, not topic which class you have.
Right. So let's say string
module, right.
I'll do it this way.
So then they're going to say,
hey if the they is equals, right?
And then we said, hey,
if the day is equals to Monday.
Right.
For example in the days equals to Monday
and then we'll do other things.
Now do I have another condition?
Just test. Yes,
I have another condition to test the test.
Multiple conditions
we have LC Right, we have else.
But now why do we need those
equals to we said Tuesday.
Right.
So that does this conditions
we do have ls e blocks right if else
if now we're saying in which case we need
the logical operators.
Right.
We choose, we will talk about having
and we will talk about having
or and we talked about not rights,
not this just reverse the condition
but then which gives you will use that
and then or whenever within one statement
we want to test multiple conditions.
Right.
Because right now within my E right
with my else if I'm just in one condition.
Hey, what if I want to test two
or more conditions
within the same statement,
within the same.
LC Right.
So then we are introducing our end or up
right?
Then we said, Hey, up in here guys,
it will be and or it will be.
Or you guys need to tell me a dad
equals to.
We said Wednesday right,
Wednesday, Wednesday.
And then you said module
we will specify a model equals
you guys were learning manual
just like manual
right.
So why should we go for all this?
Why should we go for
so the when the inoperative works, right?
So the way the interpreter works now
is this week 41.
So we set for that
and operator right for the end up ready
to give us a true.
This condition must be true
and this condition must be true right
So now when we look into this scenario,
when we look into this scenario,
we know that at one time,
right at one time,
the variable
they can hold only one value, right?
The variable they cannot hold Saturday,
Sunday, Monday, Tuesday.
Right. They can hold the only value.
So it means it's always your day.
It's always, always.
It was one condition.
It will be true, right?
But then if the one condition
will be true.
Right.
If this will be true
and if this will be false
using the end operator who will never,
ever will be able to get that true.
So in this scenario, that's what we would
we went to go ahead audit
or operator, Right.
Or operate right. But
when do we go for a logical operator
or for a logical end?
All in only one. We want to test
multiple two or more condition
in one state here in one statement,
if you have only one condition,
you don't need to have
any logical operations, right?
And you want your collaborators, right?
So this is was that or right?
This is was it or okay.
And let me actually ask that thing now.
You guys had a homework, right?
You guys had a homework.
So let me see which which
which logical operated
did you guys use the near
or can you guys send me the code?
Okay, look,
so this will be your quick recap.
Two days, of course.
Six. You
and that
was was was
like this
and needed to make it a little bit bigger.
Right. It's okay. Right.
So some of you guys
went into the capturing
some of
you went into the capturing string.
Some of you went into the capturing
integer value.
All correct.
This all correct. Yeah.
Let me see some of you.
You guys use equal
some or you use equal or not equal
some or you use equals ignore case,
which is very, very good.
And you see this confidence
right?
Right.
So this part we already know, right?
This part we already know that
we bring in the scanner
to capture the value
and to capture the value from our use.
Zero. Right.
Then we already decided, hey,
you know what?
I'm going to declare the variable
that I'm just declaring at this moment,
because I don't know
what will be the value that we will be
based on my condition.
Right then you saying, Hey,
I am test in multiple condition.
That's why I'm going for Eve else.
If else blocks right.
And here we're saying hey within one
eve right.
We didn't want eve statement right
we then here
I want to test three conditions right.
I want to say
hey in the month is equal to December
or month is equal to January
or month equals to February.
Right.
So what I'm doing, I'm
testing for those three conditions, Right.
And I'm saying, hey,
if at least one condition is true.
Right.
Because I'm using my all operator,
if at least one condition is true,
then I'm going to initialize this variable
to winter, Right?
If this block becomes true, right, then
my season will be spring in the summer
autumn.
And if none of the
conditions will be true, I am going to say
that this is invalid,
the right, this is invalid.
And then you send, Hey,
if your board in whichever season, right.
And of course you guys,
you guys should have tested with different
different conditions, right?
No, there should just
a different condition.
So in this situation you would go for or.
Right.
You would go for or
why would we go for or for example,
let's put a break in here.
So what is happening
with my.
Okay, what is enter your birth,
my right for example,
my birthday's in August, right?
Or there's in August.
So what is happening?
Our month is getting initialized
to August,
right?
Our season is still not initialized.
That's
why you don't see the value in here.
Right?
And then you're saying here
at one time, right,
that one time in here, what do we have?
And here what do we have right.
So, hey, is there
month equals to December?
Condition is false.
Month equals to generate condition
is false, month equals to February.
Condition is false. So we have pre false.
Obviously Jacqui's going to give us false.
Right then the same thing here and here
we will get false.
We will get false. We will get false.
And then our third option,
we will get a false for June.
We'll get a false for July,
and then we will go get a true for August.
Right.
So now for false
or false in here will give you false.
So then you have false or true
because we're using the OR operator right.
Then this will become true and then your
season will get insurance to start. Right?
Right.
You go,
Oh, now is your word in season
summer, right.
You would go one incident somewhere
like say we went over this last clause,
right.
Equals we'll just compare a string
letter, character
by character by character.
Right. So what is a equals ignore case?
What it does, it will compare to string,
but it will ignore any uppercase
or the lowercase.
Right.
So let me let me try to run the code
for this.
Guess please enter your birth. And what?
I'm just going to enter something.
So now it says you are born in season
invalid, right?
You were born. She's an invalid.
What if I want you say,
what if I want to see this message?
You guys,
I want you see this message only and only.
I want you to see this message only
and only when my season is actually
either winter
or spring or summer or autumn.
I don't want to print this statement. One.
My season is invalid
because it does not make sense.
If I'm going to say
you were born in season invalid,
what if I don't want to see any output
when my when my season is invalid?
I want you print only and only when this
season is winter, spring, summer out then.
But I don't want to print that message
when my season is invalid.
You wouldn't have to bother.
We don't have to call the LS.
Okay, that's fine.
But if we're not going to call, okay,
we can remove this.
Okay, let me see. I'm removing.
Fine, I'm removing.
But then why am I?
Why am I right now?
You guys know who is your friend in here?
Your compiler shows you the error, right?
Your compiler shows
you the error. Y compiler shows the error
not initialized.
Right?
Why? Why is it not initialized based?
Why do I have to initialize it?
It right.
Because what what compiler always checks
your code
compiler says okay, here
they declared a variable.
Here they're asking me to give the value
to print the value of that variable.
Right.
So when the Java runs the code,
Java needs to show some output.
However, in this scenario,
because there is no
LS block, we know that all the conditions
would be false, right?
All the condition could be false.
So then if all the conditions
could be false,
then who will take responsibility
of the season?
Right?
So now we're saying, hey, there won't be
ls block and there won't be ls block.
So now what we can do,
we can initialize our variable, right?
Or what we can do.
If you guys click in here,
compiler can help you out, right?
Compiler can help you out and compiler
can initialize a variable for you,
but the max things compiler can do,
Compiler can just
give initial value to the variable. Right?
And we set the initial value for integers.
What is the initial
value for the integers based
zero?
What about bullet?
Wollen is for boolean
is false grace, okay for boolean is false
and for strings and all other non
primitive types.
It will be no right. It will be not.
Okay. Sure.
But let me see what's going to happen now.
I'm going to please
enter your birth months, right?
I'm going to say whatever right now.
It says you were born in season
null is still shows me
I don't want you to see this output one
my one when the season is null.
I don't want to see whether
whenever we had an invalid,
I don't want to print it.
I want you print all I'm only
when the season is everything else.
But not this thing.
What if I will let this guess?
What if I'll add?
Because right now you guys know upgrades.
I want to say, Hey,
I want to print this statement
only in only
when my season is not equals to now.
What are you guys think
I want to add the if condition?
I want to say, hey, Eve, right?
I want to see if season right
my season is not equal to now.
What if I'm going to say that?
And then
right, right.
Or the way
we're going to add the LS book, right?
So what I'm saying not equal, right?
What I'm saying not equal
all and only one.
My season is not equal to null.
Then I'm going to see this statement right
then I'm going to see the statements.
So now what are we going to try to run
right?
When you're going to try to run,
lose, enter your first of months.
Right. So mental this.
So now we know the way the laddered
eve goes,
it goes line by line, private jets.
The first condition falls.
Whichever the second condition falls,
start condition falls
or condition falls,
none of the cases has emerged.
Now, what of
what is the value of this season?
The value of season still, no,
it's still No, because not
it did not go inside this.
If it did not go inside this,
if it did not go inside this house,
if it did not go here.
So our value was never
the value
of the variable was never changed.
Right. So no. Okay.
And then we go in here, Hey,
what is the value of season null?
Hey, I am going to print this message.
Only one no is not equals to no.
In this condition, condition will be false
and will not print in any statement.
Right.
If you want to add otherwise,
of course we can.
Either either was right
or when we had the ls black.
Remember guys, we had a ls black right?
LS black and inside the ls black.
You guys were defined in the season
as an invalid, right then equals invalid.
I think that's what
it was our original code.
Right.
So now if you go
and you have the ls black in
and now on the line 13.
If you're not going to do
any initialization right,
if you're not going to do any
initialization on the line 13,
your compiler is fine. Why?
Because compiler checks insists
okay, if none of the conditions there,
imagine a programmer.
So you initialize this variable
inside the ls.
So I'm good, right?
I said What do you mean?
Cannot leave it empty
where you want to leave it empty?
Which part, sport?
Well, if you want to live limit empty.
I would just suggest.
Then just don't have the support.
Can you just deuces out invalid? Yes.
You can do this out. Invalid.
Yep. So there we can just
you guys can just put whatever.
Right.
So we initialize in so this way compiler
is happy, but do we have to have it?
No, we don't have to have it.
Can we just have one C?
So please enter the valid.
Please enter valid.
Now let's season.
Yes, we can do that right?
We can do it.
Remember this else is very very optional
part, right?
So just based on your code,
you will see based on what kind of output
you want to have, you will see what
you would like to put right.
And then if the season is invalid,
if the season is invalid,
will this statement work with one work
now this one
to ignore, Right.
Because what will happen, Right.
And you could always try to run.
So now please
enter your first months right here.
Right.
So we know that my code will jump
right now into that else.
BLOCK Right.
So now what happens
this season will get initialized invalid.
Now we're saying hey, is invalid
not equal to now, right?
You're de not equal, right.
So your condition will go inside.
Then I will tell you,
you were born in invalid season, right?
Which we still
don't want to see. So now if
if you
guys want to keep invalid
now we just have to change this condition.
Right now.
We just have to change this condition.
And the way we said
we can have a node operator.
Right.
So I'm going to see if season equals
right, if season equals invalid, right.
And then what I can do, I can reverse it.
I can reverse it.
I'm going to say not right.
I'm going to say not.
So what will happen?
It's will check
is this season equals to invalid, right?
If this is an equals to invalid.
So then if the condition is true right,
then with the help of the not operator,
we're going to reverse it.
Right?
We're going to reverse it
and then it will give us false.
And then if it's false,
we cannot go inside.
Let's, let's, let's just.
You were born.
I was born in whatever.
What is the method of you?
Can you can you
can you specify a question?
What is the method of using.
So they are two different
operators, right?
They're two different operators, you say.
And in which case we can combine them.
Well, there will be
no remember one when you use in the
not right not operator,
you can use anywhere.
Right.
As long as you want to reverse
the condition. Right.
But the modulus right.
In order for you to use the modulus,
what is the module is right.
It shows you the reminder, right
Shows you the reminder.
So free for you to to to use the reminder,
you need to have two numbers right?
You need to have two numbers.
The way we use reminders, right?
The way the way we use reminder
before right when we said
one of you said, remember this one,
we had two numbers, right?
For example,
I'm not going to declare them one.
We said three, modulus two,
and then we said, not equals two zero.
Right?
Then we said not equal to zero
cannot be used in this scenario. Yes.
So what will happen?
It will check three mont two.
Right. Hey, is there any reminder? Yes.
Is there any reminder?
And then you you will check
if the reminder is not equals to zero.
Right?
Then we defining whether a number is
even or not.
Right.
So in this matter, yes, you can use.
But remember for the mod,
what do you need?
You need two numbers
because we perform in the arithmetic
operation, right?
Why are we using P
if we already did LS involved
when you
give me, are you asking about
why do we have this statement?
So my, my, my thing right,
I added extra thing right now
that was not a part of homework
but I added extra thing I wanted to say,
Hey, I want to see this statement.
I want to see this statement
all in only one.
My season is initialized properly, right?
When my season always winters
spring, summer or autumn.
Right.
If my if my season will be invalid,
I don't want to see any output.
Okay.
So I just.
I just added one more condition.
And with the help of this condition,
just trying to review the mod operator
as well.
So my still running my code
and so running. Right.
So now what is the month I had died.
Whatever. Right.
So some collection of characters
I entered.
So now with Jake
and we know that this will be false.
False, false.
Now my call because all the condition
of false will go inside that part.
Now, what will happen?
My season will get initialized, right?
My season will get initialized.
It will become invalid.
Now I'd throw another
if statement, throw another statements,
and now I'm saying, hey,
if this season right, what is this season?
Season has a value of invalid
Hey if invalid it
equals two invalid use
condition is true, right?
But then is the help of the not operator
what I'm doing,
I'm reversing my true condition
to the false right.
And we know that one condition is false.
I cannot enter inside. Right.
So now when we going to enter,
for example, December strike,
when we going to enter December?
I'm going to enter December.
Right.
My first eve statement. Right.
My first Eve block will become true.
Now, my season will get initialized
to winter, right?
As soon as Java finds a true condition.
Now it exists then that is ls blocks
right?
It exists them.
And now check.
Hey, is this season Right now
it's winter, right?
You get initialized to winter
because I entered December
Is winter equals to invalid?
Nope, they're not equal. Right.
So this statement
will give me a false right.
Then there is the help of the non
operator.
I'm converting false to the true.
Now when the condition
when boolean condition is true,
I am allowed to go inside. Right.
And then now I will have this
right.
Well this is just additional thing.
This for us to write
is just additional things for us to use.
Right now in here we look at our operators
and then here we're looking to our not
and I think this one
we did right
and this was very, very similar.
So what which upgrade did
you guys used in here?
It here we went for the and operate right.
So now we have to check that our score
right our score here
you test in one condition
you just more than 90 Right.
But then inside here and here
you have to condition to test.
Right.
So in here you saying that your score
should be more than 70 and
and at the same time
it should be less than 91.
Can we use equal signatures? Okay. So
we will be looking more guys into equals
ignore keys.
It will be based on the scenario. Right.
They will be based on the scenario.
But any time you work with this strings,
right?
Any time we work for the strings,
for example, that's when your
what automation testers do.
We will have to test applications. Right?
For example,
what if syntax is your application?
Right? Would have
syntax is your application.
So now in your you put a story
right in your user story,
what you will have to do,
you will have to test that one, two,
three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
Links are there. Right?
And you will have to text
test them to the link of the strings.
Right. You will have to test
the link of these strings.
So now testing the link.
Right. It's very sensitive.
It's very sensitive.
If you my user story,
it will say that all the links
has to be written in the uppercase here
you cannot use equals ignore keys.
You will have to check that
the link is written in the uppercase.
Right.
But for example. Right.
But for example, you want to click on
signing button, right?
Or you want to click on the enroll today,
right?
So now if you don't care
if you're not verifying the text right.
If you're not verifying the text,
but what you want to know,
you just want to see if the click
functionalities work and right
you want to see that
the click functionalities work
and that after you click,
it takes you here, right?
So then if you don't care about the text,
when we don't care about the text,
we can say, Hey, Eve,
if your button is equals,
ignore case enroll today, right?
You don't care if it's enrolled.
Do these written in uppercase lowercase.
But what you want to do,
you want to click right?
But usually when it comes
to these applications, guys will
when you will have to test
anything that you see on the application,
you guys, when it comes to testing,
you will have to verify
every single things, right?
You will have to verify
all this text in here.
You guys will have to verify.
So in this case, you cannot use equals
ignore keys. Why?
Because every every uppercase
and lowercase
and is important by, for example,
this application you will have to test
that it works in safari.
You will have to test
that it works in Chrome.
You will have to test that
B works on the Firefox.
Right?
So now whether we write Safari
uppercase or keys, we don't care, right?
So now we can say your browser is equals,
ignore safari,
then let me open this application
in Safari browser.
Right.
Because Safari upper keys are safari
lowercase.
Don't make a big difference,
but my links in here
I have to make sure
that I'm taking the case in.
Does it make sense this
okay?
I hope it makes sense,
but so once in your Java class
you guys will be looking into the stream.
You will get a look into more example.
But once we go
to the actual actual automation,
then it will start making more
and more and more sense.
Or for example, right?
Sometimes guys,
maybe, maybe right, maybe at your work
you will have to test
maybe your application
on the mobile devices, right?
So now, based on the values,
hey, if the if the applications,
if your scenario stays right,
if you use a user stories this
you have to test the mobile, right.
Whether you write mobile, uppercase,
mobile, lowercase don't matter.
It means that you have to do a mobile test
and then you will
your script will run
on the mobile application.
If it says web,
then you will run on the web application.
Right?
But this edge of things here,
we will just use equal.
We will just use equals
because here we cannot ignore the case.
And it's important that this is uppercase
and the rest of the letters
are written in the lower keys. It's
okay.
This.
So what you did in here, in here
you did your
and you did the
earlier I guess
and I know you guys shared again
we'll look into crazy
as we can look into this area.
Let me actually copy
and I'll just give one thing
right
or you're gonna let me switch
it was very quick right.
One of our main method
so this in the scanner, right.
And this scanner
and the
in here
and here.
What I see we're initialized.
We have a variables, right?
We list in our all the variables
within at all the variables
that we'll be using then our scanner.
Right.
And then once we capture our score,
mid grade
and final score, right,
we calculate in our average
and based on the average more we're doing,
we're defining the grade, right?
If this condition true, the grade is a
if this condition is true in which we test
in multiple conditions at the same time,
that's why we just incorporated.
Right.
And then outside what we have outside
have this one CS out
and saying a grade is whichever grade
it will be and your average.
Yeah, okay, that's fine.
We print in the average right.
So that's example of our.
And so my only suggestion of being
I copied from you
or I think from the right,
my only thing is write
code is correct, syntax is correct,
logic is correct.
Everything is
my only one suggestion in this code.
This will be
please make sure you follow the
follow the naming convention.
Right.
So it is.
It is it is it big mistake?
No, it's not a big mistake.
Code work perfectly are compiler.
No complaining because syntax is correct.
But this is that's why we learn
in those naming conventions.
Right.
So we say, hey,
when we work with the variables, right,
then we work with the variables.
All the variables should start with
the lowercase is not going to complain.
Java is going to execute perfectly. Right.
But your your variable
should start with the lower cases
and then follow the case right.
So that problem probably will be my
my mate so suggested but it's great
that would
I would name exploits or I would name
a mean great right
and I would name it
finals for right final score
and the error right And of course
all other things you will just have to
change in your core as well.
Right?
That's probably will be my thing.
This for this call, my suggestion
while it's okay it's exactly right.
So this will become more and more handy,
especially once you guys practice in more
and you guys are going to have another
almost three classes of Java.
So this will become very practical.
You all right?
This right.
So that was for our if else it's right
that was for our instances
and the see already
you guys are using practice that we learn
less class right so we say in here now
what we can do inside our whenever
condition becomes true right
so we inside might if block
right
this is we call block opening closed right
my E block has its own opening door
and it has its own closing door.
Right.
So this
condition becomes true,
then This is what I'm doing, right.
So what are we doing inside the block?
Based on the condition
I'm going to initialize my variable
for the value A or there will be a Well,
you'll see all that, right?
Instead of just doing this out.
That's what we're doing right? Right.
That's what we're doing.
Right. That
all right this
maybe that's 1050.
Okay.
Maybe I'll give you
guys a little of in there.
Look to.
All right.
So today, today, what are we going to days
then What are we going to look today?
The topic is our another conditional
statement that we're going to look Right.
And the thing you guys already started
looking at in the review.
Plus,
did you guys touch base a little bit?
The switch case in the review class
or not? You
this right.
So now what do we look
we look into our switch statement, right?
Each statement
which means which statement.
So now the switch statement
is being a part
of our conditional statements
and the channel statements.
Right.
So in conditional statements,
first we had the
if statement was its own variations.
Right?
We've this is contrary to what the state
and state the stance Right.
Statement with is
if as we said, can have different
it can has it can consist of just e block
it can consist of uf ls blocks.
It can consist of f else if blocks. Right.
So now the second conditional statement
that we're going to look, it's
a switch statement.
Which statement?
So very similar really
Is it our eve statement using switch.
What we will be doing?
We will be doing it selective execution.
We will be doing this select execution.
No only things.
Which statement has some similarities
with the if statement,
but of course
it will have its own differences.
It will has its own pros,
it will has its own limitations as well.
Right.
So now the best way
to look at our switch statement
this what are we going to bring?
I am going to bring the keyboard
from your class three.
Actually, I think this
woman
with rules.
Right.
I'm going to copy exact same quote.
I think it's called
and name
with my boss right now.
I need my main method.
Without my main method, it's
my code is not going to be wrong.
Think of this right now.
Looks easy for you. Right? This right now
looks easiest.
So what we have, we have a variable.
And right now. Right.
It will be just 6000 here,
but that's fine, right?
So we said, hey, whenever we have to test
multiple conditions, right?
When we test in multiple conditions,
where we what are we using in
Java we use an e elseif blocks, right.
If LC blocks and if we want to provide
the output, we can provide the block.
Right.
So another another a very,
very great alternative for our
if else if statement in Java
what we have
we have a switch case, right switch case.
It's another statement
that being
a part of the conditional statement,
the only thing switch statement works
slightly slightly different.
Right. Slightly different.
So now when we have our
if you work in some cases,
what do we do instead of there
right in FLC block
we can go a switch case.
We can go for a switch.
Now, the way our switch works,
right switch, it
starts with the switch right?
And we just see what switch, right?
You know that it's a keyboard. It's
why it's a highlighted, right?
So now as soon as you
Java will be executing one of your job,
Java executes, you could tap to the bottom
right as soon as you switch.
It knows what the switch means, right?
So now when we use it as switch statement,
right inside the switch,
we have to specify it inside a switch.
We will have to specify a variable. Right?
So now we're saying here for which
A, you be able
you are going to provide
multiple keys, right.
For which key for which switch.
You will be providing
multiple values. Right.
For which variable
we provide in multiple values.
This we're saying hey, if one variable day
this here, our date
can have the value of one hour.
They can be equal to two
or they can be equal to three.
Right?
So now we can say, hey, if they I'm
not going to define going to date,
you have exactly the same label.
So now switch date, right?
And then our switch
has its own block of goods.
How do we identify in general
block of good using early braces.
Right. Using curly braces.
Now this block of code will belong
to my switch statement.
Right.
This block of code belongs to do your ls
if block.
This block of code
belongs to your support.
Right.
This block of code belongs to the main
method.
This block belongs to my entire class.
Right.
So in here, the switch has its own
block of code, right?
Has its own block of code.
And inside this block of code,
what we have to provide.
We have to provide a values right?
So what could be the value
over day, Right?
So now you provide the values.
How do we provide the values
inside the switch block?
How do we provide the values?
We will be providing cases, right?
We'll be providing the cases.
And now we're going to read exact the same
example as we have is the eve parts.
Now we will be using
having the keys, right?
So now we can say here, case what
it was it
and now right.
We said in here case with this one
that's what we will go right.
So now we'll see how keys
right Each one right.
Hey Eve they will be equal
to one What we would like to do right?
And then we can if you want, guys,
we can go for a C, So for now,
that's fine.
They pay in the value of the
they could be equal to one.
That's technically what we say
when we say, hey, we'll say C.
So today's Monday, right?
Is there anything else we need this.
You need a break, right?
And of course that's
we will look what happens with break.
What happened with that break, Right.
Okay.
Now, do you have more cases in your day?
Do you have a do you want to provide
more cases for your variable?
D Yes, I want to provide more cases.
Right. Case.
You know, if the day is equal to two now,
we're going to say it's Tuesday,
right?
And then we need a break.
You have another, another, another value?
Yes, I have another value.
How do you provide any provide the helpful
help that's going to be Wednesday.
Right.
And then again, break.
Then we have games for right
or for Thursday.
And then the same thing.
You need a break, right?
You have another value.
Yes. You
they could have a value of five, right.
And then they will have the value of five.
Then you'll see it's Friday, right.
And then will be the break.
We have another value. Yes.
They could be equal to six. Right.
And the day equals 3 to 6.
I'm going to see that it's Saturday
and then that same thing, break.
Right. And then case seven. Right
seven.
It will be Sunday
and then the same thing again,
break right And then
there is similar as inside our E statement
we should use to send the cash.
I will go over the break.
So now we just following the correct
syntax of the switch, but we will go over
what happens if I'm going to have it,
What happens if I'm not going to have it?
Why do we need it?
What is the break? That's right.
So now when we don't have
any more values, right?
When we don't have any more conditions,
it is right inside the eve.
What do we provide?
We provide the else part. Right?
But for the else we said that else
is it's a very optional part.
So the same thing in our switch.
We can specify LS
but instead of the else
we have something called default
default.
Then I'm going to say won't be wrong.
So now default is very similar
to the else.
Basically we're saying,
hey, if the value of they won't 11b21b31
before.
If it won't be any of this now list,
then your code will come to the default.
Right.
And we can the break and I'll show you.
Do we have to or we don't have to right
there.
Now, what are we seeing in here?
Right. What we seen in here.
And if I'm going to run the code.
Right, if I'm going to run it.
So initially
I'm having exactly the same output.
I'm having the same output. Why?
Because in here I see
the value of day is 90, right?
The value of day is 90.
And that's what are we going over here?
That's what are we going
or first let me do the introduction
and then you guys will see in which case
you would want to go for a switch,
in which case you want to go for it.
Okay, so in here today is equal to 90.
All the condition is false. False.
Your code came into the
and that's why it's executed wrongly.
So now it works Exactly.
Same thing for a switch, right?
None of the cases would match
because the day was not equal,
was not equal to 1 to 3,
that they had the value of 90.
And then what happens?
Your code came to the default form, right?
So now let me change it.
This equals to I don't know why, Right.
Equals to five.
You know,
it works exactly the same way it works
except the same one.
So now what is then the difference, Right?
What is then the difference.
So now first, right, First
switch keys is a great alternative
for if else if statement.
Right so now in which case
you would want to go for else
if in which case
do you want to go for a switch keys
any time we have to check for the equality
because any time
we have to check for the equality,
for example, we say, hey,
if the day right,
what is the value of that?
Now, all of these one now
will be used to write
in this particular scenario.
We can go for a switch
and they'll give you
I'll give you more examples
because I'll give you more examples.
Okay, So now why then
in some cases
you would want to go for a switch.
Why in some cases
you would want to go for it else.
Right now, by looking at this code,
this can you tell me
I did exact this same.
I didn't deserve the same print out
statements.
Michael gives me exact the same out.
Now first, by looking this,
if I'm going to look at this code,
can you tell me, guys,
which code looks cleaner for you?
Which quote looks easier for you? Cleaner
switch or else if
a thing switch gears looks cleaner.
Right. Switch gears. Looks cleaner.
Now think of it.
If you would have to compare
the string this,
you would have to say
if these equals to money.
So it will become very windy.
And then on top of that,
you have all this curly braces
that identifies the block, right?
So just visually, just visually switch
case looks cleaner for me.
Right.
The switch case looks
clean it from second thing,
when it comes to this switch based.
Yes, switch
keys is also fast in this case,
which case is faster Now let's do
your guy is not going to see it.
Right?
You guys are not going to see
the because is going to run.
Right. Because Java runs very quickly.
Our code is very small
and now let me put a breakpoint.
This one, we put a break.
So now what we are going through there,
if else if statement, right.
So our variable B has a values
I by the way,
we said that our eve statement our
if eve ls eve blocks
it's a ladder
E right like one by one by one by one.
Your condition is going
and it has to be checked.
Right? So in here we're saying, hey,
if the they is equal to one right.
So what? Inside the eve, right?
What are we doing
is we're checking a condition, right?
We have to verify.
Hey, if did they is equal to one
if the days equals to one.
Right.
We always take in bullying condition.
True or false?
Hey, is that equal to one? Yes or no? No.
If it is equal to two, yes or no?
If that is equal to three, yes or no,
yes or no, if that is equal to five.
Right.
So the way the else eve what it does,
it goes one by one by one
by one and the checks
until it finds the matching condition.
Right.
And once it finds its exit. Why.
Because condition
because condition became true.
Right.
So now when it comes to this switch, right
when it comes to the switch,
we say switch statement.
It's a value based switch.
Statement is a value based.
So what do we look in to be looking
for the particular value of this variable?
Where do we specify the value,
the specified the value
in the matching cases,
matching cases for what?
Matching cases
for this particular variable.
So now let's look where you could go
right away.
So now it's on the line 27.
And now what is the value of the value
of these equals to five?
So what your code goes, your code goes
jumps right away to the matching case.
It does not have to go
in, check every single case. Why?
Because your day holds
this particular value.
And then he's saying, hey,
if the value of this one, it's
not taking the condition.
It goes by the value
value of date is equal to five.
Then what your code goes, you code goes
and jumps right away to the matching page.
It does not evaluate the condition.
It does not need to check for true
or false.
It knows its value
and they jumps right away to the match.
You guys register the right matching
and then it goes Friday
and then sees break and gets
it. So that's
why here we're saying a switch.
Which statement is it valid based
is it that would be
there would it?
Right.
And when we talk about Eve,
we know that Eve exists,
isn't
the either
condition based condition,
which means we have to check
for the condition, right?
True or false?
True or false.
Right.
True or
false.
So we can write code directly.
Yes, we can go.
But there will be some exception, right?
This is I'm just trying to show you
what can be done do.
Of course we don't have to go for it if
in the example in this case without else
if you guys let me finish all the examples
in here and then I'll show you.
Okay? I'll show you.
Okay.
All right.
So your statement is a conditional based,
right?
When we look at the
when we look at the context.
Right, we always say e right in here
we specify ruling condition.
We always march
to have a condition in there.
And then we have this particular thing
right then this is for our IT statement
works right the way this switch statement,
the syntax for this week
we have the variable right
in which we have for switch.
We specify the variable, right?
And then what do we do in case cases?
In using cases we provide values, right?
The only one in the value one is true.
Then we can have something else, right?
Or we'll be in here and then break right?
Or here's
another value that we choose, right?
And then the same thing.
We will have a code, right?
And then there will be some break. Right?
So what are we saying?
If statement is a condition based when we
when we look into the switch statements,
which statement is a value based?
Right.
It's a value based.
And now let's look again.
Let's look again.
What do we know what will happen?
Let's say
I'm going to enter invalidate, right?
I'm going to enter it.
Remember to take
away my statement right
The way my if statement
does, it goes in checks one by one,
by one by one.
It checks if it has to evaluate. Right.
It doesn't know right away
if the condition is true or false.
What it does, it values
hey is equals to six No right.
And it goes checks another condition.
It goes check
another condition. Condition.
None of the condition was true.
We went to the X by the way, this switch
works as switches that value base.
Right?
So where it goes,
it finds a matching value right away.
If it's not finding the match value,
it jumps right away to the default.
So you guys see
it did not have to go to the case.
One case to case P So that's why I guess
we are saying that this switch statement
is faster compared to the else if right.
But of course guys,
when we talk about faster, of course
we talk about the millimeter
linearly new seconds, right?
That comes up.
And that's two things we already see.
Right. Switch case code looks cleaner.
Right. Switch. Case is faster.
Right.
It's faster than our
if else, if our E always always checks
for the pooling condition,
our switch is a value based.
It knows the value and right away
jumps to the matching cases.
Right right away jumps to this match.
It engages it.
So now let's see why.
Why do we need a break in?
You really need a break.
We don't have to have a break, right?
So let me
remove all the breaks
and see what happens right.
Okay.
Now let me change the value of the day.
I'll change it to three.
Right.
Change it to three. So
that way our
the way it goes, we know, right?
True. Not true. No.
Once it finds a true right, once
it finds a true,
it executes and then your code gets out.
Right?
You code gets out out of the entire
if else if blocks right
whichever blocks you have,
it will get out from your statement.
Right.
As soon as it finds one true condition,
it gets out from your statement.
Right.
That's it's out.
It's not going to go in
check other conditions.
So now, when it comes to this switch,
right when it comes to this,
which we already know switches
a value based so it knows its value,
so it jumps right away to the matching
keys, right then jumps
right away to the matching keys.
So now will it funny. Yes it fine.
Will it execute it.
Yes, execute it executed Wednesday
But then what happens
because you could does not see a break.
Okay.
You could not see a break. So a break.
Key word.
What a break.
What does it tell us?
Get out.
Get out of my block.
What do we mean, get out of my block?
As soon as you find the matching keys.
Break, break block of court.
It means break hours.
Switch and get out.
Get out. Right.
So when you code,
when the Java does not see the break, guys
is just going to keep running,
running, run.
It is going to keep falling.
So now because there's no break,
there's nothing stopping Java code.
So your code will go.
Just jump into the cases, cases, cases
until it files to the last one,
which is default.
That's
why now you want to see the wrong date.
But what it did, guys, after Wednesday
because there was nothing
stop in your Java code.
It fell to the gates for it
all to the case five it's
also 6 to 7
and and then it came to the default.
Okay so that's why it's important guys
to use the break
inside your switch statement.
So what a break does.
Hey as soon as you find the matching keys,
as soon as you find the matching keys,
get out.
Get out. You are done, right? Get out.
So if there's no break,
your Java cannot get out
from where
it can get out from your switch, block
any group and continue
following full info.
So that's why it's very, very important,
guys, to use a break inside you,
which is okay.
Yes, we can have different data types.
Yes, we can have different types.
And first at which data to be looking.
It's our variable days of which data type.
The integer.
Right can work with other data types.
Yes, it can work.
But does it has a limitation?
Yes, of course it has a limitation.
Okay. There's no
we don't have to have the else.
If I just brought you else
if just to show you the differences.
There are similarities,
but there is our differences.
Okay. There is a differences.
And we want you to guys we want you do
more.
Switch statements the way
we are going to see
where you can add logical operators,
where you can unlock that.
Okay.
So at first, just understand right now
this switch case
is another conditional statement
which can be a great substitute
for the else.
If right.
With the help of switch,
we can make our code cleaner right
as switch keys is faster than the else
if right.
So switch keys is a valid base.
Right.
Or we provide it.
We provided a values value.
Value value to what?
To the variable.
How do we provide a values we providing
is the how help of the keyword case
right when we talk about else
if else if as a condition base,
we have to evaluate
if the condition is true,
then I'm going inside this block.
If this condition is true, then
I'm going inside this swap for a switch.
It's a value.
Your variable. No. Okay.
They okay, my value of the day is three,
but right away,
if it runs to the matching case.
Now inside your switch block
inside your switch work, right.
Whenever you're providing
the matching cases right after the code,
right after the code that we provide
for now we just see that.
But we can put some operation instance,
right?
We can put some operation.
Then what we will have to specify,
We have to specify a break.
Break?
You want what it does, It tells Java.
Hey, once you find the case,
once you find the matching case,
execute this statement.
And after you execute this statement,
please break.
Please get out.
Break my code, break my code.
Get out. Let's do.
Yes, we are coming.
We will come to the limitation.
We are coming to the limitation.
So let's look at all the good things
that our switch statement can do.
And then, of course,
we will see then why Java uses the switch.
Then why can we just have switch?
Why then do we need to else if are there
limitation, there is a limitation, right?
There's always this pros and cons
to all of the things right.
Right.
So we saw how that we need a break, right?
We saw that we need to break
in inside our switch statement
right inside our switch.
BLOCK What do you guys see?
You see default keyword, right?
Default keyword
as limit is
mentioned,
default is very similar to the else.
If right.
What is the default key?
What is the keyword before this is he
if the variable
they are not going to have a value of one.
Not going to have a value of two
and or three.
If none of the case,
then it will be matching.
Please come to the default, right?
Please come to the default.
And very similar as the URLs block
very similarly as the as default
is an optional.
Do you have to have it?
Look, you don't have to have it. You
did I do it in my
my extra
you are have to have it
no I don't have to have it
but it's very optional in case
you want to provide that otherwise.
Right. In case
we want to provide other ways.
Now when it comes to the default bits,
when it comes to the default
somewhere.
So all but the difference.
The difference of the default.
That's so now let me ask you,
this is the else part.
If I want to add.
Can I add my part anywhere or it
always has to be the last block
or it can be anywhere inside my if
so, when it comes
to our block,
always block has to be less right.
You cannot just take it out
and I don't know, put it somewhere,
put it somewhere in here.
You can't write your
your code will complain.
The code will complete.
Right. Compile.
Tell you what syntax is not correct.
So now
you can use only one and switch keys
and well because yet here you identify.
And hey, if this condition is true,
this is my eve block.
If the condition is true in here,
this is what belongs there.
The else eve block. Right.
If this code is correct,
it belongs to this part, right?
When it comes to switch, it's
only one open in one clause right now.
When you press the default this right else
block
ls BLOCK Oh, I did not know that.
LS BLOCK Always, always is.
The last block inside your eve statement,
right?
It's always
the last block inside your statement.
Now, when it comes to the default default,
guys can anywhere inside you switch case
default can be anywhere in the quality
for this first.
Yeah, no problem.
You can put defaults first.
Input in the middle.
Yes, you can put it in the middle. Right.
So now when it comes to the default,
it can be anywhere.
It can be sequence this or any sequence.
But of course,
because we do want to write a code
more logical, write more understandable.
Yes because it's a value based,
it does not have to test any condition.
Right.
If the days will be noteboom,
it knows that
not none of the keys to imagine
it will jump to the default right away.
Right? It will go to this.
It's a value based.
It knows the matching
value of the variable.
So if you think if a lot of the cases
will match, it knows where to jump.
Right?
So now,
because your default right
can be anywhere, your code
because it can be anywhere
inside your code,
if it can be anywhere,
then you guys can need to have a break
because if you are, they will equal.
For example,
if the they will have a value of eight.
Right.
If you
they will have the value of eight. Right.
They equals to all.
Then you could once
just enter this switch.
Right.
Once this enter this which you will go
right away to the default
and then of course
it will execute this statement.
Then your java will see
the break were in using the break.
It will help
Java to get from the switch block.
It will jump right away.
Outside,
you will jump right in without sex.
So no,
but of course, what we want to do right,
what we want to do, I probably would not
would default on very top, Right.
I would not put you for the very top
because we just want make
a nice and clear and logical.
Logical. Right.
You want to see hey, I want to see that
if none of the cases are not,
the cases will be matching,
then I want you have a default, right?
I always always prefer
to put on the bottom.
So now when your default is on the bottom
base,
your break is very optional
to be inside the default.
Okay. Exactly right.
So if you put a break in here,
if you put default as a last statement
the way it has the LS block, then you guys
don't need really any break right? Why?
Because when your days will be equal
to eight, right?
If your days will be equal to eight,
right, the equals to eight
your java while executing the code,
it knows
it will jump
right away to the default, right.
It will execute this statement.
And now what happens?
It will hit the end of this which block.
So by default it's even
it's right
it will it will exist in here. Why?
Because there is no more cases.
No, there there is no more other things.
So what we will do,
it will integrate, it will
exist.
And now when it comes to default, this
if your default is on the very bottom,
you don't have to have a break.
But because your default
can be anywhere inside your switch blog,
if it will be anywhere at the beginning
or in the middle, please
make sure you get yes.
So instead of the else we have default.
Exactly. Exactly.
Exactly.
All right.
That's that's one point
right there.
So we looked at the similarities. Right?
We look
hashing if your default
is a very last keyword
inside your switch block.
If the default is a last keyword inside
your switch, switch,
then you don't need a break.
But if your default right, think of this
Now, I'm going to add the default in here.
When you
add the
default and I'm not going to add a break
and now I'm going to put
the day is equal to ten.
What do this thing will be the output.
What is this thing
will be the output of my switch statement.
Can you just tell me
it's my switch difference
if my day will have the veil lifted.
First tell me how many outputs
and which outputs.
So. Right.
Of course it knows that
none of the cases are match,
so it will jump to the default right away.
It will execute the wrong day
and then happens
because there's no break.
What it will do, it will fall to the next
right, it will fall to the next case.
Then you guys will see Monday
it will execute Monday.
But then this is the break.
Break tells me, hey, get out,
get out. Right.
And then only lock the use and break
it will get out.
Right. So you're going to run
right?
Plan to run.
That's why
on my day, let me change it to tend to
right.
That's why I'm here.
You guys see, you will tell me wrong day
right from here.
It will tell me the wrong day.
It will go right away to the default.
But because default is on top of this.
Got a break.
That's why it will fall to the
break. Yes, Break. Very important.
This break tells exist my block of code.
They exist.
My block of block
and like we will be using this
in other blocks of code
so what a break always does
it just get out right Get out from where?
From this particular block of code.
That's what I
think.
But as I said, my preference, I would go
or before I went on the very bottom
only and only after I provide all my two
cases, I could basically
look all right.
And when I was teaching the last bad
guys, students found its similarity.
Right.
So this sets our if statement
because equal lather
if right it's
you will love letter by letter
verifying hey that these equals to one
then you have to step to the next one.
If it's two if it's three and they said
this which case is like your elevator.
Right.
It's like your elevator
it knows the value right away.
It knows to
which floor it means to go right away.
I need to go to the day number five. Boom.
We just write. It does not stop.
You're in here.
It goes to the matching case right away
and it exists.
It. So when there is a case, it's right.
When there is a cases where we have to
check for the equality case
in which
situations, which
case will be a perfect statement to use.
Right, perfect set
when we check for equality because.
Look, guys,
what do we check in here? Missing eight.
If the day is equal,
you would always say case one right?
Then if these two keys to write
any time we check for equality,
then what is the best statement?
Better or worse?
Which statement will be better to go for?
Why? Because code is cleaner.
Because code is faster. Right?
And it's also like it's very easy
to read, right?
It's very easy to read.
You know.
Hey, you're saying that
the value of the day is one day of the day
three, the value of the days four
and so on.
Well, in here,
every single condition has to be evaluated
right? Okay.
That's that's where we're going
to go over the limitation here.
Okay.
Can we do can we do the nesting as.
Yes, there's a crazy thing
then the crazy thing that we can do.
Okay. But we will go over the limitation.
Really the limitation.
Now let's look.
Well, actually, guys, let me leave
the current here.
We'll take a break after break,
we will look into different type
of variables, right?
Because right now what we did,
we had a variable of which type
we provide the variable of the integer
type in the next, in the next.
After the break, we will look what
if my variable is of the string type here?
What if my variable
is the character type? Right?
And then we will look into a limitation,
right?
There cannot be a perfect thing, right?
There is always
there is always a great things,
but those great things will have its own
constants.
Well, right.
And we will look what is
will be the limitation of my switches.
Okay.
All Hi, this 11 1130.
Let's take a break. Deal.
Let's take a break till
1145.
Right.
I'm going to leave you
the code of my switch statement right.
Right.
So another example of this.
We so we will take variable
right in the signature.
Right.
Let's take a char or specify gender.
Right. For example.
For example for now we know bringing
scalar for knowledge
is hardcoded in here, right.
For example. Right.
I don't know or whatever
regulatory system will go for this right.
So now what we want just say right
if there is m we can specify,
we can give a description.
If it's a male in the
is equal to EB, then the description
for the gender will be a female.
Otherwise we can say
otherwise we can
say, I don't know, unknown or disclosed.
Right. For example. Right.
So now what do we have?
We can we are saying
hey now based on the gender,
I want to say male or female
or I don't know
or unknown. Right.
So it means right.
I have some
I can specify based on my condition
I can specify a specific value
now before we knew only its statement.
Now we also know
what's with switch statement, right?
In this case, what are we chicken.
We will be checking for the equality.
Right.
Hey, if gender is equal to M or gender
is equal to F or gender equals
to something else.
Right. Based on that equality.
Right.
We will give a different different
outputs. Right.
So now when we check in
for the equality this, when we check in
for the equality, we can easily go for it.
Switch statement. Right.
So what we will do all this which
we will do switch right.
So which variable to which variable?
We will be providing different values
to each variable based
to gender, right to a gender.
And again there. Right.
And then opening switch. BLOCK. Right.
So now how do we values
how do we provide different values?
What do we need to use?
We need to use cases, right?
The only thing right nowadays
when we talk about the variable gender,
variable gender, if is of which type
is of the charge type, right?
So it means this particular variable
can have values
that specifies a characters, right?
So no matching values.
You will go into the cases.
But now how do we specify
a type of their values?
We specified them inside
a single quotation case.
M Right. Case.
M Hey, if they if the value right in
the value of the gender
is equal to M right.
And then we can have is
value of the gender
is what is equal to the right,
and then can we have otherwise
we will add the other ones.
But you guys see matching values
we specify with the help of cases, right?
But the values must be the same
as your variable,
your variable of the type.
So it means the values must be specified
as network of values.
Right. Is there.
And then we can either go for a C style,
but since we learn the new thing.
Right.
So let's add the I don't know description.
Right. This protection something like that
string description and in here
and description.
Right.
And recursion equals to, I don't know.
Male Right.
Mel And then we said, What do we need?
We need a break. We need a break.
So as soon as a gender finds
the matching keys, get out.
Right?
It's f description.
I don't know, equal to
female, right?
And then the same thing
breaks, right?
Then the same thing breaks in very
similarly as the if statement.
We can have the ls.
We don't have to have the right
but in this was good as would you.
Right so description.
I don't know. Something unknown right.
Logo for the unknown.
Right
outside.
Right. The same thing
outside of the switch.
Switch statement.
This the way we do outside of the in that
statement right now we can see all right
so I don't know unless we can print 50
then the last
and something like this
M was equals to M
means and then this
the description of
we between
what will happen right
this way, what will happen now to
when there is m
the variable description is not in.
It is not initialized yet right now
I would say yes,
which you just see switched in there.
Right.
What is the value that we hold inside?
M Right.
And I would say keys.
M So your code jumps right away.
Oh I do. I do.
You call that
you can just do the matching case, right?
So now description gets initialized.
Now the java is break, now it gets out
a lot of stuff
gets M in the right mix sandwich.
You need to press
right?
If we
can. There is s and we'll say we switch.
Right.
Switch to which variable to provide it.
A matching keys
is to the variable S right.
So how do you suppose to
find the matching keys
as you specify with the keyword keys?
And then you have to specify
the correct value, right?
Go female.
So now you will get initialized.
This means
so you know switchboard.
So now when it comes to the switch block,
remember this what we have to have right?
There are rules of our switch block there
also power switch.
BLOCK Okay.
Our matching cases, right?
Our matching
the right must be of
the same type as the variable, right?
So now our variable is of which
type of variable is of the charge type.
So it means every that
we use more of the charge type.
Right.
As soon as you going to enter. Right.
Was The difference between previous
M and current M was a difference
between this value.
This.
So now when you add a double course
you are,
then you find that it's a string right.
So that's why now who gives you errors
and E and now you come while it tells you
type mismatch it tells you cannot convert
from strength to charge.
So basically it's saying, hey,
you trying to give me a matching case
which is mentioned valley
which is string type of value and.
Now you want me to fold the string
inside this char, Right.
I'm sorry, that's mismatch.
I cannot convert. Right.
So that's why there are rules in here that
rules in here that
your matched value
must be of the same type as a variable.
Right
here.
What we see right is when we save
for our switch, right?
The state rules in write the rules
and then you'll go exception
in which cases we can use, which means
values in
this class B Right.
My must be same data type,
native type.
Is it
variable
local?
So values increases, right values.
In this case, as I do for my value family,
which
must be the same
type, is the variable inside this switch.
Right inside the switch.
Now let me try to add another key case.
Let me try to add another case
and I'm going to say Keystone.
Right?
So what if by mistake?
Right by a mistake?
I don't know.
I'll just add one right.
So what if by mistake what I did,
I provide f to matching cases.
I provided to matching cases.
So your compiler will complain and
it will tell you, okay, duplicate cases.
It means duplicate values, right?
So your compiler prevents you
now prevents
you of having too much in cases. Why?
Because remember this
a program cannot make a decision
all by self write it program runs
a code that you as a programmer
have the rule, right?
So now your Java write
your general one editor and the code
says, okay, gender
right here, for example, will be lower.
And right now, once
your Java goes inside this,
which look right now,
it will see too much in cases.
Now Java cannot make a decision, General.
See? Okay, I have too much in cases.
Then which one you the geometry editor
this or you want me to execute this?
Right.
So in programing
is he trying to prevent the things right?
We're not allowed to have the things
where code has to decide on its own. No.
Right.
And because that's why compiler
will give you the issue in here, right.
You give you the issue in here
of a duplicate cases
and we cannot have duplicate cases.
They go right. Why?
Because one variable can have only one
valid, one value.
We provide only one matching piece.
Right. Don't have this with you.
Right.
We can all have duplicate keys. One
white
one has to
know.
Right?
While looking at this code.
This what if you want to
then remember guys, when we lower m
an upper atmosphere and lower
and then up in there is
if you want to add the another case
in which you want to specify the upper
M, Yes, you can do it.
Yes you can do because more.
M An upper arms are two,
two completely different things, right?
Two different things.
So if you will go for the lower M,
it will go into that particular
matching case, right?
With the lower M it will go to that
particular matching case, right?
Will go that particular matching case.
If it's that upper arm, it will go to that
particular matching case right there.
They know the same and know the same
so Java can distinguish between lower
in the upper E,
in which case can we ignore the cases.
That's
actually a good point, is a good point.
But we will ignore the cases
only when it comes to strings,
but only when it comes to the string.
So now we cannot just put ignore
cases in here.
We cannot put ignore cases in here
because there's a different
things that are run behind our char.
Okay, So in our Tara thing,
as Gary explained to you, guess
how our char
works.
Our char works
based on them at the table, right?
So now every single character
has that associated with the specific
numeric value,
like numeric value for M is equal
to, I don't know, 183 or something
like that based on the ASCII table.
Right. Or 65. Right.
So in here we cannot do ignore the case,
but what we can do,
ignoring the case, is
we can do it when we do is the strings.
With the strings is we can do different
manipulation, we can ignore the cases,
we can convert the strings to the lower
keys, to the upper keys.
We can cut the strings.
We can cut strings in half.
We can
we can eliminate some parts of the string.
We can do many, many different things,
but not with the task.
Okay,
so now
now, let me ask you this.
Let me ask your default default statement.
Is it a default keyword?
Is it optional or it must.
It's an optional right
the way out else BLOCK It's very optional.
And, you know,
we're going to come back to your question.
So now I'm wondering of my default,
when you remove my defaults, what happens?
Why am I compilers not happy?
Why am I compiler on the line?
Three gives me the erroneous.
So now they go right.
So make sure you always understand
guys what happens, right?
Make sure no quotation is perfectly fine,
proficient is perfectly fine.
Always understand that things way right.
So now if you're going to hover over
a compile, it gives you a hint, right?
Because of this ID is right.
We are able to get a hint.
Compile is not happy.
What is what could be the issue?
It says a variable might not be initial.
Let's write it.
Variable might not be initialized.
Exactly this same logic as we had inside
the ls blogger's exact
the same logic right?
It says Hey, they ask, they will be asked.
They will want to make java
to print some value of the description.
Right.
So now are they
initializing it in here? No.
What are we doing in the line 14?
We just declare it right now.
Okay, then they have a switch block right
inside.
The switch block.
They initializing the variable
to this value.
If this case will be matching
or this case will be matching
or this case will be matching, hey, what
if none of the cases will be matching?
Who is going to initialize the variable?
Nobody going to initialize the variable.
Then if nobody is going to initialize
this variable, if my switch case will be
if my switch is not going to find
any matching cases,
then nobody's taking responsibility
of initializing this variable.
Right?
If there is not initialize,
then how can they ask me to print
that Look, print
something that doesn't exist.
Right?
Java by itself cannot add anything
during execution of the program.
Right. So exactly the same thing is.
So if going to use the default,
then make sure you initialize the variable
or if you guys going to have it inside
the label,
then your compiler is
fine except the same logic.
You only put no in here.
Yes, if you not going to have your default
right.
For example,
if you don't want to have a default, then
you can just have no in here.
If no one here, then it will be fine.
Right?
Or you can just in this situation,
we just decided to have this.
Okay,
so let's see if I'm going to change to
I don't know, to each thing right now.
It says each each means unknown, right?
Each thing.
So this is two things goes right.
This is two things when it comes to rules,
write your things when it comes to these
values and cases
might be the thing that I type, right?
How do we provide the values?
We provide the values after the keyword
case, right after the keyword keys.
And then we cannot duplicate cases.
There is
what which part
you do not understand.
If I show
you have a you have a husband
that is already working, right?
So maybe you already have we're ready.
When I deleted default, right
When I deleted a default.
Right. So
people right so what happens remember
right at the current case
when our gender is equal
to age right here, my switch block starts.
My switch.
Look, it's right.
So you're saying, hey, you, let's
check the value for gender right now
because it's age.
This case, one match.
This is one match. In this case,
one match.
So you switch, work one year,
execute it at all.
Right.
Your switch, case one ID be executed all.
So if you switch games
won't be executed at all.
And then on the line three, we tried
to print the value of the description.
Now your compiler says, Hey, how can I
print the value of the description?
And if here you have the empty variable
and you switch keys, if your speech keys
won't be able to get executed
what is the value trying to print?
What is the value we try to print?
Okay, so that's why it's asked you
for initialization, right?
And if you're going to take the help
of the compiler, compiler
will help you to just initialize it,
you know?
Okay.
But if you want to add the default,
if you're going to add the default,
well, you're going to add an evil.
Then compiler says, okay,
if none of the cases are matching
your code,
hundred percent will go to default.
So it will be
be fine.
All right.
So this is the rules, right?
This is the rules.
Now, let's take a look at the limitation.
Right.
Let's take a look at the limitation.
Limitation. Right.
So for example, in here, right in here.
Right.
I am looking into the keys.
I want say, hey,
the case is lower M
or if the case is upper M Right.
So my description is male, right?
Hey, if I want to use right,
what if I want to use a logical operator,
I want to say, hey, keys am Oh, keys.
M Right, keys and or keys upper.
M Then I want to say it's male, right?
Because I want to do it this way.
Probably would be better.
So now you are using this place or right?
Can I use it this way now?
A limitation.
This switch case
was the motivation of the switch case.
We cannot
use a logical operators near.
We cannot use logical operators, right.
We cannot see keys
m lower end or the upper end.
The only thing What is your switch case
does this it checks for the equality
E checks Hey is the case equals to M
Is the case equal to the upper arm?
Is the case equals to F or. I don't know.
We can add another case where the case
equal to the bigger F right.
So now inside you switch statement
we can not use a new logical operator.
So if you have to test two
or more conditions, right.
If you want to test but
you get C once again conditions, right?
Any time we talk about conditions,
we talk about the if statement, right?
When we talk about the switch
because we strictly strictly
check in the equality,
we check in for the value we stand here.
If the value of gender is m
or M or lower F or upper right.
So within a within this which keys
we are not checking
this condition is true
or another condition is true.
So the limitation on
this switch keys we have that
yes, it's
strictly strictly looks for the equality.
It does not checks in that
you don't have to check the condition,
but you basically saying,
hey, gender could be equal to M,
gender could be equal to M, upper
lower F or upper s.
It checks for the equality right.
So a limitation of this week
limitation on the switch.
The first one
we cannot use
logical
logical operators.
We cannot develop either
this or that economic
thing.
Another thing limit is less clause.
Of course we did an exercise
class, we did the exercise.
So if I can find
this exercise right, this exercise
now, in this exercise, what we did right,
what we were trying to capture a day,
right when, we try to capture D then
we were defining whether it's a weekday
or whether it's a week, Right.
So in here, what we use in
we are using besides logical operator,
what are we were also using?
We were using a relational operator,
right?
We say, Hey, if there would be more than
one or weekdays less than five, right.
Or more than six or less than seven.
Now, if you couldn't hear this,
I can not see here
if they is more or equal, this one,
I cannot say if they or more is equal
to one right or less or equal.
So now it says that
we get the error right.
There is a syntax error that we have.
So inside a switch
keys,
you cannot use any relational operator,
you cannot use any logical operator,
Right.
What this which case simply looks hey, is
the value of de is one
is the value of these two.
It cannot say hey, is the value is
the value of these more than one?
Yes or no.
If the value is less than one, yes
or no one because it's strictly strictly
looks for the value, it checks in that
It checks for the equality.
Okay. It
cannot go, will come.
How to overcome those things.
We will come how to overcome those things.
And so once again, this is in here, right?
Limitation, no logical apparatus
we cannot use.
We cannot relational operation.
Right.
For example.
Now when you think of this
scenario, right, when we have variables,
when we have variables to compare, right.
If either
if the number one is more than number two
or number two is more than number
one, or number three
is equals to
or number one is equal to number two.
Right?
So now in this particular scenario,
we can model for this which case, why?
Because in those particular scenarios,
what we will be doing,
we will be checking their relationship.
Right.
We need to identify number
one is more than the number two, Right.
So switch keys can not be used
in that particular case.
In that cases you will have to go for
is else e statement
y because you will have to
do the comparison
if number one is more than number two,
you will have to check
if the condition is true
or if commission is false.
Can. All right.
Those two operators cannot be used.
This two operators,
if you will, have to involve them
in your exercise, in your task guys,
then definitely just go for it.
If if else you speak
like if else these statements
only known when you have to check
for the equality right here.
What do we check in the chicken.
Hey keys value of these one keys
value of these two
key style of these three keys
value of these four keys.
Value of gender is m gives
value of gender is
upper and lower F upper right.
What do we check in the check inequality.
We cannot say keys
F is more than smaller s
a keys f bigger F or lower.
So that's a limitation that is in there.
Are there more limitation
inside our switch?
Yes, there's more limitation
is that our switch keeps
the minimal when it comes to yes.
Only when we check for equality.
Keys are browser.
Right. Keys browser is Microsoft Edge.
Then the execute script on Microsoft
edge case browser is Safari will.
Execute the code on safari right keys
browser is Chrome.
We execute it on the chrome. Right.
Exact same scenario could be done.
Each statement exact the same scenario
could be done using switch.
Right.
But here
because we simply checking for equality
if browser is chrome execute core here.
Your browser is a safari executive here.
When we check for equality, I
probably would prefer to go for a switch.
Right?
Because switch gives me a cleaner code
which will give me a faster execution.
A switch will give me a better
readability of the also
means
you will switch cases.
Yes, that's the right statement.
So any any switch statements,
we can easily convert them to the E
but not every single eve.
We can convert to the switch.
Yep. Why? Because switch hasn't.
Switch has a limitation.
Okay, so now what other limitation? Right.
So now also besides
having the different operator besides that
Alex, we will go is the scanner
besides having limitation in operators?
Guys,
we have a also limitation of data types.
We have a limitation of data types.
When it comes to the e mails,
we can use any data type, right?
We can use it. They need their time.
But when it comes to this switch base,
which cannot work with every single data
type in Java,
okay, cannot work
the single that it objects.
And this is a thing
like logical explanation to that.
Okay. So for example, right.
So we saw that our switch case
work with what type of data type is
is this one, two, three kind of data type
integer.
Right.
We see that switch gives easily
works as integer.
We see that switch case
easily works with the task.
But now, for example, right.
What if I'm going to have a
boolean rule in?
I don't know.
All right. Right now
boolean how many conditions
your boolean can have this
How many can the
how many values you boolean can only
two values either true or either false.
Right?
So basically, there's not
many cases that you can provide, right?
It's either true or either right.
So there's not
enough cases to work with the boolean.
So if you want to try to put a ball
in, right, if you want to try
to put a bowling inside your sweet flag,
you Java will complete it.
This switch cannot be used boolean
not enough cases. Why?
Because either true it either
false. That's it.
There's nothing else. Right.
So if it's if it's only do
then just go for it.
You state.
Okay so bowling conditions cannot be
used inside our switch statements.
Okay you find it switch. So limitation of
all operators.
Right.
And here I'll put limitation of data types
limitation of data types.
So cannot be cannot use
use bowling
ball use bowling.
They're not valid variables.
We cannot use just cannot be used
with bowling to not use boolean.
Right.
What because a limitation
of different cases.
Right.
It's been boolean
has only two now another thing, right.
Another data type that we have for example
double
D equals 1.9.
Right.
So now if I'm going to try
to put a D in here,
my switch case is also going to complete.
Right. Is also going to complain.
Now, when you think of double this,
when you think of the double,
there is a way too many variations
available.
Too many can be 1.9 can be 10.9,
it can be 10.90.
Anyways, there's a way too many variations
that you can think of.
So yeah, I say so.
You know what?
Don't go for double inside this.
Which cases go in does not allow us
to have a double inside a switch.
That's too many variation
in that
we used.
We double
double
can be used with double and it's
and is the same thing for double inflow
and it's the same thing
when you go for a double of slot.
And it's also cannot be used with the long
think and will be still
be used
for the same thing
Too many variations in there
it variations in there
so char integer
and beside before the integer we have
ruby can be by the can be, it can be.
But what kinds of was the next part of the
but sure they go goes like my mind
okay by short integer
easily can be used right?
So no double no load chart,
no problem of the char,
no boolean but it can be
easily used in this piece.
Right? These the string.
They can be easily
easily used in these and so
by short integer char strings.
No problem.
Is this right up to now.
Let's see now.
We can combine this now we can combine.
Let's combine our strains. Right?
Let's combine
our being in the scanner and the switch.
And then you guys want to do that.
You are then switch
them off.
Structure will give
you this assignment problem.
Oh, what?
I want to do this. What I want to do.
That's my favorite exercise,
but I'll leave it to you to do that.
So this is my task for you. This.
So what I want to do,
I want to capture enough.
I want.
We need to capture it.
And it country
only user.
Right.
And then based on the country,
we have to define
their a favorite food.
Favorite food from that country.
Favorite food or traditional food,
whatever you want to add, for example.
Right.
So now you have to think, okay,
I want to capture a country, right?
It means I need to capture it.
I need to use a scanner. Right.
And you choose a scanner.
I will be capturing country. Right.
So now, while once I capture the country,
then based on the condition or based
on the value, whichever way you decide.
But since we use in the speech,
I would say based on the value of
the country, I want you to tell me
the favorite food, for example.
Right?
If country is United States,
you will initialize the favorite food
for burgers, right?
If the country is
entirely your
favorite food will be possibly
the country is
Turkey, Pakistan, Kazakhstan.
Whichever country will decide
provide the case.
Then I want you to define
the favorite food.
Okay.
So now you will get have to think too
which variable
you will be provided
in matching cases and right.
And and what can we do?
Which variable you will be providing?
Imagine cases and how you will be
providing those matching cookies.
Okay.
So now you see you combining your
are you combining
your scanner in, your switch as well.
Okay.
So can you guys do it?
I guess you are you guys can do a new
at least four or five cases
do it at least four or five cases
this way you guys just do it.
Practice in typing. You
are giving us 5 minutes to do it.
All right
now, like
I could give you
a couple of minutes to finish.
We will look into it some stuff
and then in this will be doing
more tasks.
All right. This one.
So let's look right.
It was only one which I did this.
This.
Okay, I copy someone else
code guys.
All right. Okay.
So in here, right
First we already know first lines.
Were we doing we creating this scanner
to capture the food, to capture,
to capture the country
we capture in the country, using next.
Right.
And then storing inside
that string variable.
So now our variable is count is of
which type of the string type, right.
So now for a country,
what we tried to provide right now
is in here the country can have different
values, right?
The country can have different values.
And whichever matching cases us
for before.
Right.
So now, because our variable country
is of this string type, so matching values
also must be of the
the same data type, right?
How do we provide the match analysis?
Provide the match analysis,
the help of cases.
Right.
And then of course,
you guys should should test it.
Right.
And then you guys should test this.
And now we can say, okay, please.
And they country right
So let's say you would see right they go
if your
country is you
say your favorite food is a burger right.
You'll Your favorite for is a burger.
That's good.
This one worked, right? So
and politically
here, let me try to debug
Please enter the country.
Let me try Mexico right.
So now. Right.
What is the country? Is Mexico.
So now your switch case knows
the value of the variable.
What it does,
it jumps right away to the matching case.
Right? It jumps to the matching piece.
Now, the variable food before you
initialize it to the null value.
Now no will be taken out from that box.
And now what are we going to do?
We're going to replace it
with this, right?
We're going to replace it.
We stuck with the No.
One output.
If your country is Mexico,
your theory for this Texas. Okay.
That's right.
So this we should understand, right,
this rule and, this bag.
So this our switch statement
matching cases and we need a break.
Right.
So all this is back.
Now, let's look at a few variations
in here.
Let's look at the few little things
in here that you want to
that we want to fix.
Right.
So I want you to see
when none of the cases are matching.
I want you see
And then let's see what happens
when none of the cases
are matching. Right.
For example. Right.
So please enter the country, let's say,
I don't know, zero.
Right.
So since we did not provide the matching
cases,
you will go to the default bar by default.
We'll go to the default path.
Now it says
it says, right, please enter the country.
Right.
So now it's this pure rule.
It food.
Try another country.
If your country is Peru,
your favorite food is try another country.
Okay, that's fine. Right?
But we can add the same, right?
We can add the same thing.
We can we can have this statement, right?
We can have the statement.
Well, we can do a little fixing, right?
We can. Why Peru?
Because none of the cases
have matched, right?
None of the cases have matched
the same thing.
What? We can add this, right?
We can what we can do.
We can say full right if you wanted it.
So if we don't want to have a default,
we don't have to have it.
It's optional, right? Try another food.
I we could fix a little bit.
The statement actually thought there's
something else as written, but it's fine.
It's fine. Okay, that's fine.
If you're if your country is Peru,
let's do it this way.
I guess
if we were not
able to
define if favorite food, let's do this.
If we are not able to define the favorite
food, let just not print any statement.
How can we do it.
We did it already before.
If we don't know the favorite food,
let's not have the output.
Or we can say right
eve none of the cases are match.
Then we will say try another country,
something like that.
Let's let's have only one output in here.
We want to have a
we want to have a print out
only and the only one
we know the favorite food
in at statement. Right.
We can even if what
if we can at our not operate.
Right.
So let me put
maybe let me put unknown in here.
Right. I'll just put unknown.
Well now I can see if food is equals.
Right. It equals to unknown means
or not.
Right.
And then deterministic doesn't have like
if before equals to unknown
and then we'll say not, not only then
I want to print this statement
and then I want to
label.
Only then I want to print the statement.
Otherwise we can that otherwise.
Otherwise, let's add that statement.
Please try another country. Right?
We try another country.
Oh, try another.
Okay.
We probably it's more
it's more defined output right now.
We're going to try
please enter the country zero.
We go. Please try another country. Right.
So this way, when we entered Peru
because it did not find
any matching cases,
you went to the default.
Now we say, hey,
I want to see this statement.
All we know only if food is not equals
to unknown, right?
If the food is not equal to or not,
then that's why it went to the export.
Then it goes to the best. Yep.
And now another little thing that we want
to watch that we want to do, right?
What is going into the country?
Let's try to e prints right now.
What I did, what I did
I went through with the lowercase, right.
I entered with the locals.
So now. Right.
What is the value of the country?
The value of the country is Ukraine.
All our keys.
So now
where do you guys think my code will jump?
And now what happens?
My code will jump
right away to the default, right?
It jumps right away to the default. Why?
Because remember, inside this string is
everything is matter, right?
So now the value inside
this string was a lowercase Ukraine.
In here it was lowercase.
Now, what do we do when we provide
the matching cases
we provide with the first operator?
Right? He is all uppercase.
He is one up or later.
He's all uppercase. Right?
So that's why the string was not match.
You went to the default, that's why.
And what are we going to get?
We going to get that food
is unknown right now.
And this condition
was false.
So now that's why we get in poison
in other countries.
So now instead of saying
instead of seeing the output for
for this now we write for Bush, now
we seen please try another punch, right?
Please try and
so now
how do we deal with this situations?
Right.
So now basically in this piece,
what are we trying to do we trying to do?
Ignoring, right.
We trying to do it wrong, ignoring.
We want to say, hey, weather and Ukraine
all all crops or all our crops
or whichever way it's exactly the same
right Ukraine in the lower case
that case, it's exactly the same thing.
Right. So now how can I ignore the cases?
Now what we can do is I can,
let's say in here,
country equals or equals ignore case
Y, because for the equals
you have to provide
another valley,
you have to provide another value.
Now you say, Hey, if the country is equal
to what you have to say,
the country is equal to, I don't know,
let's say lowercase Ukraine. So
Ukraine.
So now you compile it with complain
right then right away you guys start
thinking logically, not because now
why am I compilers complete Now,
when you say country is equal to Ukraine,
what kind of value will be getting this?
What kind of value
will be getting country equals to Ukraine
e taken For that equality?
No. What is the expression
will be inside my inside
my this parentheses, I'm saying,
hey, if the country let's say Ukraine now
entered lowercase equals to Ukraine,
what are what what will be the value
you will be error
bowling type of value right in here.
If I'm going to enter, think
what if I'm running the code?
My code is supposed right now in here,
I'm going to enter
Ukraine in here, right inside the country.
Now I'm saying,
hey, is Ukraine equals to Ukraine?
What is the expression
it will give me it will give me a true
value is true is of which time
valid, true is of the ball in type key.
And my switch statement work
is the boiling days.
No, my switch statement
can no work with the boiling.
Right. So now what?
We need to do this and this is one
be accurate you all you check in for one.
So first we'll give you a boolean.
Second,
you just check in only for one thing.
So now how do you deal with this thing?
So now any time you work
with string and then,
which I already mentioned it many times,
because we will have a
to detail classes about different things
that we can do with a string.
But there's a two options
we can I in one option.
So there's an option is string.
What we have goes in option to string.
We can have a
something that call to lower case.
Okay, we can either convert our variable
to the lower keys
or we can convert our variable
to the uppercase
B, So on to
which case we going to convert.
Right?
Or we can go to that uppercase.
So whichever one you decide, Right?
So let's see
if I'm going to change my string, Right.
For example. Right.
If I'm going to enter
Ukrainian like this, right is the big
you choose and now what will happen?
This variable will be stored inside
this near this, this value can be stored
inside this variable.
So now what I'm doing I'm taking the
Ukrainian that was was first uppercase.
Right.
And then
I am saying
hey convert this to the lowercase.
So now what Java will do is convert
the everything to the lowercase.
Right.
It will convert everything
to the lowercase.
So now if your variable is converted
to the lowercase guys,
because everything is inside,
the string is matter what you have to do,
then all your cases, you have to provide
with the law cases, everything.
Then you will have to specify
with the lowercase
y because at first, before
what in your switch
what your jabber will do.
It will take your country,
it will convert it to the lowercase.
Right.
Then all your countries
should be specified with the lowercase
or similarly e
if instead of to the lowercase you going
use it to uppercase. Right?
It means it will convert your country
all to the uppercase is right.
So now from the Ukrainian
that you enter it.
So now it will convert.
If you're going to say to uppercase,
it will make all caps.
You make all caps, right?
You will make all caps in here.
And then if it makes your variable
to the all caps, then
all matching cases must be in all caps
and then all matching cases.
So now, instead of having Mexico
like this,
you will have to specify a keys
all in the upper keys.
In all, in the upper Keys.
Well, in here, guys, while we capture.
No, we cannot.
Just if you want to
it just using the ignite is
then you guys will have to go for it.
If if if statement can.
No, there's no way this is their way.
Let me see if it starts.
There is a
we need to look at different different.
Let me see if that starts with.
I know that we have begin and preface.
I don't think as we can define
whether it starts with the uppercase
or we start with the lowercase
foreign. Yes.
So this way you guys, as I mentioned to
you guys have to select
you want to convert
to the lower case of the operative.
So if you can, we're going
to convert everything to working.
Make sure all your countries are specified
using the all matching cases
as specified in the Lord Jesus.
I'm just going to more use. All right.
If you're going to convert
to the uppercase,
then everything has to be uppercase
in here, right?
Because what's going to happen,
even if I'm going to entry U.S., right?
So I'm entering you all in the
caps, right?
Then I'm saying inside my switch, take
my variable, convert it to the lowercase.
So now from the big U.S.,
I'm going to get a small U.S.
in all our cases.
And then only only once I converted,
then I'm going inside my switch plug
and then what I will
look I will look for a matching piece,
right?
Converting to the lowercase
or or matching cases must be the largest
if convert into the uppercase
all matching cases
must be promoted to the uppercase.
Does not mean that it's
that it's more useful or not.
Okay.
In some certain operations,
maybe we will have to convert
to the lowercase in some operations
we will have to convert to that
key will be based on this scenario,
but it does not mean that is one
is more useful than other
or I'm still running.
All right.
Now, if I enter U.S., your countries,
you see, if I read, what is it?
Right?
If we enter invalid country. Right.
So please enter the country Right.
So what we were going to write.
So whenever I'm going to enter,
let's see what happens in the right number
this quarter executes
always steps to the bottom.
Right now you could see switch it.
No, it's okay.
When I see a switch,
I have to check for the value, right?
I have to check for the value of this
particular variable that I specify.
Right.
So now I enter this rule using
the first letter is uppercase.
Right?
So first, always analyze
what happens right?
Then I'm taking this rule
right of the rule, right.
And then your case right code
executes left to the right.
It's going to convert it to small firm,
all caps, AP converts.
Then our switch statement starts. Right?
Our switch book starts.
Now you will know, Hey,
there's none of the matching cases, right?
None of the matching cases.
So your code will jump to the default.
Now you will be canceled.
Your full becomes unknown. Right?
So now you initialize your variable
to on then.
Now your java once
it's executed default,
it exists from your switch statement.
Now you want to continue now
while continuing execution.
It sees another statement right now
it says if statement
now it knows okay when I work is
it is statement.
I have to check for the condition
right now it says hey is full equals
to unknown because your value was unknown.
Now we check
and here is the non equals to unknown.
Yes, condition is true, but that condition
will be evaluated right?
So unknown is equal
to a known condition will be true.
Then use not operator we converting so
now our truth will be converted
to the false.
When the condition is false,
you cannot enter the eve block.
You will jump the L's block and that's
what you're going to get pushed right?
Another country. I
even if there's a space.
Yes, even if there's a space,
but there's a that we can any time
you guys work with this tree,
we can do a lot of things with this train.
We can we can trim the strings,
we can reduce spaces,
we can connect strings,
We can take out some pieces, the strings.
There's a many, many things
we can do in once long as you can easily,
we'll be able to fix
any other case of this.
In there you can
switch statement.
All it does
is it checks for the equality. Okay?
If if, if the value of this variable
is Ukrainian,
then I'll go there, evaluate
the variable will be Eataly.
I'll jump right in here.
Okay.
Okay guys. I think for the null. Right.
What I know I already explain in many,
many times right now
because you have default statement,
because if none of the cases are matching
efforts, they will be initialized.
So do I need to have a no,
I don't have to have a null
in this particular
now, I don't have to have a
we use the markets were inside here.
No, this inside here no.
And here we can huh.
Can you at and sub is needed.
Okay so now remember
this is a block of code that we go right?
So now we say hey
if the country will the United States
right here we have
we can have many statements that we can
have many statements in here if we want.
If you want to throw the nesting in here,
you're more than welcome to do it.
You want to add another switch,
You're more than welcome to do it
based on the scenario. Right.
But you should understand
when this scenario,
for example, if you want to add the
if statement in here, right.
If something I don't know, whatever,
whatever the condition will be in here.
Right.
So all you have to understand when this
if will be executed only and only when
a value of this variable
after the conversion
will be equal to the U.S..
But can there be more stuff?
Of course, because there's inside
can be many, many other stuff.
There can be.
Even if you want, you can throw
another switch in here, right?
We can throw another switch in here
as many things you guys can throw inside.
But then think the same thing.
All you have to.
Just make sure you understand
in which this my gear execution
only and only
when a code will jump in here.
If you code will be it,
then obviously this
switch will never get a chance
to be executed.
Right.
But is there a possibility
that they can be inside of Williams?
There's a possibility
that we can have many things inside.
One now is only one line
and they can be in many other lines
that can include many other things
in there.
Yeah.
Once again, this country ignore keys.
No, we cannot do it. We cannot do it in
like I can write more than one with Alexa.
Can you specify a question
more than once?
What do you mean?
In here
You can.
You can,
you can add more stuff in here, right?
You can add more and more stuff in here.
That's what you want.
But remember,
one variable guys can have only one value.
For example,
what if I'm going to add four equals two?
Four equals two?
I don't know.
What do you guys have in there?
And something else, right?
I don't know you guys or more.
What are you having?
That Veronika right there.
Right. Okay.
Can you have it? This way?
Yes, we can have it this way.
But let me ask you this then.
What if I'm willing to enter Ukrainian
right now?
What do you guys think will be the output?
What will be the
favorite theoretical? What
or the first one
or last one?
All right.
Let's let's let's let's before
would you run in that I want you to run
right let's let's
let's turn on our think in logic right
so now you guys need to explain me
so now I will be can have two values.
That's good. Thank you.
Right. Why?
Because we have a single variable.
A single variable
can hold only single value.
But now the question is
what will be in there?
Let's go step by step.
I want you guys give me the explanation.
So Ukraine will be stored in here.
Now, what happens in here?
Can you guys explain me
what happens in here?
I need you to explain to me
what happens in there.
So now Ukraine in form.
The upper Keys. Converse Lilac is good.
So now, from having a string
all in uppercase, we are going to get
a completely new string
that will be in the lowercase.
That's
what are we going to be? Okay, good.
Okay, then after that, we're
after that.
What happens this
if finds the matching case, right?
If it finds the matching case.
Okay, cool It found the matching case.
Then once it finds the matching case,
what happens based. Oh,
it goes inside. Right.
Okay. Off the same column.
It allows t goes inside of it. Right.
It finds the matching case,
then it goes inside.
So now what happens on the line 22 This
What happens on the line 22?
Okay.
What is the word for this
and what are we doing on the line 22?
This?
Oh, I don't see that we have t cell going,
not printing this.
I don't see any print on the line 22.
What happens
when 22
So what are we doing?
We they go we are signing right.
We are initially sizing that.
So now what happens?
We had a four in there.
Regal empty box.
Empty box we have in here. Right?
So now this empty box,
we reserve the memory java.
Right?
So now on the line 22, what happens?
We take in the value of Bush
in the storing it in here.
So what we're doing,
we are initializing a variable forward.
Right. Good.
So then what happens with
our code is our code gets out though.
What happens with the code
then when we
remember, the code goes up to the bottom
until it sees either switch
or until it sees Eve.
But you could remember
the step to the bottom that how it goes,
always remember this.
Now it executed line 22.
Now it will go ahead and execute line 23.
What happens on the line 23?
And we are signing.
Right. Reassigning.
So we're not printing in here.
We are reassigning. Right.
So now we're saying, hey, Bush,
before we had abortion here, right?
Hey, boys, get out from here.
Now I'm placing very unique in their
right of their place in this value code.
The game goes down.
What now? When the code goes down,
what does it see?
This is a break.
So what is the break is going to do?
Breaks is get out.
Stop, stop
execution inside my switch statement.
Get out. Right.
So now a Java Caesar. Remember break.
It's a key word.
He words have a special meaning in Joe.
And now Joe is break. Okay.
Somebody is kicking me out. Okay.
I'm going to get out.
But we're kicking me out.
It's kicking me out from this switch
statement where switch statement starts.
It starts from this curly braces, it ends.
And here they
they kick me out from the case.
So now what I will do,
I will jump right away in here.
So now, what is the last
value of you placed inside
the variable floodgates?
Thank you. Right. That's what we put.
So now we're saying
here is the very key equals to unknown.
Is it true or false?
Is a new key equals to unknown.
No condition is false.
And then what you see is
it sees a not operator.
So what's going to happen
in and it will reverse.
Before I had false
now I'm saying not false.
It's going revert to the true right
And then one condition is true.
I can go inside the if block and now
this is if your country is Ukrainian,
your favorite food is ready
that's what we going to go, right.
That's what we're going to get.
So you see, always, always
had to analyze
you could write so the first here
well while debugging you guys will see
right so what's going to happen right now
food At first it was bush
now is going to change to a key
and then is going to edit
my switch work
and then my switch my even here right
will give me the true
and that's where we going to right. So
get inside.
You can have whatever code you will need
to pull based on their logic,
based on their assignment in here.
Okay.
Then we use like for example,
integer x, x or same formula
and can we put it in the x key please
fix Alexander.
You can. You can try it. Right.
So remember,
remember inside the keys, right.
We providing the value. Right?
Providing the value.
But can you do some things
the value for example before that.
Right.
Can you do some things with this
with the value before that?
If it's a numbers you can try,
you can see,
you can try to perform some operations
and see if it will work.
Okay.
What we're going to have.
All right
this right. So let's do some practice.
But I'm going to maybe
actually it's one of these right? So
another assignment goes,
you boys, I'm going to give you
just these two guys
the very similar. Right?
The first one, very similar.
But now I want you to try try
converting the values to the uppercase.
Right. When you will be capturing
the country, then you will.
I want you to define the language
and the same thing here scanner,
but you will be capturing the great
the example that you did before.
The only thing right now
I want you to capture it in.
Now you guys should be able to do it
in this switch
and this is will be your homework
so we'll explain your homework.
Okay. So let me send you this right.
And what we can do is we can take an
after this assignment.
We can do it
just just to follow this,
just you for now.
And this will be your later homework.
Can be
learned.
I send it in the course announcement.
Okay?
Okay. All right. I guess I'm going to.
So it's 109.
So basically, guys,
what I'm going to give you
I'm going to give you 10 minutes to do it.
Right.
10 minutes to do it,
and then 15 minutes for a break.
So I want you to be back,
but I want you to complete the assignment,
complete tasks, and be back by
135 to 3135.
This way you guys have 10 minutes
for assignment and 15 minutes for break.
If you finish your assignment early,
you can have a longer break.
All right, This with me. Copy this right
now, to
me, the right scanner's scanners
is there to enable our and console.
Then here we provided they suction.
Right here
we capture and they charge our book value.
That's why we use it next.
And from next we use in the character
and the first place.
Right
And then here declaring one variable.
But we don't know the value yet, right?
We don't know the value
then here inside our switch.
Right.
So you're saying yay, I'm providing
a different values for a great right.
My value great is a chart type of value.
So the values my matching cases
are also as a chart type, right?
So let's say needs is eight.
Then you get excellent case
be you good Casey
average case D band and default
we name it acceptable right
and then you said any explanation
is not equal to not acceptable
and you will print
a great an explanation right
And then you guys what do you do
you test with different
in variable my greatest eight
they go A's excellent right.
They always tell me the group
migrate is me your grade is that right?
And then let's check anything else.
Please enter your grade.
My three D they go to enter another group.
So my code. What?
My code works.
So for a switch we're seeing rates,
which is a value based.
So what happened matching
now is why we are taking that is right.
We are we are checking for the matching
values for this particular variable.
Right.
And once our code,
because our code knows the exact
now only because it holds that value,
our code will jump
right away into the matching each right
matching
and right.
Let's look into here.
What do we have?
Right. So rules we are right
you will able right.
That's what we say.
The value of the case
must be the same as data type
break statement be used to
get out from this statement.
Get out from the switch.
Statement break is optional, but if we're
not going to have it, it's our code.
Our Joe will continue running
into the next cases.
Default is our block is very optional.
No, only difference.
It can be anywhere inside our switch
blocked Duplicate
cases are not allowed.
And in here, right in here
we see me talking about the limitation
so the switch case
can check only for equality.
So each case in the inside
the switch case, we cannot say that
the value is greater than something
that the value can be equal to this
or equal that.
So there is work, so there is
no relational and no logical apparatus.
Right.
And there's a limitation in our data types
that we can use with this,
which also the code
is about upper lower case,
upper lorikeets.
That was for your string.
This right, That was for your string
and right for a string.
So what you guys were doing here
when you convert something
to the uppercase, right?
When you convert something
to the uppercase, then matching cases.
Matching cases
must be also in the uppercase.
That was the
that was the first one. Right.
So in here, if you would captured country,
then I want you to country
to convert the country to the uppercase.
Right.
Some of you did to the lowercase.
It's fine. Right.
Then if you kept a converted
to the uppercase, then all matching cases
must be in the upper cases. Right?
So if instead of the uppercase
you will move to,
if instead of the lower you will go to the
uppercase, then
all the things in here
must be in the upper right.
All the matching pieces must be
in the uppercase Y, because matching cases
should match the values
that you have inside your switch.
Right.
But if it will be Milwaukee,
then it's two three.
So whichever one you list, use it.
But just to practice,
I ask you to do it with the uppercase.
All right.
Any questions?
This any questions for the switch?
Why do we need a switch?
When to use it?
What is the syntax?
What is the limitation?
What is the pros console with it?
There was something
except in both upper and lower.
Okay.
Forgot module example to ignore
the case is completely to.
We have a code that sees equals a equals
ignore keys, but the equals or equals
ignore keys
we can use all inside the f k only inside
if y because when you say equals, right,
when we say equals does we have to provide
another value.
We have to provide another comparison
to which we try
to check a current variable
because what is it food for?
Is it string type of variable?
This drink table variable will have
some type of value inside, right?
It will have some type of note.
Now what equals does it compare in right,
the way we compare
the numbers here, if number one is large
is equals to number two, right?
Same thing. What do we do?
We have we are comparing one string value
to another.
So in here you have to provide two values.
You have to give two values.
And when you compare them one value
to another one, whether it's a string,
whether it's a number,
what are you guys going to get to?
Is going to get a Boolean expression
in expression
is not going to work for it switches.
So using equals or equals
ignore keys inside our switch here is
not going to work. Oh,
we said something new this
E what if this and multiple countries
speak English?
So basically we you
you kind of like want to use or right.
Do you want to say here in the countries
United States
or the countries and England
or the countries of Australia.
So their language is English, right?
So we can not.
Okay,
so there is a way guys write this or what
for example,
can you guys send me this code?
I'll show you, even though it's
not going to look a nice coding.
But can it be done?
Yes, it can be done.
Okay,
if it can, you guys send me that code
with the
with the countries in
I they got someone already.
Someone already did it right.
Same on a copy.
I copy your record. I think
if I click
but let me, let me copy
someone who didn't want to do it
For example, it
ended
with the persistence.
Then this is what you get it right?
So that's what you do, right?
So you capture the writing, capture
the countries you save.
It's United States.
Then distinguish this is have gone
is found very Turkey's Turkish
right so the only thing
what I would ask you before this write
remember when you think of
different variations, right.
So if I'm going to enter the USA,
use it and
that way right.
All right.
We were not able to determine
a language, right?
the language. Why?
Because you say
with the first uppercase is not the same
that you see all in the uppercase, Right.
So in here to eliminate any issues.
So that's why I asked
you convert to the uppercase.
Right.
So and then once we convert
the country that we enter in
through our console, Right.
So then if you convert this country
to the uppercase,
then make sure all the countries
are read them in the upper right.
All the values are written in the upper to
speak.
So now the question was, hey,
what if there is a multiple countries
right?
What are those are multiple countries
that speak English, right?
So now is there way technically,
what do we want to say?
The is USA, all the countries, Australia,
all the countries.
England. Right.
So we know that using or operator
is not applicable in here.
We cannot say like that or let's say
now because it's in uppercase, right.
We cannot say like this, right.
We cannot say this way,
we cannot say this. Why?
Because those operators are not valid.
Operate for our switch.
But what do we can do this?
What we can do?
We can provide multiple cases, right?
What are we can say?
We can say case U.S.. Right.
And then
if we're not going to provide the value,
we can just write it like this is right?
States England
and then we can the another
is, for example, right.
So this way I think our guys
what is going to happen, right?
So think what is going to happen.
So why do logically
when we think right so for example,
I intend U.S.
right.
I heard you say
it will be stored this variable.
Then you are saying
it convert into the uppercase.
It becomes big U.S., right,
Because big U.S.
So now you could just right away
to the matching cases.
Right.
And it wants to execute after code
the after the semicolon.
But there is no code and there's no rape.
Right.
So then what happens if there's no code,
no break, Right.
Your code will fall to the next case.
Now, it will fall to the next case, Right.
And there is no code
inside the next case, right?
There is no code.
Then what we'll do
is we'll fall onto another case.
And now when they fall that case,
then it will execute this statement
and then it will see the break.
As soon as it sees a break,
it will get out from your switch.
Right.
So this way
we can handle this particular scenario.
But but does it look
does it look nice and clean?
That's a different question.
Probably
if that will be a particular scenario.
Maybe in this
case. Right. Maybe this case,
if you want to provide the
values like this, I probably would go
for logical operations.
Right?
For the logical or what can it be done?
Yes, it can be done right.
Let's see if we go back.
I don't know if it's going to go over this
spaces or not.
Center country, you would say, right,
I'm entering lowercase U.S., right?
I'm entering lowercase.
Now, what's going to happen? My U.S.
is getting converted to the uppercase
and going to see it found.
Imagine there was no code then
in full into the next case,
then fold to the next case.
And now there Australia.
Then what it does it initialize that.
Okay, so this is a way
how it could have the case.
But as I mentioned,
probably I would rather go
for a logical upper than instead of
the right in the cases. This
that makes
sense based.
If you understood the purpose of break,
then this makes then this makes sense.
Right? Why?
Because there's nothing that stops
you code
falling to the next case
and then to the next case.
And then only
when it sees a break in this.
Get that
surrogate's.
Any other questions for switch
in these break in the code
or in the class right now
import encoding of this
I mean there's a there's me there's other
we can use a break in other statements
and of course we are going to look in
more of the tomorrow class
in which statement we can use a break
or in here if you guys going to the break,
what are what is going to
happen this one or this thing
and use a break?
Of course you can use a break,
but what is going happen?
So what will happen? Right.
So let's say let's run through USC, right?
So what I will do, what I will do,
it will find the matching case, right?
It found the matching case we did not see
because there was no line
inside the matching case then.
So the break.
And that's why they're out,
right? That's why it's got out.
And because nothing was happening in here.
Right.
So the language will be now
and then that's why it will print us
now right.
Followed you collaborators.
Then you guys will have to go for it.
You will have to say, hey,
it won't be a switch.
It will be even if country is equal
to say, or country equals to England,
all country equals to Australia,
then the language is English, right?
That's what you will go.
You won't be able to go for the switch.
Right.
So you go either for switch,
you go either for if statement, right.
If states.
So all of this variation is
just remember always remember
why we use the right.
So once you know why there is a switch
once you know why there is a e
why there's a logical operators,
why there's a relational upgraded right.
It will be easier later
for you to based on the exercise,
to know which statement,
which keywords, which
which things to do right.
So switch statement once again,
it's a great alternative for if else if
right when we have to test
for multiple things right.
So the only thing
what are we doing within this switch.
We testing for multiple values right.
Multiple values
that our variable can have.
Right
and all variable can have use in switch.
We strictly checking for the equality,
right?
We then switch.
We cannot say hey
that the value is greater
than something values
smaller than something value
is equal to this or a equals to the right
is strictly value based.
So once your variable because your
variable holds a particular value, right,
and right away
it knows what values it holds, it finds it
finds a matching,
gives this and jumps to it.
That's why we say let's switch.
Case is faster.
Except there's some limitations, right?
Except there's some limitations.
So if you know in your code,
any time you have to check for equality,
then go for a switch.
Right? Go for a switch in.
Of course,
there's no need of using logical operators
or use of the relational operators.
Go ahead and use this switch.
But if you know in the scenario
where you have to check the equality
of three numbers, right. Why?
Because you will have to compare
one number to another number in
in the same time,
second number to the third number.
So you know that the switch case can now
do this type of operation.
So you will go right away, which we used
to use.
Okay.
So in
here, this will be your homework, right?
And remember what we said for a switch.
Every single scenario
that you do with switch,
you guys can do it with the eve, right?
But not every eve scenario
you can do within the switch.
So what are you guys going to have?
You guys are going to have a homework.
Okay.
You guys are going to have a homework
in which
we want you to a calculator, right?
So but the calculator,
it will be very interactive calculator.
Right?
So first you need to capture two numbers
from the user, right?
I want you to capture two users
and I want you to capture the operation
that user want to perform,
whether users want to perform addition,
subtraction, multiplication or division,
you're not defining it.
Use it as telling you, right?
So you take in three inputs, two numbers
in the operation that user wants to do.
And then based on the operator, right,
the fusion will be entering you.
Plus you will have to perform addition.
If a user will be in a minus,
you will have to do the subtraction,
if user will enter multiplication
and so on.
Right.
So this assignment I want you to do
trying two different ways.
I want you to try
using each statement and I want you to try
to use it using the switch case.
Okay.
So this way you guys can see that
it can be done using both ways,
but then you guys will see which way
to the code will look cleaner, which way
maybe you will perform more it,
but eventually task can be completed
completed using two different statements.
Okay.
So that will be a homework.
I'll post them
guys posted and our course announcement.
Okay.
And I see.
And of course, guys,
there will be more ripple assignments.
I think we did not release logical
so I will release logical today
and I will release
I will release of the switch statement.
Good.
And at the same time,
what you guys are going to have in
you guys going to have you guys
going to have a quiz?
Okay.
Are you guys going
to have your first quiz?
And I
will give you a of course, it's one
we will give you a few days to do it.
Okay.
So you guys are going
to have your first quiz
where the quiz
is one
or the unit.
Oh, it's already available.
I don't know if it should be available.
Okay, I'm going to end. Okay.
So now when it comes to quizzes, guys
When it comes to quizzes.
So quizzes are
did you guys completed it?
It should be conditional statement.
It should be included in the switched.
Oh, I've got to assign it to you. Okay.
Okay. That's good.
Then October 21st, 28.
Okay,
then he did explain it to you guys, right?
So remember quizzes are we are not going
they have a start to have the end, right.
We not going to reopen them
if you missed that. Right.
They have a deadline.
They have a limitation
in the number of times of doing it.
So if you decide to open it
and then complete it later, then open
it completely later,
then they will count as a first attempt.
Right.
Then you guys have only two items. Okay.
If you guys done already, that's good.
If you're not done,
please make sure you do.
That thing has got to give
you till October 28, which is up.
And then you go, you guys are going to have other quizzes as well when it happens.
Okay.
All right.
So what are we going to do this today?
Today we start anyways.
We're going to do an introduction
and then this.
We will continue tomorrow.
What we will do is
we will start our introduction to loops.
Okay, so loops, it's a very, very
important concept that we have, right?
In any programing language
you guys can think of.
All this
loops conditional statement.
They are exist.
But before we going to go to the loops,
I want to look at a very,
very small topic this
I want to look at the very small topic
about operators, about operation.
Remember this so far what we learn, we
learn different set of operators, right?
You guys looked into that.
Simon Operator You guys looked
at the arithmetic operators, right?
Plus minus.
You guys look at the relational operators
rate are equal, less than equal.
We looked into logical operators, right?
Logical and logical or
and now what are we going to be
looking into, increment
and decrement operators?
Well,
we're going to quickly.
So let me see my class
increment.
I want to do the introduction.
So this way you guys will be easier
for us for tomorrow.
We can look up.
So guys,
let's take our well look into basics.
If I'm going to take a variable right,
I'm going to take a variable
nom and for example,
won't seen them equals to
one one then. Now
if I want to add one
to my variable number, right,
I want to one for example.
Just one. Right.
So the way we can do it, we can say no
plus one, right?
So we say now plus one,
we will perform this arithmetic operation
and then what we will do,
we will reassign to this variable.
Right.
So now what will happen
is my number, right?
Our now will have the value of one or one.
Right?
So this is the very first way
that you guys learn.
Then you guys learn another way
that there is
a shorter way how we can add one right?
You guys are locked into this
shorthand operator.
Shorthand assignment operator. Right.
How can we add one
less to due to my variable name
is the right.
So this is what you learn before
now plus equals to one.
Right. Let's equal to one. Okay.
That's what you guys done before, right?
You guys did not learn plus plus yet.
We want to look into those two different
ways that you guys saw before, Right?
So we said, hey,
because these are medical operations.
Sometimes they can be very popular,
but you have to use
there's a shorter with you write right?
So this non plus equals one,
it's exactly the same as this way, right?
So this way is
just a longer version of this.
So what are we doing this in Haiti?
Take my variable
and I want to exact the same thing.
Right.
So now if I'm going
to bring my number, I know
that we will be one or two, right?
Code executes, come to the box.
And now there is another way.
This time there is another way.
How we can add one to our variable right?
There's another way.
How we can add to our variable
and to add one
just number or just one
to any variable that we work with,
Java gives us an increment
and decrement operators, right?
So it says, Hey,
any time you want to add one
to the variable, right, not to the value,
the variable, what do you use
plus plus, you know what this
plus plus is is mean.
It means I am increment
the value of variable by one branch.
And now if I'm going to change it,
I'm going to print that optimum.
So my value
will become one of the right one.
That's what it does. Right.
And is there an increment? Right.
This is this is what we do increment.
Increment, Increment
the value of the variable by one.
Right.
So as the increment theory,
we also have a decrement.
Right.
So what we can have, we can have now
minus minus.
So what is a num, minus minus.
It will do it will it will decrement
one for my variable
decrement,
decrement something
that's only That's right.
That's all it does
is it either increments you value by one
or it decrements your value by increments
or decrements.
That's why the call increment
and decrement operate. Right.
So the only one tiny thing is remember.
So this increment, Right,
this increment and decrement
operators, they can be used
only these variables, right?
This increment and decrement.
We cannot use them with values.
For example,
I cannot say for example right,
I cannot say ten
plus plus I cannot see such a thing.
He cannot see such a thing.
So all this increment or increment
or decrement
can be used with our variables only.
We cannot use increment the values
value
that once all these variables
will always be up.
Right.
Very, very poor to work for.
Float. Let's see this.
No, no. We'll have more of a float.
Much like slope F equals
thousand 99.
Right? This is our food,
this is our float.
And then what do we have to say?
We have to say F plus, plus F
plus it work.
Now let's try to prove right.
So it just increments our
value by one, right?
As long as we have a numerical,
so long as we have the net.
So now it's a when you look at it,
it's very, very simple.
Right? Very, very simple.
Operator
But then Y in Java, we need those.
Operator Okay, so now this increment
and decrement
hopper is this we will be using
in our loops, Okay.
In our loops.
So now what are the loops? Loops?
We can think of them like a cycles loop.
It's like a cycle.
It's a cycle of the repetitive quote.
Okay. For example.
Right.
For example, if I want to take
for example, I want to say hello to you.
Right.
Let's say we don't know loops right now.
We don't know loops right now. Right.
I want to say hello you right system
that out
that print line and I want to say hello
there the station
we're there first thing. Right?
So now
we pretend that
this is our main method, right?
So for example, is only one statement
right now.
What if I want to say hello three times?
Right?
Let's say
I don't know the concept of loops right?
So then what I would have to do,
I would have to repeat this lines of code,
right?
Oh, let's say four times
I want to say hello.
Right.
So will it do the job or printing
Hello four times?
Yes, it does do a job.
But now when you look into my code, right
When I look into my code,
what I'm doing in here,
I'm doing repetition, right?
I'm doing the repetitive, I'm
repeating the statement.
Right.
I am repeating the statement.
And what kind of statement? Repeating
and repeating the same statement.
Right.
So now, did it do a job?
Yes, it did a job,
but does my code looks good
my code does not look really good. Right?
So now what is the scenario?
I want to say hello hundred times right
then.
This is just a simple example, right?
When it comes to our automation,
of course, there will be different
things that we're going to do.
But right now, what if I want you to say
hello 100 times now?
What will happen?
I will.
I will buy a hundred lines of my code
by repeating exactly the same lines saying
hello right.
So now Java says, Hey, whenever
you have this same code
where there is just one line,
whether it's a block code, Java says, Hey,
whenever you have a block of code
that you want to repeat, right,
that you want to repeat multiple times,
please
go ahead and use loops, right?
Please go ahead and use loops.
So what are loops in Java?
Loops in Java is a statement that do words
that they repeat this same
block of code based on some condition.
Right? Based on some condition.
And This condition
we will look into ways to.
Okay.
So now when it comes to loops, right.
And I'm sure you guys already have a look.
So how many loops in Java we have
loops now.
What kind of loops we have?
We have a loop.
Then what we have is
we will have for loop.
Okay, what else
we have?
I do.
Well, we have a dual.
Okay.
And there's one more loop that you guys
are actually going to look next weekend
because for that loop to look, there is
a specific condition must be matched.
But now we don't know
those specific conditions.
So there is another loop
that we're going to look
it will be enhanced for
hand, for loop.
Think of it like a
an improved version of the for
will be enhanced for a loop
we will hold called advance for loop
or insert program
and you guys will be able for each loop
for each.
So no jealousies is hanging
whenever you want to repeat this
same block of code here, I'm meeting you
for different type of loops.
So now what do we have to make sure?
Now we have to make sure
that we learn each loop
and we underspent in which situation
we should go for it.
Particular loop. Right?
So I did what the guys and in this order
we will be learning loops today.
We are not going to touch for and
I don't know if you will come to the door,
but at least we will try to practice
and we will start with that.
Wow. Right.
Okay.
So four different variations,
obviously They are different, right?
Java would not us exactly the same things.
Exact the same loops if they would work
and the same ones.
Right.
So But all of this because
every single loop of this, it's
a it's a loop.
So it means every this loop has a power
of repeating this same block of code.
Right.
And number of times,
depending on the situation of how
we want to write all this loops,
why we are going to learn is loops.
So this way we can eliminate,
we can avoid.
You have repetitive code right?
This code does the job
but doesn't look professional, right?
It doesn't look good. Right?
There should be a better way to write
Hello five times.
What? With the help of what?
With the help of loop.
So now what are we going to do?
We are going to start this very,
very first loop is very first loop,
and we're going to look into our way of
getting the first one to look
at will be our one, right?
So always give an example.
Always give an example.
Let me take a moment
when you say integer prime,
I know it's I don't know.
It's 2:00, right integer time.
It's 2:00 or let's make it I don't know.
Let's go 24 hours at 45.
So you can repeat the same sentence.
Right For now. It just a print statement.
But eventually, with the help of loop,
we can repeat a block of code,
get a block of clock.
So why loop?
Oh, I'm taking the variable. Right.
I'm taking the variable same time.
Time. It's 2:00, right? 14, 14.
So now I want to see. Right.
I'm going to bring the eve first
and then I want you to see this.
For example, I want to if time eased,
I don't know if time is less than 20.
Right.
For example,
I'm going to see if time is less than 20.
Read less than 8:00
or let's say less than 7:00.
I'm going to say, for example,
right now is a date system
around
the queen line.
Right?
Okay. I don't know. It's a new date.
So basically, whatever. Right.
The way to go too much with the details.
But then we're going to right now
the way learn
that our eve statement works, right?
So when we learned our
if statement works, our
if statement works
with the condition, right.
If the condition is true,
then I am allowed to go inside my eve
block, Right.
I'm allowed to go inside if work.
And in this case,
14 is less than 17 right.
I wanted to put 19 this way.
It's 14 is less than 17.
That's
why we're going to print two days, right?
So now what?
Again, new this all I'll do now
instead of the eve,
What I'm going to do, I'm going to type
what I'm going to say
while time is less
than 17 and I'm going to see
me and I'm going to say it's a date.
Okay, So now let me ask you guys,
what will be the difference
between this statement
and what will be the difference
between this statement?
So in here right in here, what do we have
right? Remember, Eve, what is it?
Eve is a keyboard, right?
Every keyboard
has a special meaning for Jill.
So when the Java sees Eve right away,
when the Java Eve,
it knows I have to check the condition.
That's what I want, right?
Because it eve is a conditional statement.
So now objects.
Hey, is less than 17 years
condition is true, right?
Because 14 is less than 17,
condition is true.
I can go inside this block of code now.
Let me ask you guys
how many times this block of code line
15 will get executed?
One time.
This is executed one time. Right?
So now when it comes to
our loop, right when it comes to our
So while it's also will be
another keyword, right?
It's well, it's another key word in Java.
So now
when the Java
when I'm going to click on Run
in Java she's one right it's a keyword
so it knows okay the using loop
what a loop means.
I have to repeat black of code.
How often do I have?
How long do I have
to repeat the block of code?
As long as the condition is true.
So what the well do?
Well, we'll also check the condition.
And if condition is true,
then that will do.
It will go inside.
And while black.
Remember, guys, what do we mean by block?
This is the block.
It goes inside the world.
Look in worry will do it.
We'll repeat block of code
and number of times.
How many times
as long as the condition will be true.
So now what happens?
Your java comes in season while. Okay.
While it means I have to repeat
block of code, that's what Java knows.
I have to run.
But before I repeat block of code,
I have to check the condition.
Hey, is the condition is true?
Yes, condition is true
because 14 is less than 17.
So I'm going inside block of code.
So this will be executed once then.
Because remember this
Java cannot make a decision on its own.
Java does what you instructed it
to do then, because Java knows.
Okay, you know what?
I have to repeat this block of code
now what Java
Java archeologist exist by itself.
Java will go back and what it will do,
it will check the condition again.
So what it now Lee of time
when I'm going back again, it's
what is the value of time when I'm
going back again, a value is still 14.
Right?
Remember
as you could go step to the bottom
where did you initialize your variable?
You initialize the variable in here.
Are there any where draw the line?
I'm changing the value of the variable.
This is there anywhere
I'm not changing. Right.
So now what happens?
Your time is still 14.
14 is still less than 17.
So your code is still
your code is still true.
It will print again, then goes back
because time is not changing.
It will continue. Continue printing.
So there's this
what do we call this type of loop
we call this type of loop infinite.
So what this loop will do
is it will continuously
run your code until you out of the memory.
Right.
Which probably is going to take,
I don't know, maybe couple of days.
Right. So now what do we have to do?
Guess we have to somehow stop our look.
Right.
We have to somehow step our look.
We can use a break, right?
So maybe I use the wrong word.
So Now we have to make sure
that at some point
a condition becomes true, Right?
So now that's where what we guys can do
that's
where we can add our use,
our increment or decrement.
Operator. Right.
So now it means inside my block of code,
what I'm going to do,
I'm going to start incrementing my time.
I'm going to say time plus plus
five plus plus, right?
So now what will happen, right?
So now what will happen now when your code
goes right, When your code runs right.
So now at first, initial values
time is 14.
Hey, is 14 less than 17 years?
Condition is true.
When condition is true, I can go inside.
I can go inside.
So this way I'm going to print it
one time.
Then what happens with our time this time?
Plus plus what will happen?
What will be the value of my time
now will be 15.
Now your Java knows
your Java cannot just stop.
Your java are running in cycles.
This runs in cycles
as long as the condition true.
So your java always will go back
and change the condition.
Now when it goes back,
what is the value of time
this when it goes
back, it's 15 now check in.
Hey, is 15 less than 17?
Is the condition troubles next?
Now my condition is true.
So now what I'm doing second time,
I'm going inside the loop.
I am go in second time,
print my statement,
and then once I enter it, block of code,
what I see, I see again increment.
So now my variable
will get incremented to 16 right then?
Java cannot stop. It's a
well it's a while.
It sees while it has to say,
it says I have to run the code
while condition is true which that
the programmer
put inside this block of code.
Right.
So then it goes back.
Now it checks. Hey is 16
less than 17 years?
Condition is true on going
that third time inside the loop.
Now I will print the third time.
It's a day now.
My time will get incremented to 17 in
Java.
Still doesn't start.
This Java can start by itself.
It still goes back.
Then what? It goes back now checks.
Hey, is that when you less than 17.
So what is the condition
now? The condition will be false.
Now when condition is false
Java don't have a permission
to enter a block of code.
So now only then
your Java will start, right?
It will it? We won't be able to enter.
You will just
you will just skip the entire well and
then they will continue the code in here.
Right. Will continue the current year.
So now here what we see and you see
you think multiple things, right?
Probably.
So what do we see now?
We're looking into the well loop.
Well, it's a first loop
that we introducing regardless of
what kind of look we are using loops are,
they are to repeat a block of code,
which block of code
that you put inside its own curly braces.
Right.
That you put inside those curly braces.
Now how this block of code
will be executed,
this block of work will be executed
based the condition.
As long as the condition is true,
this code will be repeating,
repeating, repeating, repeating right now
because if we are not going
to have any increment or decrement,
our code will be running forever
running for a loop.
We call it infinite loop.
So now what are we
we throwing in increment or decrement
in the here to do what?
To make sure our loop emits
a false condition.
Okay, so now let's copy this to our
SO right this
do want
to. Yep.
So we we are we are using those
to meet this specific condition.
Yeah. If you want to
just break the loop tomorrow
guys, we will look into those keywords.
We can use some different keywords. Right.
Let me try to debug this to show you.
So what happened? Right.
What happened happening here?
We declare the variable time.
Time as equals 14.
Hey, is 14 less than 17 years condition
is true Jarvis's eve keyboard right?
Eve it means you have to check
for the condition.
And then if condition is true,
it can allow to go inside.
BLOCK Right.
So that's what Java does conditional
what's true.
It does one statement.
That's it, right? Why?
Because it was it was a it was a code that
we put inside the conditional statement.
Right.
So now what your Java seed is,
when it goes to the line
14, it's say so
it is a world now it knows.
Okay, while I have to repeat block of code
but before I repeat that block of code
to have to check the condition.
If the condition will be true,
I will continuously running
the block of code which deploys inside.
Right.
So now time is what is 14, right?
And then condition was true.
It goes inside, right?
It prints each a day,
then goes back again, checks.
Here is the time.
Time is still 14, right?
That's how you look.
Will continue continue
repeating block Of course.
Right this one year Java That's right.
When we don't have any increment
or deployment, that's what it does, right?
And then if you want to
just continues the run, it's very good.
See, your loop runs, right? Runs.
How do you know runs right
here. Right. Is can jump.
And so what we got we got the infinite
loop print, we got an infinite loop.
So now what we have to do,
we have to either
increment or depending on how
time plus, plus, plus.
And now if I'm going to debug again,
which we going to debug again.
So now this debugging
will be very hard to stop
if you got an infinite loop, you just have
to press the red button in here.
Okay.
If you forget,
then just click on Terminate.
You guys will have to do
so. Time What is the value of time?
The value of time is 14, right?
So now please, please, please.
Whenever you guys quote,
especially when you was going to
go for a loop, make sure your
make sure you using the debug.
Right.
So hey, is the time is this 14 years
time was 14 rice with java goes inside
now it executes it's a day right now
it's executes it's a day
and then what happens is the time right
so pay attention to the time
time gets increment.
Now the time is equal to 15.
Then your Java knows again
it needs to go back because it's a while.
Right.
You're repeating block of context
condition again, 15 is less than 17 years.
Condition is true.
I can go inside the block of code
on print.
It's a day.
And then what?
I'm going to do is the time.
I'm going to increment my time.
Now my time is 16.
16 is still less than 17. Right?
And then now what I have,
I have it's a day
and then I'm going to increment my time.
You guys see my time get changed,
but your code is still one back
because Java cannot stop by itself.
Java checks the condition now.
It will check the condition.
Hey, you're 17. Less than 17.
No condition is false. Condition Is false.
I cannot enter the block of code
right now.
What it will do, you will stop.
So let me ask you this.
Let me ask what's going to happen
if I'm going to do time?
Minus, minus, what do you get?
This thing is going to happen.
It will become an infinite, right.
It will become an infinite
Y, because every time I am decrement
in that time, right?
First time
it was 14, then it will become 13.
Right
now it will become 13 and.
Then it.
And every time
what will be happening with the condition?
Condition? It will be true, right?
And then your numbers can just go
and then your numbers will just go
minus, minus, minus,
minus minus is will go on to
and it will be forever true.
Right.
It will be forever true.
You will just run, run, run, run, run.
So that's why it's important to identify
whether you guys want to use increment.
Who would
you guys want to use the decrement.
Right. Increment or difference.
Okay.
Let me ask you this.
Right now
I'm just going to draw different scenarios
that you and you guys will be telling me
what to put what
not to put. Okay.
So for example, guys,
what I would like to do, right,
I want to print right now.
I want to print
numbers
from 1 to 20
4 to 20. How can I do it right?
How can I doing this?
We can bring a new variable, guys.
You know, we are not
this is just a first example, right?
So now this is different example.
I want to print numbers from 1 to 20.
How can I do it?
This know now
I want to print the numbers from 1 to 20.
Right? So now let's declare
let's declare a variable right?
I'm not going to touch this time
because this time it will.
I will kill this time for that excess.
That's right.
So now
I want to print from 1 to 20, right.
So I can go to south once it's out.
Which is out. This is out for now.
What I'm doing, I'm
repeating exactly the same block of right.
So now instead of the repeating the same
block of what, I can go for a loop.
So now let me take a variable integer.
I equal to one right?
So I have a variable
that holds the value of one.
So now how can I meet this variable
to be true 20 times
and then I can just printed, right?
So now I can say well, right.
Because that's all we have.
While I is a lot less or greater, this
is a greater key.
While I ease more than 23,
then what are we doing this then?
What are we doing?
I want you print the numbers from 1 to 20.
How can I do
what?
I can do now I'll take right.
So now the only difference right now,
instead of printing, it's a day, right?
What I'm going to print, I'm
going to print the value of this variable.
Right?
I'm going to print
the value of this variable
y because I know the value
of this variable changes, right?
Changes. Now, how can I make it change?
I just make it up.
Plus, plus, plus, plus.
Okay, so now let's analyze this.
Analyze it. Right.
Okay.
We're going to look only at this part
right now.
Integers initialize in the variable
I equals to one.
So now while it means
I have to repeat a block of code,
which block of code
applies from here to here right now?
But before I'm allowed to repeat this
block of clip,
I have to check the conditional.
I'm. Hey,
is that condition true or false? This
if false.
So what happens when the condition is fold
this What happens when condition false.
I cannot enter.
I cannot enter in here.
Then your java goes out.
It goes out outside of the wild look.
And if there is no statement,
it's the end of the mean.
And then it sees the end of the class.
And that's why you will stop read.
That's why it won't step. Right.
That's why when we say in here, right,
I want to print numbers from 1 to 20.
Nothing that printed one
because condition was false.
Now what do we have to do?
We have to make sure we meet the true
condition.
How do we make the true condition?
This.
Let's just do the rest.
If I want to include 20,
what should be my upgrade?
I want to include 20
less or equal minus one people.
And then while debugging. Right?
Always. Always.
I know it's easy guys, right?
But always try to keep up too.
This thing right
integer AI is equal to one.
One is less than 20.
Condition is true.
Going inside by printing the value of one.
And then what happens with our one
one will be increments.
Right?
Incrementing the level of I begin to write
two is still less than 20
condition is true print the value of I
it was two
now on the line 27 I'm incrementing right
and your cycle come
continuous continuous continuous.
It will continue this all the way
until the value of
I write
was 20. Right.
So now what happened?
The value of I became 21.
You still did not stop your java
one back to the line 23
because it has to check the condition
now you'll be checking
the condition 21 is not less than.
20 condition will be false.
Now one condition is full Java.
I don't have permission now.
It will continue to this.
Right?
You will continue to this one.
Now, this way,
when we see with the helpful loop
we were able to repeat this block code
while this condition was true.
Right? Well, this comes first.
So in this scenario,
condition was to 20 times.
That's why we see
the numbers are printed from 1 to 21 to
so what if I want to print them all
in one liners?
I don't want to print them vertically.
I want to print horizontally
on an all in one line
and just use print.
I can just go,
okay, So I did prints
and now maybe we will need to add
some space in there.
Space and it stops plus space.
And then let me readjust
and blend in here.
So now, right now
I have one, two, three, four, five.
All the way to 20, all the way to 20.
All right, guys, let me ask you then,
what if I want
you print, I want you print
numbers from
me. The one
now here was from 1 to 20.
Right now I want you print from 50 to 1.
So now you know, right?
We are starting from the highest value
to the lowest, right?
So now what?
It means we have to do the decrement.
Okay, so what will be my starting point?
This integer, let's take another variable
is they integer.
Why? I'm printing from 50 to 1 this.
So what is the what
should I initialize my variable to
50 right.
I'm going to initialize it to 50.
Then give me the condition. This
and now I'll go with my while
because this is
the only that we learn right?
So now we have to configure the condition.
So now we will say, Wow, why did I say 50?
Okay, sure we can use it.
Well, 50 is less than equal than one.
Okay, fine.
I'll put 50. Right, I'll put 50.
Okay But then what will be your statement?
What are you guys going to print?
I want you print now is from 50 to 1.
Now, am I going to do it?
So now who has got to have holds
the value of that variable less?
How can I do it
right?
So in here, guys, right.
We have to specify this variable, right?
We have to specify this variable,
and then this variable holds
what the value of 15.
Now, well,
this variable holds the value of 50.
What I can do, I can print it, right,
I can print it.
And then what else is important
to do This?
Then it's important to decrement,
write, decrement.
So this way, right.
So what will happen at this example?
Right?
May is $50
or it is 50 less or equal than one.
This what is our condition, true or false?
Mission is false.
How do I make this condition true?
So while condition is not less, if
my variable has a high value right,
so now my operator should be greater,
right?
My operator
should be greater than it should be.
Good.
Now this is what will be happening, right?
Hey, is 50 more than one? Yes.
Condition is true.
I am going inside.
First time I'm going to print 50 right
then what I'm doing
I am decrement to my Y will become 49.
My code goes back now it says he is a
y still more than one. Yes.
Last time I checked it was 49.
Is 49 still still more than one is.
Condition is true.
I'm going inside again now all 349.
What I'm going to do
is why I'm going to do minus one.
Now going back,
the value of Y is 48 is 42.
More than one is.
Okay, then go inside,
print the value of y,
valid y and then do what is white.
Continue discriminating, continue
discriminating, continue discriminate.
Right.
We will continue decrement
until the value of one becomes one.
Right.
And then one once the value of one becomes
we say hey, is one is more or equal,
then one is condition is true.
Okay, no problem.
Then what was the last value of Y?
It was one then we are decrement
one minus one will give me zero.
Java goes back is zero more than
no Now our condition became false opinion
Go inside
your java won't be able to enter
this block of code right
So this way it continue execution of that
next statement right? Yeah.
Okay.
The same thing we will meet the needs
needs right there.
So now what we did fear decrement.
That's where we started
from the highest value.
And we're printing all the way
to the lowest
to the lowest.
Okay, this
last thing I'm going to do,
and then it's 243.
I'm going to wait for that.
Maybe we
guys, I want you print numbers from
1 to 10,
but I want you print only even numbers.
Are you guys going to do it?
But my you have to use print.
Remember when we learn the difference
between print in print, like print
will print everything in one line.
Okay. Can you guys tried to do it?
Are you going?
I need the even numbers from 1 to 10.
It means I want to print only two,
four, six,
eight, ten.
Okay, so go ahead and read your quotes.
And this way we. This way. I'll see.
And this
way you guys will see that your classmates
think of different options to
exist
with a new class.
So no one will do this, you guys.
Then there's your friend.
Different quote, right?
So now what I need to write.
This is so the way we should analyze.
Okay,
I need to bring the numbers from 1 to 10.
It means I want to continuously
the sum statement.
Right. Repeating the statement.
I want you print two, four, six, eight.
Right.
So now I want to have
the repetitive statement away.
You just think, okay,
I need a loop right now.
We know just one loop. Okay.
So the way the Y loop works, right?
So first, what do we have?
I have to have a zero, right?
I'm going to same teacher I equals, right?
So no different ways.
How we can go two different ways, right?
So now integer,
I want to print numbers from 1 to 10.
Right. Sure.
Some of you guys started from two
and then what you did inside your world
right for the
Why would you repeat the block of what
you have to make a true condition, Right?
You have to make
the true condition. So now
to make the true condition, you say, hey,
I is less or equal then, right?
Because you want to print only 14.
And now what you guys did,
you started from the even number.
So you can start printing
that even number.
And then what you guys did,
you did you increment what you did it
instrumentation by two right
You did it implementation by two.
Right.
So this way what happens right
is to less than ten years
condition is true.
First thermal print two.
Then what do we have
instead of incrementing by one?
What are you doing?
You are adding to no extent
you are is equals to for your car
your your java goes back
hey is for less than ten years.
Condition is true
quote condition true and going 2.4.
Then what happens?
Four plus two we're going to get six.
Hey, is six less than five years?
Condition is true
and printing six in command
by two, it will be eight
and of course it will be ten after that.
Right after you print eight, then ten,
then after you are
is equals to ten,
you still incrementing by two.
You I implementing
by two will be equal to 12.
Then you are going back.
Eight is 12 less than ten?
No, 12 is not less than ten.
Okay, let me try to bring the value
outside of the loop as well, because all
we while.
So what do you guys think
will be the value if I'm going to print 90
will be the value
of the 19
on the line 19.
Okay.
See, any time you confuse
what you look as you do debug,
what is the value of
I guess what is the value of I
you develop.
I is too good. Right.
Okay.
Now I'm taking
the condition is the condition or false?
Okay.
If my condition is true,
where am I will jump
to which line?
No, I'm still in here, guys. I'm.
I'm checking my condition.
So if the condition is true,
I will go inside.
Then my code will jump to the line.
13 Right.
Then wants to jump to the line 13.
Then it will execute the line 14
So what happens on the line 14 This
where
incrementing the value by two
we are in two.
So before we have to allow us to execute,
it will be two plus two
after that where my code goes case
after line 14, it goes back to the 11.
You cannot just stop your Java,
don't have the power to stop.
Right.
So it so the it knows you have to repeat
the block of plots on your java goes back
it goes back.
So what happened with that
I was equals to four condition is true.
I'm going inside
one wire while I went inside.
I'm going to print this statement
and then I'm going to increment.
So now my I will get increment and can I
if my while block.
No, I cannot because of my Well, look,
I have to go back right.
And this way your Java will continuously
going back and checking the condition.
I'm still right
until well condition is true.
So now we now from eight
we won't return till ten.
Eight is ten is still less than ten years.
Condition is true.
Okay cool condition is two. I'm printing
am printing ten.
Right? I'm still printing ten.
Now what's going to happen was I was
increment by two, right?
It increments by two, it will become 12.
And then that's my Java stop.
Now what happens with Java where it will
go, Guess
which line, which line my code will go.
Right now it's on the line 14 five
Java code always, always will go back.
It has to go back. It cannot just exist.
It cannot just divide.
So what it does, it will increment your I,
then it goes back
you will see did increment that increment
but Java does not have ability to stop.
Your Java will stop
only and only based on the condition.
So what it does it, it has to go back now
one is going back
it checking the condition
now only one the condition becomes false
because 12 is not less than ten now
it exists right.
It now it not enters the well cycle
and it goes back.
Now when it goes back, right.
So now it has to print on the line. 19.
What is the value of I right now guess
it's all
right so the last value of
I want to be incremented it was 12 right.
That's why what it's going to do it's
going to point 12 right.
Then why?
Because as long as the value I was ten.
You were inside this cycle,
inside this cycle,
what you were doing, you were keep
incrementing incrementing increment.
And you are right.
So the last value that happened when you
I was equals to ten, which you did,
you added two to it and after you added
two, then you checked the condition.
Condition was false, but you still added
up to write these two elements.
Right? So this was one way.
Yes. This one way. How to do right.
This was one way.
How to do print all it did.
Now let's go back to the exercise.
Did we print all even numbers?
Yes, we Did two, four, six, eight, ten
right now a second away.
Right now it's slipping away.
How some of you guys did it right.
It's also a great weight, right?
It's also gain weight,
another weight, Great weight,
but using different operator
and the condition.
Right. We
another way.
Right. So now
I'm going to take this and
the mistake was to see if you make
another way Another way.
So what do we have right now? Right.
What do we have? Right.
So another way to do it,
you have a variable, right?
You initialize it to one because what
we want is we want even numbers 1 to 10.
Right?
So now what you did, you said, hey,
you put your condition right
and you want that
all the way. Go all the way till ten.
Now you're saying, hey, you want to print
more than what you did
This print statement, right?
This print statement, what you did,
you put it inside
that block,
the put inside that you blocked.
So it means for Java B printing it.
What your Java has to do,
you have to check condition.
Right.
You have to check condition
you Now let me debug this form. This
one there's just one thing I
want to show you guys, right?
So a value is equal to one, right?
We try to go another way.
Now less is equals 218 is less than ten.
Right.
Is one less than ten years
condition is true.
I am going inside.
Right.
So now while I end there, my wild book
right will enter my wild book
Jarvis's eve.
So as soon as a Jarvis is Eve
when you guys know if it's in the
conditional statement.
So now what do you what Java has to do?
The Java has to check the condition
before it goes inside.
Right?
So now
while taking this condition was false,
you were not able to access this. Right.
But then what you still do is still inside
you while what are you doing?
You increment in your E,
So now the value of E was one.
Now you want to increment E by one.
So now the very value eight
will become two.
Your Java goes back to the while.
Now it says Hey, is the tool less than ten
condition is true right now
condition is true.
Okay.
I'm able to enter my world block
that starts from here and in there.
Now, while entering inside my wild look,
I see if statements right?
I say to each statement now I'm saying,
Hey, Eve e which holds the value of two
more to if there is no reminder
at this point, condition becomes true.
And when condition becomes true,
what are we going to go ahead,
going to print. Right?
So now we are printing two
and then what are we doing is the two.
We will go over this, this
and now while doing
the two, we are incrementing our rate.
So now will have the value of three three.
Right? Three is still less than ten.
And now what about
my condition is my condition draws this
my eight
is the current value of three.
It's false, right?
Because when you divide three by two,
there will be some reminder, right?
There will be some reminder.
So now condition is false.
You cannot print, but you still increment.
You still increment.
Right now your eight becomes
four condition for a while.
It's true condition for if.
What about right?
The value of is two for
in. Okay.
So no condition will be true right now.
What are we doing?
If condition is true,
can I go inside? Yes, I can go inside.
I'm printing eight now.
It will be four so now.
Your condition for it, Eve always
will be true for all the even numbers.
Right.
And how many times my wow will be true.
My world will be true ten times.
Because I started for one
all the way to ten.
Right.
So this would when I'm go into debug right
now it's six.
That's why it went inside right.
We got incremented.
Now when it's seven it can go inside that
block first and so on.
Now with blueprint eight. Right.
So now value of is nine nine.
If you try to divide by two
there is a reminder condition false right.
I'm incrementing eight becomes ten right.
That's what I'm showing.
I am showing in debugging how to use it.
Okay, I'll show you how to use it. Okay.
So now when that I when the A's equals
to ten right condition is true.
Why? Because ten divided by two,
there's no reminder, right?
There's no reminder.
And then we print in a way.
Now we exist in the you statement.
At the end of the while you have a
and you're going to increment that.
Now your E will turn
right
now your code still goes back
and it checks.
Three is the 11 Lisbon ten
So now at this point, condition is false.
Now what happens? You exist, right?
So now if you guys want to
if you guys want to debug right,
what you have to do,
you have to put a breakpoint.
You guys have to put a breakpoints
from where
you want to start your slow
execution. Right.
I don't want to start sluggish action
here.
Now, this is an example where I want to
say to you that will please right
you do left, which was the most right
and it brings the breakpoint.
And then after that
you just have to click on debug
the bargain debugging first time.
If you doing it, this window will show up.
You just have to click on Switch
and then you just do
step over, step over, step over and over.
And if you dive again,
you just click on Stop.
It's okay.
So I'm going to give you homework.
And of course
we are going to continue tomorrow.
We are going to continue tomorrow.
So guys, please try to make sure
you complete the homework for a while.
Loop. Okay?
And please make sure you look over them
for loop for tomorrow class
and then we'll just do more exercises
and more practices tomorrow.
Okay? And I will of course, I will post
I will post all the tasks in the homework
in the course
announcement,
and God will be there on campus.
All right.
Thank you, guys. Good job, everyone.
I know right now, probably you
you'll give us a little bit
more of this that Please, please, please
make sure you guys,
you guys keep practicing. All right
okay.
Thank you, guys.
I'll see all of you tomorrow.
Okay.
Bye, everyone.