Right.
Good morning, beautiful people.
I like that.
Hey, good morning, guys.
Monday morning.
Happy Sunday to you guys.
Happy Halloween, right?
Hope you guys enjoy your time.
Yesterday didn't party too late, right?
All right, guys.
Morning. Good morning.
I need more people to join.
I don't see everyone join yet.
Okay. Okay.
Where they are, Where they are. Right.
All right.
Guess.
How are we doing, guys?
How was your Saturday day
short break from us?
Twisted.
Great.
You are here.
Syntax are me. I like that.
Brain hurts.
Well, we're going to try to not hurt
too much of today.
Or maybe it will be so deep.
I don't know.
Right. Okay.
I hope you guys all excited and ready.
Any plans for today, guys? Helping plan.
So you guys all did
your Halloween stuff yesterday.
Party Alexander to celebrate
Halloween in Ukraine.
Ahmet is partying with java.
Kids are high but not mad there Mama.
Mama will be hype next year.
She celebrated yesterday
so someone is okay.
I guess it's getting spread
pre country with the child.
That's good.
Well, so after the class today,
you still guys have time, right?
So whatever your plans are it sleep
repeat Hashem no parties for you.
That's good.
Okay. That's right.
So you guys are going to party next year
right after you get your job,
and then you guys will be celebrating it.
Okay? All right, guys.
So today, right as usual,
in the
well, it's okay.
You know, the way we say it's
very hard during the progress,
but then it becomes easier
and easier, right?
Okay. It
shouldn't be trying to
fall behind because if you guys
looking at the calendar, Right.
So now your favorite topic
will be going on now for every single day.
So you guys
will be learning a lot of stuff.
So you guys need to make sure you are
continuously put in efforts right.
Is still his candy.
This is
are you sure diligent?
No, I don't think so.
No, don't worry about if there is some,
because there will be some shift
in and it causes. No, no, no.
There is no schedule till June.
So there is a.
Okay.
No, no, no. Don't worry about those.
This I'll have to delete.
There's a few things
that we actually introducing guys
from the car and modeling to be introduced
in a few more classes starting our batch.
So that's why you see.
But we will go over it over
that, don't worry.
So you classes will be ending in
in beginning of March. Yep.
But anyway, if you guys see some schedule
that's there somewhere,
you see no classes or some timings.
Don't worry, we're going to fix it
as long as we are looking into October
and our November title looks good.
That's what's important, right?
Okay.
So sure of this
we will go quickly over the homework.
Right. So
today our topic will be
we will review the homework,
we will touch base on the recap
on our nested loops.
Right.
And then we will start with our amazing
another topic of Eric's right
because hours, the minute goes off,
the minute ours goes off. Yep.
There is a
so there's a lot of things that you you
you not a lot of things,
but there's a lot of condition
you need to think right when there an hour
and then I need to add something
and there's a minutes
I need to add something else. Right.
So that's what are we going to look.
So today is already class nine.
Class nine.
Okay,
so tell me, guys, what we were learning
yesterday.
We were looking into the next
that looks right here.
We're looking into the nested loops. Okay.
So we'll and continue and break you.
All right. Nested loops
and then continue and then breaks.
Right. Continue in quick. Okay.
So what is in this that look this
nested loop is loop inside
another loop, right?
Loop within that loop. Right.
So what we have we have one loop, right,
that we call an outer loop.
And then inside this loop
we can this another loop,
that's what we call it, a nested right.
So and as I was saying,
when it comes to the nesting guys,
we can, there's any type of loops right
we can before inside for it can be four
inside while it can be while inside, for
it can be different, different variations.
Right? Yep.
So and when we talk about the nested
loops, right when we talk,
when we talk about the nested
looks. Right.
So what, what did you guys do
on the button? This would look
so within that inner loop.
Always, always have a dependency, right?
Why it has a dependency Because inner
loop leaves inside your auto loop.
Right.
So but in order for you to enter
the outer, look, what do we have to check?
We have to check the condition. Right.
So we're saying our condition
always, always
has to be true, right?
Always, always has to be true. Right.
And in here. Right.
Oh, let me actually add
that we will do so system
that our the train line.
Right.
And let's say
morning
and here I'm going to see
look.
Right.
Okay so how many times am I going to say
good morning?
How many times
am I going to see hello, this
three times
in what, three times?
Six times.
Good morning. Hello.
Two times
two. Good morning.
Three hellos.
Hello.
Six times.
Hello. Six times
six. Hello three.
Good morning.
Hello.
Nine times.
Hello. Nine times six. Hello.
Good morning one time.
Okay, so let's see this right?
Let's see how many times
this condition is true. This
two times, right?
Two times one and two.
So this way.
Good morning.
Will be printed two times. Right.
So first time we are going to see.
Good morning. Right?
It will be printed one time.
It will be printed second time. Right.
So now what?
Before we go to print the good morning you
a java will look into this loop, right?
How many times
this condition will be true?
Three times, right?
Three times This condition will be true.
So it will print.
Hello. Hello.
Hello.
Right
then we will see. Good morning. Right.
So once it prints three hellos, right.
We said, Well, what
what happens after your G is equal to two.
Then when your J gets equals to three
condition becomes false.
Right? Then this will become false.
Your inner loop will be exited.
Then the your java sees
hello it or it brings good morning.
It goes back right?
And then you I guess increment
until two two is still less than three.
Condition is true
going inside while entering inside
and this cycle again repeats right.
This cycle again repeats.
So we are going to see
hello six times right.
And we going to see
good morning two times. Right?
We're going to see we morning to ten.
Okay.
So let me ask what about
what if I'll do it?
What if I did this?
How many times mail will get executed?
No, in a loop. Just say hello.
Good morning.
Is being a part of the outer
loop, right? Why?
Because this is where your inner loop
starts.
This where your inner look. It's
nothing.
Why? Nothing?
Because our outer loop
is a false condition.
Right? Of our loop is a false condition.
So when our loop gives a false condition,
we cannot enter inside.
So entire code, including your inner
loop, will be skipped.
Right?
Included because I is not more than three.
One is not more than three, I
think. All right.
That's how our nested loop
and of course we will look more.
Of course we'll look more
so now what is the bother?
Continue in break.
What did you guys
learn about continue in break
so what continue does right
it skips can't if the region right
or an integration
and moves to the next right
move to the beginning
move it move to the beginning.
We can put it this way.
Okay and what about break
break
exists right
Breaks the loop breaks the loop.
Right
Is it's right.
That's it. It breaks.
It breaks the block of it. Right.
Okay,
So now let's try different variations.
That's
I want to ask you what is going to happen
if I'm going to place this
on the class
new edge
on that since was that
last question
0909.
Because once we add the ten,
we want class ten,
then we want to make sure the class
is there correctly
40, 40.
And one thing what I'm going to ask you
this, I see some of you are sometimes
sending the questions
into support during class about replies.
Please, please
make sure you focus on on the screen.
Right.
Don't do any of during the class. Okay.
So just follow
the things that we are doing in here.
I'll type. Hello. Right.
I'll take a little. You
know, we're all
right.
Okay.
So if my condition is true,
if I'm going to run,
this was my previous code, right?
So what do we have said?
So allow us three times. Good morning.
One time.
Hello, three times,
and then the morning second.
Okay,
so now when we talk about the break
and in the in continue.
Right. So what are we saying?
Break breaks the loop. Right.
Break breaks the loop.
Okay.
So now what
do you guys think going to happen?
If I'm going to put the break in here,
I want you to pay attention on the line.
Okay.
So what will be the output this.
I'm on it. I'm. I didn't break. Remember,
there's break it.
So it's a very powerful keyword.
Yeah.
So what will happen?
Right.
If you go into debugging this,
what will happen right.
So initialization
first check in the condition.
Condition is true.
One inside our eyes initialize
of course, as soon as java enter inside
it sees another force so it knows that
it needs to repeat the cycle.
Right.
Initializing to zero
zero is still less than two.
Condition is true.
Okay.
Going inside so that little J was zero.
It printed one time. Hello. Right.
Or only one time. Hello.
Now Jigger increment
the tool one is going to print.
Hello again.
Now J is equal to two right
to what's still true.
Going to print again now after G was two
is going to incremental
three three will be not
less than two condition will be false
it exists our next at four then it sees
good morning right
then it says good one is going to print
and then Java sees a break.
Remember, guys, break
what it does, it breaks the loop, right?
So now where we define
the break would define it a break inside
our our loop right inside out.
So now let me ask you guys this.
What would be that?
What if I put the break in here
or do you guys think
now I change my break in that place
If inside my nested loop
three.
Hello to good morning
to Good morning
one. Hello one.
Good morning one.
Hello three.
Hello one.
Hello to Good morning one Hello.
Okay so are we agree to be okay
let's see one
Hello one
good morning one hello two good mornings.
Hello. Good morning. Hello. Good one.
Okay, let's see this again. Right.
So always, always analyze
before you in the you can run you guys
can analyze the code yourself right.
The initialization checking condition.
Condition is true.
Condition is true. I'm going inside.
Java enters inside.
It's another loop.
Okay, so for initialization condition.
Condition is true. I am going inside.
So what I'm going to do?
I'm going to print.
Hello. Then Java sees a break. Right?
So when Java sees a break, it's
breaking outside of the loop.
So would you like me to break in right
now, guys?
Which loop is it going to break?
It breaks this look right.
Word was defined, it breaks this nested
right, It breaks this inner loop.
So now it breaks it. It exists.
Now, when it exits
what it sees, it sees a good morning.
Right? Okay. It is a good morning.
Is there any break?
When we after good morning days.
No. Right.
Okay then.
Java can cannot stop the execution. No.
So what it will do?
It will go back right now.
I will get increment that it will
equal to two.
Two is still Lisbon.
Three condition is true.
Now again I'm going inside.
So what happens when I'm
going to go inside my inner loop?
What happens with my is
what happened with my nested loop.
My nested look resets, right?
It resets right Because like again,
being more right again, being born again
initialization condition.
Condition is true.
And when inside
like nothing happened before printing.
Hello.
Now your java C's break, right?
Jarvis break again.
What? It can break.
It can break only one block of code.
That's okay.
So which block of code was defined?
It was defined.
It was defined it inside
these nested loop.
Right.
So now it will see the break. Is it okay?
I got to get out.
It gets out.
And as soon as it gets out
it is good morning.
Right.
And then Java doesn't stab.
Java still goes back.
Only then it increments.
I becomes three Now when the condition
will be false, that's when it starts.
Right?
So now you guys see the way
the break works.
It does break the loop,
but it breaks the loop only inside
which it was defined, right?
So and then we say, in case of the nested
loop, it will bring that in.
It will break the inner loop, right?
It will break the inner little,
but it still will continue for our loop.
Right.
Good morning. Hello.
Good morning.
Okay.
Without a break here.
Without the break, it works as a regular
three times.
Hello.
Because condition choice
three times in here.
One good morning.
Right.
Then goes back again.
Hello. Three times one. Good morning.
But if you're are going to use a break
in here right then we are going to see.
Hello. Good morning.
Right or right or you said, hey,
if we're going to have a break in here,
then of course, because now break
is defined inside which block of code.
Now break. Define inside my auto loop.
Now, you guys just going to see three
halos. One.
Good morning.
Right behind those.
Okay, Well, let me do another example.
Maybe another example,
just to get our logic
right.
We don't want to have a four right
digit.
I think it might be equal to
one. Let's wait for the three plus.
Right.
And then side.
Well, I was going to say, I don't know.
I am for loop.
Let me take a variable right
in the oval range.
Morning equals fiction, right
now inside my inside
my for loop right inside my for loop.
I want to nest
I don't want to index my wire
while morning
thing
is all I want to see
at the moment.
Yeah. So now let's look at this.
Look this.
I want you to look at this loop.
That's what is going to be
the output of this loop.
Okay, so now what we see in here, right?
And you have a variable
that holds the value of.
True. Okay. Right.
You put the true in there.
Initialization condition is true.
What is the value of ise equals two one.
One is less than three.
Condition is true.
Yes, condition is true.
We are going inside.
Am I going to print this value?
I am for loop.
Right? Because it's just a statement.
If we did not place this statement
inside the any cycle of all of loop,
we did not put it inside
the conditional statement print in it.
Good.
Now as soon as I'm printed
in Dallas as well, what is it?
While it knows
it needs to repeat BLOCK of code?
As long as what?
As long as the condition is to my morning.
What is the value of morning days?
It's true, right?
And that is true.
So now, while that is true,
I am going inside.
I'm going to print.
Good morning.
After that, what happens, guys?
It needs to go back, right?
It goes back again.
Checks
the condition. Condition is still true.
And what is going to happen?
We are going to get one good one.
I am for loop and the rest,
what are we going to get?
Good morning.
We're going to get an infinite loop.
Well, because this condition holds
the value of true, right?
And in order for Java
to go back to the outlook,
it has to complete and number of cycles.
Remember,
a Java doesn't have a stub by itself.
Write what Java needs do say Java
needs to check the condition right now.
What do we get? We got one time.
I am for loop and then we got Good morning
Infinite infinite times.
Write infinite times what?
All right, let me
show you guys what's going to happen
if I'm going to add a break in here.
My in break I want to break my loop
because the code was running very,
very fast.
If you want to debug
because you going to see it and
nothing happened.
I don't know. I am for loop.
I am.
Good morning. One time.
So what's going to happen?
Well, nothing changes.
Why no change?
You guys?
Because in order for Java
to reach this break,
it has to exist this loop, right?
It has to exist this loop.
Only then Java would see a break now
because this loop is running
infinitely
so our break will never ever be reached.
Right?
Syntax wise is correct.
Price index by this point
would just because here we put a condition
that is always true.
That's why your java will never
come to that point. Right?
It's it's bathroom break
in this part so now right
I, I is equals to one condition is true
we print in I am for loop
we are printing them a for loop by
then you java enters
and less cycle of the good morning right
and they cannot break that cycle.
We cannot stop by itself
while because your condition
is always always true right.
So your java will never hit that right.
Like it will never hit that.
Okay.
So as I think for how do you ask before
if you going to put a break on top.
Right.
If you're going to put on break on top,
then your compiler
will give you the error.
Right?
So now you will
compiler will give you the error
which will tell you, hey,
you have unreachable code. Why?
Because compiler C is okay as soon as
you're going to enter the fourth body.
So you going to enter the full body
Java will see break now it will get out.
So these lines will never be reachable.
Right.
All right.
Let me ask guys this then.
What if all enter?
What if I enter break in here?
What will be that?
So what I will do, right?
What it will do right, It will print this
because this condition is true.
Three times
it will print that you will enter.
Good morning. It will bring. Good morning.
It is a break.
You will get out from where?
From this nested well, right?
It will get out from this list that well
and then once it out
there's no block of blood.
So it will go back
and then get incremented.
I I equals to to again
enter in the morning
print in one time he didn't break
you break in the wire loop
going back to the for loop condition
three correct third time
and then again entering the wild
seeing the break getting out of the while
going back to the four increments in
I three plus one will be four.
Four is not less than three.
When the condition becomes false,
your java cannot enter the cycle of four.
Right.
So what are we going to get right.
So are we going to get right?
So in here we got I for loop.
Good morning.
I am a foil.
I'm for loop. Good morning. I
say just good.
Just see different variations. Okay.
Let me ask you guys this.
You think this
think this.
I'm going to copy my first code. Right?
I'm going to copy my first code.
Copy my first code. Right.
So now the only thing
that's the only thing
instead of the break.
Instead of the break right here.
Up to the break.
And here we test with the break.
Okay.
So instead of the break,
what I would like to add,
I want to add continue.
Okay. It's that now
I'm not going to place it in here.
I am going to place it.
I need to
I need to e okay. I want to okay.
I need to e things.
One moment.
Let me do F in here.
He's g
equals to one, right?
Equals to one.
Then what I'm going to do, I'm going to
be okay.
Continue.
And let me start.
I'm changing the value of G to one this.
So this way to this things.
Okay, let me fix my lines.
So let me for my my right.
So now what I did I added the continuous
I added the continue
now let's analyze this.
I want you to analyze and
tell me what will be the output,
your hellos,
hellos.
Okay. Good morning.
Give me
don't run again is just doesn't
just try to look
try to look and try try to analyze
and you doesn't change
anything in here.
You continue It's a keyword
is it means something, right?
Do. Good morning one.
Hello.
Two hellos,
three good mornings.
Two, one, two.
Okay.
Two into.
Hello. Hello.
Good morning.
Okay. Hello.
Good morning. Hello.
Good morning to all of the men.
I can figure out two hellos. Okay.
Two into two hellos for Good morning.
Okay. One.
Hello, Two, one.
Good morning, One.
Okay.
I mean, of course
I saw the right answers already,
and now we will try to see you guys
likes it.
So the way the break
right break breaks the loop, but it breaks
the look with was defined, right.
So now when you think of the continue it's
gives the iteration, right?
It gives one iteration
but also iteration where this
which iteration
it will be skipping or continue
of the
in the loop right in the loop
where it was defined.
Right.
So now let's do analysis.
Always always guys just keep it, man.
All right. That's what I call it.
I equals to one.
We know I.
LISBON three Yes.
Going inside right.
While one inside J equals to one
condition is true.
Going inside. Right.
As soon as I enter it inside,
tell me this one which line?
My nested will and the minus
that for starts in word ends minus
the for
each bars on the line 39.
That's
where we open in the bracket. Right?
And then word is
43 now that the
the block of what for 43
is for the E blogger's 46.
That's
where my inner loop starts and ends.
Right. Okay.
So now once you see why you guys
also can see immediately for
this is where it starts,
this is where it goes right.
So this block of code, it's
the it's for the if this where it starts,
this is where it closes. Right. Okay.
So now going back, we said, hey J equals
211 is less than two,
condition is two going inside.
As soon as we entered our inner loop,
Java sees if condition
Java sees if condition here is equal
to one, yes, G equals to one.
So what your job I see is
the Java Sea is continue forward.
So what I continue means it says, hey,
ignore
right, skim
the current iteration and go back.
That's what I will do. Right.
It will go back.
Now, when the Java goes back,
what happens days when the Java goes back
increment.
So now J will get increment
till two checks.
Hey, is due less or equal than two years.
Condition is to go inside again.
Checking the condition eve right now.
Hey is two equals
two one No condition will be false.
Cannot enter my eve I am going to print.
Hello. Right.
I'm going to print.
Hello Then I am at the end of my
for loop right now it goes back
J is equals to three condition
three less than two.
No condition is false
and now you cannot enter the four block
right then what Your java sees you
Java sees Good morning right
then I think is good morning
It goes back right it goes back
now G will get the increment that you
Oh sorry I will get increment.
The two condition is true.
Two less than three. Right.
Go in inside
and then your cycle repeats again.
Right.
So then again when the j's equals to one
you going to skip that iteration.
But when the G is going to equal to two,
you're going to print Hello.
Right then G get incremented till three.
Three is not less than two.
Your inner set, your inner
loop will give you a false condition
java can enter and then it's going to see.
Good morning. Right.
Let's see what is debugging here.
No, they're in mine for loop.
Enter in my j loop right
now. Loop
is one value of gs, one is equals
to one is condition is true.
Java will go inside sees continue won't
it goes back to the beginning of the loop
but which loop inside the loop
in which it was defined?
It was defined continue right now
as the defined inside my for loop
right inside instead minus for it
goes back g gets incremented to
now if condition is false,
it cannot enter now with prints Hello.
Right.
And then goes back g giving increment
that three that is not less than two.
We cannot enter the inner loop
and then print in.
Good morning.
Going back now what will happen is
I will get incremented.
J That's it.
The cycle of G has ended right?
Then it goes back so I is equals to two.
And then a j again
is being given the new life, right?
And the equals to one.
And then the cycle repeats.
Prince Hello. Right. Good morning.
And then goes back.
Now I is equal to two
E will get incremental
till three condition will be false.
So your java is right.
So this way
what do we get? Hello. Good morning.
Hello. Good morning.
In this
case, it shows is is this in writing?
This gives the just shows the same.
But he does a different thing, right?
What does a different different things?
Q So this is just you see, guys,
I'm just trying to put those different,
different variations
in order for you to analyze
and to develop our watch right?
Okay.
So we go to is the continuing break
from a continual break
breaks the loop
or continuous to the night cycle.
But we then which loop inside the loop
whether we're declared
it breaks which loop inside
which it was declared.
Okay.
This needs a lot of practice.
Yeah this is
you guys can do it on your own.
Just, you know, try to throw throwing
different things in there.
Right.
And then by through,
by by drawing different different
variations, you guys will
be able to practice.
All right.
Any more of this, it's realized.
Quickly.
Go over all right,
and work with me.
See what I sent you.
I sent you the homework. Right.
Read numbers.
Rule 1 to 50.
Except those that I visit, visit divisible
by three.
What did you guys use
it? Go.
If I had shared the code. Right.
So you starting from one till 50
and then you throw an inside E, right?
You saying hey any time.
And number three. Right.
If it's there is no reminder then
continue.
Keep skipping. Right.
And then outside of that we will print in.
Okay, that's good
let's say create a program
that will ask user to apply
for credit card.
And as soon as user gets a
as soon as you get it
as a user,
then you should stop asking right.
Let me see. Right. So you see
it's now
apply for a credit card
and you keep contrary captured the answer.
Okay.
So different ways.
I see different ways it can be done right.
It's actually good. Farhad I see. I see.
I see your I see your code.
It looks very good. Right?
So you doing one action?
Hey, do want to apply for credit card?
You capturing the answer right right there
someone did is a while right.
Which is also good. Right.
So you're doing the while
and then you are using a break.
So remember, guys,
when it comes to programing, there's
always, always, always two ways
how it can be done, right?
How can we that so some of you want
we should do look right some
we would one is there will do
look some of you one with the while
but what you did
you use the break you use the break.
Okay right
good.
Now let's see.
Okay. What about number three, guys?
You needed to get that range
from a user, right?
So now instead of using an integer
are equals to one.
Now you want to use it to tell you
the starting point
and user to tell you the end point.
Let me see. So.
So now the only difference
what was happening, guys,
you needed a scanner, right?
You needed a scanner in here.
And the value is
that you are getting from this
scanner right?
The values
that you are getting from the scanner,
those values you were using to initialize
you loop.
Right. What is the starting point?
And a value of the end right now
will mean you were using to keep it
as your condition.
Right? You keep it as your conditional.
So for example,
if you are going to add there, hey,
I want the range from ten till 20
right then integer I equals to ten.
How far are we going to to
any or user could
enter from I don't know, 50 to 5000.
Right. So now we are not defining the
the starting point point
and any point in here.
So what are we doing
we defining it with the help of the user,
the values we capturing from the scanner.
Right. From the scan.
And then based on this range, Right.
If user enter from 10 to 20,
I want to calculate a
some of even or some of our numbers
from only that range.
If user enters from 55,000,
I want to calculate that French right.
Let's say please enter
the starting end point 20
and then let's say 30, right?
48 go.
So even numbers from range
12 to 30 is 150 and this 125.
Right.
So next time I want to enter from one to,
I don't know, 1000.
Right you go, it's automatically changes
and then calculate
the sum of even in the control
is the sum of all right
okay.
I see some of you guys actually did
very good.
I see.
I see some of you guys
through the condition right.
So MRC accord.
So what will happen?
That is what will happen.
Eve, Let's say
I'm going to enter the start point
higher than the end point.
What's going to happen this
F Will it be the error
based, not the syntax?
Why is this one
be error? Write this index.
Why is there one b error?
But what's going to happen?
We are not going to get an output right.
We are not going to get an output.
If you want, just say I equals to 20
and point is ten.
Right?
So now when you going to check
the condition, that condition is not true.
Right? That condition is not true. Right.
And I see some of you guys
you enter the eve, right?
Some of you entered if Hey, only Molly.
I'll do my for loop.
Eve right.
Eve my my start point.
Only in all if my start point is
less than my end point.
Right.
So when you throw that condition,
you can do that, right?
Some of you,
you guys swap right them are you.
You guys can do the swap.
So this, you guys can add
more and more solution do it right
just to add a simple, simple stuff.
Right.
I'm going to say, hey,
when I would like to do this,
when I want to do the calculation,
I want you do the calculation
only when my starting point
will be less than the end.
End point. Right.
Okay. Can I throw that if condition?
Yes, I can.
I want to say,
hey, I'll do this calculation if
my start is less than my end.
Right.
Only this condition is magic.
Then I'm going to open my bracket. Right?
Then I can calculate this
sum and I can finish it in here, right?
I can finish it in here and saying,
Hey, let me format my good.
I can say, Hey, all in.
Only if start less than the end.
I'll do this
loop, I'll find the calculation.
Otherwise I can see otherwise in here,
if you don't want to do anything,
I can enter this message
in here, writes it out.
We need
enter, start, point,
start.
Also the like that red message
start point.
There then and
then something like that.
So now if we want to put into debugging
right, if you want to put in debugging,
wasn't that this start out
entering by mistake ten
and I'm saying five,
right.
So no, I'll check.
Hey is the start is the ten
less than five?
No condition is false.
So now I'm going to skip
my entire loop and my entire calculation
and I'm good inside my else right.
I'm going to send my else and I'm going
to place their lives at their start point.
Less than that then the end point. Right?
And then don't do any loops.
Don't do any loops,
in which case I want to do the loops.
Only know Eve. Eve my
starting point,
which is three,
will be less than the end important.
Only that condition is much.
Then I'm going to do my loop right.
I'm going to do
the calculation of my loops and after
the calculation is finished, right,
only then I'm going to do this
print outs, right?
Otherwise there's no prints. Right?
Go with those.
Those things could have could be added
if some of you guys say
that you want to swap
maybe user by mistakes and three and five
if you guys want to swap,
you can try that variation as well.
Right.
Just different different a little
different more points to be adding.
Right.
All in 4:00.
Let's look at the clock.
So now
it equals less than nine.
If it was more than nine if our an hour
I see different different variations.
Let's see
the clock was crazy.
Let let me look guys.
Let me see. Okay.
I have Matthew one four.
One, two, three, four.
One, two, three, four loops.
I met you on four for loops, uh,
in JS equal less than nine.
And then if I.
I mean,
it doesn't give you the correct output
for the minutes and, and hours.
Okay. We can look at that. Okay.
That's Angelica.
You, are you statements in there.
Okay, that's good.
JS Less than ten. Less than ten.
Okay That's good.
Or do you want for three loops?
I see.
I like a
light
plus E
You need to look.
Okay, Ramani,
you want very similar is Angelique.
All right, let me copy this again.
Copy that.
Alexander,
you went for three nested loops.
Okay.
Simon,
You also one very similar to previous one.
Okay.
More of that for me.
Okay. Right.
So the same thing goes in here.
There could be
then different different variation.
Okay. There could be different variation.
Probably probably the easiest one if I'm
going to look right, if I'm going to look.
So the easiest one was four.
Let me copy this right.
What you guys said. Right.
So who defines the hours?
Hours were defined
by hours were defined by my outlook.
Right.
And then were defined by my inner loop
right in my inner loop.
So now the issue with this was
when I'm trying to print races for
if you guys were trying to print hours,
write hours,
and then concatenate
of clock
and plus minutes, this 1 hours
plus.
Right.
So now what
are we going to look at the output.
Right.
Our output was correct.
But that was correct.
One, we were having two digits, right?
2359 looks perfect
where output was not that pretty.
What?
We had a one digit in here when we had it.
One digit in here.
Right.
For the minutes
any time the minute is less than ten.
Right.
So when you time the minute this was that
and look me on this page and here you
so in
here right any time you send heat
any time is the minute right.
If the minute is less than ten. Right.
So we wanted to add it
leading zeros to it.
Right.
We wanted to add the leading zeros to it.
Leading zeros to it. Right.
That's one of the things. Right.
That's one of the things.
Okay.
So now let's see what else is in there.
The same thing.
Okay. The same thing. Hours, right?
If the minutes are less than ten,
then we looked.
I think that's the repetition.
Every wave minutes, less than ten.
We need to add the leading zeros right now
when we look also for the hours, right?
When the hours is less than ten.
So now where you want
to add the leading zeros
when the hours is less than ten, Right?
When the hours is less than ten.
Okay, cool. No problem. Right.
So that's what you guys need
to start thinking, right?
So, hey, what is the condition?
Is minute less than ten.
Then I want to add a leading zeros
to my minute.
Right.
If I was less than ten, then
I want to add the leading zero to my hours
and then just try different,
different variations in there.
Right?
Different variations. Okay, So let's see.
Let's see.
So what I can do, guys?
Right. What I can do.
Let me define one string this.
Can I define one string?
You let me define one string.
We define one string.
I'll define string.
I'm sprinkling.
Okay, So now we are saying,
hey, this approach, it works, right?
But I need to add zeros right now.
You just look, you just think of different
different variations.
Right?
So then what we said.
So first, let's fix the minutes.
Let's fix the minutes,
and then we will see you guys.
Remember, we started one by one right now.
Let me see the one you
okay, So I see.
Let me pick this right now
inside my nested for before printing.
I want to have a condition.
I'm saying, hey,
if the hour will be less than ten, right?
If the minute will be less than ten.
So what we want to add we want to add
a leading zeros before, right?
I want to add the zeros
to to my hours and I want to add the zeros
for my minutes right.
So in that condition will be true.
Right In that condition will be true.
Okay, let me change it to m.
Right.
So I'd say, hey,
if the hours is less than 10 minutes, less
less than ten,
then what will be my time
then I'll make my time equals, right?
So in
my time will equal.
I need to add a leading zeros. Right?
So zero
plus zero
plus my hour.
Right.
Then my
clock in here.
And I need to add the leading zeros
to my minutes.
Right. Plus zero.
Oops, sorry. In zero.
And then plus minutes
is. That makes sense.
That's what I did with my string. Right?
So now if it will come on here,
now I have to configure that time.
So I will add the hours less than ten.
I will add zero in here.
If the minute is less than ten,
I will let the zero in here.
Right?
I would like that zero in here.
So now there could be variations, right?
Hey, what if my hour is more than ten?
Can my hour be more than ten years?
My hour can be more than ten. Right?
My hour can be so but my minutes
still can be less than ten, right?
Even if my hour is more than ten,
my minute can be less than ten.
So if my hour is more than ten
and my minute is less than ten,
what do where do we need to add zeros?
Days.
If my hour is more than ten and my minute
is less than ten, we're doing,
what do we need to add?
The leading zeros.
What a minute. Right.
We don't need it any more for 2 hours
Now, is there another condition?
Yes, there's another something else
else. If. What could be the condition?
My hour could be more than ten.
And at the same time,
my minutes can be less than ten.
Right? Would be that the condition?
Yes. Could be that the condition.
If that will be the condition.
Let's consider my time.
Let's contribute my time.
So if I was more than ten,
I don't need meeting zeros anymore.
Right?
I don't need zeros.
My hour stays this way. Right?
Add where I need the leading zeros.
I need the leading zeros for my minute.
Right. So
if so now
that's one variation.
Right. So now guess what? If.
What if my hour is
less than ten,
but my minute is more than ten?
This variation
that now you look at this operation.
Hey, what is my hour is less than ten,
but minute, more than 10 hours.
Less than ten and minute is more than ten
is our clock should look
should we ask, is our code
going to look this way
or this way or different way?
Now, if the hour is
less than ten,
I need to add the leading zero in here
and I don't have to do this
the minute, right?
I don't have to do anything
with the minutes. Right.
So is there another condition to check?
Yes, there is another condition to check.
We can do else if right. Else. Even
if what?
Hour is less than ten.
And at the same time
my minute is more tense and.
Right.
If that's the case, what will be my time
In that case, this will be my time.
I am adding a leading zero to my hour.
Right?
I am adding a leading zero to my hour,
but I don't need to add the leading zero
to my minute.
Right.
So this way, if hours less than ten,
less than 10 minutes is more
than 10 minutes is more than ten.
I am adding leading zero to my hour
and nothing to the minute.
Right?
And if none of the conditions
are matching this
and none of the condition,
imagine what do we need?
This?
Well, if our ease is not of the condition,
imagine.
So. Do we need to add any zeros days?
Do we need to add any zeros
now? Right.
So we'll say, hey, if not in the condition
I'm watching, this is will be my time.
I'll just print our end minute
right now and me.
But now what are we doing this
my eve just configures my string.
Right.
So now once I consider my string, right,
once I configure my street,
let me add once it's out in here
and what I'm printing is
what am I printing?
After I define my FLC block
what I'm going to print,
Let me apply my time.
All right, So now let's do this.
Now let's see
logging.
So declare our our zero, right?
Declare oops already
hour and minute zeros.
Right. So now what is my condition?
Always Less than 10 minutes.
Less than ten.
Okay, I'm declaring my I'm
initializing my variable time.
Right.
All I did correct.
One moment this. I've got it
right.
This point
only setting
the hour is less than ten are in reading
zero student hour
and leading years to the minute like
hour 000.
I'm adding more zeros to my time
right here.
This block becomes true.
I'm initializing my variable time and once
I initialize it outside, I'm doing 1300.
That's what I get right?
Then what happens?
My minute will get incremented right,
my min and get increment.
And so this condition is still true.
So now I'm going to print 0001. Right?
And it will go all the way
until my minutes.
Right?
It will go all the way
until I reach minute or Valley of Ted.
Right.
So this right four
and then five, six, seven, eight,
nine.
So now as soon as my minute
is going to be ten, now my minute is ten.
So now hour is still zero,
but minute is ten, right?
So now my first block is not true.
Now one would hey, is my hour
more than ten, not hours.
Not more than ten.
Hey, is my hour less than ten?
This hour is less than ten.
Is the minute more than ten?
Okay, now, good point.
Oh, actually, no.
The condition is right
now is not becoming true.
Right.
So now I could go to the else. Right.
And then this is what we printed.
So what should we fix this?
My board should have gone in here.
My quads should have gone in here.
Right. But they did not go.
Was I still want to print zero.
I still want to print zero. Right.
I still want to print zero in here.
Because my minute right.
My minute can be more,
but because my hour is less.
Well, it's about equal sign.
Right? Let's add the equal sign.
So even right, even my hour
will be more than ten.
But let me include the ten as well. Right.
Then they will continue adding
zeros. Right.
So let me do again.
So we saw that it works
for everything till ten, right?
So now when your minute becomes
ten, Right.
So now this condition
false, this condition false.
Now, hey, our is less than ten years.
Our lives in ten minute is ten. Okay?
Now this condition is true.
I'm still adding
the leading zeros to my time
and now I'm printing it right now
again, zero zero ten.
Right. Okay.
And then this will work all the way
until my hour is less than ten.
Right?
Let me run
it is probably going to take me some time
it from here
or still going this way.
I can see good.
Okay, so now I'm going to 159.
So 59 359 450.
Now let me get to nine days. Okay.
Oh, it's already one two.
Let's
let me enter our right hours. 11
minute is 0 hours.
11 minutes is zero.
Hey, is our less than 10 hours,
not less than ten.
Hey, is our more than 10 hours
More than ten?
Because it's 11.
And now my minute by minute,
there's less than ten, right?
So now, because my hour is more than ten,
I'm just going to print my hour bottom.
Adding the leading minutes right now.
Again, oops.
Anyways, we got all of that.
That thing that printed too quickly, guys.
Yep. 11 zero zero. Right.
And then let me just run it
all the way in.
I think that's that's should be it.
Now let me check
here is correct
here is correct.
Nothing more important it will be
when we have hours and minutes right.
And okay so here's the issue guys.
Here are face the issue.
Look, my core is still not pretty.
My hour becomes two digits, right?
My hour becomes the digits. My, my.
But my minutes for the time
did not get printed.
What should I.
Six days
When my hour become ten, I'm not print.
I'm not adding
leading zeros to the minute.
So where should I add the equal guys?
Where should add the equal?
So for which block? Which blogger's
e block elseif elseif or else
on the line 17.
Right.
Hey, if the hour will be more than ten,
but not less.
I forgot to include less or equals.
That's where you want
or that's where you want our right ready.
So if the hour will be ten,
write more or equal than ten.
But minute is less than ten.
I still want to.
I'm leaving zero in here. Right.
And I think that was the only,
only mistake in here.
Everything else looks pretty
way to know.
Should look pretty. You again?
I'll meet you.
Have my ten.
Yep. They go now I get six. Right.
Ten 00010208.
I think.
All right, so then you guys just
I added more spaces just to for my my of
if you don't, you don't need to have
all these extra spaces in here.
Right. You guys are you.
Some of you just need to see
what's in there.
It's fine.
So here inside my few blocks
right inside my
if statement, I'm trying to configure
the string for my time.
And outside of what you block. Right.
Whether it falls inside,
if elseif elseif or else
I'm going to initialize my variable
and once my variable initialize
I am printing one time,
I am printing one time it.
That could be your one solution,
That could be your one solution.
This quarter, we want to push
it to the GitHub so you guys will see.
Right.
And I saw that guys, you guys, some of you
did it the little different way, right?
A little different way.
Some of you guys use that.
We three loops, right?
Let me see. Mari.
Let me okay, let me see.
Four, three, four, four, four.
Okay, so I'm on.
You won four for three lose,
but you still throw in this condition.
So I think, Oh, no,
you have to lose integer I
equals to you.
Okay.
I just don't think you need
the first initialization.
But the rest. The thing is this same.
Let me see. Alexander.
You did three loops.
Let me see how you guys did.
We copied this.
Let's see this out.
That on my for all
the way.
Right.
I'm just going to try to run it.
And if it's good, I'll keep it here.
If it's not, let's see if
it has any issues and you guys can fix it.
Right. Okay.
So I see some of you, you guys.
Well, or this is for loops.
Oh, okay. This is for loops. Okay.
So here you can control in
hours.
Two loops.
You control in hours with two loops.
You control minutes with more.
More inside loops. Right.
Let me see.
So if you check that, if everything looks
good, then you could have gone this way.
Well, okay,
so I think that's what I.
So here what are we seen in other student
he went right
using four different loops Right.
But in this case two loops
are controlling in our right
and two loops are controlling right
to control
in the middle.
Well, quiet, quiet is more clear.
Um, my, my guys, when I said yesterday,
when it comes to nested right
we are not going to try to nest
more than two loops.
Right.
But in this case I would say
the both code looks good.
If you guys asked me,
look what code looks good here.
You just throw in more if else blocks here
you just nested for loops.
Okay. Here you business and for loops.
Oh, let's see what code looks good, but
here you write this code
a little bit clean way.
Yes, we can write it
even a little bit cleaner.
We you want something, but
both of this code right now
giving you exact except the same output.
Okay.
What will make you cry?
Hey, I hope you guys did not cry too much.
Right? That too much.
Okay, I do.
I like this code as well too.
It's okay.
So, buddy,
you guys see different, different mindset.
You guys are thinking differently, right?
So thinking differently.
Well, that's what I want.
That's what, a home. Right. Okay.
Any questions for the nested loops?
This Any questions for the nested loops?
So stick on code 415 zero zero.
Let me see
what.
Oh, actually, sorry guys,
I even did not check.
This does not work completely. Does
this look? Does not work completely.
Let me see guys.
It has one twos, threes, fours.
Oh, okay, guys.
No, this doesn't work.
It does not work. Five
If that's going to work after five
this after five from 5 to 10
is missing from 5 to 10.
Admission mission hours.
I would not look at the minutes goes
minutes, minutes, minutes, minutes
That thing with good
Maria it does not have a clock again
after that from 15 to from 15 to 20
it doesn't going to have time
for this is the minute separate.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight, nine.
Okay.
It it mission the minute
ten, 11, 12, 13, 15, 19.
It missing the minute 20. Okay.
So this code, this code needs some work.
Okay.
This code needs somewhere.
This I did not look into all the details.
Okay.
Mission all it admission minute
1020, 30, 40.
Right it admission hours from after from
from five
till ten and admission hours from 1520.
Okay so there is some
if conditions you guys
probably need to drop when it goes 2459.
It shouldn't be going 2459 right
it should stop at 2359
and it's done
and it's then
okay, the mirror.
Let me see the now let me see.
We only
let me try to change
the first for
first.
Okay, so let me see guys.
So I changed the things in here.
Steps 2359 Well, I probably would suggest
you guys go and debug and see.
Okay. Now assistance.
Okay, that's good. As is 20. That's good.
22, 21, 20.
Okay. No, it's still guys.
Now it has the issue,
it stops at 1359, then it goes at 20.
Okay.
So in here you guys
you will still have to throw
some statements in there
if you want to go this way.
Okay.
Because I've seen students doing it
this way, but there's some conditions
you guys have to add.
So in probably the same thing
here it goes all the way to 359,
but then skips hours from four till ten.
Okay.
So if you guys want to look into this
so you guys can have it another way, but
please make work.
There's, there's
it could work with this week.
There's always this way
you just need to see in
which case you want to add
that is if if statements. Okay
so I'll keep this quote.
I'll keep this code, the one that works.
You guys can fix this code.
Hey, this can fix this one
or it was
just change second and fourth one.
So with this goodness.
So okay,
so this I'll give you guys as a homework.
I'll give you guys this is
this is a homework
you guys will just need to see
because this loop the first digit right
Our first digits can go only from zero
all the way till two.
Right?
Because when the hour hits 20
and whatever, this second loop
controls the second digit of the hour.
Right.
The second digit of the hour also goes
all the way, Also goes
all the way
till three and starts in starts from zero.
Right. So you guys just
will have to configure this thing.
This C controls
the first of the minute, right?
This second controls
the second digit of the minute.
Right.
So I guess I'll let you fix it, Right.
I'll let you fix it.
And then maybe in your review class,
maybe in your New Year review class,
you guys can
look at this code with
Sarsgaard But can it be fixed?
Yes, it can be fixed.
It can be fixed, but it can be easily
fixed for when you guys are debugging.
Okay.
All right.
So it's 1125.
Let's guys look at a couple more example
of the nested loops.
Right?
Well, what things we can do and then
you guys, we are going to move into them
and then we're going to move
into the Erased right?
So yesterday, right.
Yesterday, guys, I asked you
if some of you are interested.
Right.
So because when it comes to the the flip
you guys can do
very, very interesting things, right.
When it comes to the nested look,
What do you guys can do?
You guys can print different
different quadrants.
Right.
And when it comes to different
parties, right.
There can be crazy things you guys can can
friends, pyramids, reverse person
pyramids and different different
of triangles, different type of squares.
Right.
I'm just going to show you
very simple one,
very simple one in how to basically
think of those when you guys
trying to when you guys going to try
to print those press.
And as I mentioned, guys,
if you any of you interested
you guys can explore this options
a little bit more.
And the thing has got also in the review
class is going to look a little bit more.
Okay so guys, just hold with a little bit
with the break
and let me show you some things. Okay.
So ranging
in forms, for example.
Right?
For example, you know what?
If I want to print, right,
What if I want
you bring this square, right?
I want to print a square. Right.
That can see, let's say,
of course, stars, right?
Four stars, right.
I want to print this square
that consists of four stars.
Right?
So then what I can do right?
What I can do,
I can start printing stars, right?
For example,
I can put my loop right, I think before
and I think you do, I will do one right
and then I less or equal.
Let me make it equal.
Three, two, four times. Right.
One, two, three, four.
And then I plus, let's break
and then I can do
this or I'm going to print this stock.
Right?
But I'm going to not separate.
I'm going to print everything
in one line, right?
When you print everything in one way.
So now what I got, if I want to
add a little space, maybe a little space.
Right.
So now what I got I got four stars, right?
If I want to have five stars,
we can have five steps, right, to make it.
So now, if I want to make a square
like that, then what?
I would go.
I would have to go and put this loose.
Right?
I will have to go in for this.
Right.
You even without the loops, right? Oh,
okay.
No, not like that.
Let me create the new line before. Right.
So because you just print
after I finish my loop,
let me create the new line
after finish my loop.
Let me create a new line
after finish model.
Let me create a new line right
here.
What I got I got a square.
I did again. Esquire. Yes, I've got it.
But how many globes did it
take me to get this quarter?
It took me.
It took me
it took me some time to get this square.
Right.
So now easiest way.
Okay. Easiest way.
Guys to print this type of quarters
because sometimes it can be square.
Sometimes what we can get
there is besides a square,
we can get a triangles like that. Okay?
We can get triangles like that.
Or sometimes we can get a triangles
like that.
Pyramids, right?
We can get something. Pyramids like that.
So there is a different things
that we can print, right?
There's different things
that we can print.
Sometimes we can even print something like
this if we really really want
to. We really want we can print
something like this, right?
Different shapes,
different shapes in there.
We can print, right?
So now to print those shapes,
it's actually will be very easy.
Instead of using multiple independent
loops.
Right.
You have one loop in here, another
loop in here, another loop in here.
So now instead of having multiple,
multiple loops,
what we can do this weekend,
this type of part is we can print
using our nested loops,
using our initiative loops.
So now the way the logic of this
will be this, the way
the logic of this will be, okay,
maybe I should add five stars
to make it better look, but that's fine.
Actually, let me add one more.
So let me add one more star.
Yeah, one more story, one star, one.
Just to have a different look
has to have a distance.
Now, the way this type words can be
printed
is they can be printed
using our nested look.
Okay, so now we know that in this loop
we'll always have the outer loop
and we always have a inner loop, right?
So now when we look into this plot,
what do we see?
What we see? It consists of rows, right?
Remember, those rows always goes
horizontally, rows goes horizontally.
And then what we have we have a columns,
we have a columns, we have a constant.
Okay, so rows. This is my rows.
This is my columns.
Right This might come soon.
Okay, so now when we look in here, this.
How many rows do you guys see?
How many rows do we have?
How many rows
for one, two, three, four.
I have four rows.
Right.
How many columns?
I have?
I have five columns. Right.
One, two, three, four, five.
Right. I have five column. Okay.
So now how can I print a square
that will consist of four rows
and the five columns?
Okay, so remember this.
So what first comes first?
Always comes with a row, right?
First always comes in a row.
Think of it
like your in your excel. Right?
So first we have the row
then inside the row
we can have one, two, three, four,
five multiple columns.
Okay.
So now these photos can be easily printed
using our nested loops.
Okay.
So now our rows
will be controlled by our row loop.
Your columns will be controlled
by our inner loop. Why?
Because first, once we create their role.
Once we create the row,
then what do we have to do?
We have to own the same rule.
While row is one what we will be printing.
We will be printing five columns.
After we print
five columns, we're
moving to the next row, second row,
and then printing of our columns.
One, two, three, four, five.
Then moving to the third row
print in one, two, three, four, five,
and move into the fourth row printing.
One, two, three, five.
Okay, so while the column is still one,
I have a column while the row is one
and printing
column one column to column equal
for all in only one,
I completed my columns,
then I'm moving to the next row.
Right.
So when my cycle or my inner loop
ends, I'm going back incrementing my role.
My row becomes two.
And then while I'm on the second row,
I'm going to print one, two,
three, four, five columns.
Once the in the loop completes, I'm
going to increment,
my row becomes three,
and then my inner cycle repeats.
One, two, three, four, five.
Okay, so now let's see how we
can put opening that quote or
how we linked anymore.
So now let me remove this because we said
that this did not look good right?
So now we see.
So who controls my rows, my outer
look how many rows any to create.
I need to create four rows
right from row number one.
Then I need to create one.
Number two,
the new one would be the one number four.
So now we need to create five rows back.
Okay, so what?
How many specimens test for
here?
Let's make it so this way.
Know I'm going to start from the first row
how far I'm going
as long as I have four rows
and then are less flat.
Right
then what I have right then what I have.
I have five columns. Okay, sure.
So now I'm going to say four more
column equals to one,
and then I'm going to have one,
two, three or five columns.
That's columns
one be less or equal than five, Right.
And then what's right and then
now the only thing,
what are we are doing right.
The only thing, what we are doing,
we are printing our stars.
This is what are we doing?
We printing the columns. Right?
One, two, three, four, five.
So now, do you guys see if you print
in the columns all line by line or.
We printed them all in one line.
We print in the right.
Once you have a row, once
you on the first row, then
you have to print all five,
all five columns in line.
Right?
So now how do we print
everything in one line?
We just going to do
print is going to print
and then want to print
and then print in my first.
And let me add a little space between.
So this is the space, right?
And now this is what's going to happen.
Remember,
this are equals 211 less than four years.
Condition is true.
Now initialize in C and then I'm going
to print how many times my C is true this.
How many times my CS two
is right.
So then what is going to do?
Print one, two, three, four, five.
Then My inner loop will exit right
my inner loop.
Once my it prints five times,
it will exit.
So now when it exists, right then it goes
and then R gets incremented
and then C starts again.
Now I want to make sure that
when I go to the next row, right
before, after
I finish with my row one one,
I go to the my next door.
I want to create a new empty line right.
I want to create a new empty line.
And then again print all my columns on
and once as soon as I'm done,
let me create a new one.
Right.
Let me create a new line
so then I can print my columns.
Very, very nice and easy.
Okay,
so how do we create a new empty line?
This.
Let's do so.
So now, as soon as you done
printing columns before you
and let me create and July right now
let's see how it's going to work right?
Let's see how it's going to work.
So this condition is true.
Oops, Condition is true.
Condition is true.
Now I'm doing I am printing one star.
Right?
Then what happens is my C gets
incrementing, it, prints another start,
and then another start
and then another star.
And then one more star. Right.
So now after you see after
you see to five, right.
You can see my cursor is still here. Why?
Because I'm using print, right?
My cursor is still here.
Now my C will get incremented.
I am skipping my
nested for then I'm creating a new line.
Then this print create me a new line.
So now my question went to here.
Now my cursor went through here
and then cycle and here repeats.
Right. I'm printing a first star.
I'm printing the first star,
then the second star,
then the third star than the four star,
then the fifth star.
After I'm done with my nested loop,
right after I'm
done with my nested loop,
my cursor is here, right?
Because I'm doing prints.
Now what I'm going to do after I print
all my columns, I'm creating the new line.
Create a new line.
Now, my question was here.
My question is here.
And then again, I'm starting over.
I'm fringing all my columns
creating a line and then creating
print in all the columns. Right?
So then, all
right, this is how we can print, right?
So now what we got you got five rows
that for rows that were controlled
by your inner loop and now you got
five columns that were controlled by your
absurd outlook, controls
the rows in a loop, controls your column.
Right. So now, let me ask this.
What if I will ask you I want to ask you,
can you print
I'm going to ask you
all to
print
a square.
That square ten by ten.
I want it to have ten rose
and ten columns.
And what are you guys going to do? It
So now
so now, instead of having four rows, you
to have ten.
Instead of having five columns,
you want to have a ten columns, right?
So now what are you will do?
You will do the same thing, right?
You will do the same thing.
And now what you will do,
right?
So now for you're going to change the ten
from C,
we're going to change to ten, right?
So, hey, I want to have a ten rows,
a first row one's going to create on that
first row.
I'm going to print ten stars,
then I'm moving to the new line, right?
And then after I move to the new one,
this cycle will repeat
and then again create a new one for me.
Again, print ten stars.
New line for me. Right.
Okay, go.
So now what do you get that?
A square.
That is ten by ten, Right?
By ten.
So let me ask you guys, what if I know
a lot of right now, Are we good in here?
This I'm just going to show you
just a few.
So this way, you guys,
if you look somewhere so this way.
This is this is.
This makes sense, guys.
Okay, So
if some of
you is confused, just go see it right now.
And once again,
this is just to do more practice
with the nested
when it comes to our actual automation.
Of course, guys, our actual automation
is not to print stars and
and different different shapes.
This is just to develop our different
thinking.
Okay.
Okay. All right.
Let me look into this support,
because I think I think we have
I don't know.
Let me check on our support
because I know someone.
That's the question.
Okay, guys Let's take a break.
After break, I ask you a few
more questions and then we will move on.
Okay.
So one thing, that's what I'm going to do.
I'm going to push my code to the GitHub.
Okay?
So please have a look in there.
Have a look in there.
Meanwhile, I'll check, I'll check
someone's in the question in the support.
Okay?
Okay. This right.
So this podcast
once again guys, I just bring in
so this is an additional practice
for you to see how our loop works, right?
How our old works.
So another beautiful thing,
what we can guess what we can do
with this, right?
Besides just printing partners like this.
What if I want to pre in
something like that case,
you only can tell me.
I want you print a square of numbers.
Now I want you print one, two, three,
four, five.
That's what I want.
You print
What if I want to bring this square?
And now note of the stars.
Now I want to print this square over
numbers, right?
I want to bring the square over numbers.
Now, the logic will be
this same base case.
The logic will be the same
So how many be looking at how many rows
we're looking in here, guys,
We're still looking into how many rows.
Right.
Rows goes this way. One, two, three, four.
We still look on to the four rows right.
Four rows. And how many columns will
quite right
columns are still five columns are five.
Right.
So now all you guys have to define right.
So outlook controls.
Our gross rows are starting from one
going all the way to four.
And our plus, plus our plus plus.
Right.
And then inside what we have,
we have our nested four, right?
What we have, we have another nested four.
So now our nested four controls,
our columns write integers, C
equals integer, C equals to one, right.
And then going C less or equal than five.
Right. And then C++.
Now the part
you guys will have to figure out,
Hey, what am I printing?
Why am what?
I mean, what here
this rows goes horizontal, right?
This is run number one.
This is one. Number two, this one.
Number three,
this one. Number four columns.
How many columns?
One column.
Second column, Third column.
Fourth column.
Fifth column. Right.
Okay.
So now the only thing
what you have to figure out, right?
What are we printing?
Because
I need to print not just the stars.
Right. The way we did in here.
Look, printing just stars.
What I need to have instead of the stars,
I want to print numbers.
Right.
Okay, so now what I'm printing
while I am on the first roll,
I am printing one, two, three, four, five.
While I'm on the second row,
I am printing one, three, four, five.
Right.
So what are you guys think
we are printing in here?
If I'm printing one, two, three, four,
five.
Well, I'm printing the value of rows over
print, printing the value of columns.
Rows are the columns.
Rows, columns.
Okay, I don't want you to writing this.
Can you guys please don't run it.
I want.
I'm going to write the code
and then we will see right.
Awesome. More
right.
So here we see our loop controls the rows
and rows we have.
We have four rows and rows are increment
right? Or
here equals do
want to see less or equal than five.
Right.
And plus plus
here.
Now we have to define
what I'm thinking all in one line
and then we will have to define that all.
And then we're doing the same.
You in your right.
Okay, so now let's see.
Let's
let's see what I'm trying to print
when I'm printing.
I want you print
one two, three, four, five.
The new line starts.
I want you print one,
two, three, four, five.
New line start.
I want you print one,
two, three, four, five.
So now who control this?
Now is four. One, two, three, four, five.
Repeat Hadley on every single line.
So what we are printing, guys,
we are printing the columns right near
printing the columns.
So now if I'm going to print see there way
we start in our is equals to one, correct
or as equals to one
condition is true first,
then see is equals to one.
Right.
So now for a cycle,
I'm going to print one.
Then I am going back to see
gets incremented.
I am printing two, C gets incremented,
I'm going to print four,
then I'm going to print five.
Right now.
Once it becomes
six, condition will becomes false.
Am e exist in my inner loop.
While I'm exiting my inner loop,
I am creating a brand new line.
Right? Bring new line.
So my cursor moves here.
Write cursor is in here.
Now when I'm going back
R gets incremented, right?
R gives increment that RS to what happened
is our inner cycle,
our inner cycle resets, right?
So now it's again from the new line,
it will start one, two, three, four, five
when the columns are over
is going to create the brain.
You put the cursor in here and then again
you in a row previous right?
So now if you go to print,
see this is what we want to get right.
One, two, three, four, five.
Let me add a little space.
Okay.
It's already one, one,
two, three, four, five.
Okay, then. Now, let me ask you this.
What this thing will be the output.
If I'm going to put the R order,
this thing will be the output.
So now let's analyze it Now less RS one
valley C is one.
I am entering the loop. Right?
R equals to one.
So first time I am inside the inner loop.
I'm trying to print the value of
what is the value of r. This
one right?
I am going back.
The value of C is changing.
Now C becomes two,
but I'm still printing R.
What is the value of R one?
So now my inner loop will be true
five times it means five times.
I'm going to print 1111.
Right Then I'm exerting
my inner loop and creating a new line.
My cursor will be standing in here.
My my print will start from here.
I am going back R gets increment
that ah gets changed to two.
Right.
And then again I'm going inside my inner
loop.
Right.
And then my inner loop cycle resets.
It starts from one r what I'm
printing, I'm printing the r.
So at this time, what is the goal of R
now? The value of R is due
to 2 to 2, right?
And then they will go back and then we'll
print three, three, three three.
Right.
And then it will print four, four,
four, four. Why?
Because now what are we printing
a print in the value of four
or one.
One, two, two, three, three, four, four.
In this form,
this it's important to understand
Rowe's columns and the rest.
You just need to think.
Okay, if I'm printing, right,
I'm still on the first rule.
My role is not changing, right?
My role is not changing.
What is the change
in the value of my Colin's
change in one, two, three four, five.
Right.
When you look into this bottom, right,
if you want to print a part of,
I don't know, one, one one, two, two,
two, three, three, three.
Right.
And let's do well.
Four, four, four.
So how many roles in here this,
how many rows.
Rows equals two four
columns.
Columns equals to three. Right.
So now all the while I'm on the first row,
I'm continuously printing
one, one, one one, I'm on my second row,
I'm continuously printing 2 to 2.
When I'm on the third row, I'm
continuously printing three, three, three.
So what we printing in here guys,
we have printing rows, right?
We are printing the value of my row.
I'm on the first one.
That's why I'm printing one, one, one.
I'm on the second one, two, two, two.
I'm on the third one printing 3D.
Okay, let's guess what.
If I'm going to ask you, right.
That's very two less ones
I want to ask you now.
A triangle you guys will take a look.
Okay. Triangle.
I'm not going to show you a triangle.
You guys can look with that.
I'll give you maybe the last.
But let's see, it's 1213. Okay.
What if right now, guys,
instead of printing, Instead of printing
one, one, one, two, two, two,
three, three, three, four, four, four.
What if I want to print?
I want to print five,
five, five, five
or four
or or three, three, three, three,
and then choose.
And once.
Okay, so the same thing days how many rows
we have
five rows
by rows, How many columns we have
columns are for right columns.
We have four
now columns four.
Right.
So now just instead of going from the
lower to the higher,
we are starting higher.
Going lower. Right.
But still, what are we printing guys.
What are we printing.
Are we printing rows of it,
printing columns?
We're still printing rows.
The only thing there, rows goes right now
in the descending order.
Right.
So can you guys do this thing?
Can print it for me.
So you want to make sure you get five rows
and you want to make sure you
get four columns.
The only thing right now
rows you print in nor in the
nor in the increase from one, two, three,
four, five.
You print in it from five, four,
three, two, one
by two.
My can you run your loop.
Okay.
Like, you know, you need rows,
you know you need rows.
How many rows you need five. Right.
The only thing which you need,
you want to make sure
that rows goes from 5 to 1, right?
So it means what you're starting
point is five, right?
Your starting point is five.
What's your starting point?
What is my starting point?
My starting point in five. Right.
Or if you roll equals to five, I'm
starting from five.
I want to go all the way to one. Right?
I want to go all the way to one.
So from four one what happens?
We are from 4 to 1.
Are we incrementing
our discriminating dates
right from 4 to 1 for minus.
Minus.
Okay, so now you are saying, hey,
what I need, I need this condition
to be true five times.
Which operator you guys used?
I need to make sure my condition is true
five times
to make it true five times more or equal.
More or equal.
First them are equals
255 is more than one.
Decrement four is more than one.
Dickerman three more than one. Right.
Okay. Rows are good, right?
So now I need I need five.
Only four columns.
Do you care about the columns
that we print in columns?
Anywhere in here, guys, What we want.
Right.
So my columns can be whatever, right?
As long as I get how many problems?
As long as I get for columns,
As long as it gets
columns or, integers.
See if you want to be less
or equals than four.
Right.
And then C++.
And then when we say I want to print
all in one line
what I'm printed, I'm printing my rows,
I'm printing my rows enough to print rows
four times when creating a new one, I am
I go or we
get five, five, four,
four, three, three, two, two, one, one.
Right. So what happens? The same logic.
How many Rosa have one, two,
three or five.
Right. I need five rows.
The only thing my rows. Right.
I'm starting from the highest
to the lowest from 5 to 4.
What doing? I am discriminating right?
So now.
But I still need to create one,
two, three, four, five rows.
It means from 5 to 1.
I want to make sure my condition is true
five times.
How do I make make sure my conditions
to practice unusual are equal.
Right?
And then columns.
I don't care why I don't care.
I just want to make sure that I am able
to print one, two, three, four times.
Right.
I want to make sure
but that my either cycle repeated
one, two, three, four times. Right.
So that's why condition for inner cycle
two four times.
And then what?
I'm printed
on printing the value of R, right,
printing the value of books
going to the box here are RS five
five is more than one
condition is true when inside
C is one, C is less than four.
Yes, condition is true.
I am going inside
while I'm going to gain insight.
I'm thinking the value of R.
What is the value of R twice
going back C gives incremented.
Now C's equals to two
condition is still true.
Going inside printing another value of R.
What is the R? It's still five, right?
And then going again.
Now C will be equal to three condition
25 when increment C is equal to four,
condition is true,
but value of R is still life right now.
When the C becomes five,
condition is false.
We're existing.
So now our cursor moves to the new line.
Right?
And then you goes back
when your job goes back
in there, cycle resets, right?
And then R gives decrement
that now five minus one R become four.
Four is still more than one going
inside the loop.
Right.
As soon as I enter my r loop.
Right as soon there are a loop, I'm
seeing my for loop with this C variable.
Right. And then here cycle repeats.
Now going to print R, which is four
how many times
I'm going to print my R four times
y four times
because my inner loop gives me
a true condition four times.
Right?
And so.
All right. Can you show you could
and putting
my before you you were printing B
but you did not really print the b I
so I saw your quote somewhere
you didn't really need to be.
Okay.
So what you did in here,
you did the decrement, right?
You did the decrement.
So remember this in here for a C,
we can do it different ways, right?
I see.
What if I want to start C from ten again?
This time I c from ten days.
Mariam We're not, we're not printing line,
we just doing print.
I cannot start my C from ten.
Why not do
what is wrong for me starting from ten?
Okay, then how do I fix my condition
if I want my c to be ten
and then I get true.
So now what?
You guys have to remember, right?
How many columns
and then one, two, three, four.
And because in my situation
I am not printing columns,
but I'm not printing the variable variable
that refers to the columns,
I'm still creating four columns, right?
So it means I need my email loop
that controls my rows, right?
My inner loop control rows
and oh, sorry, control columns.
These are
unfolds right?
As long as make sure that my inner
loop is true four times, I'm okay.
I'm okay. Right.
Will it still work?
Yes, it's still work. Why?
Because I'm not printing C I'm printing R
So in your case, if you guys did,
if you started from four 1 to 1
and use the decrement, it's also fine.
It's also client, right?
Always saying what you to make sure
you're providing the right Operator.
So now if you want to start
from four going to one
using a decrement,
how do you want to make sure
that your condition is true four times?
Which operator is less or greater
or greater or equal
or equal rights.
So all it is right now
to make sure that your print statement
runs four times, that's okay.
And in order for print statement
to run four times,
you want to make sure you make condition
true four times.
Right?
So in this case,
we did not care about the columns, right.
We care that we need four times,
but whether we use increment or decrement
for my for my loop that controls
the columns, we did not really do.
Okay so in which situation we would care.
Girgis Give me a situation in which
I want to make sure
that my C goes in the increment.
Give me an example how if I'm going
to print, see how my quarter will look.
Right now, this is
if now
instead of the R, I'm going to print C,
how am I going to look like?
So I'm printing the value of see
what is the value of the first time this
or after that
it goes 3 to 1, right?
Going back our get decrement
and that's fine.
Our now becomes four.
Now you enter in the inner loop,
now your C resets and again
you went to print for 3 to 1 or three,
21432,
1432, one.
Let me copy this tube
so you guys will see the difference,
right
here.
I'm going to be right.
Okay.
It's actually
it's like
when I'm printing C, I'm getting four,
three, two, one, four, three, two,
one, four, three, two, one, four,
three, two, one, four, three, two, one.
When I'm printing rows.
Right. What. I'm printing them printing.
Five, five, four, four, three,
three, two, two, one, one. Okay.
With the, with, with this actual concept.
So you guys see
how you're actually in the loop
how your inner loop in our loop
relates to each other.
Right.
How your inner loop
has a dependency of the outer loop right.
How your inner loop repeats this cycle
until it completes
before it moves in here.
Here you also see in here
while I'm inside the inner
what happens with the variable of my R
and that my variable or my outlook
does not change, right? There's no change.
So this exercise, this once again
they there
just to build a logic, right
Just to build your
more practice, to build more practice,
to build more logic
when it comes to the nested to right.
So good way to practice them.
So just one thing is please, please,
please don't go too crazy
because the variation could be crazy,
right?
Because the variation could become crazy.
You can even print those.
How do you call this shape?
Right? There's a different type of shapes
you can print.
Okay, so all this will require
debugging
and analyze it in the first logic, right?
Then analyze it, then logic,
then debugging, right, then debugging.
But once again, don't go to crazy
guys, right?
Don't go too crazy y because this,
this things you are never going to use
in your daily life.
In your real life.
Right?
Once guys become an automation engineer
once again, this is strict
with strict
with strict with full practice.
So some of you get confused.
Guys try to go over it,
but try to go very simple once, right?
Try to go very simple once.
And then if you get an idea
how to print this square, right.
If you get an idea
of how to print a square
if you get an idea
how to print this values right.
How to print this values orders
more by learning
how to print these values.
Right?
Then that's what's in for.
That's what's important.
Let me actually copy these
and what I'm going to put in the column
so that see all different finds in here
that you
will see just by changing one
variable, outputs are different.
Right?
So what do you got in here?
You got all the ones
all the way to four here.
You got one, two, three, four, five.
One, two, three,
four, five. One, two, three, four, five.
Just by changing it.
Just by changing the printing
or one variable.
Okay. Triangle.
Yes. This.
You can do the triangles,
you can do more other stuff.
You guys can have fun with it
right in print and in the decrement
print in rows in the decrement,
printing columns
by Sebastian.
I think it happens to all of us
will happen.
All right.
Okay.
And you guys are going to have more prints
on repo.
And once again, with Asghar,
you guys go in.
He out, he will go over again,
those parties a little bit.
He probably will show the triangles.
And so this way you guys just can
continuously continue to practice.
Right?
By the one logic, always, always
remember this, whether it's a triangle,
whether it's reverse triangles,
square and numbers, whatever it is,
always look at it as a print in rows,
in all print in the columns.
Okay, So
any time you think of rows in the columns
or we need we need a nested nested
look will control your rows, right?
You will control your post
that goes in the horizontal way.
Right. Euros.
And there are so out of control your
your rows and the inner look will control
your columns.
Right will control your key.
And they are the difference.
Just which variable you're going to write.
Like in order to understand
which variable you're printing,
you just need to understand how the logic
your nested loop works, right?
So we know that inner loop
has to complete all cycles before it
exists and goes back and increments
the variable on the outer.
Look.
So very cool. Very, very fun stuff. Right?
If you guys, if you guys underspending
is probably fine.
If you're not underspending,
it's probably not too much fun.
But I hope at least you guys got an idea
at least how to print it,
how to print this course.
Okay,
so this will come with practice, right?
This will come as practice.
Okay.
Let me ask you guys who is confused?
Tell me who is confused in
on which loop in what
gives this output
or that output or this output?
Tell me guys,
I want to see who is confused
that I wanted to ask who is confused.
So to see.
Hopefully it will be less
good now.
So you forget.
So what I'm going to do guys,
my suggestion guys.
So I'm going to give you a of this pass
exact the same ones as we've done.
Okay.
My only suggestion guys, try to do them
after the class
without looking at the previous code
or maybe try to do them tomorrow
without looking at the class clock.
Right. And try to see try
try try to do it on your own
using your analysis in your logic.
And if you're able to do it on your own
after the class or tomorrow,
then you'll get
more attention.
You guys,
you guys have all the time in the world.
You guys have all the time in the world,
right?
Marianne So for a first for the first one,
you probably have some way of print,
right?
Let's see. You have screen, see
or because what happens?
Marianne If you look on your line 13,
look your line
13 one you trying to create a new line,
your line 13 is outside
of the nested loop.
You line 13 you put it in here.
So now if you put in here, right,
if you put it in in here
now for my chalkboard
always that's for my two code
now because your system that out
is outside of your loop.
That's
why it's not creating the line for you.
Right. This why is not created.
So you have to make sure it is inside
you are a loop, right?
It's at the end of your arrow.
Once you finish the row,
let me create a new line
with an extra.
You have to work after the class.
Well, try, try, try to squeeze. Right.
And I know guys, I keep reminding you,
but please, please, please
make sure right now
you guys are learning only Java, right?
Remember, you have to put 10 to 15 hours
on top of the classes.
If you just attending the classes,
doing the practice during the classes,
not going to work this,
you have to put time.
Okay. So every day, at least 1 to 2 hours.
If you cannot today,
make sure you put extra hour tomorrow
because next class and next week,
that's it.
You guys have all Java.
So there is no fun.
I mean, there is is still a fun. Right.
But in terms of there's no like testing.
There is no SDLC, Right.
So you will be all completely practical,
right?
So that's why please, please, please
make sure this 10 to 15 hours in,
you move in from Java guys,
once your selenium classes start,
then you will have to increase your time
more while you will have
to increase your time more.
Because besides Java,
a new concept is coming.
So then you guys have to make sure
you have a space in your brain
and you guys have time to study in
of that part right?
2 hours on top, outside of the class.
Outside of the class. Remember this?
That was our requirement
right when you joined because right now
requirement
is that you study 10 to 15 hours
outside of the time.
If that's includes your whole,
that's fine.
But just try to make sure
you practice all of it.
Because remember the concept art,
keep getting and more and more right
next week
you will be completely brand new concept
where you guys won't be touch in your
at the beginning,
you guys won't be touching their
and other stuff.
So you want to make sure you don't forget
you continuously practicing. Okay
well okay nice.
You have an issue with you
which try to close it and then reopen
it tried to close it and then we open.
All right.
Okay. This
and who want to teach selenium.
There will be different instructors, guys
that will be teaching your other topics.
Right.
Okay.
So one thing is,
when it comes to practicing websites,
it's a little bit I say
some of them are good, of them
are not that good. Why?
Because, look, whatever counts
when it comes to Java,
Java is a programing language.
Right? Then who is using this
language? Is a developer.
So some of those tasks
I'll share some of them guys.
But one thing I don't want you
to get scared because of
some of the exercises will be too complex.
They are because they are created
for developers, right?
And then in the days we are not trying
to become a developers, right?
We are testers, right?
We use in only this part of Java.
Don't need to learn all this
java that is in there. Right?
We just learning.
We learn in a good amount,
but we are not learning inside Java.
So that's why
when it comes to those different different
applications where you go, where you can
find, you know, those Java seminars,
some of them could be hard,
but I don't want you to scared them.
That's why what we do, guys, we teach,
we create our own ripple assignments.
So this way they match our curriculum.
In this way, we are there to practice
the skills that you need.
Okay, okay.
I'll share some of those.
And the one thing is try to also go
to some of the applications, right.
To try to go to some websites
when you just, you know,
Java tutorials, right.
And to those waiting
sometimes is also gives you a good right.
So I'm glad to meet you too.
Is that right?
W three schools, I know
they have a practice in there, right.
So for example here, right.
What are we learning?
We are learning a little control, right?
Little control.
So you go in here, he read in here,
try to look into the some assignments
and then try to do them as well.
I try to do them as well.
Well, there's Java. Okay, guys.
Yes. 50% of the time
your interviews will be made.
Okay. Maybe not 50, maybe 40%.
You in 30, you will be related to Java,
but there will be different concepts.
Okay. Will they ask you to code? Yes.
Sometimes they will ask you to go to.
Okay, so.
But trust me, guys, if you fall
in the class, if you fall in the class,
if you do know the whole works,
and if you are practicing, trust me, guys.
And then of the course you will be very,
very comfortable doing those assignments.
And on top of that, you guys will have us.
So we always provide a help.
Okay, Melanie,
you are missing your brackets.
You're missing your break.
Is this Please pay attention
where your break is.
That opens your code for oh, for
what is your break is where it opens
the code for a in there for loop.
You end in your statements.
We not ending the statement
after we define the condition.
Okay.
But usually the article by Novus,
it will be all mixed.
Okay?
It will be all mixed. And
our hardest to
do the testing all at the beginning.
Could be a little bit
depend on the company. Right.
But then you guys will get used to it.
Okay.
For me it was the hardest
part will be to get a job.
Once you land the job,
then then the part will be easy, guys.
Okay. All right.
But before they land the job,
we have to study, right?
We have to say.
Okay, So let me just
quickly repeat this part
when it comes to loops.
Right.
So in order for you to understand,
then this.
But look, of course,
what you guys have to make sure you guys
have to make sure that you understand
the concept of the basic right,
that you understand
the concept of the basic work.
And once you understand the concept,
when the logic of the basic loop,
then you can test one, two, three, four,
five loops.
You guys will be able to understand
no matter what, right?
So Luke once again goes the way for loop
initialization happens,
first condition happens.
Second, going inside, executing the code
after that we don't stop.
We go back and then we do the increment.
Right.
Then we do this increment
and then cycle repeats increment
check the condition going inside,
executing the code, going back
incrementing, checking the condition,
going back,
executing the block of spot right.
Can we do more to this?
We will have more exercise.
Maybe not for that.
Not or
not for what we called it
four quarters, right.
Because quarters
we just bring us just for a little fun.
Right.
So now when you add the nested loop,
a cycle is exact exactly the same, right?
Checking the condition, initializing,
checking the condition, going inside.
Now your job is another for initialize.
Check.
The condition Going inside
is an only condition is true.
Right?
Then this cycle repeats how many times
this cycle will repeat
based on your conditions.
How many times a value of j will be less
or equal than two three times right?
When the j equals three zero,
when the equals to one one equals two
three times.
So you in there
look will repeat this cycle three times
in only
and only then your java goes back to you.
Our look,
then the java goes to the
bridge to always, always remember
that logic is in place.
Please make sure you do a debugging.
Now we going to learn Java methods. Yes.
After you guys start learning. Oops.
Only then we learn all that fun stuff
about Joe.
Okay, this is just the beginning
as we learn in the basics, right?
This we're learning the basics,
which is common among
most of the programing languages, right?
And then when it comes to Java,
Java is an object oriented,
object oriented language, right?
So there's a concept that that stays
behind this object oriented programing.
There's some principles on which Java
has been built,
and those principles are important, right?
So those principles, guys,
from starting from Wednesday,
you guys or starting from
starting from
whether you guys will continue learning
after that for the next 2025 classes.
Okay. That concept is very amazing,
very interesting
and very beautiful concept.
Okay.
And then All right,
now when it comes to nested loops,
you guys all,
when it comes to us that loops,
we will give you guys more ripple.
It will give more ripple.
All the tasks we have done.
And I will ask you guys
to repeat all this part
and I'll send you them as a homework.
And once again, this.
Please don't look at this
and the solutions
look only only in the questions
and try to do them.
Okay?
If we on which level we will learn
Java or you will learn a very,
very good amount of Java.
This you will be with starting is basics.
You will be learning main oops concept
and then we will be learning advanced
concepts of Java, how to read our
How to read Excel files,
how to do different, different stuff.
Okay, so you guys trust me that you will
learn a lot when it comes to Java.
You guys will be very, very strong. Okay,
This is we call them basics.
I will call them.
Maybe it's not the right word.
You call the basics, but this is basics.
Why we call it because these basics exist
in every programing language, right?
And this is basics.
And oops, they will be completely two
different parts.
Okay, So here
we deal with variables and we deal with
if conditions and all that stuff.
When it comes to ops, you guys
will be dealing with something different.
Is this object.
There's a classes, there's a net does
there's a different principles
and they are different.
They are different. Okay.
So some students find
oops concept easier compared to what
they learned The beginning
actually majority of the students, that's
what they find it is.
Okay.
So you guys will tell me.
You guys will tell me.
All right.
So today, our main topic,
that's what I would like to start
and this is one of the last topics
that we guys will be covering
when it comes to learning together is our
if conditions
and loops and all that part,
we will be looking into a race.
We will be looking our race,
right.
So before we move into the objects
and classes
and all the strings
and all, all other other different stuff,
this is one of the last stuff
that we're going to look
and there's a different variations over
it's fake.
So now I ask you guys yesterday
to take a look at their race.
What did you guys love?
What did you guys learn about a race
dominance?
I want to know what you learn.
Besides that, they have fun, right?
I say, okay, erase this same data type.
Okay.
It can hold values of same data type.
Election of similar narrative.
That's it. That's a good point.
Great.
Cause the same type of elements
look similar to this by using a case
using the
now we will bring our square brackets
right.
Okay.
What else?
What else did you guys learn?
You guys should go. Look.
It will be used in square brackets.
Okay?
It's it will it technically a variable
that will allow us to store
multiple values inside?
Okay, that's good.
So busy with clock.
It has a size. Okay, that's good.
It has a size where we call.
We will call let. Okay.
All right, let me look.
So arrays in jump. Right.
So whenever we just started
with our Java, right?
Whenever we just started with Java.
Let me see class.
Sorry.
Oh, array store to use multiple values
in this single variable,
they go instead of declaring as separate
variables.
That's right
So what do we learn? This, right?
We learn that, hey, in Java
we have variables, right?
In Java we have variables. Yep.
Inside the arrays, of course,
there has to be a particular location
of have to sign right now.
Inside one variable
we learned that we can hold.
We can store one value, right?
That we can store one value.
So we said, Hey, I cannot store ten and
then the live one and then 12 and then 13.
I cannot store all this values
inside one variable.
Right? So what do we say?
One variable, One single variable
can hold only one single now, Right?
That's what we already know.
So now there could be a situation.
Think of the situation
that's for example, right?
For example.
Now I have all of you right now,
for example, let's think of the scenario.
Let's let's think of the scenario where,
for example, what I have to do,
I have to calculate you race, right?
I have to calculate
where was your joke was one.
Let's say I have to calculate your all
your grades, right?
I want to calculate the average.
I want to see how you guys are doing
right.
I want to see how you guys are doing.
So now what I will have to do,
I have to store the value
right of student, right?
The score of each student I have to store.
And then in order for me
to find the average,
what I will have to do,
I will have to add all of it
and then divide it
by the number of people. Right?
So now think, okay, guys,
how many variables I would have to create?
I will have to create one, two,
three, four.
I will have to create a thousand
tons of variables.
Right?
So now first 50 lines of code will just
consist of me declaring the variables
and storing the values.
Right now
it cannot work.
Yes, it can work.
What now?
Java gives us a better approach.
Better approach, right?
So now, when it comes to storing
your grades, right.
40, 13, 14, 13, 15, 11, eight.
So now they are integer type of values,
right?
They are integer type of values that.
I'm storing inside different variables.
Now, Java is he whenever you have
this same type of values, my in my case
it will be integer.
Right. Okay.
Whenever you have the same type of values,
what are you can do?
You can store them inside one variable
and this variable
will be a very huge container.
It will be a very huge container.
So now how do we how we will
be able to now
how can this store ten, 12, 13, 14, eight.
Right. All of those.
And now Java gives us a concept of a race.
Right. So if we're going to look
at this point, we're going to look.
So now before this is my variable, right
this material of integer null
and it has a it takes this phase, right?
So it was holding value of ten, right.
One variable, Right.
One variable and one value.
Right. One variable
that holds want value. Right.
What is the value ten?
What is the name of my variable Numb.
What type of L equals integer?
Hey now it would be great.
Hey, what I have now inside one
variable, right?
What if inside one variable I'm one.
Let me make it a little bit bigger.
Hey now I think it would be cool
if inside one of you are able.
Right?
I get inside, I can store these values,
I can store ten
and then we so 12, 13 and then maybe 14.
And let me bring maybe one more in here.
I don't think 12 right here.
It would be cool
if I can have one container
in which I can store all this
values will be pretty, pretty cool, right?
Will be pretty cool.
Okay, so now is this possible in Java?
Yes, it is possible.
How is it possible it passed a book
with the help of arrays, right?
With the help of arrays.
So now how am I going to define that?
This variable now, when you look right
now, when you look in here and
now when we look in here,
ready one
when you look in here, this is a variable
that holds single value.
Now, this variable
that holds multiple values, right?
But those values of which type,
those values are still
of the integer type, right Integer type.
Now, the same thing.
I have to give a name for my variable,
right?
The role of the variable.
You have to give me the name
and then tell me what are your story.
Right? So now I can say integer.
All right, so now what?
I'm just going to click on create this
and say integer are equals to 12.
Then 1314 my Java is going to complain.
My compiler will give me the error.
Now how do I identify?
I have a collection of values
inside this variable.
We have to specify that it's in there,
right?
To specify that you're variable holds
array or integer.
We will add the square bracket.
We will add the square brackets.
And now as soon as you going to add
the square brackets, your java is fine.
So now your java knows, okay,
you have a variable
which is a are this variable
a numbers integer type of values.
But what it holds,
it holds in the way it holds a collection
of those integer type of values.
Now, when you think of,
think of it as when you guys
are going to take a big box, right?
So now before you store only value,
you can easily access it
right When you store one thing.
Now think there will be a big box and you
going to throw many things inside, right?
It's going, no, no, no.
Remember,
the variable can be any, any, any name.
Any name.
Right. Any name.
So that's why I just named Air. Okay.
So now when you think of the big variable
and the one
you want to draw, just everything
like that, it will be a mess.
It will be a mess.
Then How can you find something
that you throw in there?
Right?
So if there is no order, then
there will be a big issue in Java says,
Hey, no problem, I'll give you a variable
in which you can store multiple values.
You want to store ten values inside.
That will probably want to store 20.
They'll probably want to store 1000,
no problem.
But Java says, Hey, you know,
how am I going to store those values?
Because The purpose of the variable
we store in the values
and then we want to access them, right?
So in order for you
to be easy to access them,
they have to be stored in order, right?
They have to be stored in order.
So now which order
we are following in here, the way array
the array stores, the data, it's storage,
the data based on the images.
Right. Based on the indexes.
So now indexes in Java, okay.
In those
indexes
is Java always always starts from zero.
Okay.
So now the way Java will say, okay,
this is my variable inside here.
Now you throw four values.
Now how they will be put.
So now what I'm going to say,
hey inside the variable, right,
with the index zero
inside the variable. Right.
So now what you have, it's like you,
you guys have your draw, right?
You guys have you draw inside the draw.
You have those multiple,
multiple boxes inside, Right.
So how you call this, Right.
So now you know what
you put the first one second one third,
one fourth, one fifth one,
but it's still one draw, right?
Is still one. Right.
So the same thing in here.
What do you have? Hey,
I have a big cabinets right.
I have a big cabinets.
Now, inside my first one,
I stored about 12.
Inside my second one I stored it
value of ten inside
my third one are stored it.
Whoops,
it inside my door, one
that's stored at 13 inside my fourth one,
I store 14.
Right.
So now, basically now
when you have this big box, what happened?
This big box is being split
it into small parts, right?
And small parts small boxes inside.
Right.
So now how those values, those are stored
in the organized matter, because
they won't be in the organized because
there's no way you can access them.
Right.
So how they store the store
in the form of indexes,
any programing language you go guys
indexes always start from zero.
Okay, indexes start from zero.
So now
in my variable
with the index zero,
now I stored the value 12
inside my variable with the index one
I store the value of ten
inside my variable with the index.
Two I stored the value of the value of 13
and my variable with the index.
Three are stored value of 14.
Okay, so now what?
I'm evil, I'm able to store inside
my variable eight
are able to store
an array of integer values. Right?
I store 12, ten, 13, 14.
So what I'm storing,
I'm storing integer values.
So those values, these values
guys in Java,
we call them elements
elements.
So now we are sitting here.
My variable array consists
of how many elements this
how many elements I have
four elements.
Right?
So now we're saying,
Hey, what is the size of my array?
Size of my array conceives stuff
or elements?
Okay, what elements?
And there are elements
of all the elements of this same type
always arrays allow us to have elements
of the same types.
Right.
And how do you know?
Here, you see, I have an array of what?
What's integer values.
Right.
Okay.
Are maybe okay, but majority majority
of others guys, they do start from zero.
Okay.
Programmers, they live in different
worlds, especially from zero.
Right. Okay.
So now let's see.
How are we going to take it in coding?
Okay, let's see,
how are we going to take it?
So now here we said one variable.
One variable holds one value.
Now I want to create an array variable,
right?
I want to create an array.
So this same thing where we start,
we start with sun
variable name.
Then what type of values want to store?
I want to store integer type of values,
but I don't want to store
just one integer.
I want to store every integers. Right?
So all you need to specify
era when teachers.
Now when it comes to the arrays,
when it comes to the array
arrays, we call them,
they are six in size.
So when we are creating in the array.
So you guys will have to specify new
and then each year new,
you guys will learn as you guys see new.
It's a keyword, right? New It's a keyword.
So there's something is getting created
which you guys are doing in the
following classes.
So now inside here I have to specify, Hey,
I am creating an array of integer values,
array of integer values
that I'm trying store inside this box
right now.
When you are creating an array,
you guys have to specify the size, right?
You guys have to specify this size.
So what was our size?
This is how many elements we try to store.
We try to store four elements.
We try to store four elements, right?
So now what will happen
this will happen there in the Java memory.
What will happen there is this container.
This container will get created.
And what will have
it will have four spaces.
It'll have for space.
Empty container is there and right.
So now you store the elements.
Right now we're going to store exactly
the same elements.
What we start 12, ten, 13, 14. Right.
So now we can just say right now
array equals to 12, right? Why?
Because now this is a variable
that holds in the right or integer values.
Now you have to specify, Hey value.
12 I want to store with the index zero
right value ten.
I want to store with the index one.
So yes, if you need ten elements,
you store ten elements, if you need four.
So here we always put
how many elements, right?
And we humans start counting one, right?
How many elements I want.
I want one, two, three, four elements.
Right. We are humans counting from one.
But when it comes to indexes, right
how Jacqui's going to store it right?
How Joe is going to store it.
Joe needs to store it
in the form of index.
Right?
So notice in his the value 12 will go to
array is the index zero. Yep.
And then array
with the index one right
area is the index.
One will hold a value of ten. Right.
So hold the value of this
now array
or with the index to
hold the value of 1313
and then array with the index three.
Right. Hold the value of 14. Right.
So now how many elements did we store?
We said we want to store four.
So we need one, two, three, four.
We store four elements of the integer type
inside my variable array,
right inside the right.
But how we were able to store them,
you were able to store them on the index.
This index is tight from 01230123.
So now
let's see.
We can we can try the scanner in here
and then we can
we will draw all these conditions.
Right.
So now remember, this is the way we store
values inside the variable.
Then we are trying to access them.
Right then we were trying to extend them.
In here, for example,
you access my value at ten.
I was just printing none, right?
I was just printing them.
What if other variations
be the little guys?
What if I'm not going to follow the order?
What if I'm going to add more?
What if I'm going to
unless we will look into that.
Okay, so now variable a single
variable stores
a single value to access the value.
Inside this variable,
we just referring to the
we were just referring
to the variable, right?
So now if you are storing elements,
if you are storing elements
based on the indexes now you can access
a values also based on indexes.
Tell me that is, if I want you print 13,
I want you print 13.
What should I specify?
The in the case?
I want you access the value
13 where the value 13
will store it will store inside.
Might arrange the index. Two okay,
thank You right
now I have 13, right?
That's what I have.
I have 13
lines in here. So
I mean from single
13, right.
Okay.
So remember, guys, what are this
thing will happen if I'll do this
array two plus every
two or zero.
What do you guys think will be the output?
What will happen?
So when we work with variables, guys,
we work with these values inside.
What is it now?
Inside array to the valley inside
array to its 13.
What is the value inside?
Inside array zero zero is 12 right?
So I have integer valid,
I have integer value 12.
Now I'm using
plus plus between two numbers
works as an archetype
operator works as an arithmetic operator.
You go 2524 right.
So arrays, right arrays are
the container that holds
values
of what values of same type analysis
I now look at as
if I'm going to try to do 1499.
So now what will happen?
Your compiler will give you the error.
Compiler will tell you, Hey,
I cannot count the word
from the table into the integer.
Right? Why?
Because in here
when you were just creating you array,
you said, Hey, I have a variable
that will be whole array, right?
A variable?
It's array variable that holds
what are holds integer type of values.
So Java, remember, is very strict, right?
Java.
Say, hey,
if you told me you want to store integer,
make sure store only integers right.
Make sure you still only integer
tackle values don't store double.
Can you do the question?
Yes, of course
we can do the question. Right.
So if I want to do the question
for the integer,
how are you guys going to do it?
This is just just just to recap, right?
So what you will do,
you'll say, hey, to which you mean
to which data type you want.
You can write.
I want you convert to the integer, right?
I want you to the integer.
Now, if I'm going to print
an array
is being three, what will be output
will be 14 different.
Right.
So what we're saying hey Right.
That's what I was saying,
that Arrays are collection
of values of fruit, of the same type.
Right. I'm not going to keep it in here.
So not to confuse, you know that
they can hold primitive and non primitive.
And of course you guys will learn once
you start learning non primitive,
then you guys will be able
to add it inside the array. Get
that in there. Right. Okay.
So this is was area what this is
was an array of integer values.
Right. This was array of the integer.
So now.
Okay guys, let's say so let's see.
That's a good question, guys.
So what if I want
I need to create an array
that will hold
the elements.
Elements, all of
that type of values, right?
That will tackle those.
So now what I want to store, I want to
store elements in is the decimals, Right?
Okay.
So now I need to have a variable, right?
I need to have a variable.
And when I'm making the enemy,
it can be any name, right?
So if you go in from
if you want to, let's say
under that name, it's
I don't know, for example.
Right.
So now this variable,
I want it to be a variable
that will hold
integer type of values up.
So sorry array,
but array of error, double,
double, double figure.
So now array of double check of values.
What is the name of my variable eight
R And I want to store three elements.
How can I want to store
three elements or double of those
equals new?
And then what?
You double right?
And then how many elements?
Three elements.
Elements.
The now how are we going to place them?
Three We always do.
So we always specify the size
three element.
We have the name.
Okay, so how are we going?
So we're sending you take a variable.
Now, this variable will have indexes
the in the zero
and whichever value one right 11 9999
and then array is the index one
will hold the value of 109
something in the array
with the index
two four hold the value of 3081.
Okay. All right.
So let me ask you this. Right.
So what do you guys think?
Can they replace
in replace
now live from an array
or is I can.
Right. I guess it's a variable, right?
So when we say say a variable, it's
a temporary placeholder.
Right.
So now, for example, hey, instead of
one or nine, I want to have 199.
I want to have 199.
How can I replace the guys?
How can I replace it
four instead of one or nine?
I want to have 199
we just reassign.
And how are we going to reassigning this
option now?
Is it okay where you want to store 199?
I want to store it inside
array with the index one.
Right.
So erase the index air.
Right. Meet the next one.
So now what will happen? Right.
So let's see what happens in this line
that that will have
three spaces will get created.
Right now
container with the three spaces.
Right.
You say because you said you store
you want to store three elements.
That's why you will get two spaces
for elements, right?
That's why we're saying that the
arrays, they are fixed in size.
You told me how many element. That's it.
That's
how many elements you want to store.
1199 will go in here.
One or nine will go inside here
and then three or nine will go in here.
Right.
So now you're saying, hey,
instead of one or nine, right,
I want have 299, no problem.
So what do you do?
You reassign so you will throw away
one or nine and you will place 199.
Right. So
let me check it for
now. Say you're right with the next one.
Then let's see what will be the
factors change.
And now we
open mega
and go after changing all of the elements.
And now what we got, we got 190, right?
100 and
so now let me ask you guys this.
Let me ask you this.
Okay?
I want to create I want to create
an array
that will store
colors,
that will store colors,
let's say how many colors I want that.
Just go for colors. Okay.
So now it will be an array of what
this tells me. Yes.
Now we will look into different
variations.
It's a stream, right?
So now what I have
I have an array of strings, Right?
And now what I'm trying to sell.
I'm trying to store colors. Okay.
And then what are we
going to type in? Here goes
new. New what?
New strength.
And then what I'm going to see.
So how many elements
or how many elements for.
Okay.
And now let's say
I'm going to store colors, right?
So with that in zero, right.
I'm going to store, let's say a
red and then colors with the index one.
I'm going to store a blue, Right.
And then colors with the index too, right?
Sure.
We store black and then right.
And then in here, let's store
colors with the index three.
I am going to score.
I don't know, yellow. Right. For example.
For example right now what I scored
I store for elements
of which type of the string type.
Right.
So how am I able to store
by identifying that?
Now I have array of strings, right?
The strings.
Okay, so now what will happen?
What will happen, Eve? Let's see.
Now, when I'm trying
to print
or even not trying to print right?
So let's say what will happen
if I go colors with
or equal to green, right?
Equals to green.
So my compiler is fine.
Oh, look at this. My compiler is fine.
Why am I compiler?
It's fine because my compiler checks
the syntax.
Syntax is correct.
Okay.
They declared an array of strings
they said they will be storing
four elements.
Did this store them correctly?
Is the store incorrectly right?
This sort of correctly
compiler does not give you any issue.
So now only when I'm going to try
to run my code,
I'm trying to run my code this.
So now when
I'm going to try to run my code now,
during run,
while Java was running our program,
our run into some issue,
a double ranking system.
So now it's important days.
So maybe from couple of classes
from now on, you guys will start
receiving this type of issue
and it's important to read them right.
So always read right.
So what is this?
This array interest array that enjoy
What is this based?
It's a name of our class. Right.
Array intro.
That's the name of my class.
It says, Hey, inside your class
on the line 43, you have the issue, right?
So all you see for this and as you can
just click in the array that you issue
got highlighted right
so always know where you issue comes
you issue comes on the line 43.
Now what is the issue?
Issue error
array index are one exception, right?
So it says hey
that you went out of the index
try to use the index four
which was out of bounds.
Right.
So basically
what happened right when you told Java.
Right.
Java was executed,
you put that to the bar.
Remember this line, what it happens,
it gives you a container
that has these four, four elements right?
So it store right in here,
one blue in here,
black in here, yellow in there right now.
You give it four spaces.
Now on the line, 43.
All of the sudden you said, Hey, Java,
can you add one more thing
and store green in there? No.
So now what is happening right now?
What is happening?
We're getting index
out of one exception. Why?
Because when you created a container
when you created
the container was four spaces.
That's what I guess
that's what Java your Java user,
your Java cannot while writing
look what all they need is a value.
Let me expanded all.
Let me know if you'd say
that you need four spaces.
I'll give you four spaces.
I will give you the four spaces.
So that's why in here
where you guys will get
you will get it right in the I don't want
that's what you guys will get.
If you guys going to repeat this right
now, it's
an exception you guys will get right
and I just get we can say exception
you guys will don't want an exception.
Right? So let's see
followed by
four. Right.
The same thing
when you say, hey, you want to
I want to access the value from the index
for right now same thing
pre represents what are we going to go
we will look into it right okay
so now we're trying to look what happens
if we do over what happens if we do over.
So let's say you don't want to store
you didn't want to store,
but now when you print out,
when you print out, what do you say?
Hey, I want to access the element
with the index for syntax is correct.
Compiler is headed by the same thing.
What happens when you execute in your code
right?
Java executed this line perfectly
because they work fine.
But then on which one on the line 45.
Right on the line
45 where the issue is you trying to access
element.
Why are you trying to tell me
that there is an index four which is not.
That's
why you get index out of one exception
index.
So the same thing,
this will give you a right index,
right? So
I was saying that the size of in
the rate is right.
Okay. Yeah.
Trying to access something that we never
we never created.
Right.
So now let's see what's going to happen.
Let's see what's going to happen.
Okay, stop now.
I hope it was
everything before is is is good and clean.
Guys.
Okay, good.
Okay, so now let me show you what happens.
Now we're looking into a variation
we know how to create.
And the reason we know
why need them, right?
We knew we need a
to store multiple values of the same time.
Right over the same time to keep our code
nice and clean that into easy access.
Those variables. Right.
So now you're saying inside the arrays
you can store values
with store of the integer type, right?
We store of the double type.
Now store values of elements
of the string type of values.
So before we were going in order, right.
We say that indexes start from zero.
So we started 012 here we started 012.
Hey, you know what?
What if I'll skip
one of the indexes, right?
So let me remove this. Let me remove this.
So Now
I step right.
It's important
you read your code days, right?
So now what I said, I said, Hey,
I want every
that will be holding for string elements.
Right? For string elements.
Now inside this array,
how many elements did you store this?
How many elements you store?
Three.
Now let me see.
Hey, now, if you want,
you find out if you want to find.
See how many elements
inside.
Right. Okay.
So if you want to find out
how many elements
you have inside the in the array,
what are we going to use?
We going to use one
one property,
One property that we call length.
So I'll take my array a see colors
and then I'll say that length
the now call that length,
what it will tell me,
it will tell me the size, it will tell you
how many elements inside the array.
Or we can how do we say
what is the size of the array?
What is inside the one? Right.
And let's see, let me put in here.
I rate
ease and let me get to meet.
Like if we go getting it
in, let's see what my size will give me.
Looks my size still say school, right?
My size.
You'll see for right
when I say colors that length,
it returns me the size of my array.
So now it tells me that my sizes for
because that's what you created
what you stored three elements
you stored elements.
Now let's see.
Hey you know what the store
with the index one.
You know what I saw with the index?
Do you know what is always the industry?
Now, let me.
See? Hey, what do I have on my index?
Zero.
Because that's the only thing
that you don't know.
Right.
Okay. What is there with the index? Zero.
What is there? Everything.
What are that thing will
be? There is the index. You
my thing.
Arrow empty.
What you getting will be there.
No, not ready.
You want me to running days
So now inside your
index zero.
You are having it now.
So what is in all this?
What is it? Not
now. It's not now.
Let's not empty this each.
It's a default value for a string.
Right?
So now here what happens is
why you say that this strings.
They're fixed in signs.
When you created a string,
you said that you need the space for.
For elements.
There's a space for four
elements was created.
Right?
So now whether you use it or not,
that's up to you.
Right?
That is up to you
by Java gives you that space.
It gives you space, Right.
Big container with all these indexes,
the no inside one here, you store blue,
right here you store black,
and here you store yellow.
Right?
So now you did not store anything,
but the space was occupied.
The space was acquired.
So what compiler did compiler support?
Default value
and the same default value for a string is
what is not okay is not okay.
So now think good.
What what is in there radius?
Think or when we have a classroom. Right.
Give an example of the classroom.
So when we have a classroom
now we prepare seeds 400 people, right?
We preparing.
This is 400 people now.
90 students shop, 90 students show up.
Right?
So what happens?
The rest of ten cheese was empty, right?
It wasn't empty, but it got wasted.
But they still in there.
They're still in the room.
We prepare 480 show up. Right.
So now those got wasted, right?
They are still there,
but they are not occupied.
They are wasted.
So now think good next time.
What happened you say we learn. Okay.
No, we're not going to do hundred anymore.
Let's put 90 chairs.
So now we put 90 chairs,
but 150 students show up.
Right.
So now what do we get when we have a
when we said, I want 90 cheers,
but then 150 show up.
So now what are we going to get?
We are going to get index
out of one exception. Why?
Because now we prepared full list,
but we try to store
more index of one exception.
But when we have when we said we would
you have hundred but let's show up
80 show up now 20 got wasted right
what I always that's why
we see an eraser fixed in size
Once you said that
you store in four elements,
it will give you space for four elements.
Now how do you use it?
Of course you have to use them
accordingly, right?
You have to use them.
That's why we always try to start
with this zero, right?
We always to start with you.
Otherwise, if you miss any of the indexes.
Okay,
if you put if you miss indexes, it
will your compiler will still fill
it will still fill it up.
I put three instead of the four.
Yes, of course.
So now if you said that you want
you have three values, right?
If you want,
you have the way we did it in here. Right.
So now if you said you want to have three,
but when you try to put that here
you said
but when you trying to add the extra one
with the index four,
you got a right index out of bond.
Right. So that's why it's in array fixes.
So you want to go more
sorry array on a rebounding exception
you trying to fit list compiler will
fill it up with the default values. Okay
all right in here
is there a limitation?
I think it has a limitation,
but is very, very, very huge number.
It's very huge.
I forgot which number is that? Okay.
The only thing you can specify also
a negative size goes for the negative.
It also will give you
syntax wise will be fine.
Syntax wise it will be fine.
But during the run you're in there on
your java will give you the error.
Where's the error on the line 37 right.
You cannot specify a negative,
but can you specify if you would want?
Yes, you can specify the huge one. Okay.
So I honestly I don't remember.
I don't remember the.
But it can help.
It can hold a lot a lot of doubts.
But just
to know how
many blocks lovers you want
if you want with the budget
gimmick, that guy's going to have the same
color skin.
I have two blue
and I have two blue colors.
Yes, I can have. Right.
So now, when it comes to white,
if you want into this sequence.
Right, that will be from 1 to 120.
But can you store duplicate values?
You can store duplicate values, right.
So that's why you want if you go for a
byte, right, Even if you go for Biden.
So you want to have white, right.
And then a small array, right.
That equal you might write down your store
inside this yellow store I don't know, 800
whatever elements, right? Yes.
You can store you can store
as long as long as those elements
will be
of what the buy table values. Right.
The white type about.
But can you store transfer
them you we can store tons of
white so
we'll look into how to store elements
which store the mission indexes.
We access them based on the indexes.
You find out. What is the size to find on
what is the value
whenever we use in that length?
Right.
Hey, if we are going to add extra values,
we're going to get a right
index out of one exception
if we're going to add less values.
Right?
So what are we going to get?
Some filer will fill up that space for us.
We what is the default?
That is the default values.
If two students can have the same spot,
right, Two students can that.
Okay. Any any questions for this?
Just interest
is the interest of the arrays gets
okay right.
We are not looking into how do we achieve
all the values for now
just one value and only one way.
Not yet.
Not the address.
Beginning
beginnings are always easy, right?
Okay, let's see.
What do we have on our slides?
Right? Arrays. What?
There is a collection of similar data
type, right?
It's a container object.
You guys will learn what is objects. Why?
It's a container that holds value.
So homogeneous types.
Homogeneous means the same types, right?
You cannot say, Hey,
I'm creating an array of strings,
and then all of the sudden
try to store an integer.
It's not going to work, right?
It's not going to work.
Okay.
It's fixed in size, right?
It means because your Java executes
called up to the bottom
right, you click on Run, right?
This is what we say during the runtime,
right after you click on Run.
And once you start,
once your Java start executing your code,
if you guys look right now right
here, what I have a variable.
I have a variable colors.
Now, at the beginning,
you see, that's what
it has the right there for you,
give you right away
space for four elements.
And because the string
they are on the null, right.
That's why they are not.
And if you want to extend it.
Right.
That's why it tells you hey,
with the index zero index one index two
in the right.
So that's why
we are seeing during the one time
Java because you set for once
it's created an array of four elements.
It cannot
automatic click, increase or decrease.
Right.
And then what
you guys will see happen here.
Now we store in blue.
Now a blue will come inside your array
with which index moves.
The index one, now another blue will come
and now yellow will come.
Right?
So now you have an array.
How do you know it's in there? Right.
It has this square brackets, right?
First values. No.
Second values.
Blue values blue.
What value is yellow, Right.
But values yellow and then color.
That length gives us
how many elements inside might it.
Right. Right.
How many elements?
One, two, three, four, three, four.
And then we're creating Big Red.
So now what you created,
you created in a small array, right?
Legacy and have all the 000000 instead.
Right.
It has it it's a huge array
that we created in there.
All right.
You stores values
based on the indexes, right?
The first or when a race starts
zero go right.
So declaring an array
we will go over that again so here right
every arrange is an object which you guys
will own in the following class.
That's why we started with the new keyword
indexation element
and we accessed in those elements
by index.
This note elements next each
how to
find the size or when they're ready.
We use index length
that we use in that length.
So now two different ways.
Okay.
So before doing that, I guess what
you guys do,
you give you just this exercise, right?
And I know it's a break time
and then I'll show you the other way
how to create in the
beginning
of this very quick assignment, guys.
So this way you can quit with practice
and then we'll take a break.
This what I want you to create.
I want you create create an array
to store char
type of elements, and they will be holding
the value of your great ABC the ETF.
Right.
And then I just want you to access one
great I want you just to print grade B
then you guys try quickly to do it.
I'm sure that will be able to do it quick
and then we will take a break.
Jimmy does not give the error.
It does not give the error.
But what it will give a compiler
will fill it up the empty space.
Right. You see in here
we did not start from zero.
We didn't write it.
My code run.
Fine, use my code, run fine. No issues.
But what happened?
It's now you trying to access the colors
with the in the zero compiler.
Put the default value.
There's no issue.
Okay. Do you mean now you want extra?
Remember when you specify letters
with the index six right.
Remember on the line eight.
Right on the line eight.
You said you want an array with six
elements, but the one you want in the room
is six elements, the highest index,
what will be the highest index?
And there will be six elements.
This six elements,
highest index,
highest index will be five, right?
Zero 1 to 1, two, three, right.
Four or six elements,
The highest index will go only, only five.
So that's why if you
even if you're going to skip zero, right.
Even if you want to skip zero,
if you're going to store something
with the index six,
you still running not out of want, right?
So it's your mistake
that you're not putting inside
something inside that in the Zero
write compiler still take it.
The excess base is still going
to pick up the Java memory right
and it's still going to take the memory.
Okay.
So that's what you issue in there.
So six elements always remember this.
The highest index will be Fine.
Okay, So now how are you going to store
where you want to store?
That's up to you.
But that's why we always
try to state the store in order, right?
We don't want to leave any empty buckets
in the empty cavities in the
well for now, just to practice
the different arrays.
This just to practice different arrays.
That's why I wanted to create
an array of chars right.
So just to practice.
So this way
you guys don't get used to string.
So this way, if you did this assignment
now you saw that you can store
integer type of values, that you can store
double type of values, used store
string type of values.
And now you
this are able to store it chart type of.
That's right.
If you start string, that's fine.
Mr.. That's fine.
Okay. Okay.
All right.
I guess the thing you guys all did.
That's good. Good job.
So let's take a break.
Let's take a break for 15 minutes.
Right and then I'll show you other things.
What we can do with in the race. Right.
Let's do a break.
You know, it's still 2:00.
Writing will be 2:00
recording.
Okay.
All right.
Your issue is the same thing, right?
So you said, hey,
you going to store four elements
and then it means that the highest element
was, the index, right?
If you're trying to store four elements.
One, two, three, four. Right.
You indexes start from zero.
Your highest index should be three
now you put in your index is five.
So that's why you get an index,
not a by an exception.
So you have to make sure you store
say you didn't start from zero,
you started with one.
Okay, so your first face was empty
and then you tried to store element,
but there's no space for that element.
All right.
Right.
So once again, today,
we're looking into the arrays, right?
So we're saying, hey, what is it? Right?
Is it is a collection of similar theater
type, Right.
Collection is of similar data type, Right.
Arrays are fixed in size in
the store values, right.
You store values of the same type.
And those values we call elements. Right.
We saw them based on the indexes
you guys see when on this structure.
Right.
What are we Hey array there.
What is the length of the array?
What is the size is ten,
but how many indexes it can fit?
It can fit
only up to the nine. Right? Why?
Because index is always starts from zero,
right?
Index is always best from zero.
And then if we store an element
based on the indexes,
then we can access those elements
based on the indexes as well.
Right. Based on the indexes.
So now I may show you guys
that first way
how to create in the White House.
First we have to create the memory. So no,
let think this exercise.
So let me take it inside the new cluster
segmenting this part
things
All right so this is what we had, right?
So this is what we have.
So I want you I wanted you to create
an array of chars, Right?
And then I want you to print a great big
I want to frame the great piece.
So I think that's what we do, right?
So this is what we did.
So you said Char great or great,
right?
So you're creating an array, right area.
What what array of charts,
How many elements we need to store?
We're planning to store five elements.
ABC TV, ABC,
one, two, three, four, five, six.
Okay, then you need six elements, right?
We need six elements.
ABC e f at six elements.
But then your highest element,
what will be your highest elements?
The highest elements will be store
and the index price in excess.
And then we said, Hey,
what are we trying to access?
We tried to access that, right?
So the element of me which will be element
right?
So now this is a in
one way of creating and this is one way
of creating in there rich and this is a
we do an all in one.
So let me guess
the way we had a variable, right?
So remember this one, we have a variable
genome, right equals to test equal system.
So what are we doing?
We are initializing that right
and doing declaration at the same time.
Right at the same time.
So what are we doing in here?
The same thing.
We declared an array
and we initializing the size right.
So this steps can be done in
two steps as well.
That's the way we do.
Integer now equals to ten, right?
Or what do we can do?
We can say, Hey, I need a variable
and later we're initialize height.
Later we will show the same things
we can do with our array,
the same things we can do with our arrays
right.
So let's say for example Char
Right.
And for example gender, right?
So now you can say, Hey,
you know what I'm declaring the way
I am declaring a variable, I'm
declaring a single variable
and deploying the variable
that will hold a right of balance,
right on the second line you initialize,
you know what we can do?
We can initialize in the second line
as well, right?
So now we can say gender
equals new and let's say you knew what.
Tell me, guess what will be new?
What neutral?
It will be neutral.
So for example,
I want to store two values.
When I objects do that right?
So the same thing.
This is what are we doing before another
initialize investment?
So know how many elements
will planning to store to sell things.
Right.
So this is just two
steps is just broken down.
You can go either two steps
or you can go either all in once,
all at once, the same thing as we did
for the variable, right?
You clear in the array and here
what are we doing?
Declaring in the variable,
I declare a variable
and then we do initial script
and then we place initial that.
And now this is
when it comes to the erase, Right?
And this is the first way
how we can create an array.
So if you fall in this way somewhere,
you guys might see.
So when you guys might see that
in the rate ID and sometimes people place
next to the variable,
so we place this weight.
Yes, it can be place, right?
So now when you deploy the variable,
instead of placing this array,
identify that it's an array of chars
or you can just put it in here
again, it's going to be done.
Yes, it can be done,
but majority, majority of the times
and more preferable way goes to define
you used next to your data type
next do not after the variable,
but next to your data type.
Okay. So it can be done
this way. Yes, it can be done.
This one more preferable way is this way.
That's normally what I'm having.
I'm having an array of charms.
I'm having an array of charts. Right.
And then just your variable.
Okay, You guys have all this information
in slides, right?
And this is was the first way, right?
So what is this?
It's the first way
or one way of creating an array.
Now there's
another way of how we can create an array.
There's a second way of creating an array.
Well, it's a shorter way.
It's more useful way.
Probably not more useful,
but more commonly used here.
More commonly used.
So I'm going to create exactly the same
array, but use in a different way.
Okay, So now what I have
I do have array of chars.
I still have an array of chars.
Now I want to give it a name.
I don't already.
I don't know where it's
going.
Right.
So now instead of this specifying
instead of initialize in my size,
what can do,
I can directly place
the values inside
and how I'm going to place the values.
Just specify like it's a block of code.
Right?
So now what I want to store
I want to store array of chars.
Okay.
If it's chars then just for eight
and then guess with them.
Just with the call me
pointer.
Right.
For example. Now still,
what is this thing?
If I'm going say I'm going to say C, so
I'm going to say grades
grade that length.
What are that thing will be the output.
What of this thing
will be the output of my C, So
before, right.
It's still before
because how many elements I have?
I have four elements, right?
I have four elements.
What are this thing?
If I want to access now, I want to access
my element C I want to access my values.
See how can access that this
access my C
So now this, regardless of which way
in your code you created an array.
I just feel what it does now is still
array is exact the same array
we just created a different way.
You just created different
ways and now it store a
c d, it's
still stored based on the index is zero
one, two, three.
Right.
And now what is the name of my array.
This is the name of my right. Right.
So now how can you access that value of C?
You're still take the variable, right?
You still take your variable rates.
Right. Right, right.
An index was what index?
The index
right.
Now, what are we getting.
We didn't see. Right.
We get it's
from the school element
is withstand still is C you will see
so whether you create array
this way whether you create a longer way.
Right.
Is this same thing this the same thing
what happens
we still creating
then there we find the memory.
There's a still a big container
that still will have the index.
This will be create will be quick.
Can you do a string of
you guys can go to string.
Now let's store our names. Right.
Let me create an array of names. Right.
So how am I going
to create the memory of this?
Does it matter? No, it has No matter.
But the concept of street or of array
still will be the same right now.
Let Me.
See, I want to have array of strings,
right?
I be storing needs right now.
What do you do?
You just bought it right
away. And here. Right.
So now, because you have a string.
What do we have to specify?
You have to specify
a double quotations, right?
You just have to specify
the double quotation.
Right.
And then let's see
who your House member has.
Right.
And then for having there,
I guess I have a Emelia.
Sorry.
I hope I champion them first. Right.
And all you need is in there.
No. Yeah.
Having the right.
So now still I have one.
I have a right array.
What about extreme elements?
How many elements I have right now
I store four elements.
So now let's look.
If I store four elements now
one one.
Not downside, right?
I'm not going to see any downside.
So now what happens is that because you
create in an array all in one line, right
and there is still an array,
the concept does not change.
Array is still fixed in size. Right.
For example, now I want to replace. Right.
For example, instead of the Alexander
I want to put
pre I want to put you.
So now how can I do this
instead of Alexander I want to put three.
How can I do it
if I hope say two correctly, Right.
Three
do right.
So how can I do it based?
I change it to you right now
I say Hey, before with the initial zero
I had Alexander.
Now right now I want to change.
Can I do it? Yes, I can do it right.
So now let me try to print now
with.
All right.
It's all
change.
Change.
Now you look at
me next.
Yeah.
Now let me go in my name. Get replaced.
Yes, my name replaced.
But now let's see what's going to happen
if I'm going to try,
I'm going to say names with the index.
Four equals two.
I don't know.
Let's say John, Let's put John in here.
What are the thing will happen?
Names with the index for
I am running
so why am I again say is a right index
out of one exception on the line 41.
Why am I getting that
so here.
This exact the same thing, right?
The only thing sure we did not specify
right here was specify
that I need an array
that stored two elements
and then you storing
two elements in there.
Right here. You hear what happens.
You are still creating in the array,
but when you place in the values
right away, it just gives you the places
for those four names.
That's it.
You put here. It will put me up here.
It put Emilia here
and it put nine in here.
Right. That's what happened.
So now how many index is Zero.
One, two, three.
Arrays are fixed in space.
You cannot increase them.
It is not increase
the size. Now using eight.
I want to the index. Four
I want to. I don't.
I'm sorry. There's no index four.
There's no index for why?
Because here you stored three string
you still four elements.
So the highest of the array one
it has four elements.
The highest index will be three.
That's it. Right.
So the concept is still the same.
You can not increase the size
of an array once it has been created.
Okay, Once it has been created.
So here you create the array
by storing for string elements.
It that's what you have
right now. That's what you
So here
will get three index out of one
and the same thing.
Even if I'm not going to go this way,
the same thing will get it right.
Index out of one exception.
Be quite an empty index until later.
Okay.
Like you mean to
have you mean to create this string.
Right.
So now there's you guys
will have to decide which way you go.
Right?
You guys have to decide which way you go.
If you want, you create an empty right
first and then store the values later.
That's fine.
That's fine. You can do it.
So this way you will have to go, right?
So if you want to create an array
and later stored the values,
then obviously you cannot go this way
you cannot go this way. Why?
Because when you go in this way,
you have to put the values right away.
Okay.
So, for example, you cannot say, hey,
I want to string, let's say cars.
I want to store cars, right?
I want to create a string
array of strings will hold cars.
Right?
You cannot say, hey, let me let
me just say that this will be my right.
And then I later add the values.
No, if you go in a shorter way,
you have to add the values right away.
Okay?
You have to add the values right away.
Because right now, if I'm going
if you want to leave it like that
and now I'm going to say cars
that linked, right.
So no cars, nothing will give me zero.
You did not add any elements.
Now, what is the size of my array.
The size of my errands. Right.
So now if you were right,
if in your situation
you want to first create
an array and later
add the values,
then you will have to go a longer way.
Then you will have to say string area.
What's the array of
final cars?
Right.
Are right.
Then can you go this way
and then?
But you have to specify the size here.
Compile is not going to give you a long
right compile.
No. Want to give you a look?
It will tell you
hey, you must provide this expression
for every initialize
your how many cars you would want.
I want to store three cars
now if you want to store them later.
And you could explain why. Just one.
Because the box with
three spaces will be in there.
So now can you go back to it in your time?
Yes, exactly
the same as one will remember this
when we had a variable and later
we were storing the dailies.
Right.
So this way you have to store values right
away.
This way,
if you want, you can store regardless.
If you.
So yes, enough.
Now you've got a point in here, right?
So now. Right.
Let me ask you first
this question for this.
A shorter what you create an array
the same thing, declaration declaration
on the left is exact the same way.
So what I have I have a variable.
This variable is what array of chars.
Now the only difference is initialization
part.
Instead of specifying how many elements
I have put in away those elements.
But regardless, if I'll go this way
or if I go
this way, it's still what happens.
Java gives me fixed sides here.
You said you want six elements.
Fine.
Here you store four elements right away.
That's it.
Java, fill up your box.
There's no more spaces you have.
You cannot add later or you cannot
you cannot remove.
Right?
If you have four spaces
and how those elements
elements stored
based on index is based on index
questions for a shorter way
against any questions for a shorter way.
Quick question. Sure.
Well, yeah, tell me those questions.
So regardless of which way
it's elements inside
all or
most of index
and what do we say about in this
next slides from the.
No, no, no, no.
Jimi, what do you want to be using?
See, so that was when I seen that.
Let's we just ask how many. Right?
How many?
It's a count. One, two, three, four, five.
What?
We did not learn yet
how to print all the values.
Right?
We printed how to access one.
Now we but we don't know how to access
all the values yet.
We will look into that. Okay.
Now what's your question question?
Yes, we are able. Why?
Because we specify correct
index regardless of which way
is always element
based on the index, always
index one index to an extreme index
for as long
as you specify correct index where good.
Why are we not able to store due one?
Because look, you try to store element
inside this array,
but element which element
element number five, right. Why?
Because this goes with the index for what
is the highest index inside this array.
Alexander takes index zero mathematics
index one Emilia.
Right. So I missed that.
Your name? Emily. It takes this.
Emily takes their place.
Index two now takes the index three.
That's it.
There is no index for this arrays created.
With The four elements
being stored in there.
Right. Four elements.
Highest index will be three
soon as you were introduced to four.
That's it. It's out of index.
Things.
Okay,
So now the only
line 37.
So you replace an element within the zero
sorry
personal
love.
This is a very beautiful way
and most of the time
you will be storing it this week, right?
We will be storing this way.
Because also what happens
if you know the values,
if you know the values
that you want to put right,
if you know the values that you want
to put, this is the most easiest weight.
And then here
Java is not going to skip any index.
This is what you put them in order
in the zero index one and you do it
next day in this form.
That's it, right?
That's it is to create the box right away
and put the values there right away.
Right.
So what for example,
if you know that you want to store
values, right,
but you don't know them yet,
then you'll have to go
the longer work, of course.
And if you don't know the values right
away, you will have to go this longer.
We will have to go this one right.
And one thing.
When it comes to the shorter week,
it's one thing when it comes to shorter
with look in here,
you were able to declare in the array
what is on the line
12 where the client in there right
on the line 26 where initial lines right.
So now this part is available
only for a longer creation on the right.
If you trying to say, hey right I need
if you want to say hey you know what?
I want an array.
I want an array, for example,
integers, right?
I want an array of numbers.
Declaration is fine right now, Right.
I want an array.
I'm naming this as announced. Right.
And then later you want to say, Hey,
I want you now for values.
Right? I want now store values.
Okay, Now you want to store ten, 11,
whatever.
Right?
If you if you want to go a shorter way,
you can cannot split in two steps.
Okay?
You cannot split into two steps, right?
You can.
Let's with declaration
and then adding value in two steps.
Okay.
That's what that's what that's
what someone questions.
Okay.
So you declaration initialization.
If you want to go into shorter,
we must happen in one line.
It must happen in one. Okay.
So when you go in here, you will tell you
what.
So it says, Hey,
the values that you're trying to place
must be used as initial version part.
Okay, This is just us
trying different variations.
Right?
Let me come in here
right.
Right.
So what we are going to get,
we're going to get
we in not
be clear
in a way.
We need we want to
go round in order.
Think of it this way.
It's not going to work.
Declaration will be fine, but here
compiler will give it to
here.
You will get compiler will complete.
Compiler will
complain on
this one
and then it will be needed.
40. Okay.
So to match that, there is not a set
your way where you can delete the value
from in there. Right. Okay.
So they have to be put a lot
a lot of logic.
You cannot just say so
once you place the values, right.
So for example, now let me do integer
array of integers that have nums, right?
So once you place right, once you place,
let's say v place and 1256, for example.
Right.
You cannot just remove that value.
Can you replace it? Yes,
you can replace it.
Well, because what happens is
this box is being created, okay?
This box is being created
and those values are there.
Okay. Those values are there.
So it's in here.
Ten 1256 okay.
So in the array doesn't
give you an option to remove, right?
Remove completely.
So you cannot remove completely. Right.
Can you replace with other value.
Yes, you can replace because whatever
it is, it's still a variable,
but you can adjust.
It does not give you an option
that you remove.
But will there are you guys will learn
because of some operations
there are some loops we can throw inside,
some if conditions we can throw inside.
We can be able to remove that value
but inside another array,
because what happens?
This arrays are fixed in space.
Now once you pool, once you create
an array is trivial is
it has a space for three that has a space.
Okay.
That's why we are saying
arrays are fixed in size.
In fixed instance,
once you create it, it's there.
Right There is.
We don't have a ready option such as you
replace it
such as removal, remove other things.
There will be more data structures
that will you guys will be learning
towards the end of Java.
But these arrays that will be a limitation
with arrays does not have an option.
Such as, Hey,
you know what, let me just remove
just right, right.
So when you trying to store integer values
because the numbers
you just listed out this way, right.
Ten, 12, 15.
What do you guys want assignment
to do. Right.
One assignment to do and I want you to
And there is the other one.
I'll be okay.
So or okay. We already did names.
Okay, that's fine.
We already do three names.
Do we do names?
We need names in shorter. Wait.
That's fine. Okay.
So I can even do this. Weightings.
I want you to create an array.
I want you to coordinate. Create an array.
Whichever way you decide,
I want you to create array
awards,
and I want you to store Java Saturday.
Then they
then coding them each right in this order.
And then I want you from that right.
Come up with the sentence
saying Saturday is java coding D okay.
So while accessing the elements I want you
to access in the particular week.
So this way you will get this sentence.
Saturday is the Java coding day
applicable to
this and you can try store write.
How do you create?
Accessing is exactly the same way,
but how do you store the elements?
You can store in two different ones
so you guys can practice that?
So extended portion announcements, you
so you can change something
in your program that stack, right?
That's why it's, it's, it's browsing,
browsing, browsing. So
do you think you'll be able to quit,
try to quit your coach
and then try to reopen it
or I guess I hope you did it right.
So I hope you did it.
So the main concept on this
then the bar, the array right,
the main concept about array,
that array is a container
container that can hold the values
of what of similar type.
Right So you said, hey, I have a
I have a variable that holds an integer.
And the answer integer, that string
array of strings.
Right. The array of strings.
And here
you placing all string values and right,
you place it all string values in here.
So as soon as you try
and you put anything different, right.
You Java's completeness.
Why we've seen that array holds
a homogeneous type of false right.
Would you expect from that.
And now, regardless of which way
we create an array,
regardless of which way
element's always stored, is
what was indexes
in the new index
one index two index three index four.
Right.
So now if the elements right
the elements was stored
with the indexes
why they were always the indexes.
So we can easily the right
because if we can store
all elements in whichever order then we
how can we access them.
Right?
If we throw everything in one basket,
it will become a mess.
Right.
So that's why we sent array, right.
Array is a data structure.
What is a data structure?
Data structure is a particular way.
How data are being stored. Right.
So in this one we talk of the array.
You saying that data being stored
in the form of indexes
and indexes starting from zero, right?
So now it's storing data based on indexes,
then we can access
it also based on the indexes, and that's
what you guys been doing in the exercise.
Right.
So hey,
when I'm accessing the right to access the
access, the
value
right, I'm specifying the index, right?
I'm supposed to find the index. Like
for now I'm going to say, What's this?
What? What is the index zero. Right.
What was that in the you know, here
I'm accessing the first element.
Right?
Then I'm going to change to one.
I am a persistent second element.
Then I'm going to change to two.
I am access the third element
and so on and so on.
So you start in based on things
as indexes, you're able to retrieve them
based on indexes, but now want to me
logos now,
now one will look
how many elements
you are able to access right now.
Guess how elements we are able to access?
We are able to access,
but am I able to access all five
at the same time?
No, I'm accessing one element one by one.
Right.
So now if I want to access
all five elements,
right, what I'll have to do,
I'll have to do this with.
Right. So now I'll have to change one.
I'll have to change
two, I'll have to change three.
Right.
So one, two, three, four, five.
But I have five elements, right?
I have to go all the way to here.
Right?
I'll have to go all the way through here.
So now to access all the elements, right.
To access the all the elements,
what I'm doing is
I am repeating a block code.
And why not?
Is my
is my block of what is this same this
when you really look is it is it the same
in any
different?
But what is different?
So now when you look at right to access
five elements
this to access all five elements.
Right.
So I am technically repeating
this same block of quote.
I'm saying, hey, I need words,
I need words, I need words.
Any words? Any words.
The only thing what is changing my index.
It's changing right
when I'm accessing my elements.
So my index is changing.
I'm starting accessing my elements
from zero all the way to the element.
Who is the index for.
So now what I'm doing.
I am repeating, right,
I am repeating exact.
This same c is out with exact
the same name of my array variable right.
With the name of my variable.
And then the only thing that is change
is my index.
Right.
So now remember is when we said hey, in
programing whenever you have a repetition.
Right.
And we're repeating the same lines.
Yes, I am repeating the same ones. Right.
So now in order to implement made right,
in order to eliminate this code
redundancy, what do we use this?
What do we use?
We can use
that concatenation, but it's a longer buy.
What are we can use?
We can use a loop. Think of it.
What if you are going to have hundred
elements, you go and you print this out
and the only thing
what is going to change?
Going to change your index, right?
So now what we can do,
we can use a loop, right?
We can use a loop
to repeat the same action.
Now What do we need to identify it?
So now we have two type of loops, right?
We have two type of loops.
We have a four and we have while.
Right and therefore well, we have
so in which case do we go for four?
In which case do we go for While this
or we go one?
We know how many times
we have to repeat the block of code
and wow, when do we go for while?
When we don't know. Right?
So now the question stays right now
between four and between while right.
So now do you guys know
how many times
you want to retrieve the element?
Do you guys know?
Yes. You know. Right.
So right away we'll go for a for loop.
Right.
So now when you how many elements
how do you find out how many elements
you look?
How do you find out how many elements
you will pass?
How many elements you already has?
We can go that length, right?
We can go that length.
And then what?
We will be changing in just your variable
will be changing in years.
So now, instead of the having
the ugly code like that, right.
Which is not being wrong,
if you have only two three out,
but now when you have multiple values,
I will become an issue, right?
So now we will go for a foil loop, right?
So now actually let me keep this code.
So this way you see. Right.
So this way you will see. Right.
So now I want to start accessing elements
with the index zero with the index zero.
So what should I initialize my integer
I to?
If I want to access this first element,
then of course I have to start from zero.
Right. Okay.
So now I list or whatever you
we will define a commission.
So how far should I look?
This?
So for five. Right?
So what if I'm going to start more,
start adding more, I'm going to start
add more words love
and then and then happy and whatever.
Something else. Right. So now. Right.
Why do you want to go in conscious self.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
Can you come? Yes, you can come.
But Java gives us an option.
Java gives us an option
that can give us the number of values.
Right.
So now how do you know how many indexes
I can go for words and use that length?
Right?
So now this one's that length.
What would develop the number
that it will return me.
Guess which number it will return me
or this particular string
for this particular array.
I read more. Okay, fine.
I added one one, two, three, four,
five, six, seven.
It will give me seven.
Okay, so then when we work,
it will give me a number seven.
Right?
I'll still specify what that length,
but technically it will give me seven
now and then of course, from 0 to 2.
And what are we doing This
we incrementing or discriminating?
We're incrementing I plus plus.
Okay.
And then inside my loop going to do hey,
give me my array
with what will be the index.
That's what will be the index.
Where so what?
So who is control in 01234.
Who is that?
My variable.
I, I am just going to justify my idea.
Right?
I'm going to specify my I
so now I'll go to C++
and then what I'm trying to access.
I'm trying to access words.
My words is an array in order for me
to access elements from the array,
I have to specify the index.
If I'm going to specify
zero is going to give me all the time.
Zeros.
Now want elements from index zero,
then one, then two, then three, then four.
Right.
So now who changes the values from 0 to 1
two, three, four?
Why did I write my variable?
I Okay, call my variable.
All right, so now the only thing you guys
will have to tell me
what will be condition
I is equals two zero words.
That length will give me a
how many elements?
How many elements? It's a number.
It's a numeric value.
And in our case it will be one,
two, three, four, five, six, seven.
It will be you, me, seven.
So what should we
do? What will be my operator
from one till seven?
We said incrementing.
Okay, less than seven.
That's fine. Less than seven.
Less than seven.
Let's take a look about what will happen.
Okay. Less or equal?
Less. Zero less. We're equals.
And now let me debugger, let me debug
that.
So here.
Right 19 this words.
I have an array of words
that has seven string elements, right?
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
What is my highest index?
I'm starting from zero going all the way.
Field six. Right. Okay.
That's what we go in right now. Right.
So now let's see how all of right
our loop works
because everything we so our look right.
What is that lens
What was that lens going to give me?
And number seven. Why?
Because I have seven elements.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
Right.
What is the value of I now live I zero.
Hey, technically what we want
just 4p0 less than seven.
Yes. Condition is true. We'll go inside
Now. What are we going sign?
I'm saying,
hey, I want you print an array.
And what is that?
What is the value of
I at the current moment?
This is the current form. It
at current moment develop I zero.
So now, hey, what is the element within.
Did you.
Oh it is Java.
I'm going to print java for you
then what happens with my loop this
what happens with my loop?
My loop goes back,
I gets incremented
zero plus one equals to one.
And then again check in
the condition is one less or equal.
What is the worse.
That length, it's still seven, right?
It's still seven because there's a seven
element is one less than seven.
This condition is true.
I'm going inside
then I'm going to be accessing.
Hey, words with the index one.
Okay, it will be Saturday
and then next iteration works
with the index to with the index three
with the index, four with the index five.
What will be the element
that is the indexing.
This tell me what will be the
which value will.
Give me the index. Six. Tell me this
in my particular string.
You guys should see it in your right
now is the next six
you have seven elements
so it will give me happy right
element with the index six is happy right.
So here I access happy
it will me print me happy.
Now what happens this IFB was six
What happens
It goes up
it was six six plus one gives me seven.
So now I'm checking my condition
Hey is this seven?
What is the words that Les gives me?
Guess
what is the word that gives me
words that Les give me seven?
Is the condition true or false?
Condition is true.
So now when you go inside
and you will tell it, Hey,
my beautiful array,
give me the element with the index.
Seven.
Do you guys have
element with the index? Seven
No. So what are we going to give this
arrow?
Which arrow.
No. How guys here you index.
What is the max index. Max, this is six.
Now you're saying Hey Joshua, give me a
give me element is the index seven
are wondering. Right.
That's What are you guys going
to get You guys to get a boundary.
Right. So let me run quickly.
Let me first stop
and then we will do Ingeborg
and then we will fix it
right there. Right?
It says elements from array, right?
So online 18,
you have the arrow y on the line 18
you trying to access the element
with index seven
I'm sorry, that element does not exist.
Right.
So let's do debugging again.
Looking at
this here for
a few.
Yeah.
Right.
So declared an error. Right?
We declared the variable
declarative here.
Well that holds whole
array of strings. Right.
There is strings in here. Right.
That's your array of strings
that's how many elements you have.
Right.
So now words that blend
will give it the value of seven.
Right. What does that last will give you
that live seven.
Now what is the value of I values I zero.
Now I am access the element in the zero.
Now it will give me Java right?
It will give me job now moving next
I get increment
that right
I gets increment that the one needs me.
The element is the indexed one then
gives me the element with the index two.
Right.
And then gives me the element
with the index three and get a way
to do this. Now
one more
thing that my to find, right?
So now I am accessing that element.
I get to change the index four
and then the index five.
No problem. It still exists in this right.
And then I want the element with the index
fixed, which it's fine.
So what is the value of
I now live ise six.
What is the element
that is the index six now
we going to get p right
and this is the last element.
But what happens your java goes back you
I will get increment the till seven right.
So now you spend
give me element with the index seven.
I'm sorry there is no element of
is the index seven.
Why we are getting index of bond. Right.
So what should we think states.
No. Why don't need break.
What do do if things get easier fix.
Let's stick out Let's see.
What if we take up right there Here.
All your words are given to you right?
Your words are given to you.
So now, with the help of loop,
we were able to retrieve
all elements from my array.
All elements from one.
I Now, instead
of having all these redundant lines,
we put this line my loop,
we repeat in the same block.
Of course, how often?
How much time you repeated
as many as I have the elements in there.
As many I have the
know this do in order this Java Saturday
the coding is love copy
they retrieve from 0 to 1.
Okay.
What to know
how many elements we access be access
all seven ellipses.
All right.
Because what we started
with the in the zero
when all the way to the index six right
or yeah
no no no this is not related
to your exercise.
Your exercise was correct.
This is just for me to show
how to get all the values from on there.
Right. So let's do one more example.
This I want to do one more example,
and I want to show you one cool thing
very quickly.
Let's do another example.
Let me do
again
all from every
let me create an array of numbers, right?
Let me create an array of numbers.
Do not.
And we will to do the same thing.
That's right. Area one teachers
mum. Right.
And let me store a few numbers in here,
so I'm going to call
100, 200, 301 for example.
500. Right.
So now we said if I want to access
the elements,
I have to specify the index, right?
If I want to access the element,
I will have to specify the index.
We'll have to specify the right.
And it gives me that element.
It gives me that right.
So no, why do you miss?
I'm able to access only one element now.
If I want to access others,
I can simply change the index, right?
I can simply change the index.
You can simply change the index, right?
No. Once I was saying, Hey, what if I want
to access all the elements, right?
It means I have to continuously
repeating this same action which action
by specifying number zero,
not one, not two now three non four.
Right.
So any time we have the repetitive
we'll go for loop right.
In this case.
Do I know how many elements.
Yes I know how many elements. Right. Okay.
If I know how elements I have
I can easily go for loop.
Right.
So I will go for a for an integer I,
I always when I'm doing my loops,
I always start from the zero. Why?
Because the element, the first element
located with the index zero.
Right. And then how far I'll go.
I can specify a line myself.
I can say one, two, three or five.
Right.
My Current array has five elements.
Can I specify this way?
Yes, I can specify. Right.
And then I can do I plus plus.
Because for 1 to 5 we are increasing.
Right.
But okay.
When you erase small
you can calculate yourself.
But think of it when you guys
will be working with the massive arrays.
Right.
You cannot go to your quadrant calculated.
What if you you'll make a mistake. Right?
And plus now you know
one property of the of the array
so you don't have to calculate yourself
right Let it do a job.
So it's the same thing
if you have a calculator. Right.
Why do you want to calculate yourself?
If you have a calculator. Right.
Who can calculate
how many elements I have.
Oh, deep non that low.
What you calculate
it's not going to make a mistake.
Like Jack will find out how many words
a size.
I'm not going to tell it,
but Java will find out what is the length.
Right?
Yeah, we will find out.
And then what I do will see so
and I'll just say no.
And because the variable I, it's
constantly incremental
and constantly changing.
So now this variable I will take care
of my in the expected supply.
And if I want to print all in one line,
let me find all one line, all my alleys.
I retrieved all ones by
and everything looks beautiful.
I use my loop, I use the ones this out and
that's it. In
my or.
Any questions, guys? Any questions?
How would you retrieve
all elements from your loop
is the last.
How would you put the words
in order to me?
Okay, then we will just go for hide.
We will go the way we did, right?
We will go the way we did.
But if you want to use the loop,
then there is some.
If the if statements we probably will have
try it will be a little bit longer.
Wait,
how we sum them.
Alexander, that will be your homework.
Okay, That will be homework. But.
Okay.
I actually want to just show you
one cool thing, guys, in all
because how your homework is based.
Okay, So great because I have a homework
where you guys would have to
write.
How do you find the
size right you did this
and then how do you print all the values?
You guys have this in slides, right?
And then you go over disadvantages.
But I wanted to show you one more loop
because that's how you guys
have your homework.
Okay?
That's how you guys have your homework.
I'm not going to give you the other one,
but I wanted to give you this one. Okay
It's actually very easy, guys.
You give me.
Give me five, 10 minutes.
I'll show you if you grasp that. Good.
If you not,
then I'll show it to you on Tuesday.
Okay?
I'll show again on Tuesday.
But it's very easy. It's.
It's very easy.
Okay, So
five more minutes. This.
Five more minutes, please.
All right.
No, I don't need it, actually. Guys. Good.
This comes up right now, so any
if there's an update for Java crumbs.
Guys, please don't update it.
Just give this version
standard.
All right, So now you access
all elements from an array.
There's another we can use,
and it's very beautiful.
Remember this?
We said that there's a for loops in Java,
but we looked into three.
So there's another loop that we can use
only and only for array, only for error.
Right. Okay.
So we cannot use it anywhere else.
It can be used only with array in.
Later
you guys will be learning collections.
Well now every time think go.
Okay.
If I have an array I can use.
I, I can use my another Texas
or we can use
we can use equal for each.
I promise you guys,
you're going to like it
or we call it advanced
or loop or equal enhanced.
Okay.
So enhanced.
But something has been enhanced.
Something has been advanced so far
because it's still a four.
Right.
So when do we go for four?
When we know how many elements. Right.
So the same thing.
We will start with the four
then our parentheses.
Right.
And of course our block.
So now what do we specify in here?
So what we will have to specify
guys, what we will have to specify
minimum is what it will have to specify
exactly.
Same for here will be something
and the block of code.
So now inside of four
we put a semi column,
semi column.
So now on the right side, on
the right side, what are we going to put?
We're going to put then name of my array
what is in the name of my arrays,
name of my array,
name of my reason Them Okay, cool.
Now what do we put on the left side?
On the left side,
you need to tell me each element.
Each element inside your
array is of which type, each element
inside your arrays, of which type
of integer.
It's and then your right.
And then here it's of each element.
Inside you array is of the integer type.
And then in here we just give any in the
any name you'll give,
I'll give it variable name in.
And then what I'm going to do,
I'm going to print it.
So this is what's going to happen next.
When you work with the for each
look for look very smart grids
for each look very smart.
It works with the arrays,
which it knows as starting point.
It knows the end point.
So now why does it cool for each
So what it does?
Hey, I am looking through this array
which is an m
each element inside my normal right
is the of the integer type.
Yep, it is of the integer type.
So now what happens? Guess what happens?
You'll goes to your array mystery
and it starts from the beginning.
It takes each element
force inside this variable
and then prints.
First time it will be 100.
Right when it moves next.
When it moves next what it does, you
move to the next element from your array.
It moves to the next element
and then stores this your variable.
Now, next time you're variable
and holds the value of 200,
then you'll look
when your little goes back.
So what it does.
Hey, is there next element
inside your radius?
Okay.
If there is an x element, I'll move.
I'll move to 300.
Now I place element
inside this variable next.
Then it will be 300.
Then it goes again. It moves.
Hey, array, do you have more elements?
Yes, I do. Okay, then there will be 400.
400 will be stored inside and then printed
and then it goes back.
Will doesn't show up.
Hey, hey. Array.
Which array?
Array of numbers do
still have more elements?
Yes, I do.
Okay, let me go inside your element.
Each element I am taking,
I am storing it inside this variable.
And then I'm printing
now I'm going to print 500.
And then you look.
Goes back.
Goes back. Hey. Right.
Is there more elements?
No, I don't have more elements. Okay.
If you don't have more elements,
I'm like, I'm going to step it.
I'm going to step.
So this is how your enhanced for loop
works.
On the right side, you specify your array
on the left side.
Just tell me inside this array,
which is now
which elements you have my array
now is a type of integer.
It stars integers.
Okay, So now okay, each element,
each element from this array
I'm going to take and I'm going
to store inside this variable.
Each element I'm taking,
I'm storing inside this variable.
Okay, So let me see.
Is there any version
who is non love predefined
dimmer?
Can you specify?
What do you mean by not predefined array?
No. This is a same a column.
This this is a same a column now.
So now it's not a column on that.
It's the same column
in the advance.
And right now we are signing it.
We are signing each element
takes this element.
Then take this element
and stored inside this variable.
That's what it does.
That's what
it does.
Yes. You can even
you can create array using the loop.
You can you can use the loop after
array has been created. Yes.
Okay.
Not you.
Just a column is just a column.
This okay.
Sorry. A call in. That's simple. Okay.
So yes, advanced
loop works only only be zero.
It's always a race.
Okay, All of these are errors.
Let me quickly do one thing.
This let me see string
color. Right.
Just to show you an example.
So caller Right.
So what I'm going to have
when you have read,
for example, red and I'm going to have
blue and I'm going
to have waited for exams right now
if I want to access and I'm just going
to show you advanced for loop right again,
I want to access all the elements
I want to use my enhanced for.
It starts with the for
parenthesis.
Now what a column on the right side.
The name of my array.
What is the name of my array is
color
inside my array of colors.
Right. Or let me do colors right.
Let me put the colors inside
my array of colors.
What kind of elements I have,
What kind of elements?
I have
the string right?
They are string.
Okay, So now every string element,
I'll just give a whatever variable
and then any variable name.
Any variable name. Right?
And then what I'm doing,
I'm going to print just
what you what happens.
Your enhanced for a loop is very smart,
is very smart in those as long as you tell
the correct array,
as long as you said correct array.
So what you will
does it goes inside your array.
Right.
And it's always goes to the beginning.
So now it starts from very first element
takes rate stored inside this variable.
So basically right now what you're saying,
you saying, hey, string
call equals two, right?
That's what you said.
No. In here
you're to access the value of call
in first case it will be right.
Then your job goes back.
Hey, is there a next element
inside this array? Yes.
Okay. If there's next element, grab it
for it inside this variable.
So now you send string calls equals What
there are right now
holds the value of blue.
Now on the line 26
you print in the value of variable call.
And this case it will be blue.
Then it goes back moves next.
Hey is the next element
only know if there is next element,
then it moves, then it grabs.
Then it stored inside here
and then prints white.
And then when it goes back,
is there more elements?
No, there is no elements.
Condition becomes false.
Is there more?
No, there is more, not more.
We are going to get a false.
And that's when you start. Okay.
That's where you start
to know it's no good idea.
But I wanted to show you this.
I did not know that
we going to take a long time, right?
I didn't know
we're going to take that long,
so I'm going to push The Court okay.
I'm going to push the Court
So if you guys understood
the enhanced for loop, then this homework,
I'm going to send you guys back.
And this probably not.
I'll send you this.
Okay, so this
you guys will have to create in the array
and we in retrieve all the values.
If you understand, enhance for loop, do
two ways.
If you did not understanding
how in this world to do it.
One week and then two more assignments,
I will said okay, but
try to rewatch the video
and I believe you guys
will be able to understand right?
Well, your viewing hands for a loop
is never ever going to skip any elements.
Okay.
It starts beginning, ends at the end.
It's very, very smart loop. Okay.
All right.
Okay. So
one thing, guys, one thing, because
right now we are following a little bit,
not behind,
but because we did not have one plus.
So on to use the guys for Tuesday.
Please look over this advanced for a loop.
We're going to repeat it. Okay.
Yes. We control the condition
for your question there.
Yes, we can throw the conditions
on Tuesday, guys,
since they're doing the project today.
We are going to do the project on Tuesday.
Guess. Okay.
So please
make sure your team members are there.
And for Tuesday, guys, please
make sure you look over
a topic are equal to the arrays.
Advanced for loop and to the race.
Okay.
And when we go
and you have it from now on, guys
your Java classes are four days a week.
Okay?
So I'm going to see on Tuesdays
and now guys have a shorter time
to do your homework and sorry
for taking the little extra time,
but I hope it was useful
and I'm going to push the quote
I'm going to do to send you the homework
and just please try to do it.
Okay?
All right.
Thank you, guys.
I'll see all of you
in one day. In one day.
And Enjoy your Halloween. Have fun
If you don't have a team.
Guys, please
make sure you find the team by Tuesday.
Okay?
All right. Thank you, guys. Yes,
Homework will be in the course.
This. It's all right.
Hi, guys.