We are not.
We have now started to record.
So that's very important, right?
We is Asia
and it's but
we should know the path.
Right.
And then the second important thing,
the second important place that will
always help you create that connection
or open that file inside the Java program.
What was the name If I am reading
the data, what was the name of that file?
No, no, no.
Before load file import steam.
Right. That file import stream object.
It creates that connection.
It it lowers the your file inside
Java program you can think of like this.
So we
we should know the port
and then
we can use file.
I have private file.
It could not find it printed out.
Only the word username
which is road inside us out
here to check if there is a connection.
Yes, there's a class.
It's a class.
So we should know the path.
Then we can use file
input stream class
to load that file
inside Java
program. Right.
So we started discussing about the
file input stream.
So if I show you
this is the description about that
filing for stream class.
If file stream obtains input
by from a file in a file system.
So this by its use
is the same
that the type that we discussed
in our first class
that it can hold only 256.
So all the data is loaded in the form of
what files are available
depends on the host environment.
Filing for stream
is meant for reading speeds
offered by such as image data
for reading streams
of characters, content of using file data.
So all the data that you guys
will be relating
to this file in your stream
will be read in the form of bytes.
So you guys
can think of this file stream
if kind of goes
to that bot that you guys specify
and then reads all the data in the form of
you can think of in the form of raw bytes
is not in the form of text
or in the form of key value
first, key value pairs.
Yet when we use this file
input stream inside these properties,
then that raw data is actually converted
in the form of developers.
Okay.
And then from this property object,
we can start getting the properties.
Does it make sense how these
all these different
things are linked together?
So this object,
it will go inside your computer
on the spot,
It will read the data in raw form.
Then this object that we are creating,
we are calling this load method in here.
So this raw data will be converted
into will
be converted to those value pairs.
And then using this object,
we can start getting those key
value pairs.
So in simple terms,
you guys can think of fighting
for spin class laws
that file inside the Java program.
Yes. Rather to in the form of zeros
and ones in the form of bytes. Yes.
You are right.
Filing for same laws.
The Delta
inside the program in the form of.
And if there is any issue
like, for example,
if that class is not present.
So you have specified the part
and there is no file on that pass.
So what added you guys will get
this property is object object.
Convert that data to developers.
Exception. What is that famous exception?
No file found no such file found.
Right.
So if you specify the wrong path or
if that file is not present
or there is an issue, maybe with the
extensions or you guys
are using a wrong separator, those forward
slashes are backward slashes.
They are a little different.
On Windows, Linux and Mac,
they are a little different.
They work differently.
So you guys will be getting this file
not found exception.
Most notably so loaded that are inside
the program in the form of bytes.
Then using that properties
dot law
method
that is converted to come
on, show me the correct path
exception. Yes.
So in the next class I will show you
how to create your own exceptions.
Then you guys can create
any type of funny errors or exceptions.
The property does.
Load metadata is converted to
e value pairs.
And what is the parent
class of this properties
class guys
from which class this class is inheriting
the map class, which means what does it
mean?
Guys?
Can I use all the methods that are present
inside that map, inside
this property class?
Can I use all those matters?
So all the properties and methods
they are available to?
This property is class.
So property
load metadata is going to be pairs
and we can use the
method from
map inter
interface to read and
right at the back.
Right.
So this is,
this is what we did in the last class.
Are there questions?
Is there anything that is confusing you
or maybe some piece of code?
They are not making sense
why we are using specific files
which kind of map the hash table
the tried to save map.
You guys remember that thread
synchronization transitive.
So the only difference
between that cache table and the hash map
is that if transitive arrest is seen,
Do you mean is it good idea
or do you still have any questions? Yes.
No. All code
is bought from content and absolute,
but the same are
they are not same actually on different
operating systems,
there are different types of files,
different types of parts, absolute bar
to that relative part.
And there are other types of parts.
So let me check
the types of parts in Java I guess,
and there are separate files to
those parts as well.
And they have introduced
more types of boss in Java eight,
but most probably
you guys will be using the relative back
or the
absolute part.
So there is this absolute part.
This is the relative part
and there are these
relatively than normal.
So those who are interested more in part,
you guys can read this, this blog
for me,
it works when I copy the absolute part,
but when I use the part content,
it would not work.
I have to take the longer part.
Let me check. There must be
there must be something
that you may be doing wrong.
Okay.
Actually, there is a whole new library
that the Java guys
have introduced
in Java eight,
so there is a complete
new set of classes and interfaces,
but it will take like two more months
to learn about all those.
It took me three months to learn myself.
So there is a huge, huge deal
about these parts and everything,
file handling
and all that.
So we will not be going
into those details.
But can you share this screenshot
when you use the content part
and it does not work?
What did you get?
So today we will learn guys
how to read and write Excel file.
But before that I want to show you
something.
So if I say
the let's,
let's have a recap as well.
So let's say guys something easy
you see the same as
So let's say, guys, I want to read this
I want to read the data
from this config dot properties.
So what should be the first thing?
How can I read the data from this
this file?
Well, what should I do
with the bar?
Right.
And if I am inside the integrity,
how can I get the part to
right click
and then copy what reference?
Now if we click on that
we will be getting multiple options.
I bought from the repository part
from the content road
file name, absolute part, right?
So the issue with the absolute parts
is that are
these absolute parts they can be different
on different computers.
For example, on my screen you see C users
as one of the ideal projects
on your computer.
You guys will see a different
but right depending upon
where you have stored your project.
So if I push this code through the GitHub
and if you guys clone discord,
you have to go and change wherever
I have used this part inside my project,
you have to change this part
everywhere, right?
To make this project work
because it will be a
different part on your computer,
even though the file is present
inside the project,
inside this aspect batch.
Devin
If you clone this project from the GitHub
and if I have used this absolute part
before, you guys can run this project,
you have to change this part
according to your computers.
No, if we use the relative part,
you see the really relative part,
it starts from files
and then config dot properties
if I use relative parts.
So wherever you will be storing
your project, it will not affect
how the project is structured
internally inside your intelligent.
This files dot config got properties.
It will be same everywhere.
So that's why the relative boss
they are preferable.
Okay.
You guys will be having different issues
if I use absolute boss
because they can be different
on different computers.
So whenever we are developing
a project of another, we are writing code.
We never try to use things
which are specify to our computers.
If I push this code to the dev environment
or the cube environment,
that part will be different
and my project will not work right?
Does it make sense? Guys?
If I push this to a
server I will be getting an issue right.
File not found issue.
So I should always press for the
relative paths
to string
but equal to if for some of you
if this part is not working,
please post in this fourth channel.
It should work
because this is the best practice.
This is how you guys will be doing it.
And you guys, all of you understand why,
why we are using
the relative parts
better.
All right.
So what is the next thing, guys,
that I need
to read the data
so far?
Trump file the party's prompt. Yes.
Only the name will change in here.
Only the name of the file
will change in here.
Best of things.
They will be same.
So the next thing is the file input
stream.
Right.
I now must bring the back from this file
inside my Java program
so that my Java program
can process this data.
So I use and if I have to write the data
which which class I should use guys.
So if I have to read the data,
I use file input screen.
But what if I have to write the data
is the file output stream, right?
This is how the water flows
in and out in our homes, right?
So if you are washing
some dishes in basins, right.
If you need water,
you open that tap, right?
The water sinks in and then the water
goes away from a different pipe.
So then you have to read the data
from the file system.
We use file input, same when we have less
did that to the hard disk
when we have to store the data to the hard
disk, we use the file output stream.
So that's why we have these two different
classes. Yes.
Like your wife washing your laptop. Yes.
So five steam is equal to new
file input.
Same.
And this file input stream guys,
it expects the block.
So I provided the port
and now I get this out of this error.
Actually what this error is saying.
You're saying that.
Yes, that's the device saying that the
what if I tried to read that file
and that file is not present
on your computer?
What do you want me to do? Right.
So we will learn how to write backup code.
In the case of these kind of scenarios.
So when your Java program is trying to
do something and there are some problems,
for example,
reading the that file is not present.
Trying to connect to the Internet.
Internet connection is not available.
So in those cases, Java says that,
Hey guys, tell me what you want me to do
if that happens.
So right now we are saying that,
Hey, Java, if you don't file,
don't find this file,
stop our program and throw the exception.
So this is the default behavior.
So that's why we are saying
add the exception pool method signature.
So right now
we are saying we will tell you later
how to deal with this issue
if that file is not found out, if the
if the part is incorrect
or something like that.
Okay.
All right.
So now I have read the data
in the form of raw bytes.
You guys have created a meme out of it.
Yes, Luba? Yes.
I think that
that thing is not same in here right now.
We are throwing file not found exception.
The later thing is actually
a parent child relationship
and it covers this error as well.
So that's why you don't have to write it
and you only write file
input output stream. I will.
I will teach you
how to be filing for streams.
And what are these file on found
exceptions and all that.
Reading the data in the
form of
the lives.
Ladies.
You see, I give you unique ideas, right?
You see, I will.
You guys can try these ideas
on your husband's
reading the time
they come up for our lives
in the Java
program
page How to make by Post this to.
It's very easy. It is
to put the dosage inside the machine
and just start
by doing something on your iPad
or something like that.
And when you smell something wrong,
then you have to get out of those
both around the multi
and then make it loud nice.
Oh my God.
Oh my God. I forgot so that
no one is angry at you.
Is it?
Is it as right?
So you have to make that drama as well.
It's the it's part of the recipe. It
so violent per stream
And then what is the next thing guys
all of us did when we were new brothers
So next now I need to convert this rather
to into something meaningful.
Right. That we can understand.
So we use another class
that is called property.
So properties, properties, new
properties.
And there
is this method properties dot law
that will read the raw data
and it will convert it to developer. Yes.
And I now I can start getting the data
from this file.
So for example, if I want to read,
maybe let's say a password from here
so I can see
s out
properties, not get property.
So this get the property, it will return
you the data in the form of a string.
But this that method,
it will return you in the form of of gulp.
And then you have to do proper casting.
So this get property is preferred.
And now I should be able to
read that password from my fly.
Okay.
All right.
Get property, you guys.
No story, you guys, no
list.
We will not be discussing
load from access or stored that simple.
So we will be.
There are two types of files
that we use to store the data.
One, the common ones.
They are exemplar files
and these properties files.
So both of them, they are a kind of 50 50%
used in the industry.
So these are all of these methods.
They are coming from the parent class
of that map interface.
Okay.
You guys want if you guys want to use,
you guys can use those.
And so that
okay,
I get an error.
What is the reason?
If you get null, it means that
you have not specified the one.
Do you have to press all
to enter and then you have to
add that
exception to the method signature in here
like this or right.
This line throws Iowa exception
after the signature after this
method closing parentheses,
you'll get to make sure that there is no.
So that comes out null.
It comes out null.
Maybe if maybe you are using the wrong
spelling done,
maybe there is something
in uppercase or lowercase,
or maybe that property
is not present inside your file.
So this is how we read the data.
What if, guys, I have to write the data.
What should I do if I have variety
that let's say I want to insert
a new property inside the file.
So first I can say properties dot
set property right
and let's say the property name
I want to be.
You are L and then
I want to set it to
in Google dot com.
I tried both.
When I pass absolute it works,
but not when I use the fourth content.
I send this screenshot for now
I will work with the absolute.
Okay, we can change it.
Right? Not file output stream.
Yes, we will be using the file
artwork screen.
Yes. So out only when
we want to
write the data it will be file.
So we will be using file
output stream.
File output stream is equal to nil
file output stream
and then what should I pass inside
deconstruct guys
the part where I want to store the data.
So what is happening right now?
All the data from that file,
with the help of this file input stream,
all the data from that file
is being loaded inside this Java program
and we are now processing.
We are doing whatever
we want to do with that data and then
actually every time we use this file
output stream,
we actually we are creating a new file.
Okay.
So can you guys tell me
Okay, first
let me show you actually what happens.
So I passed the button here
and then which method I should use
to store the data inside that firebase.
So properties dot
store
and I pass the file output stream
and then some comments, let's say
added new
property
the other.
So if I execute this program
and if I open this file
in parallel in here, I see my
you are right.
I see my you are.
But can you guys
tell me if I don't use the file
input screen?
If I don't use the file
input stream, why this error please
file import stream.
You have not defined the object file
input stream.
Now you have not written
this file in your stream line,
so how can you use that variable?
You have not defined this file in pristine
variable. You
you have to write this line right before
back load method
file and post-game file statement.
Part.
So guys, if I execute this program
without first
reading the data from the file using file
input stream and loading the data,
what do you guys think?
When I ignore this program,
what will happen to this file?
What that I will see inside that file.
So if I execute this program,
all the data from that file is gone.
And now I only see the you are.
Then why it happens?
Because we didn't load did.
So this file output stream,
it always creates a new file.
It always creates a new file.
So if we want to retain
the previous data
that is present inside that file,
we must use the file import stream.
We must load all the data
inside this object.
This property is object,
and then we should try do that.
Otherwise, already present
data will be gone
if you guys are not loading that
that our first inside your program did.
So this is a very common mistake.
So make sure you guys are not doing this
mistake and the comments are overwritten
with a timestamp
anyway to check the history
of those revisions.
I don't think so. It is possible.
This file?
I don't think so.
It maintains the history of the comments.
Could you comment Line 16 This one.
I have already commented this line,
so before you guys
can write the data to a file,
you must load the data
that is already present inside that file.
Inside this property is object
because this file output stream,
it always creates a new file
and it overrides
whatever is present
previously at that part.
So you will lose everything
that is already present.
So if you want to retain the data
that is already present,
you must first load that data
with the help of file input steam
and you must restore that data inside
of the properties object
that it makes sense.
Could you have used the DOT,
put metadata to store the data?
So when we load the data, we don't need
to write that, put it automatically.
It reads all the data from the file
and stored the inside.
This properties object.
So this is how you should
normally write your program.
So we have to use file in post-game,
not lose all the data. Yes.
Yes. You are right. So let's say
I have a
third property.
Will are the data.
Yes. Yes.
Set property
or put to method from that map interface.
You guys can use both
how to get back.
There is no way to get back.
It's gone.
If you guys want to get back your files.
I have told you.
How can I get back my previous files?
Previous versions of file in invalid.
You guys.
Do you guys remember
how to get back the files?
Maybe if I made any changes,
how can I get back those changes?
I can right click on my project
and then I can click on local history
and then show history
and you'll see if I click on this
config file,
let me close this,
not this one.
So now I see that
is saying that there
previously you had this data in here
and now you change the out staccato this
so I can click on this arrow
and then if I close this
I should see my back to back in here
like this.
This is how I can get that my
okay so
let me put back inside of the components.
We should always load the data
in the
in the Java program.
It gives me an error underline it being
properties because you are passing
file in stream to in here
you have path file output same
monad
one one on the you are still there before
it's been around
three more than three months.
We should always load the data
in the Java program
before we
provide the new data for their file
using PY output thing to
avoid losing
and that
yesterday was his birthday.
So today mistakes are forgivable.
Okay,
so guys, if I have this back to
Dom on
the master.
So let's say, let's say
let's add Neo that.
So if I execute this program guys, will
I lose all of this data or will
data will be retained
and I will see this new property
added in here.
So I am using file import stream.
I am frustrating the data
inside this object
and then I am writing this data
with the help of file output.
Fine.
Yes. We added this new property server
and the name is dev dev
or if sought for development, will
I lose this database
if I execute this program?
So I see the new data in here.
If I use file import scheme
and then I don't lose detect,
then I don't suppose to code.
So this was all about the properties file.
If you guys have any questions
you guys can ask
and now we will move to Excel files.
They are much more exciting
because of the right properties.
Dot Lord fight or state.
Yes sir.
Because we wrote this line.
No, it's not easy peasy.
I think
it's.
Are you guys ready?
Okay,
so let's do this.
So let's create a new file.
Thank you for being always honest with us.
Does it help
help you guys when I say something is easy
and let's say, for example,
if I really tell you
that something is not easy.
So we will not.
Not really. It does not tell help.
I should be honest with you.
Okay. So let let me be honest.
Due to the two days, glass is hard.
Does it help now?
Do you guys feel better
or not at all?
Well, what does what does help that
at least we would not be disappointed.
Nothing else.
Okay, let's create a new file,
a new Excel file.
So I hope you guys know.
At least you guys know how to create the
if new file on your computer.
Please don't disappoint me,
especially the Mac users.
Let's create
an Excel file on your computers
so new and
then X Excel x work sheet.
Okay, let's create this one.
No class helps
and let me give it a name.
Batch 11.
Yes, it should be same.
Give me create a excel sheet
using that W piece.
Make sure that the extension is x, l x
and you guys are able.
I think I have the AWP as well
on my computer.
So if I you see WP office,
I have that as well.
So if you guys don't know
you guys can do this.
Those who have WP s office
open that WP sources
and you guys should see
something like this.
Now you have to click on this spreadsheet
Those who have Excel,
you have to click on this spreadsheet
and then a new blank spreadsheet
and then you can save it
from using the save button in here
anywhere on your computer
on maybe next up, just
give me accidentally
and then you should see this.
Give me your excellence
x l s x.
This should be the extension. Yes.
In here
we don't need to change the x x extension
only Excel extension
will work with the updated dots.
Yes, I hope so.
And this time. But I have never tried.
Maybe putting a different extension.
How it will affect your program.
You guys can try that as well.
Let me know once all of you have the have
a excel X file on your computer.
I can't see Miriam.
You don't have Excel or WP or OpenOffice
on your computer.
The extension, I mean, maybe you have
hidden the extensions, so it's fine.
I shared a video on the course
announcement.
You guys can enable the extensions
on Windows Machine using that video.
It's a very short video.
So there is my file, which is Acrobat 11.
We must pass something on that file.
Yes. Let's put some data in here.
So let's put maybe
call and then $5.
Okay.
Like this.
And then let's put maybe gain
and then
Alexi
or Galaxy Happy now
and let's put any data inside anyway.
Just make sure
that you don't put that data too much
from this starting columns
because it will be hard to read that data.
Maybe,
Your Highness
x l x x
x should be at the end of the
then using your actual
Is there anyone who is still unable
to create the file?
I'm Ron.
Are you getting any issues errors?
Do you have excel or something like that
on your computer
or you don't know how to create
a file?
It's fine. It's fine.
Maybe you guys are.
So let me let let me send my a file.
Those who don't know how to create a file,
you guys can use my file.
Amran, Use my file. Place that file.
So copy this file.
So copy this file and
place
that file in here inside your files
directory.
Okay.
Control C Control. We
like this.
We could have just open
the same directory through Excel program,
I suppose.
Or there is some advantage for WP
is not the same.
Pretty much same.
Yes. Normal, actually.
Okay.
We should do that too with our file.
No, you guys just put any data
inside your excel file
and store your files
under this files folder.
If you guys know the parts of your file
on your computer,
you guys can use that part as well.
But because a lot of you faced
many issues, you started, That's why I am
storing this file under this file folder
so that you guys don't face issues.
Yeah, Control C, control
B, you'll get to control
C and then select your file
folder and control it.
Yes, just copy paste.
So we have to store the Excel to the file.
Yes, the Excel file to this file
directory.
Miscellaneous and
is everyone ready?
Do you guys have your files in here?
So let's create a file.
It's not pasting in mine.
Or what do you have a mac or windows?
You are popping this file
for example using control C
and you are saying you are unable
to paste that file. You
by clicking on this folder.
And in here,
where do you get any errors or what?
What is that
question mark next to Excel file?
Just because I have not installed
the Excel extension in here.
So if you guys want to award
that, you guys can install the plug ins.
I think it's called
Excel or something.
Yes, the Excel reader
because but I am having issues with my
because I have installed
too many extensions. So
but you guys should be able
to see that excel of client
type of icon in here
in Mac.
It's also not working.
Do you guys know how to copy and paste?
It's fine. It's fine.
So for example,
even if you are on Mac or Windows, just
just right, click on this files
and then click on Open in Explorer.
And this is the folder
where you have to paste your file.
I think now you should be
able to paste your file,
right click on your file
folder on directory, click
on opening a Finder or Explorer
to write.
Delete the URL.
Yes, You should not be having
that door to you all at the end.
But why you have not?
You are left behind and why you are
putting it inside the package.
Maria, you have not created that
the acceptor directly.
So you missed the class
yesterday.
Okay.
Post in this port channel.
Maryam. Post in this post channel.
How can you copy and paste the file?
How you can create a new directory?
I will wait for 2 minutes.
Once all of your issues are resolved,
then we will move forward.
I use command plus C and command plus V
and it works perfectly.
Yes, it should work fine.
I don't know why you guys are unable
to just to simply copy and paste.
You guys don't need to install
any plug in.
That was it will just put a a icon and
you will be able to add it to that file
currently here Screenshot
on Mac.
You need to go to opening
and then click on finder
files.
If you are having any issues, please
both in this Port General
and shared screenshots
from on
and yes, it's
normal to have that question mark.
Okay.
Yes, explorer is equal to find it
in Mac.
Nice. Follow all of your problems.
I will be back in 2 minutes.
Helper Thumbs up your smile Oscar
when you get mad does not fit you.
I'm not mad.
I'm not mad at all. Moto you are.
My life is not that easy to solve
all your problems
in 2 minutes.
That's good. Is pissed off.
We are stuck with just creating excel
files and copying and pasting.
No, actually I am waiting
so that all of you have excel file
because you guys
then will not be able to follow me.
Oh i word I was a moment ago.
It's not us.
His girlfriend or no,
it's not about the girlfriend.
And the real problem will come
and I will be getting letters.
I can still put my phone on airplane mode
and I can say, Oh, there was
bad signal or something like that.
But later on
I will not be able to make those
excuses. It's
a you'll get I am trying to push it
as far as possible.
No, no, it's not personal.
No, I'm not out the
I am the person who learned
from the mistakes of others.
I see my cousins who are married now.
They just disappear from the world.
I used to see them laughing, playing
cricket and all those activities.
Now everyone is just busy,
work, homework on their thought.
You just coding on
Java? Copy. See and copy. We
is also trying to
extend my computer's life. It's
it. And this is called Happiness
Single life.
Everyday
for the demo
fight. You.
I hope you guys have resolved your issues
so let's create
Excel demo one.
So guys, I explained
she was helping us still
for she was too much load on.
He is so the excel files
they are divided in in workbooks right
And inside the workbooks
we have different different fields
and inside the shirts
we have these columns
and the rows like
So remember the specter guard.
It will be helpful when we will be reading
the data from those Excel files.
So if I open that Excel file,
So you see on the bottom Excel sheet one,
I can create one more sheet.
Let's say maybe sheet two, right?
Then I can create more shirts.
So these shirts,
they will be having different deltas
every kind of life is cool.
The important thing is the mindset.
No, no, it's a trap.
All the ladies, they said this,
everything will be fine.
And after marriage, it's
totally the opposite.
A You guys are all same. Yep.
I don't trust
this.
So we will be.
You just need the right person.
That's the problem.
There is no right person.
The one that you.
You are being recorded.
You know that, right?
Yep. It If I were to say it openly.
All right, guys, So I'm just.
I was just kidding.
So let's create the main method in here.
So to read the data
from the Excel files as well,
the first thing as always,
we need the path, right?
And to get the part
we can right click and then
copy board reference
and then copy content.
So string
file is equal to
be bought here.
And again, same file input steam.
So most probably either
you guys will be using some kind of other
they are called readers.
By the way,
this file input stream is a reader.
They help you read the data.
So there are many different types
of readers,
but we will be sticking to file
input input stream.
So again, we need to be file input stream
of the same file.
Input stream is equal to new file
input stream, right?
And then pass
or I should change it to
what?
So now I have read the raw bytes
using this file input stream
from that excel file.
Okay.
So the thing I want to convert it
to a Excel sheet
now to convert it to an Excel sheet,
we have these special classes from this.
This is where those jobs do you guys
remember those jobs that we added?
So the building support for Microsoft
Excel file
is not present in Java, so that's why
we are using external libraries
to read the data authorized to back out
to those Excel files.
Okay. So now if you type X self
workbook and it should
be from all the data party or boy
and then access of workbook
is equal to new
X s as of workbook, then
you guys should not be getting any errors
and make sure that this track, this,
this class
is being important from user model
and then not excessive.
Do you guys see this import?
Is it working fine?
Okay.
And now this file input stream.
So in properties
we had that load method, but in here
that load method is not present.
We simply pass
this file in firstname to the constructor
and here
and now if I hover my mouse over
and if I say add exception to method
signature.
Now that both of these errors,
they should also go away.
So it worked for me a couple classes ago,
but now it gives me
an error
and I get the link to the correct jar.
I remember how to import
you just need the right jar.
Just type Apache boy on Google.
So let me let me show it again.
And this
this is the link that you should see.
Eleanor, you are using Windows
or Mac, right?
Yes, it is like loading.
So it is Windows.
So you should download
you should go to the downloads
and then
the bin.
And from here you guys are
you can download.
So this link should work fine for you
if you are feeling in windows.
Okay.
Is there anyone else
we have facing issues with the jobs?
We are all getting hacked right now
by having a party on our computers.
Which one for? Mac?
Let me send you for Mac as
this one
for the Mac.
Why is the port right now?
All because I changed
the name of the variable.
A change I was using file in here.
Then I changed it to part.
So make sure that on the line above
you use port.
And this pageboy isn't the only thing
that is using long for a log for the
almost all the applications in Java.
They use this log for this,
so don't worry about it.
And there are so many loopholes.
Yes. Let me know when you guys are done.
So now I have that.
So I read the raw data from that file
and I have converted it to an Excel sheet.
Now, can you guys tell me what is
what is present inside the Excel sheet?
What is the next thing that I should get
from this Excel file?
Where should I go next after
I have the Excel file to get the data
sheet
right, the next sheet, Well,
I get properties.
The next thing I should go to,
I should get this sheet right.
I like this.
Let me know once you are ready
to leave, I go, Well,
that's about as how valuable.
So I can say sheet
so I can create an object.
This this, this sheet is an interface
and I can say sheet
is equal to
X of workbook dot got sheet.
And inside this get sheet matter,
I should specify fy the name of the sheet
from which I want to get the data.
So for example, in this batch 11 job,
if I open it again
in which this data is present,
guys in which sheet
this data is present, see it one, right.
So and we have to make sure
that we are using
the correct spellings
and and we are also using B,
we are not also changing the letters
properties a lot of this.
So the better way is to right
click on it, edit it and copy
the exact same name
so that you guys don't make mistakes.
So get sheet.
And inside here
I write the name of the sheet.
Let me know once
you guys have written this code
and if everything is good
and you guys don't get
any errors, the
boy is done.
Katrina is done.
Okay.
So once I have once I have the sheet guys,
what should be the next thing?
Alex, you are getting the next shell.
Next thing should be rows
and columns, right?
Let's make sure that this sheet
is coming from this import.
Let me you this import to
use. Please,
everyone, please make sure that you guys
are using this import
I have done why you are getting error.
Are you doing something differently?
Excessive workbook
and then that should get one.
You should not be getting an error.
Select the first option then you.
But I don't sense
so you will be getting an error.
Make sure you guys have these imports
the correct proper imports
and if you have imported all the jobs
properly useful, you should not be
asked to convert that sheet.
How you copy shit
name or simply double
click on the sheet name.
So for example, in here, double
click in here under control C control me
break is coming for me.
We still have 10 minutes.
So the next thing I should get now,
the rules.
Okay, so roll ups.
Roll the roll is equal to a sheet and dot
get through.
And if I check
if I check my excel sheet.
Right, so I have this roll
one or two and roll three.
But same is the case in here.
These rows, they are index based.
So for example, this roll one
is actually on index is zero.
So if I want to get the data
from the row zero,
I have to specify I
row zero.
Then you please by
line 14 again, you'll get a
you want me to type it again.
You want me to type it again?
I mean, what will happen
if I type it again?
It's is there anything
you don't understand from this line?
But it's better to memorize
and, you know, I mean,
if you guys are having issues, then
you should ask the ask me about the issue.
What words will it be typing again.
Right.
So let me send you my import.
Maybe
all every everyone
you get to use these imports, the
either you have not imported all the dots
or you are importing these classes
from different packages.
So this could be the issue.
If you use these imports,
the issue should resolve.
Let me know if you still face this issue.
Why do we have sheet to get?
Because from sheet
one we are trying to get a row.
You know,
from this sheet, from this
and from this workbook.
I am getting the sheet.
I am storing it in a variable
from the sheet.
I am getting the raw zero
the first row in the Excel
by specifying its index zero index.
So once I have the row guys,
the one side we will read Maxim
so once I have the row.
So these are not called columns.
They are called actually cells in Excel.
Okay.
So now if I want to get the data
from this Excel zero,
I will get this cell from this row.
So I will say
cell cell is equal to rule dot.
In that cell.
Okay.
And now if I say s out
and then cell,
I should see data from this cell.
Why? Edit
this get role
should be filled out that you are also
costing it
Alexey you see
you guys are not using the proper import
my imports are coming from point
Asus don't use models
you guys are using wrong import.
Let me share this important
because all my standard nice
make sure that you are importing
from the same packages
not not always zero.
If you want to get the data from the zero
cell, then only you should be
putting zero in here.
So I get the call in here.
I the data that was on
row zero and cell zero.
I mean, ground starts from zero,
not from one.
Yes, yes. Cold start from below.
It's also index based.
It's fine. You guys can ignore this error.
This log for the error is because
there was an issue with the log for DE
and they Apache boy guys.
They have removed that implementation
so that you guys are not one related but
to that issue
that there
was a vulnerability in the log for J
and the Apache.
You guys they have removed that log
for their from their libraries
so that you are not at risk.
NULL Pointer Exception Files Batch 11
Make sure you have data now.
Make sure you have data in sheet one.
Make sure guys
you have sheet one in your Excel workbooks
and make sure you have data
inside the sheet. One
I do.
And you guys didn't change the name.
Even if you put a space in here
while editing it,
it will not work.
Again.
Error
Can you guys show me your Excel files?
Can you guys show me your actual files?
So you should have
this in your Excel file And in here
you should write this code.
Please match your Excel file
and your job program with my
my program.
How to Hold on, Sebastian.
I will show you how to clean
navigating for ready.
Let's go.
Step by step.
It's fine.
It's fine if you guys are getting
that logger error, you'll get the.
You don't have to write new keyword
after the sheet.
Remove that new keyword.
You see, I don't have new keyword in here
before the get sheet
these please guys, please make sure
that you have the exact same code
More than
please delete your operating system
and reinstall it again.
I hope it will resolve your issue.
It needs to stop
something wrong on line 17.
So I guess you guys are doing this
this mistake.
Are you guys passing this file in stream
to this constructor?
Ramon, this is your issue.
You are not passing this file
in stream to this constructor.
All of those who
are getting issues on line number 17 guys,
make sure you passed the object of file
input stream to this excessive
workbook.
Okay?
Yes. Let me copy the code
and send it to you.
Can you please tell about indexing it?
Same as the error is the start from
index zero.
The excel rose themselves.
They also start from zero.
So those who want to go on the break,
you guys can go on the break.
We will be back by 1145.
Those who are facing issues.
Stay with me.
I will resolve your issues. Now.
It works. Yes.
Because you are not you are not passing
this file in stream object.
I think I am getting an issue with my jar
file.
Let me make this break to
50. Please post.
In this Portner and guys resolve
what issues
mine kept trying to cast modeling.
That means that you have not imported
the jobs properly.
I thought I was the only one
making mistakes.
Your file don't work
prints create your own file.
If my file is not working.
Oh, maybe because you have
you guys compressed control.
As of writing this data in the Excel file,
nobody's gone on break
it slower.
Could not find a exception.
An internal pointer exception.
It is the issue with the data files
and a tundra
glass loader issue with the data files.
This is the error I am getting
no class def.
So all of these issues?
No class, therefore class is not found.
They are all the issues with your files
guys.
You have to import 18 jobs from the lib
folder, all access x
and mail folder and the six data files
that are outside of these folders.
There should be 18 jobs in your project.
NULL pointer
exception. You'll get to show me.
Show me your file from the intel.
So what you guys are doing, you'll be
you guys are storing the data in this
file, which is outside of the intelligent,
but inside the intelligent.
The file that you guys are reading
data from.
It does not contain any data.
So you guys have to store the data inside
this file.
Let's control s and then update this file
the intelligent alphabet.
If you guys open this
x x x log book,
merge or you guys will see
there is no data in here.
Make sure guys the updated file is present
inside intelligence
or use the part of this
file.
This one
that you have placed on your computer.
These are great
with our batch
you don't need any life to on your mind
we are doing they're just perfect.
Yep yep yep.
Control. Yes yeah.
You guys have never worked with files
just furious
with it. With the Excel files.
How many of you have never opened
an Excel file before?
Before this class?
It's fine.
It's fine If you don't have opened
the Excel files in your life.
But just curious.
Just want to know how many of you haven't
Will error
in this file is not working.
Sebastian
Ellen,
can you share this screenshot of your data
files?
A in the file not found,
but you see in your file folder
you have a space between batch and 11,
but in the bottom that you are mentioning
you are not specifying the space.
Abdul This.
Please pay attention to these small things
like spelling
of your files,
the spellings of your sheets.
You have proper data in your Excel files
before
you try to read them.
Finally, user
most of our documents
you are missing
that do not excel at sex extension.
Most of also this part.
I don't know if a file is present
on this part or not,
so right click on must have ordered
x less sex and on that file
there is the neck of Aisha and me.
Sebastian, we are next.
You have removed the next.
Now the issue with the job files.
Did you say I am missing data files?
Yes. Tundra.
Either you are missing the data files
or the Either
you have imported the wrong data files.
So when we modify the files
outside of intelligence, we save control.
S Yes, we save control. S
And it does save that file
inside the intelligent.
We have to do that separately.
And then you are importing the complete
folder that void or to bin folder.
Remove the last two imports.
Click on that and press
that minus sign on the top.
Shiva, are you with us?
Yes. Now, if you modified the data,
you have to do it again.
Shiva, can you start a meeting and
can you show them how to import the jars?
So there are a lot of students,
a lot of facing the issues with the jobs
or maybe I can show you guys. So.
Shiva okay, I will show you.
You check the other issues. So guys,
if I go here
and if I go to file,
so let me repeat it again.
Nice.
You'll get
I will explain how it is working.
So file and then if you click
on project structure,
so you guys should see something
like this.
Okay,
You guys should see something like this.
Now how I have imported these files.
So the first thing that I did,
I went to this website,
this Apache poi,
and I went to this downloads
folder in here.
Okay, so this download folder.
So I see this binary distribution
and I see this source of distribution.
So remember, guys, we have to use this
binary distribution.
Abdul
You are not putting a space on line 15
and you have a space
between the name on Batch 11
and that and other space
between before that extension.
Please make sure you remove those spaces
or you change the part accordingly.
So because I am using windows,
I will be downloading
this boy being a door to zip file.
Those who are using Mac, you guys should
download this dot b g that file.
Yes. Let me handle
those who are facing DOT issues.
Are you guys clear on this? You
the Mac users?
I made those changes, Abdul just
just give me one moment.
So don't make Mac users.
You guys have to go to this link
and the windows later.
You guys have to go to this dot the link.
So because I'm using windows,
I will be opening the second link
and then I can use any of the link
to download these DOS.
And once I have downloaded these jobs,
I will navigate to the folder
where I have downloaded these jars.
So for example, if I click on open folder,
I see this zip file in here.
Do you guys see this zip file?
Those who are facing issues
with the jar files, Do you guys see this
zip file in here?
After that,
do you have to extract those files?
Now, if you
don't have any program
to extract those files on your computer,
what you guys can do,
you guys can install that program.
It's called when they are
and if you type
now they are on Google.
You can download the software in here
and then you should see
exactly the same view as I have.
Guys.
Everyone, please download this video
audio out as well.
Windows and Mac users both
let me know what you guys have installed
this vignette.
Do you guys know how to install a program
on on Mac or Windows out
and install a new program?
Guys, do you know how to install
a new program on your computer?
Okay, so download
this like for example, clicking here
and you guys don't need to buy this.
You will see this download button in here.
Yes. This free word
and this is the free one,
dark blue one.
Let me send you the link.
But it might be different
for the Mac and Windows users.
So let me and this link in here. If
so, click on download
and then click on this blue button in here
and then you should start the download
process.
Okay,
So I see it in here.
I click on download
and then it is downloaded.
Now you guys have to install this program
on your computer, so if you guys double
click on this program, they will not
air will be installed on your computer.
Let me know what you guys are done
installing.
We're not at
now, do you guys see this icon on this?
It will be good
if you guys install all of them.
If you guys install it
because then it will be processed.
Will be same
for all of the Windows and Mac users.
If you guys have this program.
Yes. Maria, it is installed.
Yes, it is.
And so now
you going to close this window now?
I was going to have you install it
and the others who are
getting that issue.
So now right click on this file
and click on extract all.
If you do that, you
it will ask you to a part that you guys
don't need to click anything.
Just click on extract.
Okay And because I have already extracted
this file, so I get this notification
to replace these files, most probably
you guys will not be getting this option.
Mac does not have that option.
Oh, that Mac is.
It's killing me.
Which of which option is not present
on Mac, not school.
The right click option is not available.
Next step up to is not available.
Do you see this icon on that dot pd
z file?
Yes. Even you guys not near the we not our
so so everybody's so desperate
to exchange the left house.
I am afraid he will just steal a macbook
from his neighbors or something like that.
Pretty easy.
Is he the Mac folks.
Is there a
is there a mac user who can tell us
how to extract the files?
Guys, can someone help Nas? Will
Yes, we are doing something new.
You'll get them.
So once you have extracted those files,
you should see a folder
like this.
And if you open that folder,
you should have another folder
in here.
And in here you should see these $8
outside of this lab
and all all x and mail folder
and five jobs in here
and six jobs in here.
Now, what you guys can do,
you open, maybe copy all of these jobs
outside of this folder
in here
so that you have
all the jobs in a single place
and all you have to basically import
all of these dos, excluding, obviously,
this license and all this. Yes.
I show you for those who have jobs
problem.
Okay,
So let me undo it.
So now you have to go to the invalid.
Then you have to click file
and then project structure
and then click on this
plus button to import the jobs
and make sure you are on modules
s that batch 11 and on dependencies
you should select.
You should have these dependencies in here
selected based added any and modules
your project name
and dependencies tabs from here.
And then you have to click on this
plus button.
Do you guys see this plus button
break is about to over
about learn
your guitar and everyone else bigger.
See this plus button,
click on that plus button
and then you have to
select jobs or directories.
And now you have to go to that folder
where you expect to do your jobs.
So for example, in my case,
I accepted it in downloads compressed
and then inside this port
and I have to expand this lib
and this folder.
Now hold down your shift or control
button and select
all the jars from here
and then you have to click okay
index to resolve your issues.
Yes, break is over.
Now, if you guys still
if you guys are still facing
issues, please post an export channel
and fix your issues.
Nothing in my lib folder.
That means you have downloaded
the wrong jobs Maria or you have deleted
those jobs from that lib folder.
Right
guys?
So how many of you see go in here?
How many of you see the data in here?
Now we can get the whole sheet as a
well, I will teach you how to do that.
Okay.
So can you guys
tell me if I have to get this $5?
What should I change inside this code?
So this is on still delete.
All right, But it is on now.
Column cell one.
So if I can do this to sell one,
you give me one place.
It has changed.
Let me copy it again.
So you copy
and paste
it did not print the dollar
sign and it give an output as a double.
Mohammad,
are you using the same code as mine?
And you got this behavior
You guys are
getting 5.0.
Make sure you guys are using that cell.
Can you share the code?
Those who are getting 5.0.
I will show you how to get as different
as a double value,
but let's not go there still.
Let's just learn
how to get the values from Excel.
For now, I will tell you how to convert
those data types to doubles.
Are integers or anything like that.
Okay.
Did you guys store a store
the dollar sign with your cell as well?
I mean, if you store five in your cell,
you will not be getting the dollar sign
and you updated the Excel file
inside the intelligence.
Well, right
then, once you have stored that
and you'll see the dollar sign
in the Excel, but you don't see it in the
in the Java program
or you place it before the
dollar sign because Excel can do
the convergence automatically.
If you place the dollar sign before, it
will automatically convert it to a number.
So that's why I have this dollar sign
after the number
after that, because
it's your Excel guys
excel always doing it.
These automatic convergence, it's
fine it's fine if you
if you get the delta fine 5.0 or $5
both are fine.
Accountants would know
silver Simon
out of there
you guys don't need to upgrade Right now
we are just learning how to get the data
from themselves at all rows.
It's Fine.
So now can you guys
tell me if I want to get this thing?
How can I do that?
My husband dialed me.
It said, Copy that.
So I should.
So this is row zero.
This is one two, three, four.
Right.
So I should say,
get me the dollar number four,
and then this is self zero
and this is cell one, right?
So if now I execute my program,
I see King in here.
Do you guys see the king in here?
One hand is good, but two is great.
All right.
So this is this is simple thing, right?
Getting the from different cells and then
using it by specifying the raw numbers
and by specifying
the column numbers, we can get data
from different different rows.
Right.
Easy peasy.
I see Queen.
I am sensing that we will use it for loop
to get all the data
and definitely definitely
nested for loops.
Your your favorite part is coming now,
so let me put more data in
so let's say and this time nice.
This time let's use the external part.
So say
our first
name.
Last name
is City
being Alexa, age 300
and City.
What is your city Loops?
You guys don't like loops.
It's Alexa.
Which city you belong to?
Okay,
but answers are urban
and minus.
Well, you
or not being is 23 and princess 22.
It does not look good.
Uh, maybe 30 is the right way to go.
Dark mode.
And please focus on the glass.
We will do this dark light thing later on.
If someone were to leave their city
is this bright?
I think if you open this file in Excel,
it should be dark.
Let me check.
Here we go.
But still, the cells, they are white.
So if you have excellent
you are using black.
I like your that good. Thank you, Silver.
So if you guys are using
black team on your windows,
then I hope you you can get something.
But the cells still there,
they are still white.
Marvin
amongst stole my sunglasses.
So you think that is okay to have to get
okay,
okay.
Let me make the kid ten years old.
Is it okay now?
They're still bad. You or you?
You want everything black?
Okay, do this.
Select all the cells and then
do this.
Now everything is black
and I can see the text as well.
Are you happy?
No, Much better.
So, urban, What is your city?
You guys will never be happy. Yes.
And then turn the text. Why?
Are you okay with numbers, please?
Sure. Number two, with your finger.
It is number two.
Man. Is it same
city?
And let me put another value
now, let's say, and
let's imagine, guys,
we have so many cells in the
we have so many cells in this Excel
Excel sheet.
Right.
And we want to read all of them now.
It will be hectic if we type those cell
values, rule values all the time, right?
So guys, please make sure that once
you insert this deck, die
in your Excel sheet,
you are storing that, that otherwise
you will be getting null point
that exceptions.
So this is the deadline
and copy paste thing.
And so this is my file
vegetarian wondered Xl6
Abdul is issue result
as God is hiding his age.
Okay, let me
put my correct page
so so open up it again and make sure
you have your Excel data in here.
Okay? Now
let's create this
new program to detect.
Not yet.
I am working with Shiva.
I will make a video next time.
Maybe I'll import jobs
and create these Excel files
and things like that
so that you guys don't waste time
because it's hard to follow
when you are facing issues.
Right?
It's also fine.
Maybe you guys can focus now on
on the content
and maybe you can fix your issues later.
How many of you are still facing issues?
How many of you are still issues?
One, two, three, four, five,
six. Mine
resolved.
So guys, please join the meeting
and that you are left
the class for a few minutes
and join the meeting.
Apparently those doors
don't like the open office.
Elon, did you have the same extension as?
Exodus six?
Because if you have the same extension,
it does not matter if you have OpenOffice
or Excel
who try to use my file.
The file that I have sent to you
guys try to use my file,
let me send it again.
Try to use this file,
place it inside a folder and make sure
that you are placing that file in a folder
for which you know the part.
So for in my case
it's a C user as the Nazarene backstop.
Okay. So.
All right.
So again, I have to read the data.
The first thing that I need is
string. But
and I have seen users
going to their desktop and then
the name of my file, which is batch
11 naught x l.
S s, right.
Like this.
So let's not use the file in here
from the intel at this time
so that you guys know how to read the file
from anywhere on your computer.
Are you guys able to figure out the
part of your file Excel file
in guys?
Have you
figured out the part of your Excel files?
Okay.
What is the next class that I need
if I want to
If I want to read the data from a file,
I the file input stained glass.
All right.
So far, import
stream is equal to nil file bursty
and I need to pass the path in here.
And if I want to specifically work
with Excel files,
what is the that special class that I need
from Apache for
s x s ISF workbook?
Right.
Access stuff workbook.
Is it worth the new access book?
And what should I pass inside this
constructor?
Guys, the file import stream object.
Right.
The file input stream object.
And now how about your mouse in here
and add exception to the method signature.
All right,
so I have this file
in here, and inside this file
I have sheet one.
Right, I have sheet one.
So I will get this.
Good. You repeat
what is excessive workbook?
So your raw data is converted
in the form of an Excel file
using this class and this object
file in raise the data
in the form of raw bytes
in the form of zeros and ones.
This this excessive workbook object
will convert that to excel file format
then this is a clear
multi this
and if I want to get this sheet,
yes, we will print everything.
If we want to get sheet
I can use this excessive workbook object.
I can say get sheet.
And what is the name of my sheet.
The name of my sheet is capital
S at the ability sheet and then one
and now
I can maybe use all enter
to introduce a local variable.
Right.
So I have this sheet one from this x
as a self workbook.
Do you guys get this sheet
one from this exercise workbook
without any errors?
Now, if I want to look through this
data, guys,
I must to know how many rolls
contain the data.
Right?
And how many columns contain the data,
then I can write maybe for loop, right?
So that I don't keep iterating
these empty cells in here.
Right?
I don't want to upgrade them.
I only want to know how many cells
and columns the data.
And then I can write a loop
to print out the data
from those cells and rows.
So if
I say
sheet dot, get
physical number of rows,
let me rename it to something simple
number of rows.
Okay,
so this get the physical cell number.
That physical number of rows,
this method will return me
the number of rows that
are not empty.
So if I printed this out,
I get four right?
And if I go to my sheet,
I have one, two, three and four rows.
Right.
So you have got the number of rows
that actually contains the data
from this sheet in the seat in the.
Do you guys got the same
where did you get the string part.
So I drew I have placed this for this file
on my computer.
So for example, inside this folder.
So if I click my mouse inside this address
bar, it gives me this address.
So I copied this address and then I batch
11 dot Excel as after that
in here
based on that file in here
and then append this batch 11 dot.
I go to that there. Now how many
arrows in your in your excel file,
how many those contain the actual data
we are using cheat.
So when we are using sheet,
I have just changed
the name to sheet one.
Okay, let me know what you guys are done,
but do not make sure you press.
You are pressing control
as if you don't save.
The data in your Excel file Java program
will not be able to read it properly.
We use excess as a sheet. Yes.
Or it's all also fine
sheet or excessive worksheet.
Then they are both fine.
So they are both fine.
So can I move forward?
Are you guys getting the same output
file not found?
It is.
You are not specifying the file name.
You see after this memory I have specified
the name of the file as well.
Batch 11 dot Excel as you.
You are not specifying that order
two more backward slashes
and then write
the name of the file as well.
What is the issue?
And you cannot resolve
the access of workbook.
Nabeel, You are using the wrong imports.
Make sure that the import
they are from here.
So you should have these to import.
Let me do mine.
Both.
Please use these imports.
Hossam
You also got the error file not found.
You also have not specified the
this the name of your Excel
and the extension.
Right?
Because inside that folder
there can be so many files.
And so, for example, in my case,
you see I have so many files.
How do I know
I am specifically looking to this file?
I have to specify the
name of that file as well.
It will install for me
for some reason.
You have to print that out.
Put that
said hi.
I hope I'm pronouncing your name properly.
You have to get
the physical number of rows
and then you have to print those out
as well.
And guys, make sure everyone
is saving your files before
you run your Java program.
Otherwise
you guys might get different results.
Some here now.
I got it now. Thank you.
Is there anyone else
who is getting any issues?
Nabeel, is your visual field.
Someone else was getting two rows
and now you getting two rows.
After any change in Excel file,
it should be saved.
Yes, it should be saved.
Farhad,
make sure you are saving your file.
And there are four rules
in your Excel file.
There are four roads in an Excel file
and you are storing that file
and also you are reading the same file.
Make sure guys,
you are reading the same file
because I
think you guys are still reading that file
from the previous file
because that file had two rows
I have created.
This is a new file that I have created
and I have saved it.
Are you guys still using the old file?
Because that file had two rows
and yes, one is on your computer
and one is your intelligence.
If you are using the file from
intelligence, you have to save that file.
Soon it will be clear what is the issue.
Those are getting two rows.
Soon it will be soon it will be clear
when we will be printing the data.
Not very soon.
It will be clear, don't worry.
So now I got the number of rules
that are present inside.
Seems like 2 minutes.
And you still you will start yelling.
Okay, so guys,
we now have the number of frauds.
So now what I can do,
I can start a follow loop, right?
I can start to follow to get all the rules
one by one.
So for example, if
from this sheet, if I say sheet dot,
get roll, if I write zero,
I will be getting the raw number
zero, right.
If I say
you guys don't have to follow me in here.
So if I type discord manually for lines,
then I will be getting all those four rows
right.
How can I use a loop tool
to get this number zero from three?
I can save for?
I starting from 0l4
and I can write this once.
Right?
And if I boss I in here, will
I get the same behavior guys as this one?
Then will
I be able to get all the rows one by one?
Then this loop will execute
starting zero till three.
Do you guys understand
what how this loop is?
Will give me the same results
as this one. Yes.
I should be using the number of rows
to make it more generic.
Okay.
So you have replaced number of rows
because it is also returning before.
Right?
Is there anyone who's confused about this
loop over this loop is going
right so I can remove this one.
Right? This is Manuel I'm using.
So once I get a row,
so let's say A for the first start
duration, I will be on this row.
Right?
This rule has one, two,
three and four cells.
So what I can do,
I can again get the number of cells
as well in that specific row.
For example, if I say integer number of
cells, I can get the actual number
of by saying row door
to back the physical number of cells.
Can you guys tell me for the first start
duration what
this physical number of cells
will return me
for? Right.
Because there are one, two, three
and four cells in my program right?
And now
I have this number of cells.
I can write another loop. Right.
Who got the data
from all the cells? One by one.
So I can say and I can write
another loop de is equal to zero.
J is less than number of cells.
And now if I say
the row lot that cell
and I boss J in here
and if I print this out
and let's put a space as well in here
and after this inner loop,
let's put a printout in here
so that each row is printed in a new line.
So now if I execute this program,
I should use print, not print.
And then
let me executive edit
So now I get all of my data, all of my
with the help of two loops,
one loop is going through all the rows.
One by one, the inner loop goes through
all cells one by one.
Do you guys get the same results?
How many of you have understood
how these loops are working?
I get an error with what I tell you, J.
If you have used
this I somewhere else
you will be getting an issue. Now.
You guys want me to debug this code
and explain how it is working?
Okay.
Let me debug disqualify you.
Okay. Please focus in here.
So I placed the debug point in here
and then I am saying
I am saying debug so.
Okay. Perfect.
So right now I am on this line, right?
Printing out the number of rules.
So I know that there are four rows.
That's why I started an outer loop
to go through those rows one by one.
So when I say
step over, I start the loop from zero.
Right?
So right now the value of I is zero.
So if the value of I is zero
and I call this get or method
which row it will return me.
Guys, if I say sheet one dot get roll
and I pass zero,
I am passing I in here
which roll it will return me.
It will return to me First row, right?
The first row.
And once I have the first row.
How many columns
are there in the first row?
How many cells are there in the first row.
Four.
So this row door
to get the physical number of cells.
What? So that return me guys
inside the first row
I have one, two, three, four
and I am saying
hey Java from this roll
that I have got in the above line
that tells me how many cells
actually contain the data.
Tell me how many cells actually contain.
So Java is saying that
there are four cells.
So I start an other loop and that loop
starts from zero till three
because this is on
index zero, this is one, two and three.
So when I say row door to get cell
and right now the value of J is zero base.
So if you observe J is zero.
So if I say from first row, if I say
get me the value of cell zero,
which values should I get? Dies
the first name in here.
Right? This first name.
So if I open my console, if I say Sister
dot out row zero got cell
I got the first right first name right.
And if I say row zero, get to cell one
which value I should get
the last name right.
The row is still zero.
And now I am saying you're told that
Hey Java,
give me the next value from the next cell.
So if I execute it again,
I get the last name.
And because I am using print not println,
so all the data will be printed
in the same rule in the console. Right.
And the space is also printed in here
in between.
Then I say again, Hey Java,
give me the data
from the first row and cell two.
So I get it.
And then if I say a city, I get again.
Right now the inner loop
is it
will be terminated after four iterations
right?
Because we have four.
So now we will
go back to the outer loop again.
So now we print a new line in here.
System board.
Also data is printed on this new line,
and this time
what will be the value of eyeglasses?
For the second iteration
of the outer loop?
The value will now change one,
and if I save one, it means rule, right?
Getting like the third B and the city.
So this time I will repeat
this inner loop again from 0 to 4.
But this time the rule is a second.
So I am repeating same thing,
but this time the row is two.
So I will get all the cells
that are from the second row.
Then I repeat it again.
I put the third rule, I repeat it again
and I keep on getting all the data
like this. Is it clear now
if cell two is blank, the loop ends there.
Therefore, that role,
because the number of cells is dynamic,
we will discuss that as well.
Dammit,
we will discuss those issues as well.
Don't worry.
You remind me at the end of the class
let's let's go step by step.
There is there is another method
which will give you
the value of the last cell
that contains the data.
This cell is actually telling you
how many rows actually have the data.
Okay,
we will use that matter most probably
we can.
You guys can color your cells.
You guys can write formulas.
You guys can do anything
that you guys can do
with Excel using the as a particle.
But we will not be discussing that.
I will teach you how to do that.
But you guys don't need
the Excel formulas, right?
Because You guys can write your
own formulas as well In Java
now you have all the data from Excel here.
Do you guys can play with that data
as you want? Yes.
You you don't need dividual basic anymore.
Dammit.
After learning this you will not you
you can do every all of your processing
java.
Or is there any one guy or guys
who would not understand
how we are getting all this all this data.
So we use this program for big data like
test or different log ins and passwords?
Yes. And do automatic testing in test
cases.
Yes. Alex. Yes.
Access us from sheet one or two.
Get real.
Farhad, can you show me your import?
Most probably you are not importing it
from the proper classes.
Please use these imports
or let me actually
copy and paste
my code.
Yes, but remember guys,
you have the change.
The port
java dot util
and you guys are looking
for shortcuts everywhere.
Yes there is.
There is a short one,
but it can create problems as well.
These are always, always before
for the individual imports.
They are always preferred
because what happens
is that when you put that star
Java taught you to stop, all the classes
from that package will be included.
Your program.
So there there is a lot
how to do optimizations and all that.
Then your code is compiled
from source to binary.
So we never want to do that.
Start all means import
all the classes from that package.
It's not good.
Okay, so it's clear. It's clear right
now, guys,
instead of just displaying this data,
let's let's try to store this data
in Some kind of data structure
does have a replica of the library is
which libraries the Excel Apache boy ones.
No I don't think so. Excel has this one.
We have to import it manually.
Yes, it's pretty simple.
So instead of just printing out this data,
guys,
let's try to store that data
in some kind of data
constructor,
maybe in arrays or maybe in maps
or something like that.
Can you guys suggest any data
which data structure can hold the rows
and columns to
the ADD is right
to the arrays can hold the data
or but to the errors they again,
we have to specify the size in front of.
They don't have a ready made matter.
Did they have a lot of issues? Right.
So can I can
I build a combination of maps and list
or science
or something like that, distorted Data.
So let me copy this
main method from here. So
yeah, let's based
it in here.
All right.
So now this is important, guys.
This can confuse you.
So I want you to focus everyone.
So the data structure that we will be
using, it's very important.
You guys will be using same data structure
in your frameworks.
So what I will do,
I will create a map.
First, I will create a map.
The key of the map will be this header.
So I will say
let me actually
give me one moment.
So I will say
just first name as the key
and what should be the value of this key
for the first row,
the value will be in,
then the second key will be last name
The value will be
Alexi.
Oops.
Then the third key will be age.
The value will be 30, 40 will be city
and the value will be
is it five?
Am I pronouncing it right?
Then I will.
I will build another map.
No. So again,
the key will be Eve.
So the key will be first name? No.
Okay, let's forget about this.
And this time.
This time the value will be
prints.
Sorbonne.
Then in this.
And then I will build another map.
The key is will be.
And I am creating these new these maps.
They are new. Okay?
Each time I'm creating a new map.
So, Asger
and Z 27.
And now.
So I.
If I have three rows, I will be having
I transport metrics.
If so, I will be having three maps
right.
Is let's call it map one.
Let's call it
map to
and looks like map three.
Can I do this guys.
Can I create three maps and in each map
can I stored the data like this?
Guys, do you understand what I am doing?
I am creating three maps
separate maps
different from each other
and putting this data in here.
And then now
there will be too many maps
if if there are too many of those.
Right.
So let's put these maps inside a list.
So I will then create a list.
And on the index number zero,
I will place this map one
on index.
Number two, I will place
this map to
and then this map to the right.
All you guys can think of.
I will wrap this these maps.
I will create a list and each
index of the list
zero index
one or two will be having a map.
Right?
So I have built a custom data structure
with the help of maps
and loops to store this data.
And as per your needs in real life,
you guys can also use these different
vector structures that we have learned
in the collections framework
to store different types of data.
Now, if this thing makes sense,
I will write the code for you.
But if this thing is not making sense,
please ask me questions
right now.
Actually, let me keep this image
so that you guys can
therefore put it to later all.
So I will keep this image in here.
Okay. But
so let me remove this.
Oops, it's
okay. And
this time let me open this picture
in here.
So you guys remember this picture, okay.
It will help
you understand what I am doing.
So this code of ours is already working
fine right now.
It shows,
but instead of printing out the data
we want to store that data
in the form of maps for each row.
For each row.
Want to create a new map.
Yeah. So.
And this will also help
you understand the ripple tools.
Zero nine So first I am creating a list.
Inside that list.
I have a map.
And inside that map, let's
to keep things
a simple let's use settings.
Okay,
So do you guys understand
how I have created this data structure?
I created a list inside the list.
I have a map.
So each index of
the list,
it will actually be storing a map
Do you guys understand
this, this data structure,
how I am creating a list of maps.
So previously you guys were storing
personal tags,
string of diverse numbers, and different
different things inside the list.
This time I am storing
maps inside the list.
This is possible.
You can store lists inside of the maps or
maps inside the list or list inside this.
Basically, you can create any combination
of data structure.
So I have created a list of maps
and before each row
I will create a new
so I will say hash map.
String
string hash map is equal to nil
hash map.
So before each row.
So this outer loop is
is going through the rows, Right?
So before I enter this inner loop,
I always create a new map.
And inside this map, inside
this map, what do I do?
I say,
So let me show you how
to do without the map, without the loop.
So I will say hash dot put.
And what will be my key?
My key will be
first name
and what will be my data?
My data will be a rows zero door
to get cell zero.
Right.
And then I have to do those things as well
so that the data is converted.
Boasting
it is said before that class will be hard.
Is it not making sense, guys?
It will be clear.
Just give me one moment
and last
name, age
and city.
So cell zero.
Cell one.
Cell to
cell three.
Okay,
focus on this code codebase for each row.
For each row
I am creating a map
and inside that map
is something we will use a lot at work.
So you guys will create
the readymade methods for this
and then you will be using those methods.
You guys will not be writing it again
and again only once inside
your project.
Yeah.
So from each row
I get the value of cell zero.
What for?
For the row one.
What will this cell
zero will return me right? Yes.
You guys will be having access
to the frame loads,
but it's better to tool to understand
it as well
so that you guys can do the modifications.
Yes, it will take time.
No. Later
we will be getting the first name right.
If we want to get the game,
we have to start the outer loop
from which index
I start at the alternate days
if I want to directly jump
to get start of first name,
I should say one in here
right.
And I created the hash map.
I put it back in here. Right.
Let's not use this loop. And that's
that's it.
You have successfully stored the data.
And one last line.
We have to store this map
inside the list as well.
So Excel that are both ADD and that
hash map.
All right, next loop.
So when this loop will be done executing,
No, I want you to type it, Katrina.
It will be good if you type it.
But let me send this to.
Okay, So after the loop, if I print out
my list of maps, why we change it to one?
Because if I change, if I don't change
I to one,
it will read the first name
last name, ID and city as well.
And it will sort that
that I want to exclude that first row
because they are headers
line 32.
I am storing that map inside the list.
Mohamud storing
that map that I created the list,
the list that I created in here.
We don't need it.
Later on I will replace it with the loop.
Then you will be needing. Okay.
Right now we don't need assignment
right now.
We don't need
a Why don't we read the keys?
But putting them again,
Yes, we will do that.
But to let's let's go step by step
so that you guys understand at the end
I will make everything dynamic.
You guys will not be hard
coding any single thing,
but just make things simple.
So if I execute this program, guys,
I get a list.
And inside each list there is a map.
So this is a map inside
a list at index zero that contains
the as first name value as E as,
last name value
as a city, value as your key or whatever
it is.
Then on the second index,
you see this comma
on the second index
in here and here
I have first name, name Prince,
last name for bond and city.
Then age.
Then you have another map
that has the data from the row
number three.
Is it clear, guys?
Do you guys get the same results?
Are you guys able to see all of your data
in the form of list of maps?
Yes. Let me change the clock.
I hope you feel better.
Silva okay.
So tell me
how many of you don't understand
what is going on
so that I can debug this code for you.
It's fine if you guys don't understand.
I will debug this code for
what is tool string.
So all the data is ready
in the form of objects.
I am converting it to string because
I have created this map of strings.
If you make an object off,
if you make a map of objects,
do not need to load that those string.
Can you
send issue?
Here is my excel file.
Okay, let me debug it for you.
So I need to place a debug client. Right.
What is my list?
Automate list sorted on yours is not
are it depends.
Are you using array list and hash maps.
If you want the data in in a sequence
you can use a link to the hash map
Simon in here.
Then you will be getting
the same business.
Let me actually replace it
with linking the hash. Mark
It's always good to store
the got in linked hash map
so that we retained that order
from the file.
So before the debugging,
I need to place the debug point.
So I place a book
point in here. Then I see
the debug.
So initially I create is the font readable
days.
Okay.
So first of all, I create a list of maps.
Okay. Like this, a list of maps.
But right now this list of maps is empty.
Okay, it's empty.
So I put into the number of no,
that is not required.
So I get the first row
with the help of I'll provide loop
and I create a new map.
Right now, this first
row that I have got, it
contains the data in
in all the cells, right?
If I say road or to get cell zero,
I will gain.
Right.
Because I am starting the loop
this time from one.
So I am actually on this road
second, dropping like Z, part B and this
so I am saying row
zero, get me the value of cell zero.
So it will give me king
So I break this. KING
And I store in here inside this map.
And the key that I am using is first name.
Then I pick the second value
because I am specifying cell one
and I store that inside the map
with the key last name.
Then I put the third value
in here and I save it inside the map.
The form of the key. It.
Then I pick the last value.
And I started as with the key city.
So now I have a map.
Now I have this map created
and filled with the data
and now I am storing that map.
I am saying Excel data,
which is this list.
I am saying Excel data
or that and I am putting this map
inside that list at index zero.
Is it clear, guys,
or there is something that is confusing
for this first iteration?
The rest will be same.
The only thing that will change
for the second iteration,
we will simply replace the first row.
So if you check this hash map
at the bottom, first
name King, last name, Alexi, age 30,
and the city is also saved.
I am still confused
the, uh, nine row number 19 domino.
Not a line number on the right.
Number 19 is very simple.
I am hoping that the map inside the list,
just as I put the string inside the list
and number inside the list.
A person object inside this.
This map is also an object.
I am putting that object inside the list,
storing that object
inside the list at index zero.
So you can see you can do that.
Yes. Alex, We moved the data from Excel
to our hash map.
Yes, you are right.
So once the once the map is filled
with the data guys
from the row number one.
So right now, if you see this Excel
that at least it has a size zero, right.
It does not have anything.
The moment I see Excel that are not
and to what happens in here
excel that are not bad.
Now this Excel data,
the size has changed to one
and if I expand this add index is zero.
I have a linked hash map of size for
if I expand that,
I have my data inside the list.
I have map inside of the map,
I have my data.
Okay.
If kind of nesting, I am putting one
data structure inside of the other.
Does it make sense?
Now come on now
let's.
So right now on index number zero,
I have the data
from rule number one.
So when I will be on the psyche
and I iteration,
I again create a new map, okay,
I create a new map as well.
I will share the code,
create a new map, and
I call it again, hash map.
This hash map again empty.
I will fill my code
the same like you still not working.
Mustapha,
can you please post in this port?
Why did you put I is the to one
Because I want to start getting the data
from this raw second the row
that is at index number one.
I want to get the data from here.
Not I don't I'm
not interested in the in the first row
because they are simply headers. Right.
I am interested in the actual data.
Lobo, is it clear?
Okay, so now I get the second row, right?
What? What? What?
This hash map, guys, First name prince
are last name
for born, then EJ.
And once I am done filling the second map.
So right now this Excel data.
Oops, this Excel data,
it has only one element.
The moment I say Excel that are not add
this excel
that I will now store two maps.
The first map contains for Ali
masking let's see 30 bla bla.
And now the second element contains
Prince or Bon Edge and City.
So now I have two elements in my list.
First element is a map
that has four entries.
Second element is also a map
that also has four entries.
And now I can repeat,
keep on repeating this loop
and I can put all the rows
from my Excel sheet inside this map.
Does it make sense now, guys?
Rafa to this picture.
Guys,
this code is doing exactly what I have
shown in the picture.
And once you guys
debug this on your computers,
it will make much more sense.
Do you guys have any questions
and you guys
can come up with your own data structure.
Does that mean you guys don't
necessarily need to use this exact purpose
structure? Yes.
You guys can create your own data
structures,
combining maps with the lists with starts
putting the you guys can put basically
any collection inside another collection.
So for example,
I can create a map of lists, lists,
array lists, so I can have anything.
So now I'm still hard coding these values.
Can I get these values from,
the Excel sheet as well, guys,
can I get these values
from the Excel sheet as well?
This first name, last name.
So this data in which wrote this
that I stored,
it is stored in the rows zero, Right.
So let me create one more demo.
Okay. We are going step by step, right?
Making it all dynamic. So
If I say
the role, the role
of zero or maybe role
zero like this is equal to
shade 1.2 get role.
And if I pass zero which do this this,
this line of code
which role it will give me guys
the role
that is that index number zero right
that contains the first name
last name a density
is it clear, guys,
if I write the score sheet,
one or two give give me the row
and I pass zero in here,
I will be getting the first rule,
the Excel sheet.
Is it clear
now? I can I can do the same.
I can say instead of first name I can say
role zero
dot get cell zero and then dot posting.
So this role zero get cell zero
what it will return me guys.
So basically you are telling the system
go to rule one by one.
Yes the first time when you do rule I in
row zero in my map that is set up here,
please put existing data
from every cell in my map. Yes.
So this the row zero cell
zero will give me the first name?
Yes. Let me me. It.
And if I want to
if I want to get the last name,
guys, let's write it in here.
If I want to log that last name.
It is also stored in zero zero
rows, zero
dot that cell.
And then I need to pass one in here
and then posting.
Right.
And then I can do the same
to get the image.
But this time I need to pass two.
And then for the city
also three empty.
Now let's execute this code.
Max. Execute discord.
So see, first name, last name ID and city.
Now I am not hard coding,
I am getting it dynamically
from the row zero
and there is one more thing guys.
Do you see some kind of pattern?
Cannot replace these four lines of code
with a single line.
And can I write a loop in here?
I am repeating the same line of code,
but sometimes I have
012, three, four right.
Can we delete line number 28?
Yes, that's deleted, but we will be
needing it in the next iteration.
Right? Yes.
Let me send decode.
So now we are one step
into this code making it dynamic.
So let's in the next demo
and I want you to observe.
This code dies after the class.
These steps they will help you understand
what is going on.
How come I am getting it first,
Jimi, can you share the code?
You let me copy
now I will be needing this
while I am getting an
null pointer exception
is due to an
on line
to undo five.
Make sure the city is
with proper case.
Make sure the in your excel sheet and logo
you have the city with the lowercase
and make make sure
there is some kind of data inside there.
So Okay.
If you leave any of the cells blank,
you will be getting an error.
All Yes, give me because I am
using the link, the hash map.
I changed it to link Kashmir.
Okay, so now
I know
how many cells are there
in my rows, right?
And with the help of this
get physical number of cells
so I can now save for.
I gave from zero to number of cells.
And instead of writing all of this,
I can replace it with
with, you
know, I don't need because I was repeating
four lines of code unnecessarily.
Right.
I can use a loop for there.
And now if I execute my code,
I again
see my data stored in the form of list
of maps, list of apps.
So you guys see now we are not hard
coding anything, right?
Everything is dynamic.
We are calculating number of cells
which contains the data dynamic.
The number of rows are dynamic,
number of columns are big dynamically,
everything is dynamic.
So this is what we
to build for our framework.
Okay, so this is how we get all the data.
Now, there can be thousand rows.
There can be 2000 columns
inside that Excel sheet.
This program will fetch all the data
from your Excel sheet.
Is it clear, guys?
It's a little tricky.
You guys need some practice.
You guys need
for debugging to play with this code.
Okay.
And maybe rewatch
this part of the video again.
So let's build
a config.
So let's build a specific class
because if every time I need
to read the data from the Excel,
I don't want to rewrite this code, right?
I can make a lot of mistakes.
I can introduce bugs.
So let's create a function out of this
code and every I have to read the data.
I will simply be calling this method.
So this is what you guys will be doing
or on your job.
So you guys keep on asking me as God
what will we do.
You guys will be me.
You guys just need to understand
how the functions work.
You guys will be calling the functions.
Everything has been billed already.
Java is there for 25 years.
Most probably be
the issues that you will be facing.
The solutions are already on stack,
the functions that you will be needing.
They are already built by someone
and they are already shared.
Open source are your companies.
They will be.
They have built all those functions.
So don't worry about jobs.
Jobs are a lot simpler.
And because you guys are seeing this stuff
for the first time, so no matter
even if this stuff is easy,
it will look harder
because there are a lot of data structures
and all of that in work.
So you guys will be good on your jobs.
Don't worry about that.
Yes, maybe we should take a break.
And if you guys are facing any issues.
Please
resolve your issues during the break.
How many of us ask for help from you
after getting job?
Honestly speaking, I am teaching
from batch it only four or three of them.
They ask for my help
and it was very simple.
They were unable to.
Maybe some one of the students left unable
to clone a project.
The other student has to test a website
that was written in Python.
That's why he needed the help.
And these are these were simple things.
No problem.
You will have plus 95 this time
it's four
plus 90. US.
So let's have a big case.
15 minutes are enough. 17 minutes.
Okay.
Please be back 17 minutes.
Take some rest.
Thank you so.
So this guys, they always stay the same.
So that's why I have extracted those keys.
I have extracted that raw
inside this raw zero variable.
That's the header. Right.
And from header, I always,
always get the same values for each key,
but for the rows, the cell,
because every cell can contain
different data,
write different different data.
So all always I get a new row
and that from that row
I got the corresponding value.
But row zero is always staying the same.
Why? Because I am for this role.
I use the same header for this role.
I use the same header for this cell.
I use the same header. Right.
So header is always sent
from here that I am getting the case keys.
They are always same.
Even if you look at the data.
The key
first name is same for the first row.
Again, I'm using the first name again.
I'm using the first name
so it always stays the same.
That's why I am not writing.
So in here I am getting new row each time,
but I am always using the zero in here
and now you.
Can you please
explain why we are rewriting after comma?
Uh, road or cell J
So this part now it is giving me the data.
For example, this one, this one one
this one one by one.
And this part is giving me these keys.
So, for example,
I, I get to the first name
using this piece of code in here,
but for the data,
I get the data
this king using this piece of code.
That's why we have the right place
first to get the key
and then the value has to store
that inside that map.
Are there other questions?
So code is
all about closing in the end?
Yes. Or one.
We will do that.
Yes, we will do that.
So Sorbonne is saying
we are not closing this file.
Interesting. Right.
So let's that as well.
So let's say file input stream,
but closed is a best practice.
Good practice
will always close those files.
So guides are how hard it was to read
the data
using loops
and storing that inside the list of maps.
Will you guys be able to understand it
if you offered the class?
Maybe watch this part again
and debug this code on your own?
Yes, I will be sharing
the exercises as well.
I will send it to the tab as well. Yes.
I want every one of you
to debug this code once and then
write this code on your own.
It's fine if you forget to.
You can look at the code, look at that
specific line that you forget.
Then again, hide that code and try try
to write it on own and it will be fine.
So let's create a method for doing that,
guys.
Let's create a method.
Let's practice some right now,
see if we get it right.
Yes, that's great.
Dammit.
So as we have created the config reader
and the materials, let's create
a specific utility class
to read the excel file
because every time I want to the data
from the Excel, I don't want to rewrite
this code again and again.
Right?
I just want to pass the name
at the part of the file
and I should get back
the list of maps from that method.
Right.
I want to create a method,
so let me check what is the name of that
inside your project
that you guys will be writing?
So you're scored Excel really?
So let's create a class, let's call
it accelerator. Yes.
So in here, let's create
the public start, the void
reader matter.
And this method, it only needs
one team, the part of the file
string.
But in simple,
we just need to copy this code from here.
Then here
and paste it in here
and add it to
method
signature.
And we don't want to print this out
and we don't need
to print this as well.
And let's return base
Excel. That
at the end.
Mark and I need to change
the written type in here.
So it should be a list of maps.
My port word is a read in here.
Inside this method.
Yes, there was the scope
here just for
the now we have created a method, right?
If this method takes the port
and it returns the data from that sheet
and maybe it will be good
if we can create a method that.
So right now
we are hard coding this sheet one right
so that I'm like be present
in a different sheet.
So what do you guys think?
Should I create a parameter
for that as well?
It will be good, right
to give this more flexibility
so someone can the sheet as of it
right instead of hard
coding.
Yeah. So now we have this really method.
Let's create
an overloaded version of this method
so that if someone is not passing
the sheet name,
then they can still be able
our program should still
be able to read from the
default
a default sheet right.
To give more flexibility
to the end ambiguous.
So I have one created.
I have created one method
that takes the sheet name
and the other one
that does not take this name.
It only takes the part
and maybe we can create another overloaded
button
that does not take the part as well.
And it will try to read the data
from these default files directly.
Then we can also do that.
Do you guys want me to do that as well
another overloaded virgin
that does not require the part as well.
So if I create another
overloaded virgin done and,
if I remove the part as well.
So by default it will try to read
the data from
file slash
batch 11 dot x less.
Yeah. What may be.
So I think the standard name
that you guys will be using for
let me check from the framework
and what will be the okay
let's call it x
so refactor rename
x so that none of them
are more genetically.
So let's change it to excel.
Next.
Yeah.
So now I am done
creating all those matters.
Okay.
Overloaded networks
then let me put some comments as well
for you so that you guys don't forget.
So So
building the raw data
from what
parameter
using
excessive server book
blast to
convert that and back to
excel.
Sorry we had is depart from again.
I have given this default
but you guys can give any
default but
the fun and then
you getting the feed from
excel file
with excel less x
I think excel s will also work fine.
Assignment.
Can you try that
assignment?
Can you try that Excel extension
if it works or not?
Thank you.
That thing, the
number of rows so small.
But is it better now?
You know better now
that actually
being the data
in list of
maps?
Yes, it works great.
Creating a list of maps to
for the data
from Excel file inside
Java all all the things
you are doing.
The real zero
to you there the header
so that we can use it as
he is in map
loop to get all the roles
from row
one one
by one. It's
you cannot
the second rule or not there thing
you draw one by one and
then the row of it
I just changed the extension.
You could make it or be expanded.
It would still work
as long as the file itself
is in Excel format, excluding them.
And so by changing just the extension.
Simon the internal structure,
it will still be same.
Can you please create a new file
using Excel
or any other program and by default,
save that file as excellence
from that accelerator program.
Then it will store the data
in a different structure.
By changing the extension, the internal
structure of the file is not change.
And these files stream.
It actually is the internal structure.
I think that's why that DOT properties
and text
file was also lacking because the internal
structure was still same
and storing them in virtual
variable
internally they have different structures.
The excellence file
and the Excel assets file.
Right?
I think is the difference about writing
some scripts or something like that
the older one gives that a right?
Yes, because it changes
the internal structure as well.
It's good if you guys just stick
to the standard file extensions and file
how you create those files.
There are other classes
to read other extensions,
but we will not be discussing them.
Creating a new
map for
each role to store
its data
in acting.
The of
actual cells that
contain the data.
So. So
if I show entire corner will not
will not be able to do it.
I think you is watching
this a smaller screen maybe.
I hope it is still
readable, looping
through
all the cells
so that
the data this is the entire code
inside this method.
Yes, I will send the code
inserting the data
inside the map
from there.
So building that map
to the list
and then closing the file.
So that other
programs can use it, and then
returning in the index.
Okay.
I hope it will help
you understand it after after the class.
So me since you.
All right,
so now if you guys have any questions
you guys can ask, so next,
let me check what we will be doing next.
We will be learning how to
how to create
new files.
Let me check if we are missing something,
Excel or
we started the exceptions.
And here.
Okay, all looks good.
Thanks.
It is very helpful.
Question would be
hell were all these lines of jobs,
these lines
they are reading the data from a fight.
So this is what you guys will be doing.
You you guys don't worry about the score.
So in actual what you guys will do,
you guys will just use this method.
We'll just see all of this method. So
Excel Demo six
So in your project for
you guys will do this
creative part
variable.
Let me copy it from the No,
I think it wasn't done right.
Create a part variable,
Pass this variable to
excel a reader
not read
and read the data.
See what you guys will be doing once
you have created that.
But definitely if you guys understand
what is going on inside this method,
then it will be
you guys will be able to modify, modify
that as well, right?
Introduce new features
may be having some issues in the
in the existing framework to
solve those issues
if you know how everything is working.
So list of maps
all string
and then string
excel that
use that method and
play with the Stata.
Whatever you want to do.
So that's why this is actually
this is how you will build your framework.
That's what we call the framework.
See there, blah.
The system cannot find the law
that I use the oh, I changed the
I changed the name of the class
Excel data.
Okay. What was the actual name?
It was batch 11.
Right.
Let me change it back.
Batch 11 right next to this
this budget.
So you see,
if you guys have gone through this
and you get any error, you
you guys will be able
to quickly figure it out.
But if you guys run a run from it,
you guys will not be introduce
new features
to the existing frameworks.
Even if someone has written
their framework for, you
it's okay
if you guys don't understand things.
If you at the that's how you learn right
the words more than the code.
Yes the comments
they are always more than the code.
Right.
So this is what you guys will be doing.
But definitely if you have understanding
what is going inside this raid
method, you guys will be at new features
and all that.
Please open demo six
This is demo six Madina
You can specify.
Yes, that was inside my intelligence
and because I was using this absolute part
and then I was specifying the name
that that's why I was unable to find it.
No, no, no.
I was using the absolute part.
So it was looking be a floor file excel
that are this part
C users to the index job.
That's why I got the error.
This is not
where I have stored the data right.
Marina, this is this is the demo six.
You mean this this file or the last one?
That accelerator.
Okay, one more thing.
Can you guys tell me
let's say, for example,
if I want to get this last name,
so I have successfully
read the data from the Excel,
but I only want
to get this name from here.
How can I do that?
Can you guys tell me this? A list?
And inside this list I have maps.
So first the list.
It has to get my third right.
Which element I should get from this list?
So this is stored on the index zero.
This is stored on the index tool.
Right.
So what's your date idea inside to get
And this is stored on the index.
Number three, if I want to get
saw one, why should I write
inside of this? Get
I should write one right.
Because this is at index number zero
and this is actually next number one.
Now, once I write index one,
I will get a map.
And if I want to get the value from a map
which method I can use,
I can then use that.
And what is the key for this name?
The key is lost me.
Okay, so if I execute this,
I get right from the list
on the second index.
I have that map
and that map contains the value
can you show line 13 how you get it,
please?
Line 13. This one has it in this one.
This line.
Well, this line.
You mean this?
I knew that this read method returns
a list of maps.
That's how I wrote it.
I knew.
I knew that this method returns a list.
But if you guys don't know that.
So, for example, if you guys are not sure
about the return type,
you guys can also take the help
of invalidate, can select all to enter
and then introduce local variable.
Okay,
so it will write it automatically for you.
But I will prefer that you guys write it
on your own so that you can understand
why this error appears
to be not.
Have you created the overloaded versions
of the method like I did?
Is there a method
that only takes the part?
Can you show me the screenshot of that?
So for example, in my Excel reader
I created three overloaded versions.
One only takes the part
one does not take anything
and one takes part and the sheet name.
So if you have this overloaded button
in here, then you should not be getting.
And also this public started.
They are public static methods.
Yes. How about your mouse over that?
And so you see, Katrina,
you have this weird
method that you have created requires
two arguments, a part
and a sheet name,
but you are only specifying the part.
So you need to specify the sheet as well
because you didn't create the overloaded
and then you send overloaded
method. Please. Yes.
Let let me send the complete accelerator.
Actually
actual Excel Excel.
Fine. Okay. Let me show
this is the actual Excel file.
Are there other questions
or should we try to create new files
now guys, no questions.
Everything is ouch.
My brain hurts after that.
Can we end early?
Silva, you are not feeling well.
You can leave.
You can watch the recording like later
Start.
Yes, you can take some rest.
You can watch the recording.
I will upload it right after the class
as soon as that is processed.
Let us cry little bit
and then we continue.
So now you guys understand that
that report 209 we were storing
maps inside of that list as well, right?
It was the same structure.
So I hope now
you guys will be able to understand that
more easily.
How about method? Yes.
If you guys don't specify anything,
then this method will work.
5 minutes break to go cry.
You guys have whole day after the class
you guys can try for next,
I guess 18 hours.
Then we will be having the next class
review class.
What is better looking at retrieving
the data properties of file?
So if you have data in the fall for
the first name, last name and all that.
So for example,
you are storing the data of a form.
You will be using Excel files
and if you are storing only username
passwords, only one key will appear.
Then you can use properties
file assignment.
I can't even cry
after the class need to grocery shop.
You can cry in the grocery store shop.
I maybe you will get a discount as well.
Maybe they will take
if you need to.
Some I will go to NYC for work.
People will be surprised.
You will get some discount as it well.
What was this page about?
I tried to look but I couldn't find one.
When did he deliver this speech?
At the end or in the start of the class.
He did not record or does not go there.
So that's why I didn't see that.
I kept asking to record it.
But you can do it.
Or I used to give a lot of speech,
so just just let me give you a motivation.
Base.
Do you know how much money you can make
if you know programing?
There is this
you guys know, remember the
remember
the meters from this string class raised
Nas good I think I Nas knows
so this is a very simple website
might be created by me
this method this website
what does if you put uppercase letters
it can convert it to lowercase.
Okay.
But money can help others write wars
and then needy people.
You can give your money to me.
If you guys don't like money,
I am ready to take all that money.
I will share my account.
You guys can all send your money
to my account.
They will be more than happy if you are
putting a smile on someone else's face.
Right.
It's also good.
Is I am single.
That's why I need the money.
So that I can get Mary right.
So this is a very simple website
converting the uppercase letters.
You guys can do that, right?
And using those things matters.
So this guy is playing some errors
in here, right?
Simple errors in here.
Now, let me show you how much money that.
So that guy just simply use this thing
methods.
And he created this website. Right?
So website world
calculator
I invented which
all singles are each
the estimated world of this website.
Is this how much money is?
This guy's
2.499 million
By just playing a single ad,
Do you guys know how much visitors he had?
Estimated Revenue per day 1493
Because he has so many visitors,
so many people use his website
to convert the data
to uppercase and lowercase.
And it's very, very simple.
40 4k per month.
So yeah, I mean, so
we estimated you guys don't know
the power of programing,
don't want the power of it,
that that's why you guys feel like this.
It is something
if you have huge impact
you guys can make a lot of money right
these celebrities why these companies,
they pay a lot of money to them
because they have a lot of followers.
Right.
So if you can impact a lot of people
by making maybe a soft or if you have fan
following or you are a celebrity
or anything like that, you
you can be super, super rich.
You guys can now create applications
that thousands can use here.
Come to my speech
because you guys asked for it, right?
I have so much material to motivate
you both spiritually and monetary.
Whichever you guys want,
I can deliver that
with with examples, real life examples.
Actually.
Here are the real life
examples of uppercase and lowercase.
You always ask me where we are.
Will we be using those methods?
You see, this is how you will be using
those methods.
You are depressing us
if you guys can
imagine that title case,
first letter will be uppercase.
The rest of the letters will be lowercase
Inverse case.
First letter will be lowercase.
It s of letters be a per case.
Hey, sir, is this your website?
I'm not going to tell you
this is being recorded right?
No, this is not my website.
And you guys can check
Whose website is this?
Who is
who is dot com?
You can put any link in here
and you will.
So the people they have usually hidden
their info from others
you see
convert case dot net.
You know that
the info is not being displayed
but for some of the websites,
the simple ones in there,
they actually pay extra money
to hide that info.
I am working on an
android app by the way. It's
not this
Mossberg so studies jobs and all that.
So What does it do is simply expose
your expenses, generate reports.
You can use it to pass for fast to others
and all of that stuff.
What are we are going to test it.
The maybe
so I thought it will be very simple
and I can publish it as soon as possible.
But there are a lot of cases
that you have to kind of
like, for example, convergent
between different currencies and all that.
Using the API is all older,
so it's super super complex.
Maybe I can show you
if I have that on my computer.
So this,
this is the idea to develop Android
apps. It's
as good when you become rich.
If you need someone to give the card to,
you know where
to find a I am already rich
and now I am looking for
peace, vacations
and just visiting places and all that.
I am second one in the line.
So you guys
run away from this simple code.
You guys see how much code I have written?
Let me look at.
Okay. It will take some time.
We will get back it later. So
let's learn how to create new Excel files.
Yeah, how to create new Excel files.
It is also very simple,
like we did for the
I missed the entire class.
Can you please help me after that?
Yep, sure.
Don't worry. I will help you out
So excel them more
so. Don't worry, I will fix it.
Okay.
So as we learn code,
you showed demos six? Yep.
So let me know
once you are done.
Oh, there.
So if I have to create a file
on my computer.
Guys, again, what do I need first?
Let's create a file inside in here
or you guys will not be able to see.
So let me.
So I will create the file in here
on this spot.
Inside this folder.
Or maybe let me create another folder
so that you guys can see it easily.
So inside this batch, 11 right now
it's empty.
Okay.
And you
so first thing that I need
is thought.
And right now
this part is not complete, right?
So I need to specify
the name of the file as well.
Right.
Let's put it best not x x x.
Yeah.
Should we do that. Yes.
It's good if you guys follow it.
Yep. Looks good.
Let me.
Once you guys have selected a folder
where you want to create that file.
So after that part of that folder,
you need to put the name of the file
that you want to create
and. Then the extension
let me know once you guys
are done, select
any folder on your computer
and copy the part from there
and after that appended
the name of the fight like this.
Okay.
Are you guys done?
Okay, so the next thing we need to create
is the object
of X stuff book.
No excessive workbook lettuce.
Okay, So
once I have created the workbook,
now I will create a shirt.
Then create folder automatically.
Yes, it will.
It I will teach you in the next class
how to delete
files, read
files, cleared folders and all that.
Okay.
But I think even if you just write this,
I think it will create
new folders as well.
Okay.
But we will learn it in the next class.
So once I have the workbook next
I will create these sheets inside
this workbook, right?
So I can see X.
So if not create sheet
and the name of the sheet.
Right, let's,
let's call it best. One, two, three
or maybe
sheet.
One, two, three.
And once this sheet is created, let's,
let's store that sheet
inside the sheet variable.
So we need to create file or not. No, no.
You guys need to create this file will
automatically be created in here.
Inside this folder, I selected this part
so it will be created
automatically inside in.
You guys don't need to do it.
Are you going
are you guys done typing this for?
I think if we write sheet one, two, three,
it might create that
and we have to scroll down.
So let's keep it sheet one, maybe.
Okay, so that we don't get trouble.
So once I have this you guys, I can create
the rows inside of that sheet, right?
So I can say sheet and not
create role.
So for example,
I want to create a row on index zero
and once I have created that row,
row will row is equal to
do not see right now.
I have the row
and now I can start
filling
that the those cells inside this row.
So if I say a row and
create cell and if I pass zero in here,
line ten, can I say X as a substitute?
Yes. It's also fine.
So I will be having a created
a cell in here.
Right.
So cell cell is equal to cell.
And now I can say a cell dot
set cell value
and I can put any name in here.
And if you guys want to do some additional
things like
getting the formula range
from this cell, getting this tiles
and all of these things that are present
in the Excel,
you guys will be able to find different,
different matter, split unit,
maybe a cell set of these cell style.
And here new
cell die
but it will be difficult.
Well let's not go there
but you can do pretty much
all those things like setting the color,
setting the formula, setting
the color of the text and all that.
Okay, So we have set the value.
And now when we have to write the data
to a file,
which class will you guys
file?
Import stream of the file output stream
the output stream.
Right.
So we will save file output stream
file output stream equal to new file
output stream and we pass the path in here
and now we need to
include this in the header
and we can see access of workbook dot
right and file output stream.
And again it control and error.
So I will say add it to the exception as
okay, let's try to run this code
If it works.
But you guys see
the files on your computer.
So for example, a file has been created,
an Excel file has been created in here.
And if I open that file,
I see the data on zero zero
and seven zero.
So now you guys can write
loops to populate deltas
as as you guys like
populating any cells
using nested loops and all of that.
Same way
you guys can read or write text files,
any type of file
that you guys have been dealing with.
Okay.
Any type of file.
So let me put some comments in here
so that you guys don't
get confused confused.
Can we use Google chair to see
if we keep a copy of Google Drive locally?
I think yes.
But you have to use libraries.
I don't think so.
Apache boy sports, the Google
shirt number, you can search on.
You can search on the Google API to read
and write in that part of Google shirts.
Yes. Yes, you can do that.
Creating new sheet
in store.
The file
you guys will be able
to do much more exciting things
as you move forward,
creating new rules
inside the sheet,
creating new standards and side
a rule
of zero 13.
Be in that bar or that newly created cell.
You mean you are getting some issues
creating the user
output stream
Boring.
We are to their
x so five
null pointer exception on line 19
the Lord said well you
oh because you are writing a cell door
to get the cell
you have tried to cell, not create cell.
You are writing that cell in you.
There is no cell right?
First You create the cell,
then you can get it.
Yes. You guys will be having
your review class tomorrow.
Okay. Are there questions?
Are there any questions, guys,
from this school?
Easy peasy
or not easy peasy
for Java tomorrow?
For Java. It's fine.
It will be fine, guys, because you guys
are looking at the first time.
It's a little hard to head it now.
Okay.
So let me check
if we are missing something.
Okay.
And so this is your task based
how to create Second,
and it is easier to create more shirts
inside of that Excel.
So again, create more shirts
on the
on the same exact workbook,
create modules.
Okay.
Possible with an open source library
to create various files
like LOG, BPT, Excel
as excellence.
We do this task right now.
Oh no. You guys can do it next week.
Actually, next Saturdays off,
it will be 25th
and we will be having a class
on Sunday, next
Sunday session, days of that.
Can you show a code
for an interview?
Yep. Next. And
yes, on 26.
Let me let me check the canvas.
So we have three more Java classes.
No, only one Java class.
One more Java glass
and better was imported.
Okay,
but with this message or it's findable,
it's related to that low for the issue
that the Internet is facing these days.
Words are class.
On Sunday it will be Java class on
exceptions.
Yes, you should use a loop.
That is, if you want to create multiple
roles and cells, you should use a loop.
It's not going to last for values
you don't want to.
But Christmas on 25th.
Yes, it is on Saturday.
Right.
So classes on Monday, six
not on 25th.
25th is off.
How about January two?
I think first on the first off,
then it will be off.
And I guess the second is also off.
Let me check.
Technically,
this second should be off, right?
Not the first one, because you guys
will stay up all the night. Yes.
There is no class on one. Yes.
No class
on first
and on second.
There is this Java class
and first.
No class on second? No.
You guys have a class.
But we will be done that right?
We will be done with Java on 26.
So most probably
you guys will be having your
first Benjie class in here.
I am so sad.
Wait a minute.
Why do you said
imagine about the dollars
that you will be getting
when you will get a job?
You It will make you happy
for because Java will.
And if Java does not enter,
you will not get a job right?
You teach test and no, I am a developer.
I'm not a tester.
So someone with testing expertise
will teach you about those frameworks.
How about if we do a review
for whole Java on second?
What? What about the New Year night?
Let's have a Java review
on the new year of night
right at after 12
starting new subjects on second
then not good idea,
but we teach others with Java.
It's when we will see you again.
After 26.
You guys will see me
in February and here
in here it all said a squirrel.
Squirrel, A squirrel.
Time spent in class every week, 22 hours,
time spent studying, doing homework, 20
to 25 hours total, time spent 160 hours
plus crying about the classes
when somebody will get sick.
It is very weird,
almost all the instructors except so
some air and they are good.
They got sick right in batch 11
at least once.
But once a week
we will see you for Java. Yep.
Yep. You guys will see.
I will always be here.
Any sport issues, anything like that.
Okay, so party boy,
mostly used for reading.
Writing.
And you keep us calm.
I will keep sharing means and something
I will be passing by your classes.
Yes. Next set our days off.
So this is the same code
I have written in here.
I will be visiting you. Don't worry.
It's just the same code in here. Yay!
Happy you guys are finally done with Java.
So let's discuss about the exception
and types.
How many more reviews we have.
One review will be on
I guess list and add is collections
framework.
Then the second will be on file
handling and three more reviews.
Can we have any homework with this topic?
You guys will be now your projects,
so I want you to take some rest
because you guys will get super,
super busy.
So there is no homework for this.
Let's make it five.
Are you guys
okay? If I.
If I start the next class, I will.
I will tell you a little bit
about this exceptions. Yes.
And there will be a review tomorrow.
By no
homework, you mean only 30 assignments?
Actually, it's more than 30 assignments.
A project is kind of combining
everything
that you guys have been learning so far.
So all the Java Sea nadiem concepts,
you guys always
you guys will be putting all together
in the form of projects,
creating a lot of classes,
creating methods.
No, no, it will be easy.
Like, for example
instructor will show you how to do that.
You create a method
you save inside your intelligent.
Next time you have to use that,
you simply call that method.
You don't write the code again for it.
You guys should be happy.
Now you finally
you will see some practical examples.
I don't like recording here.
Take or not those projects I shall not.
The recording projects, the decoding ones,
creating the framework.
You said it's easy.
We know what it means. So
after you learn about this class, guys,
you will be able to fix
all of your issues in minutes.
Okay?
All the Java issues
that you guys have been getting Will
now you will be able to fix all of those.
So today I will teach you
when you get an error in the console,
what best does it make sense right now
other than that description that is shown
that file is not found?
Is there anything else that makes sense
at this time when you get an error
in the console?
Like, for example, if
if I go to demo six
and if I, if I change the port
and try to run it, both these lines,
they make sense.
Guys.
All of this except this, see,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
So after this class, you
everything will make sense.
All the errors, how they are generated,
why you get all
of these lines and all that.
They will make sense now
and it starts from
this very simple example.
So last 30,
these errors, they are called
exceptions in Java could not have known
from beginning.
Yes. Some of this stories,
they suggest that
we should teach
about these at us in this start.
But tell me honestly, guys,
if I start teaching about this
error first,
I have to introduce the error.
If I introduce the error,
I have to write some code
and then I have to intentionally
make that code for this error.
Will that make sense to you?
If if I start reading a file
using file steam in the first class,
will it make sense?
What is going on?
I am creating.
Hello World was very tough for you guys.
Like missing those semicolons
and variable names
and all that.
There should be one more subject.
So that's why
we keep this at the very end.
So I want you to focus guys in here.
Let's say
let's say
you have this code.
So this is this this out is representing
some important lines of code
that you have written in your program
there.
Do something
and then maybe solve a real life problem.
Another fresh group coming soon to you
next month, new baby boys.
And because
and then I write some piece of code
or maybe
we feel toddlers,
I write some piece of code
and that code throws an error and.
After that,
I again have some important lines of code.
So this imagine this, guys.
Imagine this.
Let's say you have this slack application
if you.
Okay, first let me declare this.
What do you guys think?
How many lines of code let me to do this.
Let's say only two are here
and to offer this.
How many of code?
I will see if I edit your this program.
If I execute this program, I will see
only the first two lines of code.
The moment the error is thrown
from any piece of code, from any line,
what Java is doing by default,
it terminates your
app or it terminates your
program abruptly.
I go out more
because you have more Mohamud.
You have written four lines
before that exception.
Yeah.
You still want to get two lines of code
even though if you have
written for.
Okay, so by default what Java is doing.
I did not see that.
Okay. So
by default, what Java is doing in
Java is facing an issue
Java does not know how to solve.
What is the answer to ten divided by zero?
Right.
So it's an infinite
we cannot represent infinity.
So this is something
that is not defined in Java, okay?
This is something
that is not defined in Java.
So when Java a situation
and if Java does not know
how to deal with that situation,
Java will terminate
your application right at that line
and it will not execute
the rest of the code no matter
if even there are 1 million lines
of code after this line.
This is the default
handling error handling behavior of Java.
So tell me guys, is it a good idea
to terminate the programs abruptly
even if I have 1 million lines of code?
Maybe this line of code
was not doing something special.
Imagine this slack application.
If you guys are not able to tag someone.
Should I close the whole show to the whole
a slack application should not function.
Should it all be closed
or I should be able to do other tasks
right.
It's not a good idea
that if one line code is not working,
I should just not execute
the rest of the lines.
I just terminated the whole program.
It's a very bad idea, right?
Imagine about other programs
WhatsApp, Facebook, Zoom.
If you are not able to perform a certain
operation, what happens in real life?
We get a specific ad added, right?
We get a specific error error message.
Like, for example,
if your slack is unable to connect
to the Internet, Slack just shows trying
to connect or something like that, right?
Yes. Or send the
reports to the developers
there to developers
while the users were using
your application, they faced this issue.
So you might want to look at this.
So it's a very bad idea
that if you're a single of code
is not working, it's a very bad idea
to terminate the complete application.
We never want to do that.
So if we never want to do that,
we must tell Java too.
We must tell Java how to make how to
how to fix those issues or what
to do in the case of those issues,
what to do in the case of those add us
then tell Java not to panic in moment.
Yes, that's exactly what we will be doing
using the help exceptions.
So to do that
it's very simple.
In Java we use the pride
cache block, it's the new contract.
So for example, if we
if we think that some piece of code
might throw some errors, we put that code
inside a new block
that is called a pride block.
I mean, we are saying, hey, Java,
you know what, try this code.
If it works, fine, that's perfectly okay.
But if it does not work,
fine, don't panic.
And we are saying if you get any ads,
catch those ads.
Like, for example,
if you get any exception, exceptions
catch exceptions and just print out
the error,
but please
don't terminate the whole program.
So now if I execute this program,
I will still be getting error,
but all the code inside of my application,
it will still execute.
So what I have told Java that, hey, Java,
you know what?
I am writing a piece of code.
I want you to try it, okay?
I want you to try it.
If it executes, it's perfectly fine. Okay.
Execute this piece of code.
If you face any issues,
the code that I will be
writing inside this block, please
execute that code.
So, for example,
instead of doing this, I can say this
I can put a print out
dividing
by zero.
Not possible in Java.
Okay,
I can print an error message to the user.
So now if I execute this program again,
Java will try to execute this.
If it succeeds, it's fine.
If it doesn't or succeeds,
it will print this line dividing by zero.
Not possible.
Now let's say I fix code, right?
I don't get any errors.
So what Java will do?
Java will again try to execute this code.
This time Java will succeed.
So Java will not execute this backup
code, this alternate code.
So now if I execute this code, I get five
and Java does not execute this
catch block.
It's like an if health condition.
Yep, yep.
It's like any first condition here.
We put the problematic code
that can cause problems if
a problem is caused,
this part is executed.
Okay.
If anything goes well,
then Java simply executes that part
and it ignores the catch block.
It's a backup code.
Alternative code?
Yes. If true, ignore the cache.
Now, this these errors that you guys see,
they are all classes, actually,
all the errors
that you guys have been getting till now.
They are all classes in Java.
They are everything in Java is a class.
If I, if I press control
and hover over this
exception, you see public class exception.
This is a class actually.
And what we do in here,
we are creating an object of the class.
All the exceptions. They are classes.
And as we can have
parent child relationship, we also have
been interrelationship shipping error.
Question This prior statement suggests
that a line of code could work
from time to time.
Yes Sometimes it can cause problems.
That's
why we are putting it inside the try block
So let me tell you a
little bit about the theory.
So by definition,
an exception is an event
which occurs
during the execution of a program.
So the exceptions there don't compile
time.
The end,
there can be two types of errors, right?
One are the syntax address
and the other errors that you guys,
when you are coding right
and there are other errors
when you execute a program,
then you get to those errors.
They are called compile time
errors and runtime errors.
So these are exceptions.
They don't include those compile time
errors.
Those syntax issues are all that.
So an exception is an event which occurs
during the execution of a program.
But for that we should know
that something we created might not work.
But we are professionals
of just randomly making errors.
Now you guys will not be making errors
randomly.
Now you guys will be making errors.
Professional, make a professional error
and then debug
that data. So
and that does not make me feel good.
An exception is an event which occurs
during the execution of a program
that disrupts the normal flow.
What is a normal flow?
Normal flow is whatever code
we have written, Java
should execute all the code line by line
starting from top to bottom.
Right?
But what is not normal
is to just terminate the program
between execute some lines of code
and ignore
the rest of the code. Yes.
Let the other
so it
it disrupts the normal flow
of the program's destruction.
Right.
Whatever we have written,
it does not execute.
That exception is an object
which is put on at a runtime.
Okay.
Now this is important
because all the errors
internally, you guys are right.
They are.
If else, if we go back to the demo
seven,
that's what it demo six.
I mean demo five
if you guys check this file input stream.
Okay.
If I hold down my control button
and if I go inside this file in stream,
you guys will see there
is this health condition.
Okay?
And inside this file,
Java guys,
they are checking the condition.
They are checking if the part
that you guys are providing,
you guys are providing a null value.
Java guys are saying throw new null point.
But exception.
Can you guys tell me what is this?
You guys are familiar
with this part of code,
What do we call it when we write new
and then the name of the class
in here I am.
They are creating an object right? New.
And then the name of the class
with parentheses creating an object.
Okay, Word is actually throwing
that object
who do to the person
who Whoever is calling this file,
this file, public file,
it's a constructor.
Whoever is invoking this constructor
and object of null pointer exception,
which is a class
if you hover, this is a class class
null pointer exception.
An object
is being created of this class. Yes.
You're saying a saying throw
an error message to the console,
but we actually throw objects.
Java in Java everything is classes
and objects so we throw,
we create a new object of the class
and we throw it to the caller.
Now, destroying part,
it is automatically handled by Java.
We just need to write this through so
you guys don't get confused by this tool
how this is happening.
It is happening
behind the scenes is doing it. So
I am calling this method inside file
import
theme and I am calling that code inside
demo five.
So what that new the what
that true new null pointer
exception is saying it is saying
if we pass and null value in
it will not allow directly.
So SDR is equal to null
and if I pass in null value in here,
which type of edit I will get guys,
I am passing a null value desperately
so intentionally
I'm passing a null value in here.
I will get in
null pointer exception.
Okay.
You see that that that that broke you.
Where do you see that broke?
You were inside That is condition.
This is this is the
this is all because of that throw keyword
so all the errors
that you guys have been getting till now
Java guys have written all
those scenarios with the help of
if health conditions so that if you guys
make a specific mistake,
they can throw you a standard error
and so that you guys know
what you guys did wrong.
Okay.
So when something is empty
or null pointer. Yes.
Whenever
you will be trying to call any methods
or, any anything,
anything on an object which has a null,
you will be getting a null point
of exception.
Now, I have a question, guys.
I have a question for you.
Let's say, for example.
So it's very good Java guys.
They are throwing the
as we can catch the errors and all that.
Right.
But how do
how what are what do these lines mean?
Right.
How to read these arrows,
how to make sense out of these errors.
Java guys, including us where they are
not only now the onset about
they know out errors.
You know, they also show you the answer
that they say your file is not found
or something like that.
They always help you,
but you guys never pay attention.
Yes. They anticipated and accommodated
every possible error.
Yes, and I will.
You are right,
Java guys that were very hardworking.
But you guys don't even bother
to read the errors, right?
I'm just kidding.
You guys are working
very hard as well. So a
how to refer to these errors.
If you guys want to read the errors,
this is how you should do it.
So this line
in here, it will always be same.
It's again related to
that tried to save the multiple threading.
If you are executing multiple threads
only then it will get a chain.
But you guys will never be writing
multithreaded core.
So far will this line will always be same.
The next line
tells you about the package
info and the name of the class.
Okay. Name Of the class
whose object is thrown at you
and this line tells you
so. You see
this error is originated
in file input stream door
to Java at line 130.
So this added
it is showing you the exact line number
which caused this issue.
If we go inside file input stream,
you're not
Java at line 131 130.
It shows you the exact line number
which is causing this issue.
Next, it shows you
the class who was calling this,
who was calling this piece
of functionality, this file input.
So this functionality was being called
by this piece of code.
That's why you see Java line 93.
And then it shows you the complete package
that you have written
which caused this issue.
So it's saying, hey, girl, there is a
this, there is this package com or syntax.
Inside that package
there is this sub package class 30 inside
that there is a class called
Excel Demo five.
Inside that class there is this man
a method inside that main method online
you are doing something wrong.
So if I click on this line 19,
it takes me to exact x
that exact line
which is causing the problem.
So it's insane that it is saying, Hey,
is there
a null pointer
exception is being thrown at you
and the line of code
that is causing this problem.
Here is the information about that line.
Even if you have million lines of code,
even if you have hundreds of packages,
even if you have hundreds
of methods inside the class,
Java will tell you the exact line number
which causes the issue.
Okay. Now
let me show you.
It will make more sense
if I show you with this example.
So yes, we can avoid the adverse
we can avoid the errors by writing it
false conditions like Java guys did.
But if we write the first condition
guides, will we be able to get of this
info the package, name
the class, name the exact line number.
Who is calling your method?
We will not be able to get info.
Yes, we can write it.
False conditions
like you guys can ask that test that you
You could have avoided this issue
by simply checking.
So let's say, for example,
if there are two numbers, actually user
builder was entering these numbers right?
So I can write
an if condition, I can say if
number two is
not equal to zero,
then only perform this operation right.
Then only try to divide
number
by number two
if it is equal to zero,
should set out message.
So this error message
divide by
zero, Right?
So yes, we can do that, but it's not good
way to go to handle data. Why?
Because if you do that, you will only be
getting a single piece of information.
Whatever you are printing in the console,
you lose all that stack trace
exact line numbers, package numbers
specific at us.
And as a programmers, let's say maybe
I have written ten or divided by zero.
Maybe there is another developer
who has written
not possible. Now
if you give the choice to the
to the users,
they they can write any error messages,
right?
For some of you, they will
they might make sense for some of you,
they might not make sense.
So it's not a standard,
although the added is still saying
we are trying to divide it by zero,
but now everyone will start
to create its own errors.
That's not good.
So we should have standard errors
so that
by just looking at the error,
you guys can quickly know what went wrong.
So that's why we use the trick at blocks
instead of simply false conditions.
Here is the
so let's say
guys, I have this class
right?
Public static.
Lloyd,
do something
and you have another
public static void
low math.
You have another method
public that ward
divide.
And inside this code I am doing something
which is causing the issue
and I am calling the divider method inside
do not
matter and I am calling this
boom at method.
So I am calling multiple methods
inside each other.
Okay.
Or maybe I have.
We will finish on time today.
You guys want to live there?
We still have 6 minutes.
No, we will continue in the next
from here.
You're school much
all right.
I speak some of rest.
We will start from here.
Okay.
Let's finish
in 5 minutes.
We can not do much anyway.
To date was a long blahs.
All right, guys. Bye bye.
Date summarized.