You remind me
class
for doing.
All right, let's do the tasks.
We're the house.
You guys want me to revise?
Revise the concepts
from the previous class first?
All the items to go to the
tasks first
is 14.
E I is five,
but it will leave me in.
If you are asking about the class, it's
class number 14. Yes.
Let's get in to the tasks first.
Concerts. Concerts.
Okay, well, for the last class,
if you guys look good,
I have not that many concerts.
Yes, well, the last class was about
the methods from this film class.
So let me ask you.
Okay.
So we started learning new methods
that are there
in the string class.
Yeah.
And the first method was the land
method.
Can you guys tell me,
what does this land method do?
They put the name Dot
Land and
you guys quickly tell me the output.
Give us the size.
You must decide.
My years count the total characters. Yes.
So it counts the total
number of characters
that are present inside a string.
It counts the spaces, the special
characters, the alphabets, everything.
Pretty much everything
that is present inside a string.
Okay.
And in here we have one,
two, three, four, five.
So we have five characters in here,
so I should be getting five
in the console.
Then we learned about the uppercase
to uppercase and to lowercase letters.
Right. Very simple method.
Just convert whatever string you guys have
in uppercase or in lowercase.
Right.
Then we discussed about we can get method.
Can you guys tell me, well,
what is that method?
Which is kind of an alternate
to the stink and cultivation,
the string concatenation
that you guys have been doing
with the plus sign right.
You're just because no strings
combined needs to strings in a new string.
Okay.
But which one is recommended to use
the plus operator or we can get method
B plus operator.
Right.
Because can get method sometimes
if there is a null value
in any of the strings
you guys might get, new
guys will get an exception.
Then we learned about the parts
we've met right?
But this starts with method of days.
It returns as the boolean.
Yes. Rule clause? Yes.
When does it written true?
If a string starts
from a specific character
or a word, then it will return a straw.
Right.
So in this example, we like a true
or false, we will be getting it.
Or why?
Because this name, it starts
with this letter and okay.
And if some letter investing
does not start
from a specific letter
or from a specific word,
then we will be getting false.
And so let's say what exemplifies, say
if I say it right now, this name,
it does not start with a
So what will happen?
I will be getting
a false yes
and I can check a string for
was the first spaces
for any letter for special characters.
Serenity
then similar to this start and method,
we have another method
and you guys tell me the name.
And we tried.
So if I say name Dot ends with Capital R,
will I get a true or false
and false? Ly
Because strings
and they are case sensitive, right?
So if we put a capital R,
we will be getting a false.
If we put a lowercase r,
then we will be getting a true
the next and third of all, as
contains method.
So let's see if I want to check
if a specific character
or a word is present inside
a string or not.
Right.
Then what I can do I can use the contains
method.
This contains method
a searches for their specific character
or the word inside that stain.
If it is present inside vaccine,
we will be getting it through.
Otherwise we will be getting a false.
So as this s is preserved
inside this name,
we will be getting it through
in here.
And if I put any letter
that is not present
inside this name, then
Java will return me false.
So I get a false.
Then we discussed about the equals method.
You guys already have been using
the sequel's methods
many, many times, so it just checks
if those strings,
if they are equal or not,
if they contain
the exact same letters are not right, then
we have the equals to ignore this method
and that equals ignore this method.
Right?
What is the difference
between equals and equals?
Ignore method.
It does not care about the case
sensitivity.
Right?
So if those strings,
if one of the strings, if it has
a combination of letters in uppercase
and the other one
has it in in, in the lowercase,
then for equals
C and
or equals now yes,
it should be exactly same for equals
method.
BLOCK Okay.
So if I run this program,
I will be getting a true.
But if I change the case of any letter
now in here we have an uppercase
and in here we have a lowercase.
So what will happen now?
I will be getting a false plot
of the equals matter.
Now, if I want to ignore the E
sensitive less
then what I can do
are you can use
equals ignore case. Okay
you if now
some of the letters on all the letters
if they are uppercase
Java, we not care about the case.
So in here it's a lowercase and here is
an upper case and we will be getting
for what equals ignore case.
We get a true for equals
would get a false on.
So the next method is John
can you guys tell me about this job
at third
index of back back is given
it tells me the digit at that number
for artistic director at certain index
so that in that index of that character
is a different matter index of method.
This one job that method.
So this these things internally
they are a combination of characters
okay And all the characters,
they are stored inside an editor.
Okay So yes,
I mean correct that index.
Okay,
please don't do this in your interviews.
Okay.
Don't don't say in the interviews.
If they ask something or say,
this is what I meant.
So internally,
all these things, they are stored.
I like all the answers.
So I will go with that concept to check
what is the value
of certain character in a string,
to check what is the value of certain
character add to that index.
Okay, then it will be a perfect answer.
Like.
And so internally, all the strings,
they are stored inside,
inside the characters, adding.
So in here this end will be stored
at index number zero.
Then a then as then I and then are.
Okay.
Now if you want to get specific,
if you want to know
the value of a character from this area
at any specific index.
So the indexes, they start from zero,
then we are
one to the int and for right,
this is how it is.
Look.
So if I say job at zero
so it will return me.
The character that is present
and index number zero.
Right.
So what is the character
that index number zero.
It's the character and
so I get and
if I say character number three, so
it will return me the character
at index number three.
So it's zero one, two, three
I get and I
so any character there to that specific
index
this job at method
will return me back to value
and it's a very useful method
to manipulate arrays.
Okay.
If you want to search from
if you want to search
from a string,
if you want to add something in between.
So all those operations
and looking to the characters,
you're all possible using this.
Jared And index of
the Jared method
or the next method is
how to get to
the tree.
Now what do you mean how to get to?
For that
you can use the Can you guys tell me
if I want to get multiple
more than one character?
You guys learn about a specific method
if you want to get something from
in between or or is idea
and the number of characters at any event
we have that substring, that type. Okay.
Using the subsisting
method, you guys can get one characters,
two characters, all the characters
and a number of characters
from a string.
I cannot use job fallback method.
I don't think so. You can use chartered
method. What?
Let me check. If
if we have any overloaded virgin
for this method.
You know, I don't think so.
We can use charter.
Okay. So if you guys want to find out.
So let's say this job, that method,
it takes only one integer index
and then you can read the description
says returns which are value
add specified index and index ranges
from zero to length minus one.
The first chart of sequence,
it is at index
zero, the next add one and so on.
As far added indexing.
Okay, so you guys can
read the description as well.
You can use plus to combine them.
Yes, but why use plus to combine them?
And you have the substring method
plus more or
so you're going to see
for the job at method
we have only one method available
is how to take a word from this
and from this sentence.
So then if you want to take a word
and if the words if they are separated
by spaces, you can first split them
or you can use the substring directly.
Okay.
So depends on how you want to vector.
Okay, so the next method
is index of method.
Can you guys tell me about this
index of method
or does this method of
find out
index of certain character in a string?
So for this
method is essentially doing
it searching back to area
that internal array.
We where we are supporting this name.
Okay.
And if a specific character is available
inside the array,
it will return you
The index of that character.
Okay.
So if I want to find out
the index of this letter, I
so what answer I need guys
to be.
Well, I think because this I is present
at index number three.
And if some character is not
presented inside of this spring,
then what?
Answer I will get
minus one.
And what if I try to get a character
from an index that index is not available
or what?
What are what I will get in that case
out of string index out of my old adage,
okay, so far job act.
I will be getting an added
index of
I will be getting minus one
if that character is not present inside
that that which
if the characters equals two times,
does it work.
So let's have this index of method.
It will return you the index
of the first occurrence.
If we have multiple occurrences of
the stamp with the same letter, if I have
another I in here.
So by default of this index of matter,
it will always be returning me
and the index of this first recurrence
so we can use it to get minus
one as the output.
Yes. Okay.
So I will always be getting three.
But what I can do
there is an under Virgin of this
method that takes two parameters.
Okay. And the second parameter, faith that
you'd say is there to
Tasker from there
you want me to start this search.
So if I am saying Java, start
the search from
turn number four onwards,
then it will use,
then it will ignore first four characters.
It will ignore these first word characters
because I am specifying quoting here
and it will return you
the index of the next I
If the I is present in the string.
So what answer I will go right
if I put the second parameter.
As for
so now I get the index number five.
Okay, so this is how you can get
this second utterance.
Okay.
And the third documents
and you can, you guys can create your own
methods of now, okay?
You can create your own methods
and those matters they may be
they can may be you.
The occurrence of the index
of second occurrence, right.
Or the third or the fourth one,
it will be a good, good homework.
So I want you to
I want you guys to write a method.
If I pass
one to dark matter, it should return me
the index of the first occurrence.
If I pass through,
then it should return me
The occurrence of the stake in
the second place.
Can you imagine?
How many times do we say
oops during the homework?
So can you guys develop that method?
It will be an interesting
method to develop and that method
is not present in in the JDK.
That method is not present in the JDK,
so it will be a good method to.
Right.
So if I specify one
or the I want to develop a method similar
to index of method,
if I pass one, it should return me
the index of the first occurrence.
If possible,
it should return me
the index of this second occurrence
if I pass to the which would return
with the occurrence of the
position
of the third group or the developer.
The investors are taking
some say in course. Yes.
This delegate the same
for developers or investors
or the next method that we learn about
was substring method.
And this substring method,
it also has to organize
in one of the other dates,
only one parameters.
And then what does the subsequent
method do?
If I say maybe three substring three.
Yes. It's a very useful method.
If it was a print and I.
What about if
I want the index of both eyes logo?
You can try to look for that.
The last three.
So this substring method when we pass
only one argument
it it gives you.
So this is index number zero.
This is one, this is two.
And this. I use that index number three.
So it will start
giving you all the letters
from this index
will be last index of that Adi.
Okay, so this three is included,
it will not return
you order and I, it will return you.
I r and I because this three is inclusive,
it is included in the answer.
And then we have this other word again
in which we can specify the starting index
and the ending index.
So can you guys tell me if I say three.
Three what?
Answer I read that
will let me actually put
so yes,
from this substring
we are getting nothing.
Okay?
Because what we are saying,
so three minus three will give you
00a number of characters.
So if we say four and then it will return,
you be correct that I.
Okay, so it will start from three.
This four is not included. Yes. Exclusive.
And then it will return you.
The character at index number three.
I will fly in three 8 to 5.
So index number
is 012.
So starting from three, four
and five is not included.
So only I.
And then if I want to get all of them
in the last two,
then we will be getting high.
So can you say that one more time.
So that this specifies
this first number 1012
be four
and five.
So this is the starting index
from where it will start returning.
You will be
the characters again.
And this last index is specified
in where you want
to get the indexes,
where this last index is not included.
So let's say if I am specifying six,
the six is out of bounds.
Right? But actually it works.
And this number minus one.
So it will return. You will be characters
below five starting from three.
So I and I want you
to explain the last 14.
This is please just one more last 14 case
classes
one more time
if then let's let's do it
after you get rid of
all that, there were two more matters.
The one is empty method 395
and in blank again the blank method
not known.
There is no black matter in Java.
What are you guys?
So this is empty method.
What does this method always?
I tried to watch previous videos
about GitHub book link not working.
I need to support
or we don't have this option.
No, no. You should be able to watch it.
So Alex,
which links you are using the links
that we posted in the course announcement,
these
links, they only work for three days.
After three days they expire.
If you want to watch,
you have to go to the Google Drive.
Then you should see
all the recorded videos.
So this system is implemented.
It checks if there are any characters
inside a string or not.
Okay, but this is empty method.
It will return me false
because there are letters in this name.
I think.
And then we have the
string method.
No, no, no.
It's blank method
for this method.
You guys
delete the spaces from
when will it be true if there was space?
So even if there is a space,
it will return in false.
So question. Yes.
So this string method,
it removes the spaces from
the end
and from the start of the name
or any string.
You see no spaces before or after.
And if we're going to use this
method, we see spaces before
and after this name.
In the last method that you guys like
about was
great method.
So if I want to get all the words
from this sentence,
which are separated by space, I can do,
I can split
this sentence
and I can specify the train double.
I want to split this
sentence.
This sustains
based on these spaces.
So wherever in Java I will see a space,
it will split that word
in the next index of the other.
So it will create an array.
And once the Java sees a space,
so this word will be placed on
index number zero, then there is a space.
So then this is will be
placed on the next.
Then again in space,
then it will be placed on the next next.
So when you guys
tell me the length of the
area that I will be getting
if I do a split
one, two,
three, four, five,
there are five letter of five words
inside this sentence,
so the length will be five,
but the index is Java dot language
staying on
your copy pasting the answer from Eclipse
and then I can get
in the
value of their C
next number zero.
So if I do split node index zero.
Right.
You have to share the screenshot
because you didn't
put land.
So if you guys are only trying
to prevent this out,
so let's add this
then you will be getting an edit.
Right?
And do you guys remember
if we have to print out the areas, either
we use a loop or what do we do base?
It is another method that we can use.
If I want to check out
the elements without a loop
and is door
hosting negative.
Okay.
And then I will be getting
all the elements
of this area
without using that loop
and I don't remember this one.
It's fine.
And then add the index number zero.
I got this.
Okay.
And then
what we do with index of Java
define say three.
So would be I would be getting
Java from here.
So these were some of the methods
I one to the homework guys.
Was it easy hard.
How much time you guys took to solve it?
It was okay
it was easy to 21 works
that's all the homework
tense
and with the statement for the homework
question, I'm going to
I need triple
35 to $85 million School
it me if something.
But I was able to complete
without getting too much
stress.
Can you guys help? Let's
do I only have as
so let's you need to put
this space in here
you are not using a space
so if you don't use this space, Java
will split this character by character.
Okay?
That's why you see a space
You need to create space in here.
So you guys had to write a program
that leaves two people's first name
and it leaves
if they are expecting a Y or go right
based on the input suggested name, follow
the example
Mom's first name.
If it's Mary, Dad's first name,
if it's Daniel,
and if Y, or if this is why
this suggestion name should be deadly.
Okay, so what is happening in here?
We are taking the
first name the actors
from the there is a name
and last
two that are so half of the letters
from the father's
name and half of the letters
from the mother's name.
If they expect a boy,
what wonder where do we take
the first two
half letters of the father's name and
named half of the mother's name?
Okay, If they are expecting a girl,
we take the first half
of the mother's name
and then second half of the father's name.
And then we combine this two strings.
So let's say,
or what we can say, and also declare
the string.
And here
I have lost our golden rule.
So if I use the scanner. Yes.
It's also good to use.
Cannot
I just don't use scanner to reduce time.
Okay.
But you guys should be using this
kind of class.
Yes. So if
if they are expecting a Y,
how can I check that
and why are the door equals ignore?
So I'm
so objective value of this variable
and if they are expecting it, why?
I need to know three things.
First,
I need to split
this father's name into two parts
and I need to get
the first part of the father's name.
Then I need to do the same
for the mother's name.
Right. But if they're expecting it, why?
I need the first part of the father's name
and last part of the mother's name.
So what I will do,
I will say a string
box part.
How can I get the first three letters
on first half of the office string?
Nice.
Using the substring method.
Right.
It's a father's name. Got some
substring in.
Where should I specify?
In here?
So my starting index should be zero,
but my ending index.
So if you guys are specifying three
and if the user enters a name
that contains eight characters,
what will happen
if you guys a hard
coding this value of three?
It will not work. Right?
So instead of hard coding values, guys
always try to write genetic code.
How can I find out about
the index of the middle character?
I can see.
I can see
father's name, not land
divided by now.
My code is genetic
and it will work for any type of input.
Do you guys get this part?
It's named or ten divided by two.
So what until end of this? This this name
if states right
and six new ordered by two
will be three
and fought my saying
what if the characters
in the name of father if they are on
okay so this substring letter
it expects an integer so if the
if the letters in here
if they are large they're seven.
So seven divided by two
will be 3.5.
But because we are,
because the substring method
is expecting an integer.
So this,
this decimal part will be ignored
and three will be returned.
Okay.
It will be counting it as three next.
How would it be treating the odd number
characters?
Okay, so now we have the first part
from the father's name.
Now we want to get the
what we want from that. The
second half
note from
the mother's name.
How can I get this second part
from this mother's name
by genetic.
So I want this part.
So the substring method, if I was
mother's name dog event divided by two,
it will return me to write.
And if I was only one in one argument,
do the substring matter
what is the behavior of substring letter?
It ignores
that many characters from the start
and it returns the remaining letters
from that same right.
And now we have the first part
and the second part.
Now we can simply combine
these two letters.
These two parts
are complete.
So let's test this out.
Okay,
So we get the expected output in here
and then we can wrap it.
Michael came out a little longer.
Now we can do the same quality.
The name,
the first part,
and I need to do this same thing
where this time it should be
one of those
that I need
to do the same,
but with this
then I just need to solve
any questions from this task. This
no questions.
All looks good
now. It looks more generic and useful.
Yep, it can work with any type of input.
Now let's move to the task to the
owner. Does
send me this statement for our task
for the
Is it Meredith?
While doing my homework, I look at all
that was written in the lesson.
No, no.
You guys should actually.
You guys should look at the code
that I tried during the class
to solve your homeworks.
You can take any help from Google,
but try not to copy and paste solutions.
You can check how the method is working,
how you can get certainty,
and you can search, how to maybe
can continue to stains,
how to get the specific letters
from asking all that.
So create a stain.
Your thing is not
empty, but from the following
If this thing has
an odd number of characters,
it has three or more characters.
Print the character
in the middle of the screen.
So what is the first step
that I need to perform?
I need to check
if a string is empty or not.
So let's say
I have a starting spot.
Hello in here.
So can you still show the last one
we could, yes.
So let me do it.
This is what we want to see in this one.
Michael, are you guys typing it?
I can stop if you guys want me
some time.
Let me know what you guys are done
typing it? Yes.
Should we?
Starting next task.
So the first check that I need to perform.
Can I close this one, guys?
Michael. But hard
and close this task will
now. So
if this thing is not empty
right?
So with the help of this
is empty method, I can check.
I can check
if this thing is empty or not. Right?
If this thing is empty,
I will get a proof.
But I want not off it.
I want to.
Not if I in place and not in here.
All right.
Sorry.
Once this check is passed
and then I need to perform another check.
Right.
This thing has an all
the number of characters
and has three or more characters.
Okay,
so how can I find out if string has odd
number of characters dies?
Which method I can use?
So first I will be needing,
I will be needing
to check
if the I will be getting the lent.
Okay.
The length
will return with the number of characters.
Then I will divide it
by two and I will check
if the remainder is zero or not.
STR or planned.
I take the modulus by
and it should not be equal to
zero.
All right.
It can be anything other than zero.
So those who are using
percentage two is equal to equal to one.
Is this approach correct? Twice.
If named or planned person
Page two is equal to equal to one.
So the answer from
the object of the name is it.
Is it correct
or it will fail at some point.
So this one is better approach
because if we get answer
as one, two, three, four, five.
So it will always be correct because
look at
that, which why it will fade.
I think it will work most of the time.
But this one, this one is good.
Okay,
so we don't care about any of the cases,
any of the cases.
So this is the first check.
So this check is checking
if the string has all
the number of characters.
Now I need to put them and
and then
I need to check
if this string has three
or more characters.
Right. So again, I will be
using the length method
and it should be three or more
so greater than or equal to.
So now I can return
both of the conditions.
And if all three conditions,
if they are good,
then need to print the character
in the middle of the string
of the string. So
how can I get the connector
out of the middle of the string strings?
Still so got the method that returns me
the characters at a specific index.
Right?
So first I want to find out
about the middle index, right?
So I can see string or draw at
and how can I find the middle index?
I can see SDR or length
divided by the.
So let me now this.
So I get would it work with only a single
if statement like this?
Yes. Yes.
Nested If conditions
and using the end operator they are saying
yes seen.
So what we can do we can as
Simon is swing
we can do this as well. Okay
so in here
we are saying this thing is not empty
and the string
has all the number of directives
and the spin is having three
or more characters of all three
in a single
if condition.
Same answer
any questions
based?
No questions.
You guys so so solved in the same way?
Or do you guys use different approaches?
One divided by two.
Okay, so.
So in here, what am I doing?
I am first
getting the index of the middle character.
So if I split this into the eddy
and then we
then write this index, then, you know, one
thing
for you.
So this length matter,
it will return me for a 35.
So there are five characters in here.
Then I am dividing it by two.
There will be ten me 2.5.
But this job at Method Logic,
it expects an integer
so this part will be ignored.
We are only left with two,
so these two will be passed to this method
and then we will be getting the letter
at index
number two. So
when I use
bastard, if that is perfectly fine,
mine is defined nested
works
on the next task.
This was easy right?
So just start a reverse loop.
Get all the characters one by one,
print them to a variable and that's it.
All right.
There is short lived.
There is also a building method
to reverse testing new device.
Try to google it.
How to reverse the string in Java.
Yeah, using the string before class.
Today we will learn about the string
before class
we used for loop.
For loop. It's fine.
It's fine.
It was
never say new
must be out
initially.
It is empty.
Then we need to start.
We were to
the How can I start in reverse to place
I see in period I is equal to what
as we are not
land and minus one
well while why I'm doing
why we need to do minus one case
because
because indexes they start from zero okay.
And they start from zero.
And I want to keep on going as far as I
is greater than or equal to zero.
Right.
And then
I minus, minus C,
I see a new
SDR plus equal to
SDR JAR, and then I pass by.
Oops.
And once we are done,
I drifting through the new
and then we will be having this
in the reverse
form.
Is it clear how this loop is working?
Okay. Yes, Mr.
Fischer
So if
more stimulus for the new SDR.
So this plus is saying
to get all the characters
one by one and add them to this new SDR.
Okay, So
most of
our work, This land will return me,
this SDR land.
It will return me one, two, three, four,
five, and six.
Right.
This land will return me six.
But if I check what is the index of this?
Why can you tell me the index of this life
is five, right?
So if I want to get to this last index
and I am using the length method,
I need to subtract one.
Okay.
Underlies our
are we getting spring index out of that?
Because indexes they start from zero.
So the last index will be at land
two minus one
always on this.
Is it clear now
and then this
plus is actually doing this new.
SDR is equal to a normal
for this
of plus in this charter.
Okay so it will get frustrated
leave this why
okay then if we get then
if we get this and it will apparently say
this w we know
then I will be able to lie.
Then I get b appended to why
I saw land plus one somewhere.
What is that for? Or maybe I am dreaming.
No, even if you don't do land plus one,
still
you will be getting index out of bound
or the other.
Plus substring.
I i plus one.
This works to
another condition.
Be complete for. Yes.
You guys can also solve this problem
in many different ways.
Okay.
Can you explain line 15?
So line 15 is actually in this new
SDR plus
SDR Charter.
Okay.
So when we do this plus equal to operator,
we keep on adding
the characters that we are getting
from this SDR,
dot dot at two, this new SDR, you
see, this string was
the substring
for hard.
It was also in good approach.
So you are getting character
one by one by adding one to
so you can use multiple approaches,
you know, is it clear this new SDR
plus being
I don't understand why plus new SDR
we wheels so Sandy
what works should we use instead?
So I am getting all the letters one by one
and I want to build a string.
So what should we use
instead if we want to do this, it's fine.
Whatever answer you have in your line,
just tell me if I want to build
a string from letters
and I am getting those letters one by one.
I just like this.
So. Sandy.
Yes, it also works.
If you see the output,
it will print the output.
Okay.
But in here my because we are fast
storing the output in a variable
and then we are printing it.
That's why I used this new SDR.
So let me actually show you
by debugging it.
So if we debug this.
Okay.
And Sandy,
you also boasted about the Republican
debugging that your debugging
is not working, so you need to place
these debug wires like this.
Okay.
So if I stop this,
if I don't place this debug point
and if I try to debug my application,
I will not be seeing any variables window
or anything like that and it will just
execute the complete code.
So before you debug,
you need to place these debug wires
double clicking on this line,
then that will work
and then you will see all the windows
if you have a strings.
And then why do we create another stream
that's been known
to create another string? Do
it just if you want to use
that thing in record, then
you should be creating another string.
Otherwise printing that out on
the console is fine.
So there is another problem.
The problem is
if you have to check a string for
if a single palindrome log not there,
it will be useful.
Well, do you guys have dinner?
Can you get me the next task there?
It will be useful.
No more tasks.
Okay.
Well, reflection
on page one Workouts.
Do you guys know about the palindromes
on three, maybe years in the
or this one? Yes.
So you will be getting this task today.
So in here
it will be useful to store the input first
and then check
if it is a palindrome or not
on there.
So if we go in here
so you see this new SDR right now
it's empty.
Okay. It's empty.
That is global. You guys need a break.
And when we are done with the first part
version, we have a Y in the newest year.
On the second notation, we have
a, then we have a D, and then we keep on
appending to this spring
and that's why we are using
this new SDR plus
or the B
because we are starting a new topic.
So let's have a break now.
And if I don't go to sleep,
I will be back in 15 minutes.
If I go to sleep, you guys can
read, can also go to sleep.
Okay.
I got to go to sleep.
I need to pick up my food.
You look tired. Please take a nap.
My nap is at least 3 hours.
Tell me I will have to go
to sleep as soon as you see
Diane right now
it's 623 and
I have no idea why my phone does not work.
I have no idea why my phone is working.
Yes. In Islamabad.
Yes, definitely.
You guys are more than welcome.
And which I thought the
have been dear
feel times.
Okay, I'll be
all right, guys.
Please be back in 15 minutes
and remind me about anybody
so short.
Nine days.
Can you give me
on display, please,
on the task number three?
It is. It is this one.
You know, know
the task number two,
this one, I think going to work.
I think I might like simple one.
So there are few more matters
that we need to learn.
And then we will have a theoretical
this discussion on string and string
builder class
and when we should be using one.
You have if you
if you want to be working in us.
And then yes,
you have to wake up at four m
in the morning.
All right.
So let me check which was the next method.
Okay. So we were discussing about the
click method, right?
So you
actually very good.
I mean, can you guys imagine
my reflection, which I am leaving
your, say, two room flat
with kitchen attached, but well-furnished
air conditioner
and my total expense is like 40
Completement is like $220,
including the electricity and all that.
Yes, I knew that that the benefit
that you get
from my new 25
I paid
utility.
I need to go to Hall. Yes.
So you guys have this benefit
because in IT sector
you just need a laptop
and an internet connection
and you can be working from anywhere.
So I highly encourage
you guys to look for remote jobs
Once you have like 3 to 6 months
or maybe one year
or one year of experience,
and then you can move to any other country
like there are so many beautiful country
is cheap countries to live right?
Most of you maybe want to go back
to your home countries. So.
All right. So the
earnings are geared.
Are we going to isolate you?
There is
you do
Maldives would be offering.
Yes, Maldives is great.
Maldives is crude.
Okay we here
we go to 39 standard model.
We with Norway.
Norway's
is six months and six months right right
That's
a totally different experience.
So electric rise.
If I have a bigger strain
that contains many different
sentences
or I want to split a single sentence
based on this basis or any other connector
so I can use this spirit method,
this group method, whatever character
we specify it to split the string
based on that character,
and then it returns us
and a can of strings.
So SDR or
group.
And then here we specify the character
based on which we want to split this.
Okay, then we can print out this
being I would be using
this string
and then the name of the
string.
Okay.
And what will be
the length of the string guys
doing next?
Axes?
How many full stops we have in this string
to or equivalent?
So the period in this square
record is saying that
we want to split this string
based on this,
not based on the speedier.
Okay,
so if I print out, you guys will notice
and the list
and this exchange has been split.
So so on one index we get in this part
and on the other index
we get this part and let's
see if these are
I can split on on question marks as well.
So I will be needing a question
mark here.
Okay. So now the string will be split
on this question.
Okay.
And I can speak on any character
now why we need these square brackets.
So this split method,
it is expecting the regular expression.
It will be common by default.
So Mohammad
and this comma is because we have
two elements in an array is comma
is there for that purpose.
Think it's not the part of this
and the string.
Now what are regular expressions?
Regular expressions They are
they are also like the
like programing language.
So what is the purpose of line
question?
Is it related with line nine?
The question mark now,
because I want to split on this question
mark.
That's why I specified this question mark.
So if I specify this not what will happen
because there is no dog
in this area,
so I will be getting this complete
sentence as the, as index as one element.
EDIT Okay, so there will be no splitting.
So in this split
method inside these square brackets,
we specify based on what character
we want to split.
So let's say, okay,
I want to split based on the dogs
and I specify and about in here
mind and use me as of
and we split based here
so we can split based on comma.
So let's say you foot comma
here.
Okay then group restricted based on comma.
Actually we get split on anything.
Let me, let me put the letter B, Okay.
So you guys see
now I have an array and in this area,
the first element is empty.
We don't have anything before this P
Then we have this.
D So this will be ignored. Ignored.
Then the next index will contain
all the characters.
Yes. It does not include
that specific character in the output that
that is excluded so that the next element
in the area, it will contain this.
Right. So we have this in here.
Then again this D it is ometer.
Then we have all the characters.
It'll be next D So we have this
here. Okay.
Then again, this will be
why we have comma instead question mark.
I just placed this comma
because one of the students
they ask so
and then we split on the common.
That's why I placed you.
What is this used for?
So it's used for.
It's used to process strings.
So let's say
you are building an application
to check for grammar
or to check for sentences or to check for
maybe spelling mistakes
in a very big paragraph.
So first you will be splitting
that paragraph
based on space,
see if you will be the individual words.
Then you will be
checking the individual words
if they're spellings are correct or not.
So these kind of applications
they heavily use need string letters,
and it is splitting
based on capital D on the Eastern table.
So whatever character we specify in here,
it will be splitting
based on that character.
It can be a speech.
It's going to be a comma,
a question mark period,
A, B, C, numbers, anything.
I mean, what is the purpose of line?
Is it related to line 11?
Line is simply printing out
the contents of this area
and we use the word cat or something
like that.
Yep. Okay.
So if you are discarding this word
so far
B words,
we don't need those squared because okay,
so what it is doing now,
which is splitting this part
in here.
Okay.
And then this this part is ignored
and then we have this part in here.
Let me actually put it in.
And then next question
on this one.
Okay.
So we have this to today before this to
there is nothing.
So we get this empty first index is empty.
Then we have the today, which is only good
and then we have this give the space. Yes.
And then another space.
So we have these spaces
and if then again this to the
is excluded and we have this
comma.
So we hear this from
this from
so we can split on, on characters
or letters
will always replace it with comma so
as to let me print these hours because
and you guys are confused about the comma.
So that comma is to end
only that there are
elements
in the.
Abby Okay, so now you're going
back.
Okay,
so let me not pretend data.
Okay, So this is the added
that we are getting there.
There is no command load those commas,
they are just there
because when we use the at is not method
after each element in the array.
That method puts a comma
to just tell you that
you have an under element inside that
that.
Okay.
So now in here we are printing out
individual elements of that.
Okay, so this is what we will be getting
if we split this, how can we ignore it?
Today we have
German class with
all Can we even know
again, can you elaborate your question?
What do you mean how we can ignore
why we are getting more common?
So if one common was present in here
and the remaining commas
were there to tell you that
how many elements are there?
So let's say
if we split
it based on the on the
just this period.
Okay, so we get these two
pools and tenses.
Okay.
Now their method was putting a comma
after this.
Good.
It will just tell you
that there are two elements in this
did not replace in that comma.
So it ignores that that connector based on
which you guys are speaking.
So this not it will not be included
in the output.
I'll do it based on space in here. But
why it prints two lines
and so Alexi,
we are using this period in here
so they will show a very different output.
Yes. So let me explain
about the regular expressions there.
Then you will realize why
it is showing you different output.
So when we put this to the in here,
so it is splitting now
based on P on or B, and why?
So when you when it will be
it will split it again.
It will see or it will speak it again.
It will say it will speak it.
So in the square brackets
it means or condition in here.
Let me explain
about the regular expressions.
Then you guys will see
no commas. Yes.
So then if you are using a looping here,
then you guys will not be
seeing any comma.
Okay.
Because now we are using the looping here.
So Aleksey white principal line
because we have the start.
And after before this note,
we hear the sentence and after this
we have an other sentence.
Okay. So that's why we see it to work.
So it is splitting this
bigger string based on that period.
Okay.
So in that it splits
that input into two pieces.
So let's try to learn
about the regular expressions next.
Then then the split method.
Actually,
let me let's discuss this method.
If you guys have more questions,
let's discuss this
after regular expressions.
Okay.
So the
we are missing something.
And on this part,
guys, I want you to focus.
It's very powerful and you guys can solve
many different problems with these regular
expressions vertically. You
see, I have this
in there.
So you have this sentence
and I want to replace certain things
inside this sentence.
So if we are inside this string.
So I have this method.
SDR not replaced.
Okay.
And we specify two things in here.
What is the specific name of this?
Specify name for work?
Massive.
So this thing that we want to replace
and the string
which we want to place
is the regular expressions,
relics or regular expression.
Yeah.
So that specific ping will be replaced
inside that string.
Okay.
Using this replacement pair
and now if we have a string.
Okay.
And if we call this method again,
I mean, what type a string is
this?
Okay, so what we will see in both
the occurrences will be replaced
inside the string.
But what happens is that in real life,
sometimes let's see, we have to find out
a specific
Batman's inside.
So then just
replace is a certain character
or a word inside
a string within the string.
So in here it is replacing
this word with Great.
Okay, so you specify the word
B, which you want to replace.
Okay?
And then you specify the word
with which you want to replace.
We have to replace two words
How can we do that?
So the three now, you mean that
if we want to replace good and bad
rulers like this.
So you remember guys,
we can Jean B methods, right?
So we can again call this a replace method
and this time
we can specify
batch. We
know exactly.
Okay, then we can change other letters
again.
We can so we can keep on.
Not bad. Not bad.
So you guys can keep on joining
the matters inside this string class.
What if need to replace only first word
or the second one?
So there is this method
if it is available in. Yes.
So you see this replace first
method alone.
I do not going to do it in the next line.
You guys are not going to.
Or if I only want to replace
the first occurrence,
not replace
so I can call this replace first method.
Okay.
So now
first occurrence of this good is replaced.
But this second one is still good. Okay.
That's how we replace
only the first occurrence.
And if you guys want to replace something
in between or the last and then again,
you guys can split this in
and you can a loop.
Then compare the words.
If the word is that specific word,
you replace it with something else
and then you reboot the edit.
So you guys can write any logic
when there are no specific
methods for certain things.
Is it clear,
guys, how this replace replace all
right.
Now, so I was saying that if you guys have
technicalities, then
so let me motivate you guys.
So during the break,
I was talking to a student
batch IC, making
sure to check.
So he was a very good student.
So he said that as I asked
him, that college job and everything.
So it's a completely amazing life,
completely changed from a year or two
ago, less spent more time with family.
And I ask him. So he asked me.
I told him that it will be more better
after 3 to 6 months,
and he said that it will be ending
and he was long career.
So I asked him that
how much he is getting there.
So right now
he's getting paid 90 or 90 actually,
and he will be asking for it again.
And he's very happy.
So I don't know about your current job
situations,
but you guys will be you guys will be the
soon you guys will be in this position.
The rent is bad.
So it's been just, I guess, four months.
Yes, it's four months.
And now he will be getting a raise
and he is very happy
spending more time with family
and all of that.
And believe me, some of the students,
they are only filling the Excel sheet.
They are very happy
because they are hired.
They are too much. And developers
and big companies, they are
they have to start
the automation part, yet
they haven't started
the automation part yet.
So currently is good.
But better work news than not has.
Yes, some of the people,
they want to use the physical building.
They like the physical work.
Some of like to use their brain fluid,
get part time job.
I know it sounds like a stupid.
There are so many
jobs. Even the part time jobs
for the international students.
You guys can also are
88 nine day
and there are so many companies
who will be looking for the talent
and they don't care
which part of the world you guys belong.
If you have dependent, you can apply
and they will do all the necessity,
paperwork and all that stuff.
My current job is awesome.
I can't leave.
They're just being disturbing
for backup plan.
There's also good, right?
So I was saying that sometimes
what happens is that we want to replace
not only
characters.
I used to work for a company
which I was getting more than 148,
so I desperately need a job like,
that's good.
So let's say I have a starting guys,
and this time I don't want to replace
only a certain word or a certain letter,
but now I want to replace every thing
that follows a certain pattern.
So let's see if there are numbers,
less than five
numbers, numbers from 1 to 5.
If there are lowercase letters,
I want to replace them.
Maybe if there are a special characters
like the dollar sign,
the all the symbols that you guys see
on your keyboard,
how about replace string with job?
Yes. Or one that is also possible.
So inside double corp
you can pass a single character
or multiple characters. So
let's say, guys,
I have this very complex string, okay?
Because uppercase letters, lower
guess letters and then numbers
and then the special get it
and now I want to process the string.
Okay,
So what I can do, I have done it
without replace method
this part.
So I one this one,
even if you guys know Indianapolis.
So even if you guys are able to solve
these complex problems
without the regular expressions,
these regular expressions,
they are not only very powerful,
but they are also very efficient.
So they don't use loops
at the back end
to replace these detectors.
So they will always be giving you
better performance.
It looks like the task.
All right.
So let's say nice.
You want to replace
the numbers from 0 to 5.
Okay.
So now
what you can do is
you can call this and replace
all method and this replace all method.
It expects a regular expression.
Okay.
A regular expression is nothing
but a combination of
special characters, letters and numbers
that defines a pattern.
And then Java searches for back
pattern inside your string.
And if it finds one, it replaces.
And if you would,
please show them or two on the side
to complete typing the issue.
This one
color.
So in here what we can do,
we can use a regular expression
in the regular expression.
So one way of doing this is that we say
zero one, two, three, four, five.
And if there are any letters
like this,
let's say we want to replace them
with stops.
Okay?
So every year there is a letter, a zero
or one or two or three or five,
it will be replaced with this star symbol
just to this screenshot.
It will be easy.
So in this resultant string,
we will not be having that.
But you guys can see,
let's say if I want to replace
all the characters from to nine,
then I have to type all the characters.
So there are shorter ways. Okay,
So look, I can do, I can say 0-5
if the recruiter does not like this,
like B first
you say how he will give you this on
so I can specify a range.
Okay.
Now, every number from 0 to 5,
if it is present inside this string,
it will be replaced with a stop symbol.
I would replace all of some of that,
but don't remember
which.
Then all the numbers from 0 to 5.
Yes, even 40 letters.
So I can see in there to say
maybe I want to replace
all the lowercase letters from
A to Z with this star. Okay.
So I can give the range for B letters
as well.
If the criteria went to use
the stops
in both and you to double course.
So Mohammad, when the method is expecting
a regular expression, okay,
so other than a space
or individual characters, you guys will
always be using most of the time
you will be using these square brackets.
Okay, so there is a comp
like you guys can spend the next two,
3 to 6 months
just learning the regular expressions.
They are that big. Okay.
The they are that big
and almost all the programing languages
they have gives that expressions.
This syntax of writing these veterans.
Yes, it's used to find a password
matching.
This is how companies
find out if your password
contains certain things, if it is
in the range or not.
This is how you find out
about those limitations on stains
when you are creating
your username and password.
And you guys can use it
in many different ways.
So what will happen now?
All the lowercase letters inside
my string, they will be replaced
with the star of stopped in here.
So brackets
use two and more than one character,
not only more than
one character, but to specify
B spectrums as well.
So you can do this, replace all
and the split method,
they expect a regular expression.
Other than that, you guys,
you guys will not be needing this because
these square brackets are only needed.
Five split and replace all matters
because they work
on regular expressions
and inside regular expressions.
They are many different ways
to specify the same thing.
Think so.
Can you guys tell me if I want to replace
all the uppercase letters?
What would I specify in here?
Mine did not change,
but can you screenshot?
And then I need uppercase
E and uppercase Z
case name and uppercase.
Now all the uppercase and C
is being placed
and now
what if I want to do all letters of.
But yes, let me tell you what
index this
so format.
Is there any number in your string?
If there is no
there is no number in your string,
then then how how Java can replace that
and then how double can replace that.
You are you are saying
that replaced numbers from 0 to 5.
Right.
But but there is no number So
so if I want to specify
and multiple conditions
like let's say
maybe I want to replace all the uppercase
and all lowercase,
then I can specify it like this.
I can specify it like this.
Okay.
Now all the uppercase
and all the lowercase board
will you and replace
it is testing you
to make sure you are not sleeping
good.
Yes, we can use the chaining as well.
So, Maria.
Yes, you are right.
So for example, you can do this
or you can use beginning, right?
Or do you think
you can again call this replace all.
Okay.
And this time
you guys can specify
it In your case log
with the help of staining
and specifying the condition or
how can I put out
all symbols?
Alexa, you want to replace everything
inside this string?
You want to replace
the special characters.
Okay, so
as we have the not condition
inside dialog
to negate a certain condition,
what we can do,
we can also use in negation in here.
So let's say, for example,
you want to replace
it going go to replace
numbers, uppercase
letters and lowercase letters,
but you want to replace anything
other than that.
Okay, So we can specify in non condition
with the scattered sign.
Okay,
so the scatter sign, what it is saying,
don't replace to Z lowercase,
don't replace A to uppercase,
don't replace numbers,
but replace everything else.
If we execute this code,
then all other things
other than numbers, uppercase
and the lowercase letters, they will be.
Yes. So in here
the north symbol is not the exclamation
mark, but be not symbol is D
is the letter sign
is it is a clear.
Alexi
Okay.
And if you want to completely remove
so I'll do this last last part
no spaces ever right.
So this last part is saying yes,
it's negating this condition.
Okay, here's the north of this condition.
So if you're saying don't replace it
to the end of numbers,
but replace every thing else inside,
that's fine.
Now, everything else
of these symbols in here.
Okay, so
you want but if you want to replace them,
you can.
It's not simple.
Now, let me show you some resources
to learn
about these regular expressions. So
there are so many symbols
and in these regular expressions
they are super, super complex.
So if you guys want to learn these,
actually let share in
because
if you guys want to practice them
and if you guys want to learn them,
you can go to this website
at the end.
If you guys click on these
as regular expressions
reference
and then
character classes,
you guys can start learning
and experimenting.
These are regular expressions. So
now if you guys want to check neck there.
So for example,
I specify
it Z in here
and then you guys will instantly,
you guys can see that all the uppercase
letters inside this,
inside this paragraph,
they are highlighted.
Okay,
so this square bracket it to the syntax.
This is how it works.
So what you guys can do,
you can click on this link in here.
Okay?
And then you can read the description
how, this syntax or what
this syntax is doing.
Okay?
You can save that to save match
any character in this in this set.
And then it specify
it shows you an example
and then it gives you the answer for that
and then you can select it in here.
Okay?
Then you can negated said you could
you specify the scattered
symbol in here and then you
you can negate certain characters,
then you can
you can learn about this build ranges,
you can learn about the dark symbols
and all that. Okay,
you miss.
So yes, if the
if you guys don't specify proper
regular expression master,
you will be getting an error.
Okay.
So the first thing
inside the double coast,
of course,
it must be a regular expression.
Okay.
And then you guys can keep on doing
learning all those things.
And one more thing, dialog.
So usually
as a developer or as a tester,
you should not learn about, you should not
spend too much time
on learning these regular expressions
because if you guys realize they are
so there are so many rules
and things like all the rules
that you guys will be learning in Java,
there are more
rules in in these regular expressions
than the company of Java.
So instead of doing this,
what you guys can do,
you can simply search
for regular expressions on Google.
So let's say, for example, I want to
I want to replace all the numbers
in this string.
So ah, you guys can see how to
you can see
what regular expression
will replace
numbers. Okay.
And then you guys will most probably
will see something on the Stack overflow
like this. Okay.
In first one of the answers
and this is recommended approach
that I will recommend instead of spending
too much time on regular expressions
and because they are super, super complex,
I want you
go to this platform a little bit
and then you guys can always search
if you are looking for a certain
regular expression to match
a certain pattern inside this thing.
Okay.
And one more thing that I want to show.
So that range, it actually works on
on this ask you table.
And so you see the range
that I am specifying A to Z or A to Z
or or 0 to 9
is actually working
based on this ASCII table.
So let's say, for example,
you want to replace this double course
hash symbols and just dollar sign
so you can start your range
from double code and then you can enter
your range on this opening bracket.
So this is how
Java determines the range.
Why don't you teach Selenium?
Because I will be tired of
teaching Java and I need some rest.
And selenium is just right after this
Java.
So I will be teaching school
and I will be teaching Jenkins to you.
Actually, guys, let me tell you, this
job of teaching is all about patience.
If you are tired, if you are
overloaded on your job,
you you cannot teach well
for the minimum.
I think more some or maybe,
maybe Suhail will be teaching you.
I say you are the teacher right now.
So you see this range.
You start from number 65
and then it goes all the way to see, okay,
so this is how you can
you can make your ranges
if you are working on something
very complex.
But the the thing that I will recommend
is always, always first first,
just search it on the Google.
If you don't find that thing,
then I will recommend you
to build your own regular expression here
because they are so complex
and this is how the basic syntax work.
Okay.
And I let me show you one more thing.
If you want to specify multiple characters
to be replaced,
so let's say you want to be replaced this
goal or sorry,
and then maybe this person design
or maybe any other character.
So if there are only 4 to 5 Director
So you guys see
now it will replace only this thing.
So this is it works like the or condition
or condition, but
and one more thing.
If you if you guys want to completely
remove those letters from your strings.
So let's say
I want to remove all the numbers.
All the numbers.
So instead of specifying anything,
you guys can leave this
as the null string.
Okay.
Or the empty string, and then Java will
remove those characters from your string.
So you guys see all the numbers
have been removed from this string.
So it would be entered as and is 66,
I mean 65.
So Maryam at the end,
yes it is working on those numbers.
Those are speed numbers.
Can we write like this.
Well it'd be nice to replace this.
So in here, Alex, you want to specify.
I like this.
Okay, let's try that.
You see,
it has been replaced in here again.
It has been replaced.
There was no, it was not replaced.
This.
This works like the or condition. Okay.
As many characters
as you guys want to put in here,
you can put it in here,
you can specify ranges
and you you can specify actually very,
very complex backgrounds.
Like, for example,
if you see a number
greater than nine, less than seven,
and after that, if you see a number
that is multiple of two
or something like that.
So you can specify all those
factors inside your string.
Okay.
But these are regular expressions
because they are very complex
and they have a very different syntax.
So we will not be spending too much time
on them over it if you guys needed them.
And most of the time have seen
that in the interviews.
At least one question.
If they are asking that question
from strings, it will be most probably
it will be from regular expressions. Okay.
So I want you to have some practice
of back platform
and some practice searching
and then replacing some bad trends
inside your strings.
And really, you guys don't understand
why we were using these shared records
in the split part,
we were actually looking for better
ones.
Will you be helping us
with the interviews?
Yes. Silva
I will be helping you with the interviews.
Okay. So this is how the replace works.
So replace does not take irregular
expressions as being
as the first string.
It will be taking the simple,
ordinary stains.
I mean, with the real ones. Yes.
Also mean the real ones.
The mock interviews.
We will be inviting your
your seniors
the most recent batch students.
And first they will explain
how all the process learned.
Then They will be taking your interviews,
asking the asking
the questions that were asked to them
and then if you guys boss
the mock interviews,
we will be building your ways.
Once we build it.
As always, we will be teaching you
how to apply on the jobs.
So basically
we will be taking care of everything.
You guys just need to study and
work. Need to at the end.
You guys need to remember 70 to 80%
of what we are teaching in the classes
and this
matter date on the new spring resulting
from replacing
all the occurrences of old
in this string with the new string.
When you see a market, what platforms
it means all the companies,
all the IP companies
who will be looking for
resources like you.
So this is just an example
that come on board
to place
or we would be so all the actors below
to see if they will be replaced
and the all the others.
Okay,
so it will be replaced with capital B,
then we have to replace all it works
with the regular expression
specifying the changes,
specifying the node conditions.
And these are just some ampoules.
And then we have this method.
This is just an example.
Now these are your tasks.
Does it mean that I need to remove
my contract from every We are not.
We will be asking you to build
new Gmail accounts.
We will be giving you a new identity.
We will be reviewing all your history
with the help of CIA new faces,
new names.
So these are your classmates.
So don't worry.
We have connections everywhere.
New your clients.
If we want to replace America,
we need to put it in a single course.
I know you can use the double quotes
as well.
More bot works
single course, double course.
Yes. And will
or do you are being serious?
I am 50% serious.
Good examples
of the things we are doing today.
So this is just another example.
Now let's discuss
about this string and this string builder.
Okay.
Now this is also
something really important.
So we have another class
that does almost everything,
same as distinct class.
All the matters, almost all the matters
that are present inside this class.
They are also present inside
that other class.
That class is called String Builder class.
And then we have another
sister class of same builder class
that is called string buffered class
is with new entity
and at the
end you will be in your bedroom and say,
Who is this person?
Get to send.
Okay, the now why we have these two
two different classes.
So I have a question for you guys.
And this
proxy
looks like
I am writing a very big program.
Okay.
And what
I am storing, let's say
this, this letter is
inside this string.
Then I somewhere else in this program,
I am declaring and bursting.
And again, I am storing letter in here
and then I am doing it again and again.
I think about an application
who is supporting
maybe the data
of all the citizens of the U.S.
and that software.
It has a failure to store the names.
It has a field to store DCT
and it has a field to store the state
and then a field to store the country.
Okay, Now For all the citizens of
the U.S., what will be their country guys
in U.S.
right
now when computers
in this pool of the information
okay inside
a string.
Inside a string.
So let's say
for all the citizens of the U.S.,
we will be storing these different fields
now we have storing this name,
this country name again and again.
So what do you guys think?
So for each variable.
So let's see if I am storing same value
in in two different variables,
what do I think?
Should it be better that I only declare
I only occupy one single cell
from the memory?
I store this letter this spring here
and both the variables
they applied to the same memory location?
Or is it better that I stole?
I occupied two different cells
and these
these variables, they applied for control,
these two different member locations.
One cell. Right.
And you can imagine this
scale that if you are sporting
a piece of information
like country, state or city,
how much space guys can save
if you are reusing
the same memory location again and again.
Right.
But can you guys can you
can you tell me the downside
of this
reusing this cell again and again,
what would it
what it will cost me
two large more time
How how more time Sharif
how how more time
looping and finding perfect.
So what will happen guys if have
to leave 30 plus million variables
right.
To hold the country
for all the citizens of the United States?
What Java has to work through
is that each time
I declare a new variable,
Java will check if this content
that I am trying
to store inside this variable.
If it is already present inside the memory
or not right.
So with this memory location, this memory
location, this memory location,
if there are 1 million string variables
already stored inside the memory,
Java will first scan
all those 1 million cells
to find out if this is
is already present
inside the computer's memory or not.
Right.
If it is present,
then it will not specify it.
And new memory location
and the variable will point
to the exact same memory location.
Do you guys understand
how it can nugget effect the performance?
So as I told you guys,
when whenever you guys are writing
a software application,
there are two to to check its performance.
There are two parameters
how much space that program takes
and how much time that program
to find out a solution
or to solve the real life problem.
Okay.
Now, sometimes
we don't care about the memory
okay, we needed something that can return
us the results as soon as possible.
But sometimes we are looking
for the applications,
which should not be more memory,
but it is okay if they are a little slow.
I think of the smaller devices, right?
If you are programing a fridge
or a refrigerator or a microwave
oven or a car or things like that,
they are very low on memory.
So you don't want to
you don't
want to waste a lot of memory in there.
But sometimes if you are building
an application that can process the data
of all the citizens in the USA,
you can maybe having
a lot of servers behind behind the scenes,
but you won't be.
Results will be very quick.
So can you tell me
So this is the behavior of string.
String always searches the memory.
If that specific world
is already there inside the memory
string class does not declare
new memory location
and it applied the variables
already stored data.
Okay, so can you guys
tell me in which scenarios And by the way,
the string builder, it does reverse String
builder will never search in the memory.
It will always be
declaring a new memory cell.
So can you guys tell me where
when I should building string
and when I should be using string builder?
No, no, it's very simple question.
So let's say I want to build a lot
and let me simplify this.
I want to build an application
which does not take more memory
but is okay if it takes a little
more time, which class should I use?
Sting or String builder?
Let me repeat macOS ten.
It's okay
if the application is taking more time,
but I don't want waste a lot of memory
which class I should use.
I should use the string class. Right.
Because a string class,
it does not declare new memory location.
It always try to recycle it,
always try to reuse
already declared memory locations.
And if want the performance
and I don't care about the storage,
which class I should use
the string builder class.
Okay, that's simple.
Now there is another
and there is another class
called the String Buffer Class.
And if you guys remember our discussion
about the
about the threads that there are multiple
use these days on computers
and these CPUs,
they can solve the problem
and in parallel.
So they also have consequences
when they solve the problem in parallel.
Okay so well, what happens, guys,
if there is
there is only one
cake and there are ten people
after that gig
now, they don't want to share it.
If they don't want to share
and they won't be complete cake.
I get the biggest slice,
the big fight.
So this big fight,
it also happens the computers
because there are multiple sapiens
looking for the same resource.
Okay, there are multiple physical cores
who are trying to access
the same memory location.
When that happens, there is this fight
and usually that cake is destroyed
or it just more just was wasted
and no one gets nothing.
So when this is the case
and we want to make sure that everything
smoothly and everyone gets
the proper proportion of the cake
or everyone else
follow their turn to complete something,
we use that starting before class.
They're testing
before the class in a special class.
Who takes care of those multiple
physical cores on your computer
and dictates which board should use
the variable
when and once run is done
using that variable,
it allows to use the under code to use
that variable that is called trend safety.
In technical terms,
it's called trend safety.
Now we have this difference on this slide.
So let me read this slide for you.
All right.
So this behavior
is this behavior of string class to
R to reuse these memory locations.
It causes another problem.
Let me explain that problem.
So let's say this is the memory location.
We have the US A stored.
Now we have this person, but some I show.
All right.
We have this person
and left at the lecture.
The everyone is residing in this
now most of them
they are living in the United States.
But Emma decides to move to the turkey.
This.
So what will happen, guys?
Now the country of the residents
for the AMOC
needs to be changed right?
But if and what changes is country?
Because we are using
one single memory location.
If it changes this country to Turkey,
what will happen to the country of or what
will happen to the country of resident
five i Asia.
It will also change.
It will also be changed to Turkey, right?
Is a good behavior or bad behavior.
So to avoid these things, what Java?
What what over Java
to follow this approach that when it sees
that there are too many people
using the same content in a variable,
yes, Java will automatically
have new memory locations.
It will keep on assigning
the same variable to everyone.
As soon as Java sees
that someone is trying
to change the contents of this memory
location, Java says their camera.
You know what?
Let me be clear.
One more memory location for you,
because we want to change something
that we declared
a new memory location for you and then you
please now, prior to this memory location,
instead of this and again,
you please don't change the content
for the other variables.
So this behavior of when we try to change
something in a string variable,
this behavior of Dallas
and this this behavior of string class
and that it
declared the new member location
and then it
and the person to that memory
location is called immutability.
It says that Java does not change
the contents
of a string
once they are stored in the memory.
And if someone is trying
to change the contents
in new memory,
location will be declared and.
That person has to point out
to that memory location
because we don't want to disturb
330 million plus people.
Right.
If everyone is storing
USA as the country of residence
and if one of them is trying
to change its country of residence,
we don't want to mess up the data
for all other people.
So what Java does,
it declares a new memory location
and then it finds that new memory location
for person.
Is it clear? Right.
This immutability behavior of Java
Java single
for this kind of IP, U.N.
and peacekeeper.
Okay. But that string builder class.
So do we need this immutability behavior
for the string builder as guys
we're rejecting
or we will not be facing this problem
in the string builder
because String Builder,
it always creates a new memory, right?
It never stores. It never checks.
If something is already store,
even if something is already stored,
it will be creating a new memory location.
So we don't face that problem in the next
like string
builder class is not immutable,
but the string class
is immutable.
So I shot.
Yes, I would
I would like to give you guys examples,
but all of this is going
behind the scenes inside
computer's memory
that that's why we cannot have examples.
So the the the point of this
whole discussion
is that you guys understand
when to use the string class and when to
use the sprinkler string builder class.
If it is clear when you guys
should be using the string class
and when to use the string builder class,
that's the complete point.
Can you just tell me
when I should be using a string
class?
So perhaps
actually there is a software called
or scan
Git Indian or something to look
for the contents
of your computer's memory.
Let me show you.
Actually, I don't want to mess.
This is how we hack the games
using this software.
So let's say, for example,
if you are playing a game
and you have you earn points
when you play the game.
And right now and then
there are new levels that are logged.
When you have more points.
So the data for back
line is is stored in a variable.
And what you guys can do
when the game is being
is being played
on, your computer using this software,
you can access the memory location
where the coins are stored.
You can change the value over there
and then you can unlock all the levels.
You have done this.
So but it can also mess up your program
and your operating system.
So those who want to experiment
with the memory, you guys can use this key
opinion in here.
All right.
So let me check
if we are missing something on this slide.
Can you cheat Clash of Clans?
Yes, you guys can.
To Clash of Clans using this software.
So even if you
spend some time
in a company where we used to have things,
I learned about this
and there are two
game using
them.
Okay.
Like any game using cheating
and those who are interesting,
you guys can
you guys can watch some videos on YouTube.
Okay.
Can you tell when to use sprinkler
and string builder once again?
So can you guys tell your guitar
when I should be
using the sprinklers?
US How to hack a bank account
and I don't want to be in jail
do my little bro.
Then I do this.
You guys can almost hack anything
on your computer, but make sure that
so once you restart that game,
the changes will be gone
because you are only making changes
inside your RAM.
And once that game is being played,
you guys can the variables value
and all that.
And yes,
it is possible for all the programs
so string
when we want to save memory right
things we should be using strings
when we want to save memory
because spins they try reuse the memory,
but they are slow because they first
have to touch the memory
and bin the and new with you,
but I hope can be in one.
So the hope is a server based application.
Michael So the actual variables
and all the memory is located on a server.
First, you need to access that server
to change the contents of that to hope.
So it is not possible.
Thing is immutable and stable.
That is not material. Yes.
Yes. So Sting uses less memory,
but they are slower.
The string builder
uses more memory.
But it's fast
and those who want to
hack softwares.
If you guys don't want to actually
let me stop the recording.
So it includes a lot of images and it's
actually written by experts.
Who knows how your brain works
and how to eat your brain
because most of you
think most of you can go to see it
while reading this book.
Well, usually reading the books.
So this book is written
in a specific on a specific pattern
to avoid that.
And it's a great book for B or B starters
are baby words.
Yes, this is exactly for you guys.
So do you guys understand?
What does this immutability mean?
We don't change the values of this thing.
Variables every time.
If someone has to change something
in new memory, location is declared
from that person and we want that memory
location to that variable.
So this called immutable
once string object is created,
it's back to or state
can't be changed,
but a new string object is created.
If you try to change that.
Java Skipping builder
class is used to create mutable strings
in the strings that we can modify.
The String Builder class in Java is
same as class, except it is mutable.
That is, it can be changed.
So under the hood, inside the computer's
memory, things can change
this thing.
Build only the class that used
when there is a necessity
to make a lot of modification
to the string characters.
When we are moving to some,
we're using a paper.
So if you guys are making a lot of changes
to the string variable recording
recording according to use string,
will the class
and the next idea that we will be
using the intelligent IT it will point out
if you guys are making
a lot of changes to a variable
and it will tell you use
stink class or distinguish
the class accordingly.
If a string can be modified
or change is known as mutable
string builder and angular classes
are used for creating mutable strings.
Okay, this is just an example so far.
String Builder class.
We say a singular object name new
and the string builder.
And in here we specify the value.
These
are different in stain classes
immutable string builder is mutable,
string is slow and consumes more memory.
When you can get too many things
because every time
it creates a new instance.
Okay,
so when you are making a lot of changes,
first
it will search all the memory locations.
Then it will create a new memory location.
Okay.
And then it will be consuming more memory
because every time
you are storing a new value
inside that variable.
Okay, that is fast.
And then we have less memory
when you concatenate strings.
So if you are making changes
to a string variable again and again,
try to use string data
or next year
I will go to distinguish the interesting
thing again in the next class.
And these are the tasks for you
and I have shared the task
and because called fast gender.
Okay.
And if there are no questions
let's call it
the day
of our guys remember I think care
quality night.