I am good.
Fortunately. On.
Good morning, Sebastian.
Good morning.
I hope everyone is doing great
and everyone in the room
and the.
All right.
Let's create a new package
for today's class.
So, you know, won't
be one
smart
speaker
on one.
How many of you
watched the video again?
Because you guys couldn't
focus during the class.
People, you are.
I did.
But I am still confused.
We will clear the confusion today.
Do you guys understand now the overloading
and overwriting which one is hard?
The overloading or the overriding
overloading?
Learning.
How many Java classes do we have?
More.
I think overwriting is hard
and you guys will be having 10
to 12 more classes.
Make more sense out of your lottery.
They just need to learn
how to provide in brackets and semicolons.
They'll struggling with
semicolons in brackets.
Overwriting is easy to differentiate,
therefore it's easy.
So let's start from the overloading part.
What it was like
only is same to overwriting.
Yes, they are very closely
related to each other.
The older writing
actually we achieve polymorphism
through overwriting.
Overwriting is based
like an instance variable
in a class, right?
Not, not quite.
Margaret We will discuss it, but
so let's start from the overloading.
Yes, start memorizing part, guys.
I would say focus on
only the only on the main terminologies
and try to practice as much as possible.
Because even if you guys
memorize all the key words and everything,
by the end of this course,
you guys will most probably forget
all of it.
But the practice
that you guys will be having,
it will help you out in your
selenium, in your cucumber
test and API and all that.
So I will suggest,
I will suggest to memorize these things
if you are struggling with those still
after spending five
4 to 5 months, if you are still struggling
with terminologies
like construct overloading
methods, classes off decks,
I will suggest you to revise those
at the end of the course because you guys
will be needing them in the interview
and once you clear the interview again,
it will all be practice
that you guys will be doing on your jobs.
How you you have to eat
at least for 15 days.
And if you are married,
stay away from your wife.
Otherwise nothing will work on you. 30
Let's start
from the overloading.
No, you are right. Actually I can confirm
that and a few tens of elements.
So after course most of the people
are getting dogs and I will
hopefully not the later pardon. Not
and but it is really predictability
or that
so where do you guys remember
about the overloading.
So is this overloading name.
Does it confuse you guys?
Like we are creating multiple copies
of this of the same method,
but we are calling it overloading
something like
we have overloaded.
I mean, if something can get indicated,
we have placed
maybe 100 or one configured
in that that thing.
Right.
Overloaded.
So but what is overloading
them?
Method name different parameters
exceeding capacity
method can have same name,
but different number of parameters,
different sequence or different types.
Name can be a same name will always be
same, but parameters should be different.
Overloading is one of the important
concepts in Java is that
that's a great definition of massive.
If nothing comes in your mind,
you can always say that
inheritance is a great concept
and important concept in Java.
The governance
of method must be different.
Same name format
with different parameters.
So again, same
method
then same name
Method is
existing.
I am writing more.
Okay, so
the same name method is the existing
in a class
multiple times
with different
number of
parameters,
different number of parameters.
Or what is this happen?
Can guys other than number of parameters
overloading methods
have the same name but for same idea?
For example, adding we can have different
parameters, but the sequence number
should be same or
different sequence
or different
data types.
So when same name at 30
the existing in a class multiple times
with different number of parameters
or different sequence
of parameters or
different types, then
it is called
method
overload.
Okay.
And what is the benefit of method
overloading?
Why we should use a method overloading
clean less of the right
call that is easy to use, right?
Like for example
the println method. Right?
You guys were using that method
without noticing it, right?
How many tasks, how many printouts
that the same method is doing for you?
It was handling all the data types right?
It was seamless for you.
You were always calling the println method
for all the different data types, right?
So did the
the people who will be using your code
If you are writing a class
and if you are providing
overloaded methods
to handle all the data
types, different parameters,
and the end user,
the people who will be using
your code, their life will be super easy.
Okay, so
it's easy for any of that.
Now let's discuss some rules
about the
method of
school.
So what are what are the rules?
If I have to overload a method of guys,
let's start from B from the left.
So when we are defining a method,
what is the first thing that comes
if we are starting from left?
Is it the access modifier to be started?
Non access modifier,
the return type, the method name,
the parameter,
the signature, the access modifiers.
So what do we do?
What is the effect of access
modifiers on method overloading?
Do do
do they have any effect on overloading?
Access modifiers
help with the visibility of method,
but do they play any role in method
overloading? No.
Right.
So access modifiers
do not
do not play any role in
method
overloading.
Yeah.
And let me actually write
some of them for public private.
It's okay.
All right.
So after the access modifiers
we have the non access modifiers.
Can you guys tell me
any non access modifier
this static. Right.
It's a non access modifier.
So does this static
static modifier non access modifier.
Does it have,
does it play any role in method
overloading.
Well what is the role of this static
in method overloading?
I mean, if I am using static
with a method, can I overloaded?
If I am not using it with the method
and I overloaded?
Or what is the role of this static
in method overloading
this again same
again.
It's the same
as we have the access modifiers
so it does not play any role.
That means it does not
affect would be overloading
and it has nothing to do with overloading.
You can overload static methods.
You can overload non static
methods. Right?
There is no issue
or there is no rule
about the static non excess modifier.
Okay.
I was not sure about this one.
Good to know. So
no on access modifier
modifiers
like start the final
DC again.
They also don't play any roles in method
overload.
Is there anyone confused?
Because a lot of you answered in the
yes when I asked about this
finally is also a keyword,
a non access modifier.
Hooray.
We will learn about that.
Find this final as
if two more methods have the same name
and the same parameter list.
Then they cannot be defined before
and only by using static
d keyword.
Yes, if you are right, it's a question.
Yes. So.
So what happens is that
let me actually show this as the
or we will do the example if remind me
when I start the example, I will show
one example about this as well.
So what is the next thing, guys?
When we define a method,
what is the next thing?
Let me just write notes for you.
The return type, right?
We can have a return type
like integer spinning
boolean or void.
So do these return types.
Do they play any role
or can I overload a method
by just changing your return type?
No. Again, no.
They also don't play
any role in overloading.
We cannot overload by changing
only the return type.
My question were
we need to write return type in method
bracket or after I always get at a loop.
We need to write a return type
in method inside the method.
If the method is returning a data type,
then you need to write the keyword return
and after that
the data type that you have mentioned
in the management method header.
So these two things, they should be same.
Okay, remind me
when I am doing examples, I will show
you that. So
method
return types also
play any roles in method overloading.
We can
overload.
We can overload a
method by
okay, so we can't.
We can't overload the method by just
changing
the return type.
Yeah.
Ward or any other return
time does not play any role.
Yes there does not.
You can not overload method by
just changing its return type.
So these three pointers, what do they say?
And they say we cannot overload the method
by changing the access
modifiers
like private, public or protected.
We cannot overload it
so and will overload them better
by changing its non access modifiers.
Static final synchronized Abstract.
You guys will learn about the three neat
little tricks
in the next week.
We cannot overload a method
by just changing the return type.
Okay.
So after that,
what comes after these three queries?
Next is the
name of the method.
So what about the name?
How does the name of a method
play a role in all our loading?
It must be same, right?
It must be same
if we are having two different methods
with two different names,
can I overload them? No.
Like for example, Aisha
and Jimmy were doing yesterday, right?
They created two separate methods
and they were thinking maybe
that they have overloaded those methods
or they have created overloaded methods.
So this is not overloading
the method names.
They must be same.
Okay, so.
So method names
must be same.
No return type should not need
not to be same.
So method names must be same.
If we want to
overload a
method.
Okay,
it is fine.
Just fine.
Don't think that you guys do something
wrong.
Whole idea will crash with.
Yes I do.
The first thing that I will do when she is
doing the job, she will restart.
Restart all the servers, all the computers
and everything
and she will start from scratch.
You guys,
what did you guys watch that season on it?
So every time the IT person
he gets a call, he always says this.
Did you try restarting your computer?
That's a very good season
I will send you the link
you give me and
I will do the name of that that season.
Give me
it. Cool
you So you guys will be able
to relate your your yourself.
Once you get a job you guys will be
it will be very relatable.
All right.
So method name, it must be same
if we want to overload a method
and in the return type
they don't matter.
Signature must be different. Yes.
So after the method name
we have the parameters.
So how does the barometer.
So you guys can say the parameters
are the actual things, right?
That that makes a method overload.
My computer sometimes claimed that I have
low memory, but I have 16 gigs of RAM.
Is this
because my ID is on for a long time?
So moment you can do this.
If you are using windows, you can
press the windows button
and then if your type task manager,
most probably it's Google Chrome
that is eating up all of your memory.
So if you see it
and if you click on the 76%, you see
Google Chrome
is taking about three gigs of my memory.
Okay, I have opened the 46
tabs in Google Chrome and right now
just taking to Google it
then is the intel that is taking 1.5
gates, then slack and then zoom
so you can check that program,
which program is checking more memory
and you can kill it from here.
That's the 46 I thought I was the early
and that they are actually right now
they are the lowest.
I open at least 200 times
when I am programing or doing something
so and I you guys will be doing the same
following your problem
solving on different websites and all that
is intelligence taking Bill Gates.
So how does the parameters affected
the method over
loading guys
should not have the same parameters
how to do that again, Windows button
and what else type?
Task Manager Sebastian I always get time
to go over to clean the browser.
No, the application is allowed.
Not same.
They need to follow different pattern
so barometers
should be
different for each method
either in
number.
Okay.
All right.
Number or in
sequence
or in
back to
high data types.
All right.
And then after that,
we have the method body, method, body.
It does not affect the method overloading.
All right.
Now let's
discuss about the constructors
again, I overload a constructor so
then I overload
a private method.
So all the questions,
if you guys understand these five
first five points, now you can answer
any interview questions
related to overloading
if you guys have understood
these five points.
Okay.
Now your interviewer
will try to confuse you.
Maybe sometimes asking
can we overload protected
method private method instance
method starting methods.
If you focus on these five rules,
you can answer all the questions.
Can I overload the main method? Right?
I mean, method is something different.
But again, it follows
all of these rules, right?
So why can't. Why not? Right.
I can overload the main method as well
so we can overload constructors,
private investors
main method.
Okay. And there is no issue in there.
All right.
What else do you guys remember about the
about the overloading?
Do I need a inheritance relationship
for overloading?
No. Right.
Where do I need that inheritance?
Inheritance relationship? Guys
costing in overloading
what is costing and overloading
Not all.
What is costing?
Overloading.
Okay, let's do an example.
Parent child relationship.
All right, so the first thing
overload from a data type
to another data type
automatically.
Oh, no, no, no.
This is not overloading
and that are converting a data type
to another decade type.
This is not overloading.
It is simply costing.
Overloading has nothing to do with
costing.
Okay.
So the is the first rule.
The first rule that we learned
about the overloading
is that
the method name they should be same.
Okay, so let's write a method.
Okay.
So we are now testing all those points
that we have just written on nodes. Okay.
So that it is clearly
so that you guys can really see it.
So let's say
I have this number.
So the first thing we discussed was
if we are only changing
the access modifier,
we cannot overload a matter.
So let's try to test that.
Okay, So I have copied
and pasted the exact same method
and now let me change the access modifier.
What is the access modifier right now
with these methods?
Guys, it's the default one, right?
Let me put oblique in here. Why?
I still get an error.
Guys,
because we are not overloading.
Right.
And if we don't overblow mode,
we can not have
the exact same methods
inside a class.
Yeah, we will be getting this out of that.
Maybe something is already defined.
Okay,
so method is already defined in here.
So java is confused.
Java can not distinguish
between this method and this matter.
If you try to call this method
from outside of this class
and I will not be able to
go, I will not be able to understand
or doubt.
I will not be able to judge
which method you are trying to write
for example, let's say
if I have a main method in here, here,
and if I create the object of this class,
and if I say method
passing this, then
I get this at the end of phase
order the error, say I'm on
no, okay,
Error does not say anything.
So you guys got the error issued.
Say something like ambiguous method call
ambiguous
method code or something like that.
So that means Java is unable to decide
when I am writing.
This method to do drag
method is unable to decide
whether it should call this method
or this method.
Now in real life
ambiguous method call. Yes.
So this is the error
that you should go to.
So let's say, for example, what can happen
is that these two matters,
they can be totally different, right?
They can be totally different.
So the Java is saying
their tasker,
the method that you are trying to call
I went to this class
and when I checked, when I search,
I found two methods in that class.
Okay?
And the information
that you are providing,
you are only writing the method name and
you are only providing a data type now.
But these two pieces of information,
you are saying that, hey,
it's going to by only this method name
and this parameter.
I cannot decide whether I should call this
method or I should call this method.
Does it make sense, guys,
why Java
is confused?
So which which leads us to this point
that access modifiers they cannot help us.
They can not help us in method
overloading guard
or they do not play any role
in method overloading
what was the next thing guys?
So next thing was the non access modifier.
The sheriff was asking about
not known access modifiers
that he was saying that hey. Yes.
Good. Okay.
Changing the access modifiers
like public private.
Okay does not make any difference.
But what if put a static in here?
Okay.
So again, Sheriff Java is again confused
because you can call a static method
with object
and you can also call in non static
method with the help of an object.
So again, Java saying their task
when you provide
only these two pieces of information.
Still, I cannot decide
whether you are trying to call this method
or this method.
Yes, this will change the accessibility,
but still that type is same.
So still will be getting an error.
So do you guys now understand
the logic as well behind why?
Why Java has these rules?
Why we why we are not allowed
by changing the returns,
by changing the return type
or by changing access modifiers
can you give us an example?
Example of what Sheriff
City put?
What are these
are not needing them
enough.
I will give you give more examples.
Okay.
So if this is your homework
now, you have to search
on the internet Top
ten most widely used classes in Java
and you have to find out
method overloading in all those classes.
You have to tell me
which methods are overloaded.
Okay,
I'm just getting
by the way,
if you guys really want to learn Java,
this is also something
this can be something very useful to
understand the real use cases
of all the concepts
that you guys have been learning.
Right?
Our top ten
most widely used classes in Java
and try to just read through
those classes.
I know that some of the key words,
they will not make sense at this point,
but by the end of I guess next week,
most the things
they will start to make sense.
So maybe I should give this to you
later on.
So by changing the non excess,
modify it again.
No matter overloading. Okay.
And then the next thing is
the return type.
Okay. Next.
Next thing is the return by.
I am learning one thing
and forgetting the others.
If the
said if that means
you have only one CPU core in your mind.
Okay.
Even these days they left out
they have six pools and they can learn
six things at the same time.
Only one big giant core
running or running at 5 hours,
maybe.
I'm just kidding. Don't mind.
Yes, yes.
It's hard talk.
I would not say that it's easy.
It's it's hard.
It requires
a lot of practice and reading. So.
Okay, so next thing this guy next thing
is, is the return type.
Okay.
So the next rule says that
if we would change
only the return type,
hopefully, inshallah.
So the next thing is,
if we only change the return type
again,
we cannot overload a matter.
Okay, this information is not enough.
No, no, no, no.
That is said. If I have seen students,
I think
it's because of their communication
skills.
I mean, they are below average
and they still get a job in the first
or second weeks.
So this communication is very,
very important to the skill
to be able to explain
to others about the concepts.
It's very important.
But whenever I put in color
what you should if is the last one,
you the second last one, right?
And you have to be the last one.
Okay, I'm just getting
so guys the next blind.
Is that just by changing the written type,
I cannot overload a method, okay?
I cannot overload a method.
So still I get an error,
but I am getting it under.
And that error guys, I get an error.
It says missing the written statement
so maybe Nayak can help us in here.
Naah. Well, what should we do?
So do we put return statement in brackets
or outside of these break
off these curly brackets
outside.
Right. Great explanation.
So we should put the return type in here.
Right.
So then that's
why you get to be at the.
Yeah, definitely
you will be getting the error right.
Because this is very method starts
and this is where your method ends.
Right.
So why, why
put this written outside of this method?
But if I change inside, it's still error.
No, it should not be error.
So now we have player
should be return type.
Right now we get another area.
It says are expecting a semicolon
right next for the semicolon as well.
So we are just reading the error
and following the problem.
Okay.
We still there the error
now we say is missing return value, right?
Missing the return value.
That means that means your method
is expecting a value of type
integer to be returned.
Okay.
But what we are returning
what we are returning in here now
we are returning nothing.
No, no, we are returning nothing.
We are not returning nothing.
I have replaced anything
inside these return and the semicolon.
No, I haven't placed anything.
So I am returning nothing so I can do this
error is just saying
return anything Anything
which is all type integer.
It can be a constant number
like this. Okay.
And it can be the number that you are
taking from the arguments like this.
Oops.
Okay.
So this error,
it only says just put anything,
any variable name,
any constant value, anything.
We use an integer. Okay.
And and the edit is gone.
Yeah.
So now
so so guys start trying to load this up,
start reading your answers and now
try to make try to understand those.
What are what are these errors
What are these are saying to you.
Okay.
And then after six months or one months,
if anyone will be telling you,
the anyone will be showing you
the error, you guys will be telling them
the line numbers, the classes,
the exact matters we are we're that
those people, they are getting the errors.
Okay.
So try to now go through those errors
as that.
Okay.
So again, so I have fulfilled
all the requirements of this method.
I am returning a value.
I have returned return the return keyword,
I have placed the semicolon, but still
I get an error that it says
method is already defined.
Okay,
I still get the error that there is this
ambiguous matter.
Okay.
So again, we cannot overload a method
by only changing if return by.
Okay.
Do you guys want me to comment this out?
Maybe for your reference
so that you guys can learn or keep
on changing this method?
Okay.
So first we learned about the access
modifier, right?
So we, we placed like this public
works, right?
This is the first example that we did.
So let's comment this out
and let's put in not note in here
in or
overload
by just
changing the
access
modifier.
Yeah,
delete it
so that when you change it to public.
Oh nice.
Because we are trying to redefine
the same method, it's
because of overloading.
Okay then we discussed about this
static one.
My console complained
that the name of the written method
is same as divide E.
It can also be the reason.
Are we going to go over overriding A Yes,
We will go overwriting as well because
I think a lot of you were busy
making jokes.
I was serious yesterday.
You this is you.
You guys were making jokes
to each other, right?
And you guys didn't pay any attention.
It's all because of you
that we are spending
the time again in here.
So is overloading across multiple classes
or packages
possible or off utility overload
Thing is always in the same class.
You are right here. So all are filed.
So I am practicing my
for my flight of my wife.
Right.
How to put everything on her.
So we put the static keyword.
No no overloading.
We change the excess modifier,
no overloading.
We're talking about why
So that I am asking them
questions today,
but because my overwriting is done
correctly in my own work
but did not quite understand
how to calculate the interest,
I will show you that no, no issues.
Okay.
So not possible
and not overload by just changing
non access
modifier.
Okay.
And then we can also
overload.
Yes, definitely.
Definitely one or two base
in not over
who does not love the gifts. Right.
You guys will be bringing me
a lot of gifts right.
Cannot overload by just
changing that
by just changing
the written type.
So how many of known access modifiers
we learn?
So far we have only learned about this
start date one.
All right. What is the next thing, guys?
The next thing is
the name of the method, right?
So let me remove this written.
Let me put Lord in here.
Now, if I change this method
to method 1 a.m.
overloading guys.
So if we change the method names.
No. Now this is not overloading.
Okay. Being method name should be
same. Yes.
We will not be getting error because no.
There are two separate groups.
Okay.
And after the name we discussed about the
about the parameters.
Right.
So let me let bring this one
down in here so that you guys can compare.
So now is the things
which effectively overloading.
Okay, so
let me put method back.
So same name.
I fulfilled the first condition.
Now the second condition, the parameters.
And now how do I, I overload this.
Guys, there are three ways to overload.
Can you guys tell me
what should I write in here
so that I have overloaded the method?
So first thing I say
is that we can change the data type.
So maybe I can put a string in here
strangling here.
No, I also need to change this name, guys.
The this variable name
that I put in here, or
it can be anything.
It can be anything. Right?
So first thing is change the data type.
Often I'll step parameter.
So in here it's an integer
and here is the string, right?
This is one of the ways
we can overload, right?
So let me copy this method again
and let me put in here.
What is this second thing that I can use
to overload the method?
Add another parameter, right?
Add another parameter.
So a different parameter.
Right.
So in here,
how many parameters were there?
In here there was only one parameter.
Now, in here I have two parameters,
so I am overloading now
by changing the number of parameters
and then the third one
I can change in
this sequence as well,
but I can change the sequence as well.
I can put this string
after this integer number.
Okay, this is the third
and this is the third.
We of overloading it matter. Okay.
I hope now overloading is clear.
Is there anyone who is still confused
about
overloading about the definition?
Use is how to do it.
Maybe Sharif.
So now if we call
this method.
So now Java knows
that if Asgari is passing,
maybe if it is passing it a string.
Okay.
So that's how I know it.
Because I am passing
a string for our knows.
Now I will go inside this class in
does this method
texting Nor does this method texting. Yes.
So Java will call this method. Okay
then when I
will call this method
and I will call this method.
And if I pass, if I pass two parameters
now I will say okay, let me set it
in method within name method
and let me check
if that method is taking an integer
and a string.
Okay, so Java will start this option.
No, it only takes one.
Ignore it. No.
This is also taking one parameter.
No, this one takes two parameters.
First day of the string
and the second one is number.
Hmm. So.
So parameters.
They are same in data type,
but in which way?
They are different days.
They are differing in sequence.
Okay.
In here we are passing an integer
first and string after,
but this method is taking a string first
and then the number would
all this checking and looking for perfect
match would not slow the processing.
So in the build, this matching happens
when we press this control button.
So when we press this control button,
this is compiled to bytecode.
Okay, so it is not happening at runtime.
It is happening
when you are compiling your code.
So let's say, for example,
when I
will write a software, I will compile it
once and I will create dot
easy file
if I am planning to deploy it on Windows
on a BMG file,
if I am planning to deploy it on Mac.
So all this processing,
it will happen when I convert
this source code to those easy
are those BMG files for Mac.
But once, once it is compiled,
then it will be executed in discord.
This is not when the Java is
taking those decisions,
those decisions that are already taken.
That's why it is called stack
pickle binding.
That's why it is called gone by time
polymorphism.
Okay.
That's why it is called and that's why
we have these names
because it happens at compile time.
I am sorry.
As you mentioned, casting in overloading
when called the matter of yesterday,
it was overriding.
Now it was overwriting the
with those data types.
It was not overloading.
All right. All right.
Okay.
So this is how overloading works, guys.
I have error in line 14
collects
any post of the new post,
any sports channel.
Do you have any method that takes?
Is spring only a single string?
Like I created this method in here
which only takes one thing.
So then that's why I don't get any errors.
I know the concern, but I am mixing
a few things with constructors and methods
when are supposed to do together
and especially when need to call them
where I can do separate practice.
Those are lies, so I will share more with
this constructor is really simple guys.
Don't confuse constructor with methods
because
constructor there is only one purpose.
The purpose is to initialize difference.
It is automatically called
and you should only use constructor
only slight difference for the rest of the
things always go go with matters.
Always go with matters.
It's fine now because we will be teaching
you how to build a framework in best
and we will be showing you step by step
how to build our framework in Cucumber
so you guys
will know when to write these methods
and these frameworks.
They are turned off.
They are kind of general things
that you guys will be doing on your job.
So guys will notice
where to use static methods, instance
methods, fields, all of that.
Also, these constructors
need to be for each object.
In real life.
They are always constructors,
even if you have one
field in your class.
So answer this kind of yes.
If you are doing object
oriented programing,
there will always be a constructor.
If you are following the best practices,
can you put a little bit up?
You want me to scroll up in open
here?
Okay.
This one, this, this can
only if you can understand
your dog.
All right,
So, guys, are you guys ready to.
It's good idea to are the best
integer integer far greater
intelligent all intelligent
It's good idea to distantly human
to integrate to the GitHub.
Oh yes, but not for now
because what can happen is your company
they might be using Eclipse,
they might be using intelligent
or other ID or a framework
or something like that. So
it's it's very important
that you guys know
how to do all this stuff
related to great hub with that terminal.
Because that terminal is universal.
You will find that terminal everywhere,
but you will not you
probably will not find intelligent Eclipse
or everything everywhere,
but the terminal is super important.
Yes. Remind me at the end of the class
I will show you on
maybe after the break
or something like that.
And also it gives me a feeling of that
kind of the are doing something very crazy
in front of No, no it happens when you use
terminal is nothing is not it.
Right.
So you usually you should do a terminal
in front of your family member members.
Right.
They will be thinking
oh my God our son or daughter or wife,
my lord, they are doing something
super, super crazy IP config you
I play for in front of my video.
Then you scroll up the page please. Yes.
So let me push this code.
We need learn
so we can make life easy. Yes.
Alex, at the end I'm going to show you
actually what happens
is that I used to show that
in the start of the classes.
Do you have noticed it again?
So I used to do this from Intel.
You just need to click
two buttons and code is pushed.
You need to click one button
and the code is closed.
So I used to show how to do that,
but I will
not show because your instructors,
they all all of them,
they complained to me that that's good.
When you show something simple,
they will ever be learning
something that is that is hard.
Or maybe that is in that that might be
used in the industry in actual.
So I'm not going to show you that.
But once on the last class,
I will show you all the tricks.
I want you to struggle.
I want you to struggle
to learn to make all those mistakes
so that you guys are super comfortable
on your jobs.
Now I'm in total control.
Tell everyone
if you know how to push that,
you can always Google it.
That's actually great.
If you guys can learn
something on your own, that will be great.
But still,
I will suggest you to use the terminal.
I would suggest to use that I'm going to.
It's very important,
right? It's very important.
So again, to close this file next to
the overriding, was there any
longer related to overloading?
Did I post anything
related to overloading?
Okay. Okay.
So let's move to the override.
I am tired or delayed to get hold
folder manually.
Or do we need to delete?
Yes, we don't need to delete.
Alex.
So tell me about the
overriding guys
without inheritance method.
Overriding is not possible.
All homework was overloading.
I did override.
No, no homework was overriding.
I guess the class overriding,
not overloading it correctly.
We use overriding between parent and child
class.
Okay. Yes.
Needs to be with an inheritance
relationship between two classes.
What needs to be Mohammad
happens with parent and child class?
What happens with the parents and child
class?
The matters
we can only override in child class.
The opposite of overloading are
the rules are kind of opposite opposite.
So at one mark overloading and
overloading, they are not opposite kind of
the rules.
They are kind of opposite
when we do overriding.
If we don't like something from parent
class, we can override in the child class.
Yes, return type must be same.
So over
writing just
happens when
same name,
when same
methods
exist in
parent and
child classes.
Right.
So when we have same matter.
So in here guys, I am not using same name.
I am saying same method.
That means the parameters should be
same return type,
should be same,
the non access modifier should be same.
And then there is this kind of flexibility
about the access modifiers,
but rest of the things they must be
same in overriding if a subclass
to iron
this specific implementation of method
that has been declared
by one of its parent class, it is not.
It is known as overloading
definitely from Google right now.
It can also access modify it.
We are calling the method of parent class
to just push the code.
I don't see in the gear tab.
Everything is up to date.
So which repository you are checking?
Sebastian
I push to this.
This repository
request under to you
actually do check it
and let me know if the
if the code is there or not.
So overwriting happens
when same method exist in parent
and child class.
Okay. And
so what are the benefits?
Great.
Probably benefits of method overriding.
I think this definition is good
and object oriented programing feature
that enables a child class to provide
different information for the method
that is already defined.
Yes, that is also correct.
It is not there.
Okay. Let me check that. Why? I don't see
full.
I posted to the main branch
is the default
path.
It deleted.
Okay.
I hope you guys see the changes now.
Seems like I still need some virtual
classes.
People can help.
Maybe if everyone mind is so busy
thinking about lives
even as someone makes in a repository.
Oh my God.
That is why you guys need a terminal
if something goes wrong and fix it.
But you guys cannot.
So you guys see the update now
all the classes in here
because I created
multiple branches in here,
I was doing something with those classes.
So that's why you guys are going to see.
Okay.
All right.
Method overwriting is used to I mean,
if I would have taken five more minor
so you guys would have killed me
by your jokes, right?
I don't know how to use GitHub.
Show someone.
I forget how to do that.
This.
I think GitHub changed default
branch from Master Domain
because the word master was that is just
this last time I
remember I changed it to the main
class.
21 is not bad moment.
I will be extended. Break break. Okay.
This class is for full
of sarcastically but
not is there.
Here we go. He is thinking
so what is the benefit of overwriting?
Nice.
They give priority to the child
class shortcut
sometimes not good though
step by step the pass him.
You are right.
Do make it the fun and easy and fun
method overriding is
used to provide the process
that is already exist by parent
or superclass. Yes.
Ask the recruiter
if they ask you a question,
tell them that you know the answer.
But you guys are checking them
so they are to you.
You guys want to hear from them. Okay.
And you are not telling the answer.
It is okay.
So benefit is that we can have
a specific
implementation
or a method
that is both therapies already
defined
in the
parent class.
Okay.
That where we are we have this
let's see
linearity
there.
We don't
have to come up with
different names
if we are doing the
same thing again, maybe
sorry on this
one, which is.
And now let's discuss about the rules
method that already exist in overriding
we implement a method in a specific way.
The relationship
between this and super viewer is similar
to the relationship between overloading
and overload writing methods.
I think so.
Super is more related to overriding.
Super is more related.
Overriding super is not related to
in any way to overloading
already guys.
So let's start
the rules.
So let's start from again from the left.
So first we have access modifiers.
Can I override a method?
If I change the
can I still override a matter method?
If I change the access modifier
now, does it mean yes or no?
Here we go. Depends.
Depends is the correct answer How?
It depends. You guys.
Can you guys explain
guard to be more restrictive?
Access modifier
cannot be restricted in child class.
Yeah. So
we can change
the access
modifier in the
charter class.
We can change the access modifier
in this giant class,
but we can make it
only less
restrictive.
Yeah,
we can change the access modifier
in the child class,
but we can make it only less restricted.
What does this mean guys?
Can you guys give me an example for let's
say for example, if something is public,
if a method is public in the parent class,
can I change it
to a private?
Can I change it to default?
Protected? No. Why?
Because public has more wide
access, right?
The the second one is
the default is already protected.
Then we have the default
and then we have the private.
So we can go from here to here,
but not from here to here.
We can change a private
and default or protected to public,
but we cannot the public to default
or protected or private.
Okay, So
for example, we can
change
or you can change, protected
or default to public,
but we can not
would be reversed.
Can I also change the private
to default or public or
or maybe to protected?
I will do the same thing
just to the quarter from here to here
or from here to
that big method is bound with classes
we have.
This trust method is bound with an object.
Nasu.
Well,
why you are talking about the restaurant.
Everyone is talking about East.
We are discussing about access modifiers,
not the static keyword.
We can not access private outside
so it does not qualify for the first rule.
Guys.
Okay, I said I hope you don't mind.
So the first rule for overriding
is that that thing
that we are trying to override
must participate in inheritance,
Do private fears or matters.
Do they participate in Inheritance? No.
That means we cannot override them.
Right.
Because we will never be able to access
that in the child class here.
No constructors
participate in inheritance?
No, that means we cannot override them.
But the most constructors
and the private members.
Can we overload them guys? Yes.
Now going to.
We will do the example.
Does that look me frustrated?
Ignores. So
okay, so after the access modifier.
Okay, so that's why this class is special.
You remember
you guys have been waiting for class
or like for the past one month.
So we have discussed
the effect of access modifiers
on all other items,
not overloading or overriding.
So after the access modifiers
we have the non access modifiers
like static.
What is the effect of static on overriding
guys?
Can I override the method
with static keyword
or maybe without a static keyword?
So we can actually,
if a method is static,
all the rules they are same,
but we have only in new terminology.
Instead of overriding,
we say we are redo clearing.
Okay, rules are same,
everything happens the same because
static methods they belong to the class.
We say we are re declaring those matters
instead of overriding those matters.
Okay, I will show you the examples
about that as well. So
static matters
have the
same rules,
but we use a
different
terminology.
So static methods have the same rules,
but we use a different terminology.
We say we are re
declaring a method
instead
instead of
overriding it,
we will do the examples for this one
as well.
Public static void main
static cannot be overridden but can be
declared is just a new terminology.
Everything else is same
or it means if we have static we can.
We can't override.
We need to write another method
in the child class.
No, no.
It simply means we can override it.
But don't say we are overwriting.
We say we are re declaring that it
nursing.
So after the non access modifiers
we have the return types. Yes.
Just and just the name is different.
Just the name is different.
That overriding it.
It's an annotation
now it is something different.
Yeah. Same thing. Different class. Yes.
Yes. Alex
is just political correctness
and just no single writing.
Perfect example.
Perfect example. But
so we are doing the exact same thing.
We have different names
because we have to follow the terminology.
Okay, Do you have somebody in politics?
Politics.
Okay, so.
But not in size. Yes.
So after the non access modifier,
we have the return type.
What is the importance of return type?
Can I change the return types
when I am overriding a matter?
Thank you really to
so you guys can send more
more suggestions if if you guys
maybe learn something but
learn something better in a different way.
So all the return types,
they must be same care,
they must be seen in overriding.
They need to be salmon
overloading as well.
Guys.
Do they need to be same in
overloading as well?
No, they don't need to be.
Same in overloading. Right.
They they don't matter.
Return types must be same
in all variety.
Yeah. You.
After that we have the name of
the method as well is the first rule
phrased correctly.
We can change the access modifier
in child class, but we can make it
only less
restrictive.
For example,
we can change protected.
Yes, it is correct.
Is there anything wrong
logo?
You did anything wrong in the first part?
New Jersey.
Anything wrong in the first part?
Why is there but
all because.
So we have a logo.
Because from
protected or from default
we cannot we cannot go to
from public.
We cannot go to
protected our default on private.
But we can do the reverse.
We can go this way.
So from less restrictive,
we can go from more restrictive to
we can go less restrictive,
we can increase the visibility,
but we cannot decrease it.
That's why we have this. But
but I need a break.
But we need a break.
Honestly, I think a little more slipping
for the last 1.5 hours.
He just woke up
and now he's asking for a break.
Yeah. So,
Leslie, let's discuss the well,
what is the logic of maintaining
the return type?
So building logic will make sense
when we will be learning the abstraction.
But let me give you an hint.
So let's say you are
you have written a piece of code,
and that piece of code
is expecting a method to return something.
Okay.
In your child class,
you change that return type
and instead you don't return anything.
Now, the code which was expecting
the output from that method,
now if you try to use that code
with your child class, it will not work.
And remind me of this question
once we have discussed the polymorphism,
it will make perfect sense.
Once we have discussed the polymorphism.
So return types must be same.
And then after we have the name
What about the name Andy
and the parameters the guys,
the name must be same.
And in the last we have
parameters.
Parameters should also be
think, okay, but I'm also wishing
so. Okay.
Mohammad, can you check
now if you guys have
all the updated code integrated but not
Sebastian, can you check please?
You said before that we were going
to show us to combine Eclipse
and intelligent products.
Are we going to class
or did I miss something normal?
You didn't miss anything,
but I actually don't want to do that
because this polymorphism thing,
I think it's enough for you
for the next week to
do not feel well.
So once you guys are out of the hangover
of this polymorphism, maybe you can to
how to
move your
project from eclipse to intelligent.
But if you want, I can show that as well.
Okay.
But first we have the class controller.
So guys,
15 minutes will be enough on this
break, right?
So I have pushed the overriding notes
as well.
Okay.
Please be back by 1147 and reminding me
about recording.
Usually we will do the examples
after we are back from the break.
How do you guys back
or never left
or right who?
All right, so guys, can we
can we override
a private method?
Yes, we are recording.
Medium is still saying yes. No.
Why? We cannot override
your private matter
because it's private.
Because they don't
participate in inheritance.
Okay?
They are not available to be charged
class.
We can by reducing the restriction,
not reducing by any by
a yes.
By reducing the restriction, Yes.
Did I miss anything? No.
You can't access it
in an inheritance. Yes.
Okay.
Let's now do or let's do
the example for all of these points.
So let's say we have a parent class
and inside this
parent class
main method also cannot be overridden.
Yes, but we can really clear it.
Let me put it.
That can in the left pane here
we have a method again, very same method,
simple method, but I really love that.
And intelligent would just write more
and enter than the main
method appears.
One second in the note please.
Okay. Here
there are.
There are so many other things
that appears
in the intelligent picture.
For example, if you just write for
for I
it will create a for for loop.
Okay.
If you are writing the
if health conditions
like for example and
number is equal to
and if you say if
number four then
then go something.
I hope it works as a
number equal to quantity.
Do something else.
I will save the variable.
So you guys say replace
if we switch the fourth option.
So right now
I have this effective condition and
by just clicking on this,
if and then clicking on this ball,
I can replace this if condition
with this switch cases with one click.
There are so many things
that I will teach you step by step.
You guys will able to play with your code
just like that.
Very, very helpful
writing,
implementing methods, inheritance
and all that. So
If I place my cursor in, if
in here
and if I click on this button
in here, I can, I can do so many things.
I can revoke the conditions
inside this condition if you are reading
and if condition
and that if condition is tough
for you to understand,
you can revert all the conditions.
Also, if someone has written the code
using else as it's all this stuff to read.
If someone has written
if conditions using did
not operate the operators, all this stuff.
So you can revert all of these those to
to to simplify it.
You can modify the elseif conditions.
Okay. You can
remove the
you can convert it to switch cases
intelligence will also simplify your
your if conditions.
So for example,
are you guys able to convert it
to a C statement
how we go back control Z
or you can press on this
and you can replace switch
with if condition.
Okay, so
put your cursor inside the switch
and then
you can convert it back to
if conditions there is.
One more thing being delayed, you guys
and the other companies are working
to integrate it here.
It's called
GitHub Autopilot.
You guys just need to write
something in comments
and it will write methods
you automatically.
So there are so many types of innovations
you would just need to write one line.
So for example, you just need to write
an commands, create a method
to add two things
and the method will be
created for you automatically
locate
your air based.
So I will spend just 2 minutes in here.
So this guy is creating an index or this.
So you see that guy has just written
a function, random number
and all the other parameters
mean max written
metadata flow, blah, blah, blah.
And the
the idea is is showing the suggestions
for back to
your searches
all the solutions on the GitHub
over the internet
if there is a method with same name
present over the internet anywhere
it will bring that code to your I.D.
So you guys are encouraged
to watch this hour
during the break or some time as
if no comments on that
and that.
Okay. So, uh,
so there are so many great things
that you guys will learn.
If I had enough time, maybe I will spend
a complete session on on intelligence.
Once you guys are done
writing your framework,
then I will show you the tricks
how to navigate to big code bases
so that you guys don't get scare scared
by seeing all those course. So
this is also intelligent.
Got an can to do this so let's see if this
if you are writing and if condition
if number is adequate then
and number is greater
than 10%.
Eight signs.
So in here
you are writing something extra.
Okay. So
so if you see
I am doing
something that will always be be doing
if I, if I, if I replace this condition
with this condition.
So still it will always be true.
So once you guys are done
writing the code intelligible, you
scan all the code
and if you are writing something complex,
you are if you are not following
the best practices, if there
if there is anything that can be improved,
they will show you that.
I will also show you that if we have
if we had some time.
So we were discussing about
the method writing.
Okay, so
let's say I have a method
and here I am again passing.
Now, once we are done,
I will open the overloading
and overriding example do side by side
side.
For those who are still confused,
you guys can compare these to.
And then there is this child class.
Okay, I will give the example very
experienced
parent
and if I write void
I get to this suggestion to override
I click enter
and the method is over.
Okay, now let's clear the
first class.
And in here I have the amendment.
Okay, so now let's first discuss.
Let's start the rules from the very left.
So first we have the
access modifier.
So we discussed that in over writing.
We can not decrease the visibility,
but we can increase it.
So let's say, for example,
if something is public, okay,
as soon as I put public, because
what is the access modifier in here guys?
It's the default.
And if I change the access modifier
from public to default
and my increasing visibility
or am I decreasing the visibility,
I am decreasing it.
So this is not allowed.
Okay, This is not allowed.
So let me put it in comments.
Grant
decrease the
with the
humility.
Okay.
Okay. So this is the first thing.
But if I have, how did you make
the override shortcut and just type void?
Mohammad
Just type word and it will show you
the suggestion to override that
method in the child class.
So if I allow, I have
the default access modifier in here
and now if I
don't change it, no issues.
But if I try
to make it through it again,
what am I doing guys?
I am decreasing the visibility, right?
So I cannot do that,
but I can increase it.
I can
I can put public okay, I can put public
so I can increase it, but I can not decree
that this is what it is
meant.
The first one is there
anyone who is still confused Global.
Is it clear now?
So tell me if it is clear
if I put protected
which keywords I cannot use in here.
Why I'm getting an error
use same or public
because protected is more visible
than the default one.
Okay.
So I am decreasing from more to less,
from more to less.
So I can for public,
but I can not for default.
All right.
So let me
finally think about this.
Think about this in a child class.
Can I override
as well as overloaded method?
What if you make the method in parent
class private?
If I make it private, then
and the first place
it will not participate in inheritance.
And then it will.
Now nothing will happen, right?
If something is not participating,
then all the rules and everything
related to overriding is gone
because private members,
they don't participate in inheritance. So.
All right. Okay.
So after the excess modifier
we discussed about the non access
modifiers.
Okay, so what is the effect of non
access modifier?
You guys
let me put it at the top
so that you guys can come see it.
Right?
And so if I put static in here,
you guys see
as soon as I static I get an over,
I get an error on override.
What does this mean.
What does this mean guys.
This super conceals the override.
No, it calls the method
from the parent class.
So this error is saying hey is good.
You are saying in here on line
ten that you are overriding this.
We have this method,
but I see a static keyword.
When we have static keywords
we can read the clear
but can not override.
Okay. So remove this
from here
because now you are not overwriting.
Okay.
And now it says static method in bash
cannot be cannot
override instance method in parent.
Okay.
So we can not have a static method
overriding in non static.
Okay.
So if you want,
what should I need to do guys.
I need to put static in here
as well.
So now board to be met
Thursday are static rules.
They will be same
if now you guys call the method
using this.
Okay.
So let me actually show that as well.
So if I say child dot method, then
actually let me put.
Okay.
So I have this static Lloyd method.
The parent
and I have the same method in the child.
So if I say child, I do not method
but output, I will get case.
What happens
when we override something? Guys
so we get from child care.
And if I remove this method
from the child,
what output I will get Now.
Okay.
From parent so is an ordered same.
This is what happens with the instance
metadata as well.
Right? This is the exact same behavior.
So let's say for example,
if I make these methods and not static,
okay, If I make this
static and methods non static
and now if I declare an
object of child is equal to child,
and if I say child or method matter
what, I will get guys
from child, Right.
From child.
And if I remove this method
from the child,
then what I will get, I will get from.
Right. So it are not in behavior.
This same for static and instance methods.
Do you guys see any difference
in how the static and not static methods
they are moving?
There is no difference.
But the
but we have a different terminology.
Okay.
So the difference is
only about the terminology when we read.
When we need to redefine 930 in the child
class, we say re declaring it
instead of overwriting it.
When the method is instrumental,
we say we are overwriting.
Okay, so it's only the terminology.
They do exactly the same thing.
Okay.
Is it clear the name do point.
Go do your
we can do when they launched this.
So this politics in Java
I'm making calls for this forward
thought.
All right so this was about
the static methods. Yep.
Yep. You guys can see the city code.
I have just removed the static from here
and here.
The behavior is exactly the same.
You guys good?
Can we move to the next point?
Okay,
so next point is about the return types.
If a method has wide return
type in the parent class,
can I change it to something else?
Then I am overwriting it.
No, as soon as I try to change it
I will get this added
method clashes with the method
and in attempting
to use in compatible return types. Okay.
It must to be same as the return type
inside the parent class.
Can we overload, overload and override
in the child classes?
So you guys tell me, can we do that?
What do I think?
Can we do that?
No, we cannot do that.
Well, what is this, guys?
What am I doing in here?
It's overloading.
And what I am doing in here and in here
is overriding.
There is no harm in overwriting
and overloading.
Right?
So we can do it.
We can do it
as soon. As far.
As far as if it follows the rules.
I can do everything.
Because again, Java,
I will be looking at these parameters.
Then Java will be looking
at these parameters if they are different.
Yeah, I can easily identify which method
we are trying to call in there.
Saved job.
I can call that method.
So the whole point of overloading
is about the this
the statement that gained Java.
I identify a method
from multiple meters
in the method that you are trying to call.
Can java identify that method If you can,
then you can overload.
But first you override.
Then overload is is the opposite possible?
We are
doing both of the things at the same time.
And what?
So in here I am doing it in the same class
passing who?
I have two meters with same names,
but but with different parameters.
That is called overall overloading.
Right now
you have same method name in parent
and child class with same parameter
sandwich ID and type.
That is called overwriting.
So I am fulfilling
more to the requirements.
Yes, they are two different things,
but by chance
they are happening inside the same child
class.
Scroll up.
There is nothing to scroll up. Daniel.
I am at the very top of this class.
We can use the name down.
Okay.
You are.
You mean this?
I hope you guys can read it.
We can use the name and method
by declaring another class is overriding.
Right?
Same name,
same parameters, same return
types, same non access modifiers.
Then we are overriding impact
and we should also take care of the
access modifiers.
Are there other questions arise?
Actually, this is not important. Don't.
Don't get confused about overloading
at all the writing in the same class.
I will tell you about this
at a later point of time.
Right now let's focus on the overriding.
So let me remotest.
Okay, so the return type,
they cannot be changed.
The method names.
If I changed the method name
and my still overriding
case.
No, I am not overwriting because I am not
having this same method names.
Now Okay.
Can I change the parameter
types in overwriting?
Can I.
Can I make it a string?
Yeah,
if I make it string.
And if I put that
override annotation again,
you guys will get an error.
Yes, but it becomes
right.
Yes. Then is it will become overloading.
Yes, it will become overloading
because when we inherit something
this method will be kind of copied in here
and then you will be having same
name method but with different parameters.
So please be.
Please don't confuse the other one.
So don't understand this point.
This.
So if I put the override
annotation in here.
So the it says method does not override
method from a superclass.
So which means I am not overriding.
I might be overloading,
I might be creating
a new method, I might doing anything else,
but not overriding.
If if I change the parameters,
if I change the parameters, the value
in the standard overriding
must be same on methods and parameters.
Yes, you are right.
Rules for overriding.
They are super super superscript.
Only thing that you guys can change
is the return type for the overloading.
You can have many different methods if
you change the parameter in simple time.
If you ask
why I have error
because now
you love errors, now
you are missing this equal
to sign the sequel to sign
child C is equal to new child.
So with override
we effectively have the option
of going with the parent method
of stay with child method if we want.
Yes, and you are right signature should be
same for overriding signature
should be different in overloading.
You kind of say that,
but it's not correct.
It's still error in start taking the main
method film in the screenshot
again or post in the sports channel.
I will help you out.
Okay, so
this is about
overwriting.
Let me just put none back.
If I make it private,
I am again not overwriting it.
Okay.
Now let's try.
Let's do more examples.
Yeah, sure.
Why not?
Let's no, let's do the homework first.
Then we will do 2 to 3 more examples
and in those examples I will
also try to teach you
about the polymorphism.
Can I move to the homework now?
How is the effect when we do this?
So in this case,
the method we are overloading
and overwriting at the same time?
If we have a method in the parent class
with the same name, no,
it does not matter which one comes first.
Yes, we can do our funding
because you see the parameters.
They are different.
If you are passing an integer you are
referring to the overridden method.
If you are passing a string,
you are referring to the over
the overloaded method.
I have a quick question.
If we want to override to matter from
parent class, can we have more than one
overriding child?
Yes, we can have thousand overrides.
No issues with that.
All right, guys, let's do the homework.
So can you guys send me
the homeworks?
The question,
if we are making multiple classes,
we need to come out of final, final
family bracket.
And if we are creating methods,
then keep inside the class.
Yes, you are correct.
Yes, you are right.
Create a class degree
having a method that directs.
So let's create a degree class.
Yeah.
So create a class degree.
Having him at third grade directs.
So let me start this Read X
Reward directs.
To get a degree,
you need high school diploma,
right?
And then
we have to create some classes
inside
in here. Okay.
There should be be child
classes of degrees.
So for example,
for the bachelors, we can write class
bachelors
and in here we can maybe
put there something like this
to get a degree, you need
to pass the high school right?
To get a degree, you need a maybe
high school
diploma or something that.
Okay.
And then inside the child
classes,
there should be a bachelors class.
So class degree has two classes,
namely bachelor's and master's
in masters class or worldwide math.
Third, get it X.
Okay, so in better quality method by
creating an object of each three classes.
So I don't need to override it
inside The Bachelor.
So I put experience
and then I put degree nursing.
But for the Masters
class, I need to override.
I'm going to override the method,
get direct state,
same method, but different message.
Okay, what
do, what do we need
if we want to have a masters degree?
Do we need a bachelor's degree first?
Right. To get a
masters degree? We
you need to have a
bachelors degree
and then
we can create a test for class
in which we have to create the objects
of all these three classes,
and then we have to call them.
So I say
the degree
degree is equal to zero in degree
is their degree.
Oops, I am missing the main
method, third degree
or get prefix.
Then I create the object of bachelors
class
left or right.
All right.
If they start the pretext
they are nice, they are masters
and masters exclude you
Master
first.
So that data.
Let me define the masters first
like this.
I am surprised I do in the right
way. Yes.
So me too.
One of the ones I did correctly.
Smart output.
I really got guys.
Is this the first task
that you guys are doing and doing
properly?
Well,
one of them.
So to get a degree
you need a high school diploma.
To get a masters degree,
you need to her bachelor's degree.
To get a degree,
you'll need a high school diploma.
I always doubt myself,
even after Boston give aptitudes.
Yeah.
So the previous was hallowed.
Are there any questions
about this?
You guys were very happy, right
when you wrote that Hello World
and you saw your text on the console.
If who knew
what is coming right.
There are a lot of questions,
but it will take
that.
We need to put that at overwriting.
No, it's an optional thing.
If you put it, compiler will help you
if you are making a mistake,
if you don't put it,
compiler will not warn you
or will not give you an error.
If you are making a mistake
to do
it, move to the next example.
Okay.
Here to class that ID card.
Oh my God.
You guys didn't
remind me about those girls.
Oh, my book.
Oh, sorry about that.
I asked.
I told you to remind me.
I told you.
Forget about
verticals.
What did I miss?
So many other parts.
We were busy with wedding party girls
from previous batch.
It's like.
Like Silva is asking me, like,
I like.
Let's not.
But we are the girls, right?
Like I only girls
and I do kind of business with gold.
And silver is my client that we
we are because he's
so cool with
the creative class credit card
Create a class credit card and define
variable balance and interest.
Okay, so double
balance and
double
interest.
Create an instance
method that will calculate
interest based on the given balance.
Yeah.
So any simple method, right?
So avoid
so avoid
calculate interest
and then maybe I can calculate
the interest.
Like interest is equal to balance
multiplied by 0.14.
Yeah.
And then I display
the interest
and the finance.
So in this example, guys,
I am having some instance fears.
So what I shoot
if I want to follow the best practices,
what should I write inside this class
other than these fears
and methods?
Yes, this is good,
but this is required.
And when I have a conflict
with local variables
and instance variables, is there
is there any conflict?
So what I am missing in here then
I should only slightly experience
counts.
Right? Right.
So I should have a constructor.
So whenever you instance fears
always always have the constructors
to initialize those fears.
You can.
Now I need the this keyword because now
I have a local variable balance
and an instance variable.
So now I need this.
The balance is equal to balance.
Yeah. Now
does it make sense
I had this, I did this.
Is it wrong
class credit card expense task two
or calculate
well why you are extending from task to.
I mean technically
it will not make any difference
if you initialized them.
True objects would not be the interest
method.
Also use the instance variable to
yes it will, it will use.
And that's what I want.
I did that too
and commented that out and left them.
There is just a signed instance
and balance
in the payment.
If you guys can do it
in one class as well.
So now this class is ending in here.
So I put in ward matter to ward,
calculate double balance,
double interest on that.
That is also correct.
If you want both of the fields in here
not able to correct,
create a class undefined
variable balance and interest.
Okay.
So when I say define
a balance and interests this what I mean?
Yeah,
because this is where we
define the variables inside a class.
Before we made a construction, there was
no at our SO we have to put constructor
because if you don't put a constructor
then you have to come up
with a different method
to initialize the fields.
So what we want to do the standard way
to initialize the field
instead of having a separate method,
or maybe assigning values
by something else.
So the double guys have created
something special
to initialize the field,
so why not use that?
So besides being easier, does it matter
if we initialize them through constructor,
through variable?
Variable don't balance. Yes.
So Simon,
when you guys will be writing
real practical code,
remember you will not be having fears
which are public or default or protected.
99% of the time are the instance fields.
They will be private
so that no one can access those fears
without going through your rules,
the rules that you will be defining.
Because if someone can crop
to your data easily, so your classes, they
they have to pass the index
up to the state park
and the method SPARC methods
they work on state.
If someone has corrupted your stairs,
your methods, they will not work properly,
but they are not private now.
So it would still solve the homework
without constructor. Yes.
Yes you are right.
Right now you guys can solve it
without the constructor.
Go to initialize balance
an interest in the calculate interest.
You taking the parameters from outside.
It is taking the parameters from outside
and then assigning the values.
Yes, you guys can also do that. Yes.
Yes you can.
You guys can also do that.
So let's
create a class credit card
and define variable and interest.
Create an instance of matter so
that will calculate the interest
based on the given balance.
Then create two subclasses, the Visa
and X in its class override method.
Calculate interest,
call them at third by creating an object
of each of the three classes. Yes.
So I write,
I write X class.
So class X
I say expand.
I say credit card.
So y I get an error right?
So let me see
if says there is a non default
constructor of a label in credit class.
So what are you saying right now?
It's saying there Tasker.
There is a constructor
independent class
which is initializing a field,
but in the Jala class
you are not calling that constructor.
How, how the fields will be initialized.
Because when you inherit from a class,
you are technically inheriting fears
and matters and everything, right?
So you must also initialize
those fears by calling the constructor
from the parent.
And if we want to call the constructor
from the parent,
should I also create the create
a constructor
in the child?
Or I can call the constructed
inside method?
Then how can I call the constructor
if I don't have?
So you guys want me to do this like this?
Super low
credit card
like this?
I get an
added, I get an error.
That means I need a constructor
in the X as well.
And this should also take a variable
balance and that's how oops,
I will pass. Oops
this balance to the
parent books. Okay.
So this means that if
we have a constructor
inside of the parent class,
it's a must to have a matching
constructor in the child classes as well.
Okay.
So that we can initialize the fields
we can pass through
that are two different classes as that
about the middle class school
that has a
change extra reason,
but why there is no error
from public to default.
Public to default.
We is public and we is the default. Now.
You mean the public with credit card class
and default with with this x class
and there is no, no, there is no rules.
There are no rules
that were discussed about this.
It is no restriction on classes.
The restriction
the restriction is on methods.
There is no restriction on the class.
A class can have thousand other methods.
Right.
Why would someone want to restrict
the whole class?
If you all only overwriting one
single method,
there can be a thousand other fields,
2000 constructors, thousand meters.
Why restrict the complete class?
So we only restrict that only
a single method that we are overriding.
We don't restrict the complete class
here.
And then
in a class we have to override
the calculate instance as well.
So how can I do that?
I if I type wide, I see this addition
from the intermediate I can click on.
Okay and I get the method
override.
So now I can see
maybe this time
interest is equal to balance
multiplied by 0.05.
Okay.
And then bring down these interests.
So guys, can you help me?
I don't have this interest field.
I don't have this balance word
in the next class from where they are
coming, how
how I'm able to access them.
They are coming from here.
Yeah, they are coming from here
because we extended from there.
Plus.
Yeah.
And then let's cleared the
visa class.
It also expands from the
credit card
and why I get an error
guys on the middle class.
Again, the constructor.
I must create a constructor
which should imagine this super class.
I must take the balance from here
and I must pass it to the super.
Yeah.
Bears
how the balance field will be initialized
when we will be using it
for the middle class.
So let me let me remove
this these requirements.
So that you
can see the code from top to bottom.
You guys can compute it.
So let me make I hope it is readable.
So let me create test for class
in this upper class.
I made it like this without constructor.
Is that not a good approach?
No. No. It's also good.
So the main point
was to learn about the overriding.
So it's perfectly fine if you guys have
done this without the constructors, you're
It's good.
It's good and it's good.
So now clear the object, the three class,
it's like a credit card.
Credit card
needed words on new credit card.
I pass a balance of ten.
Oops.
Can you please explain lines 17 and 20?
So this is a constructor of this class
and when I write super with parentheses,
I am actually calling this constructor
and passing this balance in here.
And from here
this balance will be passed in here
and from here it will be passed in here
and this field will be initialized
from here
because I am using this field in here.
So I first must initialize this field
so that I don't get unexpected results
in tired this calculate interest method.
So whenever you guys will be
using the fields
from your parent class,
you must initialize them
through the constructor of your child
so that you don't get unexpected returns.
And then the same is happening on line 28
for not to make a credit card
and then double
X and or credit card.
No, no,
we cannot.
It will be something very weird.
X is the child.
Then you are using the default operator
and then you are writing
the name of the parent class
and then you are saying double with me.
Can you can you write proper code?
What do you mean?
Because this is not correct
syntactically, in this case,
the balance is the same for all
and just we are changing interest.
Using over our normal balance is different
for everyone.
Balances for everyone
because they are sending instance
failed instance.
First they have separate copies
for all the objects.
It's not a static field
like create an object
is passing through the constructor.
Like create an object inside
the X
to call the constructor of the parent
So Mohammed if you do that, remember each
object has its own copies.
If you are creating an object
inside the constructor,
it will only effect that specific object.
Each object that you create.
It has its own copy of the variables,
the value
then that I am passing in here,
it will only only effect
this credit card objectify create
another object
that the object will having
will be having its own copy.
This trend will not and will not
be related in any way to that object.
We don't want that.
So if I see credit card dot
calculate
interest, then we
maybe we pass under
so 15
is the interest rate
and under this dependance
if interest in convenience
entity.
So those who are confused with constructor
mode easy for me.
Yes, you're welcome.
You can do it without the constructors.
So let's say if I say on
x x is equal to new
x and if I boss 200
in here, this x start
calculator
interests will give me 15 or 30.
So to the parent class am passing this out
and to the child class
I am passing this to 100.
So will I get the interest rate 15
and the balance at 100 or
the interest rate as 30
and the balance has 200.
If I call this piece of code
30 and 200 fight
y, I will get 30 and 200 because
the 40, not 30, because in here
I am defining the interest rate
as far as 5%.
So, so it will be ten and 200.
Now What is happening in here?
This 200 that I am
passing in here,
it is being passed to the constructor
right from the inside The constructor
I am writing this super keyword,
which means call the constructor
from the parent.
So this balance will go in here
and all of this is happening
in a separate memory,
in a separate location.
It has nothing to do
with this piece of code.
Remember that
it has nothing to do with this object.
This object. Yeah.
So this balance will be passed in here.
From here
it will be assigned to this field two
200. Okay.
And then because we are using
this expense keyword,
both the figures,
they will be copied to political.
This is what happens
when we do the inheritance.
Right?
So I will be having a balance feared.
But now inside the balance sphere
I will having a value of 200.
I am done with the dark intelligence.
So now this 200 will be multiplied
by 0.05 and it
then will be stored inside in here.
And I am printing there.
That's why I get ten and then 200.
So yes, the values they are too fast,
but the objects
they have center member locations.
They have nothing to do with each of the.
Yeah.
Similarly, if I create an object of the
visa class
and if I pass maybe 300 in here
now if I say we are not
calculating interest
what I want, I will go right here.
And guys, it shift
for two times and type 18.
So do that.
Does this view the class?
Does it have its own overridden method?
Does it have its own calculation method
gives a class? No.
So what will happen?
They calculate interest from the child
class
will be copied inside the parent
and entirely inside the parent.
What we are saying we are saying whatever
is the balance multiplied with 15.
So we will be getting 45
and then 345 and then three.
So when we are inheriting from a class,
we kind of copy the structure,
but we don't copy the instance,
feel the values that we pass
when we are creating an object
of those classes.
It's very important.
Everything is happening inside
a separate member location.
Everything belongs to the object.
When it comes to instance, features
like static fields,
they work a little different.
Do you guys have any questions
from this task?
All right.
So how how you guys have solved
this problem
without without the constructors?
Do you pass the values to the new
you guys fastly values
directly to these methods?
Oh, that will be very easy. Right
then.
It must be very easy.
Yep, yep, yep.
Okay, that's also good,
because the main point
was about the overriding.
Okay, what is the third task?
That's all easy peasy.
We take a break.
This guy is waiting for you, Sebastian.
But last, last one month.
Naughty.
You want to talk to this guy?
So let me.
We had 15 more minutes,
and then you guys want to talk
this for this guy?
I mean, it's cute, right?
It's not that bad.
So do you guys want to see how machine
learning happens?
I am training a software
to recognize pictures of humans,
and I am training it for the last 3 hours
on my computer.
So this is all it is,
printing all the accuracy.
So right now the equity is at 78%.
So my model is working 78% times.
It is predicting the values correctly.
Okay.
And it's by time.
And this is how it looks like
the all the software that you see which
like this octave
that you use to open your are
your mobile phones through your face faces
all the software that detect automatic
would be our cars
that try to break the rules
and this is how
they are built.
So it is training I am training it
for the last 3 to 4 hours.
It is running, running, running
and it's learning how the images
of two persons, how they look like,
if they are the same person.
So I have fed it.
A lot of data about two gigabytes of data
and it is going through
all the images in a loop one by one,
and then comparing the law
and trying to understand
how do the images look like.
And then I have provided it
with this information.
This is by time that these two persons
they are different.
They they are they are the same person.
So now it is learning all those variables
and all that in the background.
And then it is testing itself.
So right now it's at 78%.
I should use iPhone.
I can open my sister's phone.
Yes, it is very funny that the computers,
they can be fooled very easily.
Very easily.
So now
they are state computers, Right.
So if you put something very similar
to the these computers,
they can be fooled very easily. You.
So I don't know how many more
of our creations will be needed.
Oh, it's improvement
is very slow to do in point.
All right, guys.
So let's have a break.
And after the break,
we will discuss the polymorphism.
Oh, I slept for 3 hours before this class
record that I was busy in my assignment.
I am very dark, so it goes below my eyes.
But hopefully things will get better
once I am done with my masters.
So it's one or the one or two.
So let's have a break.
15 minutes.
So one 117.
So I need at least 80% accuracy.
So I am just 2% behind
and my professor will be happy
if I get at least 80%,
which it is stuck on
78% for the last 3 hours,
increasing very slowly.
And when it is left in the deadline,
I have someone to report.
Well,
what do you think about Java?
Python is better for the task
that you guys are doing for development?
Java is perfect.
Python cannot replace Java in that area,
but machine learning tasks
by ton is.
Yes, it's 11 p.m. in here.
I have heard a lot about react will wake
you or use that as well in the future.
So you guys might be using some libraries
from the React,
but not quite you guys
because it for React
you need to understand
JavaScript TypeScript.
And then there are so many words
of JavaScript
and our script is, is crazy
and you guys will be crazy.
You and you guys don't want to do that.
And for us both, class is the best for not
the active JavaScript.
So Solomon, do you have some development
experience like the frontend?
I think so.
After this call
studies are for lifetime to keep updated.
Are not quite that because companies
they are very reluctant
to move to the new technologies.
So it's not like that
every year or something.
You guys will be learning
new programing, languages and delays.
Therefore from 1995
it's been almost 30 years, right?
21 and then 26 to 37 years.
And it has not changed
that much since then.
And because finding the right
skilled person from the industry
who can work on the technology
that you have selected for your company,
finding the free tools
because there will be thousands
of employees who will be using the i.t.
Right.
If go eclipse is not free or intelligence
aren't free,
you have to pay a lot of memory.
So there are so many factors
that are involved.
When You have to do the technology
if skilled personnel are available or not,
if you will be able to achieve
the performance or not.
If the tools are available freely,
not if that language or tool is better
tested or not. Right. You don't want to
be doing
experiments on thousands of customers, so
you want something that is super stable,
that is here for years.
You don't want to use new technologies
that are here for like 3 to 5 years.
Companies
never do that because one minute of
software crash or something like that,
it can cost them millions.
So then never do that to do,
don't worry about Java.
It's not going anywhere.
Otherwise please be back by
120 and reminding me about it.
Obviously
it's easy for us
so poly and morphs it.
The poly means many
and more means forms.
So what will happen?
So in overloading
we call this same method,
but we pass, then we pass different
bad meters.
That method,
it can behave totally differently.
Right?
You write a
totally different logic
in a method prior to you.
You are passing one parameter.
You can maybe write a loop inside
that manages many forms.
Alexi
So that is also a polymorphism.
It's called static polymorphism because
the same method, if it is speaking at it
taking and Eddie as the input,
it is behaving differently.
If the same method,
if it is taking an integer
as the input, it is behaving differently.
Right?
So in our real life we also do this right.
We behave differently with our friends.
Our thorn are
God saves whatever we do right.
We are a totally different person
with our friends
in of father or mother.
We are the
nicest.
the the most innocent person to all.
And yes, in front of our lives,
we are the most innocent persons
that sense of of this world right
When we are
with friends, we
are the naughtiest person in this world.
So but we are the same persons, right?
What we are doing,
we are behaving differently depending
upon these scenarios.
We are behaving differently
when we are in schools.
We behave differently
when are with our friends,
we behave differently with family,
we behave differently,
but we are actually the same person.
So same centers.
When we boss parameters,
they can also behave differently.
Okay, same matters
If they are called on different
objects, they can behave differently.
Acting smart, smarter school.
So in a real life, in shopping
malls and busses in school, that calms
a person can be behave differently right?
So we we we achieve something
similar in Java
with the help of polymorphism.
And it is the most powerful, I would say,
concept of object oriented programing.
Okay.
If if someone can understand it properly.
So polymorphism is one of the oops
features that allow
us to perform a single action
in different ways.
Okay.
So 75 actually the hard part is gone.
The hard part was overloading
and overriding
because when we when I combine
these two concepts, this is where
the students they confuse the most.
Okay,
so that part lost. That part is gone.
Now we only like 10% left
out of this overriding overloading
and this polymorphism thing.
So polymorphism
is the capability of a method
to do different things based like
I act as an experienced software tester
in my interview. Yes.
So polymorphism is the capability
of a method to do different things
based on the object
that is that it is acting up on
and important
usage of polymorphism occurs in rules
in how
a parent class refers to a child class
object.
Okay.
I hope nothing from
this slide is making sense at this point.
Or is it making sense?
Polymorphism can be achieved
in two of the following ways.
So first, let me show you the example.
Okay.
Let me first show you the example,
which example will be
okay.
Dog one
If you guys are not tired
of dogs,
Bird, please.
What about a dog that can fly?
I mean, we are our developers.
We can build anything.
Now we know how to create a class.
We start to put fields
a code. Yep.
You guys can make anything fly.
I used to love dog, but now we've got
no. Ah.
Okay, So let's create a car class.
You guys love cars.
Unless we have two dogs,
we can't do it because
it is polymorphism.
All right, so let's say guys,
we have this car class.
Inside the car class, we have a method
start.
Yeah, let's make it very simple.
It was me, not me.
Use is
to start me.
And then
or start
is brakes to
the this is the correct word right
break,
not the other one that I wrote first.
English champions.
Okay.
And avoid
block.
Ask me
when it gets very simple three
three behaviors in a class.
Now let's create
for a few more classes guys classes
that are that extend
from the start class.
All right.
Woops I right Li and w
that expands
on the class
and inside the BMW
we can write some of the math terms.
We can say it void start
to bring people so
animal one item separates
the bird and other centers
but it first to see it's to
use the button
to spark me right in BMW
we can have that push start feature.
I cannot sleep
because I am always thinking and over
thinking every night to find the short
the fastest solutions.
You will be a good programmer should if
and then I can also override.
I can also have something special
that is only related
to the BMW harder to override fast.
So you guys just have to
type the void
and as soon as you type word,
all the matters in the parent class
that have
the word return type,
they will be appeared in here,
they will appear in here.
And now you guys can select
any of the methods to override it.
Yeah, actually,
let's not do that.
Let's keep it simple.
What is a shortcut for the assault?
Is s out and then hit enter.
No, no worries.
You will be fine. Sure.
If you will make birdie.
Why I get at a
Maryam is not available in this sport
last as long
extends
wide or maybe
it was me use
we all while Apple
will start me
polymorphism allows to perform
a single action in different ways.
I think it's more the right way
and quite a short way to understand
clearly yes.
Don't you need examples
should if this time
only definition is good?
I'm just kidding. I hope you don't mind
because was a student in the previous bed
and his name was also Shelly.
So I made a 2 to 3 dogs jokes on him
and he was kind of angry with me.
I can I can stop that if you guys mind it.
I don't mind
if you guys make names out of me.
Don't make jokes or do anything like that.
I always enjoy it.
You you are kind of my family now, right?
Spending
almost more time with you than my family
For the past one month.
Forgive my sarcasm.
Okay, so use mobile app to start me
and then Tesla is.
Tesla. Right.
So it was
parking sensors who
bought me.
Does anyone have Tesla?
Oh my God.
And here in Pakistan,
the taxes, they are like
1000 passes percent on these luxury cars.
So someone can not even think
about those cars
who are like us, do not have anywhere.
And then we
if you are a parent class
and you are extended class child,
and then there is this for
Toyota, built for guys like me,
which has everything men will
like.
Strings
are, and it has nothing
special.
So let's create a Astra class.
And I'm just.
So what is happening in here,
guys, is so nice.
It understands that I want to show
all the code inside single file.
Right. You see how it are destroyed.
All the matters.
So when you guys.
Yes to it.
I know which is so you guys can see that
I have this stock method
then I have the start method again.
Then I have the stock method again and
then here I don't have the stock met them.
So what is happening right now?
I have a same method
and this same method is existing
in different classes. Now,
with the help of polymorphism,
it is auto generated moment.
You can click on this
plus button to expand it if you want,
and you can click on this minus button
to shrink it again
to push the car to start.
So what is happening in here guys?
I am using overwriting, right?
And overriding is
it is a kind of polymorphism,
either type of polymorphism, right?
So what will happen
now if I use polymorphism in here,
then I will be able to all,
all of these start matters
by just changing the object
that is the on
which these methods are acting.
So how it work.
So there is this concept of up
costing and down
costing in objects as well.
So that cost
that that concept is so simple.
It says that you can create a variable off
type player and,
and you can store the object of any child
inside that variable that
you guys remember.
In primitive typecasting, we used to store
inside a double.
We used the store integer, used to store
a long we used to store the floor.
We used to store
different kind of things in here.
This got lost is as thing like that
boolean the bigger deck type.
Okay.
And in here
you guys can think of this line as if I
doing the widening convergence.
It is automatic, right?
It happens automatically.
We just assign the variables
so this child can be assigned
without any errors to this parents class.
Yeah.
And what I can do
if I call the stock
method now I have two choices.
If I look closely,
I have this stock
method available inside the parent,
but this
stock method is also presented
inside the child.
Now question is which method should be
called when I write this piece of line.
So what do you guys think?
Which method should be called
B BMW one, y, BMW one.
Because remember,
I am creating the object of this child,
this variable in sorry, in here
it's just storing that object.
The object is still coming from.
The BMW class, it's just acting.
This car variable
is just acting as a container, okay?
It is just acting of the container.
I, I am storing that BMW inside this car.
So what will happen now
if I execute the score?
I will see. Use the button to start.
Stock me.
No, no.
It has everything to do with overriding.
If I don't override this method in here,
if I don't override.
So for example, if I.
If I use the Toyota
instead of BMW, if I say Toyota.
So which method will be called this?
So now,
because Toyota does not have any method,
the method from the parent
class will be called
here, use case to start me.
So now this this
this power of storing the child class
objects inside the parent
type variables.
What it allows are allowed us.
It allows us to create areas of objects.
It allows us to write
loops outside of the objects.
It allows us to do so many crazy things.
Now we can relate these objects.
So, for example, I can do this,
I can say, God, the R
is equal to New
B and W,
All right.
I can see
New Tesla.
I can see new
Toyota to make it smaller.
Yeah.
So if I have all the objects,
if I have all the loops,
all the objects.
So now what I can do?
I can
all types of child class objects
inside and okay.
And what I can also do.
So for example, let's say guys,
I have to call this stock method
from all the guys
that are present in here.
So what I have to do,
I have to do this if I don't use
polymorphism, I have to do this
Toyota.
Toyota is equal to
and you let me start from
the BMW.
BMW is equal for me.
BMW, BMW,
dot spark.
What we know
blue the stop
BMW lot
lot right
if I have to do this
same thing for the Tesla I have to say
Tesla
s nio
that's slow
and slow right
And then I have to do this same for Toyota
in the one
and small
block.
Right.
So I have to do this.
Now, imagine
don't say that inside Siberia.
We can boss parameters too.
Yes, we can.
So but we have do it.
Imagine, guys, there are 1000 matters
that are present in the child classes.
So you put lines from quiet routines
into like quantity.
Oh, no.
There is still a piece missing
that that is not complete.
So now if I take your discord,
I will see the output.
So now I see use the button.
Usually break me manually, use the mobile.
You will replay, blah blah, blah.
So I see all the
outputs from all the objects
we use new BMW or new
to change the name road
car to use same name.
We're now.
Can you tell me the line number?
Should we do this
or just showing variations?
I would do.
If you guys are typing
now, I'm using the same name.
There's BMW here from BMW here,
if you mean these cars.
Yes, because I had a car
variable previously,
so I can not have to duplicate variables
in a matter.
So instead of writing this code
and imagine
there are maybe 50 classes, ten classes,
four classes
each class having 100 meters, 200 meters.
What do you guys can do?
You guys can write a loop
for each loop.
You can see
Gaga from cars, oops cars,
and you can see car door start
or stop
car door lock.
And even if if if I comment this code
now for a moment.
So this piece of code is equivalent to
all the code that we have written above.
Above
we are learning
how to do something a little
how not You will learn.
So I see all the output from here.
Okay,
so with the help of polymorphism,
what is happening here?
This method of star is acting differently
when it is acting up
on this new BMW object,
it acts differently
when it X on this Tesla object,
when it acts on the Toyota object.
So based on the objects
method is behaving differently.
This is all polymorphism. Yes.
I mean, this is just a start.
We still have one hour and 28 or 10
minutes.
So you guys see if
I'm just feeling
that there's all five polymorphism.
So if you guys notice that instead
of creating the individual objects
and then calling the methods
on those objects,
what I can do,
I can store the objects in an area
the time type of the array will be the
parent type.
And then using the loop, I get this
first object I call all these tree matter.
I get the next object,
I store it inside the card.
I call again
this method by the next object,
and I call these methods again.
So Nabeel was saying why in overwriting
the return type, they they matter.
So Nabeel,
you see in this cards variables.
If one class is returning and indeed
other classes that are turning a Boolean,
other classes are returning
something else, this code will fail.
You will not be able
to generalize this in here.
You will not be able to call all
the methods because for one
method,
the output will be different time,
the other methods out
will be different time.
The other method output,
the different types.
Do you guys have any questions?
So let me show you one more.
One more example.
One more in
this example will make more sense.
So as a tester, guys,
you guys will be testing your applications
on Google Chrome,
on Firefox, on Internet Explorer,
on Spotify or something like that.
Right. So what do you think?
Will you guys be writing separate code
for all of these
browsers?
No, no.
If you don't learn the
polymorphism, definitely
you will have to write a different code.
So it'll be same place.
Can I see the test?
So for you,
let me know once you guys are done
typing this.
Yes. For the loop.
Because if you guys write
anything else like BMW,
you know that we can only store
BMW objects in here.
I have already
submitted it in degree,
but I cannot store test
like in our store prior to their slide.
This type it should got here
because we have just learned
that the dependent type object
is something bigger.
It can hold all of its tiles.
Yes, it will always be paid in class.
Are we recording?
Oh my God, Yes, we are recording.
Okay,
we moved many
if it is indicating that it is recording.
Yes, I know why
you guys are dividing me
after one hour or 30 minutes.
Right?
How We're recording after 30 minutes.
And this is my question.
Why it came after 30 minutes.
My friend has this question in interview
explained polymorphism.
Can we collect all the behaviors of two
lives in a loop?
Yes, but I
we are programed for every 30 minutes.
So let's do one more example, guys.
This example, it will make more sense.
So in this very first class of selenium
in the next week,
you guys will be using this polymorphism.
Okay.
So there will be a RAM driver class
that you guys will use
as the parent class
and all the Google guys all created
Chrome, all the Firefox guys,
all the Internet Explorer guys.
Now, by the way, they are all dead,
all the funny guys, they have implemented
this web driver interface here.
And inside this web driver,
we have defined
the the the selenium guys.
They have defined which methods
the Chrome should implement,
which matters.
The Firefox should have this
The internet Explorer should have saw that
you guys
just changed the object
from Chrome to Firefox.
You execute
all the
methods and all the testing is done on.
Let me show you how it will work.
So what is what?
What happens is that
you will be having a method wide
open side
board.
Let's say you guys are writing
so many methods, right?
For to test something.
You guys will be writing
so many test cases right
click in here to check
if it really is working fine or not.
Enter the wrong password.
Enter the correct password.
Pick on that button, enter it
without entering anything.
So, so many variations.
The last.
Okay,
you guys have to do these tasks
on all the browsers.
Okay.
So let me know what you guys are done
typing
this code.
You guys are fast.
How how, how much you
guys have improved, right?
You guys used to
be very slow.
That's great.
So is it better, guys,
if I create the next classes
inside the same file?
Or should I create separate classes?
Which one way?
Which will be the better way?
Okay, so in here, now let me create last
we will Chrome
and that class
is extending from
web driver
ACP so we can see both together.
For me.
So then you guys will copy
this call will place it in here,
opening a website and
and you will
chrome
and Google Chrome.
Right.
So because Google Chrome
is a different browser,
it works differently.
So Google guys,
they have implemented all of these methods
in a different way.
Are you guys done typing
this code as well?
Then you will be having a class in which
Firefox
guys.
Yes, we are overwriting
now we have the Firefox class
that is also extending the web driver
and now I do all the testing in Firefox.
If control are
if you press the controller, make sure
you guys don't replace the previous code.
So if you press controller
it is highlighting right now this keyword.
Okay. So
if you do the replace in here
by pressing controller,
it will replace this keyword again,
make sure it is this
this keyword is highlighted in here.
If you have a Google Chrome in here
it looks create
40 over
four all these matters
to test different things on different
browsers.
They they are already written for you.
You guys don't have to write these
methods.
You guys just tell these matters
which filter to best,
which checkbox to check,
which in which field
you need to enter the data,
which page to load this method.
They are outdated and you guys just need
to understand how to test these methods
by move it to the next highlighted method.
So once it highlights this one,
I move it to the next, next, next.
And now I want to start the replacement.
I have a question.
Our class
Firefox need to be inside the main class.
No, it should be outside of main class.
Okay.
So now this word has been highlighted
as just give me one more.
Let me ask about
your review class on Monday.
If she confirms
then you guys will be having the review.
Otherwise
it so yes, you guys are having
a review class on Monday.
If Suhail feels better,
he will be doing the review.
But you can tell them that yes,
we are going to have.
So yes,
you guys are having your review on Monday.
I will post it on in course. And also
the highlighted
in this one is highlighted right now
housing on line 67,
same time. Yes.
Only for this week,
same 3 hours.
Yes. I tried in Thursday as well.
You guys will be having the classes.
It's only five week
because of Thanksgiving.
So now I can replace somebody.
So far each of
so now I have three classes
which are doing the exact same thing,
but in a slightly different way.
Okay.
Because if you compare to how
we browse the Web site on Google Chrome
versus how we write on versus
on Safari,
we get almost the same experience.
But sometimes for testing reasons,
we have to test
all our websites on all famous browsers.
Okay, So does that mean that
we have to evaluate the code for the
browser separately? No.
With the help of polymorphism,
you guys just need to change the object
and whole piece of code.
Even if there are 1 million lines,
they will be executed for a very
totally different thing.
Let me show. So.
So for example, if I create a web
browser over
faster, so if I have to test something
on Google Chrome, what I will do,
I will say, which
we will go on Google
Chrome is equal to me on
Google Chrome.
Then I
then I Google Chrome load
open website, Google Chrome Board,
sign up Google Chrome or
log in Google Chrome.
What Enter Username password
Google Chrome dot
Click somewhere to put on Google Chrome
goes about it.
So this completes one of my test cases.
We only off on Thanksgiving Day
and Friday.
Basically the rest of the
and we make it and then loop
yes we will load that as well.
So guys
if I am not using the polymorphism,
if I am creating the object
straight away, right.
The way I you guys have been doing,
I can write this code,
I can execute and all the test cases
they will be executed on Google Chrome.
Right?
So I see Google Chrome every bit.
All the test cases are executed
on Google Chrome.
And then if I have to do same thing
on Firefox,
I have to again
write this piece of code.
Firefox.
Firefox, Firefox
and then
and then I can execute
everything on Firefox.
I see Firefox, Firefox, Firefox.
Now imagine
there are hundreds of test cases.
Okay,
you guys
will be writing hundreds of test cases.
So if you want to test
those, test cases on Google Chrome,
you will be repeating
all of those under test cases.
Let's say for example, for Google Chrome.
First, then
you will create the object of Firefox.
You will repeat
all those 100 lines of code again,
then it will be executed on Firefox.
You will repeat again
those hundred lines of code
for Firefox for Safari
and then they will be executed on that.
But if you use the polymorphism,
what do you guys can do
elected to convert this out?
And let me show you
the power of polymorphism.
So with polymorphism,
we just say web driver
web driver is equal to new
Chrome, new
Google Chrome.
And let me
if you guys want to
execute the test cases,
you would simply store
Google Chrome in here.
All these test cases,
they will be executed for
Google Chrome.
Okay. Google Chrome, Google Chrome.
You want tested on Firefox
just to change this object?
There are one line code,
all the test cases.
Now they will be executed for Firefox,
Firefox, Firefox, Firefox.
You are tested safari.
No issues, just change this object
and all the test cases will be executed
for safari.
So you write the methods in here.
You just to change the object
on which those methods act.
And now all the methods will behave
differently
can behave totally differently.
Does it make sense, guys? Why?
Why? Polymorphism can be very useful.
So we just change the object
that we are storing
inside the parent by predictable.
And now all the methods,
they behave totally differently.
All of these classes
you don't have to write these classes.
They are already written by someone else.
So you guys
just need to know how to use effectively.
Okay,
if you guys don't know the polymorphism,
you guys will be writing a lot of thought,
a lot of thought.
Imagine building a framework
where there are
maybe 1000 test cases in thousand,
3000 test cases.
You have to test
those test cases on Google Chrome.
You write all the methods you do
clear the objects, you do everything,
and then you want to do it for Firefox.
You again redo all that stuff.
But in indeed in actually what
you are doing, you are simply changing
the object
that you are storing in that variable.
So if we want all the classes we use,
that is yes.
So now let's say
you want to execute all the methods
from all the browsers in a loop
so you guys can write a
loop, you can declare a an ad
lib drivers web driver
web drivers and see where to.
Then you can say new Google Chrome,
new Firefox,
new Safari.
You can write a loop
for each
random driver
or driver is included to drivers
in their script.
You copy piece of code, you put it in here
and now if I call this
call out as well,
it will execute all the methods
from all the classes
opening
a Google Chrome, Firefox Safari
and there can be thousands
of these methods
if How to change web driver to W.
Can you repeat the third shortcut?
It's not a shortcut.
You mean in here
or you hold down your all button
and then you use your left mouse click
to draw this line vertically.
Once you have drawn the line,
you can leave it like that
and then you can put anything in here.
It's called vertical editing.
If we write Neil, Google Chrome
click,
but summit, is it also polymorphism?
No, it's not polymorphism.
This is polymorphism.
Same third, behaving
differently based on the object.
This is polymorphism inside this loop
that you can make sense.
Guys.
Okay.
Let's let's go to the slides once
and then we will do more examples.
So now, now I hope it will make sense.
Polymorphism is one of the feature
that allow us to perform
a single action in different ways.
Okay. And B matters.
They are still same same actors,
but they are acting differently
because we are storing different objects
inside that beta type variable.
Polymorphism is the capability of a method
to do different
things based on the object
and that it is acting up on.
Okay, we see a different object
in the variable method X differently.
If we store a different object,
it gets different view
and important.
The usage of polymorphism occurs
in loop in oops
is how it fit in the class
refers to a Charlie class,
so this polymorphism can be achieved
in two falling ways.
Compile time static bounding through
method overloading so method
overloading is also a type of polymorphism
same method.
It behaves differently
when we pass different parameters.
It is also a type of polymorphism,
but it is a static one.
It's not a dynamic one.
So we cannot write those loops
and all that
is actually methods
acts differently according to the objects.
And so in here
the method is acting differently
based on the object in compile time
polymorphism in overloading
a method of behaves
differently based on parameters.
So it is also type of polymorphism
runtime.
Polymorphism dynamic binding is true
method overriding so far
in that website the sequence is important
because it's like the step.
Yes, for best
guess is that you guys will be writing.
Yes, you will be following the sequence,
but it's not mandatory.
You can call any method in any sequence.
So the typecasting and our assigning
value of one type
to a value of another type is known as
typecasting.
Yes, I slept for 3 hours.
So two types of casting in Java.
Again,
same learning, casting, automatic up
casting and working
the lower that type typing to hire.
So when we store a a child object
in a parent type variable,
this is what we say we are doing.
Widening what is starting binding.
Starting binding is another name
for our method overloading overloading.
So methods need to be done in sequence.
Example you need to provide the password
before log.
Yes Mama, it's your business logic.
We say it's your logic.
We follow the business logic rules,
but polymorphism,
it does not have any rules
that this method should be called for us.
This method should be called after.
That is your business logic.
It's your business that is saying that
we should first enter the log in
and then click on that.
It's not polymorphism
and then we have the narrowing casting.
Okay, same thing.
The bigger data
type to this smaller one and
in objects in classes, the parent
or the other type,
they are the bigger ones, the guys,
they are the smaller ones.
Okay, so if we go upwards,
we are doing up costing.
If we go downwards,
we are going down, costing.
So in here,
if you see we have the parent class,
we create a variable and we say new child.
Okay, so is this up
costing or down costing?
Guys,
I am storing a child inside a pattern type
variable
is the up costing, right?
Storing a smaller thing inside
something bigger.
And if I store a parent inside the child
okay,
and sometimes it is not written
but it is returned but still store
as they don't see this list
and the downside thing.
So and this is not allowed
we cannot store parent inside a child
objects it is not allowed
so in primitive data types
storing a double inside
an integer was not allowed right.
We have we had that workaround
of converting that data type
with those parentheses. Right.
So in here it is allowed, but it also
has that parents either
something like that break in here.
So for example, for example,
if I say
so, this is allowed web
driver we can store Google Chrome,
Firefox, any body and anything.
But if we say
Google Chrome, we will.
Chrome is equal to new web driver,
then this is not allowed here.
We will be getting an added
but we can do something in here as well.
If let's say we have
a web driver web
driver if we initially store
Google Chrome inside
this variable,
then we can extract it back.
Okay? Then we can extract it back.
So, for example, in here,
the down casting will work.
Okay, I can see
Google Chrome.
Chrome is equal to web driver
and in here
I can specify these parentheses like this,
but it will only work if have first stored
Google Chrome inside
that parent type variable.
Then only you can down cost it,
then only it will work.
Otherwise will not work.
But why we need that?
Because what can happen is that
looks like type thing. Yep. Yep.
So what can happen?
Is that so let's say
I can store the Firefox as well in here.
Now again, a dog and a cat.
Can they be same objects?
Can they be same?
Can a car object and be a bike object?
Can can they be same?
Can I add a plane object in laptop
object big begin with same.
So what happened is that if you store
something else in the parent
and try to get something else
out of their computer,
So do we get any error
or should it should this code work fine.
So I am storing Google Chrome,
but I am trying to sorry,
I am storing Firefox
but I am trying to get back Google Chrome.
If we try to do that
we will get class cast exception
work fine Alexa.
It works fine for you all.
My you have invented something new in Java
initially.
Screenshot of your code.
It should not work
so is there any loss of information
like explicit costing?
Yes, there is a loss of information. Yes.
Are you guys ready to take
that much information?
By the way,
before I show you the loss of information,
do you guys still have patients?
Can you guys promise me
that you will not jump from the window
on promises
named and give time to replace?
Okay.
Yeah.
Polymorphism is great,
but costing is confused.
It will not be confusing.
Let give me one.
So down
casting does not work in polymorphism.
No, no. It works.
If it only works if you store the
same object first inside the
I am confused
at all.
It depends on how out of the everyones
window.
Okay. It's
awesome.
Let me know once you are done typing
which class
and if you want me to scroll down this one
or this one
after there is nothing
or you want to.
You want me to scroll up?
There is nothing below this
all Welcome.
So if we have stored
Google Chrome already,
then we can convert it back
another way.
The Google Chrome as well.
No, this would not be an error.
Can you explain line 42?
Is this typecasting in here
down casting?
Is there same rule
like we for short value to fit into part
s near it? Same
so web driver is bigger,
parents are better
and then the Google Chrome is smaller, so
we are trying to fit it a smaller amount.
So it's working fine. Right?
So one why you going the error?
But if we initially store something else,
then it will not work.
Now you guys asked about
the loss of information. You
have a new animals
or this error.
Make sure that you have not declared
this clone anywhere.
Make sure that all
the code is commented out
and then you do should not be getting this
said.
Show me the complete class code
so that loss of information
is not happening in here.
So for middle class
because in all the classes,
all the methods are present.
If some if some methods are not present,
they coming from the parent class.
But. Latif
Rice What if a child
class has its own?
Okay, what if this Google from class?
So right now what is happening?
We have all the matters
that are presented independently.
But what if
this Google Chrome class has
something special?
If this happens, if something
is only present in a specific
if specific child
guys, can we generalize this
this thing is not present in parent.
Everyone is inheriting from parent.
If a parent separately has its own thing
now, we cannot generalize this.
So what will happen
if I uncomment this code?
And if I say w d dot
special method?
I cannot call this. I cannot call this.
I can only call this method.
Okay, So let me comment this out.
This this one,
it will be the focus on this one, right?
If I am storing it inside of a driver,
do web driver class, does
it has any information
about our special method,
this first driver class,
it does not have any information
about
that special method.
So what will happen if we try to cast
that sprite?
That is something special
which is only present in a child.
It is gone.
If we wanted, we must first convert
a D variable back to its original form.
It's in the original form and then only
we can call that special
method from that class.
Yes. So
parent
class can hold all the child classes,
but only those matters and fields
which are present parent,
not the fields of the or the methods
which are specific to a child class.
So you can think of like this.
So this box, this wrapped driver,
then it will be created
inside of the memory.
It will be having specific features
to hold all the matters
which are coming from here,
but can be called.
This web driver has no information
because the driver has no information
about this.
Google Chrome.
This Web driver
don't know if it has to reserve a space
for this special method or not.
Grandparent does not know Grandpa
because inheritance is one way
we inherit from parent inspired child we
don't inherited from child inside parents.
It's a one way relationship.
So We can get all the info from the parent
inside a child,
but we cannot do the reverse.
We cannot have this information
that something is
something special is present inside
a child.
Parent can not have that information
because inheritance is one way, okay?
It's not a movie.
So when this variable driver
will be declared a
I will only reserve the memory
by looking at this web driver class.
If it has then variables.
It will result in memory allocation.
If it 100 meters,
it will reserve hundred memory location.
Something matters.
But how do this web driver
class know that it has to resolve
the memory location
for this variable as one? So
what happens is
that when we try to store a child
and if a child has something special,
it will be thrown out.
Only those matters which are present in
the parent will be stored inside memory
and this special method will be ignored.
Yes, the passes from parent, the child,
not from child
to parent.
Magic quarter time.
If I run this
I am having last gasp exceptional.
So let me run this
only present in chrome.
I see that method now.
Can you share the screenshot?
Please explain this.
Google Chrome chrome chrome Lab driver.
So this line
in here we are down casting Mustafa
from a parent class type variable.
We are converting that variable
to the child type variable.
So it's the same down casting
as we do in primitives.
Now comment out the above code.
Yes, we can have another example.
So down casting is not allowed.
Somebody are missing
down, casting is not allowed.
And how is this working?
Okay.
It is working because initially, initially
we are storing the child object
inside the dependency.
If I say web driver, Web driver
now, this is not allowed.
Okay.
Okay. So and now I will get an error.
I will go to that
exception class cast exception.
Okay.
Because a
parent cannot be converted to a child now.
It cannot be stored in a child.
But we can do the reverse.
We can store a chart
inside the parent.
Can we write down
casting without first line parent?
Plus this one.
Then you will be getting an error
on this variable.
I mean, you have to define
a variable first, right?
Or you can also do it in different ways.
Like, for example, directly converting
just Yes, just create the object
with the new keyword
and right after there, try to convert it.
Yes, it is also possible.
So let me first
go to the slides,
store up casting, casting from a subclass
to a superclass is called
up Casting.
So from child to parent
it is allowed, it looks,
but only I can only call those matters
which are present in the parent class.
And then we have the down casting.
It's the casting from a superclass
to a subclass from a parent to the child,
which is not allowed.
But if initially we store the child
inside the parent variable,
then we can expect that
object again, because in initially
we are controlling that child.
Okay, So you can think of like this
I create a child class object.
I put it inside a box of my parent
and on the next line extracting it back.
But if I initially put
something else in the box
and if I try to extract that child from
there, can I do that guys
I can only extract from the box
the thing that I placed
inside of that box.
Okay.
If I try putting a dog and I say,
can I get a cat out of that box,
that is not possible.
So this is what is happening in here.
I take this jar,
I put it inside this box, this box
which is of my bitter,
and then I get the bag
of that child again.
So only that thing can be extracted back,
which we initially inserted.
But initially,
if you are trying to insert a parent
inside a child, this is not possible.
Okay?
Only that thing is allowed
which we put inside that box.
Okay, so this is your task.
Now, there is a very small thing
that I want to show.
We still have contaminants.
So this was polymorphism
that you guys like. It
has potential
to be lowered so we can put parent the box
inside the parent box
and, take our child from that.
No, no, no, no.
This is exactly what we can not do.
This is exactly Alex.
This is exactly what we can do.
I cannot put a parent I mean, how can I do
their thinking in the real life?
Can I put the dog inside box
and get back out from that box?
Unless it's a magic box, then
you can do that. Yes.
They had our task on this as well.
David Copperfield box.
How many of you will still have
how many of you can still learn?
And something very small?
How many of you still have patience?
You can put animal in box and take out cat
What was inside Animal?
Yes. Yes.
Can you can do that? Yes.
Alex, if I put there is this animal box.
If I put cat, I get to big cat.
If I put dog, I can get better. Yes,
I can wait till 12 hours for sure.
If can you repeat
one more time How to draw a normal
how to draw a lot
when you replaced
that room.
I know you guys will say that
How to do vertical editing.
You used the button
like this.
So for example, in here you use
all the button, then you draw the line
and then you can select
whichever area you want,
and then you can replace it
with whatever value you want.
So tomorrow
we have a review from 7 to 10 p.m..
Yes. So guys, let me show you the cloning.
So let's say you want to clone
the this repository
so you copy this link.
Okay.
It's already a shortcut.
The example we did all of them,
they were a runtime polymorphism
compile time polymorphism happens
with the overloading, not overwriting.
They were all overwriting examples.
The compile time compile time
polymorphism is in order. Use
control is out to draw the vertical line.
It's r e healthy keyboard
if you guys have it on your Mac.
So we copy this
link,
we open the
get bash
like this
as to a less
so I don't know where I am right now so
the default the
let me clone it inside
this one drive.
Yeah so I said 31 drive
I see a less
and do you guys know how to create a
new folder.
So we say m KTAR
and the name of the folder
and then that folder will be created.
Okay, so I see this test folder now
in here.
The other instructor
did not want to teach us.
If that is the case, Simon, maybe
then we should not do that
because you guys
will definitely tell Amazon
that Haskell showed us this
and then was Will call me in their T.
S Gertrud, I told you
not to show that to the student.
Why are you still sure that?
Okay, it's fine.
So we can we can move to this test
directly like this
the intelligible
and so it is to clone your project
from GitHub.
Okay.
So I go to this in here and then I see
you get clone
and then I based the link in here on
this one.
So I faced
by the way, guys will be having
proper sessions to learn about this
is to copy
the code from GitHub on your computer.
It's called cloning.
Having a copy
on your local computer transfer.
So now if I click on Enter,
all the code has been cloned
and now I can see on my computer.
Yeah.
So if I go inside one drive inside
and first I see I start batch 11.
I see. So
I see gone syntax
and all the classes and all the code.
We can clone it from any public wrapper.
Yes, you guys can clone it
from any public wrapper.
And now this project,
you guys can open it in your eclipse
or intelligent as well.
So this is what we call cloning.
How to add
code from different folder
in same project on your tub.
That is a little complex.
Alex You guys will be having proper
sessions on merging
and resolving conflicts and all that.
So we wait for that third, try
to try to digest polymorphism.
Okay,
Are there any questions Deal?
Can you show how to push from intelligent?
No, that is strictly strictly not allowed.
I want you to use this terminal
guys specially build
this terminal for you.
The feeling that this terminal can give,
you know, intensity will not be giving you
that feeling.
I will show you in the last week,
by the way,
sheer class base to get.
Okay. Yes.
Step by step in detail.
What I will teach you about that. All
right, guys, let's call it a day.
Take some rest.
Don't be at your children or your siblings
if you have not understood
polymorphism, give it some time.
It will be fine
and I will see you on the s on Thursday.
May God help your husband.
All right, guys.
Bye bye. Take some rest.