I could not find Willard.
Yes, it is possible.
It is possible.
Two types of functions
in this field, right?
What are these two types?
Guys?
Relational
and non relational.
Great answer, but.
Great. Great.
You guys.
You guys are great.
You see, you guys just start following.
Without thinking, then wonder why
you said relational and orderliness.
And you.
They are single door and multi-role.
These are the types of databases
that you guys are telling.
Relational are non relational.
Guys, it's almost fine.
Please, please, please
control your emotions
and think before you speak because
you guys will be playing a very,
very important role on your jobs.
Your your whatever you say, it will matter
a lot.
Companies will be taking decisions
based on what you see.
So you guys will be taking you guys
will be part of many important decisions.
So please think about it
then before you speak.
One wrong decision
can affect your company very,
very negatively.
Believe me.
So there are two types of functions.
I was picking my classmates. Yes.
After class when available,
please share the recording.
What do you do?
I mean, you are in the class as well.
Still,
you need the recording before anyone
for who I am recording
so desperately.
I mean, usually the weaker classes,
the instructors, they also because
we are also following the same
same schedule as a few.
So we also go to sleep
right after the class on weekdays
and we try to share the recordings
next week.
But if someone is awake,
some of the instructors,
then they can definitely share
the recordings.
Otherwise
every every employee of the syntax, then
they follow the same schedule
to follow the Eastern Time.
So what time it
is really right now for you?
I think it must be like
three four in
midnight, Three more.
What are you doing with 9 p.m.?
Go to sleep, man.
I would share the recording.
Please go to sleep.
You have some lights.
So there are two types of functions
in, you know, for Alexa year 2:10 a.m..
That's great.
I hope all of your efforts did bear
fruit very, very soon.
We wanted to make sure you would not be
so two types of functions
multi role and single role.
But what are single role functions?
Days.
Alexa Just make sure my calls.
They have food and water
and they look good
and then you can go to sleep.
Return one result.
Patrol one.
Deserted patrol.
They take one role as input
and return one role as output.
Pride.
So for each role
they will be returning a result.
And what about the multiple functions base
multi role functions take
multiple roles as input
and give a single role as output.
Right?
Can you guys give me some examples
of single role
functions, salary, salary,
the single role function?
Or are you feeling okay today?
Case case
uppercase right
count is count a single role
function guys
know it's a multi role function.
Right?
And can you guys
also give me some examples
for multiple functions
some I think you left
I shall now picking upon me
and yes guys
see if you guys here that I was
I some day
suddenly I disappear from syntax
and the police tell the police that
uh, do check with Aisha.
Maybe she has kidnaped me or paid me
for having those jokes right.
So these are single role functions.
They take
a single role
as input and produce
a single role as output.
The multi role functions,
they take multiple roles
as input and produce
a single output value.
So these are some of the examples
of single role functions
like converting the
candidate to uppercase or lowercase. Yes.
And are these functions they universalize
like Alexa, for example,
if I using a function on my school
database,
let's say may be this init function, will
I see the same function
on all the databases?
Or it is possible
that the function names can differ
or some of the functions can be missing on
some of the databases.
They can differ, right?
So totally depends on the company
who has developed
the ADD specific database.
If they are using the same names
for the functions,
there are high chances
that the function will be available.
It might just have a different name
or it to functions might be combined
in to a single function
that will perform the things for you.
So you can always Google
for those
functionality inside those databases.
On Google
or you can read the documentation.
Then we discussed the group by clause.
Right? Very, very important.
So what is this group by cloud guys?
What does this group class to
a collection of that.
Okay.
A collection of data
grouping
that it's kind of groups the guilty
by column
or were there
some homework questions
related to class there?
They share some questions
related to good or bad class.
I think one yes.
Groups the data, according to the column
we pass to interact in groups
that are why column name.
So let's see.
We have a table in which we have employers
only columns,
not the rows.
So Silva is saying
does it only group that are based on
columns, not paroles.
Then you guys
answer our question.
So let's say guys.
So I have this job title
pulled in here right?
Is it readable now, guys?
I think it groups the rows
that have the same values.
Yes. I one other.
So let's say, guys, these job titles,
they are actually IDs that
that represent a job in another table.
Right.
So if I want to count
how many employees have job I did 23.
Can you guys quickly
write like you do for that.
I want to count
how many employees have job title board?
23. How many of them have job title one.
How many of them have job 208 25
and things like that.
Google
copycat.
Can you guys quickly
articulate you for that
or. I'm not.
I mean, for all of the job titles,
I want to know they count
for all of the job titles.
I am seeing a different table.
I think
this one moment this
as such are employed
and you see a different paper.
You mean different data in at this table
you to see
And do you guys also see different data
where it seems okay,
great.
So if I want to count,
I can see.
So first I need to specify the column
based on which I want to count
the number of employees.
Right?
So I want to count
based on the job title code.
So after specifying the column
based
on which I want to create the groups,
then I specify what kind of operation,
what kind of aggregate function,
what kind of multi-tier function
I want to apply to those values.
Right?
So so
in here I am simply I simply want to count
the number of employees
in that have same job title
Core five.
Then the table name
and that's it.
Right?
And my writing,
the correct duty guys, we like to
correct results
grew by it.
I am missing group by
and some of the databases
they will throw an error
if we are trying to use
a multi row function
without material function
with a column name or with a single real
function because multiple functions
they produce a single output
while the single row function
they produce many, many different outputs.
They can produce a for each row
they can produce an output.
So that's why there will be a conflict
and some of their databases,
they will throw an error while
the other databases, they might simply
give you incorrect answers.
Is there a shortcut to execute
without selecting?
Yes, it's control and of.
So now it shows me that there are 97
employers who have died title to
34 employers that have job title ID,
36 employers that have job title.
And here like this.
So let me remove the column
based on which I want to go to by
and let me try to execute
the security again.
So sometimes you guys might want
to perform this type of grouping as well,
although it does not make much sense
because you only see the count
and you don't know
for which group discount,
which group this count is representing.
But today we will be discussing
disabilities in which we might need
to do these kind of things.
So it is also possible
that without specifying the column
based on which we are creating the groups,
we can still get
the results in here, right?
We can still go to buy things
without specifying it
inside the select clause.
And what if I let's say
I only want to see
those groups for which
there are at least
ten employees in that group.
Like, for example,
I only want to see those job titles
and their count,
for which there are at least
ten employees.
So for example,
I don't want to see this 8 to 7, this one,
this 511.
How can I remove these roles
from my results?
I don't want this 8718.
I only want from that count,
which is greater than ten.
Okay.
Can I use the we are plotting here.
Can I use the word clause in here?
No, we cannot use the
we have a clause in here for this purpose.
We have a special clause that is called
having clubs of eight
that operates on
multi role
functions of aggregate functions.
So having count
greater than
ten right.
So now I only see those
for which there are at least ten employees
in that group right.
Oh okay.
Yes. Yes.
Having
so I think you guys are now comfortable
with the group by clause.
Right.
Is there anyone who's confused about group
by clause.
Yeah.
I mean if any other than you,
it's fine for you.
Is it better to die?
The name for
it is better
to write the name of the table
and the columns in the upper case. Two.
Yes. Okay.
No. Elena is one of the in
all, almost all the matches
we have the most innocent student
in all the video.
So this batch has Elena as the most
innocent student group by clause.
Mercy verses having clause
where for single row having for multiple.
Yes you are right
group by clause versus having clause.
So you are asking
if there is any relationship
between group by clause and having clause.
So having clause is always used
whenever you have group by clause
in your queries.
So it's one of the most
most popular interview questions.
What is the difference between very close
and having blood?
When I see the results for having
this one
dedicated that I have just executed
this one? Yes.
Did. So
let me check
with this same as mine.
Okay. Why?
I have a red line
because you are having a semicolon on line
number three.
Remove that semicolon.
So I you know,
we have this table in here.
Are we following you for Excel?
Are. If you guys want to,
you can follow me.
Otherwise it is not required.
I am just using this scale to
teach you the concept of drawings.
If you guys want to follow me.
Yes, you can. Huh?
All right, guys.
And so before that.
So we were last last time we didn't
discuss the sub duties in detail.
So here is a question for you.
Not this one.
Can you guys write a query
to give me all those employers
which are having an age?
So first
I want you to calculate the average age,
and then I want you to only bring
those employers who have
age greater than the average age
inside this table,
average of the age.
So all those employees who have age
greater than the average age
that is present inside of the start table.
And you guys think of the query, the
Yep, yep.
One more time, please.
So I want all those employees
who have age
greater than the average age
that is present inside of this table.
No, no.
On just not not just the average age
still processing.
We are the core i7 of this class,
core I9 and core i7
processors of this class.
You guys cannot write a query like this.
Select a discount to thrombus.
I'm going to buy it.
Okay.
Select last name.
Count from person group by last name.
Having count.
Oh, why?
Why are you guys are using the count
function?
I want to be employs all the details
like first name, last name, gender, age.
Every year
everything is different than count place.
Okay, let me tell you.
Okay.
Just write a query to find out
the average age of the employees
in this table, all grade,
all all those queries, they are wrong.
You just write this.
Just write a query to find the average age
of the employees.
Okay.
That's why we have the sub queries.
Now you guys will understand
why we need the sub duties.
Okay,
so if I execute this query, yes or not,
I am asking something that you guys
have not learned
yet. It's
not working.
Yes, it will not
because you guys don't know the concept
for that yet.
So I have a query that gives me
the average age of the employee's
in this table right up until this point.
I not understand what is going on
right now using the sub queries.
What we can do.
I can use the results of this query.
I can use the results of this query inside
and other query
I can see select all from person
where age is greater than
and I inside of that.
Inside these parentheses
I can actually put this query.
So now what will happen
first, the average age of the employees
will be calculated
with the help of discovery
and the results.
This 23.6.
It will be used inside this query.
This part is called B Inner beauty.
In this in this query
where we are using this ability concept
and this part is called the output acuity.
So some good is
what do we do with disabilities?
We use the
resource URLs of
one query inside and other acuity,
and that we what we can do,
we can calculate
so many intermediate results
that are not possible
to calculate directly
or are very hard to calculate to directly
or another benefit of this sub duty
is that
I can divide my logic into different box
instead of writing a very big duty
in which I put all the conditions,
I can divide my query in multiple parts
in multiple steps.
First, I calculate one result.
I use that result in another query.
I calculate another result,
and then I use the results of that query
in another query.
So I can divide my logic into steps
and I can write queries
which are not possible to write directly
or are very hard to write directly.
Do you guys get the idea of subquery? Why?
Why? Why?
We should use the sub goodies
So you will see this time
we have all those employees for which
the age is greater than the average age.
Okay, so first what do we do?
And we can do it
with any type of securities, right?
Inner coded result
will be used as input for output.
Yes, Maria? Yes.
So this is the concept of subcu.
This.
So subcu is a query within a query
subcu.
This has two part outer
query and inner query.
The result output of inner
query will be used
as input for the for the output query.
So you see in here we are using select
column name from table name
and then we can put any comparison
Operator
now and ask your skill rep
where we use the other guru
now, for example,
you can, you guys can also use the inner
curious like this.
So we have so in this case
we are using the same table
to bring to calculate returns
for inner and outer beauty.
But you guys can also use multiple tables,
other tables as well.
So let's say for example,
I have this employed table
and in this
implied
table I have the departments in here
and for all those
departments we have these employ ideas
or we have this Saturday column.
Now let's say we want to count.
We want to find out all those employees
who are earning.
Let's say, maybe more than 100.
Okay,
So what I can do, I can first write acuity
to get to B e amp ideas off
those employees who are earning greater
than 100 K by writing a query like this.
So e MP ready
from employed table
to where
salary is greater than
100. Right.
So this part of the query give me those
MPI IDs right.
So I now have those employed ideas
and now I can use the results
from this query inside the other viewer
to find out the details of those persons
which are earning more than 100,
I guess I can say select all from person.
We're MPI ready
in because
I have multiple roles
I am using in in here
and I can use this query in here.
So if you want to combine the logic
from multiple tables.
So these are the employees
who are earning more than 100.
Okay.
So if you have
you have that in multiple tables
and let's say some piece of information
is presented in a in a different table,
you can calculate the intermediate results
from that table
and you can use those results to calculate
the things from another table.
So in this case, we are calculating the
we are calculating the empty ideas
from employed table,
and then we are using those employ ideas
inside of the person table to find out the
details of those employees.
Is clear.
Guys.
So that's the concept of sub duties.
And now it will make more sense when.
So once you guys are learning
the relationship between two tables.
So first thing, let me tell you.
So you guys might ask this question
that has to go to why you have created
so many tables, right?
Why you have created so many tables,
Why not create a single table
and put all the info inside that table?
Can you guys think of the reason why?
Why create so many different tables?
Why not use a single table to store
all the information
collected that
because it will be messy?
Yes. Alone?
Yes. To make us work on so many tables
all that complexity
is security managed system, huh?
Manage sister,
assume
by creating a single table
searching will be hard
for different reports
or simply simply more organized.
A speed? Yes.
All of your answers are correct.
If we use a single table
first of all,
it can compromise
the security of the data.
Because
if we have multiple tables,
we can maybe restrict
the access of those tables
for some of the employees.
Let's say you are designing a banking
application.
One table contains the username
and passwords
of the of the employees.
One table
might contain the personal information.
One table might contain the information
about the funds.
about some other
types of accounts or something like that.
So what can happen?
You will not give access to the tables
like username and password and funds
to all all the employees
that are working in your company,
in your I.T department,
and you might only want to give the access
for a specific time
if there are any problems
you give the access
once that issue is resolved to you,
I take back of that access.
And the second reason is that
when we a single table
to store all that data,
your queries will get super, super slow.
Like, for example, if someone
accidentally executes this select all.
So if you combine
all the results inside a single table,
there might be 2000 columns or maybe 1500
or 200 columns for big databases.
So it will get super,
super messy and super slow
and it will be very,
very hard to understand those table. So
and there are other
technical reasons as well, inserting data,
deleting data and manipulating data inside
a single
table is not the most efficient way
of storing data.
There is actually a complete course
in which we learn
how to design the tables.
They are.
They are called the normalization.
So those who want to learn
the technical reasons why we should have
multiple columns instead of single column,
you guys can search on the internet
about normalization in databases.
So there is a technical reason as well.
Sometimes if we use a single column,
it is not possible to perform
the deletion.
We might lose all the data
if we delete a single row.
And there are other reasons AS but
so for those reasons
we create multiple tables. Now
if I have to create multiple tables,
that means I need to split my information
in different tables.
Let's say for example, in this database,
the information related to country
is stored inside the country table.
The information related to the employee
skills has been stored inside this table.
The personal information has been stored
in tired display bubble,
and we have divided the information
in different tables.
Now, what do you guys think should not be
there some kind of connection?
So let's say, for example,
if I have
the information of an employee
inside this employee stable
and I want to find out how many years
of experience that employee has
so that information related to
the experience is stored inside
this empty work experience table.
While the personal information
is stored in here.
So what do you guys think?
How can I find out the experience
of this specific employee
from this table to this table?
So if I execute,
I hope there is some kind that is
by six has left some data.
They should have something common
like employee I.D..
Yes. Yes.
You guys are right.
Thank you.
Let me tell you from this.
So now you guys will understand
the main purpose of employer,
the main purpose of foreign keys
and primary keys.
So if let's say
I let's say if I want to find
the Department of John.
Yes, let me make it.
Is it good now?
Is it treatable?
So question number nine of our homework
laws, this kind of subquery?
You know, to be honest,
I don't remember that question.
I have to check.
But yes, you should have at least
one or two questions related to sub puris
from the homework that I shared yesterday.
You guys don't need to follow me in here.
You guys run into fun. So
let's say guys,
I have stored the information related
to employment inside this table
and I have stored the information,
personal information inside this table.
So I have created two tables
in my database.
I can have many, many more tables.
But now,
because I have divided the information
in to do two or three or four tables,
I also must find out a mechanism
to link the back of this information.
For example, if I want to find out
B Department of John,
because I have stored that information
inside this table in here,
I must come up with the mechanism
to link this information back.
So if I want to find out
the Department of John,
I must have something
that can tell me the Department of John.
So what do you guys think?
Is there anything inside of this table
that can tell me
this information? Yes.
The employer ID right.
So if I want to find out
the Department of John
what I will do, I will check the employer
I did that is associated with John
and then I will go inside this table
and I will match this employee I.D.
in here.
And once I have found the match,
I can find out this salary of John.
I can find out his grade.
I can find out his department.
Can you guys tell me what is this employed
in here?
It's the primary key, right?
And for short quality, speak it.
So let me right
here.
But I also have this empty already
inside of this table.
Can you guys check if this MPI did that?
I have inside the person table?
Does it qualify for the primary key
Jack and the data that is present in here
and tell me if it qualifies
for the primary key or not.
Remember,
primary keys can not have duplicate
values right?
They should be unique.
Are they unique? Not.
We have multiple
one contact is in here. Right?
So when ever a primary key.
Yeah. Listen carefully guys.
Whenever a primary e is present
inside and other table
whenever a primary key is present inside
and other table
it is called foreign key.
And why we have these foreign keys
and these foreign keys.
They help us create the relationship
between two tables
and using the relationship of this primary
and the foreign key,
I can link to the information
inputs to different tables.
Yes. Foreign key.
Then if this.
So whenever a primary key
is present inside a different table.
Yes. For f k for short.
It is called a foreign key
and the foreign keys.
They can have
duplicate values.
They can have null values
because in one department
there could be multiple of implied. Yes.
So you are right.
So primary gives they can not have
duplicate values.
They can not have a null values,
but the foreign keys,
they can have null values
and they can have duplicate values
as well. Why?
Because it is possible
that multiple employers
might be working in the same department
or multiple employers
might be running the same amount of money.
Right?
Or there might be an employers
who are who have just joined the company
and they have not assigned any department
or salary yet.
So for these kind of scenarios.
It is possible
for a foreign gate to have
null values and to have duplicate values,
but primary is
they don't have duplicate values.
They don't have null values.
Is it clear, guys, what do you
So on the left, the table empty
ID is the foreign key and on the right
probably empty the parameter.
Yes. Muhammad Yes, you are right.
And to why
we need these AMP employer I.D.,
why we need these primary keys
and foreign keys.
We need them because we are learning
the relational databases.
Relational databases
have a relation between tables.
And this is how
these relations are created
in non relational databases.
There are no primary key or foreign keys
they can have, but it is not mandatory.
But in relational databases,
if through tables they contain something
that should be linked to other tables,
they will have a foreign key
and a primary.
All right.
So now to
so till now,
you guys have been writing duties
that were only fetching the data
a single table.
Right?
So two tables
going to have two primary keys
and two foreign
keys are not two primary keys.
One or two tables.
Yes, almost in real life.
And you will see each table
will be having a primary key
and a table can have multiple
foreign keys.
For example, if you guys focus carefully
on this table
in left table primary key is i.t.
Yes, I agree.
So can you guys tell me
how many
foreign keys are present inside this?
Such a chart implies
maybe you guys will be able to do
that.
You guys will be in a better position
to tell me if i show you.
Can you guys open this
this slide on your computers?
And can you guys tell me how many foreign
keys are present in such a chart?
Employs
from this picture?
And by the way,
the text that is written in here
that says foreign key foreign key.
It is not labeled for all of the tables.
If you want to actually find out
all the foreign gives you,
you should look for these relationships
that you have
with other tables of this asset
that are in place.
Have relationship with this table,
this table, this table, this table.
So you should actually get out
of these relationships, but
it is hardly a readable model.
You have this slide on your computer.
The and it is still hard
to read on your computer.
It is not that.
Oh my God, I used to watch all the movies
and everything in one $0.44
and then to 40 B and 363.
I am from that that age
now everyone looks for
HD right?
So yes.
And 13 is the correct answer.
13 is the correct answer.
So for every relationship
that a table has,
the relationship is created
using the foreign key.
And that's why
there are 13 of the relations and 13
following this, for example,
I can show you from here
you see it to make a race
or it is a foreign key.
Can you guys
thank you saw one
this nation code it is also a foreign
in this implied gender
it is also a foreign you see it is in here
instead of actual gender male female.
You see these codes right?
So they are all foreign keys.
And if you want to find out
the actual information,
let's say, for example,
let me give you an example.
So yesterday you guys wrote Acuity
to, find the job
title code, right?
So it is also a primary key
and foreign relationship.
And what was the name of the table as such
a job
and job title?
Then you guys tell me
the name of that table that contains
the names of the
Yes job or item
job title.
So you see we have this 2323 in here,
23 to 0 eight quantity.
But if we go inside this table
or item job
title, they are actually the primary keys.
You see they are actually the primary gate
inside this table
and this is where
the actual information is stored
like this.
So these are the
what are these guys are the primary
keys are foreign. He's
prime the keys.
And if we check the
at just a job employs
inside of this table we have this
job title code
and it contained null values
it contained duplicate values.
What are they
are the primary key or foreign key.
They are the foreign keys. Right.
And also observe this guys
they can have these columns,
although they represent
the same information.
They can have different names in here
we have saying it,
we are calling it job title code,
but if we go inside the table
that actually contains the titles,
we are calling it ID.
So by convention, most of the time
the primary key is they will be called
ideas and in the other tables
they might be called
something different.
All right.
Now these joins they actually help us
bring
the information from multiple tables.
So up till now,
you guys have been writing queries
that were bringing the data
from a single table.
But what if I have the information
stored in multiple tables
and I want to, let's say, bring
some columns from one table and columns
from the other table,
How can I combine this information?
How can I try to query that?
Let's say bring the results
from two columns from one table
and two columns from another table,
so we can do that with the help of joins.
So first we have to tell you all about
the primary is and different give
so that you can create those relationships
and then we can tell the columns
that we need from both the tables.
For example,
let's say I want to write a query
in which I want to see the first name
and the salary of the employee
right?
So if I execute this duty,
I have first names are stored in here.
While the salary that these employees
are earning, this information is stored
inside the employer table.
And now I want both of these columns
in my results set.
So how can I combine the information
from two different tables
inside a single desk?
I'll start using a single query.
So it's very, very simple.
If you guys have understood the concept
of from primary, it can be foreign key.
So this time we will say a select
and then we will say a first name
and a salary.
Remember,
this first name is coming from percent,
the salary is coming from employee.
So you guys know that after
they select the
we specify the column names
from which we want information.
Right. And what do I specify?
What do we specify
after the front clause gave,
we specify the table names
and how many tables.
I will be needing
to bring this information again.
I will be needing to,
so I need to specify this time.
Two tables employ
and person.
But to how do ask You will know
which columns are primary keys
and which columns are foreign
Key is how do school
Law order does not matter.
You'll get the you can write in first
person later person first thing by later.
So we have to tell those columns as well
based on which school
can figure out the relationship.
So we will say we're
we're the
we are in employ dot
so name of the table dot
MP ID is equal to
person dog
MP ID
so we are telling the skill
that here skill you know what,
you can go and check the MP
d column from the employed table
and MP I d from the person table.
These are the two columns
that will tell you which salary
belong to which employ.
So school is smart enough
to find to perform this match.
So I will check the employ I do
from employed table and it will check.
It will find out the same.
So this is what skill will do
a skill will pick this john from here
and to find out
a salary scale will say, okay,
the linkage information
is presented inside this table
so it will go inside this table
or it will say,
okay, 100 is present in here.
That means this salary belong to John.
Then school will pick the second row.
Mary It will check this employ ID
and it will go inside this table.
And it was 100 known or here we have 120.
That means this hundred and ten.
Okay. Is the salary of Mary.
Then it will take the next row.
Ali with a jack. Okay.
What is the employer?
It is 110.
That means one
third B is the salary of Ali.
Does it make sense, guys,
how a skill can figure out
which salary belong
to which first name? Yes.
Skill is using these foreign keys
and primary gives relationship
to find out this information.
How about for idea 120
This is one quality that means 100 k
So all those employers
which have I be 121 to get,
they will all be having a salary of 100.
Let me actually execute this.
Yes. Same salary
because it is possible right.
Many multiple employers
going to be earning the same salary
if that makes sense.
But they should start putting extra column
with their salary into one table.
It may maybe you can create a very,
very big table in which you would
you will put all the information
inside this name.
But believe me,
it will be very, very hard.
I will one day
and then you will realize that is
that was the worst idea that you
you have ever thought of.
And then you will make
separate tables again and you will
information again.
So this is the concept of joins advice.
We have joined two tables, person table
and employed table
and we are bringing some information
from the employer table
and some information
in from the person table.
Same way.
Now with the help of joins,
you guys will be able to join
any of the tables
that are present inside the start up. Yes.
Okay. Yes, we will do more examples.
Someone that nobody
gets.
So let's say, guys,
because you guys are already familiar
with this example.
So let me use the same example again.
So this table guys or at JVM job
title table, it contains the job titles.
And now I have this requirement
that I want to bring
the instead of the job
because I want to bring
just a or
employed.
So let's say I have this requirement that
I want to display the
employee's first name
and I want to display the employee I.D.
and their job title.
But the job title information is present
inside a different table.
So what do I need to do?
I need to have
and do I need to perform a join
if I want this information
in using a single query in a single.
Well said. Yes.
So to perform that join
what should be my first step.
My first step should be to find out
the relationship.
Those two columns which can create
that relationship
a primary key and a foreign key.
So my first step will be to go
inside this or adjacent table
and I will check, okay, I have an ID,
I have a title,
I have the so I will check if this I.D.
is present inside this table or not.
If this I.D.
is not present inside the such
a starting place, can I still create the
relationship based? No.
And then I will not be able to do that
right.
I will not be able to link the information
from multiple tables.
So I go and check all the columns.
All the columns.
That's where your schema will be helpful.
So all the companies will be sharing
that schema with you
and it will have that visual information.
Which table is connected to each other,
table based on which columns.
So you guys don't have to do this
manually like I am doing in here.
You will be provided with the schema.
Hopefully.
So. Okay,
so we check from here
and we see we have these ideas.
Yes. The schema, it can easily tell you
the relationship between two tables.
Is it possible to connect to two tables
by two primary keys?
For one, you want to have
two primary gives,
you know, two primary keys.
If both of the tables
they have their own primary gives
how you can connect to them.
The information should be same right?
Otherwise,
how do I still know which role belongs
to which role?
Because one table will be having its own
primary, its own values.
The other table will be having
its own primary, its own values.
How you will be able to join them.
The information should be common
between two tables.
To join two tables.
Does it make sense? Yes.
It's like the we look up
in Excel.
Those who have worked with the SQL.
Yes, it is.
It is same as the lookups.
Finally,
full value of knowledge is benefiting.
You find at least some of it.
So idea and job
title code will be used in in condition.
Yes. Yes.
Aisha.
So I have I have found the column based
on which I can link these two tables.
Right. So now I can write a query.
I can say a select.
So I can say select.
I can say
employee ID
can say
employee
first name
and I can see
what was the name of the job
title,
actually, other than those dollars
and definitely
the dollars will be coming, but because
now their profession will be same,
they will be able to help out each other.
I think that's the best team.
When two persons are in the same industry
or on the same job.
So, for example,
I know for sure before these guys
get the job,
I know more than 50% of their tasks.
They will be done by Zima.
Silva I will simply say here
the modern things are not making sense.
Can you please help me out?
In the next
will be doing those that supports Silva
and the
salaries that they will only go to Silva
right?
That's my yes.
If Zimmer does not help,
I will not be getting the food
for that day.
And so it is called the job title.
So I will say job.
I mean, if an employee's if we take it
and then sell the table, take be employed,
be these two that are unique,
can we connect them
to each other?
I mean, in employees, if we take I.D.
and salary table, take employer I.D.
sort of on
the salary table
is actually called the employee's ID.
So do you mean the person table?
Can you please use this
proper names for the tables
so that I can get the idea?
The table
in which the salary information is present
is called Employee's table,
and the other table is
called Person's table in Person Table.
We have an ID and employee I.D.
ID is the primary key of that table.
And employee ID is the foreign key,
which is coming from the employer's table.
Now, if you want to
connect these two tables based on the ID,
it is not possible
because it represents something
totally different.
So then after the from clause,
I need to specify the table names.
So this time I need the information
from just
at the employers and
the all at m job title.
And now I need to specify the condition.
What should be my condition This
what should be my condition
to join these two tables
to tell a skill how it can find out
the job title of a person.
How can I? How can a skill do that?
How can it link to the information
from two tables?
Likes it i d
yes, the i d from the
time table. So I will say
all at m
dot i d.
So I am telling the skill that has skill.
This is how you can create
the relationship or two oh item job
title ID from this table to
and for the employers.
I need the name of the column
that contains the same information is
will.
It is called
job title for right.
So as such a job employee or not
job title or right.
So now a skill knows how to link
the information from these two tables.
And now if we execute this query,
we will be getting the information
from both of these tables.
So you see more. Zoom is cloud architect.
Apple is also cloud architect.
Madia is IP analyst
updated is our discord.
So now I see the employer these names and
their designations in a single activity
the moment does it make sense now
even bugs even bugs are cloud architect
without bugs.
Hey, we buggy the cloud architect.
Okay, so this is how willing
the information and guys,
we can also. Yes.
Let's have a break in 6 minutes. Yes.
We can also perform all the other things
that you guys have learned till now.
The group by clause, the where
condition,
the having clause, the count function,
all that you guys have learned till now
can be performed
when you are joining the information
from two different tables.
So, for example, I can write So
we are condition in here and this time
because two tables are joined.
For me it is already taken
because two tables already joined.
Now I can write the word condition
using the columns
which are in job title or table or.
And I can also read the word condition
using the asset at the employer's table.
So for example, let's say
if I go to a search party, employs tables
and let's say I want to maybe
let's say
I want to find out, the employers
who have a date of birth
may be greater than 1945. Right?
So I can say we are E and B
birthday is greater than
or to 1990
and so I can now write their conditions
using any of the columns
present in both the papers.
Let me display the birthday as well.
And here
so that you guys
can check out this information
so all of them use
you guys will see all of them.
They will be having
a birthday greater than 99 equals
zero for.
Okay.
So we can write a we are condition now
using any of the columns in there
from asset employees or from or time.
I can write glue by group by clause I
using any of the and have you guys noticed
sometimes I'm using the name of the table
and then dot and then the column name.
Sometimes I'm simply using the column
names.
You guys notice this.
So sometimes
when I am specifying the column names,
I use the table name
before that column name.
But sometimes I simply write
the column name.
Did you guys notice this
or not?
The reason is that let's see if there are
if in both the
if the column names are same,
for example, an implied table
we were calling the column as implied
and in person table
also we were calling it implied.
And now in here, if we don't specify
the table names as well, will be confused
because it can not figure out
which empty I.D.
we are trying to refer. Right.
Because they are same.
So some of the databases might throw you
an error when you try to do this.
If you are using the same column names
as you will might be confused
and it might throw you an error
saying that has the I am confused
you see column
implied in where clause is ambiguous.
So as Google is unable to find out if the
if this implied,
I am trying to refer from the person table
or implied table.
So if the column names are same in
both the tables,
then we need to specify the table names
as well.
Again, then we need to specify
table names as well.
And if the column, the names they have,
then they have different names.
Then we don't need to specify the table
names.
Okay.
Does it make sense, guys?
So that skill is not confused.
Let's say if you are writing, create a
if you are joining three tables,
four tables, five tables
and all of the column
names in all of those tables,
they have the same name
as How do I still know which column
we are trying to refer?
Right?
If three tables this all have is
same column name how to ask a law.
So we need to specify the table
name as well before the column name.
So that school can easily
link to the information.
And there is one more thing.
Let's say if the table names are very big,
instead of typing
the complete table names,
you guys can also create aliases.
Aliases are shorter
names for your table names.
So instead of writing a complete person
and employee,
I have created these short names B
and E for tables.
And instead of writing the complete
table name, I can simply write E
and I can simply write me.
So when you guys will be writing
big queries, it will be very,
very helpful
because some of the tables,
they might have very long names.
So you see in here
this table name is o item job
underscore,
we can see and also underscore attachment.
So if you are joining multiple tables,
if you are designing multiple tables
and the table names are very, very long,
instead of writing the complete long
table name, you guys can simply create
an alias like this
with a space
and you guys can use those spaces in here
that it makes
sense to date.
And if the column names they are the same.
It does not work with using
a You guys can also specify these in here.
So for example, this first name is coming
from the person table.
I can say paid
first name and I can say ID or Saturday
just to write my query
so that it is more readable.
Okay, so I can use these aliases.
Okay, let's have a break, guys.
And after the break,
I will tell you about the types of domains
that we can create.
I'm on it.
Please be back by 847
and remind me about anybody.
All right.
So let's go over some Kerry
related to joins.
By the way,
the syntax that I have shown you in here,
It is important.
Let me actually copy the security.
There is an alternate
syntax
also to do the same thing using the joins.
But that syntax might not work
on all the databases.
This one, it will work on each
and every database that if you want to do
the same thing with the help of joins
this is how would I do same duty.
So in here what we are saying
we are saying here school
give the first name from person table,
give me the salary from employer table
and I am saying
from person in to join in a join means
if the information is present
in both the tables
for example in in here.
Do you guys see that for Sara
there is no MPI ID present in here,
so skill
will not be able to find this salary
for Sara.
So there are two salaries.
For one, we have the employer already 124.
The second one there is no
MPI ID in the result set.
We only see one Sara with one salary.
We don't see the second Sara
with another salary. Why?
Because I still can not create
that relationship
because the value of PMP
ID is null in here.
So this inner join. This is how it works.
It only gives us the data
for those roles for which
the value is present in both the tables.
If any of the table
does not contain the value,
we will not be getting the results
for that table.
So in their design
we are saying you're not doing enough.
Doing means if the information
presenting both the tables
and we are saying here school this is how
this is how you should join
these two tables based on these columns.
So results will be same.
But this is that the difference
in text in here
and I always prefer this one
because it will work everywhere
but this one it might a little different
differently on a different database
or it might not work at all.
So all the databases might not support
this table order important here?
No, table order is not important.
So we will discuss four types of domains.
Mine did not work.
No, no, it should work.
It should work.
Well, let me show it again.
Make sure you are guys.
You guys are typing the same thing.
But yes,
let me share this
on, on on my skin.
It works on my skin.
It works.
Mine does not work.
What error you got is it should work
what are you
are getting
or because you are using
a different username,
you might not have access to the table.
Wait, wait, wait, wait
I'm using a different username
and password
that have full privileges privileges.
Mine.
Mine is also not working.
I am also getting this out of idea.
I notice
because I did not create
the aliases
and I tried to use the alias using like.
That's why it was not working.
Let me share the query again.
Try it now.
Recording privileges.
Does it work now?
Well, I didn't create the aliases in here,
and I was trying
to use the aliases in here.
That's why it was not working. Yes.
All right, perfect.
So let's let's learn the types of joins.
There are four types of joins in there.
Join, right, join and left and for enjoy
I think it will be more
clear in here so all in that a adjoin
will only show you that information
that is common in both the tables
that information
should be present in both the tables.
So in the last example you saw,
if I show you, let me
I used a syntax yesterday
to certain that flag
dominant.
And you also wrote that
written so
so I have certainly imported
for Sara to null
so now if I query this again
you guys will see far more to do.
Sara as the MPI ID is null.
So what do you guys think
if now I execute this query,
will I see a salary for Sara?
So now I don't see Sara in here
because the information for this Sara
for MP I.D.
is missing in the person table
and we are using an inner join in here
for inner join.
The information should be available
in both the tables,
otherwise we will not be getting
any of those condition.
Did not name.
Yep. No, you guys don't have to write it.
Even if you guys write
it will not work from your user.
So that's how the inner join works.
Inner join looks for that information
in more to the tables.
If that specific role value
the specific MP ID in
this case is present in employer table
and in person table.
In the case of and then only
we will be getting the results for Sara.
Otherwise if let's say that be implied
that we we have written in
person table if that is not present.
So let's say even if I do this
instead of setting is it to null,
let's say maybe I go for 55
now does this for 55 MP present
inside the employer table.
Let me bring all the API.
This is this present inside
this table guys.
So will I get the results for Sara again
if I execute this query
using the inner join?
No. Again. Why?
Because the 455 is present
inside the person table, but
it is not present in the employee table.
Right.
So again, as you all will not know,
which row
from the employee table belong to the SA
because the MPI that Sara is
using is not present in the implied table.
So information should be pressed in
both the tables
and it should match also.
Okay, that is how school know
which salary which person is earning.
There's how to create the link.
Does it make sense guys?
How in this interview I working
so same
information should be present
in both of the tables.
Otherwise the school will not be able
to create that link
only for Aisha.
It only makes sense for Aisha.
So the impiety that is in here.
So for example,
if I ask you this question,
this 160 is present
inside the employee ID
and this salary associated
with the employer.
It is one 140 taking.
Will any of employees
if I right there, if I execute that duty,
will I see 140 picture
for any of these employees?
No. Why?
Because 160 the employ 8160
None of the employees are using employee.
I live on 60. Right.
And same is the case with 150.
This MPI 150 is present
in tired depressed person table,
but it is not present inside the employer
table again.
So all of these employees again,
they will not be included in the results
and we will not see.
Ali Now are these
the observed in the results are
and no salaries will be displayed
for these employees.
And you guys can also verify
this from here.
You see you don't see those employees.
Why? Because skill is unable
to create the relationship, right?
The values were not present
in both decides.
Okay, so do you guys understand
why why we have like
almost
22 employees,
but the results in our results,
that is only four of the persons, right?
So total employees,
we are 22, but in results two Why?
I only see 12 employees.
Guys Because,
for only these two employees,
there is a perfect match
in both the tables.
This is how the inner join rows.
Yes. No salary for me as a
okay.
So this is how the inner join works.
So inner join only bring the doors rules
for which the information
is present in both the tables.
Is it clear guys
the inner during the working often
not doing
and there should be a separate section
with numbers in cause.
Okay.
Now if you guys have understood the inner
join, it's very very easy to understand.
Be right
during left line and fully join. Yes
they are actually sets.
They are actually sat
behind the scenes under the hood.
All of these functions,
they are implemented using sales
charts from met, if you guys remember.
Yes, you are right.
So what is the difference between dry join
so right to do and sales.
So this is how right you are works.
But if I asked you guys
I have written this right join in here
and there is this table person
and this table employee.
Which table is towards
the right of this right.
Join keyword.
This table is towards the right side
of the joint.
Right
and person table is store to the left.
Now Check of this image,
check this image and tell me in this image
I am getting all the
information from circle B,
while only that
information which is common between A
and B.
So if I ask you
if I ask you if I execute the security.
So even if there is no match
from the employer table,
let me show you the results first.
First.
So this time we have got
14 rows for the inner join.
We were getting 12 rows.
We got water.
These two extra rows in here
for the salary,
one for ticket and the salary nine ticket.
There are no employees
who are earning these salaries.
But still we have
got these two results. Why?
We have got these two results,
this 98 and this 40 again,
because this time
we are using the right to join
this table was towards the right
and this table was towards the left.
Right to join says
right to do and says hey, school
even if there is no match for the table,
that is towards
the right of the right to join keyword.
You know what?
I still want to see that information
even if there is no match,
even if there is no employee
who has the empty already,
140 or 160, it is fine.
You can you can just print out of values.
But I want to see these values.
So right to do and say is
even if there is no match
from the table,
which is towards the right,
I still want all of these employees.
If you find a match displayed
the name of that employee's,
if you don't find a match
display and null value.
But I want all of the rows
to be displayed in the result set.
Yes, it shows the
null values because there are no employees
who are earning 148
or nine ticket or there are no employees
who have employed 8140 okay.
Or 160. Okay.
But because we are using
the right to join in here,
that means even if there is no match
from the employed table,
we will still get the values in here.
But for from the left side,
because there is no match,
there is no person in the persons table
who is on
94, we will be getting a null values.
But right you can say is
it is fine.
I will display all values from the table.
Two words
which is towards the right of this duty.
And let me show you actually,
I am switching the positions of the table,
so I am putting
this person towards the right
and I am putting this employee now
towards the left.
Now, these are these two tables.
So this person is towards the right now.
And if you guys look closely,
we have this empty already, 154
which there is no match now.
So will I see this them
not as easy
after all this time in my dataset,
even though there is no match
because I have switched the positions.
Right.
So if I execute this queries
so you guys will understand it
now more more properly.
So this time as there is here, although us
there did not have any salary right
of the leaves here,
this is early NASIR Zombies here.
Why? Because this time the person table
is towards
the right and the right domain says
even if there is no match
for the table, which is towards the right,
I will still bring the information.
But from the left table,
because there is no match,
there are no salaries
associated with these in place.
So I will simply show null values,
but I will make sure that all
the information is coming from the table,
which is towards right
you guys see there
this time, as will fetch all 22 rows.
There were 22 rows in the person table
and because I am using right join in here
so skewed
is fetching all those 22 results
and for which there is no match.
It is bringing the null
but it is bringing all the values you see.
For Sara we see NULL for all that implies
we see null.
But all 22 and 22 rows have been included
in this check
because we are using the right to join.
Does it make sense, guys?
So inner
join says only bring the back data
which has values in both the tables.
Right.
You and says
bring all the data from the right table
the table
which is towards the right but from left
only bring the matching data
and you guys can now guess
the left to join as well.
So left to join
then you guys guess the output.
If I do the left to join what output
I will get.
So which table is towards the left?
The guys? Yes.
Same as this one.
Yes, same as this one.
Why? Because if we observe closely,
this simpler table was towards the right.
Right.
Which means
bring all the data from employee.
And now because I have switched
the B right down
to left to join and again
this employed is coming towards the left.
So same results as this one.
I just have switched to the position
of tables and of B join as well.
So left and right and they are actually
something very, very similar.
It just depends on which table you are.
You are writing towards the left,
all to our strike.
Although they did, they work the same.
Okay, So again, I see all the information
from the left side,
the employer table,
but only the matching information
from this first name.
Okay.
And if there is no matching information,
we get the null
values.
Does it make sense, guys?
Did I join the left?
Join the inner, join?
They are.
They are very famous
interview questions, by the way.
So if you guys don't understand,
make sure you watch
this section of the video
again, it very important for interviews
and can you guys
guess the full output of join
Yes on both sides
bring the matching data
bring the non matching data,
bring everything
or actually bring everything. Yes.
From both the tables.
Even if there is a match,
even if there is no match,
but the full output of joins
are not supported in my sequel databases.
So you guys can see
we are already getting the error.
How will they
phrase the question on the interval?
They will say what is the difference
between intertwine and right? Join
full out join is not supported in
in my school
but it is supported in Oracle database.
So let me show you the working in Oracle
one. It's
also not in line
with real life practice.
So for the real life practice,
I will be sharing
a very big assignment today with you guys.
It contains almost around,
I guess, 50 questions, 50 queries
that you guys have to write.
So that will that will be more than enough
for your practice to understand the basics
of good work.
And you guys will also
we have family that's got
a deadline is next Sunday
and if you
if you want to tell me about the be
important piece of family I mean,
if you want me to understand the pain of
not talking or not
giving the proper time to your family,
then you should pray.
I should also get a family soon.
Will you give us the rest of the week?
I mean, the interior minister right?
I'm just kidding.
Okay. You guys can take more.
Maybe more than Sunday.
Ministers are very important in
you have a beautiful family
with five kids, learn
a different coding language.
And I understand this once. Once
someone has skills that they don't
live their life from that day.
Right.
The only for their kids
on you five is not true.
Silva
I seen most of the people.
I mean, they don't enjoy it. They don't.
The first priority is their children's
months.
They have the children,
or the first priority is children.
They are above everything.
If they are sick, you cannot
you cannot trust, you cannot sleep,
you cannot work properly.
My poor mom.
Yeah.
Oh, okay.
So let's find out two tables
on which we can write
the full hour doing
is life.
Looking at my mom,
I said to you a good number of years.
Some kids there they are very naughty.
So I have a friend.
He is a single son.
And so they are his parents.
They take a lot of care of them
wherever he goes.
They are always like him and asking him
if everything is okay
and they don't allow him to go on trips
and all that.
One day he got frustrated and then
his dad was saying that he is
the name of us guy who likes you
if you are the only thing that we had.
And he was so frustrated.
He said to his father, Hey, dad,
I didn't ask you to stop after me.
You you can please have their kids.
Their brothers lives completely
flat.
But like
he is
of us are to be here.
So, like.
So let's use the job.
I do not mean
something is pleasant inside the job
Street table.
Yes. And the job? It is also pleasure.
By the way, the best practice is to have
the same column names in multiple tables.
So job history
nurse The nurse use the start date
and let me have it.
This is E for the employees
and for this
so e dot
job D
is equal to two dot.
I have
six siblings
and you have kids and parents.
You feel you have a reason to be happy.
Are we going to learn more about title?
Yes. That assignment that I will share
it contains I think 50% of the queries
you guys will be writing on on Oracle 100.
So my dad didn't have
a job or something like that.
That's why we are so sick.
We have total seven siblings,
so they have to do something right.
They had to do something.
So they thought, Let's have more kids.
I am on number three.
Let me sing Keyword select first.
Oh, so first name is coming
from Employers.
So E Dot First name
Starboard is coming from
the street table. Oh,
I hope the syntax is same
on or properly under.
Let me check this syntax for
we have four girls Go.
God told us that the angels, the animals
and the mountains refuse because then.
Yes, five girls and five boys.
We are ten or actually all of my uncles
and aunts.
They have at least been a It is only my
my family that has seven
all select the select list from the one
who loved to join due to on conditions.
Select first name started from employees.
Pull out the join history
e on.
There is no on keyword.
No there is.
And then the condition
number
and come on the not property
and the validity.
So why do the reward is giving
then someone please
check this index for full
and if you missing
something you.
I think there is something wrong
with the table.
This table is not exist.
Job underscore history, job
and or school history.
Maybe uppercase is it is sensitive.
Here are no it is not.
Just give sensitive
inside to single course.
Oh I was missing
this edge or before the table name
I'm on
so seeing mistakes. Yes.
Now this works.
And now this also work
did not in because again
at our dot.
Yes it also works and you should also.
Oh but I was using a child in here
at me
is instead of this
a child or
the job is student or not job by any
employee's dot job.
I be.
And now you should work.
Hopefully. Yes.
So that this and this is
how we write a full output to join.
So in the outer join you guys will see for
you will see
null values in the start table
and you might also see null values.
It is only bringing the $50 if you guys
might also see null values inside the left
column.
Yes, let me share it.
But it will make sure that each and every
row from both the tables is
is included in
the results set.
So inner join only brings the information
which is presently in both the tables.
Right.
Join bring all the information
from right table
and only the matching information
from left table
Left to join Bring all the information
from left to table
only the matching information
from divide table,
while the full output of join
and bring everything from both the tables.
And by the way, this full hour to join
it is not that widely used.
That's why some of the databases,
they don't even support it.
But this inner one
and this right and left one,
you guys might be using these
on your jobs.
Is it clear, guys, the how joins work
and what are the differences
between inner right and left join
so this is the syntax but
again I would not recommend that
you guys use this syntax
because again you might face
problems on different databases.
So always try to use that rare condition
whenever you have variety in join.
But for the left and right join us.
You guys can use this syntax
and this is again the same syntax.
Okay, some tasks for you.
Left, right. Join syntax,
syntax, syntax.
All again, a very,
very,
very famous interview question itself.
How do we choose
which table we put on left?
Right now you can fill up any table
on the left, the right.
Yes, it is up to you.
If you are putting a table towards right,
then you can maybe use the left to join
or the right to join.
So it totally depends on you.
If you are planning to use left to join
or right to join.
And then broadly the parents which table
you are planning to put on
to work, to diet and towards the left,
definitely this part of the requirement
it will be coming from your business
requirements.
Like for example, if the business says
that business needs all the rows
from the employed table
and if you are planning to use the right
join, then you will be placing the
employed table day.
Right.
Which question is popular interview?
Question So we have written all the
questions in, in the form of the document
and we have also written
all of the answers.
And if you guys understand the concepts
which are important.
So with respect to your job interview,
it will be very, very easy
for you to understand, to
remember those answers for a longer time.
So that's why I emphasize more on
some of the possible
if honestly, it's not clear enough.
But I need to review this record
if honestly,
it's not clear enough,
but I need to reveal the record.
The left and right joins us for one.
So what is not clear,
So let me bring it to back.
So say, for example,
tell me what is not here.
Let's let's make sure that it is clear.
Is it clear the inner join
the inner join?
Is it clear of the inner part?
And the last starts from the inner.
So in the it is not clear
how in the joint is working.
How many of you don't understand
how the inner dwelling works?
Uh, yes, it is fine if let's say
two or 4 hours don't understand it,
but if let's say 50% of you
don't understand it,
then maybe we
I need to give different examples
or need to repeat this will
bring only all those from both tables.
Yes, you'll get that. You are right.
If it is inner, join
and everything is clear.
So what time it is for you?
I'm sorry.
Is it like two or 3 a.m.
in the morning for you?
The sunrise.
And what did you eat last for 30 PM or.
It's fine then.
It's fine If you don't understand.
Yes, you will watch this video
when you get some good sleep
in the morning.
I'm just kidding.
If there are other students
I can repeat reproduce,
I'm just kidding.
Now the fun part will start after this.
In general, as school looks simple
but needs a greater tension
not to make mistakes because it does
not give us the way we used.
See from daylight.
Yes, you guys are right.
So this is
self to join.
Let me
let me give you a requirement and let's
see if you guys write actually for that.
So now you guys have
understood that.
So I have only showed you
if a general question
do database engineer
to rely on any guideline criteria
upon selecting a primary key
for individual databases with schema. Yes.
And B, actually
sometimes it takes a lot of meetings
and debates to choose the primary key.
Yes. DB is architects, senior persons.
They all sit together to decide
what should be
the primary key off the table.
It is something very, very important
because based on things,
you guys will be creating the relationship
between different
tables.
Yes, it is not an easy task.
Yes, you are right.
Yes, you are nice.
So if I had secured this
at a starting price table
and if you guys
pay attention,
this manager I d so up
till now I have told you that
if a primary key exist
in a different table,
it is called a foreign key.
Right.
This is your understanding.
A primary key from one table.
If it is exist in another table,
it is called differently.
But what if a primary key is present
inside
same table as a foreign key?
If you have something like this,
then it is
used to create a self adjoins.
So for example, this employer already
that you see in here,
the same employer already is also present
as manager already
inside the exact same table.
And why it is present in here.
It is present
because by looking at the idea in here.
So let's say for example,
if I want to find out
who is the manager of Nina,
I can check the I.D.
from here.
So now the manager of Nina is a person
whose ID is 100.
So I can look back to this column.
And I know that Steven
is the manager of Nina.
If I want to find out
the manager of David,
I need to go in here.
It says the manager is a person
with an ID 103.
So I will come back in here and I now know
Alexander is the manager of David.
So this time what is happening? Roster.
There is no roster then here.
So what is happening in here? First, the
primary guy is present as
a foreign key inside the same table
and now we need to find out a way.
So say if I ask you to write a query
guys, let's say
I want all the first names
of the employees and dear managers.
Can you guys do that?
Can you guys tell me
who is the manager of Let's
Steven, what about rules
is Alexander
but so manually we can
we can find out the managers very easily.
But what if I ask you to write a query
to find out to be managers?
Of all the employees
that are present in this table?
By the way, who is the manager of Steven?
Is he reporting to anyone or he is the CEO
of this company?
Self-managed yet
he is not reporting to anyone.
Right. Okay.
So can you guys drive the duty in which I
you bring the first name of the employee's
and the first names of their managers?
Can you guys think of a duty
just so let me show you the
what if, guys, What if I tell you that?
Can you copy this and bring it in here?
What if I tell you
that it is possible in school
to create multiple copies
of the same table?
What if I tell you I can do this?
I can create a copy,
I can call it anything.
I can call it.
Let's say
table one.
I can call it. Let's see.
I can create a copy
I can call acceptable to the if I
if I tell you
how to create a copy of the same table.
Can you guys now write a theory
to bring the first name
of the employees and the first name
my of their managers?
So now it is simple, right?
Because you guys have been doing
the same thing in here.
So you will simply say
table two dot name,
table one dot first name and you will join
B these two tables
based on this idea from table
and this manager already from table
two, right?
So let me tell you how to create copies.
And once you have two tables,
you guys already know how to link
to tables to bring the information
from both the tables.
Right?
So let me if I
it's very simple.
You just copy
and paste the same table twice
and you will give different aliases
to those statements.
Now, I will create two copies
of this table.
It will create a copy
and it will call it as empty
and it will create another copy
and it will call it as amend.
Okay, So now
I want to
link these two
tables using the joint.
Right.
So I will say we're e MP.
So from MP,
should I bring the employer I.D.
or should I bring the manager ID?
I want to get the first name
of the employee.
Should I use the employer ID Oxford,
I use the manager ID, employer I.D..
Right.
So I will say MP dog.
Employer I.D.
is equal to.
And the second copy that I have created,
which I have called as M
Benji from M
and I will bring this manager ID, right?
So I will say
M and G
not many of I.D.
And I am also bringing
two first names, right?
The first first name
I want to bring from the MP table.
And the second
first name I want to bring from the
manager David
Select MP First name Mendy First name
Mendy underscore underscore first name
from.
I don't employ that MP or employed
as amended
where I think as given is also not
supported in order. Yes,
let me try to
that duplication is confusing
needs attention.
So let me actually copy this.
Let me explain it from here.
So I have created two copies.
One I have called as MP,
the other one I have called as M.
And so focusing here today,
it will be played on on the.
And what I have done, I am saying
select MP
not first name, right
first under school name.
So it will bring the Stevan Nino legs.
Alexandra from here.
And then I am saying
join these two tables
based on the idea and I am saying MP
not IED.
But what is what is it called?
Let me copy this query.
Actually
Silva,
how can we display this
without the mistral?
This is,
you know,
this is not what I want in a in a single
or is it possible
I have to margin these columns right.
How can I merge the columns in a
in and
view. Mm.
And then
after the view
what the and center.
Where is that merging center that exit.
Go back.
Go back where.
Okay. Form
and go here or the
middle area that Oh margin center
of the operation
will cause some models to enlarge.
Do you wish to
grab.
I need to select this one as well
or like this or here
we will finally.
Okay.
So what I am saying in here
I am saying MP dot
first name,
which means bringing the first names.
These first names
from this employed table
and bringing the first names
from the menu table.
Right. These first names.
But how we should link these to
we should link to these two
based on this information
big the employ ideas
these these employ ideas from here
and check if that imply I.D.
is also present inside the manager
ID column.
Okay.
So for this
Steven school will check this ID right
and then it will check
if all we have written
if we have written in reverse.
Right.
It should not be like this.
It should.
It should be.
You guys
didn't tell me all that means you guys
do not understand it at all.
We should say MP.
I need the manager
and M and I'd like
you guys.
See you guys didn't pay attention
because you see,
for Steven we are getting this manager
Get out in here.
We should not be getting any manager
for Steven right? No.
Or the order matter
the way we join for Steven,
we should not be getting any manager
right.
But Steven should be as a manager
for others.
Now Disconnect. Correct.
Steven is the manager of Nina.
Not now. The results are correct.
Okay,
so first let me explain how this looks.
Looking.
Are you guys feeling sleepy
or just want to run out of run
from this class?
I am half asleep.
If I can sleep.
Okay. This is the last thing promised.
We will learn the next things
in in the next classes.
Okay.
I will also repeat this for me.
It's 7:51 a.m..
We need to be sleepy.
Good morning. Good morning.
All right, guys.
So me quickly explain.
So what we are saying in here
that we will bring the updated during
the what we are saying in here.
Actually this is important.
If you guys want,
we can learn it in the next class.
This is something important
for your interviews as well.
Yes. Okay.
Let's do this in the next class.
Yeah,
I will try to write the wrong query again
in the next class.
Let's see if you guys can find out
if I again or they don't
give me a.
By the way, how was the class today, guys?
Was it hard to understand
what was the topic we are learning?
Yes, self enjoying
it is called self drive.
By the way, guys, do one more thing.
Actually, I don't want
to teach you this on the
syntax database.
So there is a free service
which will allow you
to create your databases.
You will be able to create papers,
you will be able to create columns.
The primary key is foreign keys.
You will be able to delete the data.
So it is called my
school hosting.
I want you to create your user
names in here
so that you guys can practice
the delete things as well.
This is dealing guys.
Please make sure every one of you
actually posted it in the
course announcements.
Question
So from the course announcement channel,
guys, make sure you go to this website.
You click on Start my free account.
Do you guys see this page?
Can someone give me your email
so that I can?
I have already used my all of my emails
to show you
how to do this for previous pages.
Can someone share please your email
so that I can show you how to do that? If
okay.
Good position. Wow.
Very intuitive email medium.
So enter
your emails in here and click on register.
So Mohammad
My skill guys have sent you a password
and send that password in person in person
and to me don't share that password in
life was just general.
Otherwise everyone
will be using your email password and
check your email.
You should get an email with a password.
This one.
The email
that you have given to me, this one
We will not let last batch
you did the same in that person.
Shared the password with me
and everyone use this backup.
This of a
can I open it in front of class
that would contain
any personal information
if you do not maybe some links
from those you you get you guys
get those phishing emails
or articles and someone's
someone lost
some money in some kind of other country
and they don't have any relatives
and now they want you to give that money.
Oh, I God,
the password is wrong.
But can you please confirm this?
Not anymore.
I still.
Guys, those
I rarely check my emails.
Only the university is
why is my age on the by they you my name.
You don't look like 41 right?
I thought you will.
You are like 25 maybe.
Or 26.
I'm just kidding.
Please don't take it seriously.
Okay.
So you guys should get an email,
something this.
I thank you for registering with
Freescale. Blah, blah, blah.
Please use this link
to complete the registration.
Have you guys got this email?
Okay, click on that link.
So Mohammad,
you have already created the password
using click
by clicking on this link. Right?
The first password that you send to me.
Oh, okay. So guys,
have you guys created your passwords?
Oh okay.
Okay, okay, okay, perfect, Perfect.
So now you guys can enter the password
that you have created
and you can click on logging.
Thank you for reducing blah, blah, blah.
So we we can provide
and now select the country so that
they created the database near to you
so that you guys don't face any legs.
Select the country from here
in which you are right now
and then click on complete my registration
and then you should see this page.
Yes. Creating database.
Actually, it's way, way harder.
But they have made this super, super easy.
Just will start.
Otherwise, if you are creating
your database on your local computer,
it's very hard to.
So you have to select the
nearest location.
Mohammad
Are you near to North America?
West, North America, East Europe,
Asia, South America.
What should select
East?
Okay, select the nearest location
and click on same location
and then click on this button
that says Start a new database.
So now they have created
a database for you.
So this is the IP of your database.
This is the database name,
this is the database user,
and the password will be created in full
seconds and it will be sent on your email.
So let's go back to my skill workbench
and click on this home button and.
Let's configure this new database
that we have just created
so that we can write
and execute queries on this step base.
So click on the
splash button in here guys,
and for the IP copy, this
will find out my espeon.
So enter this information in here
and it will.
And then the username is this
Well, I'm
not going to be able to see the password.
So instead root to enter this.
And it will also take some time to
to this website
to be online now.
But you can also log in right now to see
again please.
Now, unfortunately, we cannot do it again
for now.
Just in just two pieces of information,
the database,
the password will take some time.
And once you get password, you just need
to enter the password in here
and you will be a you will be connected
to this database that have just created.
Let me try a bit of fresh.
Yes. Now check your email moment.
Now check your email.
Yes, you guys can name it.
Let's say maybe
free school.
Check your email.
The guy is for the passwords.
But if you have received the password,
send it to me.
Please see me.
You guys have also destroyed
the server of my super database.
There's a lot of people
trying to sign off.
At the same time,
you have to have someone
to save the password.
Oh, great, great, great moment.
Maybe we should wait for a few minutes.
We need to do DDoS attacks than you.
Yes. Now you guys are good, and the next
things I will teach you in the next class.
Those who have created the connections,
you guys can leave.
So once you receive the password, you
just need to enter that password in here
and that's it.
You guys are going to go,
okay, so I have received the password
I click on.
Okay, click on connection.
No moment.
This is not the correct password.
You have sent me the account number.
So suddenly the password,
if you have received it
incompatible nonstandard server word
and blah blah blah can be established
by some of my.
Okay, it's fine.
You can ignore this and click on.
Okay.
Now if you guys click on free school
and now you guys have access to a database
on which guys can do anything.
Creating new tables, create
deleting the data, creating new functions,
procedures, creating primary gives foreign
keys, everything.
I will teach you how to do everything
at least once in the next class,
how to delete tables, rename papers,
how to delete that, modify
the data and all that.
Yes, you are the admins
and all for this database,
but please don't do this on your jobs.
The user name is database name.
This is the user name. I share this one.
Yes, I think it is
same as your database. No.
All right, guys, take some rest
and I will see you on Saturday.
What is the host name?
This is the host name.
All right, guys.
Bye bye. Take care.