Okay, we are
recording now.
Are you feeling better?
Good.
To be honest, I am feeling sad and happy.
And at the same time,
I don't know how to express this.
And I am feeling so many things.
I am also seek
a happy
because I will be engaged on 17th of this
and sad because my sisters
and my mom took me
for shopping like three times already
and they are asking to go one more time
and then I have to go the.
I have to go shopping for my future wife
as well on Wednesday.
So I don't know whether I should be happy
or sad.
I have already spent my one last one month
birthday.
Let's
see how far and still be major things.
They are still there,
like the ring bar to be ready.
Send them in the ceremony. They are apart.
They are dressed for shopping for the mom
and the future wife.
And for me.
They make you become poor.
So if anything, I should be happy.
You see? Yes, I am happy.
I don't.
I will be numbers and you will be okay.
Okay, Bill.
I will try my best.
And you are glowing.
And you are not sad
when you have babies,
you will spend hundreds or.
Okay, Let's not have babies.
Oh, they are so, so many traditions.
I mean, it's very, very complicated
here in in some continent to get married.
And there are so many
things that you have to take
year off.
How many people attend the wedding?
Oh, my God.
It's like sometimes 300 plus people.
300 plus people on average,
250 or 300 on average.
I mean, it's like the whole community
or all your relatives, each
and every person that you know
in your in your life,
they will attend to your marriage.
How do you feel?
300 people, people
they just spent their whole life
earnings on on their daughter's marriage,
especially here in subcontinent.
Believe me, it's very,
very tough for the parents.
My first of our 600 plus.
Yes, it's totally possible.
I think I am expecting like 500
plus at least in my in my marriage,
at least 500.
You mine was by 400 plus.
So I have already starting now
you guys will understand why
Why I was asking for calls from Alexey.
I will be needing
a lot of cows and chickens
in the
near future.
And some people came to my wedding
that I never saw in my life.
Oh, yes. There. There.
Most probably there.
There were these to learn
the students,
they tried to just go and everything
that is
so there that they can have good food.
If can you share pictures
videos of family? Yep.
Should definitely.
I will be sitting
free food and feeding students
first of all.
Yeah.
And they will just like so naturally
that no one will
even will realize
that they are not invited.
They have special schools
and all the dates in their calendar.
They have special contacts with the
with those guys who or who have
these big halls
in which we do these kind of ceremony.
So they are telling them
to watch their work.
I mean, what you guys can
be in someone else's marriage
to have food that reminds them
interrelated. Yes.
It's correct. It's
people don't do that in USA.
I got married in USA.
In USA, you pay for each city.
It's expensive.
So I like this idea
very much in especially in Pakistan.
So all of the guest
who are coming in the marriage
and especially the people
that are in your community, if you are
if you are living in a village
or in a city.
So they kind of contribute a small amount
on each marriage
and they kind of writing down.
So and let's say if I am getting married,
I will be my friends,
my family, because they are
they all will be paying a small amount.
And actually that is not a small amount.
When accumulated, it will be a big amount.
And when they will be getting married,
I will do the same.
And they kind of keep record of this.
For some of the families,
they don't even feel the burden at all.
If for all the expense, it's very,
very easy for them.
They just have to finalize the dates
and do some other stuff
in here. All
right, guys.
So let's start with class.
I think we have enough people now. Yes.
I think it's a very good idea. Oh,
we started discussing the joined.
Hello. I'm our.
Okay, let's let's let me check.
Oh, good.
Fine number.
We have not started
like all
from assets that are employees. Okay
and check the employer
state best for practice are
employee status.
You know
that employer state proves
industry status.
Here we have the employer status.
Okay, so
see everything.
So let me also do this
over here.
Employee status is not so.
I'm not What is wrong with discovery?
I see this status for the employees.
It differs every time.
Not possible.
It is not possible. Aha.
What do you mean
it differs every time? Wow.
Yeah.
For example, can you check it
without an ordinal?
Yes. Why not?
You mean the count is increasing
or decreasing every time for the employer
status column?
Sorry.
Yes, I see the null values first. Now.
And you mean now?
I don't see the normal values.
Oh, okay. Okay.
This is because so much focus in focus.
And everyone, please focus in here.
The school is returning us
only the first 2000 rows in here.
And if you guys focus in the message tab,
it is saying
that although I have written this query
in here,
my skill workbench is modifying this query
actually to this
this so that we only fetch
in the first 2000 rows
school workbench is doing this to optimize
the bandwidth usage so that even if
if let's say
there are 1 million rows in a table
or 1 billion rows
and if you execute discovery
skill,
we'll have to do a lot of competition
computation
to bring all those 1 billion rows.
So by default, skill limits
the amount of data that we test or fact
so that the queries are optimized.
Does it make sense now?
So now I have a task
small task for you Search on the internet
how to fetch all the data
from from a table.
So Amit has written this guilty.
And he was confused
that when he executes discovery
he only get the null results in here.
So but some of the values are not null
and the data is there also.
So why he was not getting that data.
So this confused, emotive was not getting
this checked out because by default
at the max
only shows you only 1000 process
so that if there
are, let's say
1 billion rules in the table
and if someone accidentally arrived
security
as school has to do a lot of computation
it will take a lot of time
and network bandwidth
to display all those 1 billion rows.
So by default would be
that is limited in here
and you can change in this default
setting to get all the data
or maybe getting, let's say,
instead of 1000 to get
10,000 or 50,000 rows.
So I want you to start on the Internet,
how to bring, let's say,
all the rows from a table.
So I have this problem that the my school
workbench by default
only fetches the first 2000 rows.
And I want you to do a research on Google
to bring all the rows from this table.
I spent more than 30 minutes last night
with that.
No, no, no.
So, guys, if you if something is bothering
you for, let's say,
more than 10 minutes,
then there might be something
that you are missing
from a concept perspective.
So you should definitely send a message
in this or channel or contact me
so that we don't waste in this place
this time.
Your time is very important.
Why it does not show pagination.
Yes. Or one. This is also a great idea.
Maybe you should build a skill
workbench to
have those pagination options
in the bottom
so that we can click on those options
to bring on.
The next piece of data
is some of the software.
They do support it,
but as you guys know, the best software
that was developed by humanity
after Windows 11, that's why
we don't have this option in here.
So guys, quickly start on the Yes, in BHP.
Michael, it works. Yes, you are right.
Many other software, they also support it.
So guys, quickly do a research
and tell me if it is possible
to fetch all the rules
in my skill workbench, how to fetch
all the rules from a table
in my skill workbench.
And I also want your queries
that you are typing on the Google
to find out the solution for this.
And it should not take more than 2 to 3
minutes.
Say again please. So right now
I am executing this duty and
skill workbench useful
only showing me first 2000 draws.
I want to get all the rules
from this table for this column.
How can I do that?
You have to search this on the internet.
Select all from backgrounds
where X type is equal to you.
Select all me and select all columns.
We have X type
you means we are any row with the column.
X type is equal to you.
So you'll get by saying if we put this
we're X die.
If we put this x type is equal to you,
we should be getting all the rules.
Okay,
So let's see.
Like this, you'll get to
where X type is equal to you.
Unknown column.
Column X type in the where clause.
It means from wherever
you have copied your code.
And they had this column
X type in that, in that, in that table.
And they're all this query for that table
you just literally copied
and pasted everything in here.
Okay.
And now, because this column is
not available in here, it is not working.
Guys, please be creative.
You can easily change this limit
by going to my skill workbench added for
viewed it as a yes.
So the only the sad thing
in the excluded workbench
that we can change to change this limit.
But I don't want to change it this limit
guys, I don't want to change this limit.
Is it possible to write a query itself?
Maybe so.
If we go inside b my little workbench,
if we go inside of the edit
and then preferences
and then ask purist.
We are not asking to disturb
you. Re editor Max
in Max number of thirds 50
And here we have limit rules.
Count is equal to 1000
and then we have this option
to limit the rules.
So if I do that
and if I execute this again,
this time it has 5 to 6920 earlier.
So now and not
you should see all the data in here.
C 17 and I want to do 165 or whatever,
but guys,
please change that starting again to
1000 or maybe 5000 or something like that
so that your code is there.
Don't take too much time.
Maybe 5000 is more than enough.
Any other questions, guys?
Any other issues that you guys might faced
during your assignment
or write by writing any other query
or something that might be bothering you?
Is there anything else
that can also benefit, let's say,
the remaining of the class?
I have a question on about joins.
Yes. Alone, please.
Output of doing not used actually.
You're so very very clear
that you will be using our project.
But still. Yes.
Please ask is it right or left?
It is both left and right. Both sides
out remains to give the data
from both side.
Yes, it is full some of the databases.
Okay.
So yes, let me clarify
this also some of the databases
I actually I wanted to tell in this class.
So let me bring the
duty.
So you see, I have written this inner
join in here.
Nice. Please focus in here.
Even if I remove this inner keyword,
I still get the results.
So again,
depends on all the databases
which keywords
given itself.
They can also be slightly different
from the database or back to base.
That's why
I told you guys that I never use these.
Join the syntax.
I repeatedly told you that I never prefer
I never prefer these join syntax
because from database for database
you might have you might have to
just use inner join
or sometimes you might just write, join.
Sometimes you write out.
Sometimes you write full out or sometimes
you write full output of join it.
There are so many variations.
So many variations.
But this syntax with the weird clause
that I wrote,
I told you that it is the same syntax.
I don't know where I wrote that,
but for example, this one, right?
I can easily replace that
to join syntax with.
We had a clause,
so this is what I recommend
because it will work on all the databases
shows here.
Then they are not same alone.
It again
depends from database to database.
So which one is not same.
Full pool join and
that is which one?
Which one of them are not same
in them.
Join and
join or which one
exclusive and inclusive
right to join.
Inclusive and exclusive
Select all from right to join
Select All from right to join.
Oh no, no, no.
Also not focus on the queries
that they are writing
in above.
They are using the real condition
where B is null and below.
They are not using that query.
Otherwise the syntax for the right
try to join
it is same.
You can also modify your this
to achieve these results.
The right keyword.
It will give you the same results.
Oh also is
the right and left joins
they I saw my questions for interview
they're asking about output
and in doing so it's just full and in a
yes they are same
they are saying there is no such thing
as inclusive output of join
and non inclusive output.
At least I have not seen this.
I have not started this.
But if this thing still exist,
you guys think if it is exist,
I will do my research.
Maybe they have added something
in in later
submergence,
but I have not seen this in my experience.
I have not started in my engineering.
I have not seen this in my four years
of development.
Let me know.
Do do your research.
If you
if you feel that this is something that
we should
know, I will do my research after that.
If we don't mention do I?
And instead use where clause.
How is getting all the way to join
to perform?
It knows from this condition
you'll need to
it knows from this condition
and this is what I recommend.
Otherwise you guys will be confused.
We will be wasting a lot of time
on your jobs.
Some websites also said that output outer
join it right and left to join non.
This is not correct.
Also guys when looking for knowledge
always look for the sources
which are authentic.
Either consult a book
or either read the documentation.
I can also make website
and I can write whatever I want.
Right?
So make sure that
from wherever you guys are starting,
if wherever you are having the practice,
that source is authentic.
Otherwise you guys will be confused,
will be wasting a lot of time on your jobs
and you guys might also be
confused in your interviews,
books,
documentation,
or if you are looking for something else,
make sure that they have
at least good reputation on the internet.
Sorry.
Or you can always send me that source
from where you guys are referring.
Maybe they might have written something
in a different context,
and because you guys might not
that might not know
that concept, context or the history
that might also confused you in there.
So always
tell me if something is confusing.
Okay.
So we were discussing
about the joints, right?
The joints, as I told you, they are also
some of their databases.
They might just write it
as joint in a joint.
They are all the other names as well.
So the things which are not universal,
which
I will not be focusing on those things,
these kind of things,
they might work on one database
and might not work on other databases.
So my priority will be to teach you
that stuff,
which is universal and can be used on
almost all the databases.
And if something is
if something might differ,
I will tell you that it can differ.
So some of the databases,
they also call them these joints
differently.
So these two, they they
they are kind of important.
And I hope you guys have understood
is there anyone who has some
kind of confusion with the right to join
or the left to join?
Right means whichever table what you are
writing towards the right of this keyword.
Bring all the data from that table
are whether there is a match
or there is no match.
But from the table
which is towards the left,
only bring the rows which have a match.
And this left is actually same
because if we just change
the placement of cables from here to here,
it can
we can easily achieve the same results
that we are achieving with the left joint.
So if you have understood
actually one of them, you have understood
both of them.
It is there
anyone who is confused about this? No.
So did you guys do some kind of richer
research on self
joint?
No, research on self joins were very,
very important.
It's very, very important
with respect to your interviews.
So let me start it again from scratch
so that our regular life database
are tied to me
as a very good example
for this healthy joint.
So let me bring that.
I did what I forget.
What was it now?
It's fine. Yes.
When we look at something for the first
time, we we can easily forget that
it says it happens
when it does self screen
or something like that.
Okay.
But I think after you guys solve your
exercises, the assignments, by the way,
are you guys having a hard time
solving that assignment that I shared?
I wrote a lot of questions over there.
Are they easy, hard or
what are your
certainties tend to answer.
I think those questions,
and some of them are hard,
confusing and left with.
To ask you.
I will share this solution
with all those questions.
Don't worry.
And even if you guys still have questions
after I have shared the solution,
we will discuss those questions
as well in the class.
Yes, it will take a lot of time.
Actually.
You guys will be seeing
pretty much same table
names and column names.
And this is also a part of the good job
to finding the column names
inside those table names.
And then writing this blog
that the deadline is Sunday.
So that's why I created that.
Have you guys are are all the questions
that you have solved they belong
to my skill database
are some of them also belong
to the article one
oracle?
Okay, that will be good
because this database is
kind of shared between all the batches.
So time to time they kind of keep on
adding and diluting the data.
So it's good identity part
with Oracle first.
Okay.
And so all right, guys,
let's start with the self.
Join.
So previously we learned that
there can be two tables, right?
Table one
and table two.
And because we are discussing
the relational databases,
we have primary keys.
So it will, let's call it Prime Key two
and let's call it primary key one.
So in relational databases,
how we create relations, whatever
that is stored inside this primary table,
if we have to create a link
between table one and a table two role.
So let's say we have stored one,
two, three, four.
So let's say this table contains
the personal information
and this table contains
the employment information.
So I have stored, let's say
first name in here, last name in here,
but the salary information is stored
inside of this table, right?
So now I have to tell that the let's say,
first employee is John.
I have that the salary that I have stored
in here, let's say 200 K
this 100 K a salary belongs to John.
So how can I do that? Right.
So let's say this is also rule number one.
So I have stored prime even in here
the first name I have stored in here
and I want to store this information
and the 100 year
salary belongs to this employee
which is stored at room number one.
So how can I do that?
Everyone, please respond.
How can I do that?
Actually, give me one woman Two days.
Let me let me show you a
nearly real example.
So I have this
person table.
Give me one moment.
I have column first
name, last name.
This is a primary key.
So I have strawberries that are one.
John.
Mike I have another table which is
employer table.
It has primary key.
It has salary.
Primary key is one.
Salary is 100. Here.
So this is one table.
And this is let's say
another table.
Okay, How can I bring the borders?
Silver like this, All borders open.
Great.
Sorry for my border skill skills.
So I want to tell
that I want to create this relationship.
Can you zoom? Yes.
Is it readable now?
So how can I tell?
How can I store this information that
why I am so bad
at trying things know about non border
only border or
this area
borders?
Yeah, looks are still this
but I need extra.
How can I let this
of finally.
So what it works
for Oracle that we are practicing
now for current assignment.
Yes so how can I store
how can I link to this information
that this 100 year salary
actually belongs to John
so I can
I can create another column in here right.
I can create another column.
I can call it, let's say
let me call it
empty Iodine store.
Okay. Eight.
I can store this
non M, E
and B I can store this e mp i I.D.
inside of this table and I can store
exactly number one in here.
Now, everyone who looks at this table
and if he or she wants to find out
the information
related to employment,
he can refer to this
sorry, this number one,
he can go inside this table
and he
can look for this salary information.
Today, I will teach you how to create
columns, how to create tables,
how to put the inside column,
almost everything, don't worry.
So, guys, does it make sense
how I created this relationship?
I created a same column
and the column name can be different,
and I stole a piece of information
from this table inside this table.
And now whenever
we need to link to these two tables,
you guys can read
this piece of information.
You can go inside this table
and you can link the piece
of information
that is stored inside the employer table.
So this is how we create the drawings.
Actually. So
now so in this part of the job
will be done already for you.
You guys don't need to do this. Yes.
So can you guys tell me,
what do we call this thing?
What do we call this thing?
Is it
primary key, foreign key table column?
What is it?
Is it foreign key? How do we know?
Because the prime key,
if that is stored inside
the same table, would have to be.
Usually we all should be primary key.
But the same thing is also
in another table
that contains the same information
that is called the foreign key.
So this E and B ID it must be a primary
E in any of the tables.
Okay,
so this is what we learn to till now.
But what if what if this
same primary e from this table is,
is it stored inside
the same table as the foreign key?
Then we knew that this self joins.
So you guys understand
two different tables
from one table primary key
existing in another table.
It is called foreign key. Right.
But it is also possible
that this same primary key inside the same
table can also be can also exist
inside the same table as foreign key.
And if we have this relationship,
then we need to write big duties
with the help of self joints.
Then we use this self adjoins.
If we have to bring the data
from those type of tables.
Now, now let me show this table to you.
So this table in the
Oracle database,
if you guys observe carefully,
oops, this employee I.D.
is the primary key inside of this table
right?
Looking exactly.
Let me know, guys, if it is readable.
I think we can close this out as well.
Is it better?
Maybe I can delete some dirty.
I could not really? No.
Okay.
So I was saying
this is the primary.
Right?
And guys, one more thing.
Can I just tell by looking at the data
if that column is a primary,
you're not going to tell that.
Can I do that?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
You guys are wrong.
I can insert in that to in such a way
that will always look unique.
I can.
I can do that.
Yes. If you want to really check
if something is a primary key or not,
you should check the schema.
You should check the schema.
So for example, if we go
inside of the asset
you are in below table.
Oh, actually we don't need.
So you will see with every column
you will see this chart
and this the speaker will be written
with the column name
that is confirming
that this is the primary key.
This is also a primary key.
So this is how we are 100% sure.
Right.
So engineers, they never guessed things.
They actually do the right thing
to find out
the piece of information
that they are discussing or looking at.
You see, this is the primary.
So we cannot just tell
by looking at the data.
We can guess at mix.
So in here
I have joked this came under there.
I know.
So this is the primary in here.
Okay, This is the primary.
But if if you guys observe carefully
this same information
is also present.
And this is also I know
from schema, okay,
I am not just looking merely at the data.
I know from schema that this same key
is existing in here as well.
Today.
I will also show you
how to create primary keys and foreign
keys, how to create this relationship
in schema actually,
although you guys will not be doing it.
But still I will show you
so that for sure you guys know
how to create them
and how these things work.
So actually let me show you.
I think
you guys see this.
He already started sending me addresses.
Oh my God,
I am like this.
Hey, I bet
he will be very, very happy with me.
He will always be mad at me.
Okay, Poor me.
Let me show you
from this schema.
Yeah.
He is my primary female.
You guys check this page.
You got an opening for you
or is it only me?
So this is the schema, guys.
This is the schema.
And if you guys look carefully
for the employ already table,
it says primary e of implies table.
Okay.
This is how I know
if it is a prime or not.
And then if you look for the manager
the column in here
it says manager Ardi of employee
has a same domain
as manager already in department
stable foreign aid to employ
IED see foreign key to employ
I column of employee's
table useful for reflexive domains
and connect to buy queries.
So they are they are also this is all and
they are also the types of self domains.
So from schema, I know that these things
are related to each other.
And before you start writing your duties,
I will highly encourage you
to check out the schema of that table.
Okay.
Same that
I speak, but under different column name.
Yes. And I'll be.
That's why
we need to look at the schema yesterday's.
So with time
you will also be able to judge things
with your experience.
But you you you never know there
there might be a legendary developer
or Libya who might have written anything
just like that
although it's very very companies
they do follow
a very high standard of
things to write the column names.
And for example,
they will never write this underscore ID
If something is not a primary,
they will only write this ID
if something is a primary key
or if something is very, very important
for that paper. Is that mean foreign?
He can be something else,
but not always know It will always be.
You can do that.
You can just create any column
to be a foreign key body.
You should never do that.
You should always refer to a primary key
as a foreign key in another table.
It it's a very bad practice.
It can lead to many,
many problems later on.
Because remember, guys, once
this schema is created
and once it has been populated
with the data
then modifying the schema or the table,
it will cost you a lot.
It will be very, very expensive.
So be careful when, although you guys
will not be doing it, but
maybe later on, once you become managers
or team lead,
you guys will definitely be participating
in these kind of decisions.
So be careful if you are planning
to use something for is,
make sure that you are at least
spending days to design that thing.
So this implied the primary key,
which is also present
inside the same table as sorry,
inside the same table as the foreign key.
Also, now I can look at this information
just like that.
Like, for example,
I can look at the many variety of legs.
It is 100 and I can
then check this in for the employer.
I need four legs is one or one or two.
I go inside this column,
I check the manager ID all flex is 100.
I then again search the key hundred inside
this table to find out about the manager
of the legs.
Right.
It looks easy if we do it manually. Right.
Can you guys find the manager of let's say
maybe Nancy,
who is the manager of Nancy,
and you guys tell me.
So to find out the manager, I have to go
and check the manager variety,
which is one or two.
Then I again will
I will do a result in here
to find out the manager
and I can find this out from Nina.
So what we are doing,
we are referring to a column
inside the same table
as foreign key and as primary key. Right?
So the same information,
both the primary keys and before on keys,
they are actually presented
inside a single table.
So previously they were present
in a two different tables
and you guys were easily able
to write this to join those two tables.
But how can we do that
if we have only one table?
So the solution is
we create two copies of the same table
and we give them different names.
It is possible in a school
in actually all the that I believe
we call them aliases,
and once we have two tables,
then you guys already know how to link
the information between two tables.
Right?
If I create two copies
of these tables,
then you guys already know how to do that.
So that's what we will be doing.
And then this
this this approach is called a self join.
This approach is called a self doing.
So let's say, for example,
if I go to school
workbench, well,
why it is slaughtering
All right.
Oops looks better place.
It's always slow.
I think it's too much slower today for me.
It's all the time with the floor.
Okay. Well, guys, it is free. Okay.
It's it is fine.
So. So let's say I want to
find out the information of the employee
and your manager.
So index, I won't do it all.
So we say that it's in effect now.
And then you can also tell your fellows
what is are due to us.
Do you guys know what is a due loss?
Oh, so you'll get that
if there are 100 100 people
in a room which are calling your name
and you are in the center of the room,
and if, let's say from your family,
who is also in the room
or actually is a true caller
who who really wants to talk to you,
and if they are under 2000 people
in a room, they're not also calling you
at the same time
again and again and again.
Can you hear me?
Actual real person
who really needs your attention.
So that is doors in computers, Computers.
They have a limited capability
of entertaining the requests per second.
If actual good users
who really want to use your service,
your server has a limited capacity
to entertain them.
But indeed those what do we do?
We write a far loop
and inside that far loop
we requested the same page again
and again and again.
From that sentiment Now server,
it kind of gets our guest Meg
into turning that request
and he is unable
to entertain actual real users as that
because he is busy with someone else
very high speed
and goes can hear men can not
if it's a very simple
explanation of us
then roll thousand devices
to do the same at all at once. Yes
so let's say first so I want to get to
the first name
and I am calling it, let's say empty name.
I can do that right days.
I can rename a column. So
yes, you guys should follow me.
So you guys see
instead of first name column,
now it is called employee
Name Column, right?
I want to name the column differently
so that you guys can see the information
of the employee and you guys can see
the information of the manager
employer name.
I am calling this
first name as the employee name and then
I am creating a copy of employee
stable as MP
underscore table.
Okay.
Or maybe it will be a large name.
Let's call it only MP then a comma.
Then I repeat the same thing.
And this time I call this table
as the manager.
Okay.
Like this.
So now I have created the aliases, right?
The same table is called
a copy is created with the name manager
of this enclosed table
and another copy inside.
The memory will be created
and it will be called EMV.
It is clear, guys,
till this point, do you guys understand
what I have done until this point?
So inside the from clause
I have written the same table name,
but I have given it to different aliases.
It is
essentially the same as creating
two copies of the same table.
Although it is a logical division,
there is no actual copy
that is being created in the memory.
But to understand
you guys can think of it like a copy
has been created inside the memory.
And guys, I am saying it again.
It's very important for the interviewer,
so please pay extra attention.
Yes, it is basically renaming it
on a logical layer.
Nothing is being renamed in actual
in your database.
It's all logical
if just to make sure that you guys think
easily.
Otherwise
the information is not being modified
at any level inside your database.
Looks good. All all of you are good.
Anyone confused?
Most of I think.
And you make another example.
But Mustafa, if something is confusing you
in this example, it will also confuse you
in another example.
So ask me in here
what is what is it that is confusing you?
These are aliases they will expire
after a skill as executed Your query
again.
And Damian, there is nothing that is being
stored as alias in the database.
It is just to help
you write a query is easily
another decode inside of the memory.
Inside the permanent story.
Nothing is being being renamed.
No aliases are created.
It's just so that you guys can write
your queries easily.
The queries that I am teaching
you till this class.
Till now,
they have not modified any information
anywhere inside a memory
or inside the database.
Today I will teach you how to do that
if we run another curious.
These aliases will not work.
We are copying a renaming.
The first name as implied name? Yes.
Just for this query.
Right after I have executed discovery.
There is no such thing as empty name
inside a slot inside of the memory.
I don't run it right now.
Then kindly please
explain this again from the beginning.
Yes, sure.
So this first name I.
The first name column is present
inside the simple table.
Right?
So I am bringing this first name MP
dot because I have So this
this first name is being brought in here
from this copy of the table.
Okay. This copy of the table.
And let's say I can also now do this.
I can again bring the first name
from this copy of the table. How?
By writing M and our dog
first name
as manager.
First name like this.
So this piece of information,
this first column is being brought here
from this
first copy of the table is the same table.
And this piece of information
is brought in here from this second
copy of the table, although I am bringing
the results from same column.
But I can I can also.
You would be, let's see last name column
totally depends on.
So until now what I have done I have
created two copies of this same table.
This implies table.
I have created two copies.
One I have called as MP,
the other copy is called the manager
and I can use any of these copies
to bring any of the columns
from the back obvious.
If this is clear till this point,
then we will move forward.
Tell me if it is clear.
I have created
two copies of the same table
and I can use any of the copy
to bring the data
from any of the columns from this table.
Was table.
Does it make sense now
till till this point?
It's like, let's say for example,
we have Lubo, right?
Lubo is also break manager
so I can call him as manager
or I can call him Lubo.
But Lubo is same person, right?
So same person having two names,
this same table,
having two aliases.
But why even be name is always Alan.
There?
Because I have not written any condition.
Yes, and this is another concept.
So when we write
two tables in the front laws
and we do not write the rare condition,
what Eskil will do is will speak
in the first row of the table.
One in here, and it will create
all the combinations with this table
to all the rows from the table to okay,
then it will pick in the second doses.
This is how by default school
joins two tables.
If we are not writing
the we are condition,
you guys don't need to actually know this
ignore it if you guys don't understand it.
This is called the cross project.
Do you guys know the
it it is called something special
in activity as well.
When we create all the combination of all
the elements of table one with table two,
it is called something special.
I don't remember it.
And you guys tell me across product
I guess
a cross B multi
something multiplication like this, right?
Yes, This is what is happening in here.
So then we don't specify the conditions.
This is how by default school joins
two tables.
That's
why we see the information like this.
But you guys can ignore this.
This is not required
actually,
that these all of these skill cuties,
they are translated to do that
mathematical things.
Those are cells and then they are executed
inside your computers.
There is a complete
branch of a school that only
tells you
these relationships with respect
to mathematical, it's called
algebraic skill or something like that.
If you guys want to do some research.
Yeah, sorry.
Relational algebra, not algebraic.
It's called relational algebra.
So you guys can actually write
all of the queries
using relational algebra as well.
Those who are good with math.
You guys can have a look
then if deep diving you guys,
I just cannot control my emotion
and the amount of knowledge
that I have inside me.
I have spent a lot of time
studying these databases,
so there are so many things,
but I always tried to
actually it was very, very hard at first.
I used to tell a lot of details.
And so the idea is to get confused.
I had like 15 sessions with ASL,
and ASL told me, Hey, ask me, please,
please limit the amount of information
that you tell in your classes.
This tutor,
they cannot understand all of it.
Then I started realizing it then.
Now I know how to limit
so we can ignore
the results
that we are getting in here for now.
But this should be clear
that we have created two copies
and I can
refer to the information
from any of the columns in here.
Now the next thing is that
so I am deleting some of it
and I am creating a copy of this.
And you guys remember I will intentionally
write the wrong query first
and you guys have to tell me
or why did I tell you
it should be a surprise.
I am sorry if I missed
what do I And we have by default,
when we connect to tables,
it's called across the media.
It is called across product.
Right across. We
is alone.
We don't need to do this
all to fix the problem.
This is not a problem.
This is a default behavior.
It runs for everyone.
Yes, all the databases.
This is how they treat you by default.
We already have trust special normalized.
You should not.
We have interest rate issue.
I told Westerwelle that I will not be
exaggerating things for you guys.
If something is difficult,
I will tell you if it is difficult so.
They are learning the nested loops
and this condition.
I tell like
I told them, it's a little difficult.
Oh, they have so many friends
in previous batches they already know.
What does it mean when I say easy peasy?
So what I want to do is that
I want to bring the first name
and the last name from here.
So far we just gave two aliases
to the same table and the table generated
across the start of the first name
with the start of last name.
Yes, you are right. So
and then what I want to do, I
want to join these two tables
based on this managed ID.
So manager directly from here
if it is equal to any of the ID.
So if this number that is present in here,
if it is present
to any of the table in here,
then the first name and the last name
I want to bring from here
and then I want to combine
these two results.
I want to call it employee
first name the information
that I am getting from this table
and the manager first name
that I am getting from
this table, that it makes sense, right?
So I want to match these two ideas.
One is called the manager idea
that is called employee I.D.
and if there is a match,
So which one should I use, guys,
if I I'm trying to solve
with the help of joins,
should I use left to join drive
to join self join in join
it is actually
an inner join but because the primary
e is present inside the same
it is called a self join but it in actual
it is an inner join in a join
means the match
the b that I should be present
in both the tables.
Yeah.
So if it is same in here and in here,
then this means that let's say
this Nina a d Steven.
Why not take the proper example?
So for me, the manager is it 100,
which means
Steven is the manager of Nina.
If we do not want all the info.
So in intersection. Yes.
Can we write the query now?
Can you guys help me
write down the query now? I
So we have to write
the real condition in here.
So what should I do?
How should I write the condition
manager not
Should I put employer idea
or manager writing here
it is called a manager ID,
it is called employee ID.
So manager underscore I.D..
Am I doing it right, guys
or I am doing it wrong?
Employee Not employee I am.
I might doing it right.
Look at this table, guys.
Look at this table
and tell me I have called
this table as employee table
and this table as am and G are table.
Should I write employee dog manager.
I need our manager.
Dog manager. I.
I want to create a relationship
employed or the manager ID
is equal to manager dog employer ID
is it correct?
Guys I found a solution.
When we have a crazy table diving call ASL
then she will call directly to a square
during the class and our brains save.
Or are you guys going to record
that part of the video
like you did for was memorize that iconic
illustrate version of repository
so you guys will never forget
in your life.
Holiday poster it looks like right?
I am sorry for this.
Yes, it should be
MP dog manager i.t and
manager dot employ i.t
is too early for this
online guide.
Let's find out if we are getting
the correct results or not.
How can I.
How can I verify this without
going through the start out method?
I get a lot of results
so b one does not have
any many right?
Steven does not have any manager database.
I we are conditioned to check if I am
getting a manager for Steven as well.
If I am getting a manager for this Steven
as well as well,
that means I have
done something wrong, right.
That means I have done something wrong
that.
Means this idea 100
is being linked to this idea.
100 in here. Right.
So let's let's do that.
You guys never proved me wrong.
Right?
Okay, we're.
We are okay.
Should I say, employ
first name as Steven or manager?
First name as Steven.
Employee. Right.
Employed or first name is equal to Steven.
And so should I capitalize
first letter here as well.
Or I can just write and Steven like this
or in this s should be capital
plus later capital.
And can I also remove this employee
from here? No.
Otherwise I still will be confused
which first name
we are trying to refer right.
Oh there are two.
And instead of weird
we should write and in here
guys, we are also getting the
manager for Steven.
Guys, I told you in the last class
that I will write, I will
I will write a wrong query
and you guys have to tell me 85.
What is going on?
Okay, let me do this.
That means you guys have not
you guys have not understood this.
So don't write.
How many of you
are able to find this issue.
I still there the manager for Steven.
I should not be getting the manager for.
Steven Right.
Can you Suzanne dear record,
please give that to me.
Okay,
guys, let me explain it again.
I think it will make more sense like this.
Let me remove this
and let's focus on this
part.
So first, what I did,
you guys will see this.
Steven as well.
Don't really
let me send what what
what are the items
that you guys are getting?
How can it do I how can it
they will do and push itself.
It is weird from the beginning.
Wrong keyword not found.
Eskil come on not properly ended.
Okay let me sent this.
I think you're this guilty
and tell me if you guys
see the output.
So just to make things clear,
I think it will not confuse
you guys that much.
Let me do this case.
Why not?
Let's only
get the results
for plus, let's say
maybe one, two, three, four,
five employees.
Let me show you the results step by step.
So we're
employee ideally in
one or one
300 111 or 2113.
Tell me, guys,
if something is confusing you two and 105
So let's let's do this only for the
first
five employees.
And also let me show the ideas in here.
So right now
we are getting the growth product in here.
Let me also that
okay, now looks good.
Only five results.
But the gross product again here.
Okay.
Because we are missing the inner join.
Okay, it's fine,
but we will not be getting more results
this time
other than these five employees
when we tried to join.
So now I have created three copies
and they looks good.
The result is confusing
because of this
cross product in.
Okay, let me do this.
This should work fine.
So this index is different for Oracle.
Our tool in our role in
the last
we are wrong.
Number four.
Okay, Now it looks flawed, right?
But again,
because we do not have that acuity,
we are still getting that cross product.
So Steven is being cross product
with first with all of the
role of the other table,
other manager table.
No, no, we should not be.
Once we tried to write the proper
condition, we should not be seeing this
manager in here.
Okay, So let me right now show you will be
manager.
They did the proper link in here
all but then.
Sorry. And
so let me try this guys.
So Manager dot
employer
idea is equal to
e p dot oops.
So this
e MP dot
manager already right
here the script after the changes.
Okay, let me put it this.
I am still confused right now.
Y and during the first line
manager and or last name
as manager dot first name in the
not in the line
plus right left verify
so for Nina
the manager is Steven right.
But in here
we get the manager as the thing
right we do
let me correct this query
and then I will explain to you Let
or the people
giving the cross product in here as well.
Weird guys, give me 2 minutes.
I will. Or
I need a break
for minutes.
Okay. Just give me 4 minutes.
Otherwise I will give you a break
and then I will do the research to
fix this before and after the break.
I will explain. 40
No, just
guys.
I good.
And you see, I am bringing the employer
in from both details.
You guys didn't tell me
we spent so much time.
What we should be writing Manager in here.
Andy, are
okay?
Well, I was confused why it is not working
because one board decided
to erode the employer ID.
We were always bringing the employee I.D..
Come on, guys.
You guys didn't tell me
we are 11.
I was so confused, man.
Why? Why? This is happening in here.
The results,
they are not working either way.
Okay?
And now? No, really.
Give me five more minutes.
And the man, at least you should have
told me this flat I am using.
The manager on board decides
this is what I was doing.
I wrote employ in here
and employee in here.
Some more to the first names
and in here
or the
sorry, the first name in here.
The last name in here.
It should be first name like this
and employ I.D.
employee I.D.
And it should be employed.
So I was not bringing the first names
always
like this does.
It makes sense now
for now, confusion is universal.
Okay.
Now let me tell you what I did wrong.
Also, first, let me tell this.
This is the correct query.
Nice Forget whatever
I have been doing in last 15 minutes,
if this is the correct duty.
And now tell me
let me tell my mistake as well in
in the the
I should be bringing the first name
of the manager as well, which case
I have really confused you.
What what we were doing
we were bringing the first name
of the employees
and the last name of the managers.
I was so confused that
why I am not getting the proper results.
Because because of this,
because I never brought the first name
of the manager or who who understand this.
Let me let me reproduce
the problem as well.
Next in here, I was
always bringing the last name of manager
like this.
Like this. I
That's why even though there is no
manager, I was still getting the results
like this.
I was.
Instead of getting Steven,
I was getting going.
Right? And I was confused.
Why not?
Has a manager as a Steven.
But how come
we are seeing this going in here?
We wrote that to you before
I and Hasim
asked so many times
you ignored all My God,
maybe
I was not looking at the screen right?
And these silly mistakes
they can waste many, many,
many, many hours still. Yes.
11. Now, this is now
is the time for this emoji.
Yeah.
Okay, Let me here
because, guys, let's have a break.
I think we all need
a break before I can bombard
it. Let's have a
15 minute break.
And also let me contact this students
with two which are supposed to join us
break do 1147 You guys already told
you guys try to bag me
when something is very, very important.
And that can be the time of all class.
Call that and we need some more.
Because you wrote the last name.
Yes, I wrote the last name.
And I was confused why we are getting
the king as the manager.
Why not Stephen
Nice.
Let's have a break.
Take some fresh air
and let's meet after 15 minutes
and reminding me about the recording.
I will explain from the start.
Don't worry.
Recording.
Please be patient.
We are recording.
Okay.
I will keep my one eye on the chat
as well. I
is also here.
Oh my God.
I hear.
You missed the
I am hungry
when I am hungry and angry.
No need to record anyway.
If you will watch that video ten times
and the thing will be clear.
All right, guys.
So and we created two copies
of the same table.
Okay.
One, I called as MP, so let's say
this is the MP table
and the second copy I called as the
M and g r k, but okay
from the employed table.
So I am saying MP, not employee I,
which means I am asking a skill
to give this information
and I am renaming this information
as MP under school.
Right.
That's why I see this MP already in here.
The second piece of information
that I am asking school
to give me is the first name
of the employee.
So and I have renamed
that as
MP underscore first name.
Therefore I icmp
underscore name in here,
so I did not fascinate me.
MP name and
I am using an inner join,
which means if the information
is available on both sides,
then only I will see details.
That's why the first idea the idea
for this reason is empty
and there is no match inside.
The manager table.
That's why I don't see this. Stephen.
I don't see this.
Stephen and I start seeing the information
from Nina.
So faster that I get as Nina.
Then then Alexander, then Bruce,
then David.
It is clear guys, still this point,
it is a necessity.
Otherwise it will confuse you more.
If I don't get renamed, it will confuse
you more. That
is it.
Is it clear what I have explained
till this point?
Mike, you didn't find
I was trying to retrieve Stephen
as an employee with no manager name.
Easy peasy
so far.
The back, the manager already that we are.
So you must have written it
in a different order here.
Yes, you must have written.
I will explain that as.
But give me one moment. So.
Okay then I am also
bringing the first name
from the manager table,
which means I will be getting these
first names
from this manager table
and I have renamed that as manager
first name.
So I will see the manager
first name in here as well.
Okay, so it should be this.
The query should be clear till this part
in here.
This part I have only written this part
to only get the five results.
And which five results I want.
I want the five results for ID
100 10123425.
So that I don't get so many results
and you guys can verify
the information easily.
So five results are displayed in here.
In here.
And I have also limited
the information to five rows
so that you guys can cross verify things
if it is working fine or not.
So this part has nothing
to do with this self
and you want
you guys can ignore this part as well.
If it is confusing,
you all go till this point.
Okay.
Now this joined back
in part what I am saying.
I am saying
from the manager table this table
I want to
match the employer ID row number
easy to keyboard.
It is a way.
Yes, it is a keyword in oracle skill
only in my skill
we use the limit keyword to limit
the number rows.
We can add the join as well.
Yes. Or one you.
We cannot be joined as well.
But again joins is not a universal
it might not work on some of the databases
or it might be the case
that the join is called something else
like inner join
or simply join or something else
on a different database.
But this weird clause,
it will work on all databases.
The next thing I am saying
from the manager table,
I want to match these IDs, these ideas
with the employer table, which is this one
from the manager column.
So what I still will do
as school will pick a manager
already from here.
Okay.
And it will go inside the manager table
and it will such a person
that has this idea.
So Stephen has this idea.
Okay, so I see this Stephen
as the manager of Nina.
Then again for this second row, again
the ID is 100,
so a skill will again
start this inside the manager table.
As the employer ID,
you see manager dot employer I.
I have written manager don't employ any
so it will go manager
and then the employer ID.
So again ID find this Stephen so displace
this Stephen as the manager
for the lets as well.
Then it will match the third row.
It will check the manager ID for
the Alexander is one or two again.
It will go inside this manager table
and it will find the 102 as this let's.
That's why we get the let's as the manager
then for the brewers
and for the David
we have manager ID as 103.
So again
this Alexander
is Brown from this manager table
as the manager I think
this is the correct approach
that I should have written.
But in last 20 minutes what I did wrong
was instead of Manager firstName,
I wrote in here
the last name
and because that
But what confused me was that
instead of Stephen as the manager of Nina,
my session has expired.
Let me copy this query.
Letting the session of
the need to add debug option in database.
So what I did instead manager ID
and you guys also tried to told me, but
I didn't check the check.
I returned the manager dot last
and what was happening
instead of Stephen as the as the manager
the last name of Stephen is king.
So King was appearing in the manager first
and I was sure that
the manager of Nina is Stephen
and I was confused why it is not working.
So I tried changing this
a sequence in here
because
it affects how the results are brought.
And I tried many, many things, but at last
I found that instead of last name
I should have the first name in here
that kind of wasted the last
20 to 25 minutes.
Stephen is king, so it is normal
that he does not have a manager.
Miriam or nice
you guys very lucky actually.
You guys missed the first part.
You guys are very lucky
after many, many years.
I remember it reminded me my initial days
of working as a developer.
This is what I have been
I did for many, many years.
Those small, silly mistake.
I used to spend hours
on these type of things.
We broke out of our brain.
I saw
this is how simple the self adjoins are.
Guys. Come on.
They are very simple.
Do I think the information
to the same table?
Did we download anything new? Yes.
We downloaded so many things.
Okay guys,
spend some time with the self join
because we.
I have to cover so many other things.
I will again go through this self
join in the next class as well
so that you guys are good
with the self joins
and let send you the theory as well.
So now you guys can remove
this part as well if you want.
So there things look even simpler
self and do on without the pivot.
So we are writing a join with the
where clause
of the term is called
self can join you can achieve
the same thing with different
in different ways.
I will go over this self join again
in the next class.
No, don't worry if it is confusing you.
Let me check.
So this was self.
Join self and join a castle on a table.
Takes a selfie
itself in it is a regular join
but on the table is joined with itself.
So next thing is the SAT operator
one more skill class left right.
Hopefully we will be able to color
all in the next class,
but if required I will add more classes.
Don't worry.
If required, I will add more classes.
It will.
The next thing
is, guys, the self operators.
Now first, let me tell you why
we need this set operator
So and you guys still have
three review classes
as well, at least to review a classic
one will be on Monday
and this coming Monday
and next will be on Thursday.
And in the coming Monday.
Let me change my settings.
I think it really has
slowed down the performance.
So we have this person table and there is
also a person table, if I am not wrong.
Yes, I don't have first on two and three.
You guys don't see the percent
two and three table.
Oh let me.
Yeah.
Or I think I need to give you permission
to see this table.
I think I have not given you
the permission.
Okay, You guys don't need it.
Just. Just just just work with.
Just watch what I am doing in here.
You can test it on any table
in this table, Pretty much everything.
I think you have to restart this
in grade
software, because I clicked somewhere
where we would.
I should not.
I am not supposed to click.
We are low lowly
regions who are not allowed to access
to classified information.
No, no,
there is no classified information.
Ellen is a very simple information.
Guys like me, they started this
these all good.
So this is it is not even closing.
I think
that is my task manager.
Well, Windows by Mac.
It is not because of Windows
it is because of this
My skill workbench.
I think we are still getting many,
many benefits
from free software.
So let me show you the
this table person to
do it please.
The there is nothing to do.
I am waiting for the tutor to execute.
I think before meeting any person
we should do two things
make them use slow internet
and my skills workbench
and you guys will be in good shape
after marriage.
They will have a lot of patience
after this.
Finally, all my colleague finally.
Guys, did you notice something different
with about this person today?
But there is something weird
that you guys noticed about this person.
Whatever.
Well, what is that?
They are told it is faster
if you do that.
It's not
okay.
So there is some information
and so there is
there is an overlap of information.
The same data that is presented
inside of the person.
The table
is also present inside the person
to table right.
Except this part.
This part
is the same as this part.
Right, guys?
So two tables,
they are having the same information.
What if I have to combine the information
of two tables which have same columns now?
First, let me tell you why.
Why two tables
might contain the same information.
So in real life, what happens
is that as we create the tables with time,
if the application is
something like, say, for example,
if we are dealing with the credit, if the
if we are dealing with a credit card
domain, let's say, for example,
we might have thousands of transactions
per day and maybe millions of transactions
per month and eventually
maybe billions of transactions.
All right.
If let's say
we are storing the information related
to the transactions of a credit card,
what do you guys think?
Can we have huge amounts of data
in that scenario or not?
Or let's say if we are talking about the
about a website like Amazon
and if we are recording
the information related to orders, again,
we can have billions of records
in a table.
But whenever we put so much data
inside the same table,
if we run our queries, they will be very,
very,
very slow, might take hours to execute.
So what we do once a table has grown
to such size,
let's say millions of entries,
we archive those.
All the results.
So and if we need those results,
if the application is
required or the old information
and the new information
available at the same time, what do we do?
We create tables like person one person
to person to the person forward
so that we can speed up our duties.
So it is possible
that same piece of information,
same tables can exist in a database
having same columns.
And why we do that
so that we can split the information
in two different
and we can speed up the queries.
Does it make sense? Right?
Why we can have exact
same schema for two tables
now, whenever it happens
now we need to modify the queue.
It is also right.
If I want all the data from this table
and this table now, how can I do that?
I want to bring the first name and
the last name from this table and table.
Right now we have a problem.
Can you guys think of a query to do that?
No. Join will be bringing the data
in horizontal way, passing
not in vertical way, not stacking up
the rows from both the tables.
Does it make sense?
So guys do lines there the joins
the things in parallel if something is
matching in here and in the second table,
then we will be getting that row.
But this time I want all the data
from this table one
stacked up with all the data
from table two.
Do you guys understand the difference
between the lines and this scenario?
It is not possible with joints
right left thing.
It is not possible.
Okay.
If it is possible, right. Actually,
I want to see the results from here
and here inside
a column named as firstName.
No, thanks.
So far. Back to we have the set operator.
Let me show you.
It will make more sense
How are you asking something
we don't know.
I am not asking.
But you guys are saying it is possible
with the help of something
that you already know.
So I thought maybe you will.
You would add, you will, you would.
You would increase my knowledge as then
by doing the same thing with the setup.
It is something that you guys
already don't trust us.
So being that there's two different
tables, we can't use, joints
we can use joins, but the joints,
they work in a horizontal fashion.
They,
they don't work in a vertical effect.
Let me actually show you.
Let me write acuity for you
and then you guys will understand what
I mean.
So I am saying select first name, select
last name and
do the same from here.
Right
limit to the.
So I get to John
Daddy Mary and came right nice
from this first guilty to results
I have intentionally
immaturity results.
If I execute this query
on the second table,
it is a different table
so it might have different information.
It has same information.
Let me intentionally
change this information.
Okay for you all to find.
So in here I have Ali,
Mike, and Sara.
So now what I want to do,
I have three results from percent two
and two results from person table right.
This is clear.
These two results from percent.
Table three results from percent two.
And I want to get now
I want to write that you read
that gives me five results in total.
I want
to articulate
that gives me five results in total.
And it includes these two results from
and these three results in here.
So let me let me also do that
very quickly.
Limit.
Limit does not work with union with
it will be confusing for you.
Give me one winner today.
Let me make it easy for you
again.
No, no, no, no, no, no. Not again.
Not again.
Just 2 minutes. What again?
Just want to make sure
that you guys understand it correctly.
Not again.
Definitely not again.
I have already invested a lot of time
in order.
This time, and I will also keep on
looking the messages
that we have access to person to know
you guys don't have
when you say the it scares me,
you do the hard easy.
Are you sure?
No, no, it is very hard. Give me
give me to.
Yes. So, Dawn, Mary Ali.
Okay. And
we I will also
tell you how to do the same thing
on other tables as well.
First, let me teach you the concept.
So I do four or five, six
for Guy.
This marriage stuff
will break his brain already
seem.
I think you are right. I am.
I have started getting three there
so three rows in here
Touro three rows in here.
Right.
Don Mattingly from person to table
and Ali,
Mike and Sara from from here.
So now if I want to see both
to the results from both the table,
I can write more the theories
and I can write reunion in here.
And if I execute this query
as a whole,
I will see those those results
that I was getting from the first query.
Plus, I am also getting the results
which were from the second query.
Those results were six in total.
Right left me. So these three results from
let me draw
these three results
that I was getting individually
are coming from this query
and these three results.
They are coming from this query
and this union,
all what this union all is doing,
it is combining the results
from both the queries in a single set
so that we can see the rows in a vertical
fashion.
Is is it clear?
So guys on this one more thing
the same in the
when I put to this reunion,
all I see the duplicate results
are this Ali is duplicate right
it is coming from both the curious.
If I only want the unique results,
I can remove this all from here.
I think I should create separate tables
for each concept.
Maybe to avoid these
kind of things in the future.
So if I remove the union,
if I remove the all operator,
I don't see the duplicate that the data.
Now Ali is appearing only once.
If I put the all operator in here,
then I see the duplicate that
I as well.
So this union,
this union.
But what it is doing once
it triggered the out
from both to be curious both of the tables
it also perform
which extra operation is being performed
in here guys in the case of union
when do we get the same effects.
Well with what is the keyword
that we use this thing, right?
So the union performs
the stacking of two of the data
from two tables,
plus the distinct operation.
But the union all it only performs
the vertical starting stacking.
Can you guys
tell me which one will be faster out
of these two union all or union?
No guys it will be slow because it has to
perform that distinct operation as well.
Union all will be faster.
So most of the time in the industry
you guys will see union all being used.
But if you really don't
want to look at the duplicate data,
you can use the union Operator
Now tell me,
was it hard or easy to understand
the union operator And now tell me, is it
something that we can do with the
are clause by it
by and by joining the table?
Can we achieve the same effects by joins?
Yes, we can.
And not.
Can you write a query please?
Maybe I should
tell our skill guys they have
they have
just added this union without any purpose.
Right.
We can achieve the same thing
and with this smart again.
All right, guys. So,
okay, one more thing.
It is not the union and the union.
All okay.
Two, three, four, five, six.
We also have
intercepts.
Intercept, intercept.
What the intercept will do it
will only bring those roles which are
available in both of their tables,
but it is not supported in my school.
And then we have minus as well.
So but minus will do it
will subtract those roles
which are present in the table B as well.
And it give us the remaining result,
but it is also not supported in my school.
You guys can check if they are supported
in Oracle as well,
but they are very, very rare.
It is very, very clear
that you guys will be using them.
So we will not be looking at those two
because in here the tables
they are complex
and it will not make much more sense
and they are not that much used
user to join the results of
two or more select statements rules.
Okay, so we have some rules as well.
Same number columns must be selected.
So for example,
I cannot do this that I select
only one column in here
and I select to columns in the query
which I am doing the union with.
Right.
So but my ask really is great.
It, it might work.
We might still get results.
It's very rare
that we get at as in my estimate.
Oh, finally we have added the no.
It is also giving error in it as well.
But Oracle one,
it will definitely give you an error.
So. So this is the first rule.
Same number of columns
in both to the select statement
and a dead body.
Types of the columns and must be same.
This thing works in my sequel,
even that our types don't match.
It will still work,
but in Oracle you will be getting into.
So for example, I can not do this
in here I select the Edge column.
So in here
I am selecting firstName last name,
which are both like job types
like strings.
But in here I am selecting the Age column,
which is nomadic.
I guess.
But it will work in my skill.
It will.
You will not get any errors, you see.
But if you guys try to do
the same other databases
like Oracle or my skill server,
it will give you an error.
For example, if I do this
so firstname from employee
technical glitch
or you will be out of there
to be rejected.
So first name from
at our DOT employees.
So this task will display department
ID and managerial
from both employer and department.
Please remove duplicates and solve them.
Astounding was about union. Yes.
All right. You are right.
Is it possible to use here distinct
union have the distinct
so you don't need to do
the distinct separately.
So I want my ask Really So find does
not reject you even if you make a mistake.
Yes, you have. Right?
I use the Intersect. Yeah, Intersect.
Well, yes, I think intersect and minus
they works in in Oracle database.
I think they work,
but they don't work in my sequel. Right.
Have you guys tried this, the middle
or someone else?
Can you quickly try that?
If we have the Intersect
or minus keyword in my sequel,
if they were in my sequel,
a copy might let me share my query.
Just put
No, and so am
I spelling it right?
Intersect.
Yes, it is already giving an error
and the other one is minus.
No, they are not
even recognized as keywords.
There might be a separate
and there might be other ways
to do the same, but
they are not supported it.
We can see it because we don't have access
to person to table.
Yes, but you guys can write this query
on any table.
I just use the person tool
so that you can understand it easily.
So I am doing the same thing on the Oracle
one in here as well.
So you guys can follow me in here.
So I am selecting the first name
from the employee stable.
Okay.
And let me select so
a union
select.
Tell me some other column,
which is let's say
may be
employed.
Right? It is a number column.
So the first name is Water.
The employee ID is number.
So if I try to do the union in here,
my session will be expired
and I will reload the page.
Last night I didn't get sleep,
but now I am trying to convince myself
that you are not going too fast.
You guys, you can always talk me
So I am on still a union part.
We have only like two things
the self unions
and the unions.
So this is the channel
that you guys will get.
Expression must have the same data type.
So basically union roles from both
they both combined and intersect
shows them separately.
No, no, no, no.
Intersect will only show those roles
which are present in both of the tables.
The exact same data.
Let me show you if if I, if,
if I if intersect would have
if school sports intersect there.
And if I do the Intersect,
I will only be getting elite. And
in here, if it was supported in school
and if I would have written this
instead of a union,
if I had written it with Intersect,
I will only get this with
Ali and give because is present in both.
It is intersection. All right.
So the same as the intersection
in mathematics.
In this activity
intersection mean the information
that is present on both sides
if same as the secretary
minus is also same as this activity
this school on this all of this school
is actually a based on the theory
and other mathematical concepts
behind the scenes.
No you guys can also understand
intersect means if it is available in
both the tables in simple
all good guys.
All good guys.
And please let me know if I am going fast.
There is no use of showing this.
If you guys don't understand this,
the expression must have same data type
union puts it all together so
without duplication in union
we don't have duplication again.
Same as Secretary,
no duplicates, but all the information
from both of the tables.
Guys, if someone is confused,
please stop me right now.
What we What is confusing you
tell me now
Everything.
Then it is fine.
Is there anyone else who is confused
with that manager thing?
Olga I will repeat in the next class again
and in the review class again.
And then if you guys are still confused,
then we will discuss that.
I am not sure it will help all my board.
All my board backed their self.
John has a video in my class
How many of you are not comfortable
now because of that self? Join
manager Stephen King
A Do you guys need a break?
Maybe for 20 minutes
and then we can continue.
What I am asking I'm
not asking to my knowledgeable
and Hartmut
is there anyone who needs a break
as all managers are?
Okay Catherine,
I'm not asking you as well.
Is there anyone else?
So we need to get content
posted by you at all.
So not
can we continue tomorrow?
No. Other guys.
Let's do some funny things then.
I will do is
I will discuss this beam remaining off
to be involved in the next class.
Let's let's create some tables
and do some stuff other than this one
so that you guys feel so relaxed.
Go to your home.
Home, Babs,
and connected to your free school,
using your free school credentials
that you guys created in the last class
is more money at the moment.
Can you send me the password, please?
Check if this one is working
and I don't have the password,
but you know, we are not getting a break.
Definitely,
because right now market is super,
super hard and I want you to graduate
as soon as possible.
You can. You guys believe me?
Students are getting 3 to 5 offers,
like not a single offer.
They are getting three of our four offers
and they are choosing from those offers.
I will ask them to share
all, all their experiences today.
You guys can start.
I think it will be in 1.5 months.
Okay.
All right, guys.
So let's learn how to what is the average
salary then is please ask this question.
I also don't know because I don't
intervene too much in personal things.
I don't like this,
but when I invite the students today,
you can ask these
kind of questions as well.
And if they are comfortable,
they will share this.
I will ask them to to be kind
to at least to give us the range
so that you guys
can have an idea of the salary as well.
But I am, I am sure,
because some of the students,
they just rejected the offer below it,
So I am sure it it is above 80.
They will join around 230.
They have so many offers.
Why would someone join for 80 or 90
and why now?
You can send
whatever is above 85 here to my account.
Please.
I really need that
until my wife gets a job.
I think you have to make and resume first.
Yes, definitely.
We will be teaching you how to do that.
You should give money to us.
No, no.
From today I am very poor guy.
You make so much money.
I know all the money is gone.
Everything is gone.
So, guys,
are you connected to the new database?
I So you can also give me about 100
K to my account.
You guys are saying you are happy,
right? With
150 K for me, Zima
I think I need to give whatever
I get from the Monday
night out to you to make you 150.
You see, this is how many the person
who has a expensive life like silver,
they are looking for 150.
Okay, so guys like me
teach you how to create these tables.
I don't have the new DB.
Most of you create the
account that I
how that I showed in the last class.
I know
how many of you have not created
the accounts guys
on this free database
don't want them.
I know
you are not thinking in the right way.
This is not how you should think.
How much money you are making them. Now.
You should think how much money is paid
to a good pastor
that have five years of experience
in this industry.
You be underestimating you a lot.
Please don't do this.
Just just because of this mentality.
I have persuaded three different jobs
because always undermined myself so much.
And believe me, on every job
when whatever amount I ask, they literally
paid me that amount
and after that I was cursing myself.
Why? I didn't ask the double amount.
Please don't do that.
It will be so bad that you have to quit
your job later on because once you know
how much your colleagues are earning,
it will it will.
It will.
It will be like it all time.
It will be in your head of that
why you are earning,
even if you are earning one penny less,
then then your colleagues
it will be all time inside your head
that you are undermined.
You are not valuable.
Please don't do this.
Ask them they are that makes you happy.
But it also should also follow
the standards
as well.
Yes, it is illegal, but I don't think so.
There is any company on this side
in which you don't know
how much your manager is earning.
I'll leave that out of me.
You have very well
a very good idea about these figures.
Although it is illegal.
I mean, they literally ask me to sign
so many documents not to do this.
And the first thing that I did to do,
I knew my job
was this how motivated that person,
instead of being out with many that
we used to spend many, many hours
just to discuss
how much money everyone
is, it's not possible.
So I know
before I teach you how to do that,
I want to tell you that
these are before path of skill,
that I was telling you about.
One is the DML part.
DML stands for direct manipulation
language
using these commands and these key words
to manipulate the data.
So we have only learned
I'm sorry if you guys feel
that you have learned nothing.
We have only learned this part.
We have not learned this.
We have not learned this, this, this.
So you guys have only write this letter
and out of this you ask me if it is 100%.
You have learned like 20% from.
So you you guys
can be proud of your learning now.
So this is called
manipulation part.
I think it is more than enough for you
as a tester because remember, guys,
if you know all of this,
you are potentially, potentially deeper.
That can start your job right now
and be as a DBA.
If you know all of this,
you can easily get a job around 150.
Okay,
So but we are not a we are not devious.
We are
we are testers, so we will not be needing
that.
Come on. Silver is your card.
First tell me do card
Silver.
Let's have a separate discussion
with Zima.
It's hard from scratch.
No, it is not hard.
I don't agree with all that skill class
you the hard guys
minus the self enjoying
it is not hard.
I think it is way easier than Java.
It's fine guys, because you have not
reviewed reviewed it and you have not
spent some time with that skill.
It's very easy.
So this DML means the data
manipulation language,
which means the part of our skill
that we can use to manipulate
that manipulation
mean we can fetch the data from table,
we can store the data from table,
we can delete the data from table.
We can update the data
from that from table.
Then we have the detail part.
So in in next 40 minutes,
we will learn this
and all of this.
How do you guys ready for that?
So in the first world classes
you have learned only about select.
In next 40 minutes
you guys will learn about update
or delete inside
or drop renamed to the and truncate.
Yes, update and insert.
They are different.
So asking is so easy infotainment
or you can learn
completed your data.
So DDL is a data
definition language, which means
whenever you have to create something,
whenever you have to define something,
then you will be using detail park
And it includes the key words like draw
up, rename, create either and truncate.
Then there is this part
and that control language.
So it involves revoke and grant.
So for example,
if there are five tables and let's say for
some of the
employees of your company,
you only want them to access to table,
same as I can see the person to table,
but you guys can't see it.
It is happening because of this skill,
because you have limited to be access.
I have revoked the access
for that person to table.
I can do.
I didn't revoke it.
I didn't by default it is revoked.
I have to grant the permission to use
so you guys can only see those tables,
which I have explicitly selected
using this grant keyword.
So this is the part of this here
that are control language.
Which part of that that you want to see.
So on on your jobs,
everyone will be having a separate
username and password
and you will see those tables
which are related to your jobs.
Otherwise databases,
they are very, very big.
Thousands of tables
can exist in a database
and there can be thousands of restrictions
that they can apply on those tables.
So they will all be doing it
using the park guys.
What is DML detail?
And they might ask these things
in your interviews.
So then we have a transaction
control language.
This transaction control
language is related to something.
Say if you are inserting the data
in five tables,
the data is inserted in four
tables, but somehow it fails
in the fifth table.
Then what do you want to do?
Do you want to reverse the data?
Do you want to also remove the data
that was inserted to four tables?
Or do you want to complete information,
complete this transaction
with the errors or whatever
you want to do in those scenarios?
Think of the applications
like ATM machines, ATM machines
that detect the balance from one account
and they give you the cash.
What if the amount has been deducted
from your account but you didn't
get the cash?
They are they are treated
as complete transaction either.
It deducts the amount and gives you
the money or nothing happens.
If you do not get the money,
the amount is reversed to your account.
Will we have it in your file? Yes.
We will be having an interview files
and slides as well.
Definitely.
So that is done with the help of the DCL
part as a tester.
You guys not do not need this.
You guys do not need this.
You guys also do not need
this but you guys might need
this update insert and delete part.
But because you guys
will be putting five years
of five years of experience
in your resume soon
you guys will be promoted.
If you have a good attitude,
if you are one of those who would
like to lead others,
you will be becoming
team leaders, managers and other things.
So You guys might
also want to have a look at these things.
So if you know things
that you will be able
to search for those things in the future.
So that's why I want to at least
give you at least one example
so that in your future,
you know what you should be doing next.
So I will show at least one
example of these as well.
But it is good to know that.
So I have told you guys
what you will be needing on your job
and these are only for those which.
So it always happens.
There are some doers
and there are some followers
and there are some leaders
and things like that.
So I have seen people with 15 years
of experience still doing the testing.
They are not promoted to managers,
team leaders or directors.
And I have also the students
from Batch five.
One of them is literally
is the director of that company now.
So it will also happen to you
guys, new parents.
What is your attitude?
What do you want to achieve in life?
So I will actually show you the path so
that you guys know what to do in future.
So those who only want
to be
a tester, you
guys can start ignoring things after this.
Those who want to go a step ahead,
you guys can have a look in here
and maybe later on
you guys can also have an idea in here
so that at least the conversations
that you guys will be making with the DP
or other team members, you
at least know what they are talking about.
So for that, we created a new database
in which we have all the privileges
we in which we can do all of this stuff.
So let's start from creating a table.
Are you guys ready?
Have you guys opened that, that,
that new database
in your data?
All right, so let's create a table and
then the same person table in here site.
So to create a table
so again very simple few keywords
and you can start creating table.
So we started with create
Let me let me to create.
Then I want everyone,
all of you to follow.
Then we say create table.
Let me know what you guys are done writing
after create table.
We give the name of the table like person,
then parentheses in here.
So in Java
we use first to define the data type,
and then we define the variable name.
Right?
But in school it is little different.
In Java, we first define the data type,
then the variable name.
In school, we first spell the name
of the column and then define define
the data.
So let's say, for example,
if you want to have a column in here,
we first tell the name of the column
and then we decide the objective type.
So we want this to be a column
and let's say I want it to be a bar job,
or let's say I want it to be a number
that I can define in here.
So if I want it to be a number,
I can define it like this.
I can say, Hey, a skill,
make it an integer and
only allow up to ten numbers.
So ten for it not.
And number ten did use in this integer,
so our skill will limit it.
We only allowed ten integers in here.
And let's say
I also want to tell the skill
that create this special column
as the prime key.
So I will write primary
and I will write eight.
So now
what I am saying in
this security is create a table person
inside that person define a column ID,
and for that table I.D.,
the data type is integer.
So in Java, we by char
integer long,
but in scale we have only integer,
and inside of the integer we can define
how many digits we want to allow.
We can also have a decimal in here
if a decimal is equivalent
to the numbers that we have in Java.
And we can also have a larger.
This large chart is equivalent
to this string.
And again, in every of these
that are types, I can define
how many characters
or how many details I want to allow here.
All looks good guys, till this point.
And by the way, all of these examples,
they are on this slide,
so you guys don't need to worry
about memorizing the syntax.
All right. So this is the first column
that I have defined.
Let's define more columns like.
Let's say first name,
and now tell me the data types
for these columns as well.
Guys, what should building that
a tie for first name?
Should it be decimal integer or locked up?
What is what to stand for?
It is variable, correct? Yes.
And as so it's sure to be Law Order.
You see, it is a variable in the length.
Right? I can define the length.
And what do you guys think? Work
should be a good number.
What should be the limit of the characters
for first name?
Because if we put unlimited,
then it will slow down the killing.
Oh, can we have a first name tell
that can have 226 characters?
I assure
you. Have a first name that has 226.
And why especially 226 characters?
Why not 230?
Why not 250?
So the realistic number would be around
25 to 30.
Okay, something like that.
So this will be
the second column in my table.
Okay, let's let's define
a few more columns.
So let's
last name and again,
the data type will be larger
world record of longest name.
No, we are talking about
only first name first.
I think it is first.
Middle of last name. No.
Or it is only the first name.
If it is the first name.
I think many of the applications
can fail on this type.
Okay, let me put under.
Are you happy now?
Okay.
I am giving you Hunter Allen.
Please be happy
in your database.
You can also do it like 200 or 300.
Especially if it is a dollar.
Okay.
And let's also define maybe age
for age
so let's for
ten and let's also define the
decimal
30 like this.
So I only want to teach you
one more thing.
Let me remove the salary
so that I can also show you how
how we can do that
linkage as well
between primary and foreign.
Why age ten? I don't know.
Maybe you guys will again,
Google something
and you will tell me
how does someone come here have an age
that can have candidates?
Because you guys
now know how to Google, right?
So just to be on safe side,
maybe you guys will start using this table
for aliens or something like that.
Who Knows
now you
guys mark me the three their in here.
Okay.
However you guys are happy
so let me do one more thing, guys.
So end of universe.
So I am also created and creating
any table employee who also have ideas.
It is a primary key
and let's keep it very, very simple.
It has a salary as well.
Salary
similar
from on.
Maybe I should take a break
for next next batch
before I am done with all of that
marriage stuff.
So you do the very simple table,
create a table employ
it has idea, which is a primary key.
It has a salary column.
Let's try to create this
moment.
What was the name of the database?
What was the name of this database?
Mama, Daddy with us
out of
his moment with us.
Do you guys remember
what was the name of the database?
It was same as username, right? Aisha.
Nice as well.
Can you guys verify your user name?
Are the database names?
They are same, right? Or
I think they
they are same like
the let me try it.
Okay so it sounds all the affected
so let's let's check if this database No,
no no this is not free Haskell
your use of names audio database names,
your database.
So let's select the B table.
Select all from employee
and let's see if data
if the table has been created of non.
So we see this table.
It has idea and salary
but no data inside the table.
Do you guys also see the tables
in your databases,
your user names on your database?
So I have created a table
and this table has the primary ID
that I want to use
as foreign key in to this table, right?
So I can create a foreign key in here
by saying foreign E, f
or I in organized expelling foreign key
foreign key, let's
say empty underscore I.D.
And it referenced is
the idea from employee,
which is called I.D.
like this
and I need a comma as well.
So this is how we created before.
And so I am going I'm saying, hey, I skill
this is the foreign key
employer I.D.
workplace
create a foreign key as employ I.D.
create a foreign key has employed I.D.
And I don't need to define the data type
and whatever
because it will take all of this
information from here.
And I am saying, hey,
ask you all this employ I.D.
It is actually a reference.
So this is the primary e of employer table
and it is called inside of that table.
So bring all the information related
to the data type and all other limitations
and also make this key inside my table
and why I created this table first.
This is why I created this table first,
because if I execute this query before I,
I create this table.
What do you guys think?
Will I get an error
or will I be able to do that?
If that table does not exist,
I will be getting an error, right?
How can I reference something
which does not even exist?
So that's why
I asked you to create this table first
so that we can refer to this
E column.
MPI D
does not exist.
Let me give me one moment.
So let's all on
Why has not created the
event signifying
missing something?
Guys, give me one moment.
I have.
Yes, it looks good.
Now I want you to just make sure
that the relation is created.
It is created now.
So I have to create the
column in here
and then I can refer it in here.
Sorry, I was wrong.
Employee I.D.
is not offering this employer I.D.
is not offering this I.D..
Do you guys also see this?
Maybe need a break?
No, no, we don't need every time.
And can you guys see this relation
created
when you click on this column, Stable
Danger, this and add
a column in here
and then let's say a foreign key
and then the name of the column
that you want to Baffert as foreign key
and then tell the references
to which table.
Yes. Let me repeat and give you
guys executed this
and tell me
if you see both the tables in here
and the relation is created created,
make sure your in your how to run it.
You're just selected and created.
Make sure
that you guys are also using
the same column names.
And also here
you can share this screenshot.
How many of you have created
both the tables and the link?
Looks good
on all table person
already exist recruitment.
So because you guys
have already created this table,
you need to delete their table,
execute the security first for those
who are getting error drop table
and then the table name.
Because it is a you you already have
that table
executing this broad table command first
and then create the tables
alone.
I thought them and then they format
and there's Mustafa because most of you,
if something is already defined
we, cannot redefine
it is same as defining variables.
Next slide Drop
How to check connection between tables.
Right. Click on your tables and click on
a refresh all.
Once you do that, you will
the columns information in here
and the mail also
looks good.
Give me you look good
in We are not working It's fine to my
if it is not working for you
my dick working for you.
It's not discrimination.
I am asking for help from the right person
before blog.
Where did you define person table?
So if you have an attitude to this
even at once,
if the table will be defined.
Yep. Yep.
So let's lesson third some data as well.
In in here guys.
So this is how we can create the tables.
You guys can just then you please help me.
Can you please help Silva
also?
Silva I'm just kidding. Please
share the editor that you are getting.
I just ask to be more experienced person
and no, it's working.
Okay.
Do we also have someone who knows
Ileana in person?
It is not working for me as well and
will do the error that you get for one.
And then you don't have a wife
in this class.
Sorry, I cannot help you you.
But now you will have to select
to be database
guys read to the errors as well.
If there is no database selector,
it means you have to execute this
part.
Guys, let me do this right.
Give me one moment.
Drop table.
You guys have given the same names
as as mine.
Right?
Just execute
all of these queries in this sequence.
And before that, this this part
will be different for every one of you.
So keep this part
and all of the remaining queries replace
here.
This thing that I have sent you,
all of the all of you select
all of it in your editor and
and execute it.
It will look
all fine for you.
Let me know once
you guys have executed this,
this time
we should not be getting any out of
If you have selected your database,
I see null.
It means you look good.
Yes, Poppy, all of it.
If it works, no needs null is good.
Yes, it's stop working
the skill workbench.
You have to restart it.
That means.
Alex, let's watch this
and you have to drop the person
table first and then be
because person is adapting some piece
of information inside the employee
and we are trying to do the employee
first, which will make this person
work, not properly
because the reference is gone.
Delete, draw the person table first.
Those who are getting error,
drop the person table
first first.
Is there anyone unknown table person.
It means that you have already deleted
that person table
in here in your tables a deck.
How many tables do you have in
your database?
You will have this table
step shows here a screenshot of in here.
Before sharing the screenshot,
click on refresh all
and then showed me the screenshot.
I have none.
That means
you don't need to drop this table
otherwise you will be getting an error.
There are no tables,
just these two commands.
Yes, Alexa, you don't need to drop
that person table not dropping below table
only and then create tables.
Or if you guys are getting the error
still, let us just name your employed
table two in play. 1%. 2%. One
or use any other names
you are made of.
You have also deleted
the person table already,
so just drop the employed table and create
the new ones
of you have already.
Just read the other guys into that which
says they are not find the person table.
It means you have already deleted it.
You don't need to execute this command
if you have already deleted
that you don't need to execute this.
Read the errors.
It's fine now.
If you don't have any errors,
don't have any tables.
Just create.
Just create the tables that's it.
This is how my employees table looks like.
How many of you are still unable
to see employee and person table
in your databases?
Do you get any errors
and any
you need to remove the employer table?
Then you tell us to create both tables.
I think you
I thought you guys are following me.
That means
you should have created these tables.
But I don't know
how many of you follow me.
You guys don't follow me
when I do something in here. Yes.
That means you should have created
the tables, right?
All right, guys, let me do this.
Let's. Let's do this.
Guys, I am renaming this table to MP
and this table
to person.
Just execute these two queries
and you will.
You should not be having any issues
at all.
I had all these tables at first,
but not anymore.
And I will create these two tables,
execute this queries
and the tables will be created.
Actually, let me execute this.
Yes, it's already break time.
Just one more minute
and then we can have a yes.
All looks good.
Just knowing that your days to get
is that I have sent you.
You missed that part.
Not only just started it you're basically
this table will be created
works.
Is there anyone
who is still getting any errors?
Now it works.
Anyone else who's getting any errors
tangled?
Okay.
Can we move forward now? Yes.
We should have food table.
No, we should have it.
We should not have nothing.
All the whatever you have, it is fine.
You would just.
You should just have these two tables.
Please, Please forgive me, guys.
There is a very good video
on the internet.
There was a marriage happening
between Pakistan and some other country.
And the match was so good that Pakistan
created like around 196 score.
And that score is very good in T20.
But they still lost in that match.
All the spectators specially that their
their centimeters they were so this
so see if you are confusing today
this is all guy and spy
and if we have not to draw up
the first one just to make sure
we have these two papers, please
please make sure we
these two tables and the thing.
Yeah everything.
Nobody is
like good.
I mean, it is true, right?
If something has gone wrong in this title,
that spell that can be
it will always be really it all
you go wrong
salary drop the previous one. Yes.
And to do whatever you want to do.
All right guys,
just let's insert the desktop
as well in these tables
and then we have a break.
So to insert the index out,
we write in. So
like this, you can right click the table
and you will see a dropdown
with option of draw the table.
For your information, it is official
you are fully in love.
So insert into and after that
we write the name of the table like this.
And after we specify
the column to support example IED.
So we have the IED in here
and then we have this salary.
So I specify a salary like this
and de parentheses.
I say values,
and then I specify
a value like this, right?
So insert in two
and then the name of the table,
then the columns in which I want to insert
the data, then space values,
and then the value for the first column
IED and the value for the second one.
Or we will
you only specify the five values
which guys
who told me to have values?
Yes. Once.
Once things start going wrong, it
all goes wrong.
I have 24 salary.
I can fix it quickly,
but I am not sure about you.
So it is giving me an a warning that
I might lose some information because.
I have
a low range
for the values, so if I select the select
this for the employer table,
I should see this data in my table.
So I see I IED one and then Saturday.
How do you guys see
the information as well?
Just try to insert a lower number
if it gives me a lot
name, please confirm everyone.
If you guys don't
see the dirt in your table
and let me copy paste.
So there
looks a little better.
I need to
and maybe you want to
do the one.
So I am executing
only the last three rows again.
And now if I say select all from employee,
I should see four rules in here.
That is, insert some more data and tell me
if guys see all the dirt on your table.
Now all automatically like loop
and that I will show you later on.
We usually don't try it.
We can write loops, yes,
but usually we insert a B that file
from frontend
or from files like Excel or something.
I can, but we can also like loops, but
that is that requires the understanding
of procedures and functions,
how procedures and function work.
You write the loop inside the procedure.
We call that procedure
and then it inserts do that I using your
and if you guys want
I can share this guilty as well.
Now do one more thing.
I try to insert
and try to insert the same rule again.
So if I try to insert the same row again,
I get this error that sends
a duplicate entry for for the primary key.
You remember
we told you that this ID is a primary key,
and primary key
is they don't allow duplicate.
So if you try to add a duplicate,
it will give you it should give you
an error.
It also confirms
that you created the table correctly.
Do you guys got the error?
Yes. Yes. You should go to the error.
Do we have MP and person? Yes
Yes. You should get the error this time
because primary case
don't allow duplicate backup.
Let's quickly add the data for
the person as well.
So insert
in to name of the table person
parentheses
and in the person table
we have the ID column.
So I specify I.D..
We have the first name column.
By the way, I can also leave some columns
for those columns
and null values will be inserted.
First name,
then last name,
then ID,
and then the MP ID in here.
Then I say values
and then I specify the idea.
Let's say already run
firstname.
David, can you guys quickly
tell me some first name?
So John, being
is on day five
and what do you guys think
in the employee ID?
Can I, can I write it in here?
Stephen
Oh yes. Now.
One of the first name, right? Stephen
And then yes, I will remember you.
Stephen We can't because it does not exist
in this table
and the information
is being referenced in here.
So let's say it is opening hundred, okay?
Like this.
Let me know what you guys are done
writing the security
and not the child rule
for unconstrained fields
or or thing
where it has created another foreign key.
This one looks good.
The all the foreign key references
employer table instead of.
Oh yes, yes.
Because if you are right,
we need to update this employer
to be
now it looks good
right?
All table four
guys and security.
I fixed it so I am good.
Yes, you guys did. You guys rename it?
I did. I forgot to rename it.
Employee two MP.
If not,
it will.
Why you guys didn't tell me?
Drop that table if you have not renamed it
and created again
zero rules effect to the table
we have now.
It looks clear.
So I see ID Stephen King 25.
Anyone who is not seeing this
in your table, but.
Silva Okay. Silva You need to draw up.
You guys have already learned this command
drop table means remove that table.
The database.
I see it.
Okay, Where is the remote?
Please execute this on Silva's
computer. Drop
able person
here to find guys.
This is what you guys
will be doing on your day to day
basis.
Silva,
execute this on your computer, please.
Who else is not seeing this information
in the table?
In your table?
So those who all look good,
you guys can be on break.
Those who have errors, you go,
I am staying in here.
So with all your errors before the break.
So break is still 145.
Those who have that find in both
the tables, you guys can leave
that some who are facing each other.
I am here.
I noticed
not so many people in the class too.
The attendance looks good.
More than 50 because change many times
the name of the table.
I don't know.
Maybe they put it on recording
and just left a note there.
Adorable little child.
Yes. Silva, you and I have shared
these two things with. You
just execute this and
you will be fine.
Silva It is because see, on line
number 22, you are trying to refer
to a foreign key, 26,
which does not exist.
The unemployed table employed table
only have keys one, two, three and four.
But you are you have returned 26
in that foreign that does not exist.
That's why you got this.
And that's why
we want a little standardize.
You see, if I try to insert,
let's say maybe 100 in here,
I cannot do that
because this information does
not exist in the employer table.
So I will get this other definitely
I will go to setup.
I can only insert those ideas
which are available in here.
One, two, three, four.
I can only only insert in here
until table.
I am fine.
I have valid all values,
but I still don't say related table.
What is needed in here?
Table part does not exist.
Nabeel
you have accidentally removed the table
maybe by executing drop table command.
So you need to create table person.
You need to execute discretely,
create table person.
What is default need be
your usernames are your default of DBS.
The email that you have you
you should have got
usernames, database
names, passwords and the host names.
So Check your
the emails that you guys create that
you guys used to create my databases.
They are your databases.
Then you shared all of your code.
Yes I can share
Let them share it
in the course and ask one guy
I have shared
in the course announcement to you guys.
Can also check it from here.
Who else is getting at us?
Those who are able to insert the data.
You guys can go on break
or not share the screenshot, but
duplicate entry for primary key guys.
Also try to read your add us format.
Run the select command on part table.
You already have a role that has
one for
30 minutes.
15 minutes if I use that for
still no
inserting to reference,
you can not do that
to make sure
that when inserting the data in here
and you are only using 1 to 3 or four
as the key, I used to have more problems.
Now it is only one nice.
Please share screenshot as you're
looking at all these errors like oh no.
Actually
I am also talking a cell right now.
I am asking her to give me
some marriage bonuses or something like
that. No,
you guys can see why.
But now this picture will make more sense.
But she said
we will only think about this once
you get married.
The last error is
I cannot see the last out of it.
You know, can show me the last letter
last that it is not visible.
Some of you can also post in sport
non database selected in all
this is very simple.
In order to be selected by the
I still don't see your last letter,
you have to be database
guys and try to video your is
the last item is you know
you have not selected the database
Nabila
do you see the data in your table now
constraint foreign key MP I D
demure you mean it means that the data
that you are trying to insert
does not reference to a key in here. Yes.
Guys,
just just try to read the errors once.
I think they should make sense now.
Common errors
database selected. Which means
you agree
you guys need to execute your discovery
constraint.
Why? Later.
That means you are trying to insert
some data which is not available in here.
Table does not exist.
That means you need to create the table
first.
Dropping the table table does not exist.
That means you have already deleted
the table.
Simple things need are simple things.
Is there anyone else
we still have? Like how much time we have?
We still have 5 minutes.
The table already exist.
What do I. You can drop the table.
It's a simple right
drop table and table name.
That's it.
Any one draw effect in?
No. Will, can you execute this query?
Select all from person
so that I can see the data even that I had
when it was inserted or not. Why?
I don't see a table list on the left side.
You have to refresh it right click
and then click on refresh.
All I'm
Is there anyone else
from the far
We are not a lot of data child role
so most of you see
you are trying to online content
you are trying to insert 100
hundred in here under 100
does not exist in here.
In here, in here.
Maybe I should not have taught you
about foreign keys.
Then. It's odd.
You are also getting an error.
Mustafa handed that 100
the last 100 to something.
1 to 3 or four.
Because you reference referencing
the information in another table.
That information must first exist in that
table from which you are referencing it.
Right.
That's why you are getting error.
Sebastian You look good.
Anyone else guys got exam that is.
Can you please share this screenshot is
make sure that this last calamities
referencing this table
the information from this table
which means we can not insert
random values.
The values must be one, two, three.
Any value from this table
there smart foreign key
mean right foreign keys
means that creating a relationship
Now if these those relationships
are based on primary keys,
they cannot be null.
I was able to insert some data
that means your link is not created or not
all, but you see the data out there.
That's fine.
Also for me from the percent table format,
also 20 different person table.
Or do you also have better
in the person or that that's okay?
That's okay.
You not inserted to get on there as well.
Give me you look good.
Yep. Have the data in the tables.
Looks good.
Anyone else is animals, is confused
and is not able to insert
the data, is not able to follow me.
Okay. Insert
little tiny here as my homework.
I think
it works now do you see in the data
in person table?
Thank you, guys.
All right. Perfect.
Anyone else?
Great.
What do you get?
Looks good.
Abdul looks good.
Also, check your personal table.
Yep, it looks good.
Great.
Anyone else?
You guys,
We are the famous people of this class.
So now at your query line 24 correctly,
we learned one bit yesterday.
And this is what the Foreign Relations
looks like.
The you can not insert any random data
if you have created a relationship
with the primary of one table.
That's how we all pressed
constraints on the data
that we can insert
by David.
These are also called
constraints in databases.
We are the other famous people.
We read all the other one.
Muhammad I saw Marianne
that mean
you guys are not getting any errors
or more.
Seema Silva
four one No.
Why? Why are you guys are so quiet?
Not them as here.
I'm sorry.
Am not able to like
there are so many people in this class.
Elena is also famous.
Alex is also not present today.
Ali is usually pleasant.
I'm Ron.
I'm Ron. You.
You also some kind got at us.
Angelique is also famous
and is also not responding
to Christina.
Damian Here you guys are all.
Why? Why?
You guys are scaring me
Then I thought you guys just left.
Jumped out of your windows.
You see it also.
You all right?
So you guys now have
hopefully successfully created a table.
You guys know how to define that.
Are types. Let me check
if you by we are missing something
you know how to create primary keys
warranties by the way.
Again
you guys will not be doing this stuff.
It is the responsibility of DBAs
or architects.
Okay.
But I am showing this extra information
and you guys know how to create an
for relationships
and you guys also know how insert
that you guys might need
this part Inserted data
break and yes I am on
the first floor would not be much of a for
but Ben is asking me
when to join.
Let me let me tell them.
All right guys so so so
let's insert more data
so that I can show you
how to deliver that as well.
So I insert one because it is
a primary duplicate, so I'm not allowed.
So let me try to
let me like a bill.
Okay? I hope I am not going to reverse.
I mean, this is your first name, right?
Maryam Let me put you here as well.
Maryam, You will be my next target
is enough with Aisha.
But what is your second name?
I'm just kidding.
I am sad.
Mimi,
Who else wants to be in the database?
Awesome.
Sometimes they give feedback back.
I call feel students many times
and I don't call others guys.
It is because some of the names
of some of you are easy to pronounce
that that's
the only reason no one is favorite
guys and those
who want to be in their database.
Please fill your information
inside of this insert statement
and I will insert those
because you are too many. Now
modify your entire statement
and choose your desired desired
salary from here and
decided that you want to have used
the idea of that salary in here.
Let's also learn some skill, right?
Meanwhile, you want to be in a database.
No one is a favorite.
Was I also Nicola?
Is it Nicola or is it Nicola?
I don't.
I think I have already.
I have always mispronounced your name.
Nicola.
Second one.
Why you have it at the end of your name.
Why should not you be having IAB?
Nicola
insert into
Because of the stupid people
who wrote that way
in my birth certificate.
Or it also happens in your country.
It happens very, very tired.
It happened so many times in my country,
guys.
That's it.
Five, five rules.
Who has the year or something?
Or have you? Olga?
You see,
I don't have a salary for than 150.
Okay.
Please have at Max at 150 year.
At this point I, I have a bad
instead Dennis copy paste rules please.
On the end.
Okay so, so so
semicolon.
But we have some time here guys.
Let me put Alex Guys
and let's delete the Alex.
This is how we're dealing with that.
Our guys, my friend,
instead of being Alexander, is Alexandru.
So guys, I have this data and let's
say I want to delete some rules from here.
So this how I can do that.
So you guys already know what happens
with the draw keyword guys, the table
plus all of it, all of its data is deleted
when we draw up a table.
Right?
You guys observe what
happens where they drop the table.
Plus all of its data is gone right.
That complete is actually
the schema is also deleted.
It will be data.
No, I didn't say I.
We will be spending 30 more minutes today.
Yes, I am sure
actually more than 30 minutes
because I will invite the student at 240.
So I don't what you guys
want to ask the questions
I think it will take like what do you.
Yes, you can you can leave at that point
if you have to do something important.
So is this drop able to delete
all the data
inside the table and it also delete
the table itself, the schema by right.
And both things are gone.
But what if we only want to delete,
let's say a special rule,
only a single row, a total of three rows
for something like this.
Right?
They will be coming at 240.
So to do that, we to delete
and guys, please be careful when you are
writing this query.
So we tried to delete from
idea and empty don't have to match
they have to match alone
not because they are linked
and one of them is primary key.
So you must put some information.
Yes. I should also be careful now
delete from and then the table name
where?
So if we don't write this
we are condition.
If if we just execute this part completed,
I will be removed from the table.
So we write this.
We are condition where I.D.
is equal to six like this
so that only a row number six is deleted.
So right now
we have this row number six, Aleks in here
and I want to deliver this.
So delete.
So it says one one rule is effected.
That means that all is gone.
If I, if I do select
all from person again.
So Alex is gone from here
after the class we are.
Can I find because they are all on canvas
I will also try to push with your java
course so that you guys don't lose them.
Guys have you deleted the rows
successfully?
Are is that row deleted?
So this is how we can delete
one rows, photos or multiple rules.
You guys can also write this like we are.
ID is greater than equal to
maybe one and I.D.
is less than equal to five.
So all the rows
which have so far whichever role
this condition is satisfied,
all those roles will be gone.
So multiple rule is a single
rule is totally depends
on your rare condition logic.
Can I ask a stupid question?
Yes, sure.
Please ask. Yes.
Can we say between one and five? Yes.
You guys can specify.
So all the real conditions
that you guys have learned
When we were doing the select statements,
you guys can write all of it in here
to give any criteria
to remove the rows.
So can you guys tell me the difference
between delete and drop?
It's a very famous interview question.
The one that I will answer
drop the
the complete table plus do that to
delete only delays the data.
It can be a single row.
It can be multiple rows.
Depends on the rare condition
that you guys write.
Right.
There is also a target type.
There is also a third way
that we can use to delete the data
that is even more than dangerous
in rare condition.
We might be deleting one or two rows
in this next
procedure.
It will delete all of the data
that is inside a table.
It is called a truncate.
Can we reassign the ideas
to another person once they are deleted?
Yes, I think we can reassign.
Try, try it
and let me know if you face any errors.
I think can reassign.
There should not
be any harm reassigning those ideas
because that is deleting.
Then why not?
Why not? Yes.
Yes, we can.
Are you guys getting any errors?
What is not possible is there sometimes
once we have inserted
the ideas, let's say for example,
if we are using
the natural increment order
and if we have assigned let's say
five two, six, seven, eight to someone.
So right,
we are inserting the ideas manually,
but there is also increments as well.
That means if I have given the idea
five to something, the next rule
that I will be inserting automatically
an idea of six will be assigned to it.
So in those cases
there is a problem that if we do that
as from in between, then
how we can rearrange the data for that.
We have to write a procedure,
but we will not discuss that.
So guys are dropping
means completing that out.
Plus table delete means table will be the
the one or multiple rows can be deleted
right this time.
The type of deletion
it is called the truncate.
So we write truncate
so and then the table name.
So this third time what it will do,
it will delete everything
from the table
but schema will will stay there.
So table the structure of the table
will stand there.
But all the data will be gone.
There is one more difference
that this truncate is
way, way faster than this delete.
So we can also delete all of the data
from the table with this delete command.
Right.
If I don't specify TV or condition,
it means delete everything from the data.
But this command can
longer time this one.
It will be super, super fast and
everything will be gone in just a second.
So if I now say select all from person,
all is gone in just 2 seconds.
So truncate
it, delete everything in seconds
and delete deletes one or multiple roles.
Depends on your where condition.
You can also delete all of the data
from a table
using the world class,
but it will be slow.
And then we have the drop, which is
linear, stable, plus all of all of its.
Is it clear, guys?
It's a very famous interview question.
So I have also written in in here
just so that you guys know.
So one more thing guys.
The things that we delete using
the delete command, they can be reversed.
They can be reversed,
but the things that you delete
using truncate or drop,
they cannot be reversed
unless and until you have a separate
database as the backup database.
So this one is kind of more safe,
but it is slow.
So if your company is not paying you good
raise or you are angry with your manager.
Please
use these commands, truncate or drop.
Otherwise in
the regular routine.
You can use the delete command.
Yes, Blocked the whole thing
and data is still backup
unless you have a separate database
as backup.
So now you guys know when to use
which commands.
So Silva again again
this cannot be reversed
unless and until you have a separate
backup database.
And they are also very, very fast.
Very, very fast.
Undo button
repeatedly the difference
between drop and truncate, please.
But the difference is
if you are angry with your manager,
want to leave the company,
use that drop and truncate.
They delete all the back
to inside the table.
If you are using truncate,
all the data is gone from the table,
drop all the data plus the table itself
and they cannot be reversed.
They cannot be reversed while they delete
can delete one or multiple rows
and it can be reversed.
We will use drop
when they say you drop to the ball
drop database. Yes.
It also exists to complete
database will be gone
now but I can now ground do will not work
so record please.
I'm not showing that the code.
I have already spent so much time
creating all the database.
You guys after this class,
you guys can try
this drop database as well.
Before I had last day,
she said paid people wrong salaries
because she was mad with the team.
So these are again
the same queries and create the table name
column, then data type also guys,
if you don't want to allow,
don't want to allow null values,
you can also write not null.
Whenever somewhere
someone will try to add
null values, they will be again getting at
so and inserting two.
Then the table name
the column names and then the values
that we want to insert.
Now the update so delete
and you guys have already seen.
Now let me show you the update.
Come on.
So let's say you guys
let me start with that again.
Oh, by the way, guys,
please don't delete these insert cuties.
If have written them once, they will be
very helpful on your testing dogs as well.
So you see here this oh, this is the
this is how we take the backups
as well in the form of files.
This is all the backup will look like.
So let's say guys, I have inserted there
and let's say some
that I have inserted wrong data and now
instead
of deleting that role and inserting
that chrome, maybe 90% of the data
looks good, only 10% of it is not good.
And I want to update the data
so far that we use the update command.
So we say update.
And then you guys have also seen me
writing this command.
Can you guys help me out?
I have already updated
the many things in previous
classes.
In the previous classes,
I updated the values in front of you.
Update. Update.
I want to let's say
I want to change of all.
You go from 28 to 18
and to do you guys remember?
If you guys don't remember quickly
Google it.
How to update that I in my sequel,
I did this in class two.
I did this in class three.
Search for the syntax guys.
How to update to the dinner table
why you guys are so slow
updated table name.
Right? So let's say
you want to update to this table.
So I will write update file
and then after the keyword set
it is a result keyword
and then the column name.
So let's say for example,
I want to update the A's.
So I will say it said the ID is equal to
18. Right.
Then the we're condition to identify
for which I want to run this update
where age is equal to 28.
So I am saying, hey, a school there is it
there is a rule in the past table
which has currently has the value of 28.
So we are ages right now, age is 28.
Circle back to 18.
Okay, so back to 18.
And this is the table name
and I want to an update
as it makes sense, guys,
as school is mostly like simple English.
If there are multiple
people, all of them will be updated.
So if you want to really make sure
that only all God's age
is set to 18, you should use ID is again
a very good reason to have primary keys.
You see very good reason
to have primary keys.
So instead of having saying this age,
I should say ID
and I should specify the idea
of all like this.
Now I am 100%
sure that only one row will be affected.
Does it make sense, guys?
So one is affected.
Now let's let me query that table again.
And now all you got is
18, 18, 18, 18 years older.
Are you guys able
to update the rows on your end as
is there anyone who is getting any
errors or issues?
No errors
to do
to disable safe mode or toggle
the option in preferences as well.
And you are okay. So what?
You should not be getting that at all
because you are using.
We are ages equal to 28.
So Alexa, search
this on the on the internet.
There is a flag that you need to set
because if you are updating multiple
roles, that still gives you a warning
that, Hey, Alex, are you sure
that you really want to do that?
So this is the flag that we have to set
before we can do that
as school safe update is equal to zero.
So execute this query first
and after you have executed it, then
you can update any number of rows safely.
By default, it gives you a warning
so that you don't accidentally delete
all of the data.
Is there anyone else who's
getting any issues errors
perimeter of their sector?
This flag assumes that this flag start
at scale underscore safe
and of course objects is equal to zero.
So this is how we can upgrade.
By the way,
we can update multiple columns as well.
I have showed you only one column
and always, always, guys, please,
whenever you are deleting
or updating something double check
your wear condition and the best practice
to check these things.
This is how developers do this
before they can delete or update,
they execute this select statement
with the same.
We had a clause.
So let's say for example, before
deleting that, this is what I will do.
I will write a select statement
and I will use this word condition in here
so that I can visually verify
how many rows will be affected.
So I will not fuss. Right.
Will execute this delete statement
using the same rare condition.
I will execute this select statement
so that I know
how many of those will be affected.
So I know I am getting three rows
so I know this delete will have had
three rows.
So as a best best practice
before updating or deleting, run
a select query to check
how many doors you get.
That many rules will be affected
by a delete
or by update.
Okay.
Let me check what else we are missing.
So truncate table and drop table
used to remove that record from the table.
Not a the table.
Okay.
So truncate will not remove the table,
but all the data that is inside that table
and this is this index
drop used to delete the data
and the table from the database
so everything will be gone.
These are data manipulation
and these are data definitions.
So I hope now if you guys see these
keywords, everything will make sense.
You know, these things make sense. Now
it is the same thing.
Okay,
so you guys have learned how to do that.
Now let's learn how to do this as well.
So now
I will teach you.
Stephen,
I think
although you are in love with Stephen,
this is what happens when someone is loved
with in love with someone else.
They always stay in their mind.
They always keep on thinking about those
contacts.
The Oracle guys ask them,
Who is this Stephen inside this entity?
But ask them.
You want to meet to.
I am thinking of it.
So guys, now you know
all the rules to
bring the data from their database
with the help of queries
and some of also some of this stuff
that is required, insert
and delete the things
inside the table as well.
And also you can create tables, but
because we have to
it this, this knowledge is good.
If you are doing men were testing manually
go inside the database
execute security check if that if the
if the data has been inserted
in a specific table or not
and then maybe you can verify it
from the frontend.
Right.
But we are not manual testers only.
We are automation testers.
That means now we should also learn
how to integrate this knowledge
with the framework
that you guys have built.
So now I will show you how to
combine your Java knowledge
and your skill knowledge
to do the same things.
So now you will be able to write a Java
code to do all of this stuff,
to fetch all the data from database
inside your Java programs.
And then also you guys already know
how to bring the data
from frontend, right?
Using selenium in your Java program.
Now I will show you how to bring the data
from database
as well using Java code
and then you guys already know
how to match that to data
and make your best cases
fail or block pass the.
Does it make sense? Guys?
Look what I have just explained
so you
already know how to bring the data
from frontend.
You have started about the backend
as well, but only manually.
Now we will write the Java code
and with the help of these skill
that you guys have learned,
we will also be
bringing the data from backend
and then we will be
performing the testing.
So this is called DB testing
with selenium.
Okay.
And so
guys,
before you guys started using selenium,
you guys downloaded some dogs,
right?
Because selenium is something
that is out of code of Java,
the Java that you guys in Java classes,
by the way it is called or Java.
And let's say if you want to do something
advanced, you have to learn,
you have to use some kind of libraries
or dependencies
or frameworks
so that your task becomes easier.
So for the Selenium driver,
other than selenium driver driver, now
we also need a dependency
for my sequel as well.
So when you guys were learning
how to read selfies,
we downloaded the jobs manually,
then we added those jobs in our project
manually and.
Later on.
You guys learned about the Maven, right?
Well, what is the purpose of MAVEN guys?
Can I automate this dependency inclusion
inside a project with the help of MAVEN
support is the purpose of MAVEN Silver
is there is some kind of a rocket
that gives you scale
build management.
Yes. Guys, please
try to also pull
it is on not only for silver, try to use
try to focus on the terminologies
that you guys use to explain things.
Okay.
So that you look more professional, right?
Terminology
explaining the right things here.
Say build management tool, right in
so many other things that it helps us.
It also help manage dependencies,
which means you can just write
the name of the dependency and the maven
will take care of adding
and managing the version
of that dependency for us
so that we don't have to do it manually.
Whenever a new version comes
in, I can just change the name of the
I can just change version
of the dependency in my bombed out example
and then updated dependency
will be downloaded automatically
from remote repository
and it will be added in my in my project.
I think it's just blooming.
You guys did your project right?
Okay, maybe you guys can guide me
how to do that.
So Selenium driver is limited
to testing
your applications using browsers
to use selenium a
driver for database testing,
you need to use DBC.
So this is the driver name that we use.
It is Java database connectivity.
Stephen
Yeah,
thank you.
Thank you.
Sebastian
So it is short for Java database
connectivity.
It is an obscure level API
that allows you
to execute scale statements.
So as the
I almost diversely and Stephen away,
so as in the database
databases can be from Microsoft or IBM
or Google or other companies.
So Java guys, what they did,
they created a interface and interface
and they defined to be met, let's say,
for example, a method to bring the data
from the database, a method
to update the data inside the database,
and they the the polymorphism.
So you guys remember
the example of database I gave you in the
last classes of polymorphism
we use the
same we can use the same methods
to connect to my sequel database
to Oracle database to SQL
because they all implement that interface.
So me
really appropriate me
Sebastian, please do something.
So this is how professionally
we say we're taking the person.
Sebastian please do they need to fill
submission? Please?
Do they need full?
So there is a and there is an interface
which all of these companies
have implemented
and we don't need to learn different
methods, different names of methods
to execute this.
Curious as we have been seeing
with these skill concepts,
some of the concepts were different
for different databases.
So the Java guys,
they have solved this problem
and we don't need to learn new methods
for different databases.
We need the help of
polymorphism and interfaces.
So it is responsible for connectivity
between Java language
and a wide range of databases.
So whichever companies are locked
their databases
to work with Java seamlessly.
They already implement these methods
and we just need to know
how to use those methods.
So you see GBC is database independent.
It can work with any database
which has implemented that interface
and most of them
they implement the interface.
But the GBC is not as fully independent.
It will still be using good.
So a little bit more about it is DBC,
because I have seen
the questions related to GBC as well in.
Some of the interview databases
used to interact with the various types
of databases
such as Oracle, Microsoft Access,
my school SQL Server to connect the dialog
with different databases.
We have different drivers and jobs,
so each company
who will be developing the database,
they will develop the job.
We will just important that
the DOD in our project and that's state.
We will use the same exact
methods to query the database
Using databases we can execute
is using Java application
and retrieve the results in database.
To connect my skill to our application,
we need for download my Escuela de DBC.
Okay, so this is a little bit
about the structure of the GBC.
We have job application,
the code that you guys have been writing
that talks to the DBC driver
and that driver actually talks
to the industry.
That manager actually talks
to these specific drivers.
So these will be
this will this,
this part will stay the same in here
for you guys because we only work in here
and this part is taken care of by Java
and this part is taken care
of by each company which you are,
which wants their databases to work
seamlessly with the Java.
And then we have the actual database.
Does it make sense to use this picture?
Does it help you understand
this structure under the hood?
How can we work with different databases
so each different database,
we will have a different driver
like, this different driver,
but after after
this part will be sustaining same.
So as a developer, we will be in this
is so these are some of the famous classes
and interfaces that we can use to interact
with the database this manager.
So do you guys remember, first of all,
when we started learning school,
what was the first thing that we did
after installing the my sequel workbench?
We used the credentials
to first connected to that database
right before we can execute any query,
we must first connect to that database
using this some credentials, right?
This is our first step
all through username and password
so this driver manager takes care, this
driver manager and this connection
interfaces, they take care
about those things, that connection part.
This statement takes care.
So whenever we write the query,
that query is executed on database
server and in return we get some results.
This is statement part.
It's kind of in
this interface takes care of the issues.
It takes care of the Q report that we want
to execute this result START is again
an interface
and this is where we store
the results from the database.
So in Skill Workbench, we see the results
in full in the form of a table.
By the way, am I going fast?
All thing?
Are things making sense?
Yes, we will write queries inside Java
almost audio good Illini other guys
audio was able to connect the dots.
All right.
And then there are some exceptions
which are specifically related to school.
Do you guys remember if school exception
is a checkered exception
on unchecked exception?
I told you when we were learning
about the exceptions
file not found was a checkered exception.
It is also a checkered exception.
So we must also write the Pride
catch blocks
when will be writing the Java code.
So these are some of the steps guys
for us to create a connection
to do database, then create statements.
These statements
will help us execute queries.
Then We will be getting the results
from database.
We need some kind of data structure
to hold the results.
All right,
guys, here is one more question. Two.
So the results from the database
looks very similar to the
to how we stored the writing Excel files.
Again, can you guys tell me
how can I store the results
of a skill query?
They look very similar
to how Excel stores do that.
All right.
Column names, then.
Rules.
I mean,
I am giving you a clear, clear hint
that they look the same as Excel
File is saying file import.
Alex is saying to me arrays,
I think I should first tell you the answer
and then I should ask
the questions to you.
Or do you guys think so? Let me do this.
Well, you can store
do that from an inside a set of inside
IMAP or inside a list of maps
or inside the list of objects.
So let me ask this, guys.
How can I store the data from minuscule
field of I self, please, Alex, please.
You guys tell
by the way
you have I have
noticed this that whenever we grow up,
maybe it is because of the responsibility
to use the the common sense bar
to be active in this part
D times They are much,
much better in that as compared to others.
Right? I don't know.
I have noticed it
noticed it during the day can give much
more logical answers
if we even showed them a little hint.
But we are.
So I don't know why we missed this part,
although we have spent so much time.
First,
save it and copy paste in galah project.
Great answer and
please apply directly in Apple,
Amazon, Tesla or StarLink
over thinking full plate.
You will notice much more by time.
It is their brand is not polluted
with useless information. Yep.
I think some of the
universities
they are also did research on that.
And then guys, we must
close the connections because they are
very very expensive resource.
So can you guys tell me in Java
what is the appropriate place
where I should close the connection?
You get married first, also have kids.
Then we will talk.
Alexa, you remember that meme?
I want to do the same pause in here, Matt.
Meanwhile, that person got a yes.
That person got very famous.
So the they dropped the very simple catch.
And this person paused like this.
And it is all over the internet now.
He is also he is also an IP
guy who, by the way, is profile.
LinkedIn profile also got very famous.
So when you said hoax,
I also want to do this.
Let me know.
I don't know
if you guys will be able to see me or not.
Guys, they finally block
you remember?
They finally block is where we do
all of the important stuff,
all of the clothing stuff.
We closed all of the Excel files inside.
They finally. BLOCK
You guys also use it to close the browser.
All right, great.
So this is the
this is where we should do it.
So we will also close
the database connection.
And they finally block And as we created
be is your heart like Mario?
Or you would just stand up
and nothing changed or because my chair is
very, very tall so that you guys
can not feel the difference
when I am standing or sitting.
Special instructions for all muscle.
Please don't tell her. No.
Basically we are.
We will be closing the connections.
Quick question about family is family.
I you see I see family instead of finally
is finally
every time
get about a finally is all is executed
it's finally is
always executed.
So this is where we will
be closing the connection
and God most of you are married to
you can understand my pain already.
So guys, we inserted the
horse name or name database
name user and password inside the girl.
But to prevent you in the right in here
before
making that connection
in here.
So we need all of this information
inside the Java program
as well to connect to a database.
Right. So in here
we inserted the information
in different pieces.
Can you show some examples
how it in real life, Alexa?
What do you mean in real life or.
Yes, this is what we will
be doing in a minute.
So you guys are already familiar with this
this information, right?
Database name, user name,
password, the host name and forward.
So to connect to me
all time is more minutes.
Olga You mean I am rushing?
This is what this horse means.
I don't know.
Sometimes I feel like the mother.
The mother they can their children, even.
They are doing all they can understand.
If they are asking for the watermelon
or they are hungry or whatever,
they are right mothers.
They can just tell you by their gestures
or things like that.
I also sometimes feel like that
that's good. Not everything is about you.
Who? Why? What's the point?
That horse in this conversation
that we are trying to have
in 20, you really feel?
Student It was for Alex Okay.
Oh, you'll get all to hold your horses.
Oh, I got. So you guys started this.
I think that line was also best
and was also doing this.
Do you know someone in bed ten
Oh so glad the best.
Ten and nine.
Every time the students ask something
from future, they used to make this emoji.
They're smart to confuse me
because you guys didn't
use that too much in here.
You guys also do that.
So this is how we can combine
all the information
into something
that we can use in a Java program.
So we will be creating
something called a database.
You are in
that database, you are only contains
the information that the first part tells
you about the driver that you want to use.
Then the of day that I based
that you are working with,
then the IP address of the database
or the hostname, then the port name
and then the baby name.
So this is how we combine
all the information.
We create a very long string with stored
all of this information in here and.
Then we pass that information
to this method,
which is get connection,
and it threatens us connection.
Using that connection,
we can write queries
and we can get the results.
So now I want every one of you
to open your intelligence,
and I want every one of you
to create a Maven project this time.
And we
need any artifacts.
Let me know once you guys have
so let's call it
batch 11 baby testing
or or all of you are good.
Can I click on finish
guys,
are you here?
Okay.
Meanwhile, in days starting
from where I can find
the repositories for MAVEN project, write
my ask your old connector
and then maven.
Let me actually send you the link of this.
Please use this link.
If you are unable to find
and you guys already know
what what these numbers mean,
what is this usages and the dates,
the repositories and all that.
Right?
These are all vulnerable.
We should not
then is please focus in the class.
I know I know three or four
because I will be delaying that
about 10 minutes.
So right now this is the my what?
Your this one that is most widely used.
I mean, you're almost about to get this
vulnerable tag in here is flexibility.
This would
use this one.
You guys can call it anything or no,
it is already here.
Great. Know
who else is here?
Jamal, Are you also here?
And we are waiting for one more student
because some of them they asked that
please invite some female students
as well, especially.
So again, are you also here?
Okay, hold on. Is also joining
nice just the two
and just five more minutes.
Maybe you can also refresh this knowledge.
Okay.
Sorry I had to step out. Was that I may.
Yes it wasn't me.
When project
did you invite Steven?
The I am changing my name
to Steven from today.
Olga, how do you getting married?
You are getting married so I am not
of any use anymore.
You guys need real Steven.
Okay.
Who is single?
Single in this class in May?
I need a male single
format already.
This the autumn of Steven from today.
No, stop. You
to this Say I will be Steven.
No, no, no. I don't want to get killed.
If someone accidentally
when she gets to know this,
I am done.
All our guys.
Let's add this dependency.
I don't think so.
You guys are in the mode of learning
anything new.
We will continue from here.
Okay.
All right, guys. No.
Can you guys send me a message in here
so that I can make you host?
So I can also already allow them all?
I think you can talk now.
No, You should also be able to talk now.
Hi. Can you hear me?
Yep. Although I know I. Do.
You hear?
Nor are you here. Yes.
Can you hear me?
Yep, yep, yep. We can hear you.
Let me ask. Hold on.
Our She was waiting for for long
both party.
And you're still not at home.
Oh, Donna,
can you type something in the chat?
Let me check what username she used
for me.
Yeah, that's her.
No, she's not here.
She wrote something in a chat,
so she is here.
Her name is in Russian?
Yep Yep.
Okay, well, maybe you would.
I know you are here.
Okay. Why? Okay.
Okay.
Perfect. Oh.
What? I am unable to start.
Do I need a Russian keyboard
to search for her name? No.
You should be able to just and paste it.
It is not allowing me to copy and paste.
By the way, you guys can
share your camera's and.
And you can turn on your mic.
It's telling me I can start video
because hosts has stopped it.
Same here.
Let me change the settings
allow.
I know, I know.
Okay.
Now you should be able to do it.
There you go.
You know, can you also
I don't how the adoption
will share your screen.
I don't know.
I don't have the option.
Do you have a camera attached to your.
Yes. Yes.
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I know why you don't have any option.
Okay.
Yeah, I think.
No, Now you should have an option.
I'm good now.
Yeah.
Okay, so
you guys can start talking to each other.
Meanwhile, I will fix the issue. Oksana.
So this is batch 11.
They are.
They will be learning their last year
class tomorrow,
and they will be starting the police.
And here we have
law and all from batch ten.
I think you guys were in the group one,
right?
Yeah, one or two years.
It's like 2 to 3 weeks
since they started looking for the dogs.
And they can tell you very well,
how is the market now?
How many offers they got in.
Maybe they can also tell you the range
of salaries if they are kind enough
and you guys can ask
almost anything that you want just sure
that it does not offer any of that.
And if so, you guys can see the questions
in Life Channel, right?
Yes, I can see a screen
into yeah, yeah.
Let no take the stage
and then I'll go after him.
Okay. Okay.
So if you guys can start
from introducing yourself.
Sure. Hello, everyone.
My name is Anurag Hermansen
and I'm from Beijing.
So it's been almost I think it's
just been a month since actually,
I started looking for a job,
and within two weeks
I a job, I received an offer.
So the market is very hot.
And what ever we know so far,
what we learn in the index is,
it's just enough for finding a job.
So we shouldn't be worrying
about finding job.
I mean, we all have those questions,
especially when I mean, just
two months ago, I mean, I was still not
sure that will I learned a job or not.
But once you get into the market,
all the knowledge
that we have
that what we get and the syntax
is just
very, very good, that what we get
and then once we go into the market
and we can find a job.
But, you know, we just need a clear
and concise concept and learn
and never stop learning,
never stop practicing.
So that that's all that I can say.
Yeah.
Can should I say, okay.
Hi everyone.
My name is Jamal.
And when I started, I can also speak
to Saudi to you guys go, Hello.
Hello everyone looks a little. Yes.
You can also turn on your camera
if you are comfortable.
Yes, sure.
Yeah. Okay.
So just to tell a little bit about myself,
when I first learned about bootcamps.
I was very hesitant about it
because I didn't really like many of you.
I'm sure I didn't really trust
in bootcamps because how can you learn
something in six months
and then you can advertise yourself as
being experienced in that for five years
and try to land a job when.
There are real people who have been
working on the industry for more than us
and the they are struggling.
So I was hesitant at first,
but I decided to give it a shot,
take classes, see how they all go,
everything.
It starts slow, especially
since I have a computer science major.
So many of the things that we were
learning in the beginning seemed,
I guess easy in the beginning,
but as we kept going, it kept ramping up.
I'm sure by the time you guys get to
towards the end of the Java,
you guys realized that it's not just
just like Hello World and just that's it.
So once you get to polymorphism and stuff
like that, it starts getting crazy,
especially sequel API, Selenium, cucumber
like it is.
I guess it gets frustrating,
it gets confusing,
but if you put time in it, just listen
and just listen.
Study and put in that you
I'm sure everybody can get through
and like I'm sure everybody,
they work full time, They have kids,
they have like the married so so balancing
everything is not easy.
You have to put enough time
to for a full time job
and you have to put enough time
to study as well.
But If you do put time,
the market is like specialists
for the past several months at least,
as has been hot
like everybody in my batch
will have found jobs.
Everybody got at least two
or three offers,
and when you get two or three offers,
you can you can become picky,
you can choose what you want, you can like
even me in a beginning, like in
I would say in a week of interviewing,
I was able to land the offer,
but I didn't go with it because it wasn't
something I was looking for.
Typically, the salaries,
it depends on what you're looking for.
If you put at least five years
of experience in your resume,
you'll you will land something
at least more than 80000
to 130000, depending on how well you do
and how how complicated a job is.
The first one I landed was,
I think it was somewhere around 90,000,
which wasn't something I was looking for.
So I kept looking and after two weeks
of interviewing back and forth,
like every day, if you looked
at my calendar, like from 10 a.m.
to 5 p.m., 6 p.m., it would be
it was scheduled to interviews.