Nobel Peace Prize.
These go to tanks.
I was connected about an hour ago.
Is there any antivirus or
something like that
that might be stopping you from connection
or something like that?
Maybe you should restart your computer.
Only three more weeks of classes
until interview prep.
Oh, you guys are already done
with the course?
Yes, you.
You are just left with the AP classes and.
Yep, the two genuine classes that sit.
Yep. Yep.
So finally,
you guys are ready by David D batch
and they are doing very well.
One group is all for around.
It's their third week.
For the second group,
it's their second week.
And 15 of them, they already have offers
which which they have accepted
and other around other ten more students.
They are in process.
So hopefully by the next week
they will also be finalizing
their offers,
being drawn up by the state of mind.
I refuse to accept.
So if you guys want,
maybe we can invite some students
from Belgium
as well on Sunday or Saturday.
Remind me if you guys want to meet them.
I am scared.
We are all grown up.
Okay.
Remind me on on Friday.
I will.
And I will invite some of them again.
How was your homework, guys?
What are you guys able to do?
It was easy, hard.
It was pretty easy.
Just took a little bit of time
to find the right column names.
E That database is
is huge.
It has kind of.
How about earlier?
How did we find these columns
or a term job title
as such a chart employee A Our dependance
you guys
then you didn't find these tables.
Did I miss something?
Yes. These are tables,
not columns actually.
So you guys can have a look at
these tables
in here.
Almost done and everything is gone.
I did not say a word.
Somehow I lost it.
This at just a job. Employees.
If you go inside the columns,
they all the columns.
If you guys want, maybe we can agree
we can go all the some homework
otherwise I think they were pretty easy
can go around
doing homework.
All right guys,
let me do this.
Let's
let's give some winners for the region.
But so let's start from
this database team.
So can you guys tell me
what is in database?
Hello?
Hello.
And why we are learning about databases,
software to store and fetch
data from.
Okay, organize and manage data.
So it's a specialized software that stores
and manages the information for you.
Right?
It is a storage.
Yes, it's a storage tree.
And most of all, what are those three VMs
manipulate, manage.
Good question.
Can we go over little hole ask page file,
curious to see and below other icons?
Oh yes.
In here
I seem to you in this one
I or you mean these icons in here?
I think otherwise joining to a different
class.
So this
button in
here it says
create a new obscure tab for executing.
So if you click on you will be having it
kind of your same
as if you guys are creating
new classes in intelligence.
So it will open a new file
where you can write your queries.
And this one is to open
the already saved scripts
that you might have on your computer.
This one is open, Inspector
for this selected object.
So most of the time
you guys will not be needing them
because there are high chances
that you guys will be using
a different software and you will find
different buttons and functionality
in that piece of software.
How we can change a name.
Uh, because this is the
most advanced software ever created,
you guys have to first
store the file to make changes.
So you see,
I just clicked on that work and then,
I don't know, maybe I have to start this.
I assume this is because of you will see.
You asked me about that.
Oh, let's not go over the next icons.
Otherwise
I don't think we will be able to continue
on this class.
Okay. I am sorry.
Please, please respond back to me.
Please close this program.
No rules.
Yes, but I'm really around
the line of what I thought was like
almost salaam set
the has.
Try these buttons
and let me know what these buttons do.
Or maybe we can have a separate ball
after the class.
So let's.
Let's focus on the things that work.
This is your database.
These are the tables inside your database.
And if you want to
have a look, let's see inside
each of
the tables and there that are types
and then you can expand them.
This foreign key then triggers indexes.
I will teach you later.
For now,
you should only care about these
column names,
these indexes.
They are something to make your queries
faster for keys.
We will learn in next class and triggers
are you guys can do it.
Pretty simple.
Triggers are special events
that when whenever those events happen
and if you want to execute a special duty
against those events,
you can provide those days.
In here, for example,
if a rule is inserted inside a table
and you want to do something special,
you can do that.
If something is deleted from a table,
maybe you want to create a backup of
that role which is being deleted
from a table inside another table.
So usually we implement
these kind of things in the triggers
triangle threat.
But you guys still remember
those drawings of wrappers.
Okay, maybe I should watch that video
for you guys.
You guys give us time to Muslin, right
out of it.
Please don't give him a tough time.
He is magic one.
Anything he I think he married like
just before this bash started around
four months or five months.
So those were his initial days.
Maybe that's why he was confused
about those drawings.
If you
so well,
what is the difference
between my school and school
guys?
The difference between my school
and as you know, at
he is still trying to forget
those wrappers.
I think it's
a school is a spender
and my school is an open source database.
Great answer for the a perfect answer.
So is the standard and skill stands
for Structured Query Language.
While my school is a database
which is an open source
spec, our base.
So these are the three M's manipulate,
manage and maintain.
And a database is a storage system
that allow users to keep, organize
and manage data.
Right.
And why should not
why should we not use a software
like maybe Microsoft Excel
or something like that?
Why should we go with the databases
slow, cannot handle
large amounts of data,
cannot implement security.
For example,
if you want to allow the access
for certain tables to certain employees,
it will be possible with the skill,
but it will be hard
and it will not be scalable.
Can you guys tell me the names of maybe
three famous databases
because of amount of data?
My skill? Yes.
The open source
for companies will be using my school.
The which companies will be using Oracle
and the companies
who don't care about their products
and good quality of service.
They will be using my SQL Server,
which is the database
from Microsoft. And
so you can judge a company
from the database that they are using
and what about the
what about the guide that will be helping
you regarding your database?
It is, let's say, for example,
if you want to ask
to reset to your bill, your password,
or if you want to create an
if you want to have the credentials
to connect to the database
or if you are facing
any issue with the database.
So to whom
you should connect in your company,
you should connect the
to database administrator, right?
They are called a DB is the word,
but we always use Oracle in our job
or only my assortment.
Depends on your company, which company
you will be using Oracle for Company
you will be using my ask you.
So they are called DB as database
administrators and it's a separate team
that only manages your databases.
So we have a team of developers,
we have a team of testers,
we have a team of dev ops guys
who will be taking care of
all the softwares that you might need
to install on your laptops
to perform your duties.
And we will be having database teams,
we will be having admin teams
who will be taking care of your things,
like providing you
with a laptop and all of that.
In interview, I will first ask
which you obviously are using your
SO are there only one types of databases
or will we have multiple
types of databases?
Is a squirrel is a database? I think so.
I think so.
Yes, it is a database,
but it also looks that
someone from back six
or seven has great good
discoveries
from the look and feel of this.
And when they say my skill, we will say,
don't bother sending me and all offer us.
They told me you guys are more oh they
might we been good to their employers.
That's why they might be cutting the cost
from the tools and do
databases is also possible
and there is a donate button.
No it is not a database.
Yeah,
it might be an open source that is
it is a universal squirrel blind.
I think it's something similar
to my skill workbench.
If I am not wrong.
A software to interact
with your back to this.
Okay.
Your voice is making me sleepy today
or it always happens with me
whenever my machine learning
professor here
starts to teach half of the class.
Go to sleep.
Yes, it happens.
Me What should I do?
Let me start again.
Hey guys, let's do the database today.
What is it?
Better.
Okay, so
can you guys tell me the.
Well, what is the relational database?
That is why we love you.
Thank you, guys.
Well,
what type of databases do you guys know?
Two types of databases.
Two main types of databases, right?
One are
your voice
is like from a meditation video.
I don't know, Maybe I just woke up.
That's like my voice is
something like this.
I was dreaming of all of my
next thunderclap, all of that.
And then I And then my alarm
woke me up
just about waiting
most of our.
How do you know?
Are you also single or planned long time?
No, I am not.
Okay, guys,
let's see what happens with me.
So can you guys tell me
the types of databases I have?
Toolkits, all my bunch.
You were dreaming.
I was dreaming about my credit card
being used to its full limit.
And then I woke up relational
and not relational databases.
Right.
And what are these relational databases?
Is this the database?
My skill that we are learning right now?
Is it a relational database
comes through sometimes, Yes.
She just told me
she is looking for solutions
and so we are planning a family dinner.
Then.
She has already searched
all the restaurants
and salons and everything
that is available
in the heart waste of money.
I don't know.
So also I ask her, Well,
what do you want to have?
Do you want to do this alone?
So she gave me a very long list and
I thought maybe she is all of the magic.
Your particular I don't know,
what are these things?
And then this.
And then I ask her,
So is there anything for me?
She told me there is something
for me as well.
So let's check
what is it?
Easy to this loan for me
as that is room on me.
So can you guys
tell me about the relational databases
this is only the beginning.
Relational database.
It is this my skill and Oracle
are the relational databases
or what are the sequence database?
Okay, see or more.
Can you please elaborate a little bit?
What do you mean by sequence of database?
So I am asking
if my school is a relational database
or it is a non relational database.
Relational databases are called sequence
that ABC stole.
I think it is that are stored
based on tables.
So most of the industry is still using
a relational databases and why
they are called relational databases
because the data is stored
in the form of tables.
And these tables
they have some kind of relationships.
We will learn how to tables
can have a relationship and how
we can
create a new relationships
and how we can analyze
the existing relationships and why
we even need to create multiple tables.
Why not store
all the data inside a single table?
So we will learn that in the next class.
Then we will be looking at joints
and the other types of databases.
They are called non relational databases
and they there are quite a few of them.
And MongoDB is also very famous,
non relational database
supplier base is also a database
that is non relational.
It is from Google.
So most notably
you guys will be interacting with Firebase
or MongoDB if you will be working with non
relational databases.
And the good news is
that even though these databases
they are not relational
database is still you guys can use
50% or 60% of the skill knowledge
to query
the data from those databases as well.
So this skill will also be helpful
for building good data
and non relational databases.
And as data is stored
in the form of tables,
tables have rows and columns,
same as Excel files.
And this is a very important interview
question as well, guys.
What is a primary key?
Why? Why? You would need a primary key.
Can we have a crash session on Firebase?
Sometimes?
Damir It depends if you guys are
if yeah, if the Firebase database
is being used in the testing environment
or not.
Otherwise from my side.
Yes, I can deliver a very good session
because you have been
working with Firebase
for quite some time in the past.
I think you I still will be having some
instances that I created in the past
for my projects
for Android applications in here.
So this is how the Firebase database
looks like.
Guys.
It has this real time database.
And then there is
this flier store database.
This is the document based database
that I was talking about yesterday.
Let me just give you a look.
So this is a database
that does not have tables
and it does not have
columns and rolls.
So instead it has documents.
So in here.
So this
this is the database that I have created.
This is the folder inside of this database
in here.
I can add a document and inside of
that document I can start adding the data.
So for example, I have added firstname
and I have spotted a value inside of that.
So instead of having those rows
and columns,
this is how you guys can store
the data inside it.
Then we have a bar also,
which is called Real time databases,
most of which get applications.
They are built
using this real time database.
So it will be stored in the data
in the form of developers.
So this is the database name.
It has this user and inside the cluster,
let's
say I can create a developer like email
the password and the role
and things like that.
And then if you want to store
images, videos or other files,
you have this storage option in here
so I can upload the files in here.
Let's say, for example,
in the same text banner
and you guys can connect this to your
applications.
Like, for example,
I can share the link with you
and you guys can see this image
from anywhere.
If you have the proper credentials.
Oops,
check.
I think this is building
for this website. Yes.
So most of the
android applications
on the iOS application, they
they are using these kind of databases and
these kind of storage systems
now because they are highly scalable.
They can support billions of users.
So Android applications, they have already
started hitting billions of users.
New build.
I think last month
it appeared the 10 billion downloads
and these are some functions
that you can write on over the databases.
And if you want
to have some machine learning
and here you will find and by the way,
these are free.
And some of you,
if you want to have a look at your end,
you guys can also do this.
Just go to Firebase and you can start
using the Firebase Direct base.
So this is how a non relational database
looks like.
So primary keys must contain unique values
and can't contain null values.
Yes, that is correct.
Primary key, unique key
that differentiates
between those same records
in say column.
Okay, primary key is to have a unique part
to information stored in a adroll.
Well, why we need a primary key, guys.
Why we need a primary.
We can't really store or retrieve big data
without the primary key
to uniquely distinguish our data.
So let's say if we have duplicate data
or if we want to create a relation.
So primary is
and foreign keys will make much more sense
in the next class,
then we will be looking at joints.
So it will be super, super clear
why we need the private keys
and the foreign keys.
So as a tester
we mostly use select statement
to extract select specific data
from a database.
So this is what you guys will be doing
most of the time.
All other things are setting up
a database, creating users,
creating tables,
creating functions, storing the data.
Most probably you guys will not be doing
that, right?
Yes, obviously.
And deleting the data
and getting fired from the company.
You can also do that.
So we discussed about some of reserved
world word, the famous wizard world.
If we have to fight to do that out
from our database now please
can you guys tell me those wizard
What if I have to do that now
with which word my security will start?
It will start from this select E word
and after the select keyword.
What do I specify? Guys,
After the select keyword
worldwide, specify,
we can specify the columns
from which we want to fetch the data.
Right.
And after
mentioning the names of the columns,
what is the next keyword
that we need to specify?
We need to specify the from keyword
and after.
From keyword we specify the name of the
table
from which we want to fetch that data.
And so if I want to filter out
the columns,
I can use the select statement, right?
Let's say after this statement,
if I am specifying only
two columns, I will be getting good data
from only two columns.
So if I am specifying
three columns, all three columns,
so I'm kind of filtering the columns
from a table using the select statement
right.
And if I want to filter out the rows,
if I want to filter out the rows,
which keyword I can use.
So to filter out the columns,
I specify
those columns after they select
the filter are the rows I use.
The where clause right inside
where clause.
I can specify
different different conditions.
So in the last class all you guys learned
about these conditions,
like let's say for example,
you want to only bring those rules for
which the value of age is greater than 25.
And it is less than 20, right?
So this condition,
it will basically filter out the rows
from that table.
All right.
And again, I again,
again, you can we said that the data
that we stored inside the database,
it will always be having
some kind of order or or is it random?
Can we say that
the data in which you and the
the order
in which we are inserting the data,
we will be getting the data
in the same order?
No, right.
It totally depends upon the database
software,
how that database software
is storing that data.
But what if I
have to bring the data in a certain order
which keyword which clause
I can use for that?
The order by clause. Right.
And what do I specify after the order
by clause, the name of the column
based on which I want to perform
this sorting.
And by default, if I don't specify
ascending or descending,
yes, the default is ascending right?
So if the column contains
an automatic data,
it will be in the increasing
order of numbers.
If it contains the string data,
then it will be looking at the
ASCII values of that data
and it will be performing disheartening
in alphabetical order.
Right.
So order by class or clause is
we we write this order by clause,
then we write the name of the table.
So let's say if we only exit,
I hope the font is readable.
So if I only execute this query.
Oh yeah. So I'm getting an error.
The NSA has no database selected
what I am doing
wrong in here.
You have to run the table, execute
first line to indicate the database.
Right, so as there can be
multiple databases inside the same server.
So first we need to tell
which database we want to query,
we on which database
we want to execute these duties.
So if I execute this, a statement
that is yours
and after the use, we have specified
the name of the database.
Now if I execute the queries, okay,
so now I see my data.
So right now if you guys observe
the data does not have
any special order.
So ID 23 is first,
then we have gone be done 30.
But if I want to solve that database
based on maybe name or age,
what I can do, I can write this order
by clause and after that I can specify
the name of the column
based on which I want to sort this data.
So right now we see John and Mary
and I leave, but after I execute
complete period that has order by clause
and the first name you guys will notice
that the data will be sorted
according to the first names.
And again, I also thought my database
on multiple columns,
maybe more than one column.
Yes, right.
In that case, the first priority is given
to the first name
column and if there is something
that is duplicate.
So according to the first column,
these three names may look
same. Right? So.
So the sorting will look
same for these three columns.
In that case, the skill will try to look
for the values
that are inside the second column
that we have specified in here
to perform this article.
And then if we want to do it
in descending order,
we can specify this descending in here
right.
All right.
So how the nulls are treated in school
are the null values?
Are they
are the equivalent of empty values?
Are they are empty values are null,
values are the same.
They are different. Right?
So if I want to filter out
the role roles to based on
null values, can I use the equal to sign
or the not equal to sign
that we learned in the last class,
or I should treat them
specially.
So if we are working with the null values,
we cannot use the equal to sign.
Right.
But I am sure after sometimes,
maybe after three weeks,
if you guys will be writing some queries,
you guys will be using
those equal to sign
and you will be getting incorrect results.
So instead of that equal to sign,
you guys should use the is null
and is not an operator.
Right.
And if we are interacting
with character based data
and if we don't use the course,
we can also get unexpected results.
So we also have to make sure that
if the data type
of the column
is nomadic, we are not using the course.
And if the data type
is based on the metric based,
then we are using detect our types.
And this is same
as what you guys have been doing in Java,
specifying the conditions based on and
and between.
Is there any difference
between using this between operator
and using this greater
than or less than sign?
No on the same right.
But some of the databases
they might not support
this between operator
Okay.
Here is a question for you guys.
Let me write a query in here
and you guys have to tell
if I can write this query in a better way.
So I select all from I'm
not using the uppercase.
Yeah.
So that we can type
with cluster to select all from
person.
We have
first name is equal to
maybe John
or last
name is equal to
maybe John
or ID is equal to 23.
So my question is,
can I replace this acuity
with the operator?
Can I use the in operator in here?
And at first you said we can use in
and now you are saying
no, yes or no.
What do you guys say?
Can I use the operator here?
Not sure with the words.
If we can.
They are not from the same column.
Oh my God.
From the last time I remembered you were
struggling with the Java and now your.
Your answers. They are perfect, man.
I'm very happy.
I thought you would write the same column.
Okay, so in is shorthand
for or right after Java,
he became very smart.
Yes, I remember.
So I can not use the interpreter
in here. Why?
Because this is a different column.
This is a different column.
And this is a different column.
For example, I can not do this.
You guys are almost ready, right?
I cannot do this. We are first name
in Dawn.
Because, you
see, I also need to specify the column.
So if I don't specify the column,
because why does it say it's shorthand
for or Indian or.
Yes, it is a shorthand for the or
if you are writing the condition
for the same column.
Maria, while you were in March,
we grew up, so I cannot do this right
or so I hate it like this.
Right?
Because this is this belongs to a column.
This belongs to last column.
But if we write this,
you re using the in operator.
All of these values will be treated
as if these are the values
inside the first name column.
So that's why we cannot use the
in operator in here. Here
you will be getting incorrect results.
All right.
And then we learned
about the like, operator
and you guys tell me
or do this like operator
All right.
You literally
you guys named your group as repositories
or you guys are just getting
that,
Oh, my God, I'll let you go.
I mean, by any mistake,
if the instructor has done
something wrong, you guys are not
you guys are not forgetting that,
Inspector.
Right? You will follow him to the end.
We named it
Repository in tribute to drive.
Now I will definitely look while I'm
watching that video.
It's know Tell him.
Actually, I didn't tell him.
I just gave him a hint
when I heard about those drawings
and he started speaking himself
telling me why why
he did those drawings
and why it went wrong and all that.
So I got his point.
I will never forget how it happened.
Slide. I will.
I will
look at that with your during the break.
I did not
know.
I cannot have patience.
How do you explain?
You guys also have the
I mean, by any mistake,
if you're a senior
he is doing something wrong.
Right.
He will be in specific trouble.
And so
this like operator,
we can use this like operator
to perform
the searching based on wild card
operators.
So this and this person did
it is called the wild card operator.
This underscore
it is also a wild card operator
and how this person based sign works.
So let's say, for example,
if you want to search
the rules
that start from specific letters,
you are not doing something wrong,
but something totally different.
And that night, honestly,
I could not focus at
if so,
if let's say you want to perform
a flexible
search,
you can use this wild card operator
and this person design.
And in here what we are saying,
we are saying that he ask
you will give us all the rules
for which the first name
starts with the letter E,
and after that letter A, we don't care
how many,
how many letters are there,
or what are those letters?
So we don't care about the length
and we don't care about the type.
So it will bring you all the rules
for which the first name starts
with the letter.
So you guys will notice all the letters,
all the rules that Discovery has brought.
They all start with like that.
Can you guys tell me if I execute the same
and if I have the same data
on an Oracle database,
will I get the same result or will
I be getting slightly different results?
So if we execute the same, I think
well, we will
be getting different results on
on on an Oracle database.
I think you guys are too much growing up.
Right.
Okay.
For all.
Not really.
Not after those grinds as well.
Now I see
while my skill is case insensitive. Yes.
So if we had these same data
on an Oracle database,
for example,
we will not be getting this result. Why?
Because this law
has the name letter,
but it is in the case.
No, I know.
And in here
we have specifying the uppercase A right.
So Oracle database
because it is case sensitive
inside these course
that's why we will be getting different
those
yes for the Oracle database
we need to specify lowercase
and the uppercase in here.
Yes. This is the only difference.
And today we will learn how we can avoid
writing uppercase
and lowercase things because So
then we will learn about the functions
which can actually convert your vector
into lowercase or uppercase.
Same as you guys learned
about the starting met
methods in which you guys had the,
you know, the case
lowercase or uppercase or things like that
for these type of databases,
which are case sensitive.
And if we specify this person to assign
us, that also draws but
in a very complicated way to confuse us.
And Ms.
in instances like that,
if that ever happens.
Okay, so if we specify this person
design guys before
and then if we specify the letter
after back, how it will
how the results will differ in this case,
how a school will treat the first names.
If we specify the person based sign first,
and then the vector.
So it means there can be.
So all the first names that end
add the letter M, right?
There can be any number of detectors
before and
there can be any characters before.
And but the last letter should be M So
it will give us all the rules
for which should be first name.
Then paint ends at the letter M
So now
so you see first name.
Adam First names, right?
So all both of these
they and add the letter N
And if we want to perform a search,
like for example, something,
something similar to the contains
method that you guys learned
in the string classes, right?
So this time we don't care about
any number of letters
before a certain letter
or there can be any number of letters
after starting letters.
Right?
So it is, it is similar
to the contains in that type.
So now
wherever
you guys have a letter M
inside the first name column,
it will bring all those rows
if we execute this right.
Yes. Person did I, for example.
So in this first rule,
in this first case,
we have the letter M at the very start
in here, also at the very start.
And here start in here at the end.
And in here at the end as well.
And what what is the difference, guys,
between this person sign
and this underscore sign?
Two letters. The first is m.
And so if I ask you
which one is more restrictive,
A, is the underscore more restrictive
or the person based sign more restrictive?
The second one, right? Why?
It is more restrictive
because it also counts
how many letters can be
before that specific letter
or how many letters can be after
that specific letter.
Right. In the person they sign.
We don't care how much
that there can be any number of letters
before or after that.
M But when we use the underscore sign,
it means that there can be
only two letters in the first name column.
The first should be M,
and the second can be anything.
So it will only bring the doors, the rows
first that have only two letters.
And also the first letter should be
and a m in here.
In here
we are saying that as you'll give us
the results from the table,
but only give us only those results
for which the first name
column contains at
a contains three letters.
And the first two letters should be G
and you and you.
You can have this flexibility there.
And the third letter
can be anything, right?
So will it bring the.
So we see only two letters.
What do you guys think?
Can it also bring the results, let's say,
and if we have a first name
that contains two letters
or it will only care about
the first names, which have three letters
that are three letters, Right.
Very restrictive.
And most of the time
you guys will be searching
date of third inside the database
using these wild card operators.
But you can also search last name,
the last name.
So these two wild cards
and they will be very, very helpful in
bringing
when whenever you guys will be writing,
be curious
to bring some data from your back on base.
So now tell me if some of you have faced
any issues with the homework questions.
They were very simple,
but we can solve some of them for you.
I can solve some of them for you.
If you guys had a hard time
solving those.
How many wild card operations we have?
The famous one are these two?
Hossein I have never seen.
I have never used them.
There might be more,
but I have never seen any developer using
other wild card operators than these two.
I think there is one more famous
that is that forward slash thing, but
it is not supported by all the databases.
So this person design and underscores
saying you will be able to use
in almost all the databases
last one freelance
and the developer. Yes.
I think
Silva also asked about this question.
So there is a table
in which we have specified the titles.
If we find they will follow you
in the whole
group.
I think it's all a title
or something like that.
Yes. Job tracker.
So if you query this, this table,
is this table empty or not?
Yes. I assume unfortunately,
we gave the access to
I think it was by seven or by six,
and they almost destroyed our database.
That's why you guys will not find out by
in some of the tables.
After that we started restricting things
and from that day we have some that are in
some of the tables.
So if you look carefully,
you have the titles in here.
Don't you have a backup?
No, we only set up this database
for our testing purposes. Right.
We are not using this website
to do any business.
I mean, obviously it is being used,
but not with that priority.
So we kind of
just set up the start of base for you guys
and then we realize, yes,
we should be having a backup.
Is it plus two or three?
So we actually covered two classes
in the last class.
And so, yes, it is class number three.
They are family members.
How did you write the name for the class
Batch 11, Class three or unit two?
So, for example, you need to click on this
sign to have this new editor.
And once you click on control controls,
then this
great software created by
Google, it will allow you to
have a name for your editor.
The name of the database is syntax
item underscore skill.
The name of the table is person
y, The name is person while
it should be papers
because everything falls under tables,
please explain.
So I'll do the same
until you are saying that this table name
should be tables instead of person.
So why?
Why? Why?
Why do you think so?
Why we call it person?
Why we should call it table
person is all the way down.
That person is all the way down.
I don't know what person is
all the way up.
I don't know.
All the tables will have the same name.
So you want to call every table as table
maybe.
Table
one. Table to table three. Table four
person is the name of the table.
And to be at that, it's
I don't worry about this.
You can name your tables.
Anything person is all the way
at the end of the table.
A person is all the way.
What do you mean by person is all the way
at the end of the table
person folder.
You mean in here?
So that's why
you think it should be called a table
Because it is lying all the way.
It is lying in here
because I created this table
after all of these tables
and I created this table
for you guys
so that I can explain the concept
on a very small table that has a few rows
of data so that you guys can
easily understand the concept.
Previously, for previous batches,
we were using these big tables
and students are having a hard time
understanding the concepts.
So that's why I created this short table.
So there is no purpose,
there is no meaning.
The only purpose this table exists is
so that you guys can understand
the concepts easily and I created without
looking at their names
or something like that.
The only reason why it has the name person
because it contains
the personal data of a person.
That's why I give the name person.
But if you want to give it
a different name, yes you guys can do
it is usually decided
by architects and higher management.
What will be the tables?
Table names
so you guys don't need to worry about
because you guys
will never create in your tables,
either the libs or the developers
will create table person.
Yes, you guys can also table person
because in databases
sometimes there is a confusion
between triggers.
So there are so many things in a database.
There are functions,
procedures, views and tables.
So yes, I met some of the companies
they follow this convention that they put
table before the names of the tables
so that they can easily identified
if they are interacting with the table.
I hope it is better now.
So what what I
okay, so I was saying that in here
you guys have these ideas
and you have the job title.
So let's say, for example,
if you want to find out
all the freelancers,
if the bad seven
has not deleted a freelancer,
you should have a freelancer in here.
So here we go.
So the idea for the freelancer is
29, right?
So what we can see
a freelancer has the idea 29.
Now, if you go to the
at just a job employee payable
and if you go to the
if you focus on the column, you will see
you have mission code,
you have employed
gender code, marital status.
And in here you will see
there is
this column that says job title code.
And now you guys can
then can you tell me
what does this quantitative means
They are
because actually of the job titles.
So if you guys focus in here
where it is equal to 23,
you guys can find out
what does this 23 means.
So 23 means it is
this person is an API tester.
So this table contains
because but not the actual job title.
So first you have to find out the actual
job titles from this or item job title.
And then you have to structure your query.
So for example,
you have to say here, look,
we're job
title
code is equal
in 2029.
If this for Freelancer,
what was the other requirement?
Freelancer and
when you double click on the table
limited capacity to the code
or the column name developer
and let me just give me one moment.
I will explain what happens
when we do that.
So it is a feature that helps you write
queries faster.
Come on.
So developer have the code of ten.
All right.
So now it will bring all the freelancers
and the developers, if there are any, left
by the great batch
six and seven.
Oh yes, there are a lot of them.
So all of them,
they are either freelancers or developers.
So this is how you guys
were supposed to do this
task.
Does it make sense? Guys
select employ first name, last name
from a just a job or
not really.
It is wrong,
but this is a topic of the next class.
I am glad that
if you guys have written this security
and if you guys are able to
figure out how you can
combine two tables like this,
it requires a slight modification and
you will be getting good results.
But we will discuss
that in the next class.
Can you tell again
how to solve out of code 1040, Mahmut,
I have not memorized
the because of all the errors.
Can you tell me
when can you can you show the error,
please?
1046i don't know.
I don't want to show me the error.
Please.
I think if you get this error
when you have not selected it
that obvious, I am not sure.
Okay.
104610461046.
No database selected.
So if you are getting this error,
you have to execute this query use
and then the database name
and then you should not react.
This.
Can you please confirm
if you after executing this use
and then the database name
if you still get the error.
All right.
Those so yes.
Are there other homework questions
that you guys want me to solve?
Why didn't you start
with the user statement as in previous?
So now we have to execute that duty
only once.
When we started the MySQL workbench.
After that,
it takes that value by default.
But if you are writing this script
for a different database
and this one for a different one,
then you can execute that again.
Just for the inside info.
I also like the back note in the use.
Yes, that is not in use as well.
I'm not sure if you are right.
So as we have in operator,
we also have that not in operator.
Is there any other homework question
guys that you want me to solve?
Maybe you guys had a hard time
understanding something, or
maybe it be that I was not present.
So simple. Stupid.
The question that there was no data
against a specific employee ID.
So yes, this is possible.
Some of the data
might be deleted. And these
these
these questions were designed before that.
Can you add a select first name?
Last name.
But your job title on the nine
or ten in yours?
Then you add I said,
What do you mean by ADD.
You want me to execute this query in here
like this?
Okay.
I did that.
It is still same.
I think you make sure you are specifying
the correct of the database.
Let me actually copy this.
Execute this on your editor.
Look like mine is showing
just the job title
column.
Mine is showing just the job title column.
That is not possible
because you have not specified the job
back in the select statement.
Then how can you get the job title column
on your editor?
Can you guys please confirm?
Can you guys also execute this
and tell me?
If you guys get the job
title column in the output? Yes.
Let me try on new page.
No, I think you don't need to try
on the new page.
Make sure that you select
this duty like this
and then you execute it.
It is possible that might be
your cursor was here or here and.
You just clicked on this button in here?
Yes, ma'am.
There might be a spelling mistake. Why?
Get what?
Oscar has no script.
So if you guys don't have
any questions,
let's have a ten minute break.
And after the break,
we will start the today's
class.
My escuela is same as your school.
So did.
There was a joke also about this.
My school.
So we were using this.
My school
and the information that I based from IBM
and our manager
was a non-technical person.
So we told her
that my school is not working.
So I told her my,
my school is not working here.
She said, please, your
my colleague was channel
and he told me, please use the condoms.
Ask us to ask you,
but I need this work to be done
by the end of today.
So yes, for the non-technical person
sometimes it might be confusing.
The manager will just say I don't give you
someone else to that school.
I just need the work done.
Were manager
C accidentally gave me a box.
Actually not accidentally.
She was the same manager.
I told her that I can do this with.
I can write a piece of software and
we can solve this problem maybe in a week.
But she told me, No, you have to do it
manually.
And I told her it will take like
three months to perform this manually.
She said, It's okay, it's fine.
And still I wrote that piece of software.
I corrected all the data using acuity
and I enjoyed
three months in my last company.
So they are also blessing
actually these kind of managers.
They are also blessing.
So please
don't argue too much with your manager.
If they are saying
you have to do it manually,
tell them okay, we will do it manually,
but then write a piece of software
to solve something like that.
Yes, this is a very important device.
Your manager is always right. It's
God, it is an automatic.
You come back.
The selecting. The whole rule helps.
I thought this blessing
because that after I will do that.
Oh I cannot fool my my wife.
That is a very big problem
because she is also a software engineer
and doing her masters in CSS.
I will be in a little trouble.
All right, guys, see you in 15.
Please remind me about that
recording as well. The
All right.
So today
we will discuss about the functions
sometimes people need
a little more motivation.
So in
in school, we have two types of functions.
So they are categorized
and you do
you guys know
if you only know how to make the.
And she has already told me
that there
that that is the best that you can do.
So don't expect anything from me.
Yes, I can cook
because I spend a lot of time
in the hostel when I was in my engineering
so I can almost cook everything
but she only knows how to make the
SO two types of main functions.
One of them are called single
row functions
and the others are called multi row
functions,
the single row of functions.
So the single row function,
this is how they work.
They will take
a value from a row, from a table
and they will apply that function
on that value and they produce.
It is also one row as the input,
so one row as input
and one rule as output,
1 to 1 correspondence
while the multi row functions.
I still don't know how to cook
and I am having a baby.
It's fine.
So the multi row functions,
they will take any number of role as input
and they will produce a single value
as the output.
So this is the difference.
For example, a multi row
function can take all of these values.
Actually,
let me show you a different example.
I recently bought an electric cooker
and I cook different dishes.
Maybe I could better than you. And
so for example,
why you selected before running short?
I selected after running for one,
you can just click the second button.
This one? Yes we can. Yep. Yep.
Yes You are right,
if that is what you mean.
Yeah.
So for example,
the multi row function guys,
what it can do,
it can take all of these values
and it can, let's say maybe calculate
the average of these values.
So it will be a multi function
taking all of these
values, producing a single output.
Another example may be taking all of these
values and produce
as some of these values.
Another example may be it can tell you
the count of these rules, how many count,
how many values are there.
So multiple functions
they will take multiple as input
and they will produce a single value
as the output,
while on the other hand, the
single role functions.
They will take a single value as an input
and they will produce a single value
as the output.
So if I ask you
the let's say I have a function
that converts the values to lowercase
the text based values, the string values,
can you guys tell me if it will be
a multi row
function or single row function?
Is this function taking multiple roles
and only producing a single output
or taking multiple inputs
and producing multiple outputs?
Let me repeat this lower function.
What it can do, it can take
John and I add the output.
If there are any uppercase letters,
it will convert those to lowercase.
Right?
If let's say I give it this goal,
it will produce me a good with lower GST.
If I give MJ,
it will produce me a lowercase MJ.
So is it a multi row function
or a single row
function?
It says single role function, right?
Because for each input
it is generating an output.
Why, if I ask you, let's say may be
to calculate
minimum value out of these values.
Let's say if I write a function min
that gives me the minimum value
out of all of these values,
will it be a multi row
function or single row?
Yes, it will be a multi row function.
Right now let me show you common
single row and material function
that you guys might be using only.
So this is a set of statements
that performs to a separate
values, parameters, returns
the process value right?
So single row functions, add on each row
and return one result part The rule
can be used select and where clauses
and they can have arguments.
And the arguments will be the columns.
Or you can also use expressions.
So some of the examples
of single functions, they are character
based functions like uppercase,
lowercase, initial capitalization
of functions, or let's
say may be substring or things like that.
All these first two uppercase
lowercase substring,
all those functions that you guys have
learned, almost all of those functions
that you have learned in the string class,
they are available in here.
Then we have the date function.
Like, for example,
if you want to calculate
the number of days between two dates
or let's say, for example,
if you want to find out the month
or the year from a given date
in the form of a text or something,
or if you want to convert a date
from one format to another format.
So you will be using those functions.
And then we have a number of functions.
I will show you
the examples of these functions.
So these functions operate on single row
and only return a single output.
So for example,
let me show you the lower function.
So let's say
I am selecting the first name
from person right?
So, so right now I see these names,
but so some of them,
they contain uppercase letters, right?
If I don't want those uppercase letters,
I can use a function
so I can write the name of the function,
and then I can give this
column name as the argument that function.
And now what this will do,
it will apply this function
on E to value of this column.
So now you guys will see
that there will be no uppercase
letters in the output
that function that showed us to convert
the data type from character to pneumatic
was also a function.
So if you want to convert it to uppercase,
we also have this upper function in here.
Now, again, these functions, they depend
they can be
different from database to database.
Some of the functions
might work on my sequel database
and they might not work
on Oracle database.
So and
they might also have
different names on different databases.
So this lower function,
it might be called something slightly
different on an Oracle database
or informative database.
But so you can always Google things.
Yes, we can also define our own functions,
but Most of the time developers
do this kind of stuff as the test of the.
You guys will not be defining
your own functions
for defining your own function.
There is a second part of school
that you guys need to learn,
and so school is divided
into four main parts DML
and PCRs and things like that
that I will show you,
I think in fourth class of first class.
So you as a tester will
mainly be focus will be focusing on
DML, part data manipulation, language.
The other parts of the school.
We will not be going into those parts.
Can we look for first name
that starts with uPAR.
So Dennis now
as I have told earlier,
it depends on the database.
So you can search on the on the Google
for that specific function.
If that function is available
in the my school or not.
So you want less.
So for example for the first name
that starts with uppercase.
So let's try to search.
Okay, so you want to convert a name,
You want to convert all the names to
the names
that have first letter as the uppercase
or you want to perform a search that.
The query should give you the results
for only those letters.
I think for this one
you have to write something,
something complex.
How to
search.
Because on my school,
the gear sensitive thing is you,
as you have noticed,
upper and lower settings.
They are same on on in school.
So I think this question
will make much more sense on how to search
all the names
that have first letter as
uppercase. My
as you will.
So then there might be things
capitalized.
First letter how we can capitalize.
I'll find the first uppercase letter in
the string skill.
So yes, there are solutions,
but they will be complex
or so in here.
I think they are first converting the
letters.
I don't know.
The solution does not look good.
Spring Exercise Display
Select words beginning with uppercase.
So yes, you guys can go to search,
but it will be very complex.
We have substring word one one code led
lighting, blah blah blah blah blah.
Yes, it will be very complex. In my sequel
to find out this kind of things,
you have to combine
many different functions
because you have to find out first
if a letter is uppercase
or not.
Maybe we should search for,
oh, but how are you?
You make sure
that this is only the first letter.
So us you guys, you can use the substring
method to only pick the first letter.
Then you can try to convert it
to uppercase and then you can compare it.
Okay. I would say give me one moment.
Yes. This.
So there are multiple tricks
that you can use to solve this problem.
Let me first tell you about that.
Especially functional deep diving.
Yeah, maybe you should try
these kind of things after this class.
It will make much more sense.
So but for now,
let me show you some function.
So uppercase lowercase,
this init cap again, I think it does not
work on on my school, but it works on on
oracle one this init function
it converts the first letter to uppercase.
So I think it does not work on my super
yes function syntax,
blah blah does not exist.
But if we try this same function on
oracle live.
Thanks Maryam.
Now we are all set.
So yes.
Farhad, if you can use something
like this, default the name of the table.
Right.
Uh, Char employs if I am not wrong,
I think it is also not available here.
Yep. No
first name.
Oh yes, it is available.
So on Oracle
now you guys will not be noticed that
all the first letters, they are uppercase
and the remaining one they are not.
Yes, but the binary
one shows only my skill
I miss not the first letter.
Aisha, What do you mean by Ms..
So you guys have to find out
these functions
which are available on certain databases
and which are not available
on those specified basis.
There are high chances that the functions
will be available available,
but they might
have different, slightly different names
or they might work a little differently.
But Mike, for example, is not being faced
name.
Okay, we will have a look at that.
Aisha not ready.
Let's first learn about the basics
and then we will have a look
how to do that.
Searching.
So so this law function,
it does not make much more sense
in my sequel, but
let's say
if are searching for the lowercase,
if you are searching something
on the Oracle database,
you might want to convert your
all of your names to lowercase,
and then you might
want to perform this arch
so that if someone has to do
some of the letters s uppercase,
you don't miss those things
on Oracle database
or other databases that support
these uppercase and these
to a sense us in the inside the codes.
So this is just an example
that will work on Oracle,
but not all of my secret.
But let me also show you a demo.
So for example, if
so, let's say
if we are searching for speech, one
and let's say
I am not sure if this daemon has uppercase
s or lowercase, if I perform,
if I, if I execute this duty,
will I get something
as a result of this?
The note that I found. Right.
So in those databases which
check
if we have this law function in here.
So in these kind of databases,
you might want to convert your
data to lowercase
or uppercase,
and then you might want to perform
that search.
So then you will
you guys will see your results.
So these functions, the
this is how we use these functions
in the workplace,
but we can also use these functions
in this select class.
If you are looking
for a specific type of data.
So this is, this is the same example.
Now to find out the about the
what is the Fatima group.
It was a company in which I used to work
when I graduated,
actually my first corporate company
in which I worked
and that username
password is from my senior.
So I am still using that username password
because I am super, super lazy
and I didn't create my own
username and password.
Oh, okay.
So you guys can search on the internet
about single role
functions in my spirit.
So here you will be able to find out about
all the single node functions in here for.
Example the the length function
you guys can.
You guys will be needing this function
a lot.
So for example,
let's say select all from person.
So I am writing a duty
in which I only want the employees
who have, let's say me be
whose name has more than three characters.
So what I can do, I can here again
use the single role
function.
I can say Lent and inside as the argument.
I can boss the first name
and I can say we are.
The land is greater than maybe three
like this.
So now I will only see those employees
whose name has more than three likeness.
Right.
So this is the example of land function,
this concurred function.
Let's say
you want to get the
first name and the last name.
So let's say first name,
comma, last name
from person.
So instead of getting separate values
for the first name and the last name,
you guys might want to get
a single value in here.
So what you can do
and oh, we also have intelligence finally.
So you guys can also see what are
the functions that are available in here.
So for example, this contract function,
it will take two arguments
plus name
and the last name.
And instead of returning you to values,
it will now return you
a single column as the output
in which first name and the last name
will be combined together.
What is the difference between line
ten and 11?
Line ten and 11?
There is no difference
because there is no function in scale
that can do this.
Okay, so I see first name and last name
combined together.
I saw you got excited about those out of.
So guys, there is no space in between
the first name and the last name.
Can you guys
tell me if I want to have some space?
How can I do that?
The one trait that you guys can use
will be last name.
So using and calling this function
place right in.
So first it will continue to be first name
with this space and then it will again
continue to be desert of
this function will be under column.
So you guys can also have this nesting
of functions inside the school.
So if you can call a function inside,
another function
that will use the output of one function
inside
another function
is it here guys?
What I am doing in here.
Okay,
let me show you more single row functions.
The sub SDR function.
So let's say you only want to have
first three letters, or
maybe middle
letters are the last letters from
first names right?
So you can use this sub string method.
And in here what you need to specify
is the name of the column
and then maybe the starting index
and the ending index.
So I only see now
first of two letters from the first name.
I think you guys will be able to
to understand these functions easily.
XYZ If I give you this page, maybe
and you guys
just go through these functions
once, by the way,
they have also given the examples
of these functions in here,
if you guys don't understand.
So this is a date function.
By the way, I, I saw in date function
that was used in some of the interviews.
Let me check
if I can tell you about that function.
So the question was
there was a date of joining in air
in an hotel and the leaving date.
And we have we had to select
only those roles, although those persons
which stayed in the hotel
for more than two days. So
I saw this question in
an interview yesterday or some time
there as some days before that.
So I don't know if we have a table
that contains two dates or not, but
you guys can go through these functions.
I mean, you don't even need to go through
all of the functions.
Just have that in your mind that
if you want to do something in school,
there are functions that you guys can use
and you can simply Google it.
How to do certain thing
in school using that function land days
greater than two.
Yes, now, but you have to calculate the
the number of days from the dates.
Select uppercase or substring.
First name and two from person.
So it will select the first two letters
and then it will convert them
to the uppercase. LIMA.
So Google is your best friend again?
Yes, always.
If you are in the tech industry,
Google is your best friend.
So in here for the date of world, we have
a column.
So let me check if
it's me or B and
I want to add one month
to each of the date of working here.
Something like this?
Yeah.
Adam Months not available.
Our date or time.
So this function is not available in here.
So there are so many functions.
So instead of
going through all of these functions,
if you are looking for something special,
you guys can just Google it
and then you can use it.
No, these are not available in here.
This is the function that will read
from the position of a letter.
This will add a spaces
before and are on towards the left
and right side of the screen.
It will bring to him same as or
your java function replace also same four
months between add months.
We have to search again
how to add two months in there.
My ask you it is
add function we can use
is the synonym of added date.
My skill date time value with the date
it can
and my recipients are doing this week
with our blah blah
air date.
We specify the day and then the interval.
So for example interval and B is
the last
like this.
So this is how you guys can just
search and perform things and
our date
and instead of adding it
to a hardcoded value,
maybe you can add it to all the values.
So if you guys observe now
the results this, these are the results
when we once we have added
ten days to the date of birth.
So plus to 26
and now the updated date is 308.
So this is how you guys can search
on the Internet.
And instead of just
memorizing the functions and remembering
how they work,
just remember that there are functions.
And if you need something specifying, just
search on the internet and use it there.
Are you guys good?
Well Victorians
warned against handling of that website.
The it is the same website
so these were all of
these were single row functions.
Now let me show you some famous multi
functions
and again remember,
those are some of the functions
they might work on and on a database and
they might not work on another database.
Some of them.
They might have a different name
on one database and a different name
on another database.
So for example, these are some famous
material functions
that's
lists
that might be helpful.
So let's say if you want to
calculate, how many drawers
this query has returned,
you guys can use the count function.
So what can will do?
It will take all the values
and all the rows as the input
and it will count and the number of rows
and it will return to the number of roles.
So there are 22
rows that are being returned
by the security, Right?
So let's say if you want to use
these results in your school later on,
I will teach you how to combine your skill
and Java together
to perform the testing there.
You guys will be needing them.
And another famous function at all
function is
can we actually do this?
Let me actually combine
all of them in here so
I can use this sum function.
It will sum all of the values.
I can use the count function.
It will count all of the values
from the age column.
I can use the mean function.
It will count the minimum age
from the column
I can call to the maximum value
from the column.
I can calculate the average
from here.
So again, you guys don't need to memorize
all of these.
If you need something, just Google it
and you will be able to find out
a function for there.
Most probably.
But even if you don't have a function,
you guys can write your own functions,
but most probably you will never do that.
So right now we see that.
We see the sum of all the edges,
we see the count,
we see the minimum, we see the maximum,
we see the average.
Then we see declaration of these functions
like we did in Java.
I have to check.
I have to check if it is allow us to,
to do that.
I think for the paid databases,
you guys will not be able to do that,
but you might be able to do that
for the open source backup basis
because companies, they
don't want to share their implementations,
but it might be possible.
Then you can even Google it.
How to check the internals of a function
In my sequel workbench.
So these are some of the examples
of multiple functions.
There are other functions
that you guys can search on the internet,
but we will not be going
over all of those questions.
Now the second thing, and
it is very important in the interview,
I have seen a lot of questions
in the interview regarding this concept
that I will be telling you
now is the
having clause and the group by clause.
So a lot of questions from this group
by clause.
What this group by
can do for us.
Let's see,
can we answer in an interview
that we are going to find?
We answered on Google. Yep, yep.
Even companies there are allow you to
use the Google.
They explicitly say
that you can use Google.
Why do you keep retype Bing select
all from person?
Oh, I don't know.
Maybe just to show you guys
that I can type
so I can take the
visit. You
Okay, so let's say guys,
we have results from this query, right?
And I can I want to find out
how many mails and females are there in
this are sex.
And can you guys tell me,
how can I do that in a single query?
I want to find out
how many male and females are be
counted gender if gender is equal to and
I have I had I like to talk to you
about these conditions.
Some gender is equal to and
then you guys try writing a query
for that. Yes.
Let's say I want to find out
the count or maybe the average age of men
and average age of woman,
if you put gender
is equal to I'm in the rare condition,
you will not be getting the results
for the females.
I will be back in a minute.
Today's Try to write a query
to calculate maybe
the number of men and number of women
in this resource.
I will be like that
Wife is calling.
No, Sebastian.
She is sleeping while I am waiting. You
select count
Gender is equal to M.
Are you good executing these queries
as well to verify the results?
And Silva, you are sure that the query
that you have written
gives you a correct result?
I don't know. So
it gives the wrong with FS
if it gets is
so remember, guy is school 90% of the time
it will not give you an error,
but it will give you wrong results.
So you have to cross-check things.
So the one of the ways to achieve
this is by using the group by class.
So let's see.
You want to count
that?
How many males and females
are there inside
this gender column?
Right.
So what you guys can do,
you can tell the gender
and then you can put
the count of that gender from the person
and you can see, hey, school
group by the results,
by the gender.
So what happened in here?
So Pascual did
so mine was okay. I don't know.
You guys got ten for male, nine,
nine for female.
And there were three null values.
Mine was for me.
So let me explain.
Do you guys understand what,
what happened, how we got these results?
And you guys sure.
Yes. By grouping.
So looking in settings,
this is very important.
Very, very important.
I all in almost all the interviews,
this group by class is used.
So what we are seeing in
the security, we are saying
give us the gender
and then also count
how many rows fall under that gender
that you are specifying in here.
And we are saying group by the results
with respect to gender.
So what Pascual will do
is Google will pick this m in here first
and then it will scan
the complete dataset set and it will count
how many ends are there.
So do we count one,
two, three, blah blah, blah, blah,
and then it will put the count in here.
So then it will put
and then it will pick
the next to unique value from this
column.
So this gender column has three
unique values.
It has F,
it has M, and it has another values.
So it will group all the data
with respect to these three values.
So all the M's are in one portion,
all the FS in one portion
and all the nulls in one portion.
Then what it will do,
it will count those rows
that fall under M F and null
and it will display
the count in here. Now,
these multiple functions, they are.
So this group by clause
is most of the time
it is used with the multi functions.
And if, let's say are not using the group
by clause in here.
So some of the databases they
they will still give you the results
but the results will be wrong.
So in here
it says there are 22 mens in the gender.
This obviously these results
they are not correct.
But school is not giving you an error
and it is still showing your results.
So make sure guys always whenever
you are using the multiple functions
and if you are performing this grouping,
make sure you put group by clause.
Also, I think the Oracle database
gives you an ETA
if you try to use group by without.
Okay,
so select
may be
the salary
and count
how many employees
have the have that salary
from at your employers.
And if we don't use the group by clause,
I think the Oracle one
gives you an error. Yes.
So it says not a single group group
by a function.
But if we put this group by
and we tell that, how
well do you guys know why
we got the error?
Because check this out.
This salary column has
it might have like for example,
ten values, 20 values, 30 values,
but you remember the multiple functions.
They only give you a single value
as the output, right?
So the the result set will be imbalanced.
Right.
For for example, for example,
there is a the salary
that is 28 and then we are checking
the count in here.
If we don't specify this group by,
there will be an imbalance
because this thing will return one value
while this thing will die
can return multiple value.
So Escuela or Oracle database,
they don't know how to represent
that result. Check.
So if we put the group by in here. No.
I executed two of them looking exactly
conjugates.
So now what Oracle is doing
it is checking how many photos are there
in the salary column?
There are two photos.
How many 70 years out of there?
How many thousands are dead?
How many? 6000 out of there.
So it is picking each value,
searching the complete column
for the duplication of that value.
If there are duplicate values,
it is counting those values.
And it is it is representing the count
in front of the that.
So if you want to create some groups
in your results,
let's say for example,
maybe you want to count the
how many employees are there
in each department, right.
So instead of writing the acuity
two separately for each department,
you can use the count function
and you can go to
by your results based on department.
Then you will automatically check
how many departments are there
in the department's column and,
how many employees
have that specific department
as their
department,
and it will count those employees in here.
So same as it is counting how many 40 twos
are there in this healthy column?
How many 70 years are there
in this column?
How many 8000 values
are in this salary column.
So let me show you so that you like
and also
check it.
Really, It will.
It is it is tricky and it will take
some time to understand how it works.
So I, I want you to pay extra attention
to this group by
so if you guys observe,
we have 1000 in here
then we have to scan all the values,
the one by one.
How many thousands were there
in the query?
One or three.
Simple.
We can use it for all the common things.
Okay, There. There are 3000. So let me
execute 20.
Oh, I am again grouping your device
and exotic member
select salary from these once
a one is here.
Can you guys also verify the results
with me?
Okay, so it feels more real.
It exists.
It is only showing us
the rows from 1 to 50.
It is to optimize the database results
when your page time flies.
I just looked at the time
and it's almost ten oh oh.
Let's find out some other value
for which actually
let me show you from this
not obvious, but
select age
and then the count
of all types of ages
that we have inside the
first 20, it will easier
to verify the results from here
because there are fewer roads in here.
I don't know how many those are due
to next year to try to count
107. Yes,
it will be a lot of data
to compare the results,
so I need to grow by,
otherwise I will be getting wrong results
like I got in this case.
So two one employ has aged, wanted,
16 of them has a 23 aged 24,
three of them has 25, 28 and 28.
Now let's verify if we are getting
the correct results are not
and how this group is working.
So let's verify this.
There should be 320 fives
inside the person table for the Age column
one, two and three.
So you guys can you guys see it combines
all the values which are same
and then it displays
the count of those values.
Now it is very it is specific.
It is specific
because we are using the count function.
What you guys can also do,
you guys can apply
the other multi-role functions in here.
So let's say, for example,
you want to calculate the minimum age
of a female and a male.
Can you guys help me write down the query?
How can I do that?
I want to know
what is the minimum value for male
and what is the minimum age for a female?
And you guys, can you guys hear me?
So what is the minimum
age for a male and what is a minimum
age for a female?
We are typing in my school
so I can see that gender
and then minimum
of the age right
from person and
by which column I should grow
by the resource guys
gender
right?
So female minimum age for the females
is 20 minimum age for the male is 23.
And the null values
has also a minimum age, which is 25.
So all the readers are grouped by gender
and we are calculating the minimum.
So there are many roles that have.
B gender. M Right.
So our skill is going through
all those roles for which the gender is.
M and it is finding out the minimum value,
then it is doing
the same for females,
it is doing the same for NULL.
If there are, let's say,
ten unique values in the gender column,
it will do these calculations
for all of those ten values
because we are grouping
the results by the gender.
Are you guys getting the idea
behind this group BY It's a little tricky
as I'm worried about this.
So if you guys understand the
this group by telling me
how many employees live in each of
these cities that I you you
to find out
how many employees live
in let's say York, London or Sydney,
I want to find the count
against each city.
How many employees are living
in that specific city right?
Down to you for that.
If you guys have understood.
Yes, I will make it practice. Don't worry.
I will be giving you a lot of homework
and then a big project related to school.
So you guys will be writing right?
Like 50 plus cuties.
So again, I want to find out the count
against each city.
So I say a select city
so that I can see the name,
and then I will say, count how many rolls
are against each city
from person table and then
group the results by
city. So
there is a city null.
So employers have the value null.
For the city. It is empty, there is zero.
There are 14 employees
who are living in Dubai,
five in Istanbul,
one in Lahore, two in London.
Why count that?
I just wanted to count.
You can take average some minimum maximum,
whatever you want, but
you're just an example to show you that.
Why count now?
Why triple stars?
No double star.
Can you please rephrase?
Can we try an example of the average
function? Yes.
Why did you use a star?
You want to use something else?
I just want to perform a count.
Right.
So the you guys can go down
to the number of the bar by start.
I mean, count
all of the rows that are there in there.
So count, function, count
all the rows
if you want, do something like this.
You are
you are saying why I'm not using the city
you guys can
use, you guys can use first name,
you guys can use last name.
You guys can use anything.
Count means just count the number of rows.
I don't need to specify a specific column.
You guys can specify any column
first name, last name, age,
city, whatever you want. Count means
I don't care.
Whatever the column name is,
just give me the column.
So sometimes you guys, most of the time
you guys will see called static.
But if you are looking for a count
for a specified column.
You can also specify that you said
do whatever you want.
I mean, you can use any column.
So Nabeel was saying, can we try
an example of the average function?
Yes, sure.
So this average function required you
to boss A Actually, let me create a new
duty so that
you guys can practice this group.
So this average function
calculates the average.
And to calculate the average
we need the numeric that out here.
Right.
So let's say
maybe we can calculate the average age
of the employees in each city, Right?
So this every function
will give us that info in school.
Understanding the results that you guys
are getting is more important
than just writing the query
and getting delivers.
The you should understand
the query that you should understand
what the security will return to you.
So right, the security is returning me.
The average age in Dubai,
the average age in
Istanbul, the average age in Lahore,
the average age in London.
For all the employees
that inside that city.
Do you guys understand how well what
this average function is going in here,
Why I wrote Age
and what the city is doing in here.
So grouping the results by city
and inside
the city, take the age
of all the employees
that live in that specific city,
then calculate the average.
You guys can also calculate
the minimum age of all the cities.
Their support Example If you want
to find out what is the minimum age,
all the cities for employees,
you can also do that.
So it totally depends
what you want to calculate.
Your first.
The only important thing is
you should understand that
this group by based on
what column
you want the group to buy your results.
Right.
Let's say you are grouping by the results,
by department, by a city
is by a salary, is by date of birth
or whatever is your requirement.
And the next thing is
what kind of calculations
you want to perform on that,
that that group that you have created.
So first will create those groups
based on the column
that you have specified,
then will will perform that
specific function
that you are specifying in here.
And remember, it should be a multi role
function, not a single role function.
What about
two specific a city for example?
New York?
Yes. If you only want to see the results
for New York,
then you can use the where clause, right?
In that case,
we don't need the group by group.
By is only needed when you don't know.
Let's say
how many cities are there in your table.
You don't know how many cities are there.
Let's say
there are 1 million rows in your table.
You don't know how many cities are there,
and you just want to see the stats
for all the cities that are there.
Then you will perform the group by clause
because in group by skill
takes this responsibility
of finding out all the unique cities
and then performing calculation
whatever calculation you are specifying
average minimum, maximum counter,
whatever you want against that value.
So we are clause is when know the value.
Let's say for example, you know for sure
that there is New York in your table,
but what if you don't know
the names of the city,
then you will not be able
to write queries.
In that case, you will use group buyer
because group buyer
it automatically scan all the values
and automatically automatic click group
all the values based on the data
that is present inside that column.
Does it make sense based?
And I suppose the rest of the statistics
mathematic functions
do exist as well to be searched
and found by Google?
Yep. Yep. Nabeel, you are right.
You there are more than just minimum
maximum average sum count function.
There are many more multi role functions
that if needed,
you guys can search on the internet.
All right, guys.
So let me give you one more task.
Can you guys tell me how many employees
have the last name NASIR?
How many employees
have the last name as John?
How many employers have the last
name as Kim?
I want to find out
the count of the employees
who have the same last name.
Can you write me a query?
I want to find out the number of employees
who have the same last
name, and I also want
to find out the name of that
than their specific name as well.
So their specific last name
plus their scope? Yes.
Is there anyone who is unable
to write this query
maybe who don't understand?
So select
last name, right.
And then count.
I don't care. You can.
I am saying hey, a skill
you can use any column in here
for this count to perform from person.
And then I want the group to by
the last name.
Yes, it is correct.
And you guys can also
compare the results with me.
So John is 13 of the employers
have the same as the last name.
Three of the employers
have a zero as the last name.
All of the other last names they are
they have occurred
only once inside this paper.
Okay, perfect.
I think you guys have started getting it.
Can you guys calculate the average age
of employees who have employee I.D.
120 or 100 or 230?
So based on the employee I.D.,
I want to find out the average age
and you guys. Right. For that.
Can we see how many?
No. Zero on in there?
Yes. Yes.
Then if you can write,
Acuity will find out.
And let me show you from here.
So there are three in here.
So find out
how many employees
have the employer I.D.
What is the average age of the employees
who have the employer I.D.?
120 What is the average age
for the employee I.D. 150.
What is the average age for the employer
ID 100?
So select
empty I.D.
and then, uh, 40 average
of age
from person to person
and by
employee I.D..
All right.
So employed 100 has the average age 25.5,
130.01 2030 23.
Okay, let's let me check if we are
missing.
So this is the how group by
what's used with aggregate functions.
So this is important.
It is always used with the aggregate.
Right.
Aggregate functions mean average sum.
All of those functions
actually that take multiple values
and then aggregate the results
to give one single value
to collect
the data across multiple records
and grouping the results
by one or more columns.
NoSQL has used
as well as a manually written
one 2150 and 113 to be every function
entity exited written ID.
Ladies, it's time to leave Syntax.
Please, please grow up.
Please don't do everything as Manuel.
I tried with cities
of Asia.
If you do something like this on your job,
please
don't forget to share
with the rest of the batch.
We will be more than happy
to see your great work
that you will perform as you were tested
on your behalf in your job.
This maybe others
can learn from that.
Okay.
But I can tell you one thing
because of you shot and now because of you
other employers, they
they will be benefiting a lot from you
because the the thing that can be done
in, let's say, 5 minutes,
you guys will be doing the same thing
manually in 3 hours and 4 hours maybe.
So your manager will slowly start
to think that this specific
task actually needed
three or hours and maybe
I'm just kidding, don't
take it seriously.
Actually, you should take it seriously.
I mean, why are you
guys are still doing things manually?
Okay, don't take it seriously.
You do not take notice
that when you are hired.
So these are some of the examples
of multiple functions.
Count them in average, blah, blah, blah.
And then you can group them by
and then you can have.
Okay, so now is the final thing.
And it is again, very,
very frequently in the interviews,
this having clause.
First let me show you
what does it mean by having clause.
So you guys did the
you guys brought this query
to find out the number of employees
who have the same last name.
I will
all team down in his bad dreams.
I can remember after said when he gets
married, they will be invited.
Are still true. Yes.
Yes, definitely. Still true.
But remember,
there is this tradition here in Pakistan
that when whoever comes to wedding,
they have to bring some kind of gifts for.
The bride and the groom,
how to practice with timing.
I mean, how much time and the task needs
always, always, guys, if you think that
you can do a task in 3 hours,
always, always tell your manager
that it will require 6 hours.
Please don't be smart.
Please don't think that, Oh,
I can do this in 3 hours.
I will be appreciated.
If you are telling that you will,
it will take 3 hours to complete the task.
Your manager will start thinking,
okay, let's find out something for
then is that he should do after 3 hours
so it will already have something in mind.
Once you are done with that
task, believe me.
And in reality we because we are
not machines, we need some time to relax.
Right.
So always keep that time as well
in your tasks, maybe 15, 20 or 30 minutes
to have some break,
to have some coffee or something like that
after each task.
So please don't be smart
because I have seen
those implies
the only thing they get is more work.
If you have completed the work
that is given to you,
the next thing you should expect
is more work from your managers. It's
Do they ask you to drive? No.
Slowly they will understand you, Aisha.
Slowly they will know.
We have a great Aisha
that on average
take months to complete this task.
So they will not bother you to ask again
and again.
I'm just getting up.
Yes, it depends on task.
What do they get? Higher salaries.
Okay, so here is another thing.
Believe me, the person
who is putting all the efforts on
on a job throughout the complete year
at Max,
what they will get maybe, let's say
7% raise or 8%,
and the employee who has done nothing,
he will like around maybe 4% or 5%,
then that's the only difference.
But if you guys are working smartly
so, there is a difference.
Working hard and keeping yourself
busy all the time and working smartly.
Let's say
if your company is doing something and,
you know something better
that can save cost.
So instead of keeping yourself busy
in solving task
or think about in that time,
think you can cut down the costs
if you want to be a manager or a director
or on the higher position.
So think in a different way
other than just keep on solving things
that are given to you.
Maybe a how you can improve a process.
That's what higher management
usually do, right?
How you can improve processes
to save huge amounts of time,
how you can cut down costs,
how you can improve other things,
maybe security or something like that.
So this is what I have observed.
How f ESD
previous batches become team leads
or by the way, it is.
Yes, it is correct.
Not a job joke that some of them
they are directors as well.
After I think your syntax started in
2017 and it's three.
It's just five years.
So let's say if even a student graduates
graduated in the first batch
in just five years,
if he is a director or manager, I think he
he has done a wonderful job
and then he will be a great team.
Lead.
And here is one more advice.
Please make your manager
your best friend if possible.
Believe me,
your life will be super, super easy.
So I was saying,
if we execute the security in here,
what about two testing jobs
at the same time?
Later on you will learn how to make
your manager your best friend
just laugh on every joke
that he or she is making,
No matter how bad is that joke.
I think
most of you already know, right?
I don't need to tell this.
It's putting put what you are the manager.
Right?
So let's see guys,
I want to filter out these groups.
So I have already created the groups.
That's why we will laugh at your jokes.
You guys will get nothing but knowledge
from me as far as I am concerned.
My boss loves me because I bring him food.
If he or she said banana is being say yes.
Yes. This is the
this is also very important.
Manager is always right.
Okay.
We are we still have 10 minutes
so let's talk that you have already
created the groups. And
so there are two types of filtering
filtering the individual group
and then filtering a group.
The result of a group,
if you want to filter out, let's say
if you only want those employing names
who have occurred more than twice,
then we cannot use clause in here. Why?
Because we're clause operates
on an individual role.
If you have group with the results
using the group by clause,
we have a new clause
that is called having clause
and we need to do this
filtering inside the having clause
like this.
We cannot use the word clause in here.
And this is the difference between
we are clause and the having clause
where is used to filter out
your individual roles
while the having clause
is used to filter out
the results of your group.
So for example,
if I execute X to let me create a copy
so that you guys
can observe the difference.
So in here
I am getting all the groups right if,
whether, if a name has occurred once
or maybe 13 times.
But what if I don't want
what if I only want those results
for which the count is greater than two
or greater than one?
Then I can use the having clause
and I need to put this same aggregate
function in here and then I can write that
that I want to apply on deck.
Trust me, if I don't like a person,
I cannot laugh at his her joke,
even if it is funny.
I say, you don't want to be a manager
or director or something like that.
So now we will only get those groups
which qualify condition.
So do you guys understand the difference
between having an individual clause?
So if you want to do any kind of filtering
on your groups,
the results of your groups,
we use the having clause
and we put this same function.
Can you repeat that one more time? Yes.
So if I execute this duty,
I already have the results, already
have the groups.
Right. But in real life, what can happen?
These last name, there can be millions
of last names in your results right
When you are when you will be working
on a real database,
then you might not want
all of the results, right?
You might want to filter some results.
And how can we do that?
We can do that
with the help of having clause.
For example, I want to build a filtration.
I only want those results
which are of greater than one.
So I will put my multi-role function
in here
and I will write the condition in here.
And if I execute this query,
instead of getting each and every group,
this time I will only get that group
for which the count is greater than one
right now we have an assistant principal.
She knows like I hate.
So this having clause
is basically to filter out
your groups or a
So can you guys quickly
let me let me check
if you guys have understood this
actually, let me show you the theory first
where clause used to filter rules
having clause used to filter groups.
You guys already know
how to create groups.
And if you want to filter out some groups,
will you be having clause
string can also be in a having
filter instance applied before group by.
So we write the word clause
before the group by clause.
Otherwise
we will be getting a syntax at a used
if condition does not contain
a group of function.
If there are group functions,
we cannot use the where clause
with those group functions
applied after group bias.
So we write the having clause
after the group buy plus we have clause
before the groups
that are having after the group buy
and it is used if conditions contain
aggregate function.
Those functions
which take multiple values as input
and give a single value as output.
So can you guys write a few of.
So I want to find how many employees
have an MP already.
So how many employees have an MP added
That has occurred more than three times.
Maybe
you show us a sample with vote and having.
Yes, yes, yes. Give me one moment.
Do we need to fast What a form.
Select the last name gone from person
group by last time before we do
the having.
Yes, having clause only works
if you are grouping the results first
alone.
I was very very fast.
So like B and B already count from person
by MP already
having count greater than three.
Right.
So only those groups.
So MP ID and then count
of all the employees against that MP ID.
So if I only execute
this part of the query
just to show you
we get the counts in here right.
For a two employees have 100
MP, one has another ten nine
employees have 120 as the MPI 8150.
And then you guys are saying their task.
Well, you know what?
I don't want all the results
that you are giving me in here.
I only want the results
for which the gulp is greater than three.
So you will see once
I apply this having a to the three,
this one will be removed,
two will be removed.
This one will be removed.
So you see, I now only see four,
nine and five.
Do you guys
get the idea of having class Now
the difference where and how now
and then is well saying
can you show us where clause and
having class.
So let's say for example,
you only want to perform
this task for the employees
for which the city
let's say
what type of cities
are there in our table?
Let's say you only want to do this thing
for the New York place.
So in here
first, all the rules will be filtered
from the actual table
that does not have a city
is equal to New York
and all of these things.
They will be performed
only on the employers
for which the city is New York.
So there is no employee in
in the New York City
for which the count is greater
than which means there are no employees
in the New York City
that have the same MP
ID more than three times.
Does it make sense right. So
let me show you another example.
It will make more sense.
So for the Istanbul,
do you think 151 5151 5155 times.
So if I select this city as Istanbul,
can you guys
reduce the output?
Oops.
So if I use the city as
I hope I am writing
the correct spellings in here.
So the results are five
and why we got this
because it is greater than three
if the results are less than three,
we will not be getting any data.
Dennis, are you good now?
Any other questions?
Any other confusion?
Can we go over this again in next class?
Yes, definitely. I will revise.
You guys will also revise this
in your review class.
And you will do
you will solve many tasks related to this
dispatch guard stand
five x me.
So there is one more thing
left.
Can I have ten more minutes from you?
Because you guys waste a lot of my time
that I think you are sleepy
Silva Again,
this emoji emoji I hate to bake.
You have to bake after this class.
Oh my God. Yes.
Yes. Then.
Then this emoji is fine.
Why don't you make a deal with Zima?
Three days in a week, Zima will cook
three days in a week you will cook.
And the other day
you guys will order something
from outside the
Don't do blame games with your wife.
I am baking for parties for years.
Yeah.
Does the man know how to cook?
So Zima, best of luck for
I don't know why
you guys are having party,
but I am sure at least 2000 things
go on from Zima bucket for this party.
Maybe more than 2000, $3,000.
Best of luck.
Zima.
So there is this last thing
that I want to show you,
and then you guys can leave.
If you have multiple conditions in acuity,
you guys can break down
your results in intermediate straps.
So for example,
I'm you guys remember the scary
sketch.
So for the homework,
you guys had to manually go to this job,
I guess Oracle at our table
to find out the job titles manually
and then you guys
had to put those course in here, right?
But what if these scores
that you are putting in here,
they are in thousands or in hundreds?
It will be very, very tough for you
to first find out the code
for all those values, let's say
100 or 200.
Then remember those values
and put inside the in column
and then execute this query. Right.
You guys are getting my point.
Yes, I can do it.
Yes, I am talking of for other students
other than I show.
So again, others get
and you guys put like a hundred or 200
gold in from the
from the other table here.
Yes. And as well as well.
So this is not for not as good or nicer
you guys absolutely
just knew that you can anything manually.
I will get killed by these ladies someday.
Okay.
So instead what you guys can do,
you guys can use a
but then your class will be boarding.
So what you guys can do
instead of doing this manually,
you guys can use an inner query.
So one you will do is acuity inside
and other acuity.
It calculates
some results, intermediate results
which are used inside and under acuity.
So for example, you guys can say we're
we had a job
title is equal is in
in let's say
developer
or in the job title is let's say
it was freelancer right
you the answer
so and
instead of selecting all the data
you guys can select the IDs.
What what was this guys carefully.
If I exit your discovery.
Discovery
now gives me the ideas for developer
and a freelancer right.
Uh, a non column dog pattern.
Okay, so I get the idea then.
29 and 31
What I'm getting to the ideas
should not be
I getting only two ideas
that you've been talking
with.
Maybe we have some duplicate
that there's like three ideas.
Otherwise we should be getting towards.
Maybe someone has assigned two
different ideas to developer or freelance.
Oh yes.
So freelancer has 29 and 31 as as great.
The bad 710 stole them.
But what we've been it okay,
so this is giving me the ideas of
the developers and freelancers right now
what I can do instead of finding out
these ideas manually and inserting
in here, I can use this query
wrong database selected those.
In fact,
I can use this already
inside of these brackets
to let me make it smaller
so that you guys can see the complete.
Now what Eskil will do.
First, it will execute this query
to find out the ideas and then those ideas
will be used inside this in clause
to find out the found out.
Find out those implies
so results of one duty
can be used in an other query.
If you are bringing the results
from two different tables,
even if you are bringing the results from
the same table and you want to perform
some intermediate calculations,
you can also do that.
So you see
now we are getting all the implies, but
this time we are only specifying
the developer and a freelancer.
We are not doing this first.
We are the ideas for developer
and a freelancer.
Then we manually those ideas in here
and then get those employs.
Do you guys get the idea
the first
and this duty is executed?
Okay, I will show you in the next class.
Maybe you guys are not mentally
prepared for this right now.
I will.
I will create a simpler table
to show this.
I am typing tired.
I think you are done from your side
for today.
We are getting it.
Yes, please. Okay.
I will prepare this in the next class.
This was the last thing
that I wanted to show.
Oh, okay.
I will post the homework in the
course announcements channel guys,
please make sure you do the homework
before the next class.
I need to it so tired.
If someone is tired they should not.
Should not they be sleeping?
Why? Even if you are tired again,
that's why you are healthy, right?
Tired. Eat more is not good.
Eat your tonight eat your day eat
Will you cover review classes?
I think I will do the review You class in
morning eat?
Yes Evening Eat.
All right, guys.
I hope you guys don't mind my jokes.
It is just to some smile on your faces
so that you guys don't get too bored
because these subjects,
they are kind of very dry.
Especially programing.
So it's part of my job, actually, to.
To make you happy as well.
We know you're joking.
All right, guys, take some rest
and I will see you tomorrow.
Okay.
That's what she said.
Bye bye, guys.