How did you highlighted on bottom
this one just just from your mouse cursor.
Tammy Now you need to install a
you need to watch the complete video
At the end of the video,
I have showed you how to fix this issue.
So today we will discuss what is database.
Why do we need the SD?
Well,
what are the select statements in school?
And we are closed in the school.
So before I can show you,
I have a question for you.
So you guys are already familiar with this
Web page, this web application, right?
So I have a question for you guys.
Can you guys tell me
when you guys
enter something in this application?
So, for example, if you insert
any event card in here,
like for example,
if I click on add employee,
if I add this
that if I add something in here,
where did that that I'll go
Never seen it in my life.
I may or may not have grabbed my brain
from the last week
or let's say if I am let's see
click on employee list.
Yeah.
Do you guys have any idea
from where this data,
all of this
from where this data is being loaded
inside this page
to are remember some database
which syntax uses
some in back of this account.
We use something as a to store this data.
I mean,
I think we can easily store
this data in Excel file, right?
Maybe we can create a call
on my first name.
Last name.
And this job title implies status
and then put all that data in.
Next, an Excel logo. Do you guys think
there are tables in between?
We also have shields and rows
and columns in school,
right?
Have you guys working with large Excel
files?
The Excel files
that contain maybe vectors in millions?
Has anyone of you
working with those files?
Oh my God. That is a huge difference.
I look pretty right?
Oh, clearly worth all those efforts
from my, you know, almost.
Yes, of course.
In looking at your data, this
before, physically.
So have you guys ever worked with large
Excel files?
Woman is generally better in everything.
No, no, it's not.
Generally they
they are always better than everything,
Especially
the things that we men do that
they are best
almost too big Excel files.
Definitely.
As to your statement
about looking prettier.
So have you guys noticed that
if you try to load a bigger file
or if you try to open and manipulate
a bigger file,
sometimes Excel just stops responding.
Like for a minute it will not respond.
Or if you have to
just even just open that file,
it will take some time,
like five or 6 minutes maybe,
or sometimes it will just refuse
and it will say that the data is too much
and it cannot be stored
in a single file, cannot with loaded
load loaded in a single file.
Right.
Have you guys ever noticed that?
So yes.
Like we can store
this data in Excel file, but
Excel file has a limit.
If we
are dealing with large amounts of data,
we can not really use Excel files.
Plus,
yes, we can come up with a functionality
to connect
to that Excel file
with the website like this.
And this website
can fetch the data from Excel file,
but we will have to do a lot of effort
because sometimes,
let's say for example, right now
I am logged in as admin.
I see different
information.
If someone has logged
in, may be with another user
with less privileges you might not be able
to see maybe all of the data
or maybe may not be able to modify
all the data.
We have an alert due to word for
oh, because of that GitHub.
Oh, you guys will love this
word in school.
All right.
I'm so sorry for that. It's
but we will be putting a lot of time
this video in this course.
So sorry about that.
I have to use that bug.
So what databases are?
They are specialized software
to store the data
for your websites or your maybe
Android applications or iOS applications,
or you guys can also use to store the data
from your desktop application.
Yes, we can use Excel.
Yes, we can use Google sheets.
Yes, we can just throw this there dying
and not bad file.
We can just throw this
that bind folders or something like that.
But in the past 30 years,
software industry, they have come up
with the specialized software
just to store
manage, manipulate, connect
this that obviously your applications,
all types of applications
they can be a web application
like this one
there can be they they can be an Android
application or iOS application
or desktop application or whatever
type of software you guys have used.
And if that software,
especially those students
who have worked with payroll, softwares
or other kind of software
in which you guys create builds or
sell these or other type of desktop
databases can be used
to store audio and video as well,
but they are not generally used to store
that kind of data 90% of the time
it will be text based that meeting data
that we will be storing in databases.
But yes, they are capable of
storing audio, video, text
files, Excel files, any kind of backed out
that you might like to store.
But they are not that good
in those type
in handling those types of data.
So 99, 95% of the time, I will say
you guys will be using something.
You guys will be sporting
something like this nomadic or text
based that or maybe images that you put
with your profiles or things like that. So
so this is how it works on a very,
very high level
overview Are all this look and feel.
You guys are also familiar
with as an email a little bit of course
this alleged email, right how the website
are structured in your selenium pluses
you guys have noticed
we give ideas, classes and all that.
So in the email
it's like this if,
if I give an example from human body,
that email is similar
to our skeleton system.
The actual structure of that holds
everything together
the skin, the hair color
and every look and feel is
it comes from that course, that
beauty comes from that system,
that the behavior that you guys see on
your website is when you let's say,
for example, when you click on involves
if you enter something,
you get maybe a alert.
You guys are also familiar
with those alerts, right?
Inputting something,
maybe showing some warnings
or something like that,
or when you click on an entire
these fields and when you click on this
such a button or reset button,
all of this
behavior is coming from JavaScript.
Most probably from JavaScript
or something similar
that defines the front end of
of of a web application now.
But we also need a mechanism
to write all the rules, right?
Let's say, for example,
if you want to put a limitation
that imply name cannot be, let's
it won't be more than 20 characters, okay?
Or maybe the job title cannot be accounted
or it should be a content,
or it should be from this list
or all the business rules, right?
For example, when you show up on Amazon,
what kind of discount you will get,
how your credit card will be processed,
all those
that processing that logic,
those business rules
they are developed using
and other language may be Java, C++,
they are called the backend
language.
So CSS, SDM, HTML, JavaScript
to define the frontend
look and feel and the behavior
and other some kind of other programing
language might be
it might be B, C-sharp, Java, C++
to write all the business rules
and to connect to your frontend
with your back and with your database
so that all the data that you put
inside your website
next time you visit their website,
that data is there.
So we store that data
permanently in a desktop base
and that language that we use
to write the rules, business rules,
we use the same language
to connect this frontend
that you guys see and interact
with to that database.
So that when you click on this
such a button, it can pull the data
from database.
All this data is coming from a database
or if you have to add something,
that data is stored in a database.
Right now
you guys can think of a database,
just a very voice dictation software
that is very, very good exporting and
in fact storing
the data that
you guys want to store from your website,
also fetching that data
from that software.
So is there anyone who is confused,
who is unable to connect these dots,
or maybe who does not understand
how this front end works
at a very high level,
why we have this background of why
we why we need the database
or how this web application works? Yes.
And I'll tell you also looks good.
Just select this.
I will tell you later.
Keep it this this way and I will show you.
Look at what the
I mean, get ready.
So add button is somehow connected
with add to your Pascual.
Yes Aisha and Button takes the data
from these fields from here.
It combined this data with the duty.
And once that duty is executed, that
data is stored in the inside the database.
We will see how this
button is actually working
behind the scenes,
how that data got stored in a database,
what beauty is executed,
how we pull data
to how we push the data to database.
Database is online, correct?
Not local. It can be local.
It can be online.
Most of the dexerto applications
that you guys use,
they might have local databases
and online databases,
but the web applications
that they always have,
online databases.
So we were using a skill
without even knowing it.
Yes. Yes, you are right.
I show printing.
So let me tell you a little bit more about
databases so that you guys can see
a little bit more
how things work together.
Hello, everyone.
Sorry I am late.
Alexi is my call girl.
Have you fear?
Have you heard her? Good. Will died
so many was looking protocol.
So as we have a language.
Well, why do we need the Java language?
Guys?
What do we do with Java language?
Talk to a computer.
Same way we use school language
to talk to a database
API as we have Java language
to maybe tell your computer
with the help of Selenium framework
How to click on a browser.
We have this skill language
and with the help of this skill language,
we tell the database
If we need some data,
how to give us that special database
piece of data,
or if we want to store some data
or if we want to delete some debt,
or if we want to add some data
or anything that we want to do inside
big database.
We need we,
we need this skill language as good.
I didn't recognize you.
I thought I do another class.
Yes, you are right.
Only Java
languages using or we have more today
you guys will learn another language.
Yesterday you guys will be learning
another language.
So by the way, this school is short
for structured beauty language.
Then just a fancy to learn.
Don't don't worry about it
for short.
In the industry
we always, almost always use
school or sequel
whenever we need to stay in this
structured beauty language
except programing language.
Similar,
very similar to the programing language
that we use to manipulate the data
or to define some of the rules
inside that base
or to delete added modifier
or anything that we have to do
inside the database.
We use this language to tell that content
not being software, what do we want?
So it's short for structured
query language
and it is specifically designed
to communicate with the databases.
Java, we write Java code
to talk to computers,
to communicate with computers.
We use school to talk to databases.
We use it to manipulate the management
being databases to arms.
And as we have the rules for Java,
we also have rules for school.
But the rules for schools are very,
very flexible.
They are not that strict
like we have in Java.
Then they are very, very flexible.
If in databases,
if you are not using the proper syntax
or you are not using the proper semantics,
most probably you will get wrong data,
but you will not get an error
or something like that.
While we were learning Cucumber
as to find a cool
contract, it's
yes, I like the
I am about to sign a cool contract
so hopefully everything
will be good again.
Married once again.
You guys please give me some motivation.
Can you guys please tell me that
everything will be fine?
I am really scared.
Never.
Everything will be fine.
Yes. I might be getting married soon.
Everything will be super fine.
Let's say dream you, Atelier 14.
It's.
Yes, I am a good as well.
But I am not sure about how
my wife will treat me.
Do it.
It will be easy
from that.
I would not.
It would not be your own life.
Oh my God.
Maybe I want to run
into a different country or something,
but I am already trapped.
And I just realize when it comes
to getting married, for
especially for boys, like, for example,
my mother told me in their past
that I need this, this, this suit
and I need these these shoes
and I need this jewelry and all that.
My father told me I need this,
this sister, they have their own list.
We need this, this, this.
I am the only one who is spending
and nobody cares about me.
And now I have
to buy so many things for be
easy will pick it up you
if you will wash your computer.
If you. By the way,
she is also a developer.
She is doing her
master's in computer science as well.
I hope we will have something in common.
Maybe she will support you guys
instead of me.
Sometimes, but
then you will be programed.
Thank you guys.
Then sit and program your own life.
You will get so many others new.
Will talk if health conditions,
if I when I see let it be.
But I am really concerned.
I am scared for the babies, by the way.
My my babies, they will be coding
and then they will be five or six.
I hope so.
Learn to negotiate with 1 to 3 ratio
for happy life or I already have told her
that how much pocket money
she will She should expect from me
and all the
gifts that she I will be buying from her.
It will be from her pocket money.
So you have made some agreements already
and conditions
one day there, one dollars
pocket money gone from her account.
All right,
guys, let's get back to the class.
So as we have rules for Java,
we also have rules for school.
And we will be learning all those rules
in this course.
So you guys already know
all about the debt or the information.
So usually when things are organized,
they are plastic instead of data.
We use this term information
or facts or records of information.
So if you throw just a random data
inside a folder
or inside a file,
we refer to that as the data.
But if you put everything organized,
everything is easy.
Everything has a meaning assigned to it.
We refer to it as information,
facts on records.
So databases,
they are very, very organized.
We have papers, we have columns and rows.
All the tables
are connected to each other.
So we will be referring to that thing
as most of the time information,
usually as records of data.
You should see the woman in the slide
showing terms and conditions here.
Oh my God, I am it
a sign for me,
no matter how much money a girl.
Because after her marriage is worth money.
Her money? Yes. The man.
Is he already cooperative?
These are these.
Leave this index to the life picture.
Harmony is harmony
and has learned the money also How
we poor man What we can do.
You already signed even if you don't know
not only money, it is everything. Yes.
So then what we can say?
Can you please let me repeat Zema Mr..
So let me repeat Zuma All the money
that you have is is not yours.
It's Silver's money as well.
But the money that Sylvia had
is her money.
It's not your money.
This will be a very zema.
We don't see any comment from you
to pass that or I
beware for for
Look, you can only show to my husband
the storage systems.
So there are so many types of databases.
So whichever
system
you are using to store that information,
we call them storage systems.
And if they are allowing the users
to keep, organize and manage that data,
we call them as the database systems,
and they are not that simple.
They are very, very complex systems.
And we actually they are that complex that
in industries
we have is separate role.
We have a separate team
just to manage databases,
a separate job, just to manage database
so you guys
can just have a job by.
Just let me ask you.
Well, if you learned the proper
way, separate teams and separate
separate IP rules, they are called
a DB is just to manage the databases.
They are that much complex, that huge.
And you guys will be in fact,
you guys will be interacting with those.
DB A lot.
So these are some of the examples
of the yes.
DB As they are called.
DB As database administrators, best
Buddy, we are thinking about woman here.
So almost all the big companies,
they have their own databases,
Microsoft, IBM, Oracle,
and we also have the open
source databases.
Thank you. Silva So
by the way, this Microsoft access
that yes,
there is a firebase and I have actually
worked a lot with that firebase.
So if you guys know about the access,
I think I have it on my computer.
So it comes with this
a suite of Microsoft applications
when you install office or something.
So this is how
you guys can imagine
how our database looks.
It looks like very, very similar to Excel.
So we have columns in here
and then we can start inserting the data
inside these rules.
For example, any anything
that may be numbers or maybe you want to
insert to be named
or something like that,
all of the text related
or numeric that that that you want.
So this is how a table will look like.
It will have columns and rows
just like Excel choose,
and then you can give access
to this table.
Maybe, let's say
only a two or three employers
will be having access to this table.
Not everyone will be having access
in your component of this table, because
sometimes these tables, they can contain
very, very sensitive information.
For example, salaries of the employees,
credit card pins
or passwords or usernames.
So in companies and there will be a lot of
tables inside the databases,
but all the employees will
only be having access to those tables
which are related to their job.
So DBAs will be restricting
your access to those papers.
So this functionality is also provided
by that database software.
Let's say, for example,
if you want to give access
to a specific table or record or a column,
you can also do that.
How about my BSP, my skill?
Is it one of the tools?
Yes, it is one of the tools that you can
use to interact with the database.
Yes, BHP, my SBA.
So I'm
so this is the Microsoft access
that that I have written in here,
this Microsoft Excel.
It is ideal for small,
small and mid-sized businesses,
to be honest in the industry.
I have never seen this Microsoft access
being used as a database
system,
but this skill server, it's widely used.
Can you show again what do you do by
highlighting at the beginning in school?
I missed that part and that's will.
I will be showing all those steps again
under don't don't worry
when we will be writing the code.
I will or I'll be walking you through
all those steps is school
and of my school are different?
Yes, they are different.
So if something like that
school is a standard, school is a standard
in which we have defined all the rules
that how to write.
You re how to store the that line
and all those syntax,
all the semantic rules
and then all the company
like Microsoft, IBM, Oracle
or any other company in the world
that want to build a database system,
they follow this school standard
so that you guys, as the end users,
you don't have to learn, let's say,
a different language
if you are using the database
from Microsoft, a different language,
from, let's say,
IBM, a different language,
if you are using a database from Oracle.
So this is actually the standard
that they are all agreed on.
But still companies,
they make teeny tiny details in syntax
and in semantics here and there.
So I will I will tell you
what are those differences?
And we will teach you to database
databases.
Actually, the database from Oracle
and the database
from this open source database.
Then that is called my ask you.
So we will be teaching you this to back
that basis so that you guys have an idea
what things can be different from database
or back to base.
But I think 90% of the time
all the
companies, they follow this standard.
So you guys will not be needing
to learn too much details.
If you want to switch
to a different database,
let's say if you get a job
and they are using Sybase,
so you don't need to completely
relearn all the syntax and semantics.
Maybe 5% or 34%.
You guys have to.
So in class we will be covering my school.
So my school is the open source
database are developed by community.
It's free.
Everyone can use it this
this database freely.
But this Oracle one is the paid one.
And we will also be looking
at this database.
And these are
some of the famous databases and
they are all ideal for mid-sized
businesses, are ideal for midsize
large size
by large size,
most probably in the industry.
You guys either
will be working with Oracle
or my
school or sometimes this SQL Server, IBM,
these three are the famous ones.
Newbies are just names of those
and database softwares
that these companies have developed.
This SQL Server is from Microsoft.
My school is open source
and this Oracle is from Oracle.
Nice.
They have polyphonic.
So every application,
every website or desktop application,
mobile application, they have bookings,
frontend and backend backend
to contain all the rules and the databases
frontend contain all the look and feel
and you guys will be hearing
this term guide.
It is short form graphical user interface
and this is what you guys see
and interact with.
Back end is where
all the data and tools are stored.
So what what as a tester
we will be needing as a tester,
you guys will be verifying the frontend
and the backend.
So for example,
sometimes what happens is that
using selenium and all that you guys
might try to test cases
and when you put some information in here,
it might happen
that it forces all the rules.
But When you click on this and the button
maybe,
maybe that data is not stored
in the database.
So next time
you will not be able to find it.
So you will insert the data from here
inside this field
and you will you will save this data
by clicking on the save button
or some kind of similar button.
Then you will go to that base.
You will write a duty
to fetch the exact same information
that you have entered in here
and then you will match it.
If all the data has been saved correctly
in the correct table
or not, there can be so many mistakes
that developer can make.
Maybe they are splitting this data
in a different table
and they were supposed to store
in a different table.
Maybe they are only storing
first name, supervisor, name or ID,
or maybe they are not storing in status
or sub unit
so they can when they write these rules
and then when program do the applications,
they can make so many mistakes.
So as a tester, you guys will make sure
that not only frontend
is working perfectly fine, but all also
the back end is also working fine.
By the way,
there are two separate job roles.
Usually either you guys will work as
a backend tester or as a front and tester.
Till now you guys have been learning
different and testing from today.
You guys will be learning
how to perform backend testing.
This is the skill class next to the API.
API is also a part
of the backend testing. So
and so now you guys can apply
on two jobs at the front and tester
and a back and better.
So it will be a totally different story
from now on.
And you guys will actually be full
spec testers
as we have full spec development.
So after taking these two courses,
you guys will be full spec,
best of which can test back end
as well as frontend.
But on jobs you will be
most probably you will be testing
either the frontend or the backend.
So the title of the IP professionals
that set up which one is easy,
frontline frontend is easy,
backend is hard.
Finally, I am saying something is hard.
Title of the IT professionals
who install and maintain everything
related to databases they are called
IS database administrators button job.
Keep silence that you can do both. Yep.
And then if you will,
you will be very good.
Soon you will be manager or director
or something like that.
If you have this mentality,
if you know how to sell yourself,
how to, how to allow companies
to utilize your next crazy sign,
if that is not
going to save us.
So you would need
we have separate computers to store this
frontend and the rules
and yeah.
Yes madam, this is correct.
Frontend is sometimes it looks very,
very different.
How backend is working.
So these databases,
they are usually stored
on separate computers
and those two computers
which are exploding the frontend
and all those rules,
they are connected with these computers.
Which horse, these databases
are, Any questions still always.
Are things making sense?
What is the function of ideas?
I'll use this all the time.
Slowly
I shall please pick up the pace.
I think it's just 1.5 months or so
and you guys are ready for the jobs.
With five years of experience.
It will make more sense
when we start doing it.
Yep, yep, yep. It's
okay. So
databases are also thumbs
in different varieties.
Some of them are called
relational databases.
So the data that we stored in tables,
they are these tables,
they are also connected to each other
and they have some kind of relationship
with each other.
And the databases
which have this type of structure,
these tables and all are rows and columns.
They are called relational databases.
Later on, I have to tell you an example,
and it will make more sense.
And there are other types of databases,
as Damir
said,
that Firebase is a database from Google.
It does not have tables.
It stores the data
in the form of developers or documents.
Firebase
is a real time database
that has fired stored as well
that five stored.
It actually stores
the data in the form of documents.
So for us to take our time
tied to document and then we stored
that data inside Firebase but
we will not be learning those databases.
They are called non relational databases.
We will be learning
the relational database is only
because they are the databases
which are widely used.
Slowly, Industry is moving towards
the non relational databases, but
because they lack something very basic
and not all
the applications can be transferred
to non relational database.
You just said database
20 times 21 country to
fetch select and database.
You guys will hear these words
so many times.
Okay,
so our DB and message again is short form
for relational database management system.
And if this system, if
this is the special category
of databases that
work on the principle
that each table has a key field
that uniquely identifies each role
and that these is can be used to connect
to one table to another table
supporting
still important things in here. Yes.
So those databases
which have these papers and these tables
which are connected to each other,
with the help of these keys,
I will show you in a very great detail
how it will can be connected
with other table and what are these keys,
these special type of databases.
They are called IBM's,
and we will specifically be discussing
these type of
I have walking job interviews
with five year old tester
and I realize that I know
most of the answers.
I thought, I don't know anything,
No one, you guys.
So we will be preparing you
for the interviews as well.
But you guys are done with all the courses
we will prepare.
Your resume is
we will teach you how to do an interview
and we will be hosting separate sessions
for each course for Java as well,
Selenium and all those separate classes
to prepare you for interviews
after that, after taking those
sessions, believe me,
you guys will be much,
much more prepared than an actual person
who is actually working
for the last five years
because usually what happens in the jobs,
let's say,
if company is being benefited, let's say
a company has hired you for something
and your job is just to, let's say,
fill an Excel file.
And if companies business is growing,
if you fill that Excel file on time,
believe me, they don't bother if you know
anything else or they don't bother.
If you are learning anything on jobs
or not, they will just keep on saying
to you that, Please keep filling
those Excel files on time
because that's what is required
for the business to do so.
But when you guys will be preparing,
we will be preparing you.
We will be preparing you
as the overall person who has actually
worked in 3 to 4 different companies,
have used multiple tools and all that.
So you guys will always be more prepared
than those actual persons.
I will prepare.
I will keep learning new things
in order. Just start somewhere.
So if you have this attitude or not,
you guys will be
one of those
who become directors or managers
or go to those top positions
as well.
Let me check if you're a woman. Change.
Do you mean shall
I please show number three in fingers?
This is the number to be done, man. This
you are okay.
Perfect.
We will build a fake
you Universal specialist
that number three.
Soon I will be needing that number three.
Maybe next week.
So basics of databases
Database is a collection of papers
we stored in that timely form of papers
and when you are hired.
So maybe the collection of tables.
Tables in database consist of rows
and columns just just like Excel files.
And that old sorry that told me that
a little change of terminology
rows in the DB,
they are called red bar records or tuples.
Sometimes
columns in the
DB called fields and Attributes.
So those columns are
sometimes called fields or attributes.
And the role rows, they are
sometimes called tuples or red cards.
And so because there can be so many tables
in a database, sometimes
to understand
the overall picture of a database,
we build this kind of picture
and this kind of picture is called
it has a special name,
it is called Schema.
So in this picture, this is a table,
this is another table,
This is another table.
And you guys will notice
that there are some lines
which are being drawn
from one table to another.
Table is DV connections.
No, no. This is a schema of a database
and they are just telling you that
what are the names of columns
in this table?
So this is the date of birth.
This is the name relationship.
This is the relationship type,
use name and all that.
So the name of the columns
that you have in your table,
plus this arrow that shows you
which other table this table is connected
and how to out of these tables
I will show you.
Can you zoom a little bit?
I think it is a screenshot.
You can check
if I can if I can share this with you
guys, copy.
I hope it will allow me.
No, I'm
going to download this picture from here.
It's okay. We will have this presentation.
Actually, I will share this picture
separately as well.
Let me check actually
if I have that on my computer, give me
let's do
a rescue, please.
No, that's okay.
We will have to select.
Yes, you guys will be having those slides.
So a new term,
the term is called
database schema.
And what this database schema is, it's a
kind of graph.
It's a kind of picture that shows you
overall
about overall about the tables
that you have in a database
and the relationships.
And each this vertical column,
which actually contains
the names of the columns in that table.
And these arrows
there, shows the relationship
with this primary key and foreign key.
They are the columns
based on which these two tables
are connected, and I will show you how
they are connected.
We need to
so let's say we have a table
in which we are storing the employee
first name status supervisor name.
So are there chances, guys,
that this record
then have duplicate values? Yes.
So to avoid that duplication,
we always, always use a special column
in all the tables and we call it ID
and we make sure that the I.D.
is something that can uniquely identify
two records.
It's like the SSN, two persons.
They can have same names, but not all
persons can have same SSN number.
So similarly,
when we store some data in a table,
we always, always
try to have a column
that always contains something is unique
that we can use to refer to a special row.
And in databases.
That special column
is called Primary District.
We call it the primary key.
So why we have the primary key
so that if there are two same records,
we still have a piece of information
that can help us to uniquely
identify and record unity.
So that's why we always create this IDs.
So you see it in here. And if you
guys execute the
security, select all from person,
you will see this I.D.
column here that's not in here.
The idea is they are simple numbers.
Each time we insert
a new record
and new number is inserted in here
and we can use that number to uniquely
identify that.
So for example, in here
or actually the city is different, but
even if the city is same, we can identify
this little with this number 15
and this road with the number 14,
so that we never have that ambiguity,
never have that duplication.
Does it make sense?
You guys need the primary key.
Why? We have it.
So the theme is written in here.
Every table
in that database will have a primary key,
unique identifier, unique column
to refer to Special rule No Special column
to refer to.
All the rules are uniquely
possible.
So let me repeat it again.
Every table in database.
So overall,
we first have a database inside database.
We have tables.
Inside tables, we have rows and columns.
So what is primary key?
Primary key is a special column
that contains the unique numbers,
all the letters or sometimes
combination of both that we can use
to uniquely identify all the rows
from that table.
So primary for short, we use the can be
instead of primary, you would say, Peter.
So primary is a column
in the table
that uniquely identifies e red card
and the value is never,
never duplicate or empty.
So all the rules that we insert
for this special column,
they will always have a value.
They cannot be empty, null or
a left
on inserted.
So similar to week
it cannot contain null values.
So inside this table
be reminded me of Ahmed Hawn's movie.
So person I.D.
in here we are calling it
the person I usually
usually in databases, in tables.
We usually put this I.B.
word with the column
that we are using as primary.
We can use any column as the primary key.
We just propel the database.
That database.
Nick This column,
I will be using this column
as the primary,
so the database will know how to like
which column I need to treat,
especially as the primary.
So you guys understand
the purpose of the primary key
this new terms like primary
and then
null value.
So null in databases is used when we
do not have anything inside.
And so for
example, if
I open the Excel
line, maybe I can show you from database,
you see there's
this null, null null
written in here, null.
It means no value is inserted
for this vab
and date of birth column for this row.
These rules no values inserted so
database insert in null value.
When we do not insert anything inside
this inside the column.
When we insert a complete row of
okay so so many Newton's
school, we what is that skill base?
Is it a programing language
or a software or a standard
or what is this as well? Yes.
If suspend or there's a standard for
a, for the language that we use to
store or manipulate data
inside a database.
Right. And what what is the database
And that nothing
special question Two ladies VMs
if files in this system
are not actually
if not a file in the system,
I'm asking about the impact of this.
What is in database is
it is some kind of software
or is it
there's some kind of programing language
or is it some kind of other thing
collection of data
in terms of papers? Yes.
So it's a piece of software that explores
the data in the form of tables.
And all these tables,
they have rows and columns,
and we stored in that
in a special structure
and that special structure
that our bases are called on B, B and Ms..
Indeed, special type of databases.
We have tables and tables
have some kind of relationship
with each of them.
Okay.
And what is a schema, guys?
What is a schema?
What is a database schema?
Yes, it's a kind of visual information
about the tables and their relationship
with each other
that a database like this one
is. And
what is the primary key presentation?
How tables are linked to each other.
You need to write
a special column
that help us uniquely identify
a row inside
a table.
Yes, Yes.
All all right.
Well, do you guys have some questions
or. Everything?
Looks good.
Special column that I'd be donating.
Those would be most
birds.
And I know I adore.
What is the role for and what is column?
Yes, most of all, you see.
So this is a table
in here.
So for example, this column is ID first
name, last name, gender, ACP.
So if you go
to this human resource,
can you guys tell me
what will be the column names?
If I create a table for this page,
which of this will be table name,
which one of them will be column names,
and what kind of things will go inside
the rows
from this page?
Identify the table.
What do you guys think?
If you guys design, if you guys are asked
to design a database table for this page,
what will be the name of the table
so the
you guys can call this table
as the implied information.
Everyone agrees
that we can create the table employ
information
to store the data from this table.
Okay, identify the primary E
first, tell me the column names.
What should be the column names?
If I have to define a table
for this information,
what do you guys think?
So do we use this information
as the column names
for this table?
Right?
So for if we are creating a table
for this page, this will be the table name
and these will be the columns
of the
tell me out of these columns,
which one should I use as the primary?
I'd be right.
This one
and this one I can use as primary.
And what will be the rule?
Well, what will the rows contain?
What will rows contain inside this table?
What will those contain?
All this data.
This will be stored.
I b this will be first name,
last name title.
I need to.
Moustafa is it clear how Well,
what are rows and columns
in a database table?
Is there anyone who can still who cannot
still think
how a web page can be?
How information from one page
can be converted to a table?
Why it all, says Suhail. The best
is okay,
we will change it to batch 11 is the best
You one.
Once you guys know the school, you guys
will be able to change this information.
Whatever you guys want.
Okay, so now you guys know
how information
can be stored
in the form of a table inside
a database, right?
Okay, let's let's do one more example.
So that is the.
Okay, so let's say
I want to create a table
for this page.
Identify
the table name for this page. Yes.
After this, we will be having a break.
So leave list will be in the table name
identified the column names
all the fields.
Right.
Do you guys know we actually have
the exact same tables in the database?
Exact same tables.
Open up your my skill workbench
and click on this.
So you should see this syntax item,
underscore
my circular below
that you should see tables
in here and an arrow expand
this arrow in here.
Do you guys see
all the table names inside the database?
This is the actually actually,
this is the same database
that is connected to that.
That implication
because I am adamant right now.
That's why I see more stuff.
I have access to all the tables.
These are the exact same table tables
that are being used for that website
as the backend.
And let me tell you something interesting.
So you see this,
I did 2068 for air, so hell the best.
Let me copy this information in here
guys.
Then you
guys guessed the name of the table
that might have this information.
This imply information.
Go through all these tables
and tell me which table you guys think
then have that implied information.
I cannot see this table in my ask you a
massive videos.
Do you see this
this icon of database and return
and this syntax item
under my screen here
and do you guys see this table asset
at job employed
or asset that DOT employs? Yes.
You guys will be having fewer tables
because I am the admin.
I have access to all the tables.
But do you guys I don't want to describe
this database by your hands.
That's
why I have given you limited access.
But you guys should have this asset
that implies.
So let me show you.
What does this table contain?
So a tool
to check out what the table contains.
We like to select start from asset
at job
implies.
Okay. Like this.
Right.
And this utilize and execute this query.
You guys see this employ
number employ only
when you write asset select
start from asset that implies.
Now don't worry about the syntax
just right.
We're
employ
I d is equal to
and can you guys guess what
information I will get
if I write employ ID
is equal to and this I'd be
deciding from the front end
this this me so hell the best
then you guys.
That's what I would probably get.
I get the exact same
information on bosses
to hell, the best date of birth
and all those blah blah blah blah.
So this is how we try to query
to fetch the data from backend
so that this is how it is
in the outlook's from the frontend.
So now before going on to the break,
your task is to insert
some data
from the frontend in here, in here
and then modify the security
so that you guys can see
the same information from this database
inside of this table.
Okay.
Your task is to insert
some data
from the frontend in here inside this page
and then modify this query
so that you guys see your data in here
when you execute degree.
Is there anyone who is confused
about the task
or the task is not
after I type the
how did you get
so the best on the lower part
in any you don't work this
okay now so next page will be overloaded.
Oh by the way guys, please
don't even start doing that too much data,
okay?
Please don't destroy my poor database.
But oh, by the way,
this is how we write comments,
Write a theory
or platform,
modified the list below.
You agree to
fetch the data that you insert from
frontend.
Next will be enough for the break.
Okay.
Let's have a break for 15 minutes.
Okay. Please come back.
Is a single or double code full?
If not, what do we
some of the questions
then don't support it.
But this my school,
if it supports the single course
as well as the double course
of the Oracle one it does not support.
I will tell you the differences later on,
but right now you guys can use
both of them.
It will be it will be a good practice
if you can use the single course,
because it will work on
almost all the databases.
Okay. Not don't use the double quotes.
Let let's learn of the best
best practices.
Can you repeat task one more time?
And it is written in here.
This is the task, not worry.
It is just simply if you want to execute.
Let's say you have written so many queries
and let's say
you only want to execute a specified query
so you can select back like this
and you can execute that specific query.
Now all of the queries
will not be executed from this page.
Only discovery will be executed.
If you want to execute this one,
you can only select this one.
Or are you going to execute this one?
This is what you mean
by highlighting things.
Is there anyone who is still not clear
about the task?
I forgot. What do I do?
It's not showing a post in this portion of
or stand up from your chair,
have some dance
beads, some fresh here
and then post in the sport.
And I did. You did the dance already?
It's still not working.
Many dance
and you do get some kind of added or
for guys
you guys are already as good
champions throws
we don't need to learn anything
about skill
in the new year
because you are not executing the activity
selected.
Give slide this query like this
and then press this button in here
posting this sport channel
if you guys face any issue and please
be back 1210
other guys, see you in 15 minutes.
And don't forget to remind me
about recording
and the sub unit is developer
start game later and sales human resource
include current employees only.
Now I should click on add
base.
I'm not familiar with this application.
Yes. Is it inserted?
Not inserted
in? Should I insert the information here?
I like
for why changing my name?
Is there a bug in this website?
A lot
of. Okay.
All right.
Let let me copy this ID
so this.
Oh we can right.
And if I click on sale, will it work
so successfully.
That's why I have copied this
employed I from here.
And if I can get in here
sometimes it takes a
bugs there for us to find them.
Here we see right information
that we inserted
from front that.
All right.
So this is how this frontend backend
and tables and database
are all connected.
So you guys cannot change that.
You guys don't have the access to this
to do this one.
So let's, let's,
let's learn the rules for this skill
so that you guys can fetch data
from these tables, from this database.
Should we.
Are you guys ready?
All right, so
I will feed you
about this foreign key later on.
Here are some rules.
So ask your is case insensitive?
Okay.
Uppercase and lowercase things
they are same in squirrel,
but some of the databases
they are they do not support this feature.
For example, the Oracle database.
It is so sensitive in some of the areas.
This my skill
when it is almost case insensitive in
everywhere. The
the queries
that we use to fetch the data
from the database.
This left from this keyword
select keyword.
And we also have keywords
like update or delete insert.
They are the same keyword as we have in
Java as we have
class final Abstract.
All those reserved.
However, they are also reserved
the keyword for school.
So using these keywords
we construct ambiguities
and feel good.
They also end with semicolons
as the Java ones.
How we connect my sequel to website
by using log in and pass.
Alex We will.
I will also teach you
how to connect your applications
to database in the last class.
We will also learn that
semicolon is standard way
to separate school statements.
If you delete from school,
it will be deleted from application
Yes, I show.
But companies in real life,
they have backup databases.
They have backup tables as well.
So but still, we have not given you
the delete permission
because I know
you guys will just remove everything
from the start of this
so you guys don't have to remove access.
I only have to remove x,
but I will teach you how to do that.
Actually,
I should teach you how to do that.
You guys will destroy the databases
as well in the companies,
but I will teach you on a test database.
So as a tester
we mostly use select statement
to extract
select specific data from the database.
Okay.
So the first beauty that we will learn
from,
so we don't have to know that you guys
actually should not know that.
But I will show you
sometimes you might need.
Yes, the databases are big,
goes for the haircuts
because this is where
all the information is stored,
all those credit card numbers, things,
their balances, usernames, passwords.
This is where it is all stored
if your backup is compromised.
That said, the hackers, they don't have
to do anything with your application.
They have the database.
They have all the data.
So this is the very simple, simple
hello world.
The syntax that as you guys made
that helloworld in Java,
this is the hello world of ask you.
So we use this
this reserved keyword select.
And after they select
we specify the column name
from which we want.
I want the data.
Yes, these are the protocols
that you guys should follow.
If you get fired or delete their database,
you should.
You can actually.
But all the companies,
they kind of have always these backups.
They always
have backups.
So this is this is a reserved keyword.
You guys can type
this keyword in uppercase or lowercase
or mix up it some of uppercase,
some lowercase.
It will work.
In any case, no issues.
Then we specify the name of the column.
So let's say, for example,
if a table have 15 columns
and you want to get to that now, let's say
maybe from one column or two columns,
you can specify those columns in here.
Then this from again, it is old keyword
and after the different,
we specify the table name.
So if I ask you
if I ask you,
I have this table
person
inside this database,
can you guys write it?
You need to just refer to the first name
from this table.
Can you guys Google type activity
and send it to me?
I want all the rules.
Mark The columns should to be firstname.
This person name of
by the way,
we can also use the hash symbol
for comments.
So this is the good effect.
All the first names from Busan,
this table.
This is your task.
But I take you
to fetch all the first names from persons
table
from persons stable.
I shall please grow up.
You are about to leave syntax.
It's not from as such implied
small persons.
Everyone is about 20 years old.
I still maybe eight years old
or nine years old.
I'm just thinking of you guys.
I love your.
Why are you picking on Asia?
Because I don't mind.
Oh, Maryam, you want to be in big game.
Okay, let's.
From now on, Maryam will be. You
do it.
It's so.
I will write the select statement
right after this.
Select statement we specify the column
from which we want to fetch the data.
So what is the column name?
Can you tell me the column name?
It's the first name.
Do I need to type it exactly
the same as it is displayed in here?
Uppercase. First name?
Or is squirrel not so sensitive?
So I can write anything.
I can write first,
I can write capital, MN and anything.
Okay. It is not case sensitive.
So select first statement and I can also
do the same with this select.
Maybe some of it, uppercase
some of the lower obvious,
but a good skill
developer will write these
without keyboard in all uppercase
and the column names
same as the
entire table.
A good developer.
Okay, so once
you have specified
this is this is how we make comments
using the hash signs
or using these underscores.
So once you have specified the start
I will tell you
what does this statement is very
the start of means that the fetch
all the columns start
means that all the columns
here.
So after specifying the column name,
we again write
the next result keyword which is from
so it's it's very similar to English
we are saying here
database select this column from
and then we specify the table name.
That's simple English select
first name from this table.
And if I execute this duty.
So I see all the first names in here,
all the first names,
and you guys also see the same.
So then it is saying, why not write a star
instead of first name?
So then it's right now
these are simple toy tables.
In real life, you will be having a table
that may contain
150 columns, 200 columns, 300 columns.
If you write star, all
your query will take a
long, long time to fetch all data
from all the columns and all the rows.
So we never, ever write
this all unless and until you understand
what you are doing.
Okay, Because this query
is being executed on a server
which is right now located in,
I don't know, in the United States
or maybe in Russia.
I don't know.
We are on the list and it is all
the data is traveling on the Internet.
If you fetch unnecessary data
that you don't,
you your application will be super,
super slow.
Your processing time will increase.
So we always, always write what we need.
But for the learning purpose
we might use the static
stop symbol a lot,
but in practice we should never
nor start
means all the columns, not all the tables.
We'll get the
but yes.
So right now I have only told you
how to filter out column names.
Later on I will also repeat you
how to filter rules.
Right now.
You'll see all the rules later on.
I will teach you how to even some rules
that you are interested in.
Instead of selecting all the rows.
Okay, So
if we have to get the data
from two tables,
can you guys guess what will be the syntax
now please post in the sports channel.
Use and use. And
so and it is used for a different purpose
in here we use
we separate the column names from like
so if I write last name.
So right now
I'm using a comma to separate out
separate of multiple clients.
Actually, let me,
I will share all of these curious,
but I want every one of you to follow me.
So if I write a first name for my
last name, then I see first name
and the last name in the output.
You guys also see
two columns in the output.
Friend.
Okay guys, then write acuity
to your first name, last name, gender,
age and city
and send me the fact of first name,
last name, gender, age and city.
Does school execute
only the last word by default,
it executes the line that your
that you put your cursor on.
But let's say if you want to execute this
one, you can select and execute this one.
If you want to use this select,
you want to go to this one, select
and execute this one.
If you want to use, execute
this one, select and execute.
So this is how we do it.
Select that unit
that you want to execute and then
click on Execute Button.
Okay.
So if we want to build that from
gender
ID and City,
we separate out these column names
and then we will see that to.
Is there anyone who is unable
to see the same results
that I see in here?
All would
is there anyone who is confused
or if there is anyone who don't understand
what is going on?
Skill is literally very,
very easy as compared to Java or
something like that.
Select first and limit to zero hundred
add up or knowing that number be selected.
So if you guys see this error,
that means you need to execute this
first line at the
now you are getting this error.
So let me explain
on a single server
where you can have thousands of databases
and when we write a query,
we need to specify
on which database we want to execute.
The security.
So this use means that for all the duties
that I will be writing below this line,
all the UDC
should be executed on this database.
So you,
those who bought this add other you have
and you need to select this command
and you need to execute this at the manner
you need to do this.
After that, you will not get any entries.
So you guys see in here
on the left side on this server,
we have three databases
there is this database passed to syntax
underscore sequel.
There is a syntax item underscore school
and there is this system on the database.
So right now we need to tell our database.
We need to ask you all to fetch
the data from this database.
That's why we need to execute this Good.
Yes. Because you guys don't have access.
You will see only one database again,
you guys know the reason
this.
Okay? Yes.
I said you guys will not see
those two options.
These are system tables and they contain
very sensitive information.
Actually,
you can delete the complete database
if you have the access to these tables.
And you guys know the reason
why you guys don't see those tables.
Even if you Google,
you will not be able to do that
because you have not shared password with
it. Okay.
And if I have to fetch the data
from all the columns of a table
can you guys tell me the query for that?
If I have to fetch the data
from all the columns, here's the
select
all or static and then from
for only the reserved keyword
and then the personal data.
But right.
And now I see the data from
all the columns.
Okay, Almost all good.
Should I proceed to the next thing? So
easy peasy.
Okay, so if we say select
the first name,
most of I will tell you
what does this weird mean?
You just give me a few minutes.
So if we do that from first name,
let me execute this duty.
So you guys will notice
that there is a lot of duplicate data.
Do you guys see
the duplication in the data?
So if we do not want this duplication,
there is a result.
Again, it is old keyword that we can use
to avoid duplicate data.
Can you guys guess the data?
Can you guess the name?
Well, what can being a result
give to avoid duplication?
Unique
and distinct?
Remove Remove
so unique gives.
Yes, it's a keyword,
but it is used for a different purpose.
Why you guys are saying delete Myriam.
If I want to remove.
If I don't want duplicates, you should.
I deleted them
permanently from the database.
And you see, that's
why you guys don't have access.
Because delete is the
that will actually delete all the data.
So even if you guys are trying
to fetch the
unique data, you will still deliver
the data.
Yes. The keyword is distinct, right?
Or distinct Before the first name
and immediately
and again try to find the data and see
if that removes the duplicate
data from your
desired site.
Mohammad It does not matter
if it is the first one or the second one
because they are same.
Okay.
And if if we have,
let's say two columns, let's say a select
first name,
I want every one of you to follow me.
If we have first name, last name
from person,
let's say I am selecting the data
from two columns
and again, I have duplicate data, right?
You see the duplicate data
even when we try to select the first name
and the last name. Yes.
Then is actually this software,
this my skill workbench.
It is the most pathetic software
that you can ever use
to write skill queries, but it is free.
That's why we have to use this.
Otherwise, in your companies
you guys will be
using much more better teams,
but they will be paid.
So you have to build this one
because if you want to learn,
you should not be looking
right away
for that IntelliSense of autocomplete.
Otherwise you will get used to that
and you will not learn it.
So that's why have read the most pathetic.
They are not pathetic.
They are good,
but they don't help you that much in
writing the code. But
for it was all recorded.
All my groups fine.
So if we have
multiple data from multiple
columns.
No, no.
This is not exactly what I am saying.
Please do.
I am saying because we want you to learn
at at your best.
That's why we are offering you these tools
so that you type everything on your own.
Okay? This is what.
This is what I am saying.
Please be.
You can stop recording
and tell us the truth.
Yes. All recording.
I am saying I neither confirm this fact
nor I deny this.
You see, in that movie, it always says
whenever ask the question, it says,
I neither confirm nor deny this
next bachelor
Java notepad.
So, guys, what do you guys think?
If I have to remove the duplicate data
from two tables,
can you guys tell me the syntax for that?
And then this being tried.
I don't need to put this thing before
every column.
If I just put be this thing
in front of this column,
it will remove the duplicate that. Now,
by the way,
all the data is still present
in the database.
It is just that we are fetching some
results from the database.
Any of these cuties, they are making
any changes in the database.
We are just fetching some data
using different different queries
so that whatever
in whatever form the that I store
it is still stored in that form.
It is just a view that we are getting
when we write this query just to see.
Yes, no
changes are being made in the database.
If a person has a different first name,
but the same last name will choose
one and remove the other.
What do you guys think? Maman
As a whole,
when I fetch the first name
and the last name,
and if a person has a different last name,
are there duplicate records
or are they unique records?
They are unique because the last name is
different, so they are not same anymore.
So unique will.
Not do anything but back.
You will still get the same result
with unique and without it.
If a person has same first
and the last name,
then you will get a single record.
When you use the distinct keyword
in front.
In here is a clear race.
What is distinct function in here
as Google have you just did?
You are in the big class.
Then you guys tell me
what this distinct is going in here to.
So if we remove an article
to check this out,
if I remove that distinct from here
and if I execute discovery,
you see, that's
why I asked that question right now.
You see duplicate
that are in here, right Sada And so right.
But if you do not want this duplication
then you can use distinct keyword
and it will remove the duplicate records
from your results.
And by the way, this is called results.
Where can we see the number of employees
after executing line well?
And the third being
so by default then is if you observe
in the output
window, it is showing you
how many rules have been written.
Then if you see 22 rows, return
15 rows, return 32 rows returns,
and the time
it took for your query to execute
so you can get this information from here.
Otherwise
during this special duty as well,
that you can execute to find out
the number of records in a table
or the number of records that you're Kutty
so that you're curious, fetching.
But I will teach that later.
It will remove the duplicate
from last name as well.
So Nicolet combined from first name
and the last name.
If a person has same first name
and the last name,
if there are 15 persons
who have same first name and last name,
after using distinct,
you will see only one of them.
So question how to remove duplicate
from last name as well.
So let's say
you want to have only a single job.
Alex It will.
It will effect your structure.
You see,
if you want to have one
job, then
what will happen to these records?
Where should they go?
So this question does not make sense
away.
So how do you decide
if it should remove girl M.J.
and Sara?
And so this Dom, this Dom or this down?
So there are some things that we can do,
but there are things
that we should not do,
and there are things that are known
to make any sense to do.
Yes, you can do it still,
but you have to learn a lot of skill
for that.
But still, even if you learn that,
it does not make sense because.
Right.
You have to tell your duty to them
to only keep maybe Sara, Google M.J.
or ALEC and automatically
it will only get one gem from here.
Or Jane or Leonardo.
Visit whatever you want.
So this the table structure is will be
maintained in all the it is our search.
So whatever you do right,
you will get the results
in the form of a table.
If it is useless in
for just to tell is not relevant.
Yes. Look, in life
that bothered the family there
where you want only one
election will make more sense.
Give it more time or a
can you guys
I duties to give me
all the unique cities from this table.
So right now if I execute this duty
for the citizens I see some duplication.
New York is three times Los
and then Dubai Istanbul is multiple times.
But what I only want to know how many
unique cities are there in this table.
Can you guys write victory
in here?
Great.
So select
this thing
c b from
Bursa.
You guys still will feel much more relaxed
after taking these skill classes,
so I don't see any duplicate cities.
Is there a shortcut to run?
A Yes, there is a shortcut to run.
Simon.
It's the control enter shot back,
so it will
execute the last duty
in which you have placed your cursor. Yes.
If you guys don't pull the semicolon,
then this short person buttons,
they will misbehave.
Does it work?
Simon
Control enter from the ultimate
protect
of a law.
If you guys notice
this skill workbench
is showing you the actual query,
how do that how to get not no one,
but I will tell you how to do that.
If you guys notice right now,
school work
when it is actually modifying your duties
that are actually
being executed on the server
so that if you even if you type
something accidentally, it does not
because fetching all the data from a table
can take up to RS
if that table has billions of red bugs.
So what school workbench is doing
right now?
It is putting a limit
on the number of rules that it is
fetching.
It is right now only fighting
the first thousand rules.
But if you also want
to put a limit on your data,
let's say
maybe you only want the first bend rules
so you can also do that.
So you can see
limit and then you can specify
the number of rules
that want to fetch.
So it has only first ten rules.
This time
by using limit
and then specifying the number of rules.
No. 11 is just a number.
You see it this starting from two
Alex It starts from two.
And you guys can also verify from here.
It saves ten rules
that it is a one column titles
in the one column titles.
How can you repeat the first ten?
It starts from two. Oh, okay.
By the way, let me tell you this also
in database, when we store the data,
it is stored
with the help of a special algorithm.
And these algorithms, they differ
from companies, company to company.
So the structure, the the insertion
order of the data can never be
you guys can never be 100% sure.
If you are inserting something
at a specific time,
you will always be getting that data
in that order.
It is random.
It depends how your database
is stored in the data.
So this this, this information in here,
most of the time
it will be in order of the ID,
but you can never guarantee it is returned
in a completely random order.
If we have to guarantee that buying
a specific order,
I will teach you how to do that.
So it is fine if you see 11 in here.
If you see three in here, it is fine.
We will see how to tackle this in four.
And then this problem in execution
white paint and then came before it.
It can also come in before.
So it's random.
It is not in our control.
Good approach is use uppercase
for the reserved keywords.
By the way,
I also not using it all the time.
I should, but it will work
even if you write
it in uppercase or note or in whatever.
But I usually I have seen uppercase
use looks good,
and most of the developers,
they follow this.
So can we get different 10% each time?
No, most probably
you guys will be getting the same results
as I am getting in here.
If you execute on this same quality,
do you guys get different results?
You should not.
It should be same. Same.
You should can
always the same results, but
we cannot guarantee that
that query for is number
ten is before eight.
Then we have nine, then we have 11.
So this order is not guaranteed,
but same duty will return,
same results.
All right.
So you guys now understand how to fact did
that.
Are from any column, right.
And how to figure it out
from all the columns.
Now, let me show you how to.
So right now, you guys can filter out
the columns, right?
And it depends on you.
Maybe you want to get to that first name.
Last name, maybe from city
or maybe you want to all of them.
Now, let me tell you how
we can filter out the rules
to filter the rows we use.
The we are close
to to filter out the columns.
We use the select clause.
By the way,
these are called clauses in school.
So to filter out the columns,
we use the select clause
to mention the table names
from which we want to get to that.
We use the from clause
and to filter out rules.
We use the word clause.
So let's say for example,
by the way, you guys can also do this.
You can select
a portion of the query as well.
If you just want to execute
that specific portion,
it will also work.
So you see it has only executed
your select all from person.
So party you select
it will only execute that part.
So the reserved keyword
to filter out
the rows is called to be where clause.
Let's say
I'm removing this element.
we only
want to be employ
employers that have employee already. 120
So what we will do, we will write, we're
after that, we will write the column name
MP ID and then we can write
the conditions the same as in Java.
So in here I am saying equal.
So in Java one equal to sign
is meant for assignment
and to equal to signs
are meant for comparison.
Right.
But in here
one equal to sign is meant for comparison.
So right now what I am saying to a skill,
I am saying hey,
a skill.
Okay, then
select all the columns
from this table
where in already is equal to 120.
But if I execute this query,
can you guys guess the output?
No need of double course.
Yes. Let me tell you, when you guys need
these double single code
and when you guys don't need
if the data is an automatic,
we don't need it.
Same as in Java.
If the data is an automatic,
we don't need those polls.
If the data is based on text,
then we need to double this course.
But what the skill gives you
this flexibility,
even if the data is a pneumatic
and if even if you use the single course,
it will still work.
But in actual
sometimes
it can be super, super slow
because ESC maintains and
index behind these scenes
to speed up your queries.
So if you had it even using
for the numeric data, yes,
it will work, but it might be slow.
So if you know for sure
that that will always be
numeric don't use.
Because if the data is string
then you should be able to single course
and skill is very, very flexible.
So it will allow you to use
a single course, double course
without course, but sometimes you guys
might not get the correct results.
So let's follow the best practices and
for the numeric,
let's not use double use single course.
And for this thing this data lets you
because if in
we don't use double
if string, we use our double course.
Alex this skill it exports everything
for spring and non spring.
You can always use a single
or double course, but the Oracle database
is a little stricter
stricter than this scale one.
It will not allow you
to use the double course.
By the way,
let me tell you how to practice
your skill skills on Oracle database
as well.
Side by side by guys
type Oracle live in your browser or
sorry, now you will learn the difference
and why I'm saying
these are the best practices
because you will see those things
will not work on Oracle database,
which I am asking you to avoid.
Do you guys see this page
type Oracle live
and let me know what you buy.
See this page
for Lamar?
Because a lot of students
are trying to use it.
You might face
this issue, try to deflect this page
because right now around 70 to 80
people are trying to access the same page.
I will wait.
Don't let me know once
everyone has this page
or Oracle index student
alone.
Actually, this is a free Web site,
so that's why they didn't
spend that much money here.
Look, it's free, man. It's free.
We should be thankful.
Even if exporting it.
Students.
So those are hopefully.
Is there anyone who is a product
which apparently little pages
still loading?
Okay, now click on my session
and offer
to be there to use the same username
and password that you guys created
when you were signing up for to install
your java
usernames and passwords index.
I thought, I'm one, two, three.
It will automatically in here
if you guys don't remember
you going to create one for that
click on school worksheet.
Try to click on school worksheet.
It might work without the username,
then someone can find me
if it is working without the username.
Okay then create.
If you guys don't remember,
please create your use of names in here.
We will be a lot on this as well.
Some of your homework
assignments are also designed for
this Oracle
database.
Is there to be time for the
break it to do.
You know we had to break on
but yes, not now.
After maybe 30 minutes.
Yes, you should create account
if you guys don't remember.
No. You need a break on.
No, I was thinking because maybe you guys,
meanwhile can clear
the usernames in the break
so that we don't waste
time.
Sorry.
What are we supposed to remember?
Assignment these username and password
to sign for Oracle is the same
that you guys used to download with Java
when you guys started learning double.
If you guys don't remember
you would unclear to me. One.
So this is something companies
don't use Maryam material disparage
you mean
but not no companies they don't use it
just to test the oracle syntax
the database syntax from Oracle.
I don't remember signing up for download
there they get.
That's great
assignment. Just sign up.
I need to ask you for me
username and password on this page
or maybe I will teach you
these things on Oracle one
after a little while
because it will take some time
to create the accounts.
Let's let's practice
more on the great syntax at then
database.
And I want you all of you have created
your username and password.
Then we will also learn how to do
same on Oracle one.
Guys, please,
please.
Let's get back to the class
and during the break you guys can create
your usernames and passwords
if everyone back.
Well, we're going to create that username
and password later on.
Did I miss anything?
I don't know.
What about when did you left
and when you joined back?
It depends.
If you left after 15 years, the class
started.
You have missed a lot and
our internet went down.
Internet
shut down when we tried to sign in.
When did you guys
when did your Internet went down?
Mohamud Arwa
A month ago.
A moment ago.
They told me not to tell
you guys don't miss anything.
That's
new. Guys, remember writing this query
just like
this.
Okay, So can you guys
now write a query
the man
not believe me,
you don't need anything to it now.
No cake, no cookies,
nothing. Please, please.
Beyond night.
It's already too much.
I'm just joking. Please do it. Provided.
Thank you.
And you, madam.
You didn't see them online pictures.
He's already very healthy.
All right, guys.
So can you guys abide?
Yes. Aisha.
So you see those?
They already know everything.
What is going on in their families,
in their lives the dead, even They don't.
It does not matter
if they are classmates, colleagues.
They have all the information
from each of the.
Okay,
No, no, we pay attention.
But it is very fast communication.
All right, guys,
can you write take
you read to only fetch the employers
whose last name is Gem.
Where is Alex? Alex.
Now you will see only one gem.
And you guys that I take every
If I only want to see one,
I am meeting as we are speaking
of all to.
I cannot stop it.
I believe my baby girl.
It's good is good. Getting being hungry.
I think it's. It's super simple. Is it?
This song?
You'll need to
select all
from person we had last
name is equal to them.
Did we go through the Oracle worksheet
into that one down?
No moment.
We will do that, including giving.
So if the column contains
the text based that, that
and as part of the request of Alex,
we want to see only one damn
we can use the
where clause
and we need to specify the last name
equal to single course best practice
and we need that.
What do you think if I put uppercase them,
will it work?
Well, it works.
Why it works dies because obscurely is
keys in in sensitive.
But remember
this uppercase thing.
It will only work on my school database.
It will not one.
It will not work on Oracle. One.
So what?
What should be the best practice?
Yes. Inside this single course,
it is clear
some databases are sensitive,
some are not.
So as a best practice, what should we do?
We should not try to have
some fun
inside of the double course because
you guys might be using
Oracle on your jobs
and then you will blame me.
Is there anything that is sensitive. Yes.
The text inside the course is
this case is sensitive
for some of the databases,
but not all of them.
Okay. Alexa, are you happy now?
Oh, we'll still see a lot of them.
Alex wanted only one.
Alexa, can you modify this query
to get only one gem?
Then you guys tell me how to write.
Modify this clearly to get only one.
Yeah.
Distinct.
Are you guys sure?
Take out the star
name.
Just add this thing
I am using stored in here.
Will it work?
The distinct
Those who are saying distinct.
I am using a start in here.
Will it work?
Because why? Why? It will not work?
Because if
I could be complete role.
It is not unique.
This role is different
from this one, right?
It will not work.
So it depends how many columns
you are selecting in your select clause.
If as if you are selecting 15 rows
and if we combine the data
of 3015 columns, and if you combine
the data from 15 columns
and then that that is not unique,
then the string will not do anything.
All the
can you guys
write a query?
It is easy.
Is it easy?
Database.
Then you guys write a few to fetch
all the persons are who have
age as greater than 23.
All the data from this table for
for which the age is greater than 23.
Anyways, right click on that.
Then I run a line 19 please.
Yes, obviously you can run now.
Why you are asking.
You can run anything on your computer.
Is this okay
here?
If yes, maybe your result is good
with line 19.
You are working just with.
Yes, the complete line 19 like this.
Now. Like this complete.
Yes. So
this is the output.
While all you do
it is just because of how my will work.
When you displays the results,
it will always display and null rule.
No matter what you do write.
It is just how display
of the is.
So if we want to get the battle,
if we want to get the persons
who are older than 23.
We tried to
pass their age
is greater than 23 is.
And what if I want to get all
the employees who have aged less than 25
line 105?
You live in Dubai?
Oh, yes.
As part of this database.
Right. Can you write it?
You need to find all the employees
who have aged less than
25. This
right?
So same as Java.
Greater than less than
what they've
less than or equal to 25.
Can you guys guess this index less than or
equal to 25.
So I got 25 and all the results,
by the way, should be ages.
I am not getting greater than 23. Why?
And I will make sure
you are executing the acuity
that is on line 20 that you read like
I am selecting and you
then execute it.
And guess if you still get wrong
results, is everyone getting the results
as of your expectations?
Okay.
Thank you.
Great.
Again, you guys write acuity
for to get all the records cards for
which age is not equal to country 308
you do not equal to 25 mark
all the ages, but not 25.
Then we use a couple
where statements are Alexa.
I will teach you how to do that, guys. But
you see,
that mirror
has written a different syntax.
Can you guys provide that syntax as well
and confirm it backwards?
I mean, has used this syntax?
Yes, we can select
only those who live in Istanbul
and that also works.
So for specifying and not equal to
we can use two symbols this
greater than less than combined.
And this one.
So some of the databases,
they might not spell this one.
So you guys can try this one.
Some of the ways they might support
this one and then don't support this one
and no, we cannot use it in Java.
In Java is standard,
as is also standard,
but which companies following it 100%
depends on that company
break time?
No hard.
But we had a break on 1210 so it's 121
not intending let's have it after minutes.
Are you guys tired?
Need a break?
I want you to make the. Oh, my God.
No one at home to make tea.
No girlfriend, no wife.
At least my girlfriend knows
how to make tea.
He agreed
she will make me tea, but nothing else.
No, no, no, no.
Court Chai, I want more.
Come. It's
okay.
Can you guys write a
query to fetch the first name
and the last name
of all the emails? Yes.
He also makes me buy bread.
Most of all, the cake is gone.
Guys.
I want all the first names.
Last names for all the meals.
All the first names and the last names.
All for all the males.
So select
first name on the
last names from
Son where
the gender is.
Is there
anyone who was unable to write this query?
Is there anyone who was unable
to write this query? No.
All good.
You guys love the you guys are
loving school.
All easy peasy. Woodward.
So first name, last name of all.
You guys can also display the agenda
just to
verify being for
big boys and big building.
Now. Okay, so all
okay, you guys are champions.
All right, electronic lecture
learn next, right?
Give me that check
if you guys can do the homework or not.
You guys already know select from
use commands.
Two separate columns
start to get everything.
Oh, yes.
We were ready for the task.
Okay, Well, do you anticipate
there are a lot of jackpot
come back or both?
Okay, so how about remove
first and gender on the line?
Foster gender on the line.
Read it in few classes.
It will get complicated here.
Not as good.
I think a school is all easy
because I am taking it with lawmakers.
Even if it is hard, it will become easy.
Right?
They have to
do teaching
APIs law.
If I teach everything,
how would you guys know if I am very,
very good at teaching, right?
You guys will say, Oh,
so there was just average
queen was not will that teaching
week already.
No you'll see no.
Okay stop recording
We will have a session of 52 minutes
at the of the class and confessed It's
all right.
As we have
data types in and in Java
we also have data types in school
so we have integers
to store the whole numbers.
Are you still in math? No,
I just got back.
I told you I will be back from Mars on
Sunday.
Right. This is Sunday. I just landed.
Yes. Yes.
We also have the decimal data types.
But you guys don't need to learn because
you guys
will not be creating these tables.
You only you will only be fetching
exploding the that those DBS that
I told you or developers or architects,
they will create big tables.
They will desire to be data types
and all that.
But you guys should know
they do
they do bring girlfriend from Mars.
I didn't they occurred to Mars.
She was already here on the left.
So you guys don't
want me to be happy somewhere
in this galaxy, in this universe.
Want to talk with everywhere? This
and so this lot,
that data type, it's a little different.
If we you we can use this locked
that same as string.
We can put numbers,
special characters, everything.
But the only difference
is that instead of string database
guys, they call it what stuff.
And we can also define the length in here.
Let's say we want to have a locked out of
that can only store
15 letters, 20 letters, 30, 45.
It is up to us in strings.
There is no limit.
We can store up to billions of characters
but water inside the blackboard
so we can specify
how many characters want to allow
and when we will be inserting the data
inside the table.
And if, let's say we say only ten in here,
then only ten
will be allowed by insertion.
And then we have this data that
I will show you how to write it
using the data type
column in database
table can only accept the one that I type
is very strict rule, obviously.
Why? Why should I write it in
two zero?
One is easier.
Silva What do you mean by this emoji?
I think 90% of the time
you always post this emoji
and in the inferential fact
we have
the data is killing me.
You think you should then use a different
emoji if something is killing you?
I am kind of confused.
You always use this.
It's in the Yes, it is your favorite,
but please don't confuse us.
Who would have
that name Dot in the evening?
So this is the distinct keyword
that you guys use.
Already learned.
All you guys are already
done with the first class
where column and then
comparison operator can get to
then less than equal
to 90 Puerto
task And then last
you see you guys how easy is the skill
that you guys have already already done
with plus one
No no no we are not done for coding.
We will learn in another class
comparison.
Operators are used to compare objects.
Conditions
could be numeric based or character
for the character based.
We use course
for numeric miss, we just specify
it is just like that
character based like bar chart
or data data type.
We must use single course of key
logical of all in this class is very easy.
We can, I think, cover three classes to do
functions in a skill.
Yes, it is also very similar. This would
do no class to that?
No, I have another class for Tuesday
as well.
Here, please put the emergency level.
Please put that in. Good enough.
Let's cover all the course.
Oh, I know you guys.
You guys are so much a grown up.
You guys are learning so quickly.
I didn't realize that. Oh,
let's learn the easy things. So.
And then we will objects
select all.
So if we have to specify multiple
conditions, you see how easy that skill.
If I am teaching it,
we can see from
Sebastian.
Please,
with all why you made the 80 year old
man make it ten year old.
15 year old had
it looks like they have been coding
without water in the food for
like one month. It's
a year.
And so if we have to
specify multiple conditions,
let's say
if I only want the records
for which the age is greater than 23
and age is less than
28 eight, oh,
we need to do we're closer to like,
let's look for them all.
Uppercase
this one as well.
So can you guys guess the output
don't scare him.
Although if
yes, then we thank you.
So between 23
and 28 right?
Yeah.
Only the
new guys.
We are the same readers.
So this is how we specify
multiple conditions.
Now guys write a few read to
to create all the records
for which city is in New York
and age is 23.
I should see only those records
for which city is New York
and under age is 23 and degree for that
city is in New
York and age is 23.
But by the way, we use the
and the keyword.
If we have to write the under condition.
It is different from Java
select
the divide.
Also exit
all this period to check the results.
So where ID is
equal to 23 and
60 is equal to
New York
and this
region? Yep.
Do you guys all get the same results?
Is there anyone who is confused
or voting festival?
Is hard or getting any issues,
any feedback, suggestion
or looks good of a
Then guys write one more query.
Just in which
select
only those employed for which MP I.D.
is 120.
Gender is a male and the last name is Dem
person in stable name. Yes.
Get a personally stable name
guys.
Last name is jam
gen that is male and employee I.D.
is 120.
Last name is
equal,
gender is new
and the
and the I.D. is
MJ and three legs and yes.
Do you guys get the same results?
Most of the
so this is how we combine
multiple conditions
with the help of an operator
is it clear. Right.
We can use the order condition as well.
For example, can you guys first do that
for the records for which are ages
23 or
employ RTD is
120, age
is 23 or employed is 120.
So if one of the conditions is fulfilled,
I should say that record
you select
all strong
for some
where
it is 23 or
medium we already use,
we want to do right.
This is our with all conditions.
So you will see all the rec or adverse
for which I the age is 23
or employ ID is 120.
Well well why do I see 150 guys?
Am I getting the correct result
so they get 150
for the employed.
Yes. Why?
Because it is 23. Right.
So even if one condition
met, we will see that contact.
Okay, it looks next.
Let's write that query
in which let's combine or
and the condition right.
So give me the records for which
gender is female and 23
or MP ID 100
gender is female, F
and age is 23 or
MP Ione is 120
Gender is being in L
and age is printed
three or MP ID is one
2013 rules.
Right.
So let's test
if we are getting the proper document.
Gender is
male ID is 23 MP it is one quantity
then that is female and 23.
So this condition is one,
so we don't need to hear about
the other one.
All looks guys.
So logic works in here
either this condition is true
combined as a whole or this condition.
So if you want to be more specific,
if you are not sure
you can use these
brackets as the number.
If let's say you are
if something is confusing you,
you can use the parentheses as well.
Yeah.
To prioritize things.
This is a good
answer to your question.
Number
because it changes the result
and I can tweak it
and any way I want is use parentheses
if you want to tweak it.
How to gender Only if
you don't want the other conditions.
And it's
only gender. If
then remove the other conditions.
So like this.
So only now you will only see that if
only the ladies
only gender different
and age
so f and 23 age or D,
but always for gender.
Oh, you don't want to see the.
So if you execute this beauty
you get some males this one right.
You don't want those. Yes.
There are their condition in here as well.
This is one of the solution
you can modify, be good in any way
and and put that condition in here.
That's
only ladies not interested in men.
No. Choose
bringing those 120
is both of the only only female.
Or you can modify it
excluding other way as well.
They are not the same assignment.
What is the difference between select
all from persons with gender F and age 20
or MP B?
It should be the same,
but it is not assignment.
Why should we do same in the above duty?
You are specifying
employer ID in the below query you are.
You are not specifying ID.
So this is how it works.
Guys, let me explain to you.
I hope it will get better.
So what skill will do?
It will pick all the rules one by one.
So it will pick this first rule.
It will check.
Okay, so I forgot to specify it again.
The ref does it.
Does it have gender f the first rule? No
it does not have the gender.
If that means even if one condition
is not correct, that means
we don't to check it.
The other condition will save it.
Save mpi d12.
Does it have we want?
No, it will exclude this rule
from the desired reserve set.
Then it will pick the next rule.
It will again check.
Does that rule qualify all the conditions?
If it qualifies, all the conditions
that rule will be included in your output.
If not that, that will be ignored as well.
One by one.
These conditions will be applied
on all the rules
and only those rules which qualified
the conditions will be returned
in here, female
and age 23,
or if there are no brackets in my acuity.
So does the automatic. And then
then the priority is given to end
and then we apply the order.
If you want to ask this,
as we have the rules in MED,
we follow the DBM or whatever
that is called.
The multiplication happens
first multiplication and division,
then are plus and minus.
So same is here, but
I don't want you to go into those details
and confuse yourself if you are always,
always use these parentheses and priority
will be given to that condition.
If you want to prioritize
something, always use parentheses.
Okay. Forget about how it works.
Are all rules
okay.
It seemed like I forgot to list us a lot.
It does not want we want to go break or.
You guys need to break.
Well, I'm not tired.
I don't know why you guys get tired.
You guys know I was traveling all day.
I was super,
super tired before your class.
But when I started the class, I am not
tired anymore.
But we need to understand logic.
So, like math, ESL, X?
Yes, guys.
Okay, guys, let's have a break.
And after the break, please
make be accounts on on Google
so that you guys know
what are the things that
might not work on other databases
15 minutes are enough guys.
Okay, let's
let let's have five more minutes.
So those who don't know,
because some for some of you,
the Internet was down.
You guys have to go to Oracle live.
You guys have type Oracle live on Google,
then click on the first link.
No harm, not on Google, on Oracle life,
and then
click in here and click on Ask about.
It will ask you for the username.
You have to sign up first
if you don't have the username
if you guys already have,
you guys don't need to do anything.
Enjoy your break.
The others who do not remember username
or don't have it, please create
new username.
We will be using this after the break.
All good.
You When are you coming back?
At 205
and will be notified
once you are looking good.
Can we go on break or is there
someone who is having
any issues? Yes.
Break till 205 so that all of you
can make those accounts.
Yeah.
If strong enough.
Do you guys want to turn
a Yes?
Alexia, look, look.
All advice is backed by tools zero five
And remind me about problem.
Have you guys made
the account on
Oracle website?
Okay, so the schema for this website.
So I want to know
how many tables are there?
What kind of columns those tables have?
Can you guys tell me on
which links should I click from here?
The schema one. Right.
So if I take on schema,
right.
So there
are many different schema in here,
but we will be working with this
at Java Human Resource.
So we have the ADD
underscore job underscore history table
table departments, Table employs tables
so you guys can find out
about all the tables from here.
Right.
And so ask you all my skill we right
the use
this statement in Oracle
we just tried
at Java DOT
employs employs or employs
yes employs
and if we execute
by clicking on this this one.
So before every table
you have write at charter dot
and choose how we specify
which schema we want to use.
Do you guys see this data in here?
Okay, so now think about this guide
and tell me if
I see
last name
is equal to double course.
And if I say Stephen
in here, will I get any results?
It looks much cleaner.
I will get an error.
Okay.
If I try to use
double, of course, in
Oracle.
Sorry I'm missing. We are close as well.
Let me repeat it
to double quotes in here.
So it says invalid identifier.
But if I use a single course
this time the query is correct.
But I get no data. Why?
Because inside.
Because Oracle database is case sensitive,
so I must write it in the proper case
if I want to get that back
was the first step,
but a lot lower case for this one
creature.
Okay.
Oh, the first name right
was not the last name.
So I get the results
if I change it to all uppercase
and if I execute security
again, you know that.
All right, So for the Oracle database,
the things inside the double course,
they are case sensitive,
but the column names
the square and everything.
They are case insensitive.
How do you connect your database
to Oracle?
It is already connected in here.
Select we a capital.
So as a best practice,
when you write something
inside the boards,
make sure you specify the proper case.
Also, don't use double course because on
some of the database is double
quotes are not supported.
You see if check it on the my school
and if I change it
to double course, I still get the reverse
double code single course don't matter on
my sequel activities.
But for the Oracle one, if I use
double
course, I will get an ask.
Okay.
So as a best practice, yes, sometimes
things might work on their database,
but we should always try to follow
the best practice.
So best practice is your course
and inside the course
to specify the proper case.
But there is no exception
to integrate the add a different
databases,
give you different errors, you know,
so it will not be helpful
even if some of the databases be true.
The error will
all good guys.
How can you add common skill on Oracle?
But on Oracle, the command, the hash is
a hash also does not work for comments.
We have to use these underscores.
So I will try to teach you both things
which might work on school
or other databases.
But at the same time
I will also teach you the best practice.
Okay, so that you guys don't get confused
if your company uses
a different backup base.
So try both the things I told you about.
Be not equal to symbol using those angle
brackets and not equal to sign.
So some of the databases,
they might support both of them.
Some of them
they might export only one of them.
That's
why we have multiple things in here.
Well,
let me check what is next.
Okay.
So next is a new clause
that is called order by clause.
Mine shows
Oracle database is a little trickier. One
This is sure to be capital Mohammed
the se of Stephen should be capital
and that's why you see all our data.
All right.
So what is this order by clause?
So I told you guys that
when we fetch the data, when we stored
that database,
there is no guarantee of order.
Okay?
So if there is no guarantee
and I want the specific order,
how can I do that?
So let's say I want all the names
in ascending order.
So I will say
select all from
our sun
and order this data by
first name. Oops.
So now you guys will notice that
all the data this time has been sorted
in ascending order
by this first name.
Do you guys get the same results
sorted Data? Yes.
No, we have been numeric order as well,
so by default the order
by clause will solve the data
in ascending order.
But let's see
if you want it in a descending order.
You can also specify that
by writing this DC
So now you will see
all the data has been sorted
in descending order order
and you guys can
also do this.
You guys can start
by more than one column.
So now what will happen?
Sorry, what is descending
order means no order.
Descending order.
Let's say if ascending is one,
two, three, four, five,
six, descending will be six, five, four,
three, two, one.
Reverse of ascending.
It does not mean non,
it means opposite of descending.
It's the other way
around, lower to higher.
In case of numbers
it is ascending higher to lower.
If it is descending, four numbers.
So when we put two columns
now, what will happen if?
We have the same value for the
first column.
Let me check to give you ample
if we have one.
You guys don't need to follow this one.
Even if you try,
you will not be able to do that.
I am sorry.
I forgot what is descending for.
Can you guys tell now
what is descending for?
Let me make it.
We have to set and flag
went to the roof with the
ascending coming down from
the roof is descending. Yes.
And if you still don't understand,
you can try jumping from doodle, right.
You know,
then you will definitely understand
and feel it. Yes.
Well, so
of the.
I'm just kidding.
Please don't try it at your home.
But you might learn it
in heavens.
Well, what is ascending?
And this actually is
you, not you.
That is
for the first name.
I should change the last
mind.
You see next, what happens
when you have all the permissions
for ascending order or and the
many cities enjoying their school?
I wish we have the same lessons
in the university,
but there may be a contradiction there.
When you jump, you expect to descend,
but you may ascend to have.
Yes, here you are right.
It's relative
rule.
Who ask about descending.
Is it clear
or you want me to further explain
it? No.
Now let it clear like this. Descending.
And what is descending?
It's clear.
I just stepped out for a minute.
So, guys, when we specify
multiple columns in order by clause.
So what you will do,
the first priority will be given
to the first column that we specify.
So all the data will first be sorted
based on the first names.
But if the first name is same,
then the second priority is given
to the last name you see.
In the last name we see jam first
and then after that.
So this is how we can use multiple columns
and so fast that I will be sorted
based on first column.
If the first column duplicate
that are same data.
So skill cannot decide which Sara
it should put first, then
it will decide to based on the last name.
Because this is the second column,
we can specify three columns
for any number of columns.
Then the skill will give the better.
The first column,
second and third, fourth.
And like this.
Is it clear, guys, how specifying
multiple columns
work?
Let me check if we can do this.
Maybe.
Yes, we can also do this now.
The data is first
started in ascending order
for the first name
and in descending order for the last name
you see.
So Zoom.
It should be on the Serbian.
But now it is on the first.
Is it funny to ask the question?
The time I stepped out,
you wrote that line.
That's why I asked for the.
No, no, no, no.
It's completely
because someone already
asked the same question.
So first I explained.
Then someone asked the question.
Then you repeated that question.
So I thought, you guys are not getting it.
I didn't know you were out for a minute.
That's why everyone was explaining it
in so much depth.
No, no, it's never funny.
Even if you guys think the questions
are dumb, you guys can still ask.
And it's always don't don't mind my jokes
for everyone else do exist just so that
we can have some humor as well.
Otherwise classes will be so dry.
You guys will
feel every minute of it, right?
I know.
I have my lectures.
Are just one hour and 30 minutes
and literally I can feel a single minute
of my leg today.
It's like this is my profession
that is teaching
nothing.
Makes sense.
Okay, so guys,
you see why this time when we had
both taught us in the first name
why the exam was
and Jan was second,
we that have on some classes
now you guys know how to avoid that
so we can start on ascending order
based on one column
and descending order on the column.
But you guys will not be needing it in the
this much depth.
So it's okay.
Just if you don't understand us.
All right, can you guys now?
Okay, so I want the
data from this table
so that the smaller I.B.
is first,
and then I have the great variety.
So I don't want this
that nine is after 19.
Can you guys write the query to do that
so that ideas are in
an increasing order?
What did I do this time?
Again, think
Can you guys write acuity
so that all the data is in increasing
order of the ideas?
Not really 109 goals before 11
really
select all from
one wrong person
order by already
just does not work
so well.
Can you guys
tell me the reason why it is not working?
Any guesses
in this
and being
four leading zeros needed in?
I'd be.
Yes I am on.
You are close, but not quite.
There you didn't put order
because you said it is randomly generated.
The data
type for the i.t is water.
It is not an automatic.
So that's why in water
technically ten
is smaller than 105 and 106.
So don't get confused guys.
If you are starting
and this thing is not working,
it might be working, but it is working
with respect to watch our data type.
Okay.
So that's why it can happen sometime
and usually it will happen
when the idea is usually ideas, they are
large, are based.
The negative for the it is, it is larger.
It's not numeric usually.
So you guys get into this issue.
I am sorry.
Just make sure two lines 38 and 3938
and you don't need to worry.
It is just a flag that we need to set
before we modified
the data in a database
for security purposes.
I asked you all by default or does not
let you delete or update the data.
By default it will ask you to foster,
set the proper flags
and then it will allow you,
even if you have the Edwyn permission.
So I have just set the value of that flag
so that I can easily get to.
The second one is
data should be
sorted based on this idea,
but it was not working.
So I am just explaining the reason
that in actual
the ID is a not in numeric column
and if you guys
want to check this, so
in here you are,
you guys will see the ID is var char
and I am allowing 100 characters in here
and it is a primary key.
So you can go inside that table
and you can check the info.
Okay.
So don't, don't worry if sometimes
the order by clause is not working,
it might be because the die is darker.
But so now tell me the edge is in beta 11.
Will it work on edge?
Okay, let's try it on the edge.
Quick question of the topic.
Do we have any preview tomorrow?
Tomorrow?
Tomorrow is Monday?
I don't think so.
You have a review related to school,
but I am not sure about your project
or something like that.
Do you guys see all the data
sorted with respect to it this time?
No errors. Everything looks good.
So yeah.
So this, this, this was one thing
that might waste
your RS
and might force to scratch your head.
I will keep on telling these things.
This is what I have learned
from experience.
So I eventually did that
for the last batch.
Okay, so.
So you now know how to sort the data
based on a specified column.
So why it didn't work with ID?
Because the data type of I.D.
is var job
in strings.
Sorting happens a different player, then
in pneumatic data.
So as part of the sorting
based on character
based data, yes.
Sorry,
I googled select all from persons order
by convert ID decimal number.
Okay,
let's try to do that.
It might work assignment.
Have you tried it?
I never it.
Does it work
that create perfect.
Okay.
We have the solution for this as well
so converting
I think this this convert function
is converting this ID to decimal numbers
and then we are applying the order
by clause.
Yeah.
So if you still to sort.
As nomadic sorting happens,
you can convert that
from desktop type to decimal
and then can apply the order by clause.
It's a good addition.
Let me put a comment in here.
Converts the dark part type
to a different desktop
and then apply the
sorting.
Yeah, perfect.
So now we can also sort of be
character based things
by converting them to numeric.
So if let's say for example,
if your ideas there
contain any letters,
I think in those cases it will work fine.
But we might face some issues
if we have number plus characters.
I am sure I was going to be
just that eventually anyway.
No, I didn't know about this.
Converting Simon.
I don't know everything about everything.
I don't.
I didn't needed that actually.
So yes, let me
let me try this.
But at least it works.
If we don't have characters,
we're still very good
additions, right?
Is equal to
then here
we are, six
of your next
at least we don't get any errors
and I think still eight
is better than having nothing.
You are home. Remember that?
Can we go home ugly
because we are doing so good?
Uh, no,
because started skirting the next link.
Let me check how much we have to
cover. You know?
Thank you, Simon, for the submission
of these
order by column name,
ascending or descending
right to salt detector.
Used to sort of be reserved
by a specific column, please.
And on time.
If it does not feel like it,
we are already finished.
Class one.
It's not working.
When I did the update person so tired.
Yes or no?
Because I have not given you the access
to update things
in that database.
Oh, that class was supposed
to be taught on a week day,
but we had having a weekend class
electrical it at least two classes
and then maybe we can go if we can do that
used to sort the readers
by a specific column,
last clause section.
This lecture.
It means that it should be the last thing
if you ask to start ascending
and descending,
ascending by default,
or we can specify descending
or here is one what
your answer for the null values.
So a lot of the times you guys will be
having these null values in your data.
Can we learn what we need to learn?
Yes, that's what we are doing.
Alex, did I teach you something extra?
I don't know why
I asked you this question, Alex. Why?
Why you ask why you ask that?
I mean, finished when we pass all in full
what we need.
Yes, I not.
I'm not listening to these ladies
who want to finish up
this.
Don't worry.
It's not about ladies.
Even if men that will be asking this,
I will not be doing that.
I'm just kidding.
Nice.
Actually, this class was
supposed to be taught on a big day,
but this is a weekend class.
That's why we are learning.
That's why we are coding extra stuff.
I am sure these ladies will
one day will kill me
because I don't know why
he. Ladies, please.
Sorry. Special sorry for the ladies.
They have very big heart.
You know they don't mind.
All right, guys.
So can you guys affect the data
for which this city is null
nights?
Can you write acuity to fetch the data
for which we have city
as null.
NULL is equal to nine for null, null
is something else.
Nine for else you see
for example for 30 for this road ten.
I have this empty data
and I have this null data null and empty.
There are two different things in school.
So Hasim has pride discovery
for me.
Copy this, don't you guys?
Right. Discovery to get this.
It is where the values null.
Did it work?
It's not working right.
So why it is not working?
Try fight the
cities We are City is empty
Try to check if that works.
Is line 44 works for you know
it also does not work for
in this one.
Sorting. For sorting.
Yes, for sorting.
It works.
So there are multiple values.
Guys. Observe.
I have a zero. Yes.
Empty is not normal
so I have null zero and empty.
So these are three different things.
Zero does not mean empty.
Does not mean null. NULL is null.
Empty is empty. Zero zero.
So can you guys fetch the city
for which the city is empty?
Try something like this.
Let's.
Let's check if it works.
So this works for empty.
If the city is empty and if we put force
and if we don't
put anything inside it for empty,
we are able to set it.
Next.
Let's try to do zero.
Because cities, they are
watertight, character based.
Right?
So should I put a zero like this
or inside the double code?
If I put a zero like this, I again
don't get to the proper results,
which means so,
which means it's a very,
very good practice to use course
when that type is what job
and not use because when it is
numeric based, let's let's check
if it works with double code.
This time it works.
So this works.
This works.
But why does not the null work?
Because NULL is a special type in school
and it has a special operator.
If you want to avoid it,
you have to say is
null the equal to sign
will not work for us.
It's a special state in database
and it is treated specially in school.
So that's why we have a separate operator
for this time.
It will work not it is not a string.
It's a separate special data type.
That does not mean empty.
That does not mean zero.
It's null means null. Okay.
It works differently.
So be careful
when you are trying to fight.
Two null values we have to use is null
and if you want the data that is not null,
then should say is not null.
Instead of saying that
not equal to null or equal to null,
it will not work.
No zero is different.
Empty is different.
NULL is different.
Well, no, no.
Even putting it inside a double course,
I don't think so.
It will work the proper best practice that
will work on all the databases is using.
This is operator is and is not.
When you
want to avoid the null in the results, act
use is not null
when you want to have null use.
Isn't that now execute this for you
these guys
and tell me
if you get your expected results.
Let me repeat it again.
In school, 90% of the times
you guys will not get any error,
but you will get wrong with data.
So it's very, very different than Java.
You should always double check your delta.
For example, if you have written a query,
always double your delta
if you are getting the expected results
of not because school 90% of the time
it will not throw you an error,
it will just return you the wrong data.
And if you don't cross-check it,
you might be reporting bad results.
Getting at that error is better to see
what is wrong.
Yes, but because I am not different
databases are defined
by different companies.
Some of them they will give you an error,
but not all of them.
You cannot guarantee
that you will always get an.
Edit It depends on the company
which is implementing that well,
which is building their database.
So it's on
us to use the best practice,
unfortunately.
Yes, you are right.
We should definitely get an error
and XYZ.
Does it work
Now you guys get all the expected results
when you use this way.
49 is not getting the right results.
You are getting some null values passing.
We are not relevant. 50 column.
I don't see any.
Do you get any null values in this column
even if you put is not null.
Empty is equal to 46.
You mean
for this last one?
It will always be null.
It is null for everything.
This is how it is
how your workbench displays the data.
It's not an edit operation
or anything like that.
It's because of my skill workbench
4647 working. Yes.
Alex, did you try
try them and let me know
they don't work
properly.
What is magenta,
if I remember, is also tools, a skill or
something like that.
I know about Magneto,
that character in X-Men movie.
I don't know about the string
that you have typed in years or one
word result.
We will see.
You should see and pay for this one.
You should see zero for this one.
The City of zero 49.
Why get empty City
Because empty and annul.
They are two different things.
Empty is not the same as null housing.
Therefore
that's
what I wanted to explicitly tell you.
That's why I especially inserted
all types of the time.
This column
can you in 46 gaps
on zero.
I see null in here.
You see in the null data, I don't see it.
Are you using the course
using zero in charge?
Because now listen all empty is empty.
Zero zero once again must at least in this
case, yes, it can be very confusing.
Sometimes
with some of these things.
They took me, believe me,
they took me days to understand why
that thing is working this
with a lot of research and all that.
Because when you don't know,
you just keep on
scratching your head
for the answers.
Oh, Elena, I told you
many times this last row, it is null.
It is just how your coolest
software ever developed by humanity.
That is called my skill workbench.
The just words and null rule
at the end of need to resolve
that is because is equal work.
When you're good,
is it telling you the correct phrases
what's
known as
the argumentative type?
Okay,
so this is about the null null operator.
Not possible to test the null values
with operator
equal to or not equal to UTC.
We use
is the null operator selects only be rows.
We are specific of value is in now.
This is your task.
Okay you guys already
we have already done this
and or operator this.
Not between and in operator.
Let me tell you what Oracle
so I'm not
there is a there is one more where
to specify the not conditions
but again it is not the best practice so
don't use it too much.
But if I execute this query,
I will be getting all the results
for which the age is 23.
I can also use this
not in front of any column
to reverse condition.
Yeah, but it might not work
on all the databases.
Okay.
You can use it on the supported ones
so it will not.
It will reverse that.
I don't think so. You guys should worry.
Just have that in mind
that this is also possible.
This is also a syntax.
Otherwise always try to use this operator
because you guys
are more familiar with this
and it
will be easy for you to build a logic
using this.
Operator Right. Same Rhythms.
But it's also possible
with this, not operator
Okay, then the next is between again
between is same as the end operator.
So if I write
and again between my
do not work on all of the database is
actually looking that article without
between.
So let's say we have this query,
we are fetching only those results
where edge is
oops,
the edge is greater than 23
or greater than to quantity or less
45, and it is less than equal to
maybe 20
plus.
Okay, so we get 28, 25, 25 right now
let's try
new same.
So for the north country 325
for 28.
So again we got the same results.
So this between
is actually alternate of this one.
So whichever you guys find easier,
you can use both of them
and there is no difference
in terms of performance or anything. Yes.
Between is inclusive
25 and
28 will be included in the disaster.
That's why I added this greater than equal
to or less than equal.
So this is the alternate thing.
So you guys also don't
need to memorize this and just have that
in mind that this thing exists
and of this thing can be written
in terms of this thing
because some most of the time
you guys might be reading the queries
written by others.
So you must know what kind of things
can be written, in which other ways
all looks good guys, Or is it exactly that
it has confused you?
Okay.
And then just a different syntax.
This interpreter.
It is also a an alternate to this thing.
So let's say, for example,
if you are writing this security
persons we are age
is equal to 25
or age is equal to 28
or age is equal to 23.
So if you have multiple or conditions
on this same column, same column,
then instead of writing this or again
and again,
you guys can use the interpreter age 18
and then 2335 I get it like this.
So it's just a shorter way
to avoid writing longer duties.
So multiple are conditions age
23 or eight, age 28 or age 25.
Instead of specifying
these three conditions in again
and again with the auto operator,
if the conditions belong
to the same column, remember same column.
If this column is different than this,
then we cannot apply the information.
Then instead of writing it again
and again, try to age in
and then specify the conditions. Yeah,
on of mean I
and we
addressed this.
So these three, they are all possible
with the limitations,
but they also exist.
Some of the databases might support them.
So and the operator is same as in Java
where you specify
multiple conditions
or is same as we specify or in condition.
Notice is again,
same to reverse this condition
in operator fix,
multiple options from the same column
allows you to specify multiple values.
A weird clause.
It is a shorthand or B for operator.
Okay so use in if you are writing
multiple times between is a
alternate of greater
than and less than sign.
So test whether the value falls
within a range of given boundaries
between all.
You guys are also
done with the second class.
And that means
in next 30 minutes we can cover
maybe it is
third class or
let me do it.
Maybe in next 30 minutes
we can cover the next class. As a
reaction from Batch 11. It's
okay.
We are not covering the third class.
You are also using that.
Let's finish all of the classes.
It's easy to write this.
Is anyone confused or thinks that
I am messing with you?
It's clear. Simple example.
Simple.
So we can use between with work job.
If we sort of did that to the mirror,
you have not used it with the large data.
Can you please write?
I have only used it with numeric data.
I don't think so.
We will be getting good reasons for
then.
You open my school.
Okay.
Let me just teach you this last thing
and then you guys can have some
rest. Um,
and so this last thing is,
you guys already know it, or do you guys
all know everything already?
What?
Vanessa
You guys remember the string functions
starts with and the way
the contains function
is that there is nothing, right?
You are smart.
That's why
everything gives you the right.
Does not have to do anything with me
Genesis.
So you guys remember the stocks
with the function
in from Java Wood to No,
we are not baby boys and girls anymore.
Starts with No, no,
not not from selenium, from Java. No.
So let's say I want all the names
that start with a letter E
so what I can do I can say E
and then percent de sign.
It's the same as
starts with
function from Java
you select all from person with plus name
between olina and full or by a first name.
That's great.
But how do you know if a smaller and a
Z are in Olina
and GL?
You are literally taking it?
Sebastian
The standing order.
Okay, I will do my research on it
and maybe we can discuss it tomorrow
in the next class.
Actually remind me about it
so that we can tell others as much.
So the guide to write this function
we use the operator like.
And then inside the double course, we
the letter and this person,
a symbol actually in here means that
the first letter should be a
and after that
there can be any number of letters
and there can be any letter.
The first letter should be air after this,
we can have anything.
So let's say if we want to have
and ends with the met function,
can you guys tell me how should I
modify this?
Let's say I want only those names
that end at letter
M, I will say
first we can have anything.
But the last letter should be M
okay, just put this
M after the person based sign.
So now first name.
If there are any first names
that end with M, Adam and Zam.
So we see both of these.
So what how it is working?
It is. We are saying
first there can be any number of letters,
any letters,
but the last letter should be m in here.
We are saying first letter should be air
last after air
we can have any number of letters,
any letter.
Why do we have this error?
It's because you are missing
the semicolon on the above line.
Most probably.
That's why you will see
an editor on Select.
If you put the semicolon on the above
line, you should not have that out of you.
See, I know that you want to be married.
It's already three and five
and he is not in a hurry to go back
home.
Well, yes, actually I have observed
this then is you are right.
In my last company
I have to see married ones.
They to come to office even on Sundays.
I didn't understand at that time why
these guys are coming or even on Sundays.
And they were late after the job
each day.
Ladies, please be solved with men.
And No, no. The reason was why I now know.
Because if they
stay on,
they have to do some work in the house.
I do Sometimes kids.
And can you guys tell me about it?
Contains a method
if there is
any name that contains M
So I am putting a person
de sign and before them and in person
put in person they say after.
Why so hard working woman They are married
and plus the overtime company
used to give them over time.
So why not make money?
And they happy and feel relaxed
instead of having that much pressure
from life
and wasting some overtime?
Right.
So now, person decided any number
of letters and characters before m
any number of letters and character
after them.
So all the first names which have the
letter M, we will see them in the output
they are they easy?
Are you guys confused?
Yes. Contains right.
I think that's that's it
for this underscore
let me teach you about this decimal.
So right now there is no restriction.
There can be any number letters
after the letter F in
uh, in the first name,
the active time.
Just five more minutes, Dennis.
But if you want to restrict
the number of letters.
So for example, this empty has only two.
Now, if I only want this
be names that contain two letters,
I I will say M
and after that I will say this underscore.
So now I ask you all will keep track
of the number of letters
in the first name as well.
If a first name has three letters,
I will not see that in my letter set.
I will only see those first names
which have two letters.
First should be M,
The second one can be anything.
Previously the first the restrict
it more restrictive first.
I was not restricting school
on the number of letters
that first name can have.
I said just make sure the first letter
is A After that, any number of letters,
any letters in here
I am saying the first name should be M.
The second name letter cannot be anything
and there should not
be more than two characters.
Guys get
the idea.
So let's say I only want to start
the names that have three letters.
So let's say I will say go.
Gee, you and then underscore.
Yes, like something
like regular expressions.
So I will
it will allow only search though,
which first names will be searched
this time.
How which first names
will be such this time?
How many characters they can have.
It makes
three First two letters should g and you.
And the last letter can be anything.
So we only see some more restriction.
But 90% of the time you guys will be able
to do that with this operator.
But you should still know.
And also, let's say
the first letter should be G made.
A letter can be anything,
and the last letter should be L,
and then I will again see
this good, right?
This one is more useful when you guys
will be dealing with the dates.
So for example, me
tell you about
that.
10% of the time always finds us.
If a yes.
So let's say you have
you are searching for the days.
Let's say
you are searching for the employers
whose of birth is on
in February and you guys are the query.
I only want
those employers who are in February
and it goes right to the weekly
and then you guys can leave.
I think we will be able to conclude
a skill by next Saturday.
If you guys give me this type of response
in the next classes as well,
I think you guys will be able to complete
a school in four classes, maybe five.
I didn't expect this
from you guys, to be honest,
in the given format like percentage
zero to
all. By the way,
this is also a trick
so that you guys don't run another.
So do you guys think
or we are very geniuses
like me?
Forget what I said.
Like B or B, after
all, is the date of birth
like M,
But anything can be before this
and anything can be after this.
And this in the middle thing should be
this right?
Why? I always forget this.
We are close.
Okay,
So I see all the employers
which are born in fab.
Can you guys write this
to using underscores
Also believe
this is the last thing trust me.
And then you guys can go
How many laughs
This is the final last final that last.
I don't trust you at this point.
The last last find.
The last.
So how many
letters are before this?
One, two, three, four.
Right before this?
We have four. One, two, three, four.
And after this, we have to write
like this.
Well,
Oops.
Looking to open a new one so that you guys
get some painting
again, Right?
That's it.
I think you already covered
three classes to them.
We know you want to learn
more than Mohammad.
You're he is your brother.
Then you're putting the first.
Okay, guys, think
compare the characters by using
like with percentage
or underscore perform divided bar.
Such person beside you means any character
or number of zeros or more times.
My husband.
Okay.
So you want to beat your husband
right? Then
please give me two more minutes.
Character looks for the presence
any on the character.
Same thing that I that I did or you guys.
I see a lot of couples
I don't know in back
then as well.
You guys can make your
Q a companies one day maybe
your wife will be director of finance
and husbands can be CEOs
or something like that.
You guys just let me give me 2 minutes
to share your home.
Look, you guys can leave.
I will put it on the course
and ask my schedule.
Please make sure you do this homework
before the next class.
And some of the homework
is for this Oracle one.
And some of the homework is for this
skill one.
I hope you will be able to know
which tables to use for these works.
Thank you.
Still, mystery of class is.
And how was the classes guided by the way
our two class today and
all our geared have some
of the most by.