No, I'll agree.
We were not refunding.
We are recording now.
Okay.
So today
we will learn how to
write duties and how to do that. Now
using Java in your Java products,
in your job application,
and how you can
how you can integrate this
with your framework as well.
So if we already installed it,
there is no need for 8.7.
Yes, it's fine.
If you guys do that, we will again
be wasting 14 years like we did yesterday.
So let's start from here.
Let me call it ask you and then move on.
So you connect to the database.
You guys know that we need the username,
the password,
the database, name, the host
default,
and all of the information in here.
Are we working on Main? Yes.
You guys can work on May not even.
We had filed in the testing.
Here's just a demo.
So it will not matter.
Which plugin
do we need to run the project?
No plugins. We don't need any plugin.
Just create a simple maven project
and add the minus equal connector.
That's it.
It's.
What did I miss?
Or you have all almost missed.
I tell you, I've already told all.
So this is how we combine this information
that we need to connect
with the backup base
to connect from Java applications.
So what do we do?
We build something called
database.
You are this database.
You are.
It first specifies
what kind of Java API we are
trying to use to connect to the database.
We will be working with the database.
Then we specify the type off
to get our base,
then the IP address of the server
on which the database is located.
Then the port number
and then the database name.
And then we feed this information
to a method
and that method will give us
the connection to the database.
Using that connection,
we can execute the curious
and we can fetch the
results from the database.
So for example, this is
one of the examples
of how we can build that
database on it.
So we can try to be seen here
because we are dealing with my sequel,
that garbage, so Pollen
and then my sequel database, then the IP,
this port and then syntax data,
and then my sequel
and then this class, this driver
manager class.
It has this method get connection
in which we boss this database.
You are all that we have built in here
so that this driver manager knows
from which base
we are trying to create the connection.
We passed the username
as this document
and the password and this, this,
this method will return us
and object of the connection interface.
So the connection class that we will
stored inside the connection interface.
The driver manager class acts
as an interface
between the user and the drivers.
Okay.
It is not like the interface
that we discussed and got.
It keeps
track of the drivers that are available
and handles
establishing a connection
between database and appropriate driver.
So let me show you
so that it makes more sense.
So let's, let's do a demo
so we could hear the main method in here.
Let's be clear.
Three variables.
Look, let's call it baby.
You are
so to build this DB, you are.
We need this information.
So go to your
sequel workbench and then
open up your
connection.
So click on Edit Connection.
And from here we can find the hostname.
Yes, you should be following me.
Are you guys following me?
Yes. You should be following
again.
Please follow me
as could do my.
Enjoying your pond
or the mail for a second? Yep.
So you should have this dependencies back
and inside of that
you should have this dependency.
Alexey,
all of you have you added this dependency
you follow me to here?
Is there anyone who is having issues
with adding these dependencies?
I do not
have a job in my skill connection.
I also do not have at my sequel connection
a moment.
You mean on the page
in here
you can use the same information
that I am showing and yet it's fine.
I forgot how to define a string.
If then I am very,
very happy to hear that.
Plus, please have some clapping for
that is for this great achievement.
Where did you get the dependency?
I got the dependency from?
I tell him from where
I got the dependency.
You said he didn't miss anything.
We got it from the Maven.
Good morning. Sorry I'm late. It's fine.
Okay, guys,
let me send you this information in here
so that you guys don't get to go on.
Good work.
Is there anyone who has not ended
this dependency
in your project?
You are serious today.
Yesterday was a complete disaster.
Complete, complete, complete disaster.
So those are those who don't have
this information on your government.
You guys can use the information
from here with me.
So the first thing we specify, the
type of API that we are using.
So right now
we are using B did, B, b, C API, right
then A colon, and then we specify
what kind of database we are working with.
So which database we are working
with. DICE
it's my S, right,
so we have to specify it
without specify like this in all lowercase
and then we specify another colon
and often back
to forward slashes.
And then we need
the IP of this server on which the
Yes. Dennis
So on which this database is located.
So I am copying this IP.
Those who do not have this IP are
investing in the like questions channel.
You guys can copy it from here.
Okay,
so then comes the IP part, right?
And if we check it, then comes
the board of the database. So
IP, then column and then reports.
So or most probably this information
you guys will be getting this information
from your DB
so you guys don't need to worry
about on your jobs.
So we are using 3003
as the code then for Slash
and then the name of the backup.
So I am copying it from here
and let me put it in here
and when you define it.
So let me also send you distribution
because a lot of you
will be making mistakes.
Building this being stones
use the steepest thing.
I don't know,
even if I have delivered correctly or not.
We will see
this.
So again, let me repeat the type of API
call database name colon
to forward slashes the IP of the database
on the IP of the server
on which the database is located,
then column and then the port number
and then in forward
slash and then the name of the database.
So you will be getting these baby
strings from your DB is on your job.
So you guys don't
need to even worry about.
I am You have just explained it
so that you guys can understand
how you can even if you don't get it.
The next thing we will be needing
a username, right?
Everyone needs a username and password
to connect to a database.
Can you show your physical connection
server?
No, it is located on us
and I don't have the credential
as currently for that.
The developers are managing it for syntax.
They do all of this
setup thing and everything.
We just tell them the requirements.
So then we will be needing the username
and we also need
to be password.
So what is the username goes
to the syntax,
underscore extreme right
and and the password log syntax.
I tell 1 to 3. Right.
I am not wrong.
Syntax room one two, three.
Yes. So they make sure
that you are entering this information
as it is without changing it.
Or are you guys done
with these three things?
Now let's declare the variables
to hold the connection
object, the statements
and the other stuff.
So first I will show you how it works.
Then I will explain
what each object is doing.
So we will be needing an object
A and a variable of connection class.
Right now I'm initializing it with NULL.
Okay, then we will be needing.
Are you guys able to see these?
Make sure guys these are coming from Java
dot school import.
You are not importing
it from somewhere else
are you guys do do
you guys see this
or you are getting some kind of datas?
If you are getting right data, that means
the dependency that you guys have added.
You either have not sync your project
or you need to invalidate your
in your session.
Okay.
And very so we have this
the results sec
object.
That's better.
Let me put some comment in here
variable to hold the connection.
Remember guys before we can to anything
on the database, we need a connection.
So that connection thing
was all managed by my sequel workbench.
But in here
because we are writing the code now,
so we have to build
these steps as well on our own.
So this object will hold the connection
for us, for this database.
Yes, this results act.
It's a if an object that can store
be that in the form of a table
that you get when you gilti
something from your database.
So we will be getting the results
and the actual data
against activity from this object,
which import we use for it.
This is not
oh sorry, it should be redirected
with java door basket.
All the imports will be from Java.
Don't ask you if you guys want
I can send the imports as well.
Use this import space,
not this one of the.
And this object helps us
execute the execute
the duties on the
on the database.
And this object
here helps us
store the
results.
These three objects we will be using to
then you send them your phone or exemplar.
Yes, why not?
I can actually send you
my completely apple.
Oh, I am here to be complete pass.
And then
you just you just need this dependency.
Then add this dependency to your pond or
make sure you include a sticky
with username and password.
Serbian.
You are always operable laptop Alexa.
Make sure that if there are so many laptop
thefts in Ukraine, you
you tell your police guys
to make sure to check with this order.
Will be always interested
in powerful especially the Mac ones
they okay all look good days
Mac I search in
No no it is my new business.
So you are also partner with him.
Are you pushing the code in GitHub?
Am I right?
This code? Yes.
I can push it to the gate, I'm sure.
Why not?
So everyone use
those letters or polymorphic.
All right, guys.
So once we have these variables, now
we can use the driver, manager, player.
So it is called driver.
It is also from Java dot School.
So driver manager, dot
get connection is the method
that will take care of using this
information that we are providing in here
and giving us the connection.
So it takes three arguments.
The first is the
DB you are, the second is the
username
and the third is the Fosler.
And because now we are interacting
with the outside world
outside of the Java program.
So now we have to make sure
that if there are any exceptions
that can enter,
we are also handling those that session.
So I will write this strike at BLOCK
as well
to make sure that if we get any skill
exceptions, for example,
connection is not available,
username and password is incorrect
or we get an error,
we write some duty that has syntax error.
So this scatterplot
can handle all of those scenarios.
So we will be storing this inside
the connection object
that we here.
So I want you to execute this program
after writing this piece of work
and if you guys have followed me
correctly,
you should not be getting any errors
that mean the connection was created
successfully.
Okay.
So the next thing is
how do we write the queries
and we feed those queries to the database
so that we will do with the help
of this second object.
So from this connection
that we have got
from the database,
we can write, we can create,
we can call this method
that bears the statement.
So once I have this statement
from this connection,
I can also pull back
for the inside the statement variable
that we created here.
So statement is equal to
then action dot create statement
and now this using this variable,
we can start feeding after this.
So let's let me go to
my sequel workbench.
Look close this.
So let's see this simple table from
mechanism.
So let's see this table
and let's see what is security.
And these are the results
that we should get in our Java program
and we execute this activity.
So before we integrate the duties,
yes, I agree.
Before we
go to
create the you would use the
we need to
if we are getting the proper results.
This Lola
is not binding my brother's browser.
We are not looking for a browser.
Or why are you looking for a browser?
We lose the connection if you there slow
shows error browser not found
who shows you this at a browser.
Not old Stephen.
She's looking for Steven.
Olga, are you feeling okay?
Take a deep breaths.
Have some water please.
So Hal had that 0.5 x versus
four x squared
and nothing in between it.
Do you guys know
Olga is attending this boot camp?
Since.
Since the beginning.
So just changes her picture
in all the badges and she is always there.
Let me show you.
She was also in the back then.
I don't know.
You see Olga in here?
She just changed the profile picture
and she was all also in Batch nine.
Again, she just changed the picture.
If you are also in back, it
again, just a different picture.
She was also in by seven,
again, a different picture.
So she is attending the syntax
since Badge seven
and that's
why see you guys can imagine why she is
sometimes my boss Steven or other things.
Can you show your complete
and you see my original
It is your
that I am just looking for Steven
no suitable driver.
Oh I told you guys
not to use the latest word.
Yeah, they always have problems.
Now please, with all due respect
or downgrade to your schoolwork,
this would be better than that.
I told you.
I'm sorry. I should have done that first
try, please.
To look at what? Alexi
guys use this word.
General vascular sequence.
If you are getting that data,
then you show me your code. Yes.
Guys, use this.
This login 8.0.6 for
this is my.
Is there anyone else who is
getting the issue
like all you guys getting that
no suitable driver or
Alexey?
How can I get all mad.
What was the thought that podcast please.
It is a click on this bulb icon or press.
All right.
I thought you guys were writing
the Java code all the time.
Didn't you guys use
Java code in your customer framework?
Why are you guys forgot all those things?
It was just two weeks back, right?
What was the shortcut for autocomplete?
Come on, guys.
All to
white fields like you guys.
It's been, like, months
since you have been intelligent.
It feels weird to reconfigure after it.
Maybe they were blown in yesterday. Class.
It is all our knowledge. Yes.
In fact, all the.
All the problems in your life,
all that they are
because of the last class assignment that
both. Yes.
I will send you an written apology
for yesterday's class.
Please send me your address.
I have an error.
Yes, you are.
All in all, the batch is right.
Always wanting.
Are you doing it?
Is because you have not defined this.
Maybe you are all variable.
And the internet being
Nabeel,
can you scroll up and show me this?
Stocking lines of the arrow?
Most probably it is because of
I am watching your class for free.
Please then me intuitive. So here
it is also an ability.
Maybe because you are using
the latest version of
Driver are
can cannot be applied
to given types.
It is get connection
not that can driver that high.
It is.
It is that connection did not get
automate a lot of your mouse over
the border of username and password
and show me what intelligence is
access denied for user blah blah blah.
Using password
and you are
your password is not correct.
You have syntax at different.
Oh my God why are you guys are doing this?
Why it is happening?
I think it's just two weeks.
Right? You are. You are.
You have not touched Java, right?
Let me send you the complete code.
Guys, it's almost time.
Please, please, please do this time.
Please go to.
I will.
Even if they ask you to write a follow up.
I don't think so.
You guys will be able to do that
quickly.
Showed me all the errors.
If you guys are getting any errors,
some of you can post this for channel two
is also there.
Some of you can post in here
so that we don't waste much time.
I think there are hardly
ten lines of code.
Maybe
I should be doing this right now.
Let me know once all of you are good.
It might be a problem to as
I would get the word, the
okay, so
no, no, it's not me.
Please don't blame me
for all the problems
that you have in your life.
Are you already have so many problems
in my life
that I have to figure it out.
Geniuses make these silliest mistakes.
Remember yesterday
I got you all my going to be like
cannot say a single word, right? You.
You have written such a comment.
What? I can say no to you guys
is, guys,
please make more mistakes.
Becomes bold
black male advice.
If if everyone is
blackmailing these days.
Okay.
Do you read my Arab?
No, sir.
Can you please send it again?
I am sorry, sir.
I. It's all because of your engagement.
Yes, yes, yes.
All right, guys.
Everybody looks good.
Now of still issues.
Oh, like
these because of the import homework.
Check your line.
Number one, remove that and put
anyone else against anyone else
having issues.
We have already spent 40 minutes on this.
Then lines of code
again, maybe black anyway, because
I don't know, guys.
Is it because you guys feel
so stressed, so, so relieved after
having those discussions
with your senior there?
It's easy to get the job,
especially silver in Zimbabwe, right?
You guys, you left the class yesterday
after inviting those students.
They're
already back.
Combination of everything.
So guys, this statement object
that we have created and we can exit.
We can say statement, not execute duty.
And inside the brackets
we can write our activities.
So if we go to
my skill workbench
and you guys don't need
the semicolon in here, I like this.
So statement dot execute.
I was here till one and 15
and this all this method execute query.
It will actually give us the results
in the form of the results like this
reminder.
Remember you will, you will actually
be making 300 K right silver plasma.
Give your bank account number
in the company she will be joining.
And then don't tell me password
of your bank account.
All right, guys. So it is that it
is an object that can contain the
that table
so we get the results in the form
of the table from and from scalability.
Right.
So we try to vacuity here and we provide
we stored the results inside this.
Now this results are method.
It has a similar something similar to that
vibrator that we learned for the
so it has a method reserved set dot.
Next it will keep on giving us through
until we have that
to inside this reserve set.
So these are dot next
and now so you guys know that
once we execute security
we get the results
in the form of columns and rows.
So as far as there are rules in the table
that that that results are not next,
that result
or next that method will return as true.
That means that loop that we have written,
it will continue working
unless and until there are rules.
But then we can also
we also need these column names.
If let's say we are interested
in this specific information.
So what we can do,
we can specify the column names in there.
So let's say, for example,
if I want to check the results
of first name, what I can do, I can see
Alexis is out and it is old Dot.
Get that string.
And inside here
I can specify the name of the column.
So for example, I can see ID
and now I will be getting all the IDs
from that table
that is the result of this activity.
Will Java recognize
or ignore the last and all auto generated?
Not no, no, no.
It will not give you that null. It is just
I don't
know if it is a feature
or a bug or whatever it is.
The editor.
They also don't give you
that last row as well.
It is only the great software my work
once that gives you that class
for as no. So.
So if you guys execute the score,
you should be getting all the ideas
from that person table.
So all the ideas, these ideas in here,
you should be getting inside
your Java program.
Do you guys checked your ideas?
It might take some time because all of you
are executing the code at the same time.
So can you guys tell me
how can I modified that code
to get the first
and last name and age as well?
It is easy or hard guys writing Java code
to get the results from
that is either easy or hard, so you
just need to understand these three
interfaces.
Connection statement and result.
So can you guys tell me
how can I get the first name?
Last name as well?
Little
So some space
and then I can again say
the result.
Dart That spring
and the name of the column
is first name, right?
So the first name like this,
is there anyone who is getting any errors?
So I now get the first names as well
and then you can obviously
modify it again.
Sorry to get the last name
and a
so reserved boss.
This thing, if that string is overloaded,
is it insensitive? No.
The same column names
you can specify in uppercase case,
same rules that you guys have learned
in your classes.
But as a good practice, you should always
specify the column names as it is.
As you see on the
editor's in
here, so that
even if some of the databases they have,
this is sensitive issue,
you guys don't waste your time
resolving those issues.
So do you guys see
all of this information?
Is there anyone who is getting any errors
or issues?
Let me go through pretty little bit
so that you guys can also understand
these objects.
So the clear statement,
the method of connection are
all Andy a mod
I can not expect this out of
at this point.
Why you are typing skill and then column
is just
have you not been using intelligent
like this school dart dart.
It is a suggestion from intelligent.
You don't need to type it like this. It's
I don't understand
what is happening to you guys.
Not will.
Why are you calling result
Do not object to ASCII stream
and then passing the matter
method Just get a string method
that is Are you okay?
I thought it was only mean. So
do you need this code?
Okay.
Grade 19.
Oh, I heard that
it has effects on your brain
as well.
Java over.
And let me tell you the quote.
Complete could actually be complete mean.
Then you throw all code in school.
Alex, You mean to query the query?
It's simple.
Select all from person.
That's it.
The that is all the code that I thought
I go for.
Are you getting better than we are?
Wondered about this
so we cannot not focus.
Okay.
I am sure I did.
Good thing actually.
Oh yes, you guys, it can happen.
It's perfectly fine.
It's perfectly fine. So.
So do we move to the next step? Rise
Or if all looks good, should
we move to the next step?
Okay, so
there is an important thing
that I want to discuss in here.
These objects, this connection statement
and set objects,
they are actually very important objects.
And unless and until we close them,
they keep on occupying their resources
as far as your application is running.
So if you are building an application
that runs on a server
all the time, the resources
will all go forward all the time.
So we should close the resources
like we did for the
except for the file to be filed, we closed
the file screen.
So for that you guys know that
finally block is the place
where we should do
all of this stuff right?
Then Java Console show the structure
of table with border, for example.
I think you can write your
your source in any way you like.
I am not sure
if there is a built in method to
which we can just pass
this results are displayed
the output light
that my workbench is displaying.
You saw searching it on the internet
if it is possible,
but I have not seen such a method.
So in the finally block, we should
we should close these objects as well.
So once we are done using the results
that we should say
that result not close,
but because we are initializing these
variables with null values.
So they are chances
that if anything goes wrong in here.
So if you guys remember from your prior,
if your exception places,
if anything goes wrong in here,
these results will never be initialized.
The the execution will directly jump
to the catch block
And this where variable will contain null.
And what happens, guys,
when we call a method on an object
null pointer exception.
Right null pointer exception.
So it is a better idea.
Is a good practice
to check for the null values before
we call any matters
on those objects.
So if result is not equal to null,
then only we want to close this right?
Get again?
Yes. Also,
if the if we get any issues in here,
this this variable will never be
initialized properly.
This actually this complete code
will not be executed right.
And if something is not initialized,
the property of properly
does not make sense to close a pride
even if something is not opened,
then how can we close that?
So Eskil warned us that,
Hey guys, you should also.
You can also get an exception when you
try to close this result.
So for that
we need to add the get block again.
And remember, guys, as a best practice.
If a single
method is containing multiple
try catch blocks,
you should create a separate
method for back in your program.
So what I will do,
I will select this piece of code
I will right click and then refactor
and then extract the method.
Let me know
if you guys see this option and
select the piece of code,
then refactor and then expect
method.
Do you guys see this option
of the click on extract method
and then you can view
any name to your method.
Can I see the code behind it?
You mean above it for this one?
Give me on one more time this time.
So let me rename it. Oops
Refactor
extract method
and let's call it clause. So
these are set.
I can
do this guided less created
DB You do this class
because you guys can also use
these methods in your framework.
Let me put all these methods in so DB
utils
and let's
copy that method
from here.
So your duties
so that you can use these methods again or
and it should not be private
or should be public
and it is static.
So when you add the name of the class
dot proposal to this,
let me know once you guys have done
all of this,
I you lost me
since the right click
Mohammadi just create this matter.
The purpose of that right
click was to create a method
and write that code in that method
is the util package along with the main
I shall
do many util package along with the main.
You want to create a separate package
for this util class.
This is what you mean
and want the quality of
it is fine.
For now.
We will create those packages
in your framework actually.
Okay.
This this is just a demo.
We will create those packages in
you send the code. Yes. Issue.
So let me send you
the main method from here.
This and let me also send you
this W-2s class complex.
And guys, if you still feel
I am going fast, Lucas, you can stop me.
Alexi
But if you guys feel
that I am going faster, you can stop me.
I'm back.
Okay.
Nice.
Please take your time.
Yes, guys, please start fighting with me
to the end in place for some comments.
Nobody saying something different.
Can we write our access
that to be in configured property?
Yes. For one,
we will do that When I will tell you
when we will be integrating
all of these things with your framework.
We will do everything in proper places
like concrete fires,
properties, files and all that. So
adrenalized when
you are done.
Okay, so let's do this guys.
Let's copy this exact same code
and for the next demo
we will modify this code.
So let's create another class.
Let's call it clear Demo two
and last space.
The code in here for
I should copy the main metadata stuff
like this. Yep.
Yep. Pasting.
And I'm closing this class, guys.
Right.
Oh, we missed one more thing.
Let's go back to demo once again.
So we only close to the
results set.
We also need to close the statement
and the connection.
Let me fix the error in here
and let's close these things
so let us to next.
Why not copy this one,
copy this method again days
and let's call it
the second thing is the statement.
So let's follow up
rules
statement
and instead of passing results, whoops,
we've instead of passing the dataset,
we will pass a statement.
And then this statement is not doing no
and statement of false
and you can again copy it to
close the connection.
You guys, if you don't want to follow me
you don't need
I will send these matters to you.
So connection
and connection is not important.
And so let me show you all of these
three matters to
Alexi lost again.
I think I need to call your wife
to make sure
that you are not struggling or not going
with the big giant viper
is holding that viper behind you
so that you can focus.
So let's say DB utils dart close
statement and looks boss.
This statement and
baby is a dog clause
so it will be close connection
the yes you say
change in default
close connection.
They're concerned.
It all looks good now
close connection
close statement and close to the reset
and just to make sure
that everything works fine
you guys again again I see your data
and no errors this time
and this time.
This, by the way, this is the proper way.
Nice to open a connection. Use it.
And as soon as you guys are done, close it
all looks good.
Ways.
Also copy
the last lines to the demo two. Yep.
Thank you guys.
I should also this.
All right, so
the next thing is, guys in here,
we kind of have to
for the B names of the columns, right?
But we don't need to do this.
We can also actually factor
this information
from the database
that the query that we are executing,
how many columns it contains
and what are the names of those columns.
But to find out that information, I and I,
we will be needing another object
that obviously is called result metadata.
So let me be clear of that as well.
So it is of set metadata
is there except metadata is required. You
all get to
give the information about
table and it's there
to fill this resultant metadata.
It can tell us
how many queries that acuity,
how many rules that he has returned,
what are the column names
inside the acuity, what are the data types
of those columns and things like that.
So for example, what I can do,
I can say why
the are results that are, that are not
actually I will be needing affordable.
So for example, let's say
I want to find out all the column names
in that table so I can save for I,
I equal to zero and I is equal to result
set metadata or to get column count.
So it will tell me the column
count of these variables
and let me put it
inside the type edge ideologically.
Say that you can get an error and now
what I can do, I can actually print out.
So I am using print
instead of print alone.
So I can say a reader
segment our that our dog.
I can say get column name
and it requires an index to be passed.
And so if I lost the index one,
it will give me the column one.
It can tell me the label,
it can tell me the catalog name.
So catalog name,
they are the kind of the company name,
the vendor name has developed outside
the class, names and things like that.
So most probably the things that you guys
will be using will be the column names.
Yeah, column names.
They act as like aliases so far
are part of our
our testing of the column names
will be enough
and what I can do I can pass the index.
But there is one thing that we need to
make sure that most of the time actually
appealing.
Up till now, you guys have seen that
all the things they have a starting
this index starts from zero.
But for this reason such metadata
if starts from one.
So if you start the loop from zero,
you will be getting an error.
So and after
putting anything out of the names,
let me just bring a new line.
So there we see the information.
Excellent.
So let's execute this.
I'm closing this class. Nice.
And so that column called
Oh, what,
you're going to initialize this video,
but we need to like this valuable asset.
So these are certain metadata.
So we will be getting this result,
certain metadata
from this.
Let me talk to this code. And
so we will be getting this result
from this result, not getting metadata.
So we need to call this method as well.
I will send you the code.
We just spoke last time, but
I think we should put some spaces as well
so that you guys can see
all the names of the columns
that we see the
I need the first name,
last name and age be and
but these are actually all the columns
that are in here.
Where is that?
So we are missing the last column.
We need this equal less than equal to sign
as we would like to with this time.
The index is not starting from zero.
So many good idea was missing in here.
Let's see.
Let's get that as well.
Now it looks like so I'd be first
name, last name, gender city in papers
but then when you really
and they are
the exact same column names in here
so the information that guys
we were hard coding in here
now we don't need to hide
all that information in here. Yep.
Is it good Now for one,
you'll get that there is no difference.
Let's not discuss the column level.
We will not be needing that.
But if you guys are just curious
what you guys can do.
As I have printed out these
get column names,
you can all, all the methods and can
print out different different things.
But the main purpose
why we are using this,
there are so many metrics
we will not be going over all the methods.
The main purpose of using this object
is to make sure that we don't particle
any values and if we are building
something, we can write some genetic code
that can automatically factually column
names
and corresponding data from the table.
So can you guys tell me
how can I avoid these hardcoded values?
So I am writing a loop
to get the column names
that I am printing in here,
but how can I avoid this?
What do I need to modify inside this loop
so that all the column names
they are fashioned automatically
and the corresponding data
for all the column names
is also attached automatically.
So this texting method,
it requires the column name.
So somehow
I need to write a piece of logic
that can pass the column names one by one
to this string method,
and then we can get the cross
bonding that
then you guys modify this code to do this.
Have you guys underscore the problem?
So we want to avoid this hard coding? No,
Aleks, we
don't I don't want to specify these
these ideas.
First name, last name, because I can now
write a loop to get all of these
column names
automatically with the help of this
result of certain metadata.
So I want to modify this loop
in such a way
that I don't need to hard for these values
and I get all of these values from this.
My connector.
All right.
Straight through with the list.
Okay, So
check this out.
This I am copying this loop.
Okay, in here.
So in this result,
set the metadata to get column.
I gives me the column name right?
So if I copied this column name
and instead of hard calling this value,
if I passed that in here
like this,
oops, I'm deleting this
and I am deleting Augustus,
I will change the score.
So what I am doing,
I am starting from column number one.
I am I creating through
all the columns one by one
and I get the first column name
by calling this method.
There are certain letters
that are not that column name.
Right?
Then I pass that column
name to this string method.
Right.
And once we pass the get string
a column name,
we know that it will give us the data
from corresponding row.
Right.
So this result not
exiting, will get the corresponding data
from that column.
Right.
And then I am printing out
that information.
So instead of oops
instead of quintillion, that's the print
and, use this space.
And after that, let's print out a new line
right there, see if we get the desired.
So you guys see
now we are
not uploading any of the column names
and we get all the data in here
from that table with columns.
Oh, let me send you this code as well,
because you guys will not be writing
this code again and again.
Once this code
has been integrated in your framework,
you will just be calling the method
and you will be getting
your desired desired result.
But you should definitely know
how this code is working.
So if you guys don't understand
any of this line, you can tell me
I can debug this code for you, but
let me know guys,
if you don't understand any line of code.
That line of code is doing,
you should be getting something like me,
like this.
Yes. Yes.
Please ask your questions.
Yes, ask good questions.
And actually,
let me also put some comments for you.
Okay.
Getting the back obvious connection
from driver
manager class.
Can you debug it quickly?
So I was asking everyone else
other than Hallmark, is there anyone else
who wants to be this code
other than Anna? Yes.
Anyone else other than of
you guys?
Just just let me just put the comments you
then I will debug this for you.
Creating a statement
to execute the
duties,
executing
the duty
or building the user or
although I know
you guys will never look at these comments
Body by mission work metadata.
Is it a big class or another something
boss or another something
awesome, another something?
So let me click on this variable name.
I am holding down my control button
and I press on digital set metadata
and now you guys will tell me
if it is a class or what is it?
What is it guys?
Okay, I will be sent to code. Okay.
It is an interface that contains a method
to get column count
and you guys can read the description.
It says Returns the number of problems
in this result set object
because the number of column
is auto increment indicates
the designated column is automatically
integrated is so sensitive.
So I was saying if the column names
it should be case sensitive or not.
Right.
So you can call
this method is searchable is currency.
So you guys can call all of these methods.
You guys can read
the description from here
and you guys can also search
on the Internet of Things.
So all of these,
they are actually interfaces, connection
statements that are set.
And then we are calling these methods.
They create the object of the classes.
Which are you guys remember I told you
this database
is the heavily used polymorphism.
These interfaces are created by Java guys
and all of the vendors
which create the databases.
They implement these methods
in their own way.
So that's why they are all interfaces,
not classes.
Do you guys understand this,
why they are all not actual classes?
The actual classes are implemented by the
vendors who are developing the databases.
It is again polymorphism in here,
so that's why you guys don't need to
memorize different different method names
for different different databases.
You will just call the exact same method
for of the database
if that is supported with Java,
it can be reserved
object so that we can
back to the
column names and
other info
related to the
printing being
followed.
There we
column name it.
It would be
the string method to get
to the
content of or
there are the new.
Okay, now let's do this code
and also debug this course
so that you guys can understand
inconsistencies between
let me place an e-book point in here
and how can I debug decoding including
calendars.
I have left the debug point
for two dogs
I have nested right
and then right click.
Why you always not copy last.
But it is because Alexa,
you guys might have a different class name
and you guys might
face some issues
when copying and pasting before.
So I this is what I expect from you.
Create
any class any side that this demon matter
and then write it
and then debug as the application.
So how can I go
to the next line, step over a
step into some.
So this
is where the connection is created.
You see how much time Java takes
to create the connection.
And once we have the connection,
you guys can
get the database name
and you can check the password from here,
the user and all that info.
So disconnection that contains all the,
all that information.
Then we created this statement
and once we have this statement
object, it's also a very big object
that contains so many properties
that we can modify
to execute security
in many different ways.
What exemple executing these in batches
and all that, Then we execute the security
and we get the results
in reserve set object.
Certainly
if you expand the observed set object
again, these objects,
they are very, very heavy.
So you should always close these objects.
I didn't heard this tactic question
for a long time.
So can we create a static
can we call a static method inside the
non static method based
we cannot call affecting method
inside the non
static method severity of please,
please, please.
We're right that in the end
emit is also saying we cannot do that.
Why cannot we call a static method
inside the non static?
Why? What is wrong in that
not good idea
guys.
Well what did we do?
Well, this was a static method.
This was a static method.
Close riddle said we had.
I called it.
Okay, so it was also static.
But even if I removed that,
I can still call it.
I can still call it no issues.
You guys
okay, let's do this.
Always try to answer in reverse.
If you think you can
call, always say you cannot.
And if you you cannot always say you can.
Maybe that works.
Okay.
Yes, let's do this.
Do it for interviews.
Okay. So now we have the results.
That object
and this object, it contains the fields.
So filters zero to filter it,
and then it contains
the name of the field table name user.
We don't need to look
at the other information, but
it can give us the column count in here
and we can write a loop.
So when we are created the first time this
results are metadata or that column,
it will give us
the first name of the column.
So in the console we get this ID,
then we do the second iteration.
It is equal to two.
So we pass the I use equal to two in here.
We will get the second column
first name, then I put the third
and fourth column like this.
So we will be getting all the columns
one by one right?
Humanitarian order.
Then again,
we use the same loop, exact same loop,
but this time
instead of printing the column names,
we are passing this column
names, names to this we are testing method
and we know the exiting method can get rid
written as the data for that column.
Right.
So the delta exiting and inside here
we pass the column name.
So we will be getting the data from
for the first column.
I missed the fun part.
I guess that means
the question was
can we call the non static method
inside this static method?
So this is how this code works.
Get the column name
and then get the data for that column
and then get the next column name
and get the data and rule
will continue
working for all of the columns
and all the rows. Yes.
Yes. With static or what?
Are you good? Now
you guys can also debug this code later on
if you guys are still not comparable.
So let's celebrate, guys,
after the break, we will explore.
We will write a
we will store this resource,
these results inside a list of maps
like as we did for the Excel files
so that we can post these that are easily
two different methods.
We can use these
that are inside the framework
and we can do other stuff
with that, right?
Instead of just printing it out,
we will be using it to test different
things.
And also, guys, during the break, please
make sure that you have a working copy
of The Cucumber Project.
So I'm giving you a longer
break contained winners.
But please make sure every one of you
have a working copy of Cucumber Project.
So after the next exercise we will shift
all of this code in your cucumber,
then we will write some scenarios
in which we will get
some information from different
then some information from the backend,
and then we will compare that information
and will write test cases to verify.
Let's save
the same information that is stored in
and that we inserted in the event.
And if that is stored
inside the back end of.
And so I am giving you a lot longer break
guys please make sure your cucumber
projects, they are all working
and if they are not working, I will.
Okay. I will show you from scratch.
Starting from how to clone it
from the good repository, a fresh copy of
our base.
Please be back by
1150.
Okay.
So as you guys know about
the next previous class or an absolute
method already,
so we will start from here.
So absolute method
is used to jump to a row directly.
Let's say we want to iterate
every second row at row or before throw
so we can write a piece of logic
in which we passed the row number
and then it will jump
to that specific specific
and then this
get the input
in which we specified the column index.
We used to return the data
of a specified column
for which we are specifying the index.
So what is happening in here?
So let's say for example,
this is it or zero.
This is one, two, three, four, five, six.
And the these rules,
they are keep on going.
So and we also have columns, columns,
by the way,
they start from one column,
one, two, three, four, five.
So if we directly want to
jump to column number four
and row number five, it is also possible
how we can use the get into method
to directly jump to a specific column
and this absolute method
to directly jump to a specific row.
Ella Everyone, again
out there
and by then so in here
this into method is an overload method.
We can pass the index
of a specific column.
So let's say
I have eight columns in this security.
So I can, I can say, let's say
maybe give me the data from the standard.
All by saying one, two, three, four
by specifying integer four.
I can also specify its name
explicitly by gender.
So this method, this get into
my 30,
takes this integer and add string aspect,
and then this gets thing in
which would not it be hard coding.
I mean if sometimes you needed
you don't need to if you don't want to
board, you can use this overloaded version
in which you are specifying integer.
And if you don't,
if you want to specify the exact column,
you can use this other method.
So you might want to use these column
names as well so that
your code is readable.
Because right now alone,
if you look at your code right now,
it is very hard to find out for
which columns you are getting the data.
So yes, it is hard coding,
but it also makes your code more readable
for depends
if you are only looking with information,
maybe from one column or two columns,
then maybe it is a good idea
to specify the column names as well.
Otherwise What will happen?
Let's say you check this code
after three weeks, four weeks,
you have to execute this query.
You have to find out
how many columns are there
or you have to execute this code
to understand it.
Now, when these kind of counts,
they become a part of a big system.
Sometimes it is not possible
to just execute these small concepts.
So in those scenarios we try to write
as much as possible readable code.
Then this gets fingered same,
and we pass the call
and we pass the row index
and it gives us some natural
and this gets being
also used to the candidate
of a specified column.
This is the exact same code
with the slight modification
that we have written in the demo.
So I am creating the connection, then
printing out simply connecting is created.
Also printing out the object of connection
that creating a statement present set
and then print writing a loop.
So before writing the loop,
I am doing this next next in here
so that you can visually
also see where this it is.
Our next method returns
and how the exiting.
When we pass a specific column name,
it returns us the back for that
and then closing the results statement
and the connection
and also observe guys,
I am doing it in reverse.
So you see
I open the connection object first
just to keep the code simple
in the later demos.
As we do more demos,
the code will get real close to real.
The real life,
how you would be reacting in real life.
So you guys uploaded this.
I open the connection first, right?
But I close it at the last.
Why I do that?
Because this reader site
is connected to this statement and
the statement is connected to connection.
Okay, so sometimes you might get errors
if you don't follow this approach for us.
Some of you get that basis
because for some of the databases,
the results are statements
and connections.
They are all linked together.
This is about the metadata,
this is about the metadata.
The metadata object
that we use to get the information
about the names of the columns
from that results.
And so
there are two
types of results that one is database
metadata.
Let's say you want to get the information
about the database.
What is the name of the database,
what is the version of database
and all those info
So you can use or metadata.
But it is very rare.
Almost everybody you already know what
kind of database you are interacting with.
And then we have this reserve set metadata
that we have
just used to avoid the hard coding values.
And these are some of the methods,
these metadata from database metadata.
So has got a driver name
which will return.
You do driver, but
it does not make much more sense because
in here we are already specifying
all of this information.
But if this information
is being passed to you as a parameter,
you are writing a method
and this information is being passed
in the form of three strings
like we are passing
inside this connection,
then maybe sometimes.
And sometimes you guys need to know the
driver name, but usually those companies
would develop the underlying API
to interact with the specific database.
They need these kind of information.
The user name again, same.
The name user name
that we used in the string
and that we you possibly get connection
method,
your database product name, the name of
the database and then the word game.
So very simple
but never used in practice techniques.
On the other hand,
this one you guys might want to use and
you guys might also see it in
different flavors,
especially this call column
count and column name.
It tells you
how many columns are present in
the query that you write,
how many columns that it is returning,
and by passing the index, you can get
all the names of those buildings
and then column times
might also be helpful.
For example, some columns contain
walked our data type, some contains
integer
data type, some contain decimal ones. So
if you are not So
in this example,
we are getting all the data
as being
all the data as being.
But you can also say
negative blob vector by that globe
reference asking whether you are a
big decimal.
So you can get the data
in different different forms
and get in bigger get time.
So you guys might want to check
what kind of information
is presenting a specific column
before you do get spring or let's
see if something contains alphabets
and you call getting better on that
column,
you guys will be getting an error because
you will not be able to convert it.
And so this column type
method, that column type will help you
tell the data type of the column,
and then you can decide
if you want to get it as is being integer
or decimal double or whatever.
So it depends how you want to use that
information for the linear framework part
in your application,
and then it will give you a table.
But there are many, many other matters.
But these are for you guys will definitely
be using.
The second is
the second demo is just shows
how to get to those columns
and the count of those columns.
And this is what we will do now.
So once we have the results set, how
we can store that an object
so that we can easily pass
that information from one method, either
method from one plus one the class.
This is the code to do
that, let's have a demo for it. Now,
any questions
before we start the demo for this case?
Do you guys remember how we did this
for Excel Files?
We created a list of maps
right?
So we will do exactly the same thing
in here as that.
Are you guys ready to do stock up so
far? One rule, one map.
Yes, yes, yes.
You are right.
So I am again copying this code.
So we will just modify this code
because the only thing that we need to do
is instead
of printing out this information,
we need to store it inside
a map of list of maps.
Again, without main method. So
virtual reality of that
list of maps.
Okay, well,
let me know where you're going with that.
You can
if we're depleted after a while,
I assure you we are getting the data
inside of the while.
How would you save the data
inside of that list of map
side?
While maybe if we declare it
inside the while.
Hudson Every time that loop runs,
it will be reappeared again and again.
I am being a student at least.
Yep, yep, yep.
It's good at this.
You responding
well,
so it will be an error list
and for
So this is what we will do guys.
And let me know guys,
if this is not clear.
If you guys understand this part,
everything will be easy.
So first I am creating a list
and on each index of that list.
So this is index.
This is one
two, four.
Inside each index
I will be having a map.
So the map will contain a key.
The key for the first row will be ID.
So I will store this already in here
and this pool.
So D and to go to the you gold
then that's where you have deleted that.
Then I will still be plus name as the key.
Then John
as the value then last name
and then Jerry.
Is it the bomb on me or on someone else?
And then I will keep on doing it
for all the columns.
Please don't post-treatment.
And then for the second row again and map
again, I will use the same
ID as E,
but this time the value will be three.
The name first name Maddy
and then I will keep on doing it
for all zeros.
Does it make sense, guys?
This data structure, this list of maps
that I have created in here,
this is how we will use it.
So this list it contains,
it is a list of maps, and each map
will contain the data of one rule.
The column names will be used as keys
and the value of those that role will be
used as the value of that map.
So it means nice.
It means we need to have a map
for each row.
Right.
So this is this why loop
is I tripping through the rows, right.
So what I can do, I can see a map
string and then
string is equal to row.
So can you guys tell me
what kind of map I should use
if I have to store
this kind of character in
link the hash provide
because link the hash maps,
they also store
the insertion order, right?
So that we can retain the insertion
order off rules in whichever
order they are being returned.
So we we can use the link patch map.
Okay.
So I am removing this printout statement,
right.
Because this time we don't need to print,
we need to store this information
inside
this map.
So again, can you guys tell me
from where I can get the key for this map?
So roll all dot port
and I need a key and a value.
So which method?
This this method will give me the key
or this result set
or the exchange will give me the key.
How can I get The key is the column name.
What? What does this matter? Return, guys?
What does this method return?
The column names. Right.
And I am planning to use the column names
as the key.
Right.
So for Biggie, I see the there third
or get column name right.
And how can I get the corresponding value
for that column?
Which lines give me the corresponding
value for this column?
I am passing the column name in here
and this method, starting from here
till here, gives me the data
for that specific role.
So once this loop will be done, once
we've done iterating through this look,
we will have a map in which
we will have eight keys, ID,
first name, last name, gender, age
and eight values to John, Daddy
and between blah, blah, blah.
All right.
For the first time, then for the second
iteration of this y loop,
we will again be
having eight keys ID,
first name again, last name, same
button values will be this time
three Matic in F 22.
So then we inserting that in here
and once we have created that map,
then we can insert that map inside this
next.
So all
and after we are done with this loop,
I can in here to print out this table
like this
looks like this for
so you guys see,
please explain line 39
one more time, which is like
this one.
So to store the values in a map,
what do we need
to store the values in the map?
What do we need?
A key and a value And what we have,
what we are using as keys
column names.
Right.
This method result set the metadata.
The column name gives me the column names.
Okay, this is the desired set object.
I passed the index,
so for the first operation
the index will be one and at the column
at index number one is it this one?
The column at
index number two is first name, last name
three, four, five.
Like this.
So this five for this inner for loop.
When I will be one,
I will be getting ID and I will be two.
I will be getting first
name and I will be three.
I will be getting last name
already will be four getting eight
and I will keep on getting all the column
names.
The last in priority
and then to get the value for this idea
for first row.
So let's say I want to get
this first value from the row number one.
So this rule number one,
when the Y loop is on the first iteration.
And this I is also one.
This method will give me ID,
this method will give me two.
So I pass the column, name
the information about.
The row is coming from this result
because you remember next method all all
automatically moves you to the next row
after each time you call method.
So it automatically you
it is moving you to one row
in advance or one by one
when this loop executes.
Let me actually debug this code names,
but find
so right now the value
right now the value of I is one
and right now we are on raw number zero,
which means we are
on the first creation of value.
So if check what we get from this method
by creating a watch.
So you see it gives us an ID
for the first iteration of
this fun book and this method
that spring on other.
It gives us the data for back.
So see, we get to
when we are on the second iteration.
Now the value of I is two and now
we get as a key first name and as a value.
John When we are on third,
we get last name Daddy,
then we get gender and
so we are moving from left side
to right side.
So first we go row by row.
Once we are on the first row,
we start from left column and its value.
We pick that column name that is value.
Then next, next, next, next.
Then we move to the next row
starting from left.
Pick the column story that is a key
value added as a and key value.
So we keep on going, iterating,
as I forgot.
Never mind.
Everyone fell down asleep already.
Guys, please also tell me if you guys are
sleeping so that I can also go to sleep.
Okay. Let's go to sleep together.
I remember my teachers
that they used to do this with us when.
We used to starting in
very, very
junior grades, Prep, Katie
or whatever they call it.
So they they used to tell us,
okay, let's go to sleep altogether.
It's called class.
And my teachers told me
listening
and understanding is very difficult.
Yes, yes, yes, it is very difficult.
So already sleeping for the last one,
all guys, these messages,
they are very, very motivated.
I am very motivated to show you the next
things that I want to show you to go.
You are also reading words wrong.
Okay, English master.
Sorry for that.
So this is how the school is working.
Is not.
Otherwise let's open up
your cucumber frame books.
Okay, let's do something.
Let's
have that practice so that you, based on
philosophy,
can you please turn this score?
Is it okay, guys, if I push this code,
then you guys rejected from the GitHub
that I have shared the repository
link in the course announcement.
Please use that to launch
or get the updates.
Okay, so now let's integrate
all of this knowledge in your framework
and I want every one of you
for it to follow me.
So go to YouTube.
If you have already a working copy of
Cucumber Framework,
you guys don't need to do these steps,
but if you want to do everything
from scratch,
you guys might want to follow me.
So. Well,
what was the name of your cucumber
then?
This is a
this is the framework that you develop.
Cucumber framework batch, right
to the click on this core button
and then click on
copy the you are in for this
repository
and you go to your intelligent
and go to file
new project from login control and paste.
Let me know once
you guys have followed me to this point.
Is there anyone who follows the S.
S seeds of Samson
or who is interested in buying the S 22
logo?
Do you see any updates? Like
do you think that it is work to upgrade
this time?
I don't see much changes this time.
You have already ordered it
open is the best.
I don't know.
I got the new pixel.
Actually, I like the pixel devices
more than iPhone or Samsung
because they are cheaper
and their software
is all optimized. So.
So well.
New Galaxy looks awesome.
I preorder Samsung Country two for silver.
Not like you see poor husbands of.
Are you using Nokia 33 110
demo for yourself and
new s 22 ultra for your wife
Z My you are not alone, believe me.
I will also be ordering iPhone 13
for my future
wife and I still use this s 20
you have note
20 ultra at
least you have something better than me.
Still something better than me.
Somehow it is on the
spintex re possibly
right
guys, let me know once you are here
better once again.
How did you go to this page?
I did file new and then project
from Login control.
Are we using this?
We have address C or not.
This is not your framework
to convert framework. Yes.
You guys can rename the directories.
You guys created two frameworks.
I mean, the framework that
that Sunil showed you,
that is our normal framework with Sohail.
And then you guys created something else.
It's the same.
Okay, guys, it's fine.
We can use this one. It's fine, it's fine.
You can use whatever
whichever framework you want to use.
Okay,
Let me know Once you guys are on this page
Now, I have started understanding slowly.
Have you guys noticed this?
Females,
they don't get harder text, right?
It's always the males.
No. Now I understand all the tension.
Pressure goes to men. Women.
They are attention free.
You always.
I have literally not seen anybody
in my circle like women.
They are still all the time
living for 100 to 110 years.
Men, poor men,
they are almost done with their life
after 65 years.
So that's why we women
don't die.
Women have cardiac arrest and just to die.
No, no, they don't die even after.
No, because women have multi-task
and men only have one task.
No, this is also not within.
I can now understand
what is the true reason
this.
It's I think also women. They are kind of
they just
cry and they their heart is kind of
not that that they remove their burden
by crying or just cussing or whatever
they are doing.
But men, they usually don't cry.
They give all of their pain inside
and just wait.
Okay, enough.
So like click on Clone guys,
should we clone same Yes guys
Deacon put on
and then you can click on Trust Project
and then New window
give it give it some time guys
let them sink from the year. Come
it might take some time.
Also guys
I think you will get an error
if you are using the maven and five
so next year
come on next year and for
this is not order
to be project
that how you have grown you have
so let's
use them forward in here
and there's a consent project
and make sure that you are not
getting any errors
after thinking you should see
all the all of your pages, runners
and everything
as we should teach you how to use cucumber
frame loops please.
Then this.
I will be privileged to be out by you
guys.
My own findings. Fine.
Maybe I am using a different version
of Java and intelligent
it is.
If you are not getting any errors,
it is fine.
But I think it is good to use them for
because I guess after two weeks
I will teach you Jenkins
and it will definitely not like
with Jenkins. So it depends on you.
If you want to change now or later.
Okay.
Yes. We
need to install my sequel dog in here.
We need to use texture.
So guys.
So Dennis, can you please tell me
what is this cucumber thing
I want to add?
The the dependency for the my sequel.
So again, let's go in here
and let's use this 8.6
16 this time.
Okay? Thank you, sir.
Dennis Sir.
So I am adding the dependency first thing
because I will be working with the skills,
so I need that dependency.
So I am adding it inside
the dependencies tab in here
and after I add
the dependency,
I need to reload my project.
So make sure you are not
getting any of lines over here
and everything is up to date
and so
now let's run
any of the tests,
any of the runners just to make sure
that we have imported everything correctly
and our frame load looks good. So
I am running the smoke, but
I know you guys can run any of the runner
that can run.
So that we know everything is good.
Before we start modifying this project.
Run structured successfully,
I mean, blah blah blah.
I can get this error
so far plugin and for not found
you can use them
five and four is not working for you.
Mohammad.
Okay, so everything looks good.
Now we can start making changes in here.
You guys can use them
five and four and five.
Anyone will work for this
for today's class.
Is there anyone else
with getting any errors
on word?
So, guys, this is my requirement.
So what I want to do,
I want to go to this website, this
great extremist website.
I want to log in in here,
click on the log in button
and then
see sort of token validation filter.
This is not what I want.
After that, I want to go to be
am then an employee.
Then I want to add some information
in here.
I want to click on Save.
I do exist, but
so then what I want I want to copy this,
employ it from here,
and then I want to write a piece of code
that goes inside the A database
and it queries
the same information with the help of that
really
that we see in the front end
is called employ it.
So we're
in for
really important tool in this.
So I want to make this query in my best.
Then I want to fetch this information
from the backend
and I want to factor this information
from the front end
and then I want to match
this piece of information
if it is correct or not.
So what I will do, I will write peculiar
to fetch this information from the columns
and using this query,
using this simple already.
I should be getting the same results
and the data should support
inside of these proper columns like this
should not happen that maybe
this door is being stored in the middle
name or the last name column.
Right.
It should be stored in the first name,
middle name and last name columns
inside the database.
So this is how you can verify different
than the backend, all the requirements,
clear days.
So as you guys know,
I don't know anything about cucumber.
So you guys will tell me
how can I do that?
So from where should I start?
And I hope
because we have
around tonight
90 intelligent students in here,
I hope we will be able to do it
next to the US.
No, you can do it.
Believe in yourself. It's
a go.
This functionality belongs to the ADD
employee feature, right?
So what do you guys think?
So should I write this scenario in here
or maybe inside dashboard in place
or blogging feature
there?
So to write a scenario,
we use the tags
and you guys tell me, what are these?
What is this excel that are table
simple number scenario.
So I am using this DB
tag in here.
So let's say
if I want to run a specific test case,
I can use this best tag in my runner
to maybe only execute that tag,
or if I have used that tag
with multiple scenarios,
all those scenarios will be executed.
Right?
And just a way of
categorizing your test cases.
So after the tag,
I will see a scenario
and let's call it
front and and
back and testing right.
And have you guys already done
some of the steps there?
So I have shown you the requirements
do you guys already have steps
for some of the requirements
I should write all it
to from scratch
we have.
So where do you guys have this?
I think I can use this one right.
Adding
one employee using to convert to user
does not have to be expensive,
but I need to successfully.
But I think we can use this one.
Right. Right.
Even if we are only planning
to add the backup.
So I will just copy these steps in here
and I will say
add user and third detect. So
it already include this step.
Like for example,
it will already log in inside
the web page, right?
This step.
All right.
And then after I have entered of the data,
before I click on Save Button,
I need to capture that I be right.
So before I can
save and close this,
I need to get this employ ID in here.
Right?
I don't want to get employed number.
I want to get employee ID so
let's do this after this
and then there
the employee I.D..
Well, why?
It is highlighted in different color
guys. Why?
Why intelligent highlighting it
in a different color.
It means that in this scenario,
this step is not implemented.
Right. We need to implement this.
So once we have captured the employer
I.D., user clicks on the save button.
So must be data has been stored
from the front end.
The next step should be that
using this employer I.D.,
we vetted this same information
from the database right.
So user clicks on save button.
And after that, we have
to employ it successfully.
So do we change the name,
last name or not?
Should we change the name?
Last name or not, we are hosting.
Can you tell me the line number
48 in here?
No, Governor, depends on you.
Can we insert multiple same first names
in your grade at premise web application?
If we can, we can keep them other way.
You can also can you if you if you guys
want to insert something different.
Yes. You guys can
maybe can you to Stephen and then thing
and in between
we can have all that here center
true love triangle
so and the
user enters this information
and we capture the employee I.D.
then we click on same button, employed it
successfully.
Then maybe
you see
the information
from the backend.
And then uh,
so once
we have the information from the front end
and the back end, then we will do that
verification thing, right?
And verify
the result from UI and backend.
Yeah.
So we need to implement these three steps
then will be expected
results should be when
or and why you start your scenario
with and or
when and then and then
and then
then and
that it look good
because we have background.
I don't know anything about cucumber guys
you see you guys are
you guys are teaching me flip open the
it does
not matter we can start from anything
okay so I have written a scenario guide
what should be my next step.
What should be my next step?
So now I should dry run
so that these steps
which are not implemented,
I can kind of get those or
generated methods for these things.
Right.
So let me copy this bag from here.
Let's go to smoke.
And and instead of that one,
let's put the be bright run next book.
Cool.
Looks good
today.
Click on Execute.
Okay.
So definitely it will fail.
And now I have the
definition for the capturing ID
so I have steps in here.
Right.
And in the inside of the steps
I have this add employee steps.
So should I put it inside this class
or under some other classes?
Actually, I am planning to
create another step class for
this duty database team
so that we can put all the database
recruiting things inside of that.
So let's go.
Are you guys following me? Right.
You guys are following me.
Okay, so, so many steps, steps
that flexible all the way down
next to started in here?
No, not in here
and here.
Okay.
So, guys,
once I have the all ready,
how can I get the
have you guys already created objects
to get the already.
Let me check
the new page first.
This is the employer ID right.
The web element to get the employer ID
please
do not break our framework
that is I'm I'm doing nothing.
All all I'm doing is just following
your commands.
So how can I do that?
But which class object I need?
Add new employee page.
I want to get the ID
of a and
guys, let's create one more class inside
your utils.
Let's create a new class
inside your utils.
Let's call it global
variables
and alert.
Let's create a variable.
You already have this case.
Global variables class.
No, that is different.
The initialization or initialize
the initialize
there is different page and slightly
public
static
string.
Let's call it MP.
Right.
And all.
So once we have this
add dot
mp id lock. Right.
This is what contains the ID.
So I will say get attribute and let's
take the value of it.
And last, let's store
that inside global variables.
Dot MP IP
and I am keeping things simple,
so it just contains a public
static variable string variable.
Okay.
Yep. Yep. Yep.
I can issue with scenario for one second.
Yep. Are you guys
done? The global variables
scenario for a section
here is automatically.
Can you show steps? Yes.
You just give me one moment.
The steps. No, sorry.
Not the steps.
We see all the steps.
You don't have to create
an object of an employ page.
Okay, You guys can get this information
in many, many different ways.
Whatever way source you
you guys can use that.
You guys literally know
more about cucumber than me.
It's been a while
since I looked at things about cucumber.
Can someone copy MP I lock for me.
I missed that location.
I need the
this one
and let me know guys, once you are ready
so that we can move forward.
So when the when this step
will be executed what will happen?
The employ I.D.
from that page, the value of that employee
I need will index stored
inside this MP underscore ID.
Right?
And then because it is a static variable,
we can access this information
anywhere inside this project easily.
So that's why I have stored
this MP sitting here.
There's also got the first name guys,
and that's also going to be first name.
So Global variable start.
First name is equal to law
class named that you
value
and yes, you will be getting an error.
You can or enter
and you can click on create
for the first name in global application
just like this
and an enter field to indicate.
So we will only verify the first name.
Also guys, this website has a bug.
So will we see the same first name
that we enter inside that page?
We should we see the same
first name from the backend
we should see,
but we will not see the same information
in the back end.
Right?
So this scenario,
if we don't see the actual information,
if the information does not match,
then should pass
in our current scenario
because we have a bug index.
So I will talk to the developers as well
today after this class
so that they can fix that bug.
But we will write a scenario in which
we will make sure that the first name
that we are putting from the frontend
is not same, that we get from the backend.
This is how the website is behaving
currently, right?
If I am not wrong
or a also
just to make sure that
just to make sure
that we are getting all the information
from backend and further,
let's also print out this information
in here. So
MP underscore I'd be
R&D and
the first rule we always do
get the first
me know
once you guys have by default.
So we have successfully implemented
one step in here right?
Let's check the next step
then verify the results
from the UI and the backend of the.
So let's create
a separate class for No, no, no.
We should also be having
one more step, right? Yes.
You read the information from the backend,
looks something like this.
So I am creating a separate class
to write all the steps that involve
during the recoveries
and you send the page or.
Yes. Or I'm just going.
So let's define this step in here.
You want the adding place
page dot feature on the page.
This add new imply page.
This one
along with
well but you why do you guys need
Have you not launched
the French project from GitHub?
You guys might run into problems
if you are having some things
missing in your framework.
Can you try to furthermore
define those things?
Oh, you lost, but I don't think so.
You have made any changes in here?
I have not made any changes in here,
so let's implement
this part of the code as well.
But before I am using my framework
code, I don't regret this defeat.
We're willing to be personal.
Link to the first, don't link it anywhere.
Distorted entire the global variables.
If you are unable to follow me, you can
you can stop me.
So now this is the time to write back.
And let's just store the variables
inside the global variables class.
Just store this idea and first name.
Then you open global variables.
New. Yep.
This is the global variables.
Is there anyone else
who is lagging behind?
It's all crazy. My you.
You both die together like the way
it was written in behind the card there
there are no bags.
Will will die like legend tries
to be like three elements.
You implement one method So far? Yes.
One step so far.
Yes. No. We please open query database.
There is nothing in particular database
except that step.
I have error.
Alex, are you using your
have you uploaded a fresh project
or you are using an existing framework?
Then you should not be having this issue.
Then you should not be having this issue
global.
It is boarding for
an employee.
No, no, no.
The class name is different.
Not on the class name is different.
You have missed by for the class name.
The class name is
really that
it is add new employee page.
You have written add employer steps
it should we add new employee page?
Is there anyone else
who is getting any issues?
All good. So again,
I move to the next step.
Guys.
So now we need to
have a class inside the European spec
so as we have methods, common methods,
configurator constraint, excavators.
Now we will also have a class that will
help us deal with the databases, right?
So let's create a class
and let's call it
baby utils.
So it will have all the common methods
that we can use reused again and again.
Right? So db utils
and the methods
that we wrote inside in here,
inside of this neighborhood
is let's copy these methods
and also
let's do this guys,
the last method that we developed,
let's
copy this method and let's modify this
so that once we put a wide acuity to this
method,
we get a list of maps
that contains the results
set against that guilty.
So let me copy this piece of information
in here, and let's create a method to
complete a static list
list of maps.
And we contain
strings
and let's call it get
able that is.
And in here we will be providing
only the query, right?
Let's be based
whatever code we have written in here
and looks modified, the results.
So what do you guys think we are?
Should I call this piece of information?
Should it go inside?
Global Variables Configurator
Constants Configuration file.
Where should I put this this?
I should do this
inside the configurator.
This is where
I will put the information. Right?
So I will say.
So let's change it to
maybe
password.
Go back to utils so we can.
You want me to go back
to your distributive
property?
Where did we based From the demo
that we did before the break.
Okay, let me develop this db utils method
then I will share with you
the last demo.
Let me let me develop it completely.
Then I would share it. So guys,
I have stored the information in here.
Now how can I bring this information
from here
inside this DB Which class
I should use to fight this information?
I need this information in here.
DB You are a username and password,
so I should use my configurator
config reader Dog
guard property value.
And what do I specify
inside the get property guide?
I specify the name of the property.
What is the name of the property?
This is the name of the property. Right?
So db is
like this.
Then again.
Okay.
Same for the
username
and password.
Right.
So guys, make sure that you guys are using
the exact
same simple
username and password.
All looks good
up till now.
Okay.
Do you guys need these comments
or I should remove it to just make sure
the code.
I think it will be better
to keep these comments right.
Okay.
So we have created the connection
right now instead of hard coding the query
should change to config.
Okay.
In the config
we have added the WRAL username
and password and the will.
Do you want me to send it to you?
Oh, here it is.
Come on
today.
Stop.
Stop. Are you.
Is it worth effort and the code.
Let me modify it completely.
Let me do the modification
then I need you.
Do you guys know your goal?
Any one of you know
you are going from batch?
Well, no.
Okay.
So what I see is both so many questions
in this channel.
I mean, literally, if there is a semicolon
missing, she will not look at it.
She will pass
first post request an export channel,
and then she will
be calling.
This is missing.
I know.
So the duty that is being passed to this
method, I will
I will pass this query in here
inside to the executed right.
Then it will automatically check
all the columns that are inside of this
that we are getting
as a result of this query
and a list of map will be created.
Do I need this for.
Look guys,
it only prints the column names.
Do I need this?
I know this time
I also don't need this new line.
I create bitmaps
then copy all these
that are stored inside of the table row.
I also don't need to print in here.
I also don't need this one.
And once I am done I close the connection.
And finally I have done
the table
that I have declared this.
So it should be
before the project
so that we can easily access it.
And then I return
the table
that right?
Why? We get an error
list of map strings, string.
Oh we have not initialized it very.
The table
variable that might not have any fly.
Okay.
But we're on
here. Not appropriate.
Let's
all looks good.
So what will happen
once we pass the query to this method?
We will get a list of maps
that will contain the data against this.
All looks good.
All clear. Any confidence?
I need your db utils after
you are sure I will get it right.
Do you guys have any questions?
Do you guys want me to share
the complete utils or just this table
that our method complete?
There is no more?
Might need to change the variable name
for database user name and password.
Yes. Yes.
Yes and yes. You are right.
Nice build. Right.
What did I do with the names I use?
User name?
Okay. So
I think I updated it.
DB password.
I have already updated it.
No. Yes, you're right.
We don't need to modify.
Okay then this method looks good.
Okay.
So do we have a break up?
So as per the instructions from Manager
Lobo,
could you scroll down?
Guys, let me do
the second push this to GitHub
so that you guys can, you guys can chat
and get all the objects.
So we finally played this game
here is defined
and the code has been pushed.
You guys can also get it from this.
We can.
You guys.
What happened to your analogy?
I remember those days, initial Java days,
everyone was so
and rejected to be posting
so many questions
and everything is dead
inside is
red. That is missing my mood
battery low.
I think we are really tired
doing assignments.
I think just 25 or 20 more days. Right.
How many more guys before
you are done with your API classes then?
These are the mandatory classes.
All other things are optional.
Two weeks, just 15 days, guys.
Just for 15 days. Yes.
Please have some
something to keep your end ready for.
Next two weeks.
Will we have access to video recording
after we finish to revise the concept?
Oh, don't worry. About that.
I think still
there was a student from Batch six.
I don't know what happened to him.
And after six he now there are two.
Have the access any large pool again?
Go on the market
and you want to prepare everything.
So I am still helping him
plot his interviews coding as guiding you
everything. Don't worry about that.
I find you a little difficult then.
Other topics we learned so far.
All that's very different
and I'll
be bringing you
so that I can also use something.
20 minutes will be enough, right?
Please be back by 137.
But no appetite so that
I don't know all the details,
but it does mean something related.
Food. Right.
All right, guys, please.
If you are facing an issues,
please read all your issues.
Make sure you are in sync with me
after the break.
And will have followed all the steps here.
Have a nice minute.
Thank you, guys. I see you.
I think we should revise all of this again
if we want to change our job in future.
Yes, definitely.
You guys are right.
Should not quit on us.
I think we are still missing two steps,
so I don't know what
will be the results. Want
to upload the code we use?
Get fetch to upload the code?
No. No.
To upload the code.
Why would?
We use the fetch
on date.
You mean download to download the code
to clone it.
Updated
to update the code.
Just press this.
This blue arrow, this update project.
No, no, no. Don't clone it again.
Just Click on this blue arrow.
Every one of you can get all of this
update by just speaking on this.
Settle
or you have also cloned from there.
And so you can click on this
and let the incoming changes in
to the current branch
and you can ignore your changes
with changes that you have made
and you can accept my changes.
Okay,
You guys are already pro in a good pride.
You should be teaching me how to use it.
I don't know anything about it.
I just know about these desperados.
Blue Arrow.
Green Arrow. Green Arrow Mean turned over.
The thing to the blue arrow means that
I would have been from bigger to
actually we lack knowledge of
get from intelligent directly.
Yes you guys are all next level actors
using command to do everything.
This is this guy is for
less knowledgeable persons like me.
I name it.
I think you have the wrong
Katrina in here.
Okay.
Or he will send me a message
that has some for us.
For us.
But thanks me for something.
She takes your duties very seriously.
All right, guys.
So I hope
all of you have this code
in your cucumber frameworks
that we have written in here
right.
Anyway, thanks, Carter.
Yawn. Now, after Katrina,
I almost
to be
okay.
So we have a method
that can give us detect.
You have the utilities.
So what were we doing, guys?
You were implementing these steps right.
Uh, which step we were implementing before
this.
So global variables in here.
And of course, I'll be damned
if that database right.
So guys write down right security
to bring the same information
from the database.
So if let's say
I give you this i.t write down acuity
to bring to fetch the first
and the last name
from the database in here.
Well we already had all this query.
Okay, so let me copy the security
from here.
So how can I write?
How can I which method I should call
and where should I boss this query
or what would I do?
Guys, let's say spring
duty equal to this is my query.
So instead of hard coding this idea,
the idea that I have stored inside
Global Variables class,
I want to use that idea in here.
So I want to create the query
dynamically instead of hardening.
So how can I do that
in the table?
Yes, but let's just let's first create
the query, Right?
Let's first create the query.
How can I do that
if I tried?
Plus signs in here, how can I
how can I modify the string I is Michael,
How can I modify the screen?
No, no one knows how to do that right?
I have a string and I want to concatenate
i d with the string
or per here.
And so when we are calling
so delegate brains, then it's
E plus, plus
blah, blah, blah.
How can I concatenate a
I want to do a single code in here.
Is it okay.
Let me show you a demo actually first
baby wise
you have I think for what everything.
So what I have, let's say
if I have a string already in here,
something this let's
and if I do this
and then print out to verify my theory.
So I will be getting this security
as a result right?
If I do the concatenation this way,
I am copying the security from here
and I execute that.
You re in here. Whoops.
My little very quickly,
I don't get any results.
How can I write this code in here?
How can I do that
in double course
in here?
I need to run the single course like this.
Like this.
So if now I execute
in this query
new line for one, you want it.
You want to have new line
voting.
I be like,
Looks good, right?
Look, copy this query unit
or bring it to our friend.
So single course in here
and in here.
So we have successfully created
the query seemed like only alone.
Our brains is working.
What is going on? I didn't not understand.
Most of you also don't understand.
It's fine.
I don't understand anything from love.
For the last seven years.
Why? We're near
the same query twice in my equal.
We don't need the same beauty
twice in equal.
We were just learning how to build
a query dynamically,
how to build a query,
how to build a curious heart,
how to build a query like this.
Right.
This is how we specify the idea, right?
You guys
remember if something is off,
what are data type
and if I am not using these codes in here,
do you guys remember
what happens?
You will not get the results.
You might not get an error,
but definitely not the proper results.
Right.
And in this case, because the dynamic URI
also contains a letter,
so definitely it will not work.
So that's why we learned
how to place these
a single course after and before we ID
should not.
We put this semicolon inside this thing.
It is not required.
But if you want to do that, you can do
that.
Semicolon is when you have
multiple queries inside an editor
or if you are executing multiple queries
to distinguish one query from another.
If the query is single.
So for example,
if I remove all of these queries
so I can also aggregate it
without the semicolon.
Semicolon is an iterative and than one
lines of queries you are writing together
so that your tools
can work correctly.
Is it good to
make it make sense?
All right, so I have built ambiguity.
So what do you suggest to add or not?
In here we have a single query.
We don't need it.
If you even if you edit it is fine.
It is fine.
You want to edit, you can edit no issues.
So which method?
I should call guys
from db utils.
I should call get the table data right
and I should pass the query in here
and let's let store the results
in global variable again.
And because we don't have this variable,
yes, we will be getting an error.
So let's this field in here
and the type of the field
should be list of maps
and what the things should
be asking.
All good guys here
for you.
And I see query database.
You have to
this one right
if you
and you explain line well please
so in here of this
DB utils is a class it has a static method
I am calling it with only the class name
and I am passing the duty to this method.
This method takes security
and returns us a list of maps
that contains the data against that
good in show global place here.
Sure. This.
This is the global.
It's fine guys.
If you guys have more questions,
please ask.
Did you guys realize how these six months
passed?
So quickly?
It's just two more weeks
too quick.
I know. So scary.
Please don't start.
I think it is time
you guys should start revising things.
I don't believe it is two weeks only.
First,
So mandatory part is only two weeks
remaining is optional.
You can start applying after two weeks.
Can I see the Q2 database please?
Here, Raghu, please.
Yes, we will have sessions
for back as well.
But first we have to pass all them.
All contribute, right? Yes. Clicking?
Yes. And second,
still thinking in our brains
that I know for sure, but
oh no, you guys are all really.
You have to learn
so many things in interview as well.
Is there anyone who is still lagging
behind
third guys try to shake your hand.
Do you feel some java in there?
How just kind of just confirming
to get updated with
get quickly all we have to do is press
on which arrow exactly and I will
this one and this blue one
update project is update project.
We will take more interviews.
Your seniors
most probably students from Batch nine
because their Yes, yes,
yes they have already filled
ten interviews.
We will be teaching interview
prep class and Java.
Ask you Will Jenkins.
I will teach API most probably so Hal
cucumber test and most ASL and wisdom.
We get Amazon
and we have another instructor who will
teach how to how to dress,
what perfumes,
to use of audio, online interviews
with what jewelry to wear, literally.
I mean, it's not because as the other side
cannot feel it,
but it is for you guys, the perfumes,
they make you feel
they can change your mood,
the jewelry, the
the dresses that you wear,
they give you confidence.
So he has a Ph.D.
in Social or something like that.
So he will teach you all of this stuff.
And believe me, it effects it.
It effects.
I don't want you to give the interviews
in your pajamas sitting in front of
just laptops all by God, we haven't really
let's have a call for that.
So we want to have you mentally ready
for like, for example,
if you are sitting in front of it,
in front of maybe
two or three persons for in your real life
interviews making out in Nice,
what I never hear,
the interviewer would not see
but and you will feel it.
You will feel it.
No, but seriously,
when you are online, we need perfume.
When When
we are online, we need perfume. Yes.
So that you don't get killed
by your own smell.
You know. Nice.
But you never feel
it's.
I mean, it is also possible to write it
with level.
We will have after course,
in the middle of
you will be having
five years of experience
after
Simon.
You are right. Why?
I never read
so 30 guys.
I cannot control myself.
My thought is never feel
as good as they look.
I can tell about my galaxy.
Watch It looks and feels good.
Is it middle or zero zero? Fred?
Why are you guys ready?
We have to do some
like we are
all with five years of experience.
Mine is an old Omega.
Yes. My God. They also have good watches
for silly guys.
They also have good.
Okay,
so is there anyone
who don't understand this line? 12.
So until this point, we have successfully
captured idea of the employee.
That's why you are not wearing them.
Oh, I have actually started it.
It is starting.
So that's why I just placed it
on the on the charger.
Otherwise I was wearing
when I started the class
here that told us.
So we have successfully captured
the ID, constructed the query
and then passed that query
to the get table data method
and it will give us a list of map
that will contain the data.
So there is one more step
that we have to implement
and that is the result verified.
The results have been here
and so
let's pick in.
So guys, I have the
first name inside
global variables dot first name right?
And the first name
that we are getting from the DB.
Okay.
Lurking indicator variable
string of first name.
Okay.
From DB,
so how we can get it
have already stored that list of maps
inside the global variables.
Right?
So global variables dart table data.
So this table data
contains a list of maps.
So first I need to fetch
the first index on the list.
How can I get the
element at a specific index
if I am inside,
if I am using a list right
by get method right, how many rows
we will be getting as a result
of this query?
One. Right.
And at which index that row will be placed
inside this list of maps.
Zero. Right.
Once I have accessed the element
that index number zero.
What will
what type of element it will be guides.
What does this list contain?
No, no, no. What does this list contain?
It does not contain strings directly.
It contains maps.
And from map
I can get data by by passing the key.
Right.
What will be the key for the first name?
MP Underscore First name
or only the first name?
MP First name right.
Because remember we wrote a genetic code
that fetches all the columns
and for each column
then it fetches all the names, right?
So MP first name.
So if I pass this MP first name in here,
this, this is the first name
that I am getting from the database.
Everyone understand this.
This is the first name that I am getting
from the database, right?
So let me write
the first name from
that obvious
plus first name
and where we have stored
the first name that we got from the Dubai.
Do you guys remember?
Where did we store
the first name that we got from the UAE?
Let me show it again.
We implemented a step
capture, employ I.D., Right.
We capture the employee I.D.
and also the first name that we enter.
Where do we put it?
We store it inside
the global variables dot first name
right face.
So this is the first name
that we are getting from the Dubai
right.
And then
just print out
this information
and let's see what information we get.
Let's because we have written so much code
and we have not tested
all of these methods, so there are chances
that there might be problems.
So let's first
print out the things and let's verify
if everything is fine or not.
So how can I
how can I execute this test do what is
why is it that the interface
has a graphical user interface UI or the
user interface or the.
So we should go to do it on our class.
So we change changed
the runner class right already.
And then we simply need
to execute this class.
So everyone close your eyes,
have your hand on your heart
and close your doors and windows
and stop your breath for a second.
And pray together that it works
fine.
It works.
You have already done it
or it should be false.
Sorry. False.
Actually false.
Did you change or not?
I have just seen
at least I am on the wall
so it has opened the browser.
Are you guys also running with me?
Everyone is running.
Can you guys please stop for a moment
so that we at least know if it
if whatever
we have to do today to get there?
It looks
good.
It entered.
I think I missed something
since I got an error on the last step.
My utils or the global variable is null
so I missed something
but we will find out.
Don't worry and we will find out
if we are getting it.
There might be some issues
related to saving.
Stephen is not allowed with all the sorry,
we have to change it for something else.
Sorry on the
you cannot wait to get that
blah blah.
I have you guys also use the same
same name that I am using in here.
Maybe every one of you
have you guys use the same save names.
Please don't copy everything.
You that lists make some changes
that we're going to be
again this time please vote.
So it might be my fault
yours is nursing.
Actually, this website has already
also have a lot of bugs.
Sometimes it works, sometimes it doesn't.
You guys know better than me.
And yes, it was.
It was the name that caused the problem.
Employ saved successfully
and let's see what we have planned.
So when user
enters blah blah blah blah blah blah,
no suitable
found for the day and the dependencies
formed or tags email.
And I want to make sure that I reload
the front of the
i also guys if you are getting
even if after using the older word,
then if you are the error you can
invalidate invalidate your cache as well.
From here
and you can restart your intelligence
so that it builds everything
from scratch.
So many tests are working
with this website and it still has bugs.
Wait for it to index the file.
It might take some time,
not even to do it and not enough
developers.
Is there anyone who has also
got this skill?
Can you show how you did it?
The invalidate thing it is file
and then invalidate caching me error.
Sure.
Me same.
Let's wait it for.
Although being as this is a class
for testers, one could argue
all bugs on the outside
are not in fact bugs, they are features.
Was it helpful?
What then is it?
Is it still indexing?
Next, let's see if it was helpful and
so you guys should see
a progress board in here
that is indexing.
Maybe if someone is using a core
I9 or a good laptop, maybe
the indexing is already done for them
and you guys,
it is working now.
And one Mac Yep.
They are faster, they are faster.
Still running,
not working.
We have millions of projects.
Look at next to you.
What did you change for?
No suitable driver
I have just invalidated the cache.
Maybe we might need
to change the connector. Got.
Then we might need to change
the building out in here.
We did.
I ran it and it also got that problem
embedding
null pointer exception.
Then it's going to show me
the start of the error.
NULL pointer is fine.
We can fix that.
Let me check. Why? Why?
Because we want us to say goodbye.
See my as
we are
use the same string
guys.
Give me what I think right
now. Understood.
We need to remove this double course
because it is taking
this whole string
like this.
Nice.
Go inside your config file
and remove those double code in here.
We will fix the null point, but not very.
We will fix not find that
notebook and not invoke java list.
Dart into that because that isn't
for the username to do.
We have all the
we also have double course for username.
Oh yes, yes.
Yes. You are right.
We should also with
this is going to stick
now we will get another data
for not entering the property
username and password.
Okay. Now look
remove semicolon.
Yes, I have a little bit, but
what about semicolon. Yes.
Remove access denied
because there were double faults
with the username as well
as is.
Great.
Great. Great.
Let me also check it on my end.
Works now.
Oh but still right.
It didn't work in the first go.
It always happened
like no matter how many years
you have been coding
and if you have written so much code
and if you run, you at least
at least one after.
If it happened only once.
I wrote so much code and it all worked
perfectly fine, but only one
works fine.
So slow means
try removing this all
the maybe it will become faster
or you guys now have added blah blah
as well.
Who has edited this blah blah now.
Okay guys, you will never let my desk
pass right?
Don't you get answers to.
I know. Then is it? Is you right?
Let me be quicker than you.
Hopefully
my entry will be passed to study it.
No way.
I I will.
If it still does not work,
I will move it to a different screen.
I will enter something different
and then I will bring that.
So you see Usman
in here?
Mine must be one oligarchic.
KING Okay, of
this time it passes.
So that
the employ it was going to be 500, right?
The first name was blah.
This is the information that we
entered from the front back,
and then we perform the
captured employer I.D.
then save the employer successfully added
the security information from back
and the first name from database is bla
first name from July is also blah.
Then verify the results from
you are going back
end so we only need this simple part
in which we need to write the assertion.
Right.
But how do we write it?
Alert's equal.
Am I missing some kind of
alerts.
Well, this one right?
And we boss the expected
and the actual results
are so firstname from baby.
And then the first name from the guy
looks work, right?
Gestures.
Is there anything that you guys
want to document
or you want to add something you can
and now you can remove these print out
statements if it is working, fine.
But I think it will be good
if instead of removing, we can come out
show your db utils please.
Yes. Now let's resolve all of your issues
first, the issues
that you guys are getting
and then we will run together
the b utils.
Here we have the debut documents
and let me also push this to Bertram.
Just just one
and be the first thing.
Dude,
what does this error means?
Which error invoke
java list door to get to because
utils or two global variables
that our table is null,
you'll get that you are doing
some mistake in your query be met.
Third to get a table
that is returning you in null value.
So there is something terrible
going wrong inside your get table method.
Do you want the method from me?
The print out straight
only the print statement statements.
Let me you mind.
Maybe you can.
And I think you would also be needing
these matters.
And I have guys
I have already pushed the code to the
YouTube as well as version pass.
Yes, it should pass.
We will also execute it. So
you guys want to have a look at the
this is the db utils
then if you want to have a look in here.
Uh, yes.
The sequence is important for us to leap.
First we should pass the WRAL,
then the DB username
and then the DB password.
The sequence is important.
Mustafa, you, you have written. Thank you.
I'm done. I don't know.
Is it in Afghani?
What does it mean by done?
I mean, if you call in Lady John in here
in Pakistan,
she will beat the hell out of you.
Yes, G
John means like
it's like, like, like you are calling it.
It's something, for example,
it has a very bad meaning in it.
Yes dear.
In but in local in here they call John
someone like for example
whom you love very much.
And you want to
you want her to be your wife or something.
Very, very close in here.
This is what it means in here.
Same in my country. Yes.
In India as well.
In India
as when you don't accidentally call
someone done it
in Turkish as well.
Yep. Every name has done
after the name hon.
And John.
Okay.
In my country they call everyone John.
Thank
everyone.
John But there is also John studies
also. John
and Bill is also done do though.
So John, what does it mean in John
and not in your country?
B Oh yes, the literal meanings
they are here,
but the actual meanings are very,
very different here saying
or is there anyone who is getting issues,
errors, unable
to get the results, getting no values?
Yes, same in Farsi.
You did life, love and
add steps dot add employ
steps verify result from db
logo.
Share a complete screenshot of the error
some of you can post in this portal
and some of you can share in here.
Yes, you want to see the steps which
the steps to verify the
we need there to be.
We we need to do this one
alone.
We were using double codes with
the individual and a semicolon
also with user name and password.
So we removed those. Yes.
Because in in config files
we don't use double codes for screens.
It is automatically treated at this time.
What was the purpose in this case
we talking different
we took a different result
from front and back
and so the purpose was for
but sometimes what can happen is back
and let's say
developers can make mistake and instead of
starting this door
inside the first name column
in your database in here,
they can store this information
maybe in the middle name
or maybe in the in the last name.
Right in the in the logic, there can be
so many things that can go wrong
or it can also happen that the data is not
stored at all in the backend.
So we now have verified that
whatever columns we have decided
for these front end fields,
the data is actually getting stored
inside the exact same fields in the back
and the frontend.
One more thing, this database, and
it might be
that there might be multiple applications
that might be using this database.
So for example,
you guys must have noticed that
for the Facebook, when you use it
from your smartphone and when you use it
from the laptop, it always contains
the same information, right?
If there are no bugs,
whatever you post from your computer,
you should be able to see
from your smartphone and whatever
you do from your smartphone,
it should be in sync with your desktop.
So that means that app and the Facebook
page should be web application.
It is all synchronized.
They are using the same databases.
So these databases, your API is my next.
You will learn the API
if your API might be hitting databases,
your smartphone app, your desktop
application to your web application.
So we don't create
separate databases for that
because this database stays the same.
We make sure that every application,
wherever that application
is supposed to be data,
the data is actually getting stored
in those
columns.
Mahlobo is getting a lobotomy.
The first line of the error.
Then it is also getting an error
access denied for the user syntax.
No to that.
Remove the semicolon at the end from
if you
you are also doing the same mistake
in here.
In here in the config properties
file, remove the semicolon
and the double course.
Then if I still have this error, no
suitable driver Marina, please make sure.
No double course, no semicolons with DB
you are all first name
and last name.
I did
access denied for using password.
No, your password is incorrect.
The password that you are using.
Nobody is incorrect.
Let me. Let me show you this.
Maybe you are legal
guys, please use this information
in your config file.
Update the db
you are username and password with this.
Can you paste the code from my sequel?
Yes. This one?
Sure.
Welcome.
I got mine passed
just now after the fourth trial.
There it is.
So guys, I have
a homework for your ability to do this.
So I want you to add one more scenario
and this scenario, what I want you to do
may be you.
You guys can pretty much write
anything, enter
any information in the frontend,
fetch the same information
from the backend,
and make sure the information is same.
You can choose any of the scenarios.
It will be good
if you guys can write those scenarios
before the next review class
and guys also make sure
that you are to be review classes
because I have intentionally not covered
some things that might help you,
so I have only covered the basics.
That is enough,
but it will be better if you guys
can spend some time
attending the previous classes.
Who will teach the review?
You know, guys, I'm getting engaged.
I am a busy person for the next four days,
so I will not be available.
Sorry guys.
It's the right. Now.
I am supposed to take the review class,
but I am trying my best not to that.
So I have written a very long message
to ASL that I am not available.
Let's see what response we get from other
next review class voltage
guys.
All you have to do so many things so
and by the way,
you guys might have your review
or tomorrow on Monday.
And this is the advice from me
guys, please, please.
Soon you guys will be in your interviews.
And I have noticed this.
It happens with many student interviews.
They just ask them to write a simple class
and a method inside their class
and maybe a look at students
cannot even do this.
Please, please start
having some practice with your java.
No jobs without those Java skills.
If you want to be applying as a
automation tester, should we get
our flight tickets to Pakistan?
I am trying my best to get it done.
2224, 2022 ends.
I don't know. Code weird.
So many things that are going wrong.
I know maybe the world
will end by this year, so
I am trying my best to do it before people
get it.
Plus 92 more guests. Yup.
Wedding day is not confirmed yet.
Yes, you guys will be. I will postpone.
Get off the announcement
about the saw and heard what you said
and he said you are dramatic.
Yep. Yep. So
life in life is very short.
I think we should be staying happy.
I am really very.
It's very, very weird.
I am serious. It's very, very rare.
And maybe in years
I get serious for 5 to 10 minutes
and the next moment I start again.
Even though I can hardly hold my love,
even when I am somebody is dead,
then you know when we go on funerals
and things like that.
It's very, very hard for me to know.
Someday those people,
they will beat the hell out of me.
Because what you are talking your wedding.
Usually you
now you are dramatically funny
and or funny
and then you
actually you and I,
even if I am not making jokes,
I just look at the face of my friend.
And because we done so many things
in our childhood,
I we cannot control our love.
You are not allowed to go to funerals.
I mean, you you guys must all
also have those friends, right?
They don't even speak you.
You can just be with them
and you will not stop laughing
all bad calls.
I am that friend.
They should be printed his photo
on the funeral gates with this sign
not allowed
for me.
All right.
Please let me check
if we are missing something there.
You guys, my client has helpful.
Okay.
There is a YouTube series,
so you guys will not be having time
to go through all these
five or 3 hours videos. Ask
really?
So I want you to at least go through.
These are very good videos.
I am 5 to 6 minutes
and it will also teach you
how to actually install the database
on your computer starting from scratch.
And they are
these are very detailed videos.
So just make sure that the only slides
that you have written
which concepts are important for,
your interviews.
Just make sure you guys are watching
those videos
at least.
So here is the link.
I think you want us to run yours, please.
I think you want to sleep. Oscar.
Did you do that after Save button?
It shows other potentials that we insert
video that after
save button and show other credentials
that insert.
You mean the first name and the last name?
You want me to run? Michael?
Have I done something wrong?
Where is that step? Is
is. Is there something wrong in here?
150 No, no,
You guys got to watch 150 videos.
Just only those
which are important for your interviews.
This person has also used
very short tables with only 5 to 10 rows.
To explain the context.
And after watching these videos,
by the way, if you have time
and if you can watch,
you can write on your resume
that you have experience with Oracle,
as given my skill and skills
are about three different databases
from three different companies.
Just if you can manage the time
and it will be a very,
very good impact on you and to be honest,
only separate jobs
just for the is in the industry.
You guys can also do
the research on your own.
Okay. So then is here is here is the deal.
Even if we get any errors,
we are not solving those errors.
We are ending this class
in fast.
That's it
you are you getting any error
on your order?
No. Can be.
It did not pass.
You saw that? What?
I didn't see anything
after save button or.
Yes it changes the name. This is that.
That's what you guys want to tell me.
Yes, I know. This is this is a known bug?
That's what I was saying.
I will talk to the developers for this.
I will fix
it will be fixed by in one or two days.
Don't worry about that will be fixed.
I will talk to the developers.
What's the difference between
what are what are to learn and ask
you also these
What are and what told they are.
It is the underlying
implementation is different.
So it is and this stuff is related to
the DBA is only we
don't need to do
and we don't need to go into the details.
These are different variations
of the water as well.
Something this water is for backward
compatibility.
This what our tool was added
later in the databases.
But these tables, the schema, either
the architects or
the senior as they will be deciding
how to create these things as a tester.
Well,
you guys will never create these things.
Tell the developers always change to blah
blah, blah.
It's a big bug.
They don't do that to us.
Yes, I will talk to them tonight.
Sorry, which one is the bug?
They're not cool. You don't know the bug.
You guys have been using this outside
for so many years.
Five years, right?
All those five years.
Two years.
And all your efforts, right.
That you have put in this website.
Oh, by the way, is dated a student.
If you want to join, but I don't think so.
You guys need them, right?
You were also sleeping yesterday.
We are now enrolling in program.
All right, guys.
See you later.
Take some rest
and I will see you next week.
Maybe for the Jenkins classes.
We have to prepare
one list of questions for
for previous library
guys, for the students.
It works better.
Take care.
Thank you, guys. Thank you so much.